coming up on Garden talk having a
diverse and healthy roots on ecology is
like one of the non-essential elements
of a growing that is probably one of the
most essential things that we're
learning so like the environmental
factories your soil moisture content and
you know the temperature of the room
have a huge role to play in the nutrient
uptake and transpiration ability of your
plants you know your mineral nutrition
your your nitrates your phosphorus your
potassium that is the same molecule
regardless of bottle salt bran country
of origin all of that the plants are
constantly evolving as we're growing
them you know because they're not
growing out in the wild so their needs
are going to evolve as well so it's a
that's why I think things like Leaf
tissue testing leachate testing are so
important to really know what the
plant's eating
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 95. in this
episode I interview Mike Chang he works
for Canada Crips Consulting and he does
Consulting for things such as IPM Plant
Nutrition gaining efficiency and
cultivations and cultivation protocol
planning I narrow down the focus in this
episode to proper nutrition for plants
throughout their entire life if you gain
value from these podcast episodes please
click the like button and also subscribe
to the channel if you haven't already
that way you can be notified when new
episodes are released if you'd like to
support even more visit patreon.com Mr
Grow it there are various rewards set up
for those that support and you can
pledge any amount that you'd like 100 of
the money pledged through patreon goes
right back into the podcast it helps
this podcast keep going so thank you so
much for your support there before we
get into it I want to acknowledge that
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free gardening information of all
plants to the general public the that
being said I'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that goal possible thanks to aec
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
they now have humidifiers called the
cloud Forge I'd be using the cloud Forge
T3 which has a 4.5 liter capacity and
can be filled from the top it also
includes a hose so you can place the
humidifier outside your grow tent and
feed the hose into your grow tent saving
you precious space it also connects to
the controller 69 Pro so you can control
it from your smartphone I'll have a link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about their humidifiers
and the discount code Mr Grow at 15
works on both Amazon and their website
AC infinity.com and we're back welcome
to the Garden Talk podcast today I am
joined with Mike Chang from Canon cribs
Consulting how you doing today hey good
how are you Chris good good thanks for
asking so you and I have worked on some
projects in the past and I feel like it
was just a few months ago where I was
like come on the podcast gotta get the
podcast
you have so much good knowledge when it
comes to Horticulture you have a ton of
knowledge and plant nutrition IPM
gaining efficiencies and cultivations
and cultivation protocol planning so
today I figured we'd focus in on Plant
Nutrition I have a bunch of good
questions lined up for you and I think
this is going to bring a lot of value to
the audience but first can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and how you
got into gardening yeah sure so I guess
I started everything after I got out of
the military in 2010 and I started to
grow at home in California uh just kind
of a hobbyist but back then it was kind
of wild Westy and you could sell your
bud to co-ops and all that other stuff
so it's pretty fun
um and after that I wanted to kind of
get a an education in agriculture and
kind of do things a little bit more
properly so I went to the U of A in
Arizona and uh while I was there I got a
really good internship at an ad company
and pivoted into agriculture for a while
and so I was working in like field corn
um cotton a lot of greenhouse stuff so
cucumbers Tomatoes the agricultural
World in Arizona is pretty pretty vast
so I wasn't uh I wasn't short on work
there but I just got the itch to come
back and that's when I got with Nate and
uh and we started to just uh I started
to work for him and we kind of built
this Consulting side awesome
so getting into Plant Nutrition there
are essential elements for plants and
there are non-essential elements for
plants talk to us about the Essential
Elements for plants sure so the common
knowledge for most essential nutrients
is going to be like your NPK your
nitrogen phosphorus and potassium and
then you have your slew of
micronutrients the micronutrients that's
uh that's what we know as essential
right now things like molybdenum Boron
iron manganese you know the the main
Usual Suspects but we're constantly
learning about new
roles that elements play in Plants as we
continue to study plants which is kind
of an interesting thing that you asked
about non-essential elements I mean I
can go over the Essential Elements first
here so like nitrogen
basic building block that's going to be
for all your amino acids you know um all
of the cell structures things like that
so that's basic building blocks for
tissues and chlorophyll your phosphorus
is going to be mainly your energy
transport things like it's moving in ATP
it's it's helping move
um metabolites across membranes things
like that potassium is going to be for
your enzyme activation and to move
sugars across the plan and for osmotic
pressure so those three things are the
most used by the plant
in addition to oxygen carbon and
hydrogen of course but all the
micronutrients play other roles in the
plant they're kind of like vitamins in
humans where we need carbs fat and
protein but we also need vitamins for
all of our other functions and the
micronutrients like calcium sulfur
magnesium those all fill that role and
so the micronutrients and the
macronutrients would be considered your
Essential Elements and we can go into
any one of those in more detail okay got
it and then for the non-essential
elements for plants I think one that
comes to mind right away is silica right
although silica is essential in some
plants but not in the medicinal plant
that we all know and love right correct
however the research is still out
because what a lot of the current
research on silica's role in a plant's
metabolism now is finding is that not
only is it kind of a maybe not part of
metabolism and it just gets deposited
onto cell walls and that's why everyone
knows that it's good to have silicon
plants so that they don't get overfed on
by bugs but silica actually plays a
pretty important role in a lot of the
metabolic pathways for biotic and
abiotic stress in the plant whether it's
drought or some sort of a pest like a
chewing bug or even like a fungal
pathogen so now that we're seeing that
silica is involved in those metabolic
pathways a lot of those metabolic
pathways we know are conserved in other
plants and higher plants so all it takes
at this point is for us to connect the
dots in the research to see how silica
actually functions in the medicinal
plants that we're typically trying to
cultivate at large scale and then kind
of have hard evidence for that but now
the kind of common knowledge is changing
where silica is being considered a a
kind of an essential nutrient as far as
making sure that a cultivation whether
it's field AG or indoor AG is maximizing
its growing potential and reducing its
need for like pest control products by
increasing the plant's natural
resistance to things what are some ways
that folks can add in silica to the
Garden I know like on the organic side
of things you've got rice holes and then
if you are going with synthetic or a
mineral based it usually comes within a
bottle right usually it's what
orthosolic acid I believe yeah some sort
of salicic acid yeah
and those are all great sources salicic
acids kind of work in the principle of
like Direct Delivery or kind of uh very
close as close to Direct Delivery as
typically was available
um other potassium other sources like
potassium silicates kind of rely on your
root zones ecology to make that silica
available to the plant as well there's a
newer technology out that certain
companies like I think I know of antenna
plant science is using it it's a silica
nanoparticle so it's an SNP and there's
been research showing that silica
particles under 20 micro meter or 20
microns in size can directly get uptaken
into the plant so there's there's newer
ways that we're finding to deliver
silica into plants that are a little bit
more efficient and won't really mess
with mineral nutrition programs like
potassium silicates and things like that
would and are kind of I use at a lower
rate so you don't have to use so much of
it now so my next question is what is
like the application rate for silica it
that is one of those gray areas where
the research has hasn't fully been
elucidated yet for like things like
medicinal plants or even some of our
more major crops we know that it does
help there are certain set PPM
guidelines or set application guidelines
for certain products but those are all
based on a very narrow scope of research
right now so
I think as we kind of like study it more
we'll find out the best way to the best
way to apply and the best amounts to
apply so that we're not kind of over
applying because over applying
fertilizers has kind of been one of the
biggest issues right now in agriculture
so it's all about making sure that we're
being as efficient as possible that
makes sense what other non-essential
elements are out there that you would
recommend Growers consider adding into
the garden
um you know as far as elements I can't
really think of like uh like I couldn't
name like a metal that you should add
but there's certain aspects of plant
cultivation that are lost on the purely
mineral size out of it you can
absolutely grow a plant in an inert
environment with the right mineral
nutrition but there's certain things
like making sure that your carbon and
nitrogen ratio is correct having added
root Zone ecology to help fixate more
nitrogen out of the air help fixate
phosphorus that's in the soil that may
have become immobilized so I think
having a diverse and healthy roots on
ecology is like one of the non-essential
elements of a growing that is probably
one of the most essential things that
we're learning is like the interactions
that plants have with their roots on
ecology and just the the space around
them that kind of helps them optimize
their growth growth or not yeah the
balance of elements within the medium is
certainly important you know it's often
said that medicinal plants require more
nitrogen in the vegetation stage and
more phosphorus and potassium in the
flowering stage is that true science or
Bro Science
it's really true science yeah I mean the
Bros are right A lot of the times they
just haven't been validated yet you know
that's the problem
um so the main reason why you want to
add more nitrogen really to any growing
plant is to increase the growth to have
more basic building materials for those
building blocks for those amino acids so
and also High nitrogen delivery can
signal things in the plants that kind of
shift them to produce even more
vegetative growth more luxurious growth
to kind of be more hungry for other
nutrients which in turn adds to more
growth so higher nitrogen in earlier
stages is typically
recommended also because there's a lot
of research out that directly correlates
more plant biomass in the vegetative
stage equating to more inflorescence or
like more Cut Flower yield towards the
end so if you have more biomass in the
beginning if you can get more vigorous
healthy fast growth in a shorter amount
of time usually with higher nitrogen
rates then that's what you'd opt for so
that in flour you can get the most
benefits from that veg time and then as
far as kind of Shifting over into the
phosphorus and potassium side
phosphorus definitely is required by the
plant in in really both stages whether
it's the vegetative or the flowering
stage because like we talked about one
of the main reasons why the plant needs
phosphorus is for that energy transport
and for its metabolism
we don't want the plant to be
bottlenecked by phosphorus during those
critical stages in flower where we're
pumping secondary metabolites or we're
trying to increase cell density in
flowers things like that so phosphorus
can be very important in those later
stages and you might want to add like a
PK boost so you make sure that
phosphorus isn't your bottleneck now the
jury is a little bit out on potassium
there's been a couple of research
studies done on how potassium kind of
affects and it seems affects the growth
of medicinal plants or even other
cultivars of just kind of flowering
plants there seems to be a range that
like medicinal plants can tolerate when
it comes to potassium which is actually
a pretty wide range and there has been
research that shows that it's almost
maybe cultivar specific there's outliers
within research that show like you know
we didn't really get any results off of
high or low potassium in these in this
study except for this one strain where
you know higher potassium gave bushier
growth larger families things like that
so we're we're seeing that it's a little
bit cultivar specific when it comes to
potassium but the phosphorus definitely
you don't want that to be a bottleneck
so you do want to make sure that you're
applying enough
and um and you do want to make sure that
you are applying enough phosphorus in
the beginning stages where you need
those roots and shoots because it is
very important in that new growth as
well but it's also important in energy
transport later on down the line where
the plant is having a lot of secondary
metabolite actions and it needs to move
a lot of things throughout the plant and
it requires energy to do so
so yeah phosphorus definitely important
later on in flower but you definitely
don't want to over apply something like
phosphorus you want to do things like
maybe Leaf tissue testing to make sure
that you're doing the right amounts so
when you're growing hydroponically it's
a little bit easier to Precision feed
and get certain ratios of nitrogen and
phosphorus potassium so on and so forth
right but how about the folks that are
growing with bottles synthetics right
how do they control that how do they
ensure that they're not that the medium
is balanced with the proper elements
throughout the entire plant's life
so with keeping your nbk balance you
really have to kind of defer to the
manufacturer's specs on whatever
nutrient you're using
um that's why they'll usually break it
off into like a nitrate bottle or like a
cow mag bottle things like that so that
you can play with those numbers
if you wanted to get hard data of course
you would do things like Leaf tissue
testing which honestly is available to
the home Growers nowadays you can just
mail in your samples but if you didn't
want to get that kind of uh granular and
that focused on it what you'd want to do
is kind of just look at the numbers on
your bottles and then just do the math
on what you're putting down in that
gallon or so of water that you're
applying to your plants and then at that
point you can be assured that you have
at least those numbers I kind of call
that the shotgun approach
you have at least those set numbers that
you're delivering to the plant so that
the conditions are right enough the
plant will use those nutrients in that
ratio
the big thing is testing your leachate a
lot of the larger plant cultivators out
there will test the water that's
leaching out of their substrate so they
they can actually know hey this is too
high in phosphorus so we can lower our
phosphorus hey we can do this with that
barring that you really just have to
trust the ratios that the manufacturers
provided and then you have to make sure
you're just doing good watering and
fertigation practices like getting your
runoffs making sure that you're applying
evenly throughout your substrate things
like that that's pretty straightforward
let's not forget about organic
cultivators the folks that are adding in
organic inputs some people might be
listening to this and be like balance I
just add it on top and let the plan
uptake as it as it needs to yeah what
are your thoughts on that I mean is the
plan in fact uptaking what it needs when
it needs and leaving behind in the
medium what it doesn't need
technically yes I mean that's that's
what plants do you know but
with Organic production it's kind of uh
it's a slow burn it's like barbecue you
can't really know what you're putting on
the plant every day and what's being
taken up you're putting on basically as
much as you think you need for this for
a set amount of time and then in that
time you're hoping that your plant
doesn't run into a deficiency and by the
time you reapply you're hoping that you
don't have an accumulation of that
particular thing like say nitrogen so
with Organic production you you really
have to know your cultivars that's one
big thing like all these great producers
and tomato producers that are doing it
outdoors and organically they're doing
it with cultivars that they know exactly
how to run and they know exactly what
the nutritional needs are in the
different life stages so if if you know
your cultivars that well then it's
fairly easy to plan
your applications of organic nutrients
if not then you kind of again do like a
shotgun approach in your media where you
add as much as you think you need that
plant's going to need for a set amount
of time and then you reapply after that
time is expired ideally doing Leaf
tissue tests
a lot of um field agriculture they they
live and breathe off of leaf tissue
tests because that allows you to know
exactly what you need to put on and you
don't need to over apply which means you
don't need to overspend on fertilizers
so when it comes to organic production
you can kind of look at it the same way
where if you do a leaf tissue test maybe
once every one or like maybe once or
twice every growth cycle and just kind
of track how your nutrients are being
used in your media as you amend it
during your mix then you can know that
oh I need to add a little bit more
calcium sulfate or hey I need to add a
little bit more nitrogen during this
phase because my plants seem very hungry
so it would have to be it's a very time
intensive process if you don't have Leaf
tissue testing because you're just going
off of symptoms in the plant and just
kind of how you know that plant should
grow but if you you could speed that up
with with Leaf tissue testing and kind
of really dial in an organic program
almost as good as a conventional
agriculture salt program you mentioned
Leaf tissue testing but you don't
mention soil testing there's a reason
why you don't mention soil testing so
with Leaf tissue testing it's a little
bit more of a consistent picture of
what's in the soil because the plant is
taking it up and distributing it as it
sees fit with soil testing it's
It's Tricky especially in an organic
media that you've amended because if you
take a core sample and if you do a soil
test off of that that may not be
indicative of what's in that entire root
Zone also how you irrigate and what the
plants are sitting in whether it's a pot
or a bed is a big difference on how it
can affect nutrients either leaching
through and out or being used up by the
plant so typically we like to use the
liquids that either go onto and off of a
plant and then at that point you kind of
think of the media as more like a like a
buffer a sponge that's holding certain
amounts and with the right amendments
with the right CEC you'd expect it to
hold certain amounts of certain
nutrients so if you just measure what
you're putting on with what you're
putting out even in an organic setting
you can find you you're going to have a
ratio of uptake what's actually going
into the plant what's not coming out on
the leachate over time and then at that
point you can get a clear picture as
well okay that's interesting flipping
back to synthetic nutrients I have a
viewer question here which uh
it's kind of funny it's funny to me at
least which is uh if base nutrients have
a phosphorus and potassium in them our
PK boosters really necessary I know had
a couple people actually say that PK
boosters were just snake oil it's it's
mineral nutrition so it's phosphorus and
potassium so is it necessary well it
really depends on your nutrient program
so in
like for instance I would say that PK
boosters for certain cultivars would be
necessary especially if you're running a
very efficient fertigation program
because in an efficient fertigation
program you're not over applying
phosphorus and potassium definitely not
phosphorus at times where the plant
doesn't need too much phosphorus so you
would want the phosphorus to be right
within the ranges that you would expect
to find in healthy Leaf tissue tests
now certain cultivars may have a certain
point at which they do have a higher
than Baseline need for phosphorus and in
those situations having a PK boost that
you can do for maybe one to two weeks of
that plant's growth cycle when it really
needs that phosphorus boost would
definitely benefit because like I said
before you don't want that phosphorus to
be a bottleneck in the plant's
metabolism especially in those important
stages where there's a lot of secondary
metabolisms happening and we're making
all of our nice secondary metabolites
that we like so
there is definitely a need for PK
boosters I mean to tell you the truth
the most common PK booster that I that
we've used in the AG world is just
straight up monopotassium phosphate you
know it's 0 5234 doesn't get more PK
Boosty than that really there's
different versions like dipotassium
phosphate
um there's a product from ICL called PEC
acid which is basically a crystallized
phosphoric acid it's 0 60 20. but
there's plenty of
mineral nutrition Solutions in the AG
industry for PK boosts because that
requirement exists in plants to have
certain boosts of certain macronutrients
during growth stages where you don't
want to apply those high levels of those
um like phosphorus and potassium
throughout the entire growth cycle
because it's unnecessary
so yes PK boosters do have a place
but they have a place in a well
programmed and a well-planned
fertigation and fertilizer protocol yeah
I've heard from uh several different
people that a lot of these nutrient
companies are putting an excess amount
of phosphorus in there you know more
phosphorus is the plant is going to need
for its entire life are you seeing the
same thing have uh have there been any
companies that have kind of revised
their formula since those findings have
come out I think as you look at the
mineral salt programs that are coming
onto the market and are being revised on
the market you I like um there's a
couple of nutrient brands that I've been
watching you know for many years and
I've slowly seen the numbers of their
macros and micros to kind of evolve and
I think that's definitely where it's
going because a lot of these original
salt recipes are based on like tomato
formulas or cucumber formulas or cut
flower formulas none of them were
specifically made for you know medicinal
plants or you know specialty crops like
this so once the research is done on
what these specialty crops need then the
formulations of the nutrients will
follow now I'm really glad you mentioned
that about the feeding chart because I
remember back in the day when I first
started I was using Fox Farm nutrients
and if you look at their feeding chart
you'll see like the recommended ppms are
just out of control and a lot of people
don't know this but you had just
mentioned it is these formulas are
created for a wide variety of plants not
just medicinal plants
so a lot of folks you know you often
hear that it's recommended to start with
a half dose according to what the
feeding chart says that's why it's
because that nutrient line is probably
formulated for other plants besides
medicinal ones so right I'm glad you
mentioned that one
absolute and and newer cultivars or
older cultivars you know like the plants
are constantly evolving as we're growing
them you know because they're not
growing out in the wild so their needs
are going to evolve as well so it's so
that's why I think things like Leaf
tissue testing leache testing are so
important to really know what the
plant's eating you know unless you see
the plate after they're done eating you
don't really know what it liked or
didn't like you know so that that type
of analytical testing gives us that
window into what the plants really need
and allows us to dial it in that makes
sense organic input so I want to flip
back to that we're kind of going back
and forth back and forth here but it's
it's all good
the folks using organic inputs what
should they know prior to using them one
of the biggest things that I would
recommend is know where your Source
material comes from there's a lot of
kind of smaller organic soil producers
or media companies and you really want
to get companies that have vetted where
they're getting their Forest materials
from where they're getting their peat
from and obviously you want to look to
see if they're certified if they have
Armory certifications or any other sort
of like governing body certification to
show that they're organic
um barring that
it would really have to be like knowing
the consistency of your product as well
um media like I brought up isn't a is a
good example there could be a media
company that makes fantastic organic
media but if their supplier for Forest
material drops out then the media itself
can change and be completely different
so finding consistencies in that type of
an organic world is very challenging
definitely not as challenge or
definitely more challenging than the
mineral world where it's a it's a
chemical that has a certain number of
these molecules in that molecule and
that's it you know with an organic
there's so much involved in the
production and decomposition time and
all these things of the forest materials
and the peat and the Aging of that that
it's very hard for all those pieces to
line up all of the time exactly the way
that you expect and have expected it so
consistency would be the biggest driver
of looking for a source of any sort of
organic input like look at the
historical data see if they do
certificates of analysis like quarterly
weekly they'll just give them to you if
you request them
and yeah and and make sure that you're
following up on it because a lot of the
times people find a good organic input
and then they keep using it without
realizing that you know six months ago
they changed this or that that's why
everything's everything in their growth
has changed because of that change that
the formulation that was in the
formulation but they weren't privy to it
so you really have to stay on top of
your supply chain when you're using
organic inputs and look for products
that have known good consistency known
testing data things like that that's
really good advice I think a lot of
people these days are using the organic
Blends so the organic fertilize it's a
blend of different amendments and
they're typically doing the top dressing
right that's the the main way to do it
is the top dress or you can do the
initial amending of the soil to begin
but when the plant is growing in the
grow pot they're top dressing that
organic fertilizer and then they're
watering that in a lot of folks say
that's the easiest way to do it and you
can't overdo it however I'm hearing
otherwise that you can overdo it so can
you overdo it with Organics absolutely
you can absolutely over apply any
fertilizer to tell you the truth um it's
it's like uh it's like food you can
overeat anything you can even over drink
water and and plants are the same way
you it's harder obviously to overdose
your plants on a certain
um say phosphorus because it takes so
long typically for that to become
available in a root zone so unless you
do some sort of an egregious over
application of something like that then
you're you're typically not going to see
toxicity symptoms or any sort of like
ailments of the plant but certain things
like nitrogen calcium you know those can
be absolutely apparent when you do have
toxicity and the problem with Organic
agriculture too is
remedying those problems say you know
you can absolutely over apply nitrogen
you you put triple the amount of fish
Emulsion you know into the root Zone you
start to get weird growth of like
pathogenic cultures you have this
overabundance of nitrogen going into the
plant the leaves are getting leathery
nitrogen Cycles getting weird within the
rhizosphere as well so you can get those
symptoms but how do you alleviate that
in rockwool with nitrates you just water
through maybe 30 minutes for about four
like 30 minute cycles for about like you
know four or five hours and then you can
be assured that that cube is well
flushed enough that your next
application of fertilizer will kind of
reset the balance in that with an
organic with a soil plot with you know
organic soils it's a lot more difficult
to alleviate those issues just because
of the fact that it's being immobilized
by the root zones ecology like the
things living in there it's being
immobilized by the types of substrate
that's in that so it can't leave that
substrate because it's stuck to the
particles in it and generally you'd have
to use things like maybe potassium
carbonate or activated charcoal or
things like that to kind of deal with
toxicities in your root Zone and kind of
help sequester sequester things but
you're never going to get the fast
bounce back that you would in like a
hydroponic situation so with Organic
inputs you can overuse them you just
have to make sure that you kind of do
the lowest application possible and move
up from there like I said with Organic
inputs and organic agriculture it's
really time intensive you have to know
your cultivars and if you're trying to
if you're trying to blast through them
and try to treat it like Hydroponics
you're going to be going back and forth
from either end so yeah start slow and
moving up and not over applying would be
the best
technique with uh organic agriculture
but yeah you can definitely over reply
that that's no question got it I want to
flip things over to pH pH is something
that is closely monitored by those folks
growing with synthetics a lot of people
that say you have to have that pH in
that certain range in order for the
plant to uptake now on the organic side
of things you hear a majority of people
saying they ignore pH completely what
are your thoughts on that
I think if they are growing organically
with healthy root zones they're
non-caring is well-founded you know the
roots on ecology is there to provide the
ideal conditions for that plant and if
it's set up correctly it will even in
Hydroponics we're starting to come
around most people are starting to come
around to the fact that it's not this
insanely precise range that you have to
be in it's a fairly wide range because
even in an inert setting like rock wool
you still have endogenous cultures like
cultures in the air that will land in
that root Zone and as they live and die
you know they acidify the area they do
cellular respiration and push out CO2 as
well which goes into the substrate water
and acidifies it so there's lots of
Pathways naturally for your media and
root Zone to balance its pH out
absolutely you don't want to water
outside of the range of maybe like six
to seven or like five to like seven and
a half
but within those ranges typically the
root Zone can recover as long as it's
not like a prolonged exposure to like a
a wild outlier or pH
when it comes to Mineral nutrition guys
you know obviously the lat phosphoric
acid or potassium hydroxide with Organic
production you can still do pH
adjustments
um pretty easily you add things like
dolomitic lime to the substrate if you
need a little bit more basicity
um there's certain fertilizers like down
to earth makes a good acid mix that's
acidifying you can even add things like
citric acid which you can buy Omri
listed and at a small rate with whatever
nutrient or top dress formula to add a
little bit of acidity sulfur products
are a great way to add a little bit of
acidity into your soil and kind of
increase that root Zone ecology so yeah
you need to adjust your pH in an inert
situation more and you definitely don't
have to worry about it as much in a soil
setting but it is important but just
know that if you have a healthy root
Zone ecology and your plants are set up
with a good substrate or media then the
pH will balance itself out as long as
you're not wildly out of the range of
typical like rain water or natural water
that we'd find standing on Earth so if
somebody's water sources over 7.5 pH and
they're growing with Organic inputs do
you recommend that they PH down that
water before doing the soil drench or
could they just add in that water that's
above 7.5 pH
that's a that's a tricky question you
know I want to know what else is in the
water you know if it's like carbonates
or if it's sodium carbs that sodium
bicarbonates or if it's just like
standard like typically if if your pH is
that high then that also means that your
um total dissolved solids are high too
so I'd really want to take a look at the
quality of your well water at that point
um if it's just like say calcium and uh
and other kind of beneficial kind of
secondaries that are and it's just a
bunch of bicarbonate bringing it up
as long as you've amended your bed
correctly there should be no problem if
you know like say the water has this
amount of bicarbonate in it and you're
going to apply this much water to that
land then you should maybe know how much
sulfur you want to amend to that bed so
that over the course of that watering
year you know you're going to have
enough of a buffering capacity naturally
built into that soil things like things
like that are considerations you have to
do before and after even the watering
happens to answer something like that I
feel yeah it's hard to go round about
and not answer your question no that's
fine I I uh that topic in particular is
super controversial I mean I had
mentioned to lower the pH in the past in
one of my videos and there was just an
uproar of people growing organic they're
like PH down doesn't exist in nature and
blah blah blah so there's a lot of
organic Growers that actually do have a
water source above 7.5 and they're just
putting in their soil and apparently not
having issues so I figured I'd ask that
you know get your thoughts on that one
yeah it really depends on the soil and
how things how you're watering things
like that absolutely now how about EC or
PPM this is another thing that when
you're growing with synthetic nutrients
people tend to monitor more closely than
growing Organics do you think when
growing Organics you should just be
completely hands off when it comes to
the EC and PPM or do you think that
should be monitored as well you know
it's difficult in like row AG things
like that but if you're doing organic
agriculture in pots or in containers
then absolutely I would monitor the EC
of what you're what you're putting on
and what you're what's coming off of the
plants that's really going to tell you
um basically what's going to the plant
because it's basically a simple math
equation you have this much nitrates and
then you put it on the plant and then at
the end when you're watering you have
this much nitrates so maybe in the
course of a couple of days you you take
the average of those numbers and you say
like oh yeah so it's using this much
nitrate so that it can be just as useful
in a soil world as it is of hydroponic
you can control it the you can control
the inputs a lot more precisely in
Hydroponics
um it's going to be a little bit more of
a longer wave function when it comes to
your Corrections in organic agriculture
but the potential to make those
Corrections are still there so
monitoring your ECS is very important
especially if you're doing like you said
well water with like 7.5 pH because like
I said that probably means you have a
ton of dissolved solids in there as well
and if you have a ton of dissolved
solids you want to make sure that you're
not over applying the salty probably
calcium or maybe even sodium Laden water
onto an organic bed so there's a lot of
different little considerations when it
comes to
um like the EC and what that EC is made
of and that's why we don't that's why I
typically don't recommend people use PPM
as a measurement of nutrient
concentration in their solution because
I mean what scale is it first of all are
you using the 500 or the 700 scale what
size particle like and are you using a
blue lab meter are you using an EC meter
to measure that PPM because all it's
doing is taking the EC data and
multiplying it by number you know so PPM
is very hard to judge the the true
measure of uh like a PPM number would be
to take that liquid go get it analyzed
and then find out exactly what's in it
at what concentrations
so we don't like to use PPM EC is is
just electrical conductivity how much
salt is in this solution how much ionic
bonds got broken into this liquid and
that is I think a better indicator of
plant Health plant Health on the fly or
roots on Health on the Fly and then once
your EC ranges are out of range that's
when you can really like take that water
and get it tested you know ideally you
would do periodic testing anyway but
that EC is going to be a simpler
indicator and if you know what's going
on your plants and your plants are
growing then you can kind of assume that
it's taking up at least a minimum of the
balanced nutrition in order to grow so
you can kind of assume that what your
lead shape is going to come out as is
typically going to be balanced as soon
as you start to see deficiencies or you
start to see issues and uptake you do
that leachate test and if you're still
within like a healthy leachate EC range
of maybe 0.3 or three to seven then you
take that water into for testing and you
go oh this is only 0.5 EC but it's like
literally all phosphorus in there so we
need to really dial back the phosphorus
dial everything else up a little bit and
then do a leachate test on a different
pot a couple days later and then see
where we're at at that point and then
you can kind of see that your number is
balancing out your phosphate leachate
goes down and it balances out with all
your other macronutrients that you
should expect to fall out in healthy
Roots so yeah easy measuring and
monitoring absolutely is is critical in
both regular conventional uh Hydroponics
or in conventional like soil or uh yeah
like container soil grows
it's harder to measure of course in like
row agriculture usually just um you go
at scale and you let a rip for those
guys you you do soil tests beforehand
you make all the necessary calculations
you plan your applications and yeah you
just set it on autopilot you Let It Rip
but in a controlled environment where
you can control your inputs whether it's
in soil and pots or rock wool or any
inert substrate having that EC input
output readout is is extremely helpful
and critical in dialing in a nutrient
program understood for the record I was
born and raised on PPM measurements uh
should uh should probably switch over to
UC
simpler man just it's got two numbers
that's all you need and then decimal
decimal point sometimes yeah that's
funny I want to Circle back to balance I
mean we've mentioned that quite a few
times throughout this episode and we
know that things need to be balanced in
the medium if you have in excess of some
cations it can lock out other cations
for example right what are some of the
most common lockouts that are out there
and how do people resolve these lockouts
and prevent them from happening it's um
it really depends on how you're growing
so if you're in a hydroponic inert media
a lot of these like lockout or imbalance
situations can be really corrected on
the Fly just by flushing the substrate
out rockwool of course is going to be
the easiest or some sort of uh you know
expanded glass but even in Coco coir or
even in Pete you can you can flush it
you can flush your substrates through
and kind of reset and start reapplying
your base formula to kind of reset at
that media
when it comes to like I mentioned
earlier in a soil substrate it's a
little bit harder because you have
different particulates that hold on to
different ions they promote different
cultures growing in the media which can
also hold on to different nutrients so
when it comes to maybe preventing a
lockout or or trying to at least
diagnose a lockout one thing that we
usually recommend is look at your
environmental data first so a lot of the
times we've seen lockouts can happen
from environments being too cold too wet
not enough light things like that if all
of your environmental data is good then
at that point I you and at the same time
you probably want to dial your nutrient
program just back just simply back and
then start doing leachate testing once
you dial your nutrient program back then
you can kind of be assured that you're
not locking anything out and you're that
increased volume of water is maybe
flushing out something that maybe have
may have been accumulating and then at
that point you can kind of
get your Leaf tissue tests or kind of
get a baseline idea of what's in your
substrate as you're applying new
fertilizer solution and and see if that
deficiency comes back a lot of the times
we've seen like deficiencies arise from
fertigation techniques like how the
fertilizers are being applied more so
than the concentration of the
fertilizers themselves especially
nowadays with all of these formulations
kind of getting dialed in more and more
it's not like Growers are putting too
much calcium and it's locking out the
phosphorus it's more about like Growers
are putting too much of everything and
they're watering too many times a day
and so the root zone is either
waterlogged or their watering periods
are too far apart and they have too hard
of a dry back and that can really kind
of upset the uptake kind of balance
within the root Zone as it prunes itself
and has to grow back new new shoots so
the the General Health of the plan is
going to kind of like in my opinion
comes down to knowing the Baseline of
how that cultivar grows and then knowing
that you know you're applying a certain
amount of blank so if you dial that back
then you can't be over applying anything
and then from there like for me I would
do the leaf tissue testing if that's not
available at that point you'd see if
that deficiency persists and if other
deficiencies come out arise you dial
your nutrient program back up and then
you you'd see if it was an environmental
factor or if it was in fact a nutrient
Factor if it's very obvious like one
thing that I've seen very obviously is
magnesium you start to get that
intravenal chlorosis on the leaves
things like that and a lot of the times
guys will increase their magnesium and
it's just doesn't get doesn't improve
and then you find out like they don't
ever have dry back in their root zones
they're using like a a plastic pot
without any drainage so
it a lot of the times we've seen a lot
of these um lockout issues go back to
environmental factors and just growth
environment of the plant
if you do have a nutrient kind of
imbalance in Hydro you usually flush and
reset in soil you have to
amend with
yeah it's difficult in soil you'd have
to add if it's a product that can be
sequestered by activated charcoal you
can do that barring that heavy flushes
with water work too but you know you're
going to stress the plant out a lot
doing that whereas in a inert media
typically you get faster try back so
it's not going to stress the plant out
too much
I hope that answers that question yeah
lots of good information for sure one
thing actually made me think of another
question which is you mentioned
environment and temperature can you talk
to us about how the temperature the
varying of temperature you know whether
the temperature be too high or too low
how that impacts nutrition and nutrient
uptake absolutely like you know this is
a big thing that happened when everyone
switched from HIDs to LEDs they've
realized they had to change their
nutrient programs they had to change
their room parameters because the rooms
are less hot so heat in and of itself is
energy too so not only do you need the
light energy to drive photosynthesis but
of the kinetic energy from the heat of
the room moves the water molecules in
the room and helps those processes out
as well you know it's almost like a
catalyst in all of those processes so
heat definitely plays a factor in the
transpiration rate it triggers stress
responses and and kind of growth
responses in the plant so if your rooms
are too cold or if they're honestly too
cold or too hot you're going to have
interruptions in in the metabolism of
the plant which is going to interrupt
the uptake of the plant and once you get
an interruption in the uptake you're
continually applying so that's when you
start to get the issues of if this plant
is locked out because it's dry for half
of the day and you start to keep
applying more it's not going to use up
all of those nutrients during that day
while the light is hitting it so like
the environmental factories your soil
moisture content and you know the
temperature of the room have a huge key
to have a huge role to play in the
nutrient uptake and transpiration
ability of your plants so yeah like I
said if you're if you're too cold the
plants really don't have enough energy
to move a lot of water through uh also
the water itself has is low energy so it
doesn't really want to move up and
through the plant as well if it's too
hot then you have too much water
transpiring out a lot of the times if
it's too hot your root zones get um
any uneven dry back or too much dry back
and that can stop the uptake of water
which stops the uptake of nutrients
which also at that point starts to get
accumulation in your root Zone and then
your easy starts to spike once your EC
spikes and your EC gets too salty then
the root zone is too salty for uptake
that affects your uptake immensely
that's when you start to see a really
spindly plants with the tiny golf balls
just going down the stem when it comes
to medicinal plants for like in a tomato
plant you get these tiny small fruits
you know so
the EC controls a lot of how your plant
grows and the EC is really a function of
the water content in the soil too so the
water content
itself is kind of
um affected by the environmental
conditions like the temperature and the
irrigation frequency things like that so
yeah your environmental factors like
like I said when it goes back to
deficiencies or nutrient problems we
always Circle first to your environment
to see if your environment is good if
that's not the case then a lot of the
times changes in the environment will
correct or increase the uptake within
the root Zone and then they can get back
onto their kind of Nutri their standard
nutrition program as as they planned it
so what's the ideal temperature range to
keep your environment you know it's
cultivar dependence um especially for
medicinal plants but it's anywhere
within the ranges of like
65 all the way up to 85.
um you know that magic VPD number comes
in when it comes to those types of
outlier temperatures you really want to
monitor your humidity in those
temperatures and again cultivar
dependent certain cultivars do great in
65 certain cultivars don't grow in 65.
certain cultivars
stunt out and they don't grow at 85.
certain cultivares veg out and Bush like
crazy in 85. so I would say it's
definitely cultivar dependent but um the
ranges for like our most common
medicinal plants would be anywhere from
like 65 to about 85. and life cycle
plays a huge part in that absolutely
because because temperature also you're
you're trying to mimic the natural
temperature cycle for an annual plant so
of course in those earlier spring and
summer months the veg months you'd have
higher temperatures and in the flower
senescence months in the Harvest months
you definitely have cooler temperatures
and the the inner metabolisms within the
plant are triggered by those changes in
temperatures as well so it's important
to consider the temperature shift within
a growth cycle of medicinal plants as
well as just the Baseline temperature
that's good to know so there's a
different type of feeding that I want to
touch on you know a lot of people will
mix in their synthetic nutrients into
water then do a soil drench other folks
will do a top dressing of organic inputs
for example and then they'll water them
in however there's another way to go
about feeding which is foliar feeding
talk to us about how foliar feeding
works and what type of folio feeding can
Growers do
folder feeding is basically
trying to
directly apply mineral nutrition to the
parts of the plant that seemingly need
it that can't get translocated from
other parts of the plant or it's not
getting from the root Zone
you know I we definitely have I
definitely have an opinion about foliar
applications of mineral nutrition
especially
um it's kind of like uh
it's not something that I believe
Growers should lean on for their
nutrition program it's definitely a just
a general part of any part of crop
cultivation but it's it's kind of like
um you you'd want to feed a child a
fully balanced nutrition from the get-go
into his mouth you don't want to feed
him only macaroni and cheese and then he
gets scurvy and then you got to take him
to the doctor to get a direct injection
of vitamin C every month and that's kind
of if you if you consider having a
constant foliar feed program that's kind
of the type of nutrition program you're
planning out for your plants you want
that nutrition to come because we're not
growing orchids or you know like plants
that are growing up in tree canopies
we're growing plants with full root
zones and root systems so we want to
deliver their nutrition that way the the
more conventional way the way that is
kind of a pathway laid out by the plant
rather than using Fuller applications a
lot of the times Fuller applications
applications would come when
that Baseline nutrition program seems to
have a deficiency and when you
specifically identify that deficiency
whether it is uh calcium or magnesium or
this or that a zinc for example is
actually common in medicinal plants if
you find those specific deficiencies
then yeah a folio application is an
absolute Powerhouse tool to get that
mineral nutrition directly onto those
areas of the plant where that particular
nutrient can't get translocated up into
from the other tissues of the plant but
barring that
you know Fuller applications especially
on an like an ornamental plant or a cut
flower product like medicinal plants
typically are you want to reduce any
application of any product to the plant
especially after influences have said
after after flowers are there because
you know that's that is the end product
and anything that you add exogenously
can typically degrade or Denude the
quality of that product so you don't
want to apply as you want to reduce
applications as much as possible that's
why beneficial insects or beneficial
mites are so great they allow you to
have good pest control over under over
threshold numbers without any
applications of sprays or anything and
there's no possible possible problem of
France or anything like that so that's
why I think BCAAs are taking over on the
IPM side and when it comes to folder
applications were in my opinion seeing
less products Market themselves as
Fuller products and a lot of products
kind of try to roll all of that value
into their mineral nutrition there is um
there are certain foliar products
especially amino acids that we found
that are not part of a mineral nutrition
program but do actually have added
benefits a lot of the times we see it a
lot in turf or when I was in the AG
world we saw it a lot in Turf like
um there's a certain Amino Proline for
example you spray that on grass and that
helps trigger pressure and all the
blades stand straight up you know so
we're finding that there are other
products that we can apply to the plants
foliarly that would give the benefits of
that we couldn't really get through a
nutrition program in the root Zone and
those are the products that I'd probably
suggest if you wanted to do a full year
program you rolled those into a full
year program with some base IPM products
but also know that full your products
work best with adjuvants so if you don't
have like a spreader sticker like a
organic silicone
adjuvant if you if you don't have like
even like an acid chelator or something
like that say the pH of your foliar
spray is off off or you're not agitating
as like there's a lot of considerations
that you have to lock in for a full year
program to be truly effective
once those things are locked in and
you've truly found a product that works
best as a failure application good on
you go nuts but in my opinion foliar
nutrition is is
um yeah it's a shot in the arm when it
should have been just part of the meal
interesting yeah I think the only time I
ever really do foliar feeding is when I
have magnesium deficiency and I'm in veg
like I don't spray in flour but
magnesium deficiency and veg I use epsom
salt so magnesium sulfate put that into
water spray the plants and that helps
with the magnesium deficiency I do know
some people who will do a foliar feeding
of silica not so much that it goes into
the plant that way but I believe that it
helps with some resistance to Pottery
mildew in particular I don't have too
many details on that one and I know some
folks that will use they'll actually
foliar feed compost tea so for micro
purposes yeah to to get those
lactobacillus cultures in there get
those healthy cultures on there
absolutely that makes sense as long as
you're doing it at a uh kind of a sane
rate that really doesn't affect the
quality of the plant
um silica obviously that's been done for
quite a while
um that's that directly if if it's small
enough can kind of go through into the
plant and be absorbed fully and I was
just going to say with the magnesium
sulfate too you can failure that but you
know you could you could simply top
dress a little bit too and then you'd
probably get the same results in about
three or four days and uh you can even
add a little bit more to your
fertigation program as kind of a last
step Amendment to the batch tank it'll
melt down easily easily enough if it's
magnesium sulfate and it really doesn't
affect your ppms too much so that that's
something that you could do as well so
there like I said there's other ways to
to get those benefits without risking
someone maybe doing a improper
application or over applying something
fully early good points so we are coming
up towards the end of the episode I want
to give you an opportunity to let us
know what else should gardeners know
about Plant Nutrition is there anything
that we didn't cover in this episode
that you think we should cover
you know one thing that I that I've kind
of wanted to scream from the rooftops a
lot is um you know your mineral
nutrition your your nitrates your
phosphorus your potassium that is the
same molecule regardless of bottle salt
brand country of origin all of that so
it really comes down to understanding
what you put on your plants more than
kind of
in my opinion um trusting a product at
this point back in the day there was no
information about medicinal plants no
information about certain specialty
crops that we could go off of and have
kind of historical data to to see if
we're within ranges for certain things
now that that information is being found
out in places like Canada and like even
here in the U.S that type of information
needs to be applied you know like like I
said I come from the AG industry I come
from the AG world and and there's not a
cotton Farmer in the world that would
overspend on a nitrogen molecule you
know they they sometimes they make you
know like less than 100 bucks per acre
on their cotton so it's like it's it's
tough out there in the AG world and I
think
that is also a really good point in
sustainability too we have to make sure
that we're not following the same
mistakes of Ag and from the get-go we're
trying to be as efficient as possible
with our nutrient delivery so that we're
not setting a bad example like it needs
to be done properly with the right
science and that starts with people
understanding just the basic science of
how plants take up mineral nutrition how
what the basic needs are for plants you
know very similar to us they need
three big things and then all the
vitamins so we just need to find the
right balance of those and then find the
right way to deliver that and uh yeah we
shouldn't be too hung up on Brands and
stuff we should just try to find the
best way to mishmash everything to make
things work and try to be the most
efficient as possible I think that's
some really really good advice
so let's wrap things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future uh I should be
you should see me in a couple more um
can of cribs and Deep Roots episodes on
The Growers Network YouTube channel
um definitely helping them out with a
lot of that stuff I'm helping them on
the back end
um with their plant science info you can
check me out directly at canacribs.org
if you click on the Consulting tab um
you'll see a little bio and a little
picture of me uh if anyone has any
questions about cultivation or
cultivation at scale there's a form that
they could fill out and you'd be happy
to answer any questions directly too so
awesome well this has been an insightful
episode I'm super glad that you decided
to sit down and talk with me I learned
so much from this you explain things
very well very very uh beginner friendly
manner in my opinion and hope I can have
you on again in the future because I
think uh we can continue this
conversation or even go towards some
other areas we have a lot of knowledge
of such as IPM sure yeah I'd be happy to
come back on yeah just ask me anytime
Chris sleep if you enjoyed this episode
click that Thumbs Up Button also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single weekend I'm
releasing a new Garden Talk podcast
episode and I would love for you to tune
in to future episodes I'll definitely
have a link to your Instagram or to your
website or something down in the YouTube
description section below so folks can
go down there and visit you pretty
easily thank you all for tuning in and
I'll catch you in the next episode peace
out everyone