welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden hey what's up everybody for those
of you that don't know me my name is
Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned into
the garden Talk podcast this is episode
number 152 in this episode I interview
Chris Swank he has been gardening for 11
years and grows plants exclusively in
Rockwell which is what we get into in
today's episode he talks all about how
he grows his plants in Rockwell
everything from preparing for planting
nutrition pH irrigation strategy
environment controls and more if you
want to see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to aec Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
instant potty mix a soilless grow medium
made from 100% organic cocao fiber it's
buffered and triple washed to maintain
pH stability and reduce salinity it
comes in a 2lb brick which expands to
fill up to a 3 gallon growt click the
link in the description section below so
you can learn more about their instant
potting mix and the discount code Mr Gro
15 works on both Amazon Amon and their
website AC infinity.com stash blend
stash blend is a 215 plant additive that
can used with synthetic bottle nutrients
or in living soil systems simply mix
half teaspoon of stash blend into a
gallon of water then water your plants
with it ingredients include corn steep
liquor seaweed extract humic acid
beneficial bacteria silica and micro
risal fungi check it out at stash
blend.com Link in the description
section below and use the discount code
the stash and we're back and I'm joined
with Chris from Swank genetics how you
doing today I'm good bro how you doing
doing good man thanks for uh coming on
to the podcast today you've been on the
from the stash podcast a couple
different times great great
conversations in those episodes real fun
conversations and we are friends IRL in
real life and so you live locally here Y
and I've been to your gr before and one
thing I noticed is you grow on Rockwell
entirely yeah and we are overdue for an
episode of growing in Rockwell I haven't
had anybody on this podcast growing in
Rockwell yet I've had some people that
started out in Rockwell they did
seedlings in there and then they
transferred over to either like a soil
or cocoa or hydroponic system for
example but y growing in Rockwell
throughout the entire growth cycle
that's a way you can do it successfully
and so I'm excited to have you on here
today and talk all about it yeah bro I
appreciate you having me on bro it's
it's an honor man you linking with you
and the boys has been uh just it's just
so organic how this all happened man
that's the only way I can put it that's
the best way to describe it is just
organic you know so I appreciate you man
big time I completely agree before we
get into Rockwell deeply can you give us
an introduction tell us a little bit
about yourself and how you got into
gardening yeah uh my name's Chris I'm
the owner founder of Swank genetics uh
we're essentially a genetics company uh
uh we focus primarily on breeding
genetics and and eventually as soon as
we get to a certain point we'll be off
offering those genetics in various forms
seeds tissue culture whatever um but
yeah primarily a genetics company I fell
into it by just loving the plant from a
very very young age um I got into it
around 2001 and I didn't see my first
living plant till around 2013 so um yeah
I that was it I mean that was the change
I saw the plants for the first time
growing in full flower and and it just
changed everything I had to learn I had
to figure it out I had to become a part
of it and uh a buddy of mine who showed
me that Garden was willing to take me
under his wing and teach me how to grow
and did that for a while and then we uh
came back left California and uh which
is where his garden was and came back to
Vegas and started my own thing that's
awesome yeah before we started recording
you mentioned you were doing it for
about 11 years have you been in Rockwell
the entire time or have you tried other
grow methods so initially when I learned
they were in Coco um so at the Garden I
was learning out NorCal they they had an
outdoor which was all soil and then they
had an indoor which was all cocoa under
High Press sodium so initially I learned
Cocoa High Press sodiums indoor and then
just straight soil with amendments
outdoor um and then honestly in doing
that I mean I know there may be people
that aren't going to like me saying this
I just I could not wait to never touch
soil again I just it's back breaking bro
especially when you're at scale and
you're really doing it for real on a
farm it's it's no joke and hats off to
every Gardener that that does it because
it's you guys are the real the real
Workforce for real so I just me being
the type of person I am initially was
like all right well how can I create
more efficiencies just naturally in my
life I'm all about finding efficiencies
and soil just was not it for me and
neither was Cocoa neither was most of
the Alternatives until I stumbled on to
specifically Rockwell you mentioned
being at scale and I think that's one
good thing to clarify is you're not just
a small home grower with a couple tents
you are growing at scale and uh yeah
that makes a big difference going from
just growing a handful of plants six or
12 plants up to Growing I don't know
what are you growing 50 100 Plants Plus
plants at a time or what it dep it
depends like when we were on the farm it
was it was uh I mean we had I mean this
is back in like the the prop 215 days so
um we had you know 99 outdoor and then
he had I don't even know you know 15
lights indoor you know so yeah thousands
at that point but it it's all broke down
like he's that the person that taught me
how to grow is kind of where I got the
ideology of you can have a 100 lights or
200 lights and still be small batch and
that's very counterintuitive to what
people think and it's like well no it's
just because you don't have to build a
60 light room or a 100 light room you
can have a 100 lights and have 10 10
light rooms that are all staggered out
in various points of growth you know to
and you can that'll allow you to have
you know variety and multiple harvests
of different genetics so you're not just
sitting there doing the same thing over
and over so so yeah like he's the one
that kind of put me into that ideology
where it's like damn you've got a lot of
lights but really you don't because it's
all in eight and 10 light rooms got it
so why rockwool first of all what is
rockwool we have a lot of folks that are
beginners they might not even know what
it is can you explain what is rock wall
and why growing it what are the benefits
to grow plants in Rockwall yeah so it's
basically uh spun rock so they heat rock
up and uh I don't know that this is the
necessarily the greatest analogy for it
but think of like a cotton candy machine
you know they they basically get the
Rock from my understanding to like a
almost a molten State and they spin it
and it becomes this very fibrous
um yeah it's like a fibrous almost
almost kind of like fiberglass
insulation for your house would be like
the way I could compare like the feel to
it if that makes any sense but a little
denser than that and um and yeah it's
just it's it's it's it's a natural thing
people don't think it's natural
obviously the process of doing it isn't
but it it is essentially just rock
melted down and then spun um into this
very fibrous soft material uh and then
that's something that I found when I got
into it initially like you ask why the
why was again trying to figure out how I
could get away from soil and so I tried
cocoa and it's like all right well this
is basically just a not soil soil and
and it's still heavy and it's still it's
still messy it's still dirty it's still
a process that I just don't want to do
how could I get clean like to me that's
the whole point if if you're going to go
through the hurdle of setting up an
indoor grow then you and it's all about
cleanliness indoor I mean indoor you
have to extra be careful with what you
do so to me how can I avoid having soil
like doing dryb backs with soil and now
we have dry dust essentially so you know
dirt that's going to naturally get into
the HVAC and get into the de system and
get into your fans and your filters
because it's just dry dirt that's what's
going to happen you know and Coco
similar and you know sure there's like
pellets and other things you can do but
you know and I think when you get to
that point it's just preference but with
pellets I find that when I tried that it
didn't make sense for the root mass I
like the fact that the roots will
actually penetrate through the the
growan you know the rock wool and so
yeah that's kind of how I got to it was
you know you you can pot an entire room
we also pot which is something that I
don't feel is necessarily common
practice with people that grow on hydro
but um when we pot you know you can run
through an entire room of pots several
hundred very quickly and it's it's not a
lot of weight it's not hurting it's not
like the whole crew isn't like dreading
the day of transplant like you do when
you do soil or cocoa you know it's it's
a very very easy friendly thing to
utilize in my opinion got it so yeah
there's a handful of benefits there on
the flip side what would you say some of
the downsides of using Rockwell is uh
you have to be on top of your wall
watering if at any point you you lack on
your watering that's it your plants are
dead there's really no buffer um and
also in regards to buffer from a
nutrient standpoint there's no buffer
you know the benefit of soil especially
when you're a beginning grower is that
the plant the soil has you know like the
way I like to tell people that grow in
soil which I'm not a soil King by any
means I I know probably less than 1%
about soil but the little bit I do know
is that you know essentially you're
never feeding the plant you're really
feeding the soil and the soil is feeding
the plant you know so because of that
the soil has its own ecosystem and its
own pH and its own EC so it will act as
a buffer if you the beginner grower mess
something up you know you don't have
that buffer at all zero when it comes to
hydro um if you do one wrong feed and
it's wrong enough your plants are dead
you know you could maybe attempt to
bring them back but if you do something
bad enough they're dead and you know the
same could be said for soil but that bad
enough would have to be much worse than
it would be you know if it was Hydro so
so yeah I think I think the downsides
are that the there's no buffer there for
watering there's no buffer there for
nutrients um you have to really be spot
on on what you do and then how does
growing in Rockwell compare to other
methods of growing such as soil
hydroponic systems cocoa in terms of
yield and quality I mean so the quality
thing is I'm a firm believer that you're
a good grower if you can grow good in
any medium you know and it doesn't mean
anything other than that like there's no
need to deep into it when we talk yields
when we talk you know the end result a
lot of that's PR like it's all it's all
subjective it's all objective it's all
preference it's it's there's so many
variables to that so it's to me if you
can just show me a finished product that
doesn't hurt my throat that has a great
nose to it that tastes good that's
enjoyable all around you know I don't
really care too much about the bag ofo
but bonus if it's there you know it's
it's like that's what I care about and
then after that we can talk about how
you grew it because that's to me a
second secondary you know people get so
wrapped up in how it's like just smoke
it if it's good and you enjoy it then
it's good and you enjoy it like don't
let the fact that they grew inorganic or
organic or in salts or in soil or
whatever don't don't don't let that play
into what you think about it just try
the end result first and then work
backwards from that and figure out what
they did a lot of people assume I grow
soil or organic you know or living soil
or no till or all these famous catchy
phrases that are popping up in the last
five years so it's like when I tell
people nope none of that you know I'm
proud to say that I grow in salts I'm
proud to say that I grow hydroponically
and I'm proud to say that I figured out
a way to grow quality flower without all
the backbreaking work of soil like I'm I
just keep going back to that I'm a lazy
dude
bro yeah I know quite a few people who
say that the yield is better you know
you're going to get a higher yield you
kind of got more control over the the
nutrients pH you got to kind of be
bought on but you can achieve a higher
yield and as far as quality you talked
about flavor and stuff and kind of
comparing and stuff I've got a lot of
your stuff right here and uh you were
nice enough to gift it to me and every
single one of these is very flavorful so
like the papaya syrup is just it's my
favorite it's incredible aw there's a
big debate on Pon growing organically
versus growing with synthetic nutrients
and the flavor profiles and all that
stuff right now it's really just debate
you can definitely still get flavor and
proof right here still get flavor from
growing in synthetic nutrients
particularly in your style with growing
in Rockwell so fig I'd mention that one
I appreciate that yeah man I mean you
know I've done labs and and 100% Labs
show that in my experience a and being
between like say a 600 watt Dita high
pressure sodium vers the fluence LEDs
that I use right I use a 630 watt
fluence versus a 600 watt HPS way back
7even eight years ago when I really
started trying to compare an A and B and
figure out if LEDs were better you know
at that time they were better you know
because the labs would show that okay
cool this genetic oh granted there's
other environmental factors that play
into this but assuming you can get your
environments roughly close each time
right then your lab shouldn't skew too
much but there there'll be differences
but when it goes from say you know
1.7% turine profile on a dry cured plant
When I Grow It In A gavita and then I
grow that same plant under a fluence and
all of a sudden I have 2.4 2.6 2.8%
turine profiles that's not a little
difference that's like a 60 70 80%
difference in tpine content so it's like
that's undeniable and when you do that
for so many labs and so many plants and
you do run that through several
different genetics and you a and be it
against the high pressure sodium versus
the fluence it's like no I mean
historically speaking in my experience
with the labs I've paid to get done
independently yes there are higher
turpine profiles in in LEDs at least our
LEDs but I'm also not a person that's
going to sit here like most people do
and be like well that you know LEDs suck
or hpss suck or no bro it's again it's
preference just because you get a lower
tpine profile if when I smell the plant
I like it you did great bro so people
get so wrapped up in the data and that's
cool when you're trying to develop your
your way of your processes but it's not
cool to wrap up the end consumer and all
that data because then they're driven by
something that they don't fully
understand as opposed to just being
driven by their senses which is the best
thing you could do smell taste touch we
eat food with our eyes before we ever
taste it you know what I mean if
something comes to you and it looks
disgusting like sewage because it's
spinach based you it may be the greatest
dish on Earth but it looks like sewage
and you're probably not going to want to
eat it or you're going to have a
negative condensation to it right from
the junp so there's no difference to me
with plants and people understanding or
wanting to get fed to science to get in
the way of your based instinct which is
just how does it smell how does it taste
you know it's like let's just go back to
that you know and let the Growers worry
about all this nonsense that we're
trying to have a conversation about yeah
I totally what you mean when it comes
down to preference right Different
Strokes for different folks yeah now I
want to jump backwards to get into the
initial planting in Rockwell so how do
you properly prepare and condition
Rockwall before planting seeds or clones
into it yeah so rock wall has a natural
higher pH so it I believe it sits
somewhere around like 75 77 something
like that at least the the grodan which
is the company that whose Rockall I
utilize um I believe it's somewhere in
the mid to high sevens so you actually
uh will essentially just get a big you
know like 100 gallons of water pH of
water down to 5.5 and then we'll drop
all of the blocks that we're using uh
into that water to soak for like a half
hour to an hour and essentially what
that does is it brings that pH level
down to more of a neutral pH of around
six 62 to 65 somewhere in that range
which is safe for for younger plants and
then yeah that's it you know you
essentially just have to excuse me you
just just have to condition the plant or
condition the the the medium to receive
a plant but that's it it's super easy
and then the cool thing with that is you
don't have to saturate afterwards like
with soil a lot of times you'll have to
you know you'll you'll kind of dampen
the soil then you'll plant your seed
then you'll cover it or you plant your
clone or whatever and then you'll go
back and rewater the soil you not even
have to do that because you just did
that soaking process so it kind of also
removes a step just just in an act of
having to do that so yeah pull it out
put it in a tray if it's a clone or put
it into a block if it's a if it's a
clone going into a block or whatever
stage of life is with all of the the
rockel you have to you have to condition
it if you will and get the pH correct
and then from there you just put
whatever you're going to put it into and
then as that is a Seedling or a clone
that's rooting what techniques do you
use to encourage strong root growth in
rock wool I mean for one I definitely
use clonex I'm not a person says you
have to there's been plenty of times
where I've gone and need to take cuts
and didn't realize I was out or
something like that we take the cuts
anyways because the cuts got to be taken
you know so but ideally I use CLX if I
can because it just it has a rooting
hormone and it also kind of just helps
when you make a cut if we're talking in
Cuts Not seeds it it helps when you make
that incision and that cut line to just
sterilize it make sure there's no
infection that's going to get into it
and then also give it some hormones and
something to Kickstart that rooting
process um outside of that nothing you
know it's just you know I go into the
1.5 in AIS which are the Clone cubes
that we use um and yeah I mean the
conditioning of it is is really that
simple and as far as seeds go I'll
usually put I do the the cup Tech where
I'll just pH some water to like 65 uh
some R to 65 and I'll just drop the
seeds into a solo cup let them sit for
usually just one day and they'll crack
sometimes two days but never more than
two days you know it's and then as soon
as they split and I see the little
um tap rout I'll just take them place
them out tap rout down and pop them in
one by one individually into the same
1.5 inch AIS so rather I'm doing clones
or seeds it's always the 1.5 inch AIS so
the clonex that you use are you just
dipping the cutting into that or are you
doing a soak of the rock wall with the
clonic solution no there's some people
that do that um but no I just do
strictly water and then I just have a
little shock glass that I'll pour some
clonex gel into and just dip each clone
in and
yeah super easy and then what are you
using for a nutrient lineup and how do
you go about feedings throughout the
growth cycle yeah so the company we use
is current Solutions so that's another
little uh thing that's slightly
different about us is that most people
have never heard of our nutrient line
and that's because it's made by a
company called current culture and
current culture specializes in dwc which
is deep water culture um so deep water
culture without going into that too much
it's it's a totally different
methodology of growing where your plants
are are essentially constantly suspended
in water similar to aeroponics but
aeroponics utilizes misting at at
certain you know intervals whereas with
with dwc the roots are literally
suspended in water 247 and the way that
they don't root rot is through a process
called hyper oxygenation where they have
oxygen pumps that are essentially
pumping air into the water so much so
that the plants don't The Roots don't
realize that they're suspended in water
so you don't get that root rot you don't
get what would usually happen to
anything if it's sat in water for days
weeks months but um I utilize their
nutrient line in hydro which can be done
but it's definitely not the line's
designed for per se it's more designed
for the dwc um but yeah it's called
current solution it's a two-part there's
a a and a B for veg there's an A and A B
for Bloom uh they also have boosters if
you want uh depending on what we do I do
or don't use those um if we're growing
for flower I'll utilize the boosters to
get some more density if we're growing
for Ros and I do not utilize the
boosters and that's a whole another
conversation we have it another time but
um but yeah so yeah just a simple
two-part man and then as far as uh
regiment start out very very light um
there is a three there is a third part
to that like uh it's current Solutions
version of essentially a cow mag it's
it's called coco cow um but it's
basically just a a cow mag essentially
and so it'll be a cow mag and then the A
and the B uh when they're in clones uh
when I first take Cuts it'll be very
mild it'll be usually 1 mil per gallon
on the cow mag and one mil per gallon on
the v&amp;b until I see Roots form and at
that point I'll up the cow mag to two
Mills and I'll keep the veg at one um
until I'm ready to essentially start
acclimating them and once I acclimate
them then I'll start slowly each week
working up the feed but our feeds change
weekly from the from the day we take the
Clone until the day we harvest the plant
we don't ever have the same feed for two
weeks in a row are you measuring like
the EC or you have a TDS tester to
measure like a PPM and are you going off
of that or you just kind of looking at
the feeding chart and kind of using that
and not touching the EC or PPM Nei I'm
not looking at the PPM not looking at
the EC and um I'm also not going off of
any D anything data related 100% of how
I feed is strictly based on how the
plant responds um I try to demystify
whenever I talk to people man I really
do try to
demystify the growing for people I think
that everybody should grow you know I
really do and know people like why would
you say that it's bad for B it's great
for business I don't I'm not looking I'm
trying to sell seeds I don't you know
like so in my business the more people
that grow the better it is you know I'm
trying to sell tissue cultures I'm
trying to show people that growing for
yourself is good because once you smoke
your own thing you'll never want to
smoke anybody else's again and you may
have had better stuff but there's
something rewarding about doing it
yourself that is unexplainable unless
you do it you know and it's it's I I
encourage it so so yeah okay so yeah I
think that's probably a little shock
factor for some people people seeing
that you're a little bit hands off when
it comes to EC PPM and following a
feeding chart I imagine to begin you you
probably had some struggles right and
then you kind of figured it out over
time repetitive and getting the
experience now you grow healthy plants
every time I assume because every when I
went to your grow space man everything
was healthy like everything thank there
wasn't a deficiency
anywhere I appreciate that bro thank you
um yeah so I guess it's because I I try
like was saying I I demystify it so I
utilize a lot of principles that nature
would utilize even though I'm indoor and
even though I'm using salts as people
like to say I really hate that term um
we could dig into that later but I'm I'm
not a fan of that I'm not a fan of
people uh miseducative people and trying
to say that salts are bad or somehow
unhealthy for people that's that's it's
crazy talk it's absolutely crazy talk
but
um no I I think that taking approaches
to Growing that mimic nature as much as
possible will always result in a better
end product and and so I just yes in the
beginning I screwed up some plants
because I didn't understand exactly what
they wanted in in relation to
specifically the nutrient line I use but
you know then you find a range over time
and you go okay cool like 80% of
anything I grow is going to probably be
fine within this range you know and then
it's like cool we'll have the outliers
and they'll show signs you know if we
get burning all right we got to back it
off a little bit if we get yellowing all
we got to increase it a little bit you
know I'm broadly speaking but it really
is kind of that simple you know and and
so yes I don't focus on EC or PPM
because it's it's again I'm not a fan of
putting that much science to it I'll put
that much science to getting my
environment correct and getting the
humidity dial to where I can have it
within a one or two% of exactly where I
want it all the time same with
temperatures you know but outside of
that no when it comes to the feed in my
opinion the
more within a range the
more inconsistent you are with your
feeds the better the plant will respond
to that and overall the more trione
production you will develop and overall
the higher tpes and flavonoids and
cannaboids you'll get from doing that
and the reason being is that because in
nature the plants produce tricomes as
when they're stressed you know for
various reasons there's so many reasons
the plants stress in nature to create
triome production but all all that to be
said the thing that we enjoy about the
plant is the essential oils that are in
those Tricom heads and those Tricom
heads are formed through various
stresses you know so if you can induce
certain stresses by not letting the
plant get comfortable and complacent by
having the same exact feed every single
day and it knowing that at 10:00 a.m.
when your lights come on they're getting
watered you know maybe instead 4 days a
week you water it exactly when you want
to water but then those other three days
maybe one day you water an hour and a
half late maybe the other day you water
3 hours late maybe the other day you
don't water until you see the plants
just starting to have a full dryback and
want a droop on you then you water and
then the rest of the week you go back to
water in the same time you know and when
you do things like that and when you
don't worry about your ppms being the
same and you don't worry about your EC
being the same and you're okay with your
pH fluctuating maybe 0 2 or3 which a lot
of people think that's a lot it's not it
is more in hydr than it is soil but it's
still not a lot and especially if you
only pick one or two days a week to do
that like those little things are what
create a better product overall because
you're allowing the plant to have the
same types of natural stresses it would
have in nature I was going to ask you
about pH next now you already mentioned
5.5 pH for 30 to 60 Minutes soak to
begin and then that's going to end up
about 6.2 6.5 pH but how about the
remaining parts of the grow like the veg
flower are you aiming for a specific p
of the nutrient solution yes yeah so
when we're in clones I aim for between
62 and 64 when we get into vegging
meaning clones are acclimated and we're
transplanting them and we do three
transplants essentially so we go clone
into the first transplant which is an
aoke Cube and then we go those those 1.5
inch AIS into 4 inch I forgot what they
call them the six inches or the hugos I
forgot what they the name is for the 4
Ines but we go into a 4x4x4 block right
and then from there we go into a three G
gallon pot if it's a mom five gallon pot
but if it's something that's going into
production it's a three gallon pot um so
that's it and so at each stage of that
we change the PH range until we get into
flour and then we maintain a consistent
PH range for majority of flour so we
start out from 62 to 64 and then when we
get into the 4in cubes we go from 6 to
62 and then once we essentially are
ready to transplant into pots we'll keep
it at around that six and then over the
course of three or four weeks in once we
transplant into pots we'll usually
continue to veg for another 3 to four
weeks and then over that 3 or four weeks
we'll wean It Off from 6 6160 to roughly
5'8 and once we hit 5'8 we'll flip to
flower and then we'll start our
flowering and then we'll usually
maintain 5'8 until the very end of
flowering and we'll kick it down to 5'7
and that little tenth is it you'll get a
little bit more C again in our system I
can't speak to everything but in our
system we'll get a little bit more Tri
home production because then you're
getting pretty low in the pH which is
fine in Hydro but you are getting down
there so you'll start seeing that adds a
little bit of stress to the pl so we'll
get that little extra trione production
right at the end to just get that a
little bit of frost so yeah that's
that's it so I would say from broadly
speaking 64 to 57 would be our range
over the course of you know roughly the
14 to 16 weeks that that plant will be
alive from clone till Harvest got it now
have you ever encountered PE pH
fluctuations that has caused problems
with the plant's growth no no I mean if
you go crazy yeah of course but uh
everything's within range so I I find
that if you keep when we're talking when
we're talking pH if you can keep it
within 3.4 you're not going to hurt the
plant that is a big swing but it's it's
it's not going to hurt the plant so
something happens where maybe you didn't
calibrate your pH meter or something
like that and you are an extra a tenth
or two10 off in One Direction or the
other no you're fine it's not going to
do anything you'd have to do you'd have
to skew it pretty bad okay let's get
into water and irrigation strategy next
you kind of touched upon it a little bit
but I like to get a little bit more
detailed you already mentioned using R
water now I live in the same area that
you do the uh water out the to is 485
PPM almost unsafe to drink according to
EPA guidelines anything over 500 BPM is
unsafe yeah just below that but it's
very high in sodium
bicarbonates and my experience trying to
use that water that tap water is just
it's been unsuccessful you get lockouts
that happen and uh really raggedy plants
so I use reverse osmosis I know you use
reverse osmosis what do you do for an
irrigation strategy uh so yeah so we
just have a essentially a uh it's it's
really just a three stage but it's it's
technically a two-stage but we have a
pre-filter system because of how bad the
water is here so uh we go into a
pre-filter two stage that's a sediment
and a carbon filter uh and those two
kind of strip it down pretty good so
that my main R doesn't the membrane and
whatnot doesn't have to get replaced as
often I'm replacing the the pre-filter
every three months and that's that's
allowing me to not have to replace the
main filter usually for about a year
somewhere between 9 to 12 months I'll
I'll out of having to replace the main
filters um outside of that I mean yeah
once we go into once it comes out the RO
you know we store like I usually have
the try to store three days uh I've
found that if we can have three days of
backup usually within three days we can
fix any issues you know that's enough
time where if some a problem falls on a
weekend or something like that you know
and we can't get somebody out for a
Monday or something it's we're fine so I
store three days but and as far as uh
like irrigation we don't utilize
irrigation we hand waterer everything uh
which that's another thing that a lot of
people are kind of shocked about is that
you know we'll have you know 100 plus
lights going and it's all handw water
you know and people are like oh it's
inefficient it's this it's that you
could be better utilizing your time to
work on other aspects of the garden to
make the plants healthier I hear all the
arguments and a lot of that's I mean
quite frankly I I'll keep the swearing
to a minimum this will be the only one I
say it's [__] it's just it's bull
you know it's it's nothing you know you
can run through a 100 lighter you can
have one employee run through water if
their sole job every day was to just
water plants one employee in an six hour
shift could run through 100 plus lights
you know so it's it's not over and and I
believe in doing that because it allows
you to put your eyes on every single
plant every single day there is nothing
that will get missed there's nothing
that will be overlooked there's nothing
that you won't see happening on one
random plant and also it allows not all
plants feed the same even if it's the
same genetic not all plants feed the
same if I have a hundred of 100 clones
of a given mom in a room not all 100 of
those clones are going to feed the exact
same they're all going to uptake
slightly differently so it'll allow you
to see like oh you know what today I can
skip this plant this plant's not
drinking like the other 90 of its
cousins like you know it's just it
doesn't want water today you know so
that's the other thing is it allows you
to kind of feel things out look at the
plants assess and determine if you
really even need to water that plant
that day and in Hydro I think that's
better cuz mats are a big thing in Hydro
Nats Nats I would say more in Hydro than
anything I've ever seen they're very
prominent that's because generally
speaking people that grow in Hydro do
utilize irrigation of some kind and that
irrigation keeps a constant moisture on
the block or the rock wall which allows
perfect environment for knats you know
so I don't do that we also hand water
because it allows us to do dry backs
which is something that people think is
an absolute sin when you grow in hydro
and no bro you can totally do a dryback
it's all about just watching and just
tending to the plants and understanding
what they want and so we do promote dryb
backs we tell people yes you can dry
back in Hydro you know you should drive
back in Hydro yeah I know you're set up
utilize all these different trays and it
would be perfect for a flood and drain
and I assume that that was the case but
then I'm now I remembered that you said
you hand water everything now how do you
determine when to water though um so I
mean a lot of it just has to do with the
plants uptake you know I I don't I don't
stick to like a regiment if that makes
sense
um especially now when we're in veg once
we're in flour the way that we propagate
the rooms we it's we know when to flip
to flow from a size standpoint of the
plant where once we're in flour the
plant will drink every day where if we
didn't water it the following day it
would die but we try to not get to that
point until we're in flour um leading up
to that what when we first transplant
into the 4-in cubes um that initial
transplant day we won't water those
plants again the Clone into Cube or the
Clone into 4inch block that block being
soaked because there's no roots in it
yet because we just put it in there it
takes four or five days for those roots
to spread out into that block a little
bit so we won't water those clones for
four to five days until those blocks
fully dry out you know and then when we
do water it'll be a light watering I'm
not going to sit there and reatur those
blocks all the way fully because there's
still not a massive root mass in there
yet so like even when we do go back and
water it'll be a light water to make it
so that I don't have to water them every
day so that we again we can get the dryb
backs it's always about the dryb backs
because in Hydro knats are your worst
enemy and they are coming all of the
time so you know unless you want to
utilize crazy [__] which I don't I just
you you dryb backs dryb backs are the
best way to try to to to fight those
especially in Hydro yeah definitely
helps with reducing the pests because if
you on the flip side if you keep the
moisture content too high you could have
issues such as like overwatering
symptoms and root Rod right have you
ever come across those things no no
because we do it how we do it I mean uh
you know and I don't mean that at all in
a cocky way whatsoever but just because
we don't have irrigation and again not
to say people that grow with irrigation
are going to screw themselves and and
it's a no no win scenario it's not true
there are people running millions of
lights across this country right now
doing irrigation drip systems that are
completely fine but that being said like
yeah I
um no I've never ran into a root Rod
there's no there's no ability for it to
happen you know in in the way we do it
got it one thing that can show up on the
Rockwell cubes that we actually had a
conversation last time I I was over
there we talked about the algae that's
on there and uh I think there
misconceptions about algae yeah break it
down for us talk to us all about algae
being on Rockwell is it harmful or
harmless what's your experience with
that yeah completely harmless it's uh it
just doesn't look good you know people
want to see the the rockel and it's
pristine so a lot of people will get the
plastic inserts that go over so you know
the sun can't hit it but algae when
we're talking specific Plants algae is
completely harmless it it does nothing
it does ACT annoying because it creates
like a little barrier on the top where
like you'll have to water like an extra
couple of seconds to penetrate through
the algae outside of that it absolutely
does nothing it's it's it's very it's
common anywhere that you have Water and
Light constant Water and Light algae
will form it'll do it in a fish tank
it'll do it in a pool it'll do it
anywhere that's why we use chlorine in
pools that's why we use you know
cleaners and scrubbers and fish tanks
and other fish to specifically eat algae
in nature nature figures out its own way
to handle algae but you know there's we
could do it but now we're adding
different things that don't need to be
mixed into the plants just for the sake
of taking out something that's already
harmless for the plant anyways so yeah
it's just a lot of people look at it
like my God is that no just algae it's
no big deal calm down but yeah it's
nothing it's no big deal at all I think
the only time it would be potentially a
problem is if you see it on soil and
your plant is struggling right then you
could potentially have an overwatering
symptom that happens and that happened
to me before where it's like seeing that
little bit of allergy growth on there
look up at the plant and be like uhoh
looks like it's a little bit overwatered
so that might be an indication if you're
in soil to kind of back off on things
but this is something that is in Jeff
lenell's book I'm not sure if you read
teaming with microbes no probably not
cuz I know you're not a soil guy but
he's very in depth about utilizing
microbes and growing plants and stuff
like that he has a whole chapter a
section on algae and it talks about how
really it breaks down to like silica and
so that's that's a non-essential element
for the plant so it's actually can be
beneficial so yeah I figur I'd bring up
algae because uh I know it's a common
misconception when it comes to growing
in Rockwell yep yeah and it's in
everybody's I mean I've never seen a
garden in Rockwell that doesn't have it
unless they're using those little
plastic inserts that go over the blocks
I've seen in my humidifier before and
again like you mentioned that the
sunlight does it on the water and it
could algae can form and you obviously
have to go in there and clean it and
stuff I had a pool and I had to manage
my pool and you get algae blooms that
come up and what do you do well there
are products that you can buy to get rid
of algae really what what feeds the
algae is phosphorus and particular like
talking about me I just think about me
managing my swimming pool there was a
product called L free which you put in
once a week and then you obviously you
remove the plant material that's you
know the Fallen debris that comes in the
pool remove all that because that's just
feeding the algae so um anyways yeah
it's funny how this all relates yeah
there's correlations everywhere it's and
that's the thing is again going back to
wanting to demystify it there the
correlations between humans and plants
are insane the correlations between how
humans reproduce and plants are insane
you know there's it's endless like it
really is an ecosystem that isn't
different than ours it actually fits
into ours you know it's it's pretty cool
next let's get into environment
conditions what do you typically aim for
for temperature relative humidity do you
supplement CO2 if so what do you aim for
there uh it all changes yes yes and yes
um so early on in life like when we're
talking clones before they're acclimated
we're obviously throwing them into trays
with domes ideally keeping them around
84 85 86 degrees with hopefully as close
to 100% humidity as possible um and then
once they're acclimated ideally I want
my Nursery to be somewhere between you
know 82 to again 84 85 degrees with
roughly 70% humidity um and then once we
get into blocks and we start
transitioning to closer to them being in
pots uh you
know mid 60s to the 70s and you know low
70s in in humidity and you know maybe
creeping down into the high 70s at night
but still maintaining around 80 to 82 uh
in temperatures when the lights are on
uh and then once we get into pots over
the course of vegging I'll get the room
basically down to roughly 78 79 degrees
uh and around the mid to low 60s and
then once we start flowering for the
first 3 to four weeks of flowering I'll
maintain in the low 60s and humidity and
I'll maintain the high 70s uh and then
as flowering progresses once sight's
actually form that's when I'll start
weaning everything off um now the
exception to that is if I'm growing for
rosin uh when I'm growing for rosin I do
not wean off humidity um that's another
conversation but to stick to flour I
will wean off humidity and temps
throughout the course of the rest of the
flower and time of that plant um and so
by the end when I'm you know in flush
per se
I'll probably be somewhere in the range
when the lights are on of around 68 67
69 somewhere in that range temperature-
wise and roughly about 50% humidity um
again for flour uh and then yeah when
the lights are off that'll get down to
probably 58 59 in temperature um and
humidity same roughly around 50% you
know uh and then when it's verzin we'll
dip the temps but not as crazy I'll go
down to maybe like 72 73 when the lights
are on and maybe 66 67 when the lights
are off but I will maintain the humidity
in the mid to high 60s um because you
end up with a more resinous plant um and
when you can maintain above 50% even if
you go 51% if you can just maintain
above
50% uh humidity relative humidity then
naturally you're going to have less off
gassing of tpen and and and things on
the plant and essential oils just kind
of doing their thing so you know temps
yes drop because that slows off gasing
uh but humidity keep it higher you know
when we're talking for resin production
or rosin production and then how about
CO2 you're supplementing there are you
measuring the PPM that's in the
environment yeah now that's something we
will use yeah that's a time where I will
use PPM this
year yeah so do you aim for for
different ppms throughout the different
stages of growth so early on uh just
natural atmosphere is usually enough to
take care of the Clones so you know most
atmospheres around where we're at is
somewhere in a range of 400 to you know
between 350 and say 500 is what the
natural atmosphere is so that's plenty
fine for clones uh once we get into
blocks and they're not in domes anymore
uh I'll start introducing CO2 at roughly
around 550 parts per million um so not
much higher than natural atmosphere um
and they'll stay there until we go into
pots once we go into pots I'll kick it
up about 650 and then every week that
I'm in vge in pots which is usually four
four weeks for most strains I'll kick it
up a 100 so week one a veg I'll be at
say 650 750 850 and at 950 like usually
at the end of that week or sometimes at
the start of that week depending on the
size of the plants that's when I'll flip
to flower um and then from flower I
found like we've pushed it as high as is
you know 1900 2000 at certain points of
us just trying to see what would stress
the plants out and they were fine like
you I found that you really have to kick
it pretty high like you need to get
really high almost where it's it's it's
dangerous for humans you know you need
to get around like four 5,000 PPM to
really hurt the plant and and I mean
it'll you can may be affect it less than
that but there's no need to do it I
didn't see a benefit in yield I didn't
see a benefit in higher Tarpin or
flavonoids or canono production when we
would get it tested so um honestly when
we're in flower now I keep it around
1,200 and that's it I don't up it I
don't down it I don't change it once I'm
in flush I'll usually cut off the CO2
entirely um which again that's just an
added stress to the plant it's it's
little things like that where that last
week of flush is just no CO2 whatsoever
that room's going to deplete everything
when I walk in the parts per will be
around 80 or 100 which is basically
suffocating the plant at that point and
that's intentional you know because
again it's an added stress right at the
very into life you know just to it's no
different than people doing that whole
three days of dark thing which I'm I
don't necessarily agree with just
because it's not really whatever it's
neither here nor there it's just
creating stress it's just same same
concept I just do it through kind of
suffocating them a little bit you know
as opposed to just freaking them out for
three days like you know I just kind of
naturally let them deplete any CO2
around them got it now you mentioned
flush that's probably uh spark some
people's interest when we you talk about
flushing yeah you do flush at the end of
the grow cycle first of all what is your
definition of flush because there are a
couple different definitions some people
think that flushing is running a large
amount of water through the medium other
people consider flushing just stopping
nutrients at a certain point what's your
definition of flushing and how do you go
about flushing uh so my definition of
flushing is depleting the plant of any
and all nutrients to the point where all
that's left that it's uptaking is water
essentially um so it's the being
depleted of of any and everything
because when you can deplete it like
that that's going to make a much
smoother smoke it's going to make a much
better cure it's going to just make a
much better end result of the plant you
know that that quote unquote white ash
that everybody you know chases which
honestly is somewhat a myth that you
know I don't really care to debunk but
the white ash thing is kind of bull too
but um you know for the people that want
to chase that cool just flush your plant
a lot and you'll get a white ash you
know it's it's it's not guaranteed you
also got to not be an idiot and grow and
care about your plants throughout the
whole point but if you cared about
everything up to that point and then you
flush on top of that to truly deplete
the plant of any of its nutrients that
it's going to have in the water leaves
in the sugar leaves in the stock in the
medium to where it's literally just
water in the inside of that plant yeah
you're going to get an I mean it's just
common sense like if you had dirty water
and you ran it through a charcoal filter
and now of a sudden you have Crystal
Clear clean water which one would you
prefer to drink you know so for that
same log which one would you prefer to
smoke you know that's why I've always
you know to be honest with you I've
always had a beef with people that don't
flush like a lot of soil Growers
especially like the no till people and
the living soil people they have this
ideology you don't have to flush like
nature doesn't flush and it's like no
guys nature tills and nature flushes
nature does flush that's what a monsoon
season is and nature does till that's
what animals are that's what storms are
that's what wind is like you know that's
what that's what a lot of things are
like 100% soil gets tilled in nature you
know and 100% there's insects there's
worms there's things that are in the
soil that are moving it around and
tilling it you know and that's that's
underneath on the surface 100% surface
layers of soil are getting removed every
year through Monsoon seasons and through
just natural you know storms nature
mother nature doing what Mother Nature
does so yeah I'm a firm believer that
there's no scenario whatsoever where you
should not flush your plants I don't
care what you grow in so to get to your
goal of completely depleting the
nutrition are you running a large amount
of water through it or are you just
cutting off nutrients and doing water
only uh water only I'm cutting off
nutrients doing water only uh initially
like for the first couple of days of
flush I will like say for conversation
sake I water one gallon per plant um
I'll Water three or four or five gallons
I'll just sit there and soak the medium
to try to just flush the medium itself
out because it's it's a little more
difficult with soil because soil wants
to retain right but with Hydro it
doesn't want to retain so if you just
literally run water through the medium
long enough you will rinse out all of
what's whatever little deposits are
still left in it so the first couple of
days maybe few days I will just fully
just oversaturate with water but still
just once a day and still when of the
lights first come on so that they have
the next 23 hours to to to dry that out
and get back to a dry period um I'm
definitely not trying to sit there and
just keep the medium soaked for a week
straight no but yeah the first couple of
days I will weigh overw waterer the pots
to literally just get them to the point
where they're just flushing and then
after that I'll just continue to water
for another until I see yellowing
happening you know once and not all
genetics will do it there are some
genetics where I flushed them for weeks
and they just would not like after weeks
they would finally start to give me a
little something it's like dude I know
through Labs that I don't need to flush
this long like Labs have shown me that
past five days you're technically
passing any lab there will be nothing
that's showing up on the parts per
million or parts per billion in their
given you know fields of where the the
ranges are for safety or not so it's
like after 5 days at least with our
nutrients the way we do it we're safe so
but I've gone two weeks just to see and
there are a few genetics that won't fade
but I I would say nine out of 10
genetics will show you a fade meaning
that you'll start to see the plant from
the tips like yellow out and you'll see
the Green in the plant the chlorophyll
start to deplete out of the plant and
and it'll just start to have this
beautiful fade some are more beautiful
some are kind of ugly but you'll just
have a fade happen and that's when you
know like yeah the plant's now basically
starting to eat itself because there's
nothing left there's no nutrients
anywhere for it to absorb and then you
could safely pull it understood yeah
flushing is a super hot topic a lot of
people like to talk about flushing and
some people flush some people don't
flush I'd love to know in the comment
section below for those folks that are
tuning into this on YouTube in
particular comment below and let us know
if you flush if so how do you go about
it if you don't flush why don't you
flush let us know let's spark some uh
debate friendly debate in the comment
section here I got a few more questions
for you before I let you go I want to
know about common mistakes that are made
when growing in Rockwell and how they
can be avoided break it down for us for
one underwatering um again and
overwatering people there's people that
won't understand that Hydro does not
retain not Hydro that rock wool does not
retain water like that you know and
they'll maybe go into it with an IDE
maybe you're somebody like all right
I'll paint two scenarios you're already
a grower
that you may want to switch to Hydra I
specifically Rock wo if you come from
soil or cocoa where water will retain
for a little bit then naturally you're
going to assume that water will retain
in the hydro or specifically rock wall
and it's not going to you will have to
water every day so underwatering for
sure is is a killer right away because
there's no buffer if you if you forget
or skip a pot good luck that next day
that plant's dead like especially the
later in life they are maybe if they're
clones possibly if they're blocks you
can go back and try to save a plant but
no once they're in pots if you miss a
date they're dead so yeah underwatering
is big and overwatering because most
people that grow in Hydro traditionally
speaking in my experience of what I've
seen around Gardens nobody is handw
watering Hydro they're all hooking up
drift systems of some sort you know or
drain to waste or or something you know
so because of that overwatering too you
know it's a super bad thing with hydro
and people do it because the first thing
people think to do when they set up a
hydro system is how can I set up
irrigation and if if you could rewire
your mind and not think irrigation just
because it's hydro and instead think
well no let me still try to apply
classic like growing principles I.E
potting that's another thing that a lot
of people don't do in Hydro I pot so
that I can develop a root mass you know
so it's like little things like that
where if you just kind of don't think
hydro and just think growing the same
way that if you've grown before you will
continue to grow don't change it you
know and if you're new to it then also
don't run to a drip system because you
should learn your plants and the best
way to learn your plants is to see them
every day and the best way to see them
every day is to have no choice but to
walk up to that pot and water it so it's
like you know there's just so many Pros
to it and um you know other other cons
would be understanding that you have no
buffer with ph that's that's a big big
thing you know in the beginning if you
want to monitor your ppms and your EC do
it I'm not somebody that says don't do
do it shame on you there's a reason
those numbers exist there's a reason
that they're correlated to certain
things you know and if you want to take
a more scientific approach as you learn
to grow that's okay because growing in
Hydro generally speaking is a much more
scientific methodology of growing than
soil so you're already doing that if
you're choosing to take the steps to
grow in Hydro specifically rock wall so
understanding that pH is is not your
friend if you mess it up it's there is
no buffer same with your your your
overall EC um yeah basically anything
again if you're coming from a world
where you are an experienced grower
going trying to transition into
something that maybe is a little easier
on your back or something like that yeah
just just all the buffers that you have
in what you do currently they're not
going to apply in Hydro specifically in
Rockwell at all get rid of them realize
that you got to be on your um and then
outside of that if you're new to it alog
together I honestly tell people to stray
away from it I don't necessarily think
beginner Growers should do maybe they
can do Hydro but they shouldn't
necessarily grow how I grow because it
is very very dependent on you
understanding how to read your plants
and knowing when you're messing
something up or just more importantly
even down to the fundamentals of
understanding what you're doing to the
plant what what what does the pH mean
what is too acidic or too alkaline even
mean in in relation to the plant you
know and so yeah there's a lot more
in-depth understanding that you you have
to have to successfully do this unless
you were to like follow my recipe it's
like yeah cool if I just handed you my
recipe told you to buy my lights my
medium my everything and just do this
you're going to be fine but if you're
just starting out and you hear this this
this podcast and you're like oh I kind
of want to try that then yeah just
respect the fact that there is no buffer
you will have to have a natural better
understanding and a much sharper eye and
a much much greater attention to detail
of the plant so that you can see those
little things that are onsets to you
Ming something up lots of tips there man
this has been very insightful for me I
mean I am a soil grower as much as you
hate soil I got to admit I'm a SL grower
but hearing about the differences it's
very interesting to me I have used
Rockwall cubes just to start seeds
clones and so on and so forth but I've
never done a whole grow with Rockwall
I've seen your grows and they're
beautiful but I've never done it myself
so it's really cool to sit down with you
today and hear about how you do it let's
wrap things up here can you tell the
listeners how they can find you and what
you have upcoming in the future well
firstly bro let me just say thank you
man I I as somebody that's respected by
a lot of people in the community the
fact that you appreciate what I'm doing
and that that you look at my Gardens and
you you don't have knocks on them I
appreciate it bro so thank you for
having me on here and just thank you for
for just considering me an equal bro I
respect what you do for real and as far
as getting in touch with me and whatnot
we don't have I'm saying I'm now
starting to say this on every podcast
because I've been finding out that
people are like creating telegrams and
saying they're me and doing a bunch of
really [__] up and taking money from
people and and whatnot and it's just we
have no telegrams and and I'm not just
saying this is not a ploy I'm serious we
have no telegrams we have no Snapchats
we have no nothing there is no way you
can contact me unless you go to my Swank
genetics Instagram or Swank tools
Instagram or the Swank collection
Instagram and if you even try to ask me
for product I'm just going to block you
and there's so many people that can
attest to that for the last six years
that have been trying to get in touch
with me that I don't respond so yeah if
you want Garden talk if you want to just
you know chop it up about plants if I
can help you in any way like that's what
I want to do there's not enough of that
and there's way too much gatekeeping in
this community and way too much people
that I have a problem with because all
they want to do is act like their Tech
is something special and it's not this
is a plant let's all grow it so hit me
up for reasons like that don't hit me up
because you think I'm going try
don't hit me up CU you think you're
going to get plugged hit me up because
you want to learn you want to talk
plants I'm all about that awesome I'll
definitely have a link to your Instagram
down in the YouTube description section
below and if you're on one of the
podcast platforms just search for them
you'll find them yeah I see you've been
Making Waves amongst uh several podcasts
I know you're on the fromont the stash
like I mentioned I'll link that episode
down in the well two episodes actually
I'll link it down in the YouTube
description section below so people can
go to those episodes next but you're
also on Goblin's Channel I saw that I
caught that made an appearance on that
one definitely want to give a shout out
to our patreon folks as well those folks
that are supporting this podcast or
patreon 100% of the money that gets
donated through patreon goes right back
into the podcast helps keep the lights
on in the studio so thank you so much
I'm putting you names on the screen
right now for those folks that are on
the producer tier special thanks to you
Chris once again thanks so much and uh
yeah I'll let you go hope you enjoy the
rest of your day thank you bro I
appreciate you man peace out everyone
catch you in the next episode