coming up on garden talk you know you
really have to be ruthless
and deciding you know what's going to
make it what's going to move forward and
i'd rather cut the plant down and not
deal with bugs in my greenhouse if you
have high nitrate levels in your plant
material you're very susceptible to pest
pressure do not change labs because all
their machines are different all of
their calibration is different trying to
compare two results from two different
labs you're gonna have a very bad time
employ some of the science and you'll
really be able to see and and have you
know recordable data next to what you're
seeing tissue testing sap testing soil
testing the whole reason i'm doing all
of that is so i don't have to fight
pests at the end zap testing has really
opened up a new level of cultivation for
me it's like the cheat codes for growers
for sure
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr gruit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 42. in this
episode i interview tyler platt from
grassroots fabric pots he has been
gardening for 10 years and he grows a
variety of plants such as aloe vera chia
apples various vegetables and medicinal
plants in this episode tyler talks about
various testing processes such as sap
testing soil testing and tissue testing
he also talks about the outdoor in
greenhouse operation that he's worked in
thanks to all of you who support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's podcast who helped make that
goal possible
big shout out to spider farmer for
sponsoring this podcast spider farmer is
well known to produce high quality led
grow lights at a price lower than nearly
all other companies they have board
style led grow lights as well as bar
style led grow lights i've used their sf
1000 sf 2000 and sf 4000 led grill
lights in the past and i got some
excellent results with them they also
have grow tents in-line fans and carbon
filters i will leave a link to spider
farmer down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
grow at 5 during checkout for a discount
on their products ac infiniti is a
sponsor of the podcast coupon code mr
growit will get you a discount on their
products
i've been using their cloudline t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now and
absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high and low
humidity this greatly helps control my
indoor garden environment so the
temperature and humidity stays in the
ideal ranges i will leave a link to ac
infinity down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit for discount on their
products
thanks to dutch pro for sponsoring this
podcast dutch pro products are now
available in several countries across
the world for those of you that don't
know dutch pro is a plant fertilizer
company that has base nutrients
additives and ph regulators they have
different formulas of base nutrients for
if you're in soil or if you're in hydro
or cocoa they also formulate their base
nutrients for if you're using hard water
or if using ro or soft water i will
leave a link to dutch pros amazon store
down in the description section below
and you can use coupon code mr grow 10dp
for a discount on their products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
tyler platt from grassroots fabric pots
how you doing today
doing great thank you so much for having
me on here i
really love chatting with you we'll
never get a chance to this is gonna be
fun
yeah so we
known each other from mj biz con i think
that's what we met back in i want to say
2017 i believe is when we first met so
it's a long time ago and then we saw
each other a couple months ago a month
ago at mjbizcon
and figured we'd do a podcast episode
it's about time you have extensive
amount of knowledge in so many different
areas today we're going to be talking
about tissue testing sap testing
soil testing and then if we have time we
might talk a little bit about your
outdoor greenhouse operation uh that
you've been working in so
super excited for this one but before we
get deep into the whole testing side of
things the various ways to test can you
give us a little introduction tell us
about yourself and how you got into
gardening
i'm 32 years old i've been cultivating
to northern california for a little over
10 years um the beginning five years
definitely wasn't as successful as like
the most current five years um but uh
been working for grassroots for the last
six years and um honestly i've had a lot
of customers just pouring into me
what works great for them and the just
the
success they have in using our products
or using other products similar to ours
so i've been taking all those cool tips
and just putting them to practical use
my own personal garden and trying to
get down to the possible best quality i
can get to and you know one day i'd love
to enter into some competitions later on
down the road and come back on and
really show what i can do awesome so
what's your overall growth style would
you say i mean you indoor outdoor do you
grow in soil cocoa are you synthetic
organic what's your grow style
i mean i've tried them pretty much all
super deep water culture um but i am
predominantly i'm very very comfortable
um outdoors um preferably uh in a
greenhouse that doesn't have its cover
on it um and we put our cover on a
little bit later in the season
uh it's a really benefit towards the
flowering um but we're obviously
uh in the foothills so we have a low
amount of electricity some of it's on
solar power so you know i can't keep my
greenhouse cover on all year and pay for
all of those fans or even be able to
have power to move all those fans so we
don't have a cover on our greenhouse
most of the season so it's kind of like
outdoor and then when we get down to you
know that kind of season where we gotta
uh keep things going and get to get the
flower and really pushing forward we'll
put the cover on uh it's a poly weave
cover that's 12 millimeters so it's not
just some basic plastic you guys are
throwing on you know little things so
outdoor organic living soil i've been in
the same soil for four years now
and uh i've just constantly been seeing
improvements because i'm not counting on
bro science i'm using actual science to
amend my bets gotcha gotcha and that
kind of wraps right into what we're
going to talk about first which is soil
testing so i assume you've done soil
testing on the bed that you've been
using for four plus years can you talk
to us you know
what is soil testing and why do it you
know soil testing
is really something you should use to
take the weight off of your shoulders to
know what you put together is going to
go forward in the right direction
growing you know many maybe medical
plants that we're growing or whatever we
could be growing but there's so much
science and data that's been collected
over the last 50 75 years on what our
soil map should be
let the chemical make the composition
mpk your mirror levels uh we've got so
much data that we can really count on to
make sure that we're starting out the
right foot forward so you know why
wouldn't you use those tools just to
make sure things are going to be
successful
i have customers doing this in a 2x4
raised bed a couple fabric pots
just because they really want to see
that super high quality jungle boys
product without having to
go through all of the effort of you know
maybe some crazy fertigation or rock
wool you know people know we can do it
with living soil already so it's like
let's let's get rid of all the bs and
get down to really the meat and potatoes
of the situation because when you do a
soil test right you're getting i think
most people use logan labs i know
there's a ton of different places you
can get soil tests but i feel like the
most popular one is logan labs they give
you a breakdown right there's several
different tests that can be done and
they give you kind of a breakdown can
you explain kind of that process and
what it consists of that you see on that
breakdown
yeah and there's a lot of different soil
tests you could do you could do a very
simple soil test for just a couple
dollars for a local lab the main thing
is and the reason why people use logan
labs is because they took in the most
amount of samples in america and they
have the best rapport
and main thing is even if you find
somebody local which you might want to
do
just because of the cost of things stick
with that lab do not change labs because
all their machines are different all of
their calibration is different trying to
compare two results from two different
labs you're gonna have a very bad time
so uh pick a lab stick with it uh many
people are using logan labs because it's
just so easy to translate in common ways
but i still personally take my soil test
for that on over to
the
soil doctor
he charged you forty five dollars to
give you a big you know four page write
up on that and take all the guesswork
out of you and tell you exactly what to
amend per mineral so you can't go wrong
in that situation um and you should be
doing that soil testing a lot in the
beginning and then taper off later down
the road as we're seeing patterns i know
a lot of commercial facilities use it
right i mean it's it's so justifiable
when you're going to have such an
increase you know what i mean you
mentioned 45 dollars for the consulting
i think it's another 50 dollars for the
actual test it's a hundred bucks i know
sometimes they'll do it before they
plant and there's companies also will
spend the money and do it before they
flip the flower to make sure that
they're optimized going into the flower
stage and that's more of a commercial
facility so it's very useful there what
about home growers would you recommend
they get soil tests too or what oh
definitely um you know the
soil testing side of things takes a lot
less i mean you only need two cuts of
soil so if you're growing in any more
than two cups of soil you know you're
definitely a candidate for it it's just
can you justify spending that much money
in such a small situation you know for
me i want to reuse my soil forever my
soil is something like some of my
consider like some of my customers
consider their soil to be something that
i could pass on to the next generation
the next generation of feet on this farm
so then managing it moving forward is
very important to them i know in a tent
that's not that big of a deal you can
just wipe it clean and start over
but the main thing is return on your
investment
you know let's let's do this once let's
do it right and let's prove to everybody
else going along with viewing me to do
this that is successful and i know what
i'm doing um so a small grower small
tent grower um
you know five or seven gallon pots
situation kind of changes too much to do
this but if you're going towards living
soil or going towards just reusing your
soil more than once or twice definitely
do it
now what about the folks that are
running synthetics you know we say it is
they can justify the cost of the test
and the consulting but they're a
synthetic grower they go use synthetic
or salt based nutrients would you
recommend them also getting soil tests
we would recommend a little bit of a
different test
the test that we would recommend is
called a drip
drain test so we're going to send in a
little sample the water that we're
fertigating into the plant and we're
going to send a little sample of water
that's off you know draining off the
runoff so we're going to compare those
two in the laboratory and see what's
holding into the media by obviously
what's collecting on the bottom of it
and we can adjust our nutrients levels
with that drip drain test to know where
things are at and where we should move
forward okay gotcha and then i talked
about the frequency like i've heard of
commercial facilities getting testing
before they plant the crop also
flowering stage what is your
recommendation for how often
i've heard some people say only once a
cycle you know once before you plant
would you recommend
once before you plant would you
recommend
you know more than once throughout the
life cycle or what if this was me
helping somebody to set up a new
facility a new grow a new situation i
would start testing as much as you can
afford to so you know once that soil is
mixed it's in the bed you're getting
ready to plant or obviously before
you're getting ready to plant as long as
that soil is in the bed and you've done
everything you're going to do to it i'd
say that's a perfect time to pull a
sample because even if you do plant you
can still make adjustments by just doing
a basic fertigation that's got minerals
or the nutrients that you need to how do
you actually take a sample for those
that don't know how to do the whole
sampling process
um definitely with rubber gloves on
because we don't want any oils from our
fingers to you know affect that test or
anything like that
if you can afford to you should go to
amazon
and order a course sampling tool so
there's a cool t-shaped device you can
insert into the soil turn it pull up and
then it's going to collect that sample
so you can dump it into a bag so you're
not touching it with anything you can
guarantee it's going to be as best as
possible
logan labs requires two cups of soil
um i personally will do a saturated
paste test where i'm sending them my
soil and um eight ounces of my water
they're gonna combine the two together
and create a paste so they're best
trying to recreate my situation at home
and then they read the available
nutrients that's available to my soil
allowing me to know what to amend and
most most of the time i'm amending what
the plant has removed from the soil
gotcha okay and then what's the
turnaround time to kind of get results
back from them um i'm in california so i
will ship out my sample overnight and
pay a good amount of money for that um
you want to get your samples there by
monday or tuesday and then you're going
to get a email by about friday
requesting you to pay that invoice and
then you get your uh results back okay
so it's not too long of a process there
it looks like it sounds like they get
through them pretty quickly yeah they
get through pretty quickly and then the
next step would be forwarding that
information over to whoever's going to
translate out your soil tests
you can you know invest a lot of time
and effort into trying to figure out
where those levels would be
i recommend at least getting uh with a
soil doctor once to have them explain
what these levels should be
and so then gives you something to work
towards you know in the future
absolutely and if anybody wants to learn
more about soil testing i actually did a
whole podcast episode with the soil
doctor so i recommend you guys go check
that out if you want to learn more about
soil testing
because we are going to move on to sap
testing want to talk to us about what
you know about sap testing yeah you know
stop testing has really opened up a new
level of cultivation for me um
when you talk to jenny garli at new age
laboratories about stop testing and she
commonly tells how a lot of our
customers were referred to sap testing
as getting the cheap codes on these
plants uh for really trying to get the
best genetic
expression possible
we really want to have the best nutrient
load possible
we're asking
these plants whether it's a fruit tree
or whether it's a vegetable or anything
to run a race for us and to be producing
the best possible product at the end of
that race because we want something
that's going to be you know highly
highly minerally charged to really
benefit our bodies um so
you know using sap testing uh we compare
the top leaves at the top of the plant
and we compare the bottom leaves at the
bottom of the plant at the bottom you're
always going to see the deficiencies
you're going to see those yellow leaves
first you can see that discoloration you
see that weird stuff
also plants if they have an over of too
much nutrients of one kind they're going
to get rid of it in those lower leaves
so we're going to collect
about 90 grams of samples from the lower
leaf of the plant
we want leaves that are fully developed
but still have obviously you know a nice
green color in them
and then with the top of the plant we're
going to collect from almost the top of
the plant but a little bit lower where
we have full growth of the leaves you
know we don't want a brand new leaf
that's still let's go go and push it out
we want something that's gotten out to
its full full
stride at least we're going to take
those leaves the laboratory is going to
extract the sap out of those leafs so
they're going to squeeze it out extract
it out and they're going to compare it
to the bottom to the top and see
obviously the newest growth at the top
is going to have all the nutrients in it
and like we discussed a few moments ago
the bottom is going to have all the
deficiencies so they're comparing the
bottom leaves to the top leaves that
gives us a chance to see what's not
making it to the top of the plant
we can do the soil test and we can get
this soil absolutely dialed in and
perfect but the sap test allows us to
quantify what's processing through the
plant to create that end product
so
it's very important to do that you know
as soon as you have enough leaf material
to send in that 90 gram sample a 90 gram
sample is about a full one one gallon
ziplock bag i just fill up a whole one
down one gallon ziploc bag measure it
out and we're well over 90 grams every
time and that gives them plenty of
material to really uh go at that
um if you don't have enough leaf
material i think you would very find a a
tissue sample testing very simple and
very easy because you can take a small
sample of the plant whether it be the
petiole or the stock and send that in
and that allows them to do a different
um
where they ash it they burn it and then
they measure those those levels to see
what's in the plant unless it's what
it's going to do compared to a sap test
we're squeezing out the juice
and measuring that kind of like a blood
test that the doctor would do giving you
a real-time way of doing so uh so with
the soil doctor i know he counts on the
tissues testing he says that's the way
to go he counts on that he loves that
that's just been around for a lot longer
the testing is definitely a little bit
newer to the game and can give you a
little bit of a more real-time situation
with what's going on
um
first time i conducted sap testing i
found out if i feed any more nitrogen
i'm going to start creating a pest
problem if i don't feed my minerals that
i'm lacking in i'm going to end up
having some pm issues
so
it's very commonly known
in all agricultural all plants if you
have a deficiency in copper you're most
likely going to end up with mold or
mildew
so i saw those copper levels were almost
non-existent they measure them in parts
per billion so i said to myself
immediately okay i need to start doing
some copper
foliar sprays
now the only way to obtain a lot of
these minerals is to use a sulfate which
is a non-organic product
so that's a big shocker for some people
i don't want to use something that's
non-organic in my organic garden well
you have to understand that as far as
everything goes in the state of
california everything goes in the united
states if we're taking a test a sample
we're sending it into a laboratory that
laboratory is determining that we're low
on these levels we're allowed to use a
non-organic substance to
to get those levels where it needs to be
and it still remains organic because we
have not gone over those levels now the
second we add way too much we go over
those levels it's not considered organic
farming and you're synthetically feeding
the system or obviously and you're going
to have problems because you've given it
too much
so with that stop testing it really let
me lead forward with some corrective
foliar sprays and some improvements in
growth and
that year i was blown away you know i
planted july 1st in my greenhouse and by
i think june
or excuse me about august 14th or 15th
the time when everything flips over to
flower in california um i have
tremendous growth i had sometimes eight
foot growth in some of these plants uh
which is just absolutely insane but you
know i'm using that stop testing to be
feeding it supplementally like spoon
feeding it everything it needs and i
know what it needs because i collected
those samples and i'm not using bro
science um
so it's been fun it really has been it's
been quite a journey it's like the cheat
codes for growers for sure
so how often would you do a sap test
um you know just like a soil test you
want to do it you know frequently you
know for me the first year i did it i i
pulled my samples i saw these low levels
i did some corrective folder spray for a
week or two um i had to wait three days
after foliar spray before i can collect
my next sample so then i got to the
point where a friday afternoon i'd come
to my farm do my corrected foliar spray
i'd be there monday morning at 8 00 a.m
collect my samples before 8 a.m because
it's really important to collect those
samples as early as possible in the
morning
then we're gonna you know immediately
overnight ship those out uh we're gonna
cold pack them so they don't you know
get a chance to volatilize or anything
crazy happening and that's gonna be nice
and cold uh get that out there and it's
gonna give you um you know a great
response of what's going on so when i
first started doing this i did it a lot
because i wanted to see the changes and
see what's going on
this last year i felt it a little bit
more accurate to
do a test before i planted
so i saw my plants and what their health
was before going into my soil system
which i knew was in you know a really
good situation um i planted them in
there i let them sit for a week or two
and i'm still well in veg i pulled
another sample just to see how things
are going in the soil that i've put on
the right path and i still saw a couple
little things like iron copper um also
uh boron which creates the big holes if
you're low on boron you're gonna get a
big hole in your stem which slows down
the amount of water that can pass
through the stem so i decided i'm going
to spray some i was excuse me i was told
that i should uh correctively foliar
spray some boron but also at the same
time with calcium boron and calcium
should always be applied together and it
really makes the get into the plant a
lot easier i'm sure you've heard that a
lot of times before so i kind of went
through this process but twice a week i
do a boron calcium spray and i do a
little uh
iron and copper foliar spray to offset
that and um
if you're ever impressed by the way your
plants grow
if you do this stuff it's gonna just
blow your mind especially if you've been
working for the same strain for several
years and you're just so used to what it
looks like so used to what it does it's
just it this is the plan i know it you
put it through this process you're going
to see genetic expressions you've never
seen before gotcha so it sounds like sap
testing can be extremely beneficial in
certain circumstances especially if
you're at like a commercial facility now
let me ask you this
home growers do they traditionally get
sap testing done well with the stop
testing you have to have the right
amount of leaves to send in the sample
you got to have 90 grams with the top
and the bottom so you know you're gonna
have to be at least you know in a four
by eight tent pushing four plants per
four by four square to have enough leaf
material to do so if you don't have
enough leaf material to do so honestly i
think you're gonna find tissue
tissue testing um a better way of going
because it's a smaller sample and you
get pretty much the same amount of data
how much does a sap test cost
um new based laboratories if you just do
one test it's just once i think it's 75
if you sign up to do 10 tests over
whatever period of time you want to do
you can get it for a little bit of a
lower price i believe it's somewhere
around 60
okay and so that one test is that that's
for both the top part of the plant
leaves that you collect and also the
bottom part of the plant yeah that's
considered one sample the new and the
old and they're compared together
and then we get a breakdown of every
different mineral um your brix level so
we can see what the sugar levels are
we're going to see the ph of the the
plant material we're going to see so
many different things that
really allow you to become an expert in
your own situation
especially for people who are doing
side-by-side stuff or have the same
setups as other people you really want
to take a step ahead employ some of the
science and you'll you'll really be able
to see and and have you know recordable
data next to what you're seeing that
makes sense
yeah sap testing is something i've never
done before you know i'm just a smaller
home grower i grow no more than 12
plants that's all i'm allowed to grow in
my state soil testing i've done before
but the sap testing i haven't so i think
i need to kind of send one out and i
think for me being a home grower when it
would be beneficial to us maybe while
it's in veg big enough to where i could
pull the leaves off before flipping a
flower i feel like potentially that
would be beneficial because then i'd get
that report
know where i'm struggling and make
adjustments before flipping to flowering
what do you think that's exactly what i
would do at a bare minimum because you
know you're going to be flipping the
flower you've got several weeks of
foliar spraying that could be done there
until you get to a point where you're
like oh my gosh these buds are getting
big and i don't feel comfortable foliar
spraying i'm risking mold and mildew and
that kind of stuff
me i fold your spray quite a while
through flour because i'm supplementing
products to prevent those issues from
happening in the beginning
and i don't have my cover on my
greenhouse so i'm not trapping in a
bunch of humidity you know it's getting
a chance to dry out pretty fast so
everybody's situation a little bit
different that makes sense
let's move on talk about tissue testing
so you kind of touched on upon it a
little bit give us the details about
tissue testing yeah um i honestly would
count on somebody like the soil doctor
for all of that advanced information i
personally have never conducted a tissue
test myself uh two years ago i got into
sap testing and that was the first thing
that you know was shown to me is it's a
better form of testing because they're
not burning the material you're getting
you know the best information directly
out of the plant right then and there
so tissue testing i think can be better
for somebody that's on a smaller scale
and you know maybe you should be doing
one of each just to see what test is
more beneficial for you
um you know maybe it's stop testing
that's the only way to go because you
like that process and it's easy for you
maybe the tissue testing is going to
really be a better simpler process for
you in the end so you know me me
personally i'm going to imply some
tissue testing and i'm going to compare
some things and i'm going to see what's
easier what's what's more simpler for me
it's really about the less labor and
what what's you know making us
have to enjoy growing let's let's enjoy
growing and not be like oh my gosh i
have to follow your spray oh it's
ruining my life
so i like to keep things positive now i
assume tissue sample it sounds like
you'd need a lot smaller amount of plant
material
is that right so how is like a tissue
test done you know how much does it cost
things like that you know i actually
don't know because i haven't i haven't
done one myself
at all i've seen people take you know
samples of stock put in a ziploc baggie
properly label it and send it out to the
laboratory there's a lot less risk
because you don't have to worry about
keeping the sample cold
you can collect that sample throughout
the day and then ship it out once you
drive past the post office later on the
end of the day uh compared to a sap test
you have to be very critical about these
things you have to cold pack it you got
to get it out there immediately so um
it's going to depend on what works for
you guys and where and logistically how
far you've got to ship these samples as
well is a big thing
okay and then as far as the report the
breakdown i think you might have touched
on is pretty much the same information
as a sap test or are you going to have
different results no you're going to
have all the same results you're just
like not going to have a comparative
from the bottom to the top
so you know and now that i'm thinking
about it the real thing you know if if i
was looking at a plant and i was seeing
some definite deficiency issues
and were like what the heck is going on
with this thing uh you would definitely
want to do that sap test because it will
comparatively show you you know what's
in the top leaves what's in the bottom
list and what's moving through the plant
you know that tissue sample is just
going to tell you if we chop that stem
off right there it's just going to tell
us what made it to that point and what
the plant was able to create
at that point in time in growth and when
we collected the sample
so i think that tissue testing first
stop testing thing really depends on
where you're at and what situation
you're going to be best in okay yeah
that makes sense for sure let's talk
about the outdoor greenhouse operation
that you've been working in so you talk
to me before we start recording this
you're excited about everything you've
got going on there so talk to us about
it what do you get going on out there
yeah so i'm running a couple of 48 foot
raised beds uh we're in northern
california so
you know we're kind of uh
riding it and out as long as we can and
having a great time um obviously we're
growing our six plants but on a very big
scale that they can become you know
large and you know give us what we need
for for the year um
but uh
the soil testing has really progressed
in a way that is i'm showing less
amendments every year so my soil is
retaining nutrients and is moving
forward in a very positive way so i
i think by three or four years from now
there could be a point where i don't
have to do anything in my soil i could
go out there and make sure it's
saturated and plant my plants
so you know that's going to be a
beautiful day a really beautiful day
when i just walk out to my farm and
plant those those plants and they take
off and they do their thing that's
that's kind of
the goal everyone's getting to and i see
that on the horizon which is uh
it takes a lot of weight off your
shoulders
putting through a large crop without
having any pest issues
probably been one of the most
relieving things i could have to my life
um tissue testing sap testing soil
testing
the whole reason i'm doing all of that
is so i don't have to fight pests at the
end
um i'm really trying to set up the soil
and set up these plants to where they
can treat the soil like the kitchen and
get everything they need whenever they
want it and they can live the healthiest
best possible life they can so i'm
treating these things like my children
and i'm taking them to the doctor which
is my soil test my sap test and i'm
making sure that they're going to be
healthy throughout the way um taking as
much care for these things as you would
for your infant in a certain sense you
know on a scientific level
so it's going great i'm really happy
with it this year was some of the
highest quality crop i've ever turned
out
um
and
it's amazing i'm very happy with it
definitely
yeah it would be cool to get to a point
where you're just adding water and you
don't even add any amendments anymore
like the goal you had said i actually
just got done talking with blue of green
tank not sure if you heard of him he's
yeah he's got avocado attacks so he's
literally just at the point where he's
feeding his soil you know feeding the
the insects the worms avocados and
they're breaking that down and providing
nutrients for the plant now oftentimes
he does do i believe he calls it a mash
where he's
mashing together some amendments and
then putting that in with the avocado as
well but the worms and insects go crazy
for them and that's all he does he
applies one i think he said he applies
one in veg and one in flour half in veg
half a flour
and that's like so much hands off
compared to you know feeding liquid
bottle nutrients for example where
you're you're mixing up nutrients every
single week you know sometimes several
times a week
or even just growing with organic
amendments to where you have to top
dress you know two or three times
throughout the grow so becoming more and
more hands hands-off a lot of people see
that as the ultimate goal now what about
chop and drop did you do that can you
talk to us about that no i got i got rid
of cover props because they can harbor
bad pests
um we found out a long time ago that the
russet mites can feed off of the clover
can feed off of those kind of things so
if i ever do any sort of a cover crop
it's going to be maybe a dichondra maybe
some grasses
but that's mainly going to be in the off
season while my soil is taking a rest
and that kind of thing so now that i've
harvested my crop i threw down some more
dichondra seed it's rained like crazy
for the first time ever in california so
it's going to pop like nuts uh come
around next spring i'm going to have a
big old mess to deal with and have to
clean up my beds and get them all ready
to plant and everything like that so um
i don't do the chop and drop thing
that's not my style i'm more of doing a
one inch cover crop excuse me a one inch
mulch layer that most layer is broken up
three equal parts of straw
rice holes and wood chips i take three
equal parts i mix them together in a
wheel barrel i fill it with water i put
a couple bricks on top for a few hours
make sure everything saturates real well
and i add no more than one inch of mulch
on top of my soil
more than that can suffocate your soil
make things hard for the worms
so everything i've learned you don't
want more than an inch layer
and it's been working out very
successful for me and the main thing is
no pest problems that's that's the goal
i'm willing to sacrifice a few other
things but if i don't got to deal with
with pests at the end of the year
we're good
what's your ipm routine in order to try
to prevent pests uh soil testing stop
testing is the main thing because
that'll let you see your your nitrate
levels so when you do a sap test there's
gonna be breaking down nitrogen at three
different points you're gonna have
nitrate in excuse the nitrogen in a
nitrate form you're going to have
nitrogen in
two other forms i can't reference right
now i should have my soil my stop test
with me but we found out
if you have high nitrate levels in your
plant material you're very
susceptible to pest pressure and and
because pests they don't have eyeballs
where they view these plants they have
antennas and they're looking at radio
signals and they're looking at radial
waves that these plants are giving out
so if they have high nitrogen nitrate
levels they're giving out heavy signals
wanting those bugs to come to them so
for me if i have low nitrate levels and
i have beautiful green growth i know
that my plants are going to be very less
susceptible to pests
so this last year i did not foliar spray
once
for
any sort of ipm i did not do that at all
the only thing i do is i apply
beneficial biology
at grassroots we have the concentrated
biology line which is beneficial liquid
microbes it's a compost tea product um
that has a one-year shelf-stable life
when you want to use it you combine it
with our microbial food
that activates the microbes
you can foliar spray that on the leaf
surface and veg or obviously i've mainly
just root drenched that into my soil
system every single week
so i'm mainly farming with microbes and
i'm putting a protective layer on my
leaf surface early in the plant's life
so it's got beneficial microbes on the
leaf surface
due to science we now know that
microbes do survive on the leaf surface
after your your folder spray is dried
out so you don't get the full life but
you do get microbes left on the leaf
surface and if let's say uh
a
powdery mildew spore lands on the on
that plant surface but we've got
beneficial microbes there to consume it
and i'll compete it we're not going to
have those issues
so i'm a microbial farmer um
using science and using science as much
as i possibly can
that's awesome that's interesting that
you're not doing any ipm sprays i mean i
talked to a large handful of outdoor
greenhouse growers and everybody
spraying with something whether it be
neem oil or some some sort of essential
oil you know peppermint rosemary some of
those things in order to try to prevent
pests that's awesome that you've gotten
to that point where you're literally
just utilizing sap testing soil testing
you know looking at your plant for the
health making sure those are in line
that you don't have to spray at all yeah
you know there was a grower a very
famous grower in humboldt kevin jordary
if you ever get a chance to have anybody
else on you know that's a legacy grower
from humboldt i would really look out to
kevin drawer he's got some of the most
amazing knowledge of anybody in the
cannabis industry
you know a long time about four years
ago i got to sit down and share share um
some medicine with kevin and
he explained to me the difference in
between
a good grower
and a great grower
is the difference between the healthiest
plant in the garden and the unhealthiest
plant in the garden and how big that gap
is
do we have a very small gap in between
the healthy and unhealthy and a very
healthy crop or do we have a large gap
and we have more unhealthy plants than
we do healthy plants
so my whole life i've been trying to go
is you know let's close that gap and
have those healthy plants that are there
to survive and they're ready to run that
race that we're asking them to run and
be those athletes that we want them to
be because they can they're already kind
of there you know you wouldn't pick a
320 pound man to be on the track to even
expect them to win a race this season
you don't do that you know so grabbing
that plant that's got purple stalks
purple stones fading leaves on it and
picking that to go into your garden it's
probably the biggest mistake you made
that whole time and foliar spraying or
doing a pesticide when your plants
really don't need it is affecting them
on a greater level than you really
understand so i'm not gonna i'm not
gonna use an ipm product unless i have a
really bad issue
and if you are going to use one i would
suggest maybe stuff oil x
which is retailed by arbico organics
it's a mineral oil and the times that i
have used it or need to use it the
plants freaking love it and i'm not
going to use it again for a week or two
and if i have to use it again i'm
debating getting rid of that plan
you know you really have to be ruthless
and deciding you know what's going to
make it what's going to move forward and
i'd rather cut the plant down and not
deal with bugs in my greenhouse than to
continue on and be like i'm going to
fold your spray again i go to folders
pretty good it's still not healthy you
know if you're folding spraying ipm
products and expecting the plant to be
healthier that's not going to be the end
result the plant you're just wiping off
that those bugs and hoping that it
doesn't continue you have not
fixed the problem from the beginning
that's creating the buds that's that's
been my whole life purpose the last five
years is what stops bugs from ever
coming and what can we do i don't want
to get to the ipm side of things that's
a horrible situation it's stressful and
you're not happy i'd rather be on the
other side of things where we're
constantly preventing it and having a
happy life
so yeah happy plants happy life i think
that's a great way to go about it you
know prevent the issue from occurring at
all you know to begin let's transition
let's talk about grassroots fabric pots
you say you've been working with them
for about six years i believe you said
talk to us about what they do at
grassroots what you've got for products
and so on and so forth uh we're here to
educate people that normal fabric pots
are not smart they actually suck
which is why we have the living soil
fabric pots right here that have a liner
in it that help you
grow plants in an organic way
so normal fabric pots that don't have a
liner they dry out from the top down the
bottom up and the sides in so there's no
situation in the world where a plant
dries out from all those different
situations besides maybe something that
grows in sand straight sand 24 7.
so you know
throughout the years we had people that
we thought were crazy telling us the
fabric pots sucked we're just like man
these things are great everybody buys
them leave me alone you know go go have
fun now you know a couple years later
people were telling us
i'm having problems and then we're like
what you're having problems
so they started telling us how the soil
was drying out unnaturally
and i'm like unnatural explain to this
me to explain this to me further and
they said well when you plant native
soil the sun is going to dry out the
soil from the top down
you're not going to have it drying out
from all these different angles we want
to recreate native soil as best as we
possibly can
um we went into a grow um the first
commercial situation
we ever dealt with we did some custom
pots we did some really cool stuff
especially for uh scott of crested soil
services which is another great person
to have on here he's a soil scientist
we did some really cool stuff with scott
he was the first one to kind of
implement that in fabric pots and one of
the people he was growing with is kind
of uh noticed like hey there's a big
difference when i wrap these pots with
saran wrap on the outside
so if you're ever cruising around living
soil hashtags or cruising around on
social media seeing people playing with
with living soil you'll commonly see a
fabric pot wrapped with plastic on the
outside
so that is somebody who's trying to
recreate native soil as best as possible
and eliminate the dry rolls from drying
out
that fast so with that living soil liner
we're allowing the roots to grow all the
way to the edge they can grow down
before they start circling they're going
to realize this normal fabric down at
the bottom and start their air pruning
process
so it's really cool how this is behind
me it's just worked out
um but your roots are allowed to grow to
the edge and have a better utilization
of the container in all areas
one really cool aspect that we really
were not expecting
is these growers started reporting back
to us lower energy costs as in their
their pg e bills their power bills were
coming lower
because this liner right here was
holding in the water from every time you
watered instead of it going out
immediately into the room it's being
held back
and it's making a lot less effort for
your dehumidification system of your
fans to battle all of that system so um
safe water uh immediately have fungal
life growing so that was one of the
first things that if you wrap your
fabric pot with saran wrap you'll
probably see
a mushroom or two pop up within 20 or 40
24 to 48 hours so it's like oh my gosh
all that biology is there but it just
was never given the right situation to
really
cultivate
and go crazy and be able to do his thing
so anybody out there growing in a normal
fabric pot i i
really would urge you to wrap it and see
the differences see how much water you
save and see how much happier the plant
is and then on top of that move to a
living soil fabric pot or raised beds
because you know that's really where you
need to be in the future for growing
your vegetables your plants your
medicine all on the same program
so grassroots faber poss we we really
make a lot of custom stuff
um we're in sacramento california and we
have a 12 000 square foot manufacturing
facility where we make all this stuff
right here in sacramento
our fabric is from the state of georgia
so it's american-made um if you've ever
been in the military or have any family
members in the military this fabric will
look very familiar for to you because
this is the same fabric that's used for
the us military and their hesco barriers
barricades any forward operating base
anything like that this is from the same
exact manufacturer
we just have a little bit different
specifications
as far as the thickness goes
with those barricades they can go with
the thinnest material possible and
it does great so for us we went with
something a little bit thicker we went
with an 8.5 ounce material which shows
the weight per square inch
um
american made no heavy metals a very
consistent fabric
indoors
i can't estimate a life on it it's
probably going to last for pretty close
to forever
because there's no uv light to break it
down
outdoors you've got the uv light coming
down from the sun that's what's going to
break down the materials over time
there's not much you can do about that
you know our products outdoors and the
harshest harshest conditions are going
to have a minimum life of about five
years
probably well well over that we know
we're being conservative awesome yeah i
have the two foot by ten foot bed
outside i got some veggies there you
gifted to me several years ago man i was
i had to do a 2019 i think is when you
you gifted me that one so i appreciate
that i like them i agree with what you
say about how like fabric pots it just
dries from dry oats from all angles
and when you've got microbes that you
need to be there to break down those
amendments for the plant you know turn
them into usable nutrients for the plant
well if they dry out and there's no
water there
they go dormant right they're in a sleep
state so they're not able to work and
break things down so you are more prone
to see deficiencies potentially happen
because the plants aren't getting a lack
of nutrients so i'm a believer in
grassroots fabric pots for sure i've
actually also just done plastic pots
over fabric pots just for the reason you
you mentioned you know what i mean
because i don't want them drying out
from all different sides specifically
yeah yeah well this has been a great
talk kind of wrapping things up tell us
how the can looser just find you and
what do you have upcoming in the future
yeah we've actually got some absolutely
amazing stuff coming out in the future
this is one of our new shirts we have
soil life
we have a new version of our logo coming
out some really cool stickers save the
soil
so we haven't done any new marketing in
about three years we've just been
focusing on our products and focusing on
getting out as much fabric pots and
raised beds as we can to people but now
for the last eight months the owner and
myself have focused on some new
marketing and we're really going to get
down to showing how much we we benefit
the culture and how much we are a part
of
the culture of the industry that we work
in so we've got some amazing marketing
some new boxes that all of our products
will be delivered in a lot more support
a lot more help for you know getting
forward throughout that process
so you can reach us at
grassrootsfabricpots.com
you can also reach us on social media
just grassroots fabric pots on instagram
we have a facebook uh we also uh i
personally host the grassroots living
soil podcast it's available on spotify
and apple uh i do what i can to have
some of the best people on there as well
so you should we should get you on there
too man
that would be awesome that'd be pretty
cool well i'll certainly leave links to
the stuff that you just mentioned down
in the description section below but
thanks so much for coming on man
definitely learned a few things it's
great catching up with you it's always
good catching up with you and and just
talking shop and yeah i hope you enjoy
the rest of your day thank you thank you
um your guys's success is my success so
i'm here to give out any of my knowledge
totally free and free source so i'd love
to help you guys out absolutely all
right take care
you