welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden hey everybody for those of you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned into to the
Garden Talk podcast this episode number
140 in this episode I interview Dr Gary
Yates he is the former Chief science
officer of Pharma seeds and graduated
with honors and genetics from the
University of glasow he has extensive
knowledge in the molecular biology of
plant stress responses which is revealed
in today's topic all about crop steering
these podcast episodes are broken up
into small clips and posted on the
garden talk Clips YouTube channel I also
have a gardening Channel where I show
the plants that I grow I'll link both of
those channels down in the YouTube
description section below one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who help me that go possible thanks to
AC Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their cloudray Gen 2
oscillated clip fan their nextg clip fan
has been re-engineered to provide a long
lasting motor and customizable air flow
for all stages of your plant's growth
cycle it features 10 speeds and 10
Dynamic win modes to simulate outdoor
air flow in links with uis controllers
for Wi-Fi app control click the link in
the description section below so you can
learn more about their cloudray clip
fans and the discount code Mr Gro 15
works on both Amazon and their website
AC infinity.com stash blend stash blend
is a
215 plant additive that can be used with
synthetic bottle nutrients or in living
soil systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and microle fungi check it out at
stash blend.com Link in the description
section below and use the discount code
the stash Mars Hydro Mars Hydro has now
been in business for 15 years and to
celebrate their anniversary they're
doing a 15% discount on their products
from now until August 15th during the
sale they also do flash sales where some
items are even at a bigger discount
everything from grow lights grow tents
ventilation equipment hydroponic
equipment and more go to their website
Mars - hydro.com for more details and
you can use the discount code Mr Grow to
save on any of their products and we are
back and I'm joined with Dr Gary Yates
how you doing today yes very well Chris
thanks how are you I'm doing pretty good
thanks for asking today we're going to
talk all about crop steering now there
are many things that you can do in the
garden to steer your way to a specific
result some people do it to achieve a
higher quality some people do it to
increase yield we're going to get into
all of that in this episode but first
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening sure um so so I started
gardening with my grandfather when I was
like you know single digits he was he
was a master of Just Like Home grow of
every kind so all sorts of vegetables
and fruits and stuff and we were in Bas
in Scotland where the growing season's
quite short it's quite limited it's not
very warm so that was quite it was quite
a good indoctrination and just like
being around plants as a kid but it
wasn't until many years later that I got
kind of seriously involved and got into
medicinal plants um eventually I started
uh kind of drove me actually to to study
genetics I was really fascinated how
some medicinal plants would Express
certain compounds that weren't really
present or at least not in as much
abundance in other plants that was one
of the kind of driving questions behind
why I wanted to study genetics so so
that led me on that path and and and
from there I went on to do a PhD in
plant science where
concentrated on plant pathogen
interactions um I discovered a classic
enzymes in there and and a in a specific
signaling mechanism which had been
overlooked in the whole Cascade when
when any bacteria is seen by a plant
cell essentially so that that was really
fun that that that was um a really
competitive side of plant science and
really interesting but I I kind of you
do so much in certain fields and I was
always one for branching out so so from
there I moved into work on on
photosynthesis is where we took a
photosynthetic algae which could
supercharge it CO2 um and basically we
were trying to reverse engineered that
so we could grow massive crop plants of
of all kinds um and then after after I
did that St I joined with seedsman uh
Team essentially they had a few
different you know sides of the business
and I was involved in one of the kind of
medicinal um plant side of things that
was was geared towards the legal medical
industry in the UK um but over time I
did more and more for seeds and their
Market in the US and was much more got
to do with you know small scale home
cultivation and things like that so it
was a good it good kind of like wide
birth of of of experience so in that
role I I went to like big outside um
grows in the Caribbean or in Spain and
then we did also the kind of small craft
style tents inside you know um around
different places Canada us and so it was
good it was a really good wide range of
experience and then finally on on my
story what was a kind of a pinnacle part
was was partner up with jge cantes um
which was through seedsman as well we
got to know each other we became really
good friends actually but he's been he's
been quite instrumental in in in both my
my understanding and learning side of
things but also in my ability to express
what I'm trying to say because he's got
like 40 years of experience writing
medical plant books you know and pushing
it out to to the public there especially
when times where it wasn't so easy let
just say um you know so so that was that
was a you know that's that's me full
circle now now I'm working in a I'm the
head of cultivation for a for a medical
plants company based in Scotland and
I've also got a few other little
projects going on here and there um in
different different levels yeah awesome
so much formal education background
which is really good from time to time
we have somebody like you that has
formal education on the podcast and
people just love it you know getting
real deep into things we're going to get
real deep into crop steering here in a
minute but yeah I know about you through
seedsman I was introduced to you and you
have so many good articles on it uh I
recommend folks to Google Dr Gary Yates
seedsman and you'll see a whole bunch of
different articles that come up that
he's written lots of good information
some of the things I've actually cherry
picked out of those articles to bring
within this talk here so I'm excited to
bring that particular information to my
audience but let's get into crop
steering can we start with the basics
can you just talk to us like what is
crop steering sure um so so crop
steering we all do crop steering to a
certain extent whether we realize it or
not but essentially it's it's the
directing the the way the plant grows
the the outputs of the plant or
sometimes even the inputs that it's
required to make the plant successful so
crop steering is all about kind of
guiding the parameters in order to get a
specific outcome or a specific um I
would say trait because I'm I'm a
geneticist which basically means you
know a specific expression of the genes
that allow for a certain thing to happen
so so that's essentially what we're
trying to do it can be anything from
taking a a variety that's specifically
mold resistant but doesn't produce a lot
of you know compounds for example that
are valuable so it's like taking one of
those plants and and and driving it
towards making it more you know
medically valuable or something like
that it could be it could be the
opposite way as well where you've got a
really good sprad of the compounds
you're after when you grow a plant but
then you want to kind of build in some
kind of resilience to that plant which
maybe isn't already there so crop
steering is a little bit about that if
if you combine crop steering with with
kind of you know Advanced phenotyping
then you can really take a seed lot and
really push it in actually several
directions if you you know I always
always like the analogy of like if you
give a thousand seeds to you know let's
just scale it back 100 seeds to the same
100 seeds to 10 different people could
all pull something very different out of
that because they grow in a specific
environment because they're looking for
something very specific from the plant
and they've actually got S A lot of the
times different standards on what the
what the gauge the performance of the
plant on so you combine all those things
and you sometimes get really really
diverse outcomes and that's what's
happened actually with a lot of the the
poly hybridization that's going on and
and and in our industry for the last you
know 30 40 50 years even like a lot of
that started from a fairly small Jee
pill and it's it's been amazing what's
come out here I mean I'm I'm mind blown
like how how much variety and and
different ranges of different things
we've got out of that but there's also
still a whole lot more to be tapped into
you know like but anyway I digress but
that that's um combining the phenotyping
with the the crop steering is really The
Sweet Spot to to drive and an outcome
from the plant that you really need or
you or you desire so so that's kind of
the basics of crop steering it sounds
little bit more fancy than actually is
you know it's it's simply managing the
conditions and the response of the plant
for a specific output essentially that
is a good basic definition of it and
yeah for you expanded I appreciate that
and it is exciting to see different
Expressions that can happen really just
from different seeds you know each seed
is its own pheno and each seed can have
its own expression and it's really cool
to be able to do such as fenal hunts for
example and see these different
expressions it makes gardening fun in my
opinion got a bunch of strawberries
growing in my back Garden right now and
like that I don't know what's the
variation but even within the same plant
the ones that come at slightly different
times they can taste quite different you
know the terpine profile on them seems
to be pretty different and um and I'm
kind of keeping little notes on that and
it's just super interesting but for now
I can't work out any pattern at all it's
just it just seems somewhat random you
know that's super interesting so if a
gardener were to start crops steering
what actions would you suggest that they
take in order to make it successful yeah
so I mean it sounds really basic and
simple but listing the criteria that you
want to meet is is the first thing then
obviously choosing the right variety to
match that is the second thing but
really what you want to do is is figure
out from your grown environment where
your what I call the dials are which
things can you control and change and
which things can you not the variables
that you can control and the others that
you can't
and then it's working within the
confines of them throughout my career
and actually in other you know this just
the versions of my life that I've I've
lived before getting to this point I've
always been what what I call a master of
limited resources so taking a fairly
small amount of tools and be making
something that would be quite unexpected
from from that range of tools and that's
kind of what what what this is all about
as well it's like okay you might only
have a you know 300 watt light and you
might only have a kind of one by one but
what can you do with that and and some
people have really mastered crazy little
kind of niches within that and and
that's really what it's about is about
driving
towards um fulfilling a kind of
potential if you will whatever that may
be and and the Very the variables are so
vast that each one of us can have our
own little specific niche in that sense
you know because it's almost unlimited
when you think about the amount of
variables go into it so yeah I would I
would say but before you get started so
make your list have an idea the the
dials and then really just start you
know reading up finding out as much as
you can about what to do a lot of the
stuff with the plants that we were
talking about it's not very well known
it's not well documented the science is
a little bit behind but we've got
examples from other plants and we've got
an experience and we've got the kind of
the greatest thing about this community
is the just the powery numbers the
amount of people who are out there doing
it for themselves and feed them back so
so that's what you really want to do is
is keep on course with all your
parameters but then understand where you
can change those and and and lead them
to the kind of the outcomes that you
want does that does that answer the
question yeah absolutely all right so
let's hop into the different stages of
growth and kind of the triggers that you
can do in order to crop steer right so
let's start with the seedling stage
lighting environment conditions
irrigation nutrition all these things
can be adjusted when you're crop
steering right so maybe let's start with
lighting know what do you recommend for
say the amount of par or
Spectrum yeah so so one one thing I
would like to break down with the light
before we actually go into the specifics
like that is is I think we mentioned
before this this um this this chat that
um one of the things I got interested in
was the different quality of light from
indoor from outdoor from glass house and
what's really interesting is like and I
know I know this from my time working in
photosynthesis the par range is like
it's like trimmed at the ends at both
ends it doesn't include the UV Spectrum
it doesn't include the kind of far Red
Spectrum which is just like it's just an
interesting point because my
understanding physiology both of those
things are pretty important um and if
you just went by the textbooks you would
say oh well you can't do without them
but we know from experience you can very
well do without them both you know
generations of of Horticultural plants
that have been growing in glass houses
all sorts of things from fruits and
vegetables right through to you know
medicinal plants and and also indoor as
well we know that the horiculture
markets Thrive without the the needs for
these clipped spectrums if you will um
so so that that's one thing to consider
though it's like Again part of crop
steering is understanding like so for
the seedling stage and for lightting if
you've got a kind of harsh environment
like I would suggest that you try and
sew your seeds in quite a harsh
environment which what does that mean
okay this if it's kind of cold do it on
a window ledge so it's inside but warm
but not extremely warm and try and get
the seeds to germinate germinate at a
little bit lower temperature that bows
in a hardiness um giving them exposure
to the outside early on as well really
helps build up their stress resistance
for for the future so that you've got
things like wind resistance that they
build up so they they tend to be a
little bit stockier if you put them out
right if you're growing um for was the
next one I was going to say yeah for
like I said with the UV light so so UV
being light triggers a bunch of stress
responses in the plant which actually
changes gene expression quite um quite a
way actually and there's a lot of things
like it will do it will help with UV
protection actually believe it or not
which is is ironic but it will also help
with things like DNA repair so whenever
there is damage to the cells from other
you know whether it be chemicals in the
ground whether it be you know extreme UV
that the plant can actually repair
itself a lot more readily if it's been
exposed to UV uh
be light so so understanding that is
important first of all is that you know
what do you want to try and Achieve here
if you've got a harsh environment you
want to prepare your seedling to be
ready for that otherwise if you've got a
perfect environment however then what
you want to do is is literally live
pretty much by your favorite textbook or
your favorite you know whatever light
manufacturer you you've chosen go by
there by what they say I found that
often times the best thing to do is just
stick to the you know what says on the
tin to quote an old advert um so so but
but generally what you want from from
the seeding stage is a lot of blue light
compared to Red Light plenty Green in
there not too intense probably I mean
like just germinating seeds as it just
comes out like maybe 200 micro moles um
of light in terms of in you know
intensity I don't know if that's a a
thing you understand micro mes per met
squar per second for example um so so
that's what you would um you know you
would keep it on that now if you wanted
to like I say make your plant ready for
for the a harsher environment and you
can't you know have a hybrid indoor
outdoor way doing it then a UVB lamp
which is now quite readily available
with a lot of the LED setups is is
probably worthwhile because like I said
it gives it it doesn't necessarily at
that stage increase anything in terms of
the the the medicinal compounds or the
overall yield but what it can do is
buffer against some of those stresses
that are harder to manage um which you
know you're basically giving your plant
a a little bit of a a head start in
terms of resisting you know various
types of stress by adding in that UV
light so that that would be my we little
kind of top tip on on the seedling stage
would would introduce something you know
in the in the kind of like low blue
Spectrum into the UVC UVB um especially
because that that would trigger a a a
light comp a light complex called uvr8
and this was like um only discovered in
like I don't know the two early 2000s um
something like that was actually in the
lab in Glasgow that discovered it um
during my undergrad so so that's why
I've got a little bit of insight on that
that protein but it regulates a bunch of
things um and if it's not activated you
still get activation of those things
that regulates but you don't get such a
strong response so that's sometimes I've
seen plants chosen for their their
specific pheno and then they're grown
under glass and the and they don't they
seem really susceptible to different you
know stresses and this is one of the
reasons why CU they're not having that
UVB Activation so so sorry to kind of go
on about that but it kind of sets us up
for talking about light for the for the
next phases of light as life as well
really good tips really good tips I
appreciate you uh expanding on that and
I also appreciate how you mentioned the
textbook par range and how that's really
a bit outdated right they say par 400 to
700 nanometers but the plant can utilize
Beyond 700 nanometers and lower than 400
nomers right UV IR or bar red so yeah
I'm glad you brought that up because you
know a lot of people do know it but not
everybody knows it people might still be
referring to the textbook which is a bit
outdated but yeah there is an extended
range now that we know that it does have
an impact on the plants yeah I mean the
so most are clipped at 700 nanometers
you're right but the there's a comp
there's a light receptor called um pyto
Chrome B and it needs to see far red
which is 730 so this this compound can
see two two different spectrums of light
and it needs the other one to convert it
back to to being ready to receive and
one's an active form and one's an
inactive form and if you can't activate
it then what happens is the gene can
overproduce it because it's it's not
getting that switch back and forth at
the protein level so the light would
normally switch this protein back and
forth and that helps regulate the
processes if you don't have that the
gene then the compensation for that is
to over produce the protein do you see
what I mean so that I don't know what
effect that is it's not really been
largely you know it's not been hugely um
explored but that is one of the the the
the the mechanisms that would be
affected by by capping your your your
your your power range at 700 um and it's
like I say it's the same at the other
end they got you know having a peak of I
like a blue Peak like 355 maybe even you
know a we bit lower than that so some of
them capped at four is crazy even light
receptors work um some of the kind of uh
light receptors involved in specific
processes outside photosynthesis they
they're they're activated lower than
that as well which is um you know like
right down to 280 down in the UV so it's
crazy that that's completely missing
from a lot of the stuff but yet the
stuff still grows pretty well you know
think that's it kind of my mind how you
can have you know we say You must have
this but you can kind of get away with
not having it you know yeah the plants
will adapt for sure right now how about
nutrition you know generally speaking in
the seedling stage it's often said that
nitrogen should be more heavier than
some of the other elements would you
agree with that disagree do you have any
tips in regards to that I mean like so
personally my favorite way to you know
the way I've had the best results is
actually just to have a hands off
approach if you can get a really good
soil mix just leave it just water it and
just let it go that's what I've found
that gives me the best cuz then what
happens is between the microbes and the
and the soil and the plant itself they
kind of they kind of steer themselves to
what they need and what they want is
what I've found again without without
kind of getting scientific about it
because I can't back that up necessarily
with science but but my observation is
that when when you have a good soil
based system the plant seems to just you
know take care of itself you you don't
see much signs of any of these issues
you do in a hydroponic system where
everything's really tightly regulated
and if you have even just a change in
temperature of your nutrient you can
have a pH change and then you know you
can see the effects and in the plant so
I like a soil based system for that
getting a really good mix um Jorge
cantes put me on to chicken manure as a
as a good um additive to soil as well
and I've been experimenting with that
this year the effects have been
tremendous absolutely tremendous I was
really surprised but um but otherwise
yeah there's a thing about having high
nitrogen I I don't know they kind like a
balanced blend throughout you know like
that I think that's the point I'm trying
to make through all is like I kind of
like I don't want to be messing about
guessing what the plant needs as it
grows you know like that's I think
because again not a lot of that's based
on science a lot of that's just based on
what people before us did and we're kind
of just following suit even but just a
step back to the light a lot of old
school ways of thinking is that you
increase light intensity up until like
week eight and then you can and all this
and it's it's just nonsense that's not
how it works at all like you just blast
it with as much light as it can take for
as long as it can take it because that's
what happens outdoor in the Sun and
that's what they evolve from you know so
that that's the best way to attack that
as well I always try and find the I'll
always take the light to the highest
level I can to until I see a stress
response in the plants and then dial it
back a little bit
that because that little stress response
actually helps them to take more light
heavier amount of light in the future as
well so that's another little kind of
crop steering tip is if you want your
plants to take a bit more light than
they have done previously if even if
you're in a clone mother cycle you can
actually train your plant to be
highlight responsive again the genotype
will dictate how how far you can push
that but if you expose your your young
plant to a like intermittent high
intensity light when you put it into for
example flour and you give it a little
bit more than than you had done before
it should be able to cope with a little
bit better and there's there's a whole
bunch of epigenetic effects in there
that are you know it's basically
controlling different gen expression
mechanisms and again preempting them
seems to be somehow it's like I can of
we used to when I was training or when I
was at Uni they called it um plant
memory things like this you know like
this this idea that the plant can
remember if you give it certain stresses
when it's young the plant will remember
that when it's old older but what it
actually means is it can it can shortcut
the response you know it doesn't have to
like learn what's going on and then
respond to it's already done it kind of
like our immune system right when we've
been immunized or exposed to a bug
before we have those antibodies and we
just we can get rid of it much quicker
it's kind of like that without being
similar in mechanism but it's it's like
that in in concept if you know what I
mean um but yeah sorry I deviate but
nutrient is um yeah I like I like hands
off with my nut Trent I don't like to
overpower it um and again the light I go
for top down but the nutr I go bottom up
if you understand what I mean I tend to
be light on the nutrient and and see and
build it up um rather than go with what
what's the most you can take in that by
down because again it's just you don't
have much of a chance to fix it if you
go way over you know if you go a little
bit under you can you can catch up in a
few days um with with nutrients so yeah
no massive tips there for me other than
just think try and try and get a good
mix a good uh depending on your
substrate but try and get a good mix of
the nutrients that you want throughout
the veg period and give it that from the
start is what I would say understood now
how about the vegetative stage do you
have any tips for crop steering in the
vegetative stage so so yeah like so
there's a couple here like if you wanted
to have and again this is a little bit
plant training as well right but if you
wanted to have like only like what the
used to call triaa grade you know um
finish let's just say then then we you
can condition your plants for different
styles of of cultivation different
cultivation techniques so for example in
a vegetative day if you wanted to grow
what we call the sea of green style
which I'm sure you you'll know which is
lots of plants close together you make
this kind of like literal sea of green
because there's no space anywhere
there's a really good econom again
depending on the scale you're on
depending on what outcomes you want it's
a really good way of of of of achieving
like a a fast turnaround consistent
quality you know if you have the Clone
numbers going in there and you kind of
even just do a single Cola on each plant
you can get like really high levels of
consistency so that's good for like you
know for the medical industry for
example who have like kind of really
tight tolerances on what the what the um
the compound level sh could be so so you
know so if you're going to grow for for
sea of greenic for example you can you
basically want to ramp your light again
back to light you want to ramp your
light up um pretty quickly in vegetable
in vegetation because you probably got a
short veg of time right so you want that
plant to put on as much mass as possible
so that was the other thing I was going
to get with veg um so rather than the
nutrient itself I'll talk about the
watering schedule if I may um so so
combining that like highlight with a
really good watering strategy something
that's massively overlooked in this B A
lot um you you can you can steer a lot
of the crop with how you water it um and
again whether there's feed in the water
or that doesn't matter it's just the
scheduling of of delivering you know the
liquid to the plant's feet let's just
say um so for for if you want the plants
to grow fast you know like and really
push them on like lots of short burs of
of of of feeder water early on in the in
the day that's what I've found that you
know just if they're if all in all
they're going to consume say I don't
know
eight ounces in the day that just say
small right they got to do eight ounces
you would do like two and two and two
and two right so rather than do all
eight at once or go four at the start
and four halfway through you just do two
short ones or or sorry four short ones
of two throughout the throughout each
day I found that that pushes the plants
on especially um linearly you know in
height not not necessarily in bushiness
but that kind of pushes the growth rate
up so again if doing single Cola and you
want you know a good epical bud there
and you're going to strip away a lot of
the the secondary and tertiary you know
growth that's that's what would be my
advice for that if you want to Bush the
plant out in veg then two shots early
Two Shots late bigger do shots um is
what I would suggest with your watering
schedule there so those kind of two
different you know different types of
accelerator I would say um but you can
start to get a response from those
especially um the first one with the
short bus often you can get that
response out of the the vegetating
plants pretty quickly you can see the
difference um it's a bit
counterintuitive to do short short
amount of of watering because but what
basically happens is if you if you will
the mechanism is you don't give the
plant enough it creates more root hairs
in sear your water and you just get you
you're just giving it enough you know to
to to to give it enough water but it's
also pushing itself to try and find more
water at the same time which means that
it overall in ability to update water
increases you know it's supposed to giv
it a big shot where it's sitting in it
its own water it doesn't need to go
searching for it all day the root The
Roots don't tend to expand at the same
rate when you do that um but that's a
technique you want to use in in
flowering because you don't really want
to be gaining root mass and fling
necessarily you want to have built your
root mass by that point ideally um you
know and you want all the growth and all
the energy to be going into the top of
the plant um so yeah that's that's kind
of combining your your irrigation and
your nutrient there again I'm light on
the feed I like you know getting getting
the water and right and getting the
substrate right you'll have absolutely
no problems through veg you know that's
what I've found it's generally the I
like the early stage of Life a lot of
people like the Finish but I I really
like the early stage the first like 21
days I just think it's phenomenal speed
of growth and amount of change from this
little Pip into this like you know
sometimes like 10 in 12p and you're just
like what how did that do that in that
space of time you know yeah these plants
grow so quickly it's it's incredible and
appreciate the advice on the irrigation
on that Avenue now some people believe
in drought stress as far as I've heard
claims as much as it brings out the
secondary metabolites more is there any
truth to that or is that just Bro
Science um I've not come across any
studies suggesting that I I I do like um
the dryback technique you know like when
when you potting up and stuff like that
and let the plant pretty much dry out
that's pretty much that's what we're
referring to yeah yeah like so so that
that for potting up I like um I'm not
sure that I I just like it because it
helps the roots expand into the new pot
you know they be be beyond that I don't
know what it does to I can't can't
imagine what it does to tune the the
secondary metabolite um Pathways but but
we we we know so little about that it's
possible you know it's it's possible
that something there is is connected um
Sciences are nothing else surprising a
lot of the times when you when when
these connections are made um like the
ones about I don't know if you've ever
looked up to um mechano stimulation
which is a technique where you basically
create vibrations around or on the plan
and and again that's reported to
increase all sorts of secondary
metabolites and stuff and there's a
there's companies Now set up to go come
to your facility and set up mechano
vibration you know simulators and stuff
like that so there's all sorts s of
things that we don't understand yet so
yeah it's possible but I've not seen any
evidence for that yet so much more to
uncover yeah it's incredible that's one
thing that makes this plant so much fun
cultivating it at least is like not
everything has been uncovered new things
are being identified so uh yeah I I love
keeping up to date on that stuff you
touched upon plant training a little bit
but I want to get a little bit deeper
cuz in one of the Articles you wrote you
mentioned plant training changes gene
expression can you talk to us a little
bit about that
yeah I think I think some context and a
little bit of background on how genes
are expressed is is relevant without
getting too technical about it um people
forget that and plant has DNA of course
right um but the they have an entire
genome in every single cell of their
their entire existence right so every
cell every cell that makes up the roots
every cell that makes up you know the
stem the leaf the thing each one of them
has its own genome so and each one of
those cell types have a different way of
Express expressing The genome right so
they have different genes that are
active versus ones that are inactive in
other tissue types and that's true in
cell types as well it's why a flow is a
flower and a Root's a root right they
start from the same essentially the same
precursor but they deviate down the line
cell division and and and and
differentiation so so when you um when
you have when you say oh there's a gene
expression change doesn't always mean
throughout the entire plant sometimes it
can be loc locally to the area that
you're talking about so that that's just
a little bit of Preamble that I wanted
to give in qualification to that if you
if you cut a plant for example doesn't
mean necessarily mean that every every
cell expresses its jeans now differently
you know but there can be big changes at
the site where you made that where you
made that cut but there is also
signaling mechanisms that do go
throughout the plant and it can prime
the plant for like I say stress
resistance and stuff like that so your
your specific example if you are you
know if you're taking if you're taking a
clone um you injur the plant okay you
you cut through the plant um branch and
then you take the Clone away now forget
about the Clone what happened what
happened at that site that you cut so
the plant has a wound response mechanism
that's evolved for millions of years
this has got to do this is this is a a
kind of an advanc an advancement on the
tra of um or ISM so like you know
whether it be a small animal or insect
that chew on the plant that eats the
plant for for its dietary needs um the
plants have got a response to that
whether it be producing certain
compounds that will repel them you know
different tast whether it be some plants
have developed like spikes and needles
like stingy nles for example to try and
you know repel that so so they have like
a whole you know tens and tens of
millions of years of evolution hundreds
of millions of years of evolution behind
those me mechanisms right so so that's
the other thing to bear in mind it's
like when we taking a cutting it's
nothing new to the plant you know the
plants you know as well is well ready
for for for an injury like that but what
we can do there is we can we can make
the
injury um in a specific way at a
specific time that we can try and direct
some of that expression and and changes
in gene expression so
like this a like the wound response
mechanism itself right like that's
that's a good one to preactivate so the
earlier that you can pinch out or top a
plant generally the more Hardy and
resilient the plant becomes to that
specific thing again back to your crop
steering right if you want it's not
necessarily that you need to do it now
but you want it to be able to do it
later so injuring the plant early on in
that respect can change the gene
expression so that we get a better
response the next time you see it's this
kind of same mechanism as I was talking
about earlier the conditioning I mean
it's it's it's the same formula the
plant you know the plant knows what it's
doing um so so yeah that that that
that's in that sense it changes
expression so what what we have now in
that um in that site of injury is a
plant has to now decide what it's going
to do with that with that site so the
first thing is it has to close it up to
stop infection right so you got a bunch
of genes activated there that weren't
activated before in order to to
basically heal that wound then what you
normally get is is New Growth that come
from there you know the kind of classic
thing is if you take a a bit of a branch
away to make a clone you have two new
ones that appear from that that's an
interesting change in expression as well
because you've went you you've each
although there's a like a what we call
the epical mer stem which is like you
know the tallest part of the plant is is
where the the main Suite of uh stem
cells are in the plant but it's also
true that on each branch you have an
epical kind of dominance as you go up
and down that that Branch itself so when
you take away that epical dominance from
even a branch not even the full plant
just from that Branch what happens is
because it re um starts back from the
the kind of the stem cell say the merry
stem
cell because the plant symmetrical you
end up with two so we we know this
phenomenon right when you take a cut you
often get two that grow back so that's
what's happening there you're changing
not actually that's actually has to do
with gene expression and actually more
to do with how the cells differentiate
you know because you've set them on a
pathway but it's triggered by the fact
that you've caused this wound so it's
all like a series of of gene expression
protein um receptors and you know it's a
big feedback loop which one action
results in another action results in
another action and often that does
result in a series of gene expression
changes so very literally that's what
that means but then a little bit more
kind of holistically it's it's about you
know readying the plant for the
different types of things that's to come
as well IE more stress you know and
that's how you
can mitigate the stress response because
some things you want a stress response
some things you want you don't want the
stress response you want to be able to
do things and the plant just keeps
growing doesn't care right and that's
the whole big battle between pathogen
and yield pathogen resistance sorry in
yield pathogen resistance is great but
sometimes what happens if the plant
doesn't defend itself and it just keeps
growing it ends up decimated at the end
right because it's it's been been by
this this bug or whatever on the other
hand um if the plant's susceptible to it
what it does is it shuts down it doesn't
grow it redirects its energy reserves
and tries to fight off the the infection
in the best it can or it shuts down that
side of the plant and tries to regrow
somewhere else you know they can another
half of the plant because it it knows
that's compromised and plants are also
really good at killing themselves so
like locally they'll kill certain cells
to stop this the spread infection and
that can actually be you know quite
widespread a plant can actually just
program it's called program sell death
and just like completely like destroy
itself in order to save itself um you
know and and again different parts of
the plant will do that you even see it
with like a bit out stretch but the same
thing is is like when the when the wel
leaves it's a kind of similar thing
right it's okay that's done now we just
cut off the supply that slowly pinch it
and then it just it's no longer getting
any nutrients from the stem and it
wethers and dies and drops off so it's
the same kind of thing you know slightly
different but it's the same kind of
thing that's wild yeah have a bu who
super crops every single branch and he
does it very early in the vegetative
stage and he right he swears that it
helps make the plant more Hardy and you
just kind of confirm that there is
science to back it that uh if you're
doing this type of damage early on it's
it's going to build up some sort of like
resistance right some hardiness to it so
that that's really cool to hear about
the details on how that works
yeah it's also gen again genotype
specific right what which variety you
have some will not take it so well
because some of overreact to that but if
you get the right variety and the right
person's hands as well I must say
because you some of these things are
quite a delicate touch even although
they they seem extreme you know um but
yeah that's what I'm saying there
there's such there's a lane for everyone
the variables are so vast it's it's a
fascinating study like you know I've
seen all sorts of crazy things people do
and and I say if you get results then
keep doing it if there's no science to
back it up doesn't matter there's a guy
who drives nails through his his stems
there's a guy who what was it he does it
really likes to use like warm animal
blood you know for for feed in the soil
yeah they just strange things like that
and they swear by these things and like
yeah there's all sorts of crazy things
we've come across um oh I can't think
anymore now but they some just really
wild stuff you know um but again you
probably you're probably elic eliciting
a response from the plant which could be
otherwise attained you see what I mean
like it doesn't necessarily always need
to be that extreme to to get that
response um but yeah that that's really
cool the super cropping thing is um yeah
but I bet he he gets a lot of yield as
well from from doing that right because
you got a lot of really good kind of top
buds essentially yeah he you know one of
the main reasons why he does that is
because it helps with the strengthening
of the branches he claims so when the
you get into the flower stage and youve
got all these buds on the plant there's
less flopp of those branches cuz it's
they're stronger from that super crop
early on at least that's what that's
what he claims so I thought that was
interesting yeah that is super
interesting but yeah so so plant
training in general like is you're doing
two things you're basically
restructuring the architecture of the
plants to suit yourself but you're also
then conditioning it to be able to take
that and to be you know maybe like
heavier Branch um yielding because it
can take the weight I remember like the
first plants that we ever grew um they
were like extremely floppy we didn't
know what we were doing like everything
was FL you needed like four layers of
net you know because it was just like
flopping off the place ideally what what
would be like in your kind of sci-fi
mind right what would be the ideal way
to grow grow a medicinal plant it would
be you plant a seed in a little jar and
in this just huge big bud appears right
there's no leaves there's no stem it's
just like w and that's essentially what
you know your mate there is is doing on
on a certain scale it's like s not
sacrificing but you're well yeah
compensating you know stem um elongation
and stuff like that for a more stocky
and again the plant's got a potential of
biomass as well people always forget
that they break it down into the
different components but like a metric
in a lot of other crop plants is is just
biomass what's the bio
you'll get it in the in the seed um you
know the listing tell you a biomass per
area you know tons per area whatever it
may be um that's not something we tend
to talk as much about um a little bit in
hemp the hemp world will do it um but we
tend to talk about in medicinal plants
we talk about dry weights and you know
things like that so but the plant the
point I'm trying to make is that it has
a genetic potential that's actually
often based on on biomass and not
necessarily the specific tissues within
that biomass um I've seen someone
recently someone recently published a
paper and they had because one of the
the biggest um missing components of the
the genetic side was we don't we don't
have really good yield markers we don't
have really good you know gene
expression markers for high yield um but
someone's recently just put some out so
I've not looked into that yet but
that'll be interesting to see how how
those correlate because again
I would imagine it be very variety
specific just given the variety of
different ways it can grow I would think
it would be hard to find that Master
regulator although again for all other
crops we tend to know it you know we
tend to know what's the biomass of that
is this and there's a range there and
you would be really disappointed if you
didn't hit that range um yeah but we
we're in the infancy with this plant in
terms of you know understanding and
because it's been it's been so cuz you
had to do license for so long it's been
so difficult to actually do a massive
work and have it well documented and Inc
comparable conditions and stuff like
that you know so it's like the biggest
citizen science project of all time in
some senses you know we've all just went
out and done our own thing for years and
now we're kind of able to come together
and share some of that which is pretty
cool um but I know in the States you
guys are fur way further ahead but I'm
still I'm still reving in the novelty of
having conversations like this you know
and and and being able to kind of like
you know talk about this openly and
having different levels of availability
in different places as well you know so
like sometimes experience
is always experience helps but sometimes
it's less relevant to a certain
background you know like I'm not going
to go in and tell your mate how to how
to cut his plants any better you know
when he's super super scug into that
croing to that extent so that's another
thing about it is like any plant you're
grown of any type just be humble and be
respectful of what it's doing and you
know don't try and don't try and
overtake the process just let it do its
thing just all you try and do is like in
my mind it's like wrapping it in Cotton
will you know you're just creating this
environment a little bubble for it to
thrive in um that that's all like actual
interaction with the plant is you know
sorry interference with the plant not
interaction interference with the plant
is is is the less the better in my my
opinion you know you mentioned bio M and
my next question kind of relates to that
bud density is what I want to get into
next another article you wrote you it
was something very interesting really
popped out at me you mentioned that
light schedule can impact Bud density
can you explain yeah there was um I
think there's two papers now and
Publications that show this but
essentially like so so for many many
years we just went under the the kind of
the metric of 18 hours um of light
during veg 12 hours during flow right
but I always like thought well why 12
hours like it seems like if it's just 12
hours that activates fling then that
seems awful close to the line to pick 12
hours right so actually it must be
higher than that and for what I can
gather if you averaged it out like when
is the actual flowering time initiated
if you averaged it out between you know
a lot of the varieties that we had data
for we found it was 13.5 hours right so
so most of them would be triggered into
flowering at and a half hours of light
not 12 right so what these studies did
was they we 10 they took some of the you
know some of the plants that actually
flowered under slightly longer days like
14 14 and a half hours so they did like
a a 14 um 10 schedule they did like a a
1212 then they did a 1014 schedule in
the opposite way and what they measured
was like you know how that changed the
morphology of the buds and essentially
what happened
was the shorter the
daytime the smaller and fatter the buds
were and the longer so but but it seemed
like 122 was kind of The Sweet Spot
believe it or not you know like again it
would be variety specific but what they
found was if you want to a good balance
between elongation and and fattening
then then you would You' probably hit
122 what's interesting is a couple of
buddies one of them shout out to Stuart
Maxwell up in up in Vancouver he done a
few interesting things and he would
would he would augment the time so we'd
use 1212 to initiate flowering then he'd
push it up to 13 and 1 half hours of
light for you know three or four weeks
to give it that extra
photosynthetic um you know activity then
it would dial it back down to finish it
um but what I've come to realize and one
of my personal tips is is to dial it all
the way down in the finishing weeks
after you've had your Boost week um you
know your big Bloom um onset when you
you get most of your mask coming through
after they can it so like in my in my
head fling follows this pattern if it's
10 if it's 10 we flowering for example
you have five weeks of oh yeah look at
this it's coming it's coming it's coming
and you have two or three weeks of just
boom batting and out like you're now
it's starting to gain some weight and
then that last few weeks doesn't look
like much is happening but what's
generally happening in my mind is is is
getting density right so if I follow
that pattern and apply it to what we
were talking about about you know
controlling the light to control the the
shape of the bud then what I tend to do
is in that after that boom phase that
two or three weeks of Boom phase between
5 and 8 I tend to dial it right down dog
with 10 hours late and what you see is
that finish um that that density there
at the end where is normally it finishes
on 1212 it just really comes through and
that goes you know there's evidence
there and the Publications to show that
that happens under that but rather than
do like a full cycle under one or the
other you know why not change it
throughout I actually like St I I really
like to stagger the transition as well
it's another little crop steering trick
as well if you go from 18 hours of light
straight into 12 hours of of like you
tend to have a little bit of couple of
days of the pl going who what's going on
you know figure this out and right okay
I'm away um if you if you if you can of
graduate it down um I find that the
plant tends to transition much smoother
and we get where we want to be a little
bit quicker um again
is that a scientific claim not really
it's it's just an observation thing and
whenever I do that and you can be quite
you can be quite extreme you can take
two two hours off every other day you
know but just do some kind of
incremental decrease towards 12 I prefer
to do it maybe over two weeks um and
just like slowly you know an hour or so
a day give or take some days you won't
do it doesn't really need to if you've
got a good programmable LED you can
automate it to go from this to that over
this amount of time which would be the
ideal way doing it because it just
mimics a natural thing because one of
the big things that we learned from this
plant is the the autoing phase is really
of the Fall you guys call it right the
fall phase of a plant's life is really
important especially to the finish of
this plant so in the fall we get less
daytime as well as well as dropping
temperature right but whenever we're
talking about getting color or getting a
nice finish we don't often talk about
the light we only talk about dropping
the temperature generally and given only
water for example so starve the plant a
little bit and you take away its
temperature well why would you not go
all the way and then reduce the light as
well because you know that that has an
effect on how it finishes um and my
experience tells me that I wouldn't not
do that let's put it that way that's
really interesting I think I'm going to
try adjusting the light schedule in the
future to kind of what you had mentioned
there gradual transition down it's
something I haven't really personally
experimented with much the only really
experimentation I've done with life
schedules is 11 hours on 13 hours off
but some people doing 10 hours on 14
hours off so I think I personally need
to go through and do some more
experimentation especially since you
mentioned that there is a a potential
impact on bud density when it comes to
messing with the light schedule so
that's pretty cool to hear yeah I mean
the the plant isn't entirely locked in
to that because we know that auto fling
exists right which kind of like you know
it does but again I find the same
applies if you still reduce the the
light time and give it a natural b um
onset of fall then you you tend to get
just got a better finish if you you get
a little Flex of color coming out you
know you drop the temperature reduce the
nutrient you give the the light down and
even even even the auto flowers tend to
you know stiffen up a we bit in terms of
they just feel a little bit more compact
at the end um but but we know that
that's we know that that path is being
sueded in some respects just by the life
cycle of the plant and an aut flower you
know um so yeah tricky to try to figure
all this out you know what about flower
never considered
that in this Theory but no it's it's
something that um because my
understanding the genetics is there's a
an awful lot of overlap there's very
rarely like one on one off switch you
know there's often way many different
stimuli will feed into a pathway so
there's multiple points within that
pathway that can be activated if you
know what I mean depending on the
stimuli so that's or the stimulus so
that's how the um that that's how you
know generally that's plants are they
basically this big mass of feedback look
they're really responsive actually they
have to be because they're stuck in the
ground right they can't run away from
their problems so so they have to have a
really good adaptive strategy for for
survival you know and I think the plant
that we're talking about is probably one
of the craziest in terms of its ability
to adapt um just just really far out
there you know super adaptable yeah I
mean if we can take something that's
been grown I mean Lane races are a good
example of that right grown in one
environment for so long and then we take
in transition and completely change up
the environment conditions and it adapts
you know it'll still adapt it'll still
grow and you'll still get to harvest so
super super adaptable let's get into the
flower stage i' like to know what tips
or advice do you have in regards to crap
steering in the flower stage yeah so I
kind of mentioned a bunch of them there
about the kind of changing the lights
and stuff like that the light schedul
but back to the light um Quality itself
again kind of Fairly standard now people
know this but you know increasing the
light sorry the red end of the spectrum
doing flow is important I like make sure
I have that 730 in there nanometers as
well because like I say I like I like
the mechanism to work as it was designed
and not necessarily to you know be maybe
hold them a plant back but again it's
not always possible a lot of the jobs
that I've had and the facilities have a
light that you know is limited to that
and that's what you're dealing with so
but again if if I get to choose whatever
I want to do then that's I make sure
that the light's capably going up that
far um although I was saying I was a
little bit kind of like you know ease
off with the feed and stuff like that um
if you're going to do it Now's the Time
to do it you know flowering um again not
not too harsh too early but by week
three you really want to be really
ramping that up um if if you're a
nutrient Sky you really want to be
starting to push it by the time you get
to week five really ramp it up now again
if you wanted to steer a specific
outcome over another then that's where I
would I would maybe change what you're
doing with the nutrients um I'll give
you an example of that let's say your
plant is is adapted
to no let's go other way your plant
produces a high level of medicinal
compounds but it's not specic it's not
particularly well adapted to cold
environment right so but you know that
the facility that's growing this is
going to get pretty cold at the end of
the season and you know what's one of
the things you can do to to help with
that I've found that the temperature
correlation between what a plant
optimally grows at is is very sorry it's
the temperature a plant optimally grows
at and what it can grow at is correlated
with the feed schedule so again if if
you're growing slightly colder you you
ramp everything back right and and the
opposite end of the scale is also true
if you want to really you know if you're
in a hotter environment you can actually
push it a bit more um within within
reason biochemistry and a plant operates
optimally somewhere between 20 and 30
degrees right so when whenever we're in
the lab and we're doing like maybe
taking a sample from a plant putting in
a Cell keep a dish and keeping it alive
usually we target like 28 Dees for that
um something like that so that gives you
an idea where the pl sorry I'm talking
about Celsius here and just just so your
your audience knows because I know you
you um you Americans like to use the
fahrenheit skill I'm not very good at
converting it but um I'm always talking
in Celsius apologize um in a hotter
environment they can take more nutrients
is what I found but the problem is you
need to kind of balance that with with
more water as well which is well you
just diluting your nutrient back to what
it was but just giving it overall more
you know like there's that balance some
plants will take more nutrients out than
others as you know like some some
varieties especially but I would say
like so you're trying to you're trying
to get this PL to be more tolerant to
the cold you dial back then you trains a
little bit and you you allow the the
growth rate to slow and you precondition
it that way so so you're basically you
high medicinal compound producing plant
it's not particularly you know good in
19 degrees celsus right per production
so what you do is you you you you grow
in normal conditions say 25 to 30
degrees Celsius apologize to your
viewers again for not using Fahrenheit
but um you maybe you can put a little
overd on this afterwards Chris correct
that um what you want to do is is is
grow it at the the temp the desired
temperature at the um a reduce nutrient
rate and then when you move it across
for example to to a lower uh temperature
you'll get away with you basically what
happens is all the growth will slow down
a little bit but the plant will be able
to with withstand that and still finish
to a decent level in that colder
environment so that's a little one of
those dials that again doesn't get spoke
about that much but because everybody is
again it's counterintuitive right it's
like oh you want more out the plant you
give it more nutrients it's not always
the case sometimes you actually want to
slow the plant down a little bit because
if it goes too fast it can't respond to
the stress and sometimes it has to sit
in the stress okay right now I'm
comfortable and now I can finish growing
so you don't want to be doing that
during production right you want you
want to precondition that and obviously
when I'm talking about taking plants and
moving on them I'm talking about
conditioning mothers and then taking
clones from there you can obviously do
it with with with vegetating clones as
well um and you can do both but the
basically preconditioning you can
actually do it with seeds as well Chris
you know like setting seed in certain
conditions will give you certain traits
and in that condition when the seeds
Sprout so so it's all about just that
you know I I guess the overarching theme
that keeps coming around here is is just
this idea of like pushing the plant's
ability to adapt but giving it time to
do it make sure it knows what's coming
before it comes and then you'll have a m
you'll have a much wider room for error
for when you want to do this new thing
like for example in the example I just
gave dropping get getting it to grow
well at 19 degrees CSUS um you know you
want to give as much Readiness for that
as possible you I've seen so many people
fail by taking clones that are grown
indoor only in in Canada or outdoor in
California you know and then they come
into a glass house in in Europe and they
wonder why it doesn't performed to the
same degree well that clone has not been
in any way conditioned maybe been
hardened but that's not quite the same
as as is you know what we're talking
about here when we're actually steering
the crop towards something um I guess
it's kind of like just changing the
traits changing the expression of those
genes but always limited by what those
genes can do at the same time you know
so much good information man this is
actually the first episode that we have
on crop steering dedicated crop steering
on this podcast and I think we've
touched upon it a little bit here and
there in episodes but nothing this
detailed and I'm so glad to have you on
here today because you have so much
experience in it so I appreciate you
coming on to the podcast today we're
going to wrap things up here can you
tell the listeners how they can find you
and what you have upcoming in the future
yeah so um I I still like to um write
some articles for seedman so you can
always find me through the seedman blog
I tend to do a couple articles a month
at least or or you know a bit more um
I've got a an in Instagram account
called the god star Paradox um I'm also
a musician I like a little bit of
ambient metal a little bit of electronic
stuff so you can go check me out on
there I've got some stuff on there I
tend to not much in the way of of
growing and and things like that on
there but I sometimes interact with
people on there but that's the best way
to do me is um the godar Paradox on
Instagram um I've got a Gary y's um
YouTube channel as well um yeah and
probably Through The The J cantes
network as well he's he's usually got
links to my stuff on on his site as well
awesome I'll definitely have a link to
Dr Yates down in the YouTube description
section below so you can easily navigate
to him and give him a follow shout out
to the patreon folks those have been
supporting appreciate you so much you
keep the lights on here in the studio so
thank you so much for your contributions
there I'm going to put on the screen
right now those folks in the producer
credit tier thank you thank you so much
once again if you want to join patreon
help support the podcast
patreon.com grow that'll get you there
and there are different tiers that you
can choose from and I'd love to know in
the comment section below what tips do
you have for crop steering there's so
many people here that tune into the
podcast that do crop steering what did
we miss what do you typically do let us
know down in the comments Dr Yates thank
you so much once again for coming on to
this podcast this has been awesome I've
learned so much and this is definitely
one that I'm going to have to replay
over and over again to grasp this
information so thank you so much and
hope you enjoy the rest of your day yeah
it's been a pleasure CH happy to come on
again there's a few other topics that we
discussed that we might get to we never
got to them so quite happy to more in
the future and and discuss it you've
been great and um your podcast I love
the work that you do so keep it up and
we appreciate you as much as as you
appreciate having us on so yeah all the
best and keep on growing thank you so
much if you want to see Dr Gates back on
this channel comment part two and uh
we'll see how many people we can get
that wants a part two and we'll probably
get you on here all right until next
time peace out everyone catch you in the
next episode