what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and i'm back with another video i have
the pulse monitor here with me some of
you may have this and also i have the
sensor push monitor here a couple of
them actually and i figured i would do a
video comparing the two so there have
been quite a few people that have hit me
up in the past a lot of you know that i
run the sensor push monitor i talk about
it a lot in many of my videos but some
people have been asking how does the
pulse compare to that one so that's
we're going to go over today the first
thing we'll talk about is the dimensions
weight then we'll get into what the
units actually measure bluetooth first
wi-fi we'll talk about some of the
features we'll get into the app and then
lastly conclusion
but first big thanks to happy hydro for
sponsoring this video happy hydro now
has complete grow tent kits and many of
the kits actually come with my beginner
girl book the kits consist of ac
infiniti grow tents an ac infinity
ventilation system your choice of
lighting whether it be spider farmer hlg
the green sunshine company or grower's
choice so home living soil nutrients
oscillating fans and more i will leave a
link to happy hydro grow tank kits down
in the description section below and you
can use coupon code mr grow it for a
discount on their products
so right off the bat you can see that
there are
definitely a big difference in size here
the sensor pushes 1.75 inches by 1.75
inches by 0.65 inches and the weight is
1.4 ounces the pulse is going to be
quite a bit bigger actually this
measures 4.5 inches by 2.5 inches by one
point one two five inches and the weight
is two point nine ounces you can't
actually hang both of these that's what
i do is i hang them at canopy level
there's a little hole here you can slide
i usually slide the light ratchet rope
through it tie it and then hang it down
you can do the same thing with this so
it'll be a little bit easier with this
this hole is a little bit small for
battery life the sensor push really has
this one beat it's going to take one of
those smaller
cr2477 batteries and that's gonna last
one to two years according to their
website the pulse is actually going to
take three double a batteries which is
gonna last you four months so a lot less
battery life however you can actually
plug in there is a spot you can actually
plug in and then run a line directly to
your wall outlet so you wouldn't have to
worry about batteries at all with the
pulse now what i'm just showing you here
is just a couple different models right
this is the the pulse one they also have
a pulse pro and then the sensor push has
three models they have the ht1 the ht.w
and
http.xw i think a fair comparison would
be with the ht.w
comparing with the pulse one there are
some features that are different which
we'll go over here in a minute but
that's kind of the closest i would say
so the sensorpush ht1 is their cheapest
model it's going to be at 49.99 current
price i kind of hate mentioning prices
sometimes at videos because they do
change the price so somebody might
comment say hey the price has changed
this information is wrong well yeah
expect the price to potentially change
right now the ht1 is a 49.99 this is hd1
right here it's the oldest model that
they have actually bought this one back
in 2017. so i've had it for many many
years still works only we've had to
change the battery i think once on this
one measures the temperature humidity
and i believe now they've changed it so
it can calculate vpd as well maybe
dewpoint as well but don't quote me on
that the next model up the ht.w that one
does temperature humidity vpd and dew
point and it's gonna be a little bit
more accurate when it comes to the
temperature and humidity plus or minus
two percent for relative humidity and
then plus or minus 0.2 degrees celsius
or plus or minus 0.36 fahrenheit the
ht.w is going to run you 64.99 it's a
little bit more expensive than the ht1
and then the
htp.xw measures temperature humidity has
vpd dew point and also barometer as well
so air pressure it's measuring current
price on that is 89.99 so of course a
little bit more expensive than the other
models and i believe the
htp.xw is a little more accurate as well
pulse one is 199. so 199. for the pulse
one it's going to measure the same thing
as the sensor push temperature humidity
vpd dew point as well as light intensity
so one additional thing that it measures
here it's not going to be as accurate as
the sensor push unfortunately so they're
reporting plus or minus three percent
for humidity plus or minus one percent
for temperature and then plus or minus
four percent for vpd sensor push did not
mention what their plus or minus was for
vpd so pretty big price difference there
in regards to the units but there's a
good reason for that and that's the
connectivity so the sensor push is
bluetooth only the bluetooth range on
this is 100 meters about 325 feet data
is collected at one minute intervals
also alert ranges can be set for
temperature humidity vpd dew points so
you can be alerted when there is a
problem when things are out of range you
get a push notification directly to your
phone or you can ask alexa which is new
to me i haven't hooked this up to alexa
yet there is a wi-fi adapter for this
it's called the sensorpush g1 wi-fi
gateway and that's gonna run a hundred
dollars so good comparison would be the
center push ht.w that's gonna run you
64.99 plus the wi-fi gateway which is
99.99 so you're looking at about 165
dollars for the sensor push with the
wi-fi capability and again comparing to
the pulse it's 199 total this already
has wi-fi built in you actually need
wi-fi in order to use this so for my
understanding there's no bluetooth on
this device at all for the sensor push
one mobile device can monitor an
unlimited number of sensors and one
sensor can be monitored by an unlimited
number of mobile devices for the pulse
unlimited number of sensors including
multiple locations and wi-fi networks
viewable on one dashboard i couldn't
find out how long the data is stored for
the pulse but for the sensor push 45
days of storage on the sensor and
unlimited in-app storage for unlimited
devices on their database one thing i
really like the sensor push is you can
actually extract the data to a csv file
so really you can put that into excel
google sheets
other programs like that and then you'll
be able to manipulate the data as you
wish i'm pretty sure you can't do that
with the pulse which is unfortunate i
know a lot of people do like to extract
the data and manipulate it to see
different trends and such okay now let's
take a look at the apps
first up is the sensorpush app you can
see right here i have one two three four
different devices loaded up here let's
just click on one of the devices we'll
do
2x4 canopy
you can see it takes a little bit to
load the data not too long
this is actually in my two foot by four
foot grow tent and i'm actually not
using this tent right now so you can see
significant changes in the temperature
and humidity as far as the craft is just
it's pretty big swings there is what i'm
trying to say but you can see a section
for temperature a section for relative
humidity a section for vpd as well gives
you a little summary at the bottom there
and then a chance to export the data as
a csv file like i mentioned before you
can see the data by the hour you can see
the data by the day by the week by the
month and even by the year as well then
in the settings you can set a high and
low limit for temperature relative
humidity barometric pressure dewpoint
and vpd so you can see for example i
have my relative humidity high set for
seventy percent and low set for forty
percent i don't have the alerts on if i
put the alerts on here i would get a
alert when it is out of range but right
now i'm not using a tent so i'm keeping
the alerts off down here on vpd you can
see i don't have a high or low limit set
but that's something i can easily add in
when i want there's also a spot for leaf
temperature offset which you can see
here and read here the explanation for
that that's pretty much the sensor push
app in a nutshell now let's go into the
pulse monitor app all right there we go
so i just have one pulse monitor you can
see that it looks like there's a battery
alert on there so i have a low battery
need to change that soon just a quick
review of the dashboard see the
temperature humidity
light vpd dew point pressure click in on
that you can see some more data you can
see a spectral analysis there's some
settings here change wifi settings vpd
leaf temperature offset you can
calibrate the unit you can also
calibrate on the sensor bush i just
didn't show that part usually there's a
graph here i'm not sure why the graph
isn't showing but usually you would see
a graph here see a lot of different
information alert settings it's
definitely a lot more extensive than the
sensorpush app you can do daytime
settings nighttime settings up here you
have a calendar that you can actually go
in and edit you can do different entries
for things that you did new events for
example there are also different
templates here that you can use to
manage settings across multiple devices
up just noticing now you actually can
export the data into csv just like
sensor push so i wasn't aware of that
that's awesome that they have that
because i know there's a lot of people
that really like to extract the data and
manipulate it so they can see different
trends and such and that's pretty much
the pulse app in a nutshell
so there's a quick comparison of the
pulse monitor versus a sensor push
monitor since the push monitor is going
to be significantly smaller than the
pulse monitor however the sensor push
only has a bluetooth enabled so you have
to actually buy a wi-fi adapter if you
want the wi-fi capability pulse monitor
already has wi-fi built into it both of
these measure temperature humidity vpd
dew point however with the pulse one
you're actually gonna get light
intensity as well accuracy sensor push
is gonna be a little bit more accurate
than the pulse monitor and then for the
actual app on your phone you're gonna
get more with the pulse app i personally
would like to see the sensorpush add-in
co2 monitoring pulse has another monitor
called the pulse pro it has co2 it also
has par measurements in ppfd so i think
the next step for sensorpush would be to
add the co2 and potentially add in ppfd
measurements as well i certainly didn't
go over all of the details for each of
these monitors in this video that would
make this video way too long just the
features that i thought were pretty
important for
monitoring your garden what features did
i miss that you think i should have
mentioned let me know down in the
comment section below which monitor do
you use to use the pulse to use the
sensor push or do you use a different
monitor let me know down in the comment
section below links to all the sensor
push models with the wi-fi gateway and
also the pulse one and pulse pro will be
down in the description section below if
i have coupon codes for you i will link
those down in the description section
below and yeah i'll leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]
you