hey everybody welcome back to my channel
for those of you that don't know me my
name is Chris aka Mr Grow it and you're
tuned into my garden talk Channel today
I have a q a video for you but I want to
make a quick announcement stash blend is
now released sash blend is a plan
additive that was developed by the from
the stash team and it has a whole bunch
of good stuff in it you can find out
more at stash blend.com all right let's
get into the episode
good day get a question my autoflowers
gorilla cookies are starting to show
white pistols when you recommend to
change nutrition so yeah Auto flour is
probably on the same light cycle
probably plan to be on the same light
cycle for the entire grow whether it be
18 6 20 0 24 0 whatever it may be you're
not really sure when to start feeding
those flower nutrients for me I
typically do it around 8 30. you know
what I mean I'll make that transition
day 30 40 if I'm a little bit late with
it but yeah that's usually when I'm
starting to see pistols and that's
usually when I'm transitioning over to
the flower nutrients I'm sure it can
vary from grower to grower you'll
probably hear a different answer from
different people depending on who you
ask I'm sure there's some people that go
four five six weeks in their using their
veg nudes then flip to their flowering
nudes you know they're just seeing that
transitional flower happening but for me
round day 30 40 is when I'm switching
over to the flower nutrients are there
any companies doing sales for Prime day
yeah shout out to Mars Hydro they're
actually sponsored entering this q a
episode a prime cell all month
apparently up to 25 percent off yeah
you've seen me use their lights in the
past let's click on this and see what
they got so they've got a bunch of
featured deals here FC series looks like
they have the fce series they've got
some grow tents yeah a whole bunch of
good things you can get and more looks
like they have their ts series as well
UV and I are bars so yeah check out
their Prime Day Sale I'll actually have
a link to it in the YouTube description
section below and you can use my
discount code Mr Grow it I'll get you an
additional percentage off what is good
ways of adding humidity temporarily to a
grow tent until you humidifier arrives
SO waiting on the humidifier huh man I
was in the same exact situation as you
quite some time ago and uh it's it's
funny though the creative things as you
can think of to do search online you'll
find a whole bunch of stuff but things
that I have done is the wet towel method
so I've taken a bunch of towels wetting
them like crazy and then hanging them in
the grow tent you know as far as how
much it helps it's obviously going to
depend on how much you're exhausting out
of the grow space if you're just
exhausting 24 7 you could easily just
rip that humidity right out but uh yeah
I'm at the common amount that people are
using will wet towels pudding like
containers that are filled with water
into your grow tent that kind of helps
but as far as how effective it'll be
really is dependent on kind of how much
you're exhausting out of there how wet
the towels are what you're you know
current humidity is as far as how much
will actually increase so there's lots
of variables on that one but those are a
couple things I could think of that off
top of my head what did I miss I know
there's some of you guys out there that
are doing that just that trying to add
in the humidity don't have a humidifier
there's no down in the comment section
below I asked this once before but do
you notice any smell from the cannon
troll if string if so during what stage
I'm actually going to be doing a full q
a video on the can of troll just really
do a q a live stream like this where I'm
just answering kind of troll questions
not sure want to have that scheduled so
definitely follow me on Twitch twitch.tv
slash Mr Grow it and then make sure
notifications are on and then once
notifications are on you can come in and
ask questions about the canadrill I will
answer this one here for you right now
of course almost immediately I
definitely did notice the smell
particularly when drying like I just put
two plants in there well I put one plant
in there filled everything up and this
was uh
six days ago now filled everything up
yeah it immediately starts to smell for
me you know what I mean like you have
the uh the drip pan on the back things
are dripping out and probably what's
happened is that's just volatizing a lot
of it's just volatizing coming into
there so definitely notice the smell my
girlfriend notices the smell that's when
it's most strong the strongest is during
the dry period Then when things are kind
of stable you don't really smell it as
much like for example I had the can of
troll kind of right next to my door and
outside my door there's a hallway and
the next next door over is my
girlfriend's office and she said she
smells it when she walks by that's it
just when she walks by she'll smell it
and it was really only during the dry
period now me I really I smell because
I'm sniffing for it you know whenever I
come into my office here and I have it
on other part of my office right next to
right behind me actually you can see it
and I'm drying and I do smell it but as
far as how strong I wouldn't say it's
like crazy strong to where like your
neighbors are going to be notified stuff
like that but uh like I mentioned if
you've got it next to a door into a
hallway way and you got people walking
by they'll probably sniff it out if they
know what the smell is of course or
they're just like
and then just keep moving past the door
as far as just storage though when I
just have stuff in stores it's not
actually drying I can't I can't really
tell during that time there's really
nothing dripping in the back drip pan
after the drying period anyways so but
yeah I have two plants drying in there
right now I let one dry for a few days
then I was able to kind of consolidate
it down into and then make room for
another plant that had smaller plant so
I got two plants in there right now and
things are going pretty good things have
always been pretty good so hands off I
love it I've come to really despise
trimming do you have any tips or know of
any devices to help expedite the process
one thing I'm looking to get my hands on
is a bowl trimmer now I know I know
there's a lot of controversy behind the
bowl trimmer seems like everybody that
has a bowl trimmer that I know really
enjoys it once they understand how to
start using it pigeons 420 for example
I'll give him a shout out he is somebody
who was skeptical about the bowl Tremor
ended up getting his hands on one and
just absolutely loves it and he gave
some good tips in regards to using it as
well like more larfier type bud when
you're putting it into that ball term he
says it doesn't work as well so it needs
to be kind of more dense and you kind of
get the hang of it you know it takes a
little bit to kind of get used to I
can't wait to get my hands on one to be
honest with you just to try it but there
are people on the other end that are
just like uh ripping off your trichomes
is destroying your buds so um yeah I
mean buy one at your own risk I guess
you could say if you do buy one you can
use code Mr Grow at 15. specifically the
AC Infinity one I think they have a I
want to say 16 inch and 19 inch I could
be wrong about that but yeah you get a
little discount with my discount code I
need to get my hands on one though
that's one thing that uh you know from
what pigeons was saying really speeds up
the process could you recommend a
cultivar that has a terp profile that
can be contained and in with the carbon
filter much of the wide Leaf cultivars
have a very strong odor that is not
scrubbed fully by filtration interesting
which carbon filter you're using that's
one thing I want to ask I also want to
ask what size growth space you're in and
what size carbon filter you have in that
grow space because that could certainly
impact it right airflow not all carbon
filters are created equal it's so hard
to you know verify which ones are going
to work better than others of course
maybe it's just a brand carbon filter
using maybe I don't know if using a
cheaper brand or kind of a more a brand
known for Quality could be the carbon
filter assuming it's not the carbon
filter well it must be I mean if it's
escaping any sort of smell something's
wrong now with the carbon filter because
I've grown a large variety of cultivars
and as long as the carbon filter is
hooked up properly then it's always been
working pretty good for me tricky
question I don't really know how else to
answer that to be honest with you
there's so much it's going to vary
whether or not it smells during during
the flowering period right higher more
terpenes are going to volatile right so
if you're lowering the temp you're not
going to have as many terpenes
volatizing so if you're worried about
smell that might be something you want
to do maybe run like a temp you know 75
78 degrees throughout the grow instead
of kind of going up into the low 80s you
know in theory you should have less
terpenes volatizing you should have less
smell but uh tough question yeah
interesting question wish I'd have been
a answer for you zero to one hundred
percent how far would you say you are
towards completing your book
65 yeah I've got uh I would say a
majority of the sections written you
know chapters written and um I'm
actually kind of going back and
scrubbing some of the first chapters
that I've written every day I'm just
writing trying to get this book going
things looking pretty good though you
know I'm uh kind of timeline I hate
saying timelines because uh you know if
I miss then all of a sudden you got that
those people reaching out to you and
like hey you've missed your timeline but
uh within the next two months I want to
completely September 1st I want to be on
to the next stages which is book design
obviously like the editing have send it
over to an Editor to review proofread
then it goes the actual design I'll
actually be collecting photos
photographies from you guys to see if
anybody wants to get their photography
featured in my book so keep an eye out
for that one on social I'll definitely
make just a ton of announcements I did
that last time and the submissions it
was so fun seeing all the submissions of
you guys and yeah I'm excited to see
some new photography that you guys
submit in but yeah about 65 I'd say so
far and I hope to have it a hundred
percent written and onto the whole
designing process and so on and so forth
come September you know early September
is what I'll say do you have any set
scale for weekly PPM or EC yes I do Josh
uh actually it's in my book which I'll
bust out right now you guys familiar
with this one or what there's a section
here for PPM I don't have EC in here
that's definitely going to be included
in the next revision I'll add like a
scale for EC but we flip to the PPM
section which is on page 68 of the book
General recommendation so some people
are going a little bit higher than
what's here some people will go on a
lower so after Sprout weeks the ceiling
stage week one vegetation some people
call it 100 to 250 PPM at a 500 we're
talking 500 scale PPM meter vegetation
stage wait weeks two to three 300 to 400
PPM vegetation wig weeks four and Beyond
typically from like 400 to 50 to 700 PPM
now if you're growing in a larger
container larger plant certainly you can
go higher than this right so these are
just general recommendations assuming
that you're growing like small to
medium-sized plants growing larger
plants you can definitely get away with
going higher flower stages one to four
750 950 PPM flower stage is five and
Beyond 1000 to 1600 PPM and then in here
actually one thing that a lot of people
used to do they don't do it much any
more is like reduce the PPM as much as
possible as you're getting close to
harvest so it says here two weeks prior
to harvest less than 100 PPM so this is
just if you are a flusher if you like to
flush if you want to go buy that method
some people will flush their plant
towards the end of the grow to try to
reduce the PPM as much as possible they
swear it brings better terpenes and
cannabinoids and better taste and all
that stuff but do that at your own risk
I feel like these days it's kind of an
outdated technique that not a lot of
people are doing that is something I
definitely want to clarify in the next
revision on my book what has been your
favorite cultivar to grow have you come
across any finicky ones yeah yeah I feel
like I've answered this question in a
past episode so I won't get too deep on
it but Queen Anne's Revenge by TGA
genetics formerly TGA genetics went to
sub cool seeds
think Miss Jill took over the Queen
Anne's Revenge that's definitely been
one of the favorite plants I've ever
grown beautiful plant I had magnesium
deficiency to begin it was real slight
easy to fix once I fix the magnesium
deficiency which I believe was late veg
early flour plant was healthy throughout
the rest of the grill I feel like it was
a real easy feeder dense buds top top to
bottom there was basically towards the
end when it's ready for Harvest it
changed colors covered in trichomes as
far as effects real narcotic effect
chill effect it's an entirely coach lock
side of things but uh definitely
narcotic effect that's the first thing I
think of when it comes to the actual
effects but yeah that's been my favorite
as far as finicky man Sour Diesel oh
historically you know yes people who
have who have grown the true Sour Diesel
and they'll tell you it's a challenge it
can be a challenge to grow that one mine
was very finicky very sensitive in
nutrients uh it would it did not come
out good at all I didn't even get a good
harvest from it you know what I mean so
yeah like I mentioned every time I talk
about Sour Diesel and kind of it's
difficulty or the difficulty that I have
I've had you definitely get a handful of
people that are like yep absolutely
that's how she is it's not easy so but
it can be fun you know it could be a fun
challenge what happened to Mr Canuck I
heard someone was trying to steal his
channel from them by registering a
business with the Mr Canuck title I
don't know what happened to him yeah he
hasn't uh been posting as much lately
anymore but he's got some fantastic
videos videos of you guys that don't
know who Mr Canuck is I mean just search
for him on YouTube just amazing
cinematography and he's coming up close
to a million subscribers he might be the
first one to actually reach a million
subscribers in the community that has
that plant that we all know and love
uh but I don't know what happened to him
yeah I actually uh I found that out
trademark search if you do a trademark
search for Mr Canucks grow you'll see
that it's not him that owns it and uh so
somebody did it I don't know if there's
been anything beyond that as far as uh
people like threatening him or trying to
steal his channel from him because of
that but yeah maybe he'll uh come back
and start making some more videos soon I
really enjoy his videos really enjoys
content I've known him for many many
years I mean we've been in contact since
I think 2016 if I remember correctly and
uh man he has just grown more and more
he's gotten better and better when it
comes to his filming editing and just
when you think he somebody can't get
better at that you see him and he does
so I miss him hope he comes back soon
ever ran 18-6 last 10 days of flower not
that in particular but I have tried out
the 24-0 self non-stop light for the
last 48 hours of the grow I don't
readily have access to testing here so
I'm not able to kind of test the
cannabinoid profile terpene profile so
on and so forth of the two differences
and kind of report back what the change
was that was there but yeah so just kind
of looking to see if there was a
difference I didn't really see much if
anything so um and I haven't done the 18
6 for the last 10 days like you
mentioned there have you done it let me
know let me know what your results were
is nicotine poisoning a real thing you
mean like tobacco mosaic virus because
that's uh that's certainly a real thing
nicotine poisoning on the plant are you
talking about like on humans yeah
tobacco mosaic virus I think that might
be what you're referring to yeah just
Google that and you can find out more
about it is there any tests that I
shouldn't be worried about or all pest
bad I would say there's pests that are
easier to manage than others one of the
ones that come to my mind right off the
bat is fungus gnats it's something I've
battled on and off but I feel like I am
able to easily get rid of and kill off
the population as needed you know you
just gonna have to have the practice and
know what to do several of the pests are
like really bad I mean there's some
pests where like you just can't recover
from it I mean we could sit here for the
next hour and go through pests I highly
recommend a podcast episode Garden talk
with Matthew Gates I don't remember what
episode it is just Google it I'll
actually search on YouTube Garden talk
Matthew Gates and great episode where we
talk about is it the top 10 pests and
how to battle them really really good
episode that guy has so much knowledge
in regards to it but uh yeah if you come
across fungus gnats I wouldn't be too
worried about it not sure what stage
what level you are how long you've been
growing for I know some people see
fungus gnats and they just start
panicking you know they think
everything's over and they gotta wipe
everything out that's just not the case
as long as you stay on top of it you
should be able to get rid of them pretty
easily and the way I like to do it
there's so many different ways to go
about it first of all yellow stickies to
identify it's not going to kill off the
populations but you can at least
identify and trap and kill some of the
ones that are active so yellow stickies
in every single pot is what I do I like
using the mammoth control which is their
their IPM product that they have and
that one uh I love using that thing to
knock up knock down populations and also
as a preventative as well that's been
one of the strongest things I've used
also Dr zymes is another fantastic
product that has helped out tremendously
for both preventing and for knocking
back some populations on some of those
pests so off top my head those are the
two main products that I can kind of
recommend and vouch for that I've used
and worked well but yeah kind of going
back to your question fungus gnats if
you do come across those I wouldn't be
overly worried about them also mosquito
bits is another main one that people use
that kind of helps with the larva it's
basically beneficial bacteria that helps
knock Back The larva population so look
into that as well and then diatomaceous
earth is something that uh is used by so
many people it's just having that in at
the top layer of the soil it's pretty
much like glass shards for those pests
and there is some controversy behind
diatomaceous earth and I'm not really
too ready to speak about it but there is
somebody who is concerned about their
effectiveness and there isn't really
studies on diatomaceous earth to knock
down fungus in that population in
particular so I won't get too deep into
that one maybe I'll maybe I'll invite
Matthew Gates on to speak about that but
I've been using it anyways I have some
so why not use it doesn't do harm it's
uh it's really silica is what that is
have you switched from Earth dust to
kiss Organics for reamending soil yes so
I stopped using our dust unfortunately
green Sunshine Company is no longer up
and running you know unfortunately that
business closed down yeah it's sad to
see them go you know very small company
I knew Dan personally he was actually on
my podcast we did several videos
together we had the electric sky ES1 80
and ES 300 very very popular I used them
for many many years and then the Earth
dust Amendment so unfortunately they're
no longer Earth dust is no longer being
made I actually reached out to him and
asked him about the manufacturing birth
dust and I've tried to bring it back and
uh doesn't look like it's feasible it
doesn't look like it's worth it to bring
it back is what kind of what I should
say so yeah I've been using kiss
Organics I use build a soil craft blend
for several years now I just just coming
up on completing a grow using kiss
Organics nutrient pack for those that
don't know it's a blend of organic
amendments and just top dressing you
know I did the initial amending of the
soil to begin and top dressing every 30
days plants would looked fantastic
throughout the entire Grill and um yeah
just harvested two plants talk about a
little bit earlier on the stream here
and I've got them in Canada troll right
now drying
thank you