coming up on Garden talk if you're
adding uh you know algae to the soil if
you're adding rocks in whatever you're
doing to the soil you can come back and
measure it two or three four weeks later
and see whether it's having an impact
increasing the biomass because if it is
you want to continue to do it but when
the plant seed germinates in new soil it
brings with it the kinds of bacteria
that are beneficial to that particular
plant start out knowing what the soil
food web is it's going to be really easy
to start gardening if you go chemical
you've got to figure out what those
chemicals do how much to use how much to
measure when to use them when not to use
them it really makes gardening work and
it's not supposed to be work it's
supposed to be a wonderful Hobby
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 85. in this
episode I interviewed Jeff lowenfels
Jeff is the author of The award-winning
teaming with series of books teaming
with microbes teeming with nutrients
teeming with fungi and the brand new
teeming with bacteria in this episode he
talks about the soil food web microbes
and several other things that relate to
organic gardening thanks to all of you
who support this podcast through patreon
if you'd like to support you could do so
by going to patreon.com Mr grellit
before we get into it I want to
acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible
thanks to vivosun for sponsoring this
episode vivosun has been one of the top
manufacturers of horticulture equipment
for over 10 years as some of you have
seen in my grow videos I have grown
successfully using their grow tents
their inline fans LED grow lights hid
grow lights and numerous accessories
vivosung continues to create really
interesting technology that makes home
gardening easier check out their website
at vivosun.com I will provide a link in
the YouTube description section below AC
Infinity is sponsoring this episode they
have two different series LED grow
lights the ion board and the ion grid
the ion board fixtures are board style
and use Samsung lm301b diodes while the
ion grid series has an open Center
design and uses Samsung LM 301h diodes
I'll have a link in the description
section below so you can learn more
about these grow lights and you can use
discount code Mr Grow it if you're
buying off their website
acinfinity.com that discount code works
for all AC Infinity items or discount
code Mr Grow at 15 if you're buying off
Amazon
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with Jeff
lowenfels how you doing today great
couldn't be better I'm excited to have
you on you are a well-known author
mostly known for your incredible teaming
with series you release teaming with
micros back in 2010 which I actually
have right here so awesome awesome book
I love it teamed with nutrients in 2013
team of the fungi in 2017. you actually
put out a auto flowering book as well in
2019 and then brand new just released
now available teaming with bacteria here
in 2022. I just ordered that today
actually super excited for that one I
can't wait to start reading it yeah me
too
no it's I I've obviously read it but uh
it really messed me up because I used to
have a Trilogy so I call myself lord of
the roots and now it's what's known as a
quadrilogy uh actually a word quadrilogy
uh four books on the same basic subject
that's what it means uh and so it's it's
it's pretty exciting I I can't wait for
people to get into this new book because
it really is a major change to the soil
food web no I can't wait yeah I'm super
excited let's talk about today's episode
I'd like to get into microbes and I want
to start with the basics of the soil
food web and then get a bit deeper into
things but first before we do that what
I like to do with all guests is an
introduction can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening well uh I'm 73 years old maybe
70 yeah maybe 74. uh I started gardening
when I was about six months old in a
little basket my father used to bring me
out to his his gigantic Garden he was a
frustrated uh New York City worker who
lived out in the country and he would
come home and he would garden and if you
wanted to be around my dad you gardened
uh and so I learned at an early age
unfortunately he was not organic until
oh I would say I was about 15 so I
learned as a chemical head and then was
exposed to organic gardening which you
had just started actually back then
believe it or not and uh I've been
gardening ever since and I've been
organic basically ever since with one
small exception a chemical that is very
well known a very well known fertilizer
the guy that the guy that it was in
charge and then sort of invented the
company uh and it ends in Gro
uh worked for my dad and my grandfather
and put my picture on a margarine
package they were in the butter business
and so he he made me happy boy margarine
you can Google that and find my picture
um but because of our friendship with
him we would be organic except
occasionally we'd use that product I've
learned since that that product is not
good for the soil food web and that
probably gives us a good jump off point
to talk about what the soil food web is
yeah absolutely what is the soil food
web and why should gardeners care about
it okay well everybody I think is a
familiar with what's known as a food
chain you know where the little guy gets
eaten by the bigger guy who gets eaten
by the bigger guy well there are all
these chains down in the soil of various
organisms and every now and then
something on one of the chains looks up
or looks down and sees a different chain
and says hey I can I can eat that guy
and so they connect These Chains get
connected together and they form a web
it's basically a description of who eats
whom in the soil now normally we would
leave it there but we're gardeners and
so we grow vegetables and we grow
flowers we grow all sorts of terrific
plants and so so from our perspective
the soil food web also includes the
plant and the plant is in charge it
takes photosynthetic energy up to 50
percent of it and it creates these
things that drip out of the root Zone
that attract bacteria and uh uh fungi
and they're attracting the bacteria and
fungi because the bacteria and fungi
need the carbon that's in these exudates
you're actually dating right now sweat
uh and that sweat actually attracts
bacteria uh and fungi uh uh but in the
soil it attracts the bacteria and fungi
they're very happy living right by the
root Zone in what's known as the
rhizosphere that little area right
around the root uh and and they in turn
attract the things that eat them
protozoa which we all studied in high
school amoebas and parameciums if people
think back to 10th grade they may
remember that from biology class uh and
and uh nematodes which are a true
microscopic worm they're hair size uh
and they eat the bacteria and the fungi
because they need carbon too and so they
take the carbon out of the bacteria and
fungi uh and the excess is pooped out
for one of a better word and it's
nutrients in plant usable form
particularly all important nitrogen and
this is moved into the plant and that is
how the plant feeds itself now notice I
say the plant feeds itself the plant is
in control and if it needs a different
kind of food if it needs to protect
itself a different way it can attract
different populations of bacteria and
fungi to do what the plant needs it to
do the plant is in control not me and
you the gardeners it's the plant that's
in control so that's that's the basic
soil food web system but there have been
over the years three things I'm going to
say that have added to that soil food
web picture the first is known as
rhizobia bacteria you and I know that as
the as stuff that we roll close you know
that we roll legumes in uh and it forms
uh when the root hairs form uh they curl
around a bacteria that's attracted to
the plant by the plant uh which gives
that bacteria a little a little space
where oxygen can be limited and it can
fix nitrogen feed the plant feed the
soil so that's that's the second part of
the soil food web the third part of the
soil food web which I covered in in in
the book in 2017 I guess uh teeming with
fungi are are the fungi that associate
with the roots and form a symbiotic
relationship mycorrhizal fungi and they
take these nutrients from the soil and
move them right into the plants so we've
got basically two things that are moving
nutrients into the plant this rhizobia
uh although more of it comes when it
dies uh and these these mycorrhizal
function okay now the the fourth book
teeming with bacteria is about what are
known as endophytic bacteria some of
those bacteria that are attracted by the
exudates that the plant is producing as
a result of photosynthetic synthetic
energy that it's using some of those
bacteria are tricked by the plant to
back into the very tips cells the
meristem cells in the root and they're
they're tricked to back into that cell
they go through the cell wall but they
don't go into you know the the membraned
cytoplasm section of the cell so if you
would imagine I always use the tofu
container that you see at your
Supermarket the outer white part that
plastic that's the cell wall
of the root meristem cell the tofu in
the inside is all of the goodies that
are inside the cell the you know all the
things that that make enzymes and do all
the all the organelles but around that
tofu it's floating in this water that's
known in in cellular talk as the
periplasmic space and that's where these
bacteria end up and they get in there
and the plants sprays them with a
special super oxygenated uh uh chemical
molecules and they strip off
the cell wall of the bacteria and absorb
that internally and then they don't have
a cell wall they begin to move around
the that little liquid section in the
tofu container uh and as they do they
don't have any cell wall anymore they
multiply bacteria multiply every 20
seconds I mean every 20 minutes now they
don't have a cell wall so it's probably
even quicker and as they multiply
they produce a nitrate that they spray
at the plant to stop it
from causing it to Decay and and that
turns into nitrates which the plant
absorbs now these bacteria circulating
around the plant is circulating these
bacteria and they're multiplying inside
the plant roots mirrors themselves and
they're also producing ethylene which
causes the root to stretch out the cell
begins to stretch out that's what
ethylene does inside a cell
when they get too plentiful they back up
against the cell wall producing ethylene
it's not being circulated anymore it's
being produced in one spot they create a
little tube to form in the in the cell
wall and outgrows a road hair and the
bacteria are thrown into that root hair
and they're blown out of that root here
and there are five or six explosions as
the root hair grows
throwing these bacteria back out into
the soil where they regrow their cell
walls re-nutrify themselves and then a
couple three or four days later go back
into a new mirror stem cell to to do the
same thing so what we've got is the
plant
sort of farming in the first instance
it's it's it's putting an exudate out
there it's attracting bacteria it's
detracting and it's and it and it Farms
those guys now we've got a situation
where the plant is bringing them into
the barn shearing Off the Wall taking a
couple of you know lamb chops and then
putting these guys back out into the
pasture so they're ranching so we've got
plants farming and ranching that latter
part is known as I pronounce it the
rhizophagy cycle rhizo meaning root
remember rhizosphere that area right
around the root and fagi which means eat
so it's like root eating it got that
name because the discoverer in Australia
in 2010 so it's brand new that's why you
probably haven't heard about it uh
literally thought that the cell was
opening up and bringing in the the
bacteria that not happening now and
there's a gentleman named Dr James White
at Rutgers University who is really the
guru of this stuff now uh and it's
really quite something so we've got Dr
Elaine Ingham uh you know with the
original soil food web and all those
good you know the grease and the
mycorrasal funds and all of a sudden
we've got this new thing that results
from the ability to be able to see uh
using different kind of microscopy and
different kinds of testing to to ensure
that what's going on is what we think is
going on so
that was a mouthful wasn't it that's
absolutely fascinating so much good
information there I do want to back up
to the rhizo sphere you mentioned that
pretty briefly and from my understanding
the rhizosphere is a very very small
area we're talking one to three
millimeters that's directly outside the
root Zone and that's really that's where
the cookies and cakes with Dr Landing
hand talks about are in that area and
then that's where the actual exchange is
happening with the bacteria and I've got
some pictures of that by the way in in
teaming with bacteria phenomenal
pictures of of these extra dates
attracting bacteria in that little in
that little Zone there it's really
really phenomenal oh that's so cool so
so the pH of the rhizosphere versus in
the medium so a lot of folks the
gardening they will do a runoff test to
check the pH or they'll do a slurry test
or they'll use like the blue lab probe
that you can stick right into the medium
and get an idea of what pH is however
from my understanding the pH in the
rhizosphere can be drastically different
can you talk to us about that a little
bit yeah of course it can uh and really
it's the only pH that that counts if
you're an organic Gardener uh you don't
care what the pH is up on the surface
there no roots there and you know
nothing nothing's being absorbed there
and incidentally when I use that word
absorb
root hairs when I learned and when you
learned we always thought the purpose of
a root here was not to put bacteria out
into the soil which turns out to be
their real purpose but to absorb
nutrients which they do but I think they
absorb the nutrients as the root grows
you know the the older hairs are there
and uh you know they're not I don't
think they're absorbing nutrients as
they're as they're blowing up uh and
again the pictures in the book are
phenomenal literally you see these
bacteria
pushed into this tube that is the root
here the root hair is part of that
original cell and
they're blown out in it's just
absolutely amazing uh
yeah but but it's the you know it's the
pH May matter to them out there but you
and I as as gardeners taking care of
plants it's the ph and that rises fear
that we really care about uh and it's
caused by all the metabolites and the
extradates and and whatnot that are
produced you know we we don't recognize
how big these populations of microbes
are bacteria holy crow I always
encourage people I didn't include the
picture in the book because it cost 400
but I always encourage people to to look
up on the web uh head of a pin bacteria
and then go to images and there's
several pictures of bacteria on the head
when we think of bacteria you know we're
not we're not thinking about the
unbelievable numbers that are there well
they're producing stuff all the time
that impacts the quality of the soil uh
slime which creates soil structure and
sticks things together uh and and and
the pH
uh it's really really all happening at
this little TV level uh and and we don't
know about it as gardeners because we
can't really see it so would you say
measuring the pH of the runoff or doing
a slurry test is is pointless or not
useful to do because of the ph and the
rhizosphere being the only thing that
really matters I've never had any real
use for it although it's it's it's nice
to know what the pH is in general I mean
if you if you take your pH
someplace in the root Zone not
necessarily A rhizosphere you know and
it's way out of whack you know there
there there's a need for a fix there
um because if it's not impacting the
bacteria and the fungi and the nematodes
and the protozoa are right there and the
rhizosphere it's impacting other
microbes that are in the soil food web
that are outside of the rhizosphere so
uh yeah I mean they're not they're not
particularly a waste what I like is it
and I have to reveal that I'm an advisor
to the company is something called a
microbiometer uh an invention that that
enables you for five bucks and ten
minutes to test the microbiomass of your
soil which correlates to nutrients and
it also has built in now a pH reading uh
and so you can sort of correlate some of
this stuff together it's it's really
quite an invention you can find it at
www.microbiometer
microbiometer.com uh it's it's really
quite quite useful because it tells you
whether what you're doing is teaming
with microbes so yeah I was going to ask
you about the microbiometer so what
would you do with that information if
you were to get a result and the result
is correct me if I'm wrong I'm not too
familiar with it it gives you a bacteria
to fungi ratio and then you can kind of
make adjustments from there so how would
somebody go about taking the reading and
then making adjustments in the garden
well it also gives you a number so so
initially it was just the number and
then the company added fungal bacteria
because it's so important and the reason
why it's important is because fungal
dominated soils versus bacteria
dominated soils are produced two
different kinds of nitrogen and so
things that are in the ground for less
than a year that would be vegetables
annuals uh you know row crop kind of
things
they like they like the nitrate that
bacteria produce when they bring break
down and Decay organic material whereas
trees and shrubs they like the stuff
that fungi break down and so you want to
try to get a ratio that's
appropriate for your particular kind of
plant and that's a real gross
oversimplification
um you you need both in in the system
but
um
the number tells you
a starting point and then you take a
test later on if the number is high
enough you you know right away that your
soils are good if the number is low or
and or changes based upon what you're
doing if you're adding uh you know algae
to the soil if you're adding rocks in
whatever you're doing to the soil you
can come back and measure it two or
three four weeks later and see whether
it's having an impact increasing the
biomass because if it is you want to
continue to do it got it okay you
mentioned algae I want to actually talk
about that that's it it's really
interesting because a lot of people see
algae in their Garden they think it's a
bad thing they think they need to start
eradicating the algae they need much of
changes in the garden but after reading
your book team with microbes you have a
section in there for algae and it's
super interesting can you talk to us
about algae yeah I'm trying to remember
I I was going to say to you that was the
one thing I left out of TV with microbes
I you know I wrote the book in 2000 six
originally what you have is the revised
Edition
um
uh and incidentally on page 47 I think
of the of the first edition of either
the revised Edition or the regular as
well as the audio uh I reverse the
definition of pH
is low when you have lots of uh hydrogen
ions and fungi tend to produce a lower
pH bacteria tend to produce a higher pH
now I forgot your question oh algae so
algae algae is has a couple of really
kind of neat properties it helps in
forming soil structure uh and it's a
it's a uh organic uh food for microbes
and so you know it it has a lot of
purposes and of course it's
photosynthetic
um and any and so it can be adding to
the soil in that regard it's it's and
and you're right people don't understand
it's in the soil it's in deserts you
know we tend to think algae algae that's
that's Pond scum uh it's you know it's
not in soil it's not a desert with algae
yeah they have these little pads of PODS
of algae and stuff it's it's interesting
stuff uh I you know I don't encourage
people to go out and add algae to their
Garden but you can uh and you surely
could add it to your compost pile uh uh
that's probably the best place to add
stuff is your compost pile and then add
compost uh to your to your plants uh and
the fall incidentally is in areas where
you plant in the spring the fall is the
time to make sure that you've got a
couple of inches of compost over your
soils so that you are you are working
the process and feeding the soils and
these microbes are working their way
down into the soil uh and into the root
Zone during the fall and winter so that
by Spring you've got some fertility back
in your soil
which is which is important for
gardeners if I could just add one other
thing because we really
obey the law of return what falls down
from a tree for example is supposed to
those leaves are supposed to Decay they
contain all the nutrients that the
plants sucked up out of the soil and
they Decay and go back into the soil
again and feed the plant we're Farmers
we're gardeners we're Growers we remove
things from the system we violate the
law of return and it's important to make
sure that you're
adding stuff back into the system in a
timely basis so that you don't have to
resort to chemicals period good point
one thing about algae that I wanted to
bring up I actually have a quote here
from your book and I don't think a lot
of people know this so that's why I want
to read it here is you put quote the
cell walls of diatoms which algae are
composed of silica covered with an
organic skin that decays and disappears
after the organism dies leaving behind
in huge numbers the silica skeletons
that make up diatomaceous earth
so algae once it's dying off it's
leaving behind silica well it's a kind
of algae I mean there are lots of
different kinds of algae but yes uh and
not not all of it does but but certainly
that does and and
you know that diatomaceous earth if you
ever get a chance to look in the look at
that stuff under a microscope it's
fascinating it has all these poor spaces
and uh uh you know it's just it's
spectacular condominium and provides a
little bit of food and substance and
drainage and storage it's it's of water
it's really amazing stuff yeah a lot of
people use it as use like a preventative
or to battle fungus gnats you know they
keep it in there and it helps tackle
that population but correct me if I'm
wrong that diatomaceous earth that's not
really in a usable form that the plant
can uptake right it needs to be broken
down by microbes in order to be in what
solicit acid or orthosolic acid in order
for the plant to uptake well yeah it has
to be it has to go in to the ionic form
in order for it to be taken up by the
plants uh teeming with nutrients the
second book I wrote the first book
really was was designed to explain the
soil food web as we knew it at the time
this is how food gets to the plant and
it occurred to me one day after I wrote
the book that I had no idea how food
gets inside the plant and then once it's
inside what's it doing there and so
teeming with nutrients is about that
particular subject and and and one of
the take homes is the microbes in the
soil food web system break down the
nutrients into the proper ionic form so
that they can get through that cell
membrane which is again going back to my
tofu container which is you know holding
all of that tofu together in that little
tofu block and that membrane has little
uh uh proteins in it that act as tunnels
and there are various different ways
that individual uh eye ions nutrient
ions can move through and each tunnel is
specific for the one kind of ion which
is really mind-blowing when you think of
something like you know Boron just a
teeny little bits using they the plant
has to make that protein and insert it
into the membrane in order to be ah it's
just it's gonna make we we think plants
are stupid and dumb and they are
unbelievable microcosms of of of the of
Earth and what goes on in Earth they're
phenomenal and we think we know a lot
about plants and soil biology but we
probably know a fraction of what's
actually out there right oh well I can
tell you I mean I would never have told
you that I would be writing a book on
teeming with bacteria I mean it just
wasn't even in the realm even three
years ago uh yeah and now it's it's at
the point where uh we've learned so much
for example uh uh certain plants have
trichomes okay tomatoes have trichomes
as a result of studying rhizophage
we now know that what's happening inside
trichomes is nitrogen fixation by
bacteria and you get the same kind of
reaction you don't you don't necessarily
get the stripping and the but you get
this you get multiplication uh you get
you get different chemicals being
produced some of which are very wanted
chemicals uh to to lower the oxygen
level so that this fixation can take
place those little we now know what's
going on in those factories which we
didn't know before so when you when you
take your tomato plant you know and you
you that smell comes from rubbing those
trichomes that's probably some kind of a
metabolite coming from bacteria that are
in those trichomes as you crush them
with a with your hand unbelievable stuff
and uh we haven't even gotten into the
other endophytic bacteria because some
of these bacteria go in and then they're
ejected out but some of these bacteria
stay inside the plant and move
throughout the plant and do a number of
things that benefit the plant
first of all as they go into the plant
and they cause the plant to spray this
what's known as Ro onto the bacteria to
strip those walls the plant goes oh wait
a minute I better strengthen my own cell
wall or I'm going to be stripping my
cell walls by mistake and so it
increases its strength it's better able
to handle stress as a result of the
bacteria Invasion then these bacteria
produce phytohormones gibberellic acid
auxins all the things the ethylene all
the things that you want to have a good
healthy plant these guys are inside the
plant producing them and then it gets
even Wilder there's a philosphere around
the leaves which is like the rhizosphere
and then there's the area around the
flower well the bacteria get into that
area and they get trapped into the seed
coat and so when the plant seed
germinates in new soil it brings with it
the kinds of bacteria that are
beneficial to that particular plant
whoa and over the past five or ten years
farmers in particular and in the book I
hope we're going to start getting more
gardeners and Growers uh have been using
various different kinds of bacteria to
to fix nitrogen inside the plant and to
do all sorts of really cool things for
the plant to help it be stronger and
better uh these These are known as
endophytic bacteria
one that uh you know these medicinal
Growers uses is uh azosperidium it can
be purchased it's in a Spore form it has
a fairly long shelf life but there's a
mix of five or six bacteria that people
can use
to get benefits out of their plans and
and depending on what the plant is
different bacteria impact the impact the
plant different ways so there's a
difference for some plants when you use
vermicompost versus using thermal
compost because there's a different
bacterial base in either one of those
whoa so you know I I don't want to
overwhelm people with all of this
information and I promise you if you
pick up teaming with microbes and read
it and don't understand what I'm talking
about I'll buy that book back from you
three times the price now nobody's ever
taken me up because and it's not it's
not me it's the subject matter
once you have the vocabulary and
understand the system and it really is
just the little guy getting eaten by a
briefer guy you need by a breather guy
and one of those populations doing in
there before they get eaten uh it's
really simple stuff and really easy to
understand you will finish the book and
you will never Garden the same again you
can't incredible yeah definitely mind
blown off of a lot of that stuff the
endophytic bacteria also called
endophytes which is what A mycorrhizal
fungi is by the way it's an endophyte
um you mentioned that it can be
purchased is the application rate is it
something that's sprayed onto the plant
as like a foiler or is it actually a
soil drench or a drench the ones I've
seen are drenches but I'm sure there's
sprays but this has lots of implications
for people who are growing plants I mean
if the plant is bringing to the soil the
bacteria that it needs
well doesn't that mean maybe we should
be reusing our soil not throwing it away
because it's full of bacteria that we
need now we've got to make sure that the
law of return
has been taken care of but why do people
throw away soil that's the craziest
thing I ever heard of even pulling up a
tomato plant out of a pot doesn't make
any sense to me you cut the plant you
plant right there leave the roots where
they are they form channels that have
organic material that decay they have
the right bacteria right there in the
rhizosphere and the roots of the new
plant will grow down into those little
tubes uh and benefit from all of this
stuff I mean there's so much we can
learn by just listening to the plant and
unfortunately we have to listen with
microscopes and and we have to have
people like James White and and Elaine
Ingham uh you know do this stuff I don't
invent this stuff all I do is report it
uh and and my hats off to these people
who have really uh I think changed the
tenor of gardening when I started
gardening with my with my dad bacteria
Syria that was bad fungi that was bad we
sterilized soil no I mean you know we we
know Growers that sterilize seeds today
no and if you start seeds you know your
tomato seeds in a you know in a paper
towel situation
you don't just take the little new
seedling and put it in the soil because
there are bacteria that jumped off that
seed that are in the paper towel bury
the paper towel too uh so we start to
think more logically what is the plant
doing and how can we help the plant do
that as opposed to using chemicals which
we haven't really talked about when you
use chemicals there are now proven
studies that using chemicals reduces the
bacteria and the bacterial activity when
you use Organics you increase that well
that's all I need to know uh I mean you
know in the book at the time in 2006
when teaming with micros was written you
know basically the discussion was that
some of these chemicals killed the
bacteria uh later on in the revised
Edition it was some kill uh some
increased populations and changed the
ratio of the populations well that's not
what the plant wants either the plant is
in control you you put down XYZ
fertilizer and all of a sudden you get a
lot more XYZ bacteria than you than you
necessarily want so the natural system
works it's always worked no one
fertilizes the forest that you go and
spend time in no one fertilizes the
Redwoods I like to say uh you know
nobody put the the the fertilizers down
there and spray them with herbicides and
root chemicals
they did it themselves because they use
the microbial system it works it's the
basis of regenerative gardening it's the
you know it's the basis of no-till this
is where you want to start folks if you
don't know anything about what I'm
talking about here and if you know about
some of it already you want to
continually use the internet to
continually update the information
because we're learning more and more all
the time you mentioned throwing away
soils and I think the reason why a lot
of people do that is because they are
using chemicals right and they're
worried about the balance of ions being
off balance you know if you have an
excess of some cations it's going to
lock out it's going to prevent the
uptake of other cations for example
right so if yeah the gross pH too same
thing I mean if you have a you know
really bad pH in oil in the soil it's
going to lock up a lot of the stuff sure
so for the folks that are using
chemicals and switching over to organic
you're saying they could probably rehab
that soil that they use chemicals in how
would you go about doing that I thought
in a compost pile compost I mean to me
that's the best way uh you throw it in a
compost pile you let the compost uh
microbes take care of the situation and
it you know it definitely works there's
no question about it
um
you know I I don't want to leave the
subject without mentioning that you can
use too much organic material as well uh
so so this time of year I always tell I
write a garden column I always tell my
readers you know an inch or two of
compost that's it
you know we don't plant we don't do
raised beds and compost it has it has
you know it's got too much phosphorus in
it uh phosphates uh and a lot of them
are locked up of course but it changes
the whole tenor of the soil so just you
know a little bit the plant will take
what it needs but you don't want to
overdo it all right what is the doctor
at least the Goldilocks rule uh and and
uh now I use compost tea so there are a
lot of people that just simply say
there's no science behind it I to me
I've always had great success I've
turned my lawn green uh using compost
tea so
maybe it's the tenor of the compost I
don't know but if you don't like the
idea compost tea use compost no question
yeah I think the the point of the
compost tea would be to multiply the
microbes in that tea right faster than
you would with just adding compost in
right right right uh and and yeah you're
multiplying it whereas you can make a
leachate by taking the compost you know
putting it into a bag and squeezing it
in in a you know bucket of Fairly of
nice warm water uh and you'll get
microbes from the compost there but they
just won't multiply so you have to feed
them and aerate them to get the
multiplication but again it's very it's
very hard to find great scientific
studies to say it works and yet what I
do when I do my side by side with
cilantro and different things holy crap
I haven't used you know I mean it's it
works for me I don't know what to say I
don't know what to say maybe it's just
my imagination
now with composting I just started
vermicomposting last year and from my
understanding there can be bad bacteria
in there as well so you have to kind of
worry about that making sure you're
composting correctly can you talk to us
about like good bacteria versus bad
bacteria and how to kind of avoid the
bad bacteria yeah well you know you
you're a little let's take about let's
talk about Verma composting I mean the
there's no thermal activity here this
stuff is going through the worm and the
worm is cleaning the stuff up uh if you
if you take the stuff when it's too
young you know you'll still have some of
the castings won't have been uh you know
they won't be the way you want them uh
Verma cast I always let my stuff go for
about six months Then I then I use it uh
thermal compost is is a different thing
the it's the Heat and the cycling that
takes care of the bad guys and uh you
know if it goes anaerobic and stays
anaerobic if you don't turn it the right
way you can have pockets of anaerobic
anaerobic stuff uh depending on what
you're using as as your base material
you know if you're going going around
the neighborhood and picking up black
bags of leaves that people leave in the
curb in the fall uh without checking to
make sure that they don't have a dog uh
you know you may be putting manure in
there a lot of people use fish guts and
different kinds of things you got to
make sure that it's composted and and
there are studies that indicate that
many many yard composters don't actually
thoroughly compost their compost and so
they may end up with different things on
it that they don't want
and anaerobic bacteria
is what E coli is you know the bad guys
tend to be anaerobic and so you want to
make sure that you're turning it that
it's getting to the heat that all parts
of it are being turned and get to the
Heat
and you want to make sure uh that your
inputs are known I don't like to use
horse manure for example it's got
tetracycline in it I don't want that
tetracycline any possibility that any
would be left
um yeah so you just have to pay
attention
or you just pile it up and leave it
there for a couple of years and you'll
have some great compost
the easy way right yeah what are your
thoughts on bokashi composting yeah it's
all great you know I mean it it's all
great you got to take you know you get
the lead shape from the bokachi uh but
you got to take the stuff and put it in
a pile at some point in time anyway uh
to me uh to finish the job
um you know Korean natural Farm all that
stuff it's all good uh you know those
tend to be uh anaerobic uh but they use
lactic acid and the same stuff that's in
yogurt and
um yeah they're all good it's all
microbes we're teaming you know some
people team differently than others okay
and then for the earthworms I want to
get a little bit deeper into that
specifically for firmer composting or
even people just having worms in their
bed can you talk to us about the
earthworms is there a specific type that
they should use you know we've got red
wigglers African nightclaus European
night crawlers there's a variety that
can be used right right I I always use
the red wigglers uh what we what we're
worried about now is that new worm
that's beginning to pop up all over the
place it's uh that little band that's
around it is is is different than the
earthworm uh or earthworms that we're
used to uh these guys move like crazy uh
and they're very destructive to the duff
layer we've already got a problem with
fishermen who go fishing with even red
wigglers uh you know they're in Michigan
and they don't catch anything because
they don't live where I live in Alaska
which has got all the great fishing and
so they throw their fishing worms out at
the end of the day as they're going back
to their car and those worms multiply
and they eat the duff uh and and then
they mess up the mycorrhizal symbiosis
uh and we end up uh you know with some
serious problems so you got to be
careful what you use to me I use
vermicompost in a Verma compost bin I'm
not a big one on throwing worms around
um they'll come if your soil is good uh
if you live in an area that has worms
and I think most people in the in the
United States do live in an area that
has worms oddly enough when I first came
to Alaska we really basically didn't and
I still get letters from from readers
and emails that say what are these
little lumps in my lawn well those lumps
are Verma compost those are berm those
are castings worm castings they're not
really compost uh and what goes through
a worm concentrates the nutrients uh you
know the next X more times nitrogen
export oh it's just a phenomenal
opportunity uh to enrich or concentrate
nutrients in your soil uh people I know
used to throw night crawlers around I
don't think that makes any sense you
want
you want your worms to be in a bin uh
worms will get into the soil not it's
not something that I really encourage so
we are getting towards the end of the
episode here and a couple things I like
to close out on would be advice for new
gardeners do you have anything maybe we
haven't talked about in this episode
that you think should be brought up or
you know advice for new gardeners well
again I mean I I and of course it's
self-serving but read to me with
microbes understand the soil food web
and if you don't understand the soil
food web teaming with microbes I think
the United States Department of
Agriculture Dr Elaine wrote a little
picture booklet about the soil food
we're very very simplistic we'll look
enough on the internet if you don't want
to buy a bulker you know and and read
about the soil food web that's how your
plants work don't start with chemicals
that's not the way to go I know you're
being yelled at by some Scotch guy you
know every spring to do X Y and Z I know
people tell you that glyphosate safe uh
this is not something that you want to
be fooling around with you want to be an
organic Gardener you want to be a
Natural Gardener and it's really easy to
do the work comes when you have to
convert from a chemical situation to an
organic situation which ultimately is
where you're going to want to be when
you go to the supermarket do you buy
chemical Laden apples do you buy
chemical Laden fruit or do you buy
organic you buy organic and so you want
to grow your own organic as well and
it's so easy to do because the plant is
in charge and if you get the plant to
balance what it needs
your inputs water and that's basically
it water and then the compost as well
right that you have to add and
everyone's going on absolutely yeah or
or different kinds of mulches I mean you
can use mulches which are compost in the
making
um but but one or the other you should
be using there are no bare soils uh
don't Rollo till it's not necessary and
it breaks up the soil food web and just
displaces members of the soil food web
that are supposed to be you know in one
zone uh to another Zone where you know
where it takes a long time for them to
get back into the root system it messes
up the mycorrhizal network that's been
created in your garden so you got to be
careful uh and again it's just what what
I'm saying to you is if you start out
knowing what the soil food web is it's
going to be really easy to start
gardening if you go chemical you got to
figure out what those chemicals do how
much to use how much to measure when to
use them when not to use them uh and it
it really makes gardening work and it's
not supposed to be work it's supposed to
be a wonderful hobby well said so
wrapping things up how can the listeners
find you and what do you have upcoming
in the future
oh I don't think I'm going to be writing
any more books but that's what I said
after the first one uh ah man I tell you
what
um you can find me on Instagram and and
whatnot at Gardener Jeff
lowenfels.com is my website uh if you
need to email me you can do so my email
is not hard to find
um and uh there are lots of different
things that you ought to be looking at
other than me go on the internet look up
the soil food web and learn about it
from as many different sources as you
can and then teaming with bacteria in
your new book now released so I actually
put a link to your book down in the
YouTube description section below or you
can just search for it on Amazon it'll
pop up super and if you need if you need
it in different foreign languages all
over have been translated available in
audio although I don't know this this
next one I don't know if they're going
to be able to do an audio on it because
it has so many bacterial names and
they're really hard to pronounce you
don't have to do that as you read the
book just go by them uh but yeah you
should definitely take a look at these
books uh take a look at the reviews uh
on on Amazon uh and see whether they'll
be helpful for you I think they will
fantastic well again my channel
definitely have a link to your book down
in the YouTube description section below
also your Instagram I'll link that down
if you enjoyed this episode click that
Thumbs Up Button also subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend I'm releasing a new
Garden Talk podcast episode and I'd love
for you to tune into future episodes
Jeff well thank you so much for coming
on this has been insightful great
conversation I think there's a lot of
things here that you had mentioned today
that my audience is going to take away
and definitely gain some value from so
thanks again for coming on my pleasure
always a pleasure to be on Mr croat
thank you so much peace out everyone see
you in the next episode