welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr grew it
and you're tuned into the garden duck
podcast this episode number 107. in this
episode I interview Brandon rust he has
been gardening for 20 years and is the
owner of bokashi Earthworks some of you
may remember Brandon from episode 16 of
this podcast where he talked all about
utilizing microorganisms in the garden
in this episode he talks about several
different Garden amendments why they
would be applied and the pros and cons
of using them there is now a separate
Channel called Garden talk clips on
YouTube with these podcast episodes are
broken down into highlights or smaller
Clips simply search a garden talk clips
on YouTube and the channel should pop
right up for you I want to acknowledge
that one of my goals for this podcast is
to bring free information about
gardening all plants to the general
public that being said I'd like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible thanks to
Mars Hydro for sponsoring this episode
check out their spring sewing sale which
is going on right now they're doing 15
off some of their LED grow lights such
as the TS series NSP series
they also have two by two three by three
four by four and five by five complete
grow tank kits on sale
they also have other items so go to
their website at Mars hydro.com and you
can use the discount code Mr Grow it for
discount on any of their products thanks
to AC Infinity for sponsoring this
episode my entire ventilation system is
AC Infinity I have their inline fan
ducting carbon filter and their
controller I love the controller 69 Pro
with temperature humidity and VPD
programming and having control of
different fan speeds this makes it so
much easier to control my grow
environment their controller 69 pro
version also controls their oscillating
fans grow lights and humidifier the
discount code Mr Grow at 15 works on
both Amazon and their website
acinfinity.com
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with
Brandon rust how you doing today I'm
doing good how are you doing yourself
doing good man thanks for asking so this
is your second time on the podcast the
first time around was episode 16 back in
May of 2021 so quite a while ago you
talked all about utilizing
microorganisms in the guard and uh there
was so much great information in that
episode and it got over 63 000 listens
on YouTube alone so that's nuts you've
definitely touched a lot of lives in
that episode in this episode we're going
to get into various Garden amendments
why they would be applied and the pros
and cons of using them so really excited
for this one but first can you introduce
yourself for those that didn't catch the
first episode we did together sure for
any of your listen listeners who aren't
familiar with myself my name is Brandon
rust
um I specialize in Agronomy and
microbiology for medicinal plants but I
also you know work with people who do
food production and all you know all
types of other types of agricultural
crops
um I own bokashi Earthworks and we have
a couple of different things that we do
at focashi Earthworks so one of the
things that we've that we are ramping up
and starting to do on a larger scale is
our green waste recycling program where
we take organic waste from other
Industries and we convert those into uh
biological fertilizers through a process
of solid state fermentation we might
have touched a little bit about that on
the last episode
that we did together we also manufacture
a product called micro plus here in
Oklahoma City
um at the office
and that is a Consortium of
microorganisms fungus yeast and bacteria
that is used for bioremediation for
nutrient cycling pathogen suppression
has a bunch of different applications in
across agriculture remediation and even
it is used in livestock industry as well
as a probiotic
um and then we also sell uh bulk soils
amendments and humate fertilizers that
were developed by NASA agricultural
Technologies
and so we have a lot of different
aspects we just opened up our bokashi
Earthworks Learning Center where you can
actually come in person on our scheduled
days and you can learn about different
subjects similar to what we're doing now
while we're doing
um we're going to be talking about
organic amendments we have classes on
solid state fermentation different
practical applications uh of you know
microorganisms in gardening so we have a
lot of different things that we cover
and we'll be making more schedules and
more events as the year progresses we'll
also have guest speakers such as Dr
Pepper Hernandez and some other people
doing some knf classes as well some
natural farming classes
so we kind of bundled everything
together because I the biggest hurdle
that I found when it comes to breaking
into conventional agriculture is the
education is is greatly needed uh before
people will put their faith in doing
something new especially when it comes
to you know when we're talking about the
American Farmer one of the things that a
lot of times they face is the fact that
a lot of these people are actually
mortgaging their land and their property
to get the things that they need to be
successful and so they always typically
go with what has worked in the past and
they that's been replicatable because
their livelihoods are on their line on
the line and if something goes wrong
they could be out everything
um their whole family their whole their
family's livelihood and their business
and everything so
it's one of the things that a lot of
people don't understand about how you
know American agriculture works but
they they do a lot of uh labor not a
great return and a lot of times they're
putting everything on the line to do it
so we have to make sure that the people
who are
switching over these types of programs
really understand
the way that they operate and the
practical application that's behind the
science
so that way they can achieve the success
that they need to be profitable and
maintain a sustainable agricultural
model I like that you not only have good
products but a big focus of yours is the
education you know you're not shy and
holding back information right you're
trying to educate the community and
that's a big deal you know not a lot of
people will be open to that you know
they just want to sell their products
and that's it they don't really care
about the education side of things I
mean just going on your Instagram alone
I know before we start recording you I'd
mention that you're not able to really
keep up with as much as you like but
there's a lot of great information in
regards to the science behind the plant
and things that can be useful in the
garden in order to grow these plants
successfully so I'll definitely have a
link to his Instagram down in the
YouTube description section below for
those of you tuning in on YouTube highly
recommend you give him a follow because
there's great information on that
channel alright so getting into the
topic so you gave me a list of
amendments prior to recording here I
want to ask to begin are all these
amendments that you're about to talk to
organic or are some synthetic okay so
let's talk about what organic is first
of all because there's uh some
misunderstandings about organic versus
synthetic so you could have and and also
natural
so in most people's minds when they hear
organic they are thinking about a
practice you know using things that are
naturally uh around them things that are
sustainable and that I consider you know
uh
natural farming
where you're using where everything is
pretty much organic but here's the thing
what organic truly means is carbon based
so if you were to approach any any
institution any type of scientist or
anything else and you're talking about
organic it means that it is carbon based
now some of the things that we use in
agriculture don't contain carbon but
they are natural things like gypsum for
instance which is calcium calcium
sulfate
now it's a natural component comes right
out of the earth there's an abundance of
it
it's it's easily accessible and it
doesn't have any negative impacts on the
environment when it's applied correctly
it you know even in and also I want to
make sure people understand just because
something is is considered organic
doesn't necessarily mean safe either
because there are things that are
organic that are also
um
they're not safe you know or if you're
over applying something it can still
have a detrimental impact to the
environment or people around you
and so when we're talking about organic
in this context we're talking about
both meals those are usually organic
inputs and then you have things that are
natural like your rock minerals and then
you also have natural salts like Epsom
salt that is a natural occurring mineral
and it is assault and what assault is
it's just a it's a cation an element
with a negative with a positive charge
attached to an anion which is an element
with a negative charge and what happens
is it just means that negative and
positive attract and so they they've
attracted they've created a covalent
bond it's not a very strong bond and so
they disassociate in the presence of
water and so when we're looking at
something like gypsum or copper sulfate
or iron sulfate there's these things are
natural they come from the ground they
are not synthetically produced so the
difference between organic and natural
so we're using things at organic and
natural
we're not using things that are
synthetically created
right like
um that come from the Herbert botch
process of creating nitrogen from from
gas
right so there's just and then you know
some of the synthetics
if you were to talk about like dap
diamonium phosphate right you're
essentially mixing uh ammonium and
phosphate and what the way that that
would work is you would take a natural
mineral element that contains phosphorus
you're attacking that parent appetite
material with something like phosph uh
like with a sulfuric acid and what that
does is it releases the anion that we
were mentioning that phosphorus anion
from that parent appetite material
liberates that and they're able to
separate that out now they take that
phosphorus and then they mix that with
the ammonium that was made during the
Herbert process and they get you know
monoammonium or diamonium phosphate
now those things take a lot of energy
and resources to produce that's why
we're looking at these and going hey
this is may not be the best way to do it
because of the the resources allocated
to the production of those things
they're not in and also
like if they're used properly or if
they're
you know they have less of a detrimental
impact right and so
the but the problem is that even when
you create something like diamonium
phosphate which has really high nitrogen
value and a really high phosphorus value
those things are both biologically
mediated right naturally in systems and
so
as soon as you put that down you're
going to lose nitrogen immediately
because it volatile it it goes through a
process of that is mediated by biology
and some of that can off gas back into
the atmosphere as atmospheric nitrogen
some of it will be leached away it's got
a very low nutrient use efficiency so
even though you're putting High numbers
on there maybe like 42 percent uh
phosphorus in this case
not all of that is going to be available
what happens is as soon as that is
liberated both of that that cation from
the ammonium and that anion from the
phosphorus those are liberated and so
now you have a highly highly reactive
anion that doesn't stay in that form
freely in nature for very long and so
what it does is it's it attaches to
other uh positively charged particles in
the soil and so it can tie up things
like iron and calcium and zinc and
manganese it can tie up
these these other elements making them
unavailable the plan and so you're
essentially the thinking is oh I'm
adding in a bunch of this mineral
nutrient but what you're actually doing
is you're causing a chemical reaction
when those things disassociated or
liberated within that system where they
start to tie up other things making the
things that were already there that were
available become unavailable and so
there's a bunch of chemical reactions
that are happening and there are
biological reactions that are mediated
during these processes you know Carbon
phosphorus sulfur nitrogen and iron are
all very very highly biologically
mediated in these soil systems and so we
have the nitrogen cycle we have the
phosphorus cycle we have the carbon and
sulfur cycles and then iron is a whole
different beast in itself when we're
talking about the natural acquisition of
iron into the plant is because iron you
know it it oxidizes so rapidly in in
you know the pH ranges that these plants
are usually optimally operating in and
then also in the presence of water
because it's it's Ox the water is an
oxidizing agent and so it it gives off
its hydrogen ions to that ferric iron
and cause and causes it to oxidize into
fe3 plus which isn't really available to
a lot of plants
and so with Biology you can have things
like the the production of amino acids
and sadiophores that can keep that iron
in a metabolically available form so
there's all these different nutrient
interactions that are happening
and so when we're talking about
synthetics versus natural
um we have these anions that are in
great abundance that start to tie up
stuff but also they acidify the the
organic matter that's already there
causing a reduction in the amount of
total organic matter and we need you
know about five percent is ideal for for
you know ideal crop production and for
these biologically mediated processes to
be able to continue to happen and the
the less percent that we go under that
the less biological mediated processes
are happening so we have to add
continuously more and more and more and
it just compounds the problem over time
and so when we're looking at things that
are naturally derived or organically
derived we still have to look at the
application rates we still have to be
responsible and the timing the wind the
the and the why or the when and uh and
the in the where you know we have to be
mindful of the application still however
these things are usually less
resource dependent and they're also less
energy dependent and then they're less
environmentally impactful or they don't
have an environmental impact that's
going to be negative they usually it
will have a positive environmental
aspect to it because with an organic
Amendment like a meal and we'll divide
these up
we have meals which are going to be a
slower release you'll get some nutrient
availability right away when you apply
those but things like alfalfa meal
soybean meal blood meal uh bone meal
guanos those types of things they'll
take a little bit up to three or four
weeks to be completely broken down
now so that those are all organic and so
we're talking about organic amendments
I'm usually talking about meals
specifically because those are a
carbon-based organic substrate that
actually takes the breaking down of that
material for whatever's in there to be
released into the system and become
metabolically available for the plant
and the bacteria and fungi in the soil
then then there are the rock minerals
that you have things like calcium
phosphate azomite um
you have uh you know glacial rock dusts
you have those type of things that are
usually going to increase your cation
exchange capacity
your ECE of your soil it's usually going
to bring in some type of calcium Source
some type of phosphorus usually and then
Trace trace minerals
and then you have your natural salts
right things like Epsom salt gypsum
um oh also step back uh in those Rock
minerals we also have things like
calcium silica
and also uh lighting agents that will
help with ph
then we get into
natural salts Epsom salt gypsum which is
uh calcium sulfate we have all the
mineral sulfates that are all naturally
occurring potassium sulfate and then all
the micronutrient sulfates
and then also for Boron either Borax or
solublear which is sodium borate which
is another naturally occurring salt and
again these things aren't detrimental
and in the systems but you do still have
to be mindful of what you're adding in
because you're looking for sufficiency
but you're also looking for balance
between all the elements
and so
uh the difference between all of those
elements is that three to four weeks on
the organic meals usually you'll have
some mineral availability in the Rock in
the Rock minerals like you know calcium
silica you'll get the silica and calcium
a nice portion of that is available
and then you have your salts salts are
immediately available and so what
happens is they disassociate when you
put them in water some of them will
react uh
with other elements so that's one of the
things that you need to be you know
mindful of if you have a
if you have a cation it's going to be
attracted to an anion so that's why the
sulfate the sulfate is the anion and all
the mineral sulfates and then all the
rest of them are all cations so whether
it's zinc copper manganese magnesium or
calcium they all have a sulfate uh state
that they can be in
those disassociating water and they're
metabolically available right away so
you can add Epsom salt gypsum and all
your you know iron sulfate one of the
things that you can do when you're
adding these into your system is you can
add humic and fulvic acids and that'll
help them uh stay in a metabolically
available form because just because they
are available
they change things change in real time
right some things will bond with this
the plant will take some stuff up you
know some of the biology will use it and
moat and
immobilize it to the for the plant and
then it'll be in the you know and
that'll have to cycle to be released
again so a bunch of different stuff
happens but out of all of those natural
compounds
the mineral salts
uh will always be more available you'll
always have higher availability that's
interesting yeah I'm glad we went over
this first because it's definitely going
to be helpful as we go along here
because they're we're going to be
talking about salts we're going to talk
about meals and so on and so forth so
let's start going down this list now
calcium silicate talk to us about that
one of my absolute favorites so
calcium is a is a it's considered a
secondary nutrient but for a lot of
medicinal plants and a lot of heavy
fruiting plants uh calcium will actually
uh be about second or third as far as
the amount that it'll store in the
tissue and the amount that it will
actually uptake calcium mediates so many
different aspects this particular
element is it works really really well
to stabilize pH so if you have a low PH
it is it's not going to have as fast of
an acting time to increase it's not just
going to make it jump up from like you
know 5.5 to 6.5 it's more of a slow jump
so it it's not as fact fast acting as
something like high calcium agline or
even something like Dolomite lime
which will jump it up a little higher uh
faster
but the benefit is that
you get the calcium and the benefit of
the silica as well and Aldo silica is
not considered a an essential plant
nutrient it's as it's not needed to
complete the plant's entire life cycle
it's kind of something that really AIDS
in a lot of other aspects that I
not going to get too much into
but yeah it's a it's a Rock mineral so
some of it will be available the
majority of it will be cycled through
different processes through the Pieology
and the soil and it's one of my
favorites to actually front load uh
calcium early in the vegetative state
when plants are really starting to you
know fill out and put on the the green
foliage and everything else
and it helps with a lot of different
things like chemical messaging signaling
it helps with
um you know really thicking up
thickening up the the the the cuticle
layers uh on the the leaf surface which
can help as a protectant from leaf
eating insects
and then it's also responsible for
helping with you know the movement of
other elements
so it's really important another calcium
source that we would use
and this one is actually a salt and so
it has more availability right away is
gypsum or calcium sulfate it's one of
the other go-to
mineral elements that I use
to get adequate levels of calcium
and there are a couple of other things
too that I'll use for calcium
but the calcium silicate and the gypsum
are the number are are the the first
when we're talking about calcium because
the other elements that we're going to
talk about that have high levels of
calcium in them also have
phosphorus and some micronutrients that
are associated with them as well and so
in the instance that I would not want to
be adding in any more phosphorus if I
had a plenty of phosphorus I didn't need
to bring any in or I didn't want to
bring any other elements in and I was
strictly addressing calcium I would only
use the gypsum or the calcium silicate
now bone meals
that is going to be an organic Amendment
it is it does have carbon in it
and it also has a lot of calcium and a
lot of phosphorus so in in the instance
that I needed to implement and get both
phosphorus or maybe I didn't need
phosphorus really
but
you know my like my you know it's it's
not gonna hurt because it's an organic
meal to add that extra because the way
that it's going to be broken down is
going to be really slow anyway so it's
not going to have an extreme impact on
other elements in the soil or the soil
biology it's not going to set anything
out of balance with like a bone meal
um unless you're using something like a
fishbone Meal which you could bring in
too much and you have sodium too much
chloride because it's an ocean input
so bone meal is really good calcium
Source you'll also have the phosphorus
associated with it there's some other
stuff too
that also has calcium but you should be
careful with and that is going to be
high phosphorus seabird guano and
typically
what people are using that for is for
phosphorus it has a high availability of
phosphorus and it it's pretty quick to
release even though this is an organic
uh substance so you can get the
phosphorus in there a lot faster with
that with the guano but you also have to
remember that if you're already loaded
up on a ton of calcium already it's it
might not be something that you would
want to add as your phosphorus
supplement simply because it's probably
going to have something like 18 to 23
percent calcium also associated with it
and when you're looking at a label it's
like a plant label you have a part on
there that has your NPK
right and your calcium and magnesium and
all that stuff isn't off isn't always
going to be on there it might be listed
on the back if it's listed at all and so
from a consumer standpoint if you know
about your NPK and you're trying to
address something just for phosphorus
you're inadvertently adding something
that you may not want to be adding
so it's important to know exactly what
other elements are associated with the
mineral amendments or the organic meals
that you're using now regards to bone
meal there's some controversy behind it
right it's kind of like a not the best
source to use so I think you're talking
about it being a byproduct from the
slaughter industry and the the same can
be said about things like blood meal but
this is this is the issue
those Industries aren't going to stop
you are people are going to continue to
eat meat yes we should strive for
ethically sourced and we should
but that comes with our dollar that
comes with the buying power of the
consumer so that is that falls on the
consumer to you know uh get their meat
from producers who have ethnic treatment
of animals
that being said it you know
all of the waste that comes from any
industry if it were not recycled and
used for some other purpose it's just
going to go to waste and so the it's
there there there's a conflict right
okay so there are producers and I'm not
using like that we get R all of our bone
meal uh locally so we know where it
comes from and what it's not like these
giant desert cattle Farms that exist in
like New Mexico and stuff like that
these are all
uh you know Oklahoma and in Texas uh you
know it's a it's a product uh that's
being recycled for and repurposed and so
it's kind of a double-edged sword when
it comes to it because yes we need
ethically sourced we have to you know
obviously
um
if we're not using the byproducts though
then then they're going to waste so
you know it's going these industries
exist
and they're they're going to create
byproducts
whether or not you
buy that type of meat or that type of
product that's personal preference I
know as a company and I'm into organic
waste recycling that we're going to take
waste from the industries that we
operate with
because we want to close those carbon
cycle Loops we want to get that carbon
back into soil we're once to
promote regenerative farming systems and
we want to be able to do things in a
manner that is less detrimental to
our our environment and to our own
selves you know so
but yeah you're right it is it is
it's one of those things you know you
might not want to buy products if that's
that's the case but then you have to
look at where the products are coming
from where they're sourced from and so
we've done our we do all of our due
diligence when it comes to all of the
inputs that we use
um when it comes to both our soil our
compost
and all of the things that we that we
sell to our consumers understood all
right let's move on down the line here
this next one I actually have in my
garden and I use it quite a bit from
time to time which is magnesium sulfate
AKA Epsom salt talk to us about that oh
it's a good one
it is out of all the mineral sulfates it
actually has the highest solubility and
so I'll um a little goes a long way
and typically
when it comes to you know medicinal
crops and even heavy flowering fruiting
crops if you're doing like for me when I
do all of my home growth stuff I love to
use magnesium sulfate as a foiler spray
you know I like to use a tablespoon per
gallon and the reason is this because
it's really really soluble
you have uh you have
four major soil uh cations it's going to
be calcium magnesium potassium and
sodium we always want sodium as low as
possible
um but all the other three all those
four things are antagonistic to each
other so they need to be in Balance so
they can be absorbed by the plant and
the right ratios and when we're talking
about Epsom salt it's very soluble and
it can cause antagonisms with calcium
and potassium so we
over applying it through a soil or
through watering it in
unless you're doing what I do with the
Agronomy and you're doing soil analytics
doing soil uh soil testing saturated
Pace testing Leaf tissue testing and
whatnot
if you're just a home grower you can
kind of avoid that situation that you
might put yourself in by locking out
some of that other stuff by over
applying too much right because you
don't you might not know how much you
need to be applying
if you just use it as a foiler spray you
can avoid that so you can avoid that
negative chemical interaction that would
happen within the soil those
antagonistics uh relationships that
could could potentially be there with
the misuse and you can just use a
tablespoon per gallon and spray it on
the plants and it's going to have great
great efficacy now one of the things I
do have to mention that whenever you're
doing a foil an application using a
spray that you need to start with clean
water something like reverse osmosis or
distilled water because if you're not
using clean water you could have a lot
of sodium or a lot of bicarbonate or
your pH could be you know really really
high and so it decreases the efficacy of
what you're trying to apply so when
you're using clean water you have a
greater efficacy you know the plant's
not uh yeah there's not any kind of
negative reactions antagonisms that are
actually happening because the water it
you know has high you know boron in it
or this or that or what not you know so
tablespoon per gallon is a little bit
different for me I used to use a
teaspoon per gallon it looks like I need
to update up my dose a little bit there
I always use as a foiler as well and you
can do it a couple times a week even too
you can go and spray and one day wait
another day spray again like it's
I wouldn't recommend doing more than
three times a week but that is a really
really great way and one of the things
that I see pretty consistently across
the board and uh your Leaf margin so
they'll start to show a little shadowing
in between the veins where it'll kind of
be a slight discoloration that's a very
verse that's not the very first sign but
the the leaf petiole will actually start
to turn purple
that's a good sign so if you start there
you can do your foiler sprays and you
can kind of avoid all that and the thing
about magnesium is it's a photosynthetic
element so at the center of every uh
chlorophyll molecule
is going to be magnesium
right so you need it for chlorophyll for
the plant stiff to photosynthesize so it
it can be a really limiting factor
especially in veg if you do not have
enough magnesium everything else is
going to slow down because your plant
doesn't have the ability to
photosynthesize or create more
chlorophyll in the chloroplast and
you're never doing a foiler and
flowering is that right
up to about
um week two you can you know during the
bolting but I try not to spray anything
after we've had like you know flower
sets the last thing that I spray is
usually around day 21.
I'll do uh I'll do my my pruning on my
plants that need to be done bottom prune
up all the stuff whether it's you know
medicinal herbs or even you know
tomatoes and stuff like that Peppers you
I prune all that stuff up all that crap
on the bottom so the energy is at the
fruiting sites and I'll spray
trichoderma and bacillus septillus as a
combination and they have so many
benefits it has benefits as a soil
drench but as a foiler application
that's the last thing I spray and that's
usually for the prevention of things
like botrytis and powdery mildew and
crops it helps suppress any type of
leaf-borne pathogen and then it also
works as an end of endophyte so it will
penetrate inside of the plant cell and
it will help fight off any other type of
pathogens so we're basically what we're
doing is we're inoculating the the plant
um endosphere
uh
and the uh the phylosphere uh to
basically out-compete other pathogens
and kind of give that extra layer of
protection Endo fights are super
interesting that's that's a whole nother
episode itself yeah we get really deep
into that but it's really really cool
yeah dude dude the way that microbes
work when you start understanding
actually understanding microbial
metabolism and like what photosynthesis
is right because there are a lot of
different
microorganisms that photosynthesize in
fact photosynthesis in Plants came from
bacteria that that combine with their
cell I mean if we're looking at
chloroplasts right they have their own
sets of DNA and cells and so they
replicate independently of the plant
cells themselves and so it's a it's a
it's an ancient function of a symbiotic
relationship that became encapsulated
into one system it's a very very
fascinating and when you're looking at
microbial metabolisms we'll have to do
that one another episode
uh magnesium you don't want uh too high
a magnesium actually going into
flowering also or get remember it's a
photosynthetic element and so if you
have too much it'll actually decrease
your just like nitrogen it'll decrease
your your cannabinoids it'll decrease uh
terpene expression so it can have some
negative impact on some additional herbs
while on some other herbs it'll have
positive impact like on tomatoes you're
going to have you know better
uh the health benefits if you have more
magnesium more calcium stuff like that
so it depends on which specific crop
you're growing that these that these
things
um they're situational you could say wow
that's interesting I didn't know that
one okay let's move down the list a
little bit further here uh we are at
soybean meal talk to us about that yeah
so we'll let's talk about both soybean
meal
alfalfa meal
uh blood meal
Feathering and feather meal these are
all
nitrogen sources they're used pretty
much for nitrogen sources and while they
do contain small amounts of of other
elements typically we're not addressing
you know we're not going to address iron
with soybean meal we're not going to
adjust calcium with soybean meal
although they have small amounts of that
in there we're looking at these
specifically for nitrogen these are
nitrogen inputs there are also
biostimulants like amino acids that can
be categorized into an organic Amendment
as well however that's more of a bio
stimulant and it has much more
beneficial properties than just the
meals themselves and they operate a
little differently on the plant's
metabolism
and so when we're talking about any of
these these meals they all take use
typically between three and four weeks
to be completely broken down so you get
some solubility of nutrition when you're
applying it
but it's a slow release and you can and
by week four the majority you know I
think for blood meal and feather meal
it's three weeks a hundred percent
release
of of that you know if the blood meal
was at 14 blood meal
and you put in a pound of it you can
figure out what the PPM of that is by
you know doing some mathematical
conversions
and you can figure out okay so I'm
getting this much PPM of nitrogen over
the next four weeks and so you can kind
of that's how I know how to do my
application rates as far as when I'm
looking at agronomic data and giving
people personal recommendations for
their crop
and each one of those is a different one
you know soybean meal in Alfalfa are
going to be
um they're going to be plant-based right
and they're going to have a slightly
lower nitrogen content than than the
animal based products like the feather
meal or the blood meal
those are going to have a higher
nitrogen value
the
the uh
soybean meal I really like that that's
one of my go-to's that is like one of my
absolute go-to's it's about seven
percent nitrogen and it has about three
and a half week span to where it will be
completely broken down it it
offers a little bit of a difference in
comparison to something like blood meal
because the blood meal will have higher
ammonium uh concentrations in it as
opposed to
the uh soybean meal which has more
complex nitrogen Source like amino acids
it has amino acids associated with it or
nitrogen that hasn't been broken down
fully while the blood meal will have a
it has a higher nitrogen content and a
higher amount of that nitrogen content
is going to be in its ammonia ammonium
form which means it's going to be more
readily available so when you put that
in it will have way more solubility than
the other types of meals like soybean or
the or or alfalfa meal Alfalfa has
actually a really really small usually
only one maybe two percent nitrogen
associated with it and it has a slower
release as well so that might be a total
release of maybe like 75 percent over
four week period of time now what about
kelp meal would you group that into that
same category or no no if you look at if
you look at kelp meal and this is one
the things I absolutely do not use cow
milk I after all of the research that
I've done kelp meal is a no-go and this
is why
uh at when I've looked at maybe 20
different brands uh suppliers of kelp
Mill there's only one single company and
that is espoma
that has
low arsenic okay so across the board
kelp is notorious for for arsenic
contamination
um espoma had like one point three seven
PPM all the rest were between
uh 20 to 30 percent uh PPM parts per
million of arsenic
and now so that's a great concern
especially when we're talking about
commercial uh production of food or
medicine especially in you know
medicinal herbs
um we we we're testing we we get you
know we have to test these products and
that can be a huge problem for
commercial cultivation
so and then if you look at the actual
nutrition of kelp if you're looking at
the NPK it's usually less than one
percent across the board we might have
one percent nitrogen you might have half
of a percent or 0.25 phosphorus and
maybe half a percent potassium
the amount of kelp that you would need
to add into a system to bring that
system to nutritional sufficiency
would be exponentially more detrimental
because of the high heavy metals the
high sodium and the high chloride
content because all kelp has high sodium
chloride
sodium and chloride because it's an
ocean input and all ocean inputs well
there's oyster shell crustacean meal
fish bone meal all those things have
higher uh sodium associated with them
and so when you're adding a bunch of
kelp if you're trying to add it in there
to bring these systems oh I need to my
NPK levels up it's not an adequate
source of those to bring it up and then
the amount that you would have to bring
in you would detrim you would it be
detrimental to that system that's one of
the things that we're talking about just
because something's organic doesn't
necessarily mean safe or doesn't
necessarily mean that it's going to have
a positive benefit the cons for kelp for
me and the people that I work with and
consult with the cons outweigh the pros
is what I'm saying so there's more
native impact associated with using kelp
now the thing that most people will say
oh I want to use kelp for the the
phytohormones the things like the The
Oxen which is endocetic acid or the
cytokinin or the gibberellic acid or the
trace mineral elements
well you can find most of those Trace
mineral elements in most of the organic
meals like I was talking about before
blood meal bone meal feather meal they
all contain Trace mineral elements your
compost contain traceant mineral
elements and then we also have and if
you're looking strictly for like
um a phytohormone input the the benefit
from plant hormones I use kiaja I use
cold pressed kiaja not the dehydrated
but the cold pressed and that's because
the kiaja doesn't have any of the
negative associations with the heavy
metals the sodium the chloride
but it does contain all the bioactive
compounds the organic saponins it
contains all of the cytokine and
subrulins and and into acetic acid
as well as a bunch of other things like
amino acids
so there are you take different
approaches and I know which approaches
work best for the practical application
of these things now the science most of
the science will say oh kelp works
wonders kelp works wonders but most of
these things are done on just regular
food crops and none of those food crops
are being tested
you know what's what is the the end
result you know what are the metals
levels content what is the actual
mineral nutritional value of these so we
can get bio-stimulating effects from a
lot of different things including
microorganisms and so I take just a
different approach when it comes to kelp
and that's my reasoning behind that
understood yeah I was going to ask you
about the cytokinins the hormones toxins
because you hear about people using kelp
specifically for those reasons so I'm
glad you got into uh into that one our
cold pressed kiaja is actually sourced
from regenerative Farms down in Chile
and it is now if you were to look at the
comparison of like the other products
that are the dehydrated products that
they have a higher
um content of saponins because there's
everything else has been extracted out
with our product we have 8.6 percent
saponins which is very high but it's
also all of the other bioactive
compounds and the diversity of those
saponins so you might only get maybe
um like 70 or something like that with a
dehydrated product and then with a cold
press product you'll get something like
114 115. saponins huh that's interesting
up next let's talk about potassium
sulfate yeah so potassium is a
interesting element in the fact that
the plants need it in abundance it is a
macronutrient it is a it's responsible
for the opening and closing of the guard
cells it is responsible for sodium ion
pumps for you know diff uh to make
diffusion work across cellular membranes
um it's it helps with water transport
because it it you know those guard cells
on the stomata they open it up and allow
for transportation of nutrients and
water throughout that system potassium
is responsible for for that system
it's got a bunch of different things
that it does however
these think potassium comes from
uh mineral mineral appetites it usually
comes from minerals right and
it is not typically in abundance in you
know uh conventional agriculture soil
outdoor soils most of the land that we
see uh isn't really super fertile like
you you would have to remediate it
before you could uh grow crops or you
have to use fertigation techniques and
crop covers and add carbon whatever so
when it comes to potassium sulfate it is
a mineral sulfate it's a naturally
occurring mineral that allows us to get
that much needed element
really quickly when we need it now
there are a couple of different things
that I use for potassium now potassium
comes in in a couple of different ways
typically in soil
so composts
it comes in composts and not in huge
quantities where usually maybe two three
percent potassium when we're talking
about compost and those are all slow
release now
we potassium I see uses is is probably
the number two element
um especially in hot and heavy fruiting
and medicinal plants have recruiting for
vegetable varieties I mean we need a lot
of it it needs a lot of potassium a lot
of these plants do
so we can get it from potassium sulfate
another another one is potassium silicas
is what I like is another thing that I
use which is
um the trade name agsil 16 it's
essentially uh potash and sand heated up
really hot together it's mixed together
and it's a water-soluble form of both
potassium and
silica in monosilic acid in that form so
it is available form in a very it's the
least expensive form of silica so if
you're using a silica Amendment
this is by far the most cost effective
way to get silica in it has uh one it's
got 32 percent potassium by volume so
you can use small amounts to get
the potassium that you need and it is
water soluble so you can mix it into a
fertigation tank and water it in you can
also foiler apply axial 16 potassium
silica and it works really really well
because it it changes the pH of the
water makes it really high so if you're
using it as a foiler application it'll
change that it'll temporarily change the
um the phylosphere of the plant which a
lot of pathogens don't like that so it
can be used as a fungicide in that
respect well also adding the potassium
and the silica which is uh available to
the plant as a spray as well
the potassium sulfate
it depending on how much it's processed
and what I mean by processing is they'll
they'll micronize it they'll grind it up
so you can get it in chunks and the
benefit of having chunks is that you can
get it as a top dress and just kind of
leave it in there as your top dress and
as you water in it'll slowly release
over time when you have higher granulars
also if it's a granular form of
potassium sulfate and you're using that
in like a soil mix the benefit is that
it'll be a slow release but it'll also
add pore space and so that'll help with
you know water penetration throughout
that soil system if it's a granular it
also comes in fully water so water
soluble uh form so that way you can add
it to a reservoir or you can water it in
and again because it is a mineral
sulfate it's going to be metabolically
available so you can use this to quickly
adjust levels like so if I were to get a
soil test back and I saw that somebody's
potassium was low my go-to is usually
going to be potassium sulfate or axial
16. there are other things that contain
potassium like green sand right I've
seen people try to use green sand as a
potassium Amendment but the problem is
this
the release of potassium for green sand
is so slow we're talking about
you know several months to years
for it to become available so while it
does add some component of aeration
and a very very small component of
potassium it's one of those things that
is is almost just like an extra that you
could have in there if you wanted to and
it's not going to hurt it's not going to
really affect anything
but I can't but it's not something that
I could you know recommend as a you know
as an as an agronomist and say hey this
is what you should be using to try to
get your system back into sufficiency
because it just doesn't add the amount
that's going to be needed to bring it up
in a adequate amount of time
another another a mineral amendment that
we can talk to talk about is solpomag
also known as kmag also known as
langbonite
now it usually has around 22 percent
potassium right but what they're what
what you're not typically looking at is
on the back of it it also contains
sulfur and magnesium and the problem
with langbonite is that the magnesium
and that sulfur are way more soluble
in this when they're in the system
either as a top dress or if it's been
you know if you've you know tried to mix
it with water let it dissolve the
magnesium in there if you're trying to
address just potassium you have to
remember potassium and magnesium are
antagonistic so if you're deficient in
potassium you go add sulpomag or
langbonite thinking hey this has got 22
percent potassium it's all gravy you
just neglected the fact that you added
in nine percent magnesium that is pretty
much 100 soluble so you have this
partially soluble 22 percent that's
going to be slow released over the next
couple of months versus this magnesium
that you just added in jacking up your
magnesium levels creating more
antagonisms between the magnesium and
the potassium so you could actually be
thinking you're putting in a potassium
amendment when what what you're doing is
actually uh making its less available
for the potassium that's already in
there because you just jacked up the
magnesium and you didn't need magnesium
that's crazy yeah there's a lot of
Growers that reach out to me that
they're Tinkers they like to add things
in as they see fit and they're throwing
off the balance the overall balance and
they're really getting into hot water
there because sometimes it's hard to get
Back in Balance in that case right do
you have any tips for for that yeah so
what what I'm typically looking at the
the there are some major things and the
the three major things are going to be
sodium bicarbonate and chloride so
bicarbonate will antagonize
all of your cations calcium magnesium
iron uh just everything you know and so
it makes it so that way the plant has to
work way harder to get what it needs so
even if you have sufficiency and
everything is balanced in there if
you've got really high bicarbonate
levels it's going to drive down the
ability for the plant to uptake those
nutrients
the same thing can be said with sodium
when sodium levels get higher and higher
and higher it causes osmotic stress on
the plant the plant actually and then
and then if you have events where you're
drying out your soil well then your ECE
spikes and your and you have all of this
oxidation occurring of all your mineral
elements it's it it's not conducive to
plant Health right it causes a lot of
osmotic stress it causes issues with
with all the other nutrient interactions
and then chloride chloride chloride is
an anion and high chloride will also
negatively affect
those types of elements that are anions
phosphate nitrate
um molybdenum so there's sulfur
also one of the things that you have to
look at is sulfur sulfur can cause
osmotic stress as well and so if your
sulfur levels are too high and they can
especially if you're using a lot of
mineral sulfates and so I you know I'll
change up the mineral sulfate sometimes
I won't use gypsum or potassium sulfate
at all and I'll use calcium silica and
axial 16 because if my sulfur level is
already high and I go ahead and add
those in I have to be mindful that I'm
also adding a certain amount of sulfur
into that sulfur is an anion it's used
to help with charge balance it's also
used for protein production it's used
for oil production it's used for a lot
of different things in the plant and you
need it it's a photosynthetic element as
well
so
but
when you dry out that sulfur causes EC e
spikes the electronic conductivity of
the soil it spikes up and cause issues
with osmotic pressure and then also it
can have some negative impacts on other
anions like phosphorus and uh nitrate
you mentioned sodium and bicarbonate and
that's uh that's the reason why I can't
use my tap water here where I am is
because we're looking at about 80 PPM of
sodium and it's real high in
bicarbonates as well pH is high so I'm
not even I can't even use my tap water I
have to filter it I've been using
reverse osmosis but that's another area
where I think a lot of people kind of
neglect looking at is they don't
actually have a one they don't get a
water test so they don't even know what
they're they're using to begin and then
they're adding in these amendments along
with their water and it's jacking
everything up yeah and so what happens
too is it's not necessarily going to be
an issue the first round the second
round the third round but what happens
is a lot of times these problems are
compounded over time and so you bring
sodium a little bit a little bit a
little bit a little bit until it adds up
to a point where someone's like dude I
don't know what's going on I can't
diagnose the issue I haven't done
anything different my regimen's the same
what's going on and it's and that the
first thing I do when I go to a consult
say hey you guys need to make sure
you're testing your water I don't care
if you're using Ro City water well water
it all has to be tested and we'll test
if you're on a well we'll test your well
water we'll test your RO water we're
gonna see if we even need Ro right we're
going to see if if we just need specific
filters because we're not trying to
waste money either you know we're not
trying to waste water we're trying to be
as as environmentally positively
uh you know we we want to we don't want
to create more issues we want compound
problems it's the same thing with kelp
you know oh what's happening I'm
starting to fail for arsenic well it's
come to a point where that arsenic
finally built up in into the soil
because you kept bringing it in with
certain products you know you can you
can mediate that by just knowing you
know but the thing is home Growers
aren't they they're they don't test
you know they're not testing and uh
commercial facilities a lot of times
don't test it's a very it's it's very
seldom
that people are doing what I'm doing in
the industry that I work in when it's
pretty standard practice across all the
rest of the agriculture industry you
know whether you're growing corn or soy
or ornamental flowers or tomatoes
there's Agronomy and data involved where
we want to know how much of what we need
to use so we don't over apply and so we
keep nutritional sufficiency and balance
heavy metals is another area where we
could do an entire episode on if we
wanted to I've been learning so much
about heavy metals recently and um it's
and they're called scary they're complex
they're complex too the way that they
work but we'll save that for another
episode we do have time for a few more
of these amendments to go over I know
you got the list in front of you is
there ones you want to kind of pick out
that you'd like to talk about here yeah
we can kind of uh we can kind of put all
of the micronutrient sulfates all
together in one which would be iron
sulfate copper sulfate zinc sulfate
manganese sulfate and then sodium borate
okay these are these are all natural
natural salts and they're using
extremely extremely small quantities and
what I mean extremely small I'm usually
talking about one-third to a half
and you know the the most that you would
do was maybe like three teaspoons
per yard of soil so we're talking about
for every you know 650 pounds of soil
you have we're talking about you know
maybe half a teaspoon you know for
something like sodium borate to bring
that to sufficiency for several runs you
could put in point you know
0.33 of a teaspoon or one third of a
teaspoon into one yard of soil
and know that you're going to have
enough Boron and that you're not even
have to address Boron for that for the
remainder of of your your your grow
this is kind of the same thing with with
zinc and copper and and manganese the
amounts that you use are so low that
it's actually hard to use them as a top
dress right so typically what we're
doing with these micronutrient sulfates
is
were Distributing them evenly over the
soil surface using either a spray
application or by watering it in
so let's say I have a yard of soil and I
know hey I'm going to be using a five
gallon I'm going to use five gallons for
this yard of soil so I'm going to mix my
nutrient sulfates into this yard of soil
with my humic fulvic acid and I'm going
to water this in so I have an even
distribution of all of these
micronutrient sulfates
um but when we're talking about like if
you started off with zero micronutrients
copper uh iron you're gonna have a
little bit more you could put in about a
cup and a half to two cups per yard of
soil but when we're talking about
uh let's say zinc you'll you could do
two and a half teaspoons for an entire
yard of soil that has nothing been added
to it as far as micronutrient and you
are going to be sufficient and that will
give you enough sufficiency
to go for several runs as long as the
biomass that you're pulling off like
your Leaf material and stuff is getting
recycled back into your system
now if you're taking all of your biomass
out of your soil system and not letting
that cycle back naturally you're gonna
have to add more sooner with copper you
can do the same three and a half
teaspoons for an entire yard of soil
will bring you up to nutritional
sufficiency for
a while for a long several Cycles
manganese sulfate you can do two and a
half
teaspoons and bring that up to
sufficiency sodium borate is half of a
teaspoon
borax just regular borax would be twice
that amount or one one teaspoon
and then you don't have to do it anymore
and you could even if you were to take
those and start off with nothing and
stretch those out over a six month
period and be like I'm gonna add one
milliliter of this one you know
it's like those ratios right there are
solid and we'll get you know get you to
nutritional sufficiency so a little goes
a long way with those micronutrient
sulfates yes and unless you're talking
about the the macronutrients or
secondary nutrient sulfates like
potassium calcium and magnesium right
because calcium sulfate magnesium
sulfate potassium sulfate
you usually use a little bit more those
are in the cups per yard like I might do
uh you know half of a cup of magnesium
sulfate if I was deficient you know I I
it depends you know it depends on the
target the data but I'm always just
looking at the data and saying hey this
is how much is missing this is how much
needs to be added got it I think we have
time to squeeze in azomite you want to
talk about that a little better yep so
azomite is one of the Amendments that I
don't currently use anymore uh I have
found that it doesn't contain enough of
anything to realistically be of any use
that's what I found about it it says it
has a to z micronutrients and minerals
but when we're looking at a sufficiency
perspective the amount of azomite that
you would have to bring into a system to
actually have
the right amount of calcium or manganese
or zinc or that other stuff it's just
not there
it just doesn't exist so but there are
things that are associated with that
have been associated with azomite such
as heavy metals and aluminum
that could have detrimental impact on
the soil so this is one of those things
where for me
the cons outweigh the pros so I don't
see a big benefit if I wanted to add in
a type of rock mineral
I'm looking at it from us what
perspective why am I bringing in this
Rock mineral do I need to increase my
ECE
do I need to bring in calcium do I need
to bring in phosphorus
um all my micronutrients are covered
because I have micronutrient sulfates
and I have also meals organic meals that
contain those things so
it's more of just like a luxury thing if
you want to add it in you can I don't
recommend pump like relying on it for
anything in specific because it's not
going to do one specific thing it's just
kind of a luxury item to have that you
could use
and I always go with the less is more
approach right if it's not something
that I don't if I don't have to spend
extra money on it if it's not necessary
I'm not going to especially not at scale
because all of those additional costs
they all add up and as a small business
and as a farmer all of those additional
costs are something that we could have
put back into our pocket at the end of
the day and use for you know to take the
family on vacation you know get some
much needed R and R or you know to
get the tractor repaired or get the
tools that we need to to be successful
so
I'm always looking at this from really
cost uh analytical perspective and
that's actually the reason why I got
into Organics because I did Hydroponics
for 11 years and then I switched to soil
and I was using chemical synthetic
fertigation salts and it wasn't until I
needed to find a better uh business
model how I could reduce my costs that I
really started to look at all of the
inputs and that's the biggest thing as a
cultivator there's so many products on
the market and one of the classes that
we're going to be doing and we'll have
that live on page on our patreon is
going to be I'm going to have the people
that come into the class bring stuff in
from their home that they're using and
we're going to talk about what is in
there you know if you have a bottle a
bottled nutrient let's say Advanced
Nutrients right or something like that
that's uh 96 percent water and it has a
little bit of dymonium phosphates a
magnesium sulfate and potassium sulfate
in it well you can buy all those things
in bulk and cut and save yourself on
shipping a bunch of water and getting
ripped off
you know it's you're being overcharged
and then you're being taxed for shipping
and so it's it's it's really important
for any person who's cultivating at home
to understand what the product is that
they're using and if they're using X
product that has this this and this and
this and it know individually what these
components are used for and what what
benefits they have and and then figure
out hey
can I figure out how to apply this
single element itself like if something
has bone meal and crab meal and epsom
salt and gypsum and humic and fulfic
acids and all this other stuff and
they're jacked up the price way high
because they blended it when you know
you have to look at that you have to be
able to distinguish what is in the
products that you're using and figure
out
if you could do it more cost effective
or
if you're being you know charged extra
money just because there's a fancy logo
on it a lot of people fall into the Trap
of buying more than what they need and
really yeah they're spending more money
than they need to and they could be
spending their money elsewhere and it's
also one of the reasons why I do package
up these amendments individually for
people and there is a surplus on that
because it costs labor and packaging and
all that other stuff but we also Supply
bulk and 50 pounds so that way if you're
a farm or if you're if you need to get
these things in larger quantities you
don't you're not spending the money the
extra money to have it packaged and the
labor associated with that so you can
buy it all at the wholesale price which
is way more cost affordable I mean when
you go and buy a 50 pound bag of Epsom
salt for 25 bucks
I mean bam that's money you know you can
buy a 50 pound bag of gypsum for like 17
18 bucks in most cases you know so if
you have a provider someone that's local
to you that has all those things it's
just much more cost effective and it's
much more sensible from a business
perspective that makes sense so let's uh
let's wrap things up now who tell us how
can the listeners find you and what do
you have upcoming in the future yep so
uh you can find me on social media I
have two profiles
um and a backup account actually uh so
rust dot Brandon rust dot
b-r-a-n-d-o-n- I am Shadow band so you
have to type that out and then also
bokashi Earthworks which is
b-o-k-a-s-h-i Earthworks all one word
and that's uh on Instagram we also have
the website which is
www.bokashiearthworks.com where we
provide things like seeds we have
biostimulants amino acids all the
Amendments that we talked about we also
sell bulk soils uh amendments all that
other stuff so if if it's not listed on
the website
um you can just inquire through email
about pricing and all that other stuff
and then our patreon
um because of the censorship on social
media and we're seeing that right now in
the news Congressional hearings all that
other stuff it's been uh it's been
difficult to really reach a lot of the
people that that are following um so we
are off platforming you know we're
building up our our own platforms by
doing podcasts with great with other
great content creators like yourself
we'll have we have our own patreon where
we'll actually organize all of that
content and then we have exclusive
content uh we have live educational
presentations
for instance we're doing uh something
similar to what we're doing today we're
going to be more in depth we're going to
have all the Amendments on hand people
can look at them feel feel them
and that's going to be in class in
person in Oklahoma city so we have those
those will be live streamed on the
patreon and then slowly released over
the course of the next several months on
YouTube and stuff like that but yeah
it's it's a lot of moving Parts a lot of
things that we got going on but uh we're
we're working hard I'm working hard to
make it all happen come together awesome
well this has been another informative
episode Brandon I appreciate you coming
on here again and and spilling your
knowledge this is going to be one that
I'm gonna have to watch over and over
again in order to absorb all the
information that you uh revealed here
today so thank you so much for coming on
if you enjoyed this episode click that
Thumbs Up Button also subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend I'm releasing a new
Garden Talk podcast episode I'd love for
you to tune in to future episodes all
right Brandon I'll let you go for now uh
I'm pretty sure people are going to want
a part three so uh definitely welcome
you back in the future and we can
continue on this conversation all right
you have a great rest of your day I'll
talk to everybody soon thanks peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode