what is up everybody feel that don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and today I got a product unboxing video
for you but those of you been following
my channel for a while know that grown
with the California leg works solar
system 1100 LED grow light in two of my
past grows I was very satisfied with the
results I got from using that light and
California light works decided to
sponsor this video and send me over
their new light the solar extreme 500 in
this video we're gonna unboxing it and
we'll also talk about some of the
features
[Music]
[Applause]
this'll extreme 500 is a full-spectrum
LED grow light designed especially for
grow tents and small-scale home growing
I measure the unit and then mentions our
nineteen point two five inches by nine
inches by four inches and the fixture
weighs 11 pounds this LED realize good
for all stages of the growing from
seedling through flowering it has a
coverage area of full foot by four foot
when the plants are in the flowering
stage and five foot by five foot when
the plants are in the vegetation stage
simplicity is one word that I'd use to
describe this light
there's no switches knobs or dimmer to
make adjustments you simply hang the
light using the supplied hooks in your
choice of light hangers and then plug
the unit into the wall the girl light
consists of eight high efficient cob
LEDs and uses new direct AC drive
technology which eliminates a need for a
Cepheid LED driver this combination
results in not only less energy draw it
consumes only 400 watts but it also
allows the unit to be sold at a much
lower cost and other LEDs that have the
same coverage area now let's talk about
power output California light work lists
a few different ppfd measurements for
this LED grow light when the grow light
is hanging a distance of 18 inches ppfd
is 800 when the light is hanging at a
distance of 24 inches ppfd comes in at
500 on the screen right now is the light
spectrum emitted from the scroll light
California light works causes the solar
extreme up to grow full-spectrum the
fixture uses 3.3 amps at 124 thermal
management this unit has a large
aluminum heatsink and two active cooling
fans the way they work is air will come
in through the top of the fixture and
then blow out of the sides the heat
output on this unit is 1280 BTU
California light works borns that all of
their solar extreme series grow lights
will be free from defects in material
and workmanship for a period of one year
from the data purchase they also offer a
full satisfaction 90-day money-back
guarantee on all of their products they
have a few other lights in the series
the solar extreme 250 covers a three
foot by three foot area and the solar
extreme 1000 covers a five foot by five
foot area backs I have a factory tour
video on the YouTube page which I
thought was pretty interesting I'll link
that video in the description section
below for those of you want to see how
their grill lights are made they've been
in business since 2009 and
all of their products have made the USA
the cusp of the solar extreme 500 is
$449 and they provided a discount code
my viewers 15% off with code MGI 15 I'll
link to this girl light is in the
description section below what do you
think of this light let me know in the
comment section below that's pretty much
it for this video guys if you enjoyed it
please click that thumbs up and I will
leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]
[Applause]