spider from a recently launched a new
series of LED grow lights called the G
Series which is good for both home
growing and Commercial operations they
sent me the g8600 LED grow light which
is fantastic for a five foot by five
foot grow tent which is what you see it
in here but it'll also do great in an
open space they show a flower coverage
area of four feet by four feet in a veg
coverage area of five feet by five feet
they do have other grow lights in this G
Series for other size coverage areas
such as the g3000 for a three foot by
three foot grow tent g4500 for two foot
by four foot grow tent g5000 for a four
foot by four foot grow tent and the
g1000w for a 5 foot by five foot grow
tent hey everybody welcome back to my
channel for those of you that don't know
me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it and
today I have another product highlight
video for you in this series we
highlight some of the best gardening
products on the market today I'll talk a
little bit about the g8600 LED grill
light while I unbox the unit so you can
learn more about it and see what comes
in the Box I do have a discount code for
this grow light code Mr Groot 5 that
actually works for all spider farmer
grow lights and all of the products on
their website Linked In the description
section below opening up the box the
first thing here is a sticker pack they
include 10 stickers here is their user
manual which includes specifications for
all of the G Series grow lights
installation instructions user tips
warranty information and more the bars
are what comes out next there are eight
bars here for the g8600 yes this girl
like does require assembly although I
must say was actually pretty easy I'll
show you that in a minute they use
Bridge Lux diodes It's a combination of
Warm White Light 2800 to 3200 Kelvin
Pure White Light 4 800 to 5000 Kelvin
and what they call a rich red light 660
nanometers next out the box are these
plastic pieces these pieces connect the
driver to the grow light and this bag
there are four rope ratchet hangers and
an rj11 cord which is used to connect
and control multiple lights you can
actually connect up to 60 g8600 grow
lights at the same time very beneficial
for those of you in a commercial grow
operation driver hangers here's the
driver with the dimmer box attached it
also has a six and a half foot power
cord attached to it and lastly our two
frame pieces the girl at bars will
connect to them I place the two frame
pieces onto my coffee table and I'm
going to Simply clip both ends of the
LED bar to the fixture the first bar
slowly clicked into place since I wasn't
sure of how much force to use the
remaining Bars were much easier to put
in once I realized how much force to use
the wire on each bar then needs to be
connected to the frame so as you can see
I'm doing that here after all the wires
are connected to the frame we're ready
to attach the driver to the fixture I'm
using those plastic pieces that I showed
earlier sliding them onto the bottom no
screws needed those pieces will then
click onto the frame and the driver is
now secure since the driver is
detachable it can be placed outside of
the grow 10 instead this will result in
less heat being generated inside the
grow tent spider farmer said this will
also help provide a longer lifespan for
the grow light I like to use only one
row ratchet hanger on each side Loop it
over the grow tent top bar and then
latch each end onto the fixture the
dimmer box can be turned on full power
or you can adjust the dimmer anywhere
from 10 to 100 this unit pulls 860 Watts
from the wall at 100
PPE 2.8 micromoles per Joule ppf
2391 micromoles per second and the ppfd
map here shows the light spread across
the coverage area you can of course
maximize the light and increase plant
growth if you add CO2 spider farmer also
sent me their uvr 40 which is their UV
and IR bars it comes with mounting clips
its own driver and switch so you can
independently control the UV and IR
user manual
the two bars
and two pieces that connect the bars to
the frame
they were super easy to install they
latch onto the fixture and that's it
they list these benefits and have more
information about both the G series LED
grow lights and the UV IR light bars on
their website click the link down in the
description section below also place the
link in a PIN to comment and don't
forget to use the code Mr Grow at five
for a percentage off
what do you think of this grow light let
me know down in the comments section
below I hope you enjoyed this product
highlight video if you have any
suggestions for other products that I
should highlight in future videos let me
know thank you so much for watching and
I'll catch you in the next video