what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're watching my extra channel here I
have the spider farmer SF 1000 LED grow
light in this video I'm gonna unbox the
unit and also test the power output if
you want to know about the specific
features of this grow light or
specifications I will provide a link to
it in the description section below
after I open the box and pull out the
contents first up is a spider farmer VIP
card they've included some plant tags a
thank you card have a pretty nice user
manual here and now my cats teller is
gonna join us she's excited to see what
else is in the package after moving the
top you can see the LED grow light which
does have the driver and power cord
attached they've included wire hangers
and to ratchet hangers in this bag and
then lastly they've also included
measuring tape for the part test I'm
going to use the appo gmq 500 par meter
this meter measures from 389 nanometers
to 692 nanometers plus or minus 5
nanometers so if there's any light being
emitted from the scroll light that's
outside of this range it won't show on
this par meter measurements are shown in
ppfd
and this is just going to give you a
general idea of what the power output is
it's not meant to be a hundred percent
accurate I am taking measurements in a
grow tent which does have reflective
walls that could increase these part
numbers so just keep that in mind this
LED grow light has a flowering coverage
area of 2 foot by 2 foot I'm gonna take
measurements in a two foot by four foot
grow tent so I'll keep the light to the
side of the tent and keep the meter
within a two foot by two foot space I'm
gonna take measurements at three
different distances 12 inches away 18
inches away and 24 inches away now let's
take a look at the measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
again I have provided a link to this
grow light in the description section
below and I'll leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]