what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're watching max's channel
spider farmer sent me over there sf 2000
led grow light
and in this video i'm going to unbox the
unit i'll test the power output
and also do a heat test on it i'm not
going to talk about all of the grow
lights features
in this video but i will leave a link in
the description section below
so you can learn more about it spider
farmer also hooked me up with a discount
code for my viewers
i'll leave that in the description
section as well okay first thing out the
box
is this cable this cable is used for
multi-light connection
you can connect up to 12 lights next
thing out the box
is the user manual they've included
two rope ratchet hangers and some wire
hangers are also in this bag
the power cord is connected to the
fixture and here is the fixture
for the par test i'm going to use the
apogee mq620
extended range part meter this meter
measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers and the measurements
are in ppfd
if this your first time watching my pod
test videos i do them just to give you a
general idea of what the power output is
they're not meant to be 100 accurate i
take measurements in grow tents which
have reflective walls
that could increase the numbers so just
keep that in mind the flowering coverage
area for this grow light is
two feet by four feet and i'm taking
measurements in a two foot by four foot
grow tent
this light does have a dimmer on it for
the part test i'll set it to one hundred
percent i've plugged the led grow light
into my kilowatt meter
and it shows 1.72 amps pulling
203 watts alright let's get into the
measurements
[Music]
hey
um
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comments section
below
just a reminder that there is a link to
this grow light in the description
section below
and i'll leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
[Music]
peace
you