coming up on garden talk i usually start
by going around certain areas on google
maps and when i want to find a new spot
to grow outside cut it in a circle
so i uh cleanse in the middle and then i
clamp the medical plants in there so to
speak and then i try to go out through
the dishes so i just had a you know a
little bit of a spot i think that's
horrible if you're going to grow outside
i think i think you have to be
responsible of course and don't pollute
the nature be a grown-up you know take
your with you and or put it in a
trash bag nearby
choose often plants that are pretty
sturdy that are known for
they can handle these type of not
optimal conditions try to keep it pretty
minimalistic to take your with you
be responsible and that's my advice
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the guard talk
podcast this episode number 63. in this
episode i interview mackie he's been
gardening for six years and is a gorilla
grower in this episode he talks about
the many stealth practices that he needs
to do in order to grow his plants
without anybody knowing thanks to all of
you support this podcast through patreon
if you'd like to support you can do so
by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to spider farmer
for being a sponsor a new grow light
they released here in 2022 is the
se1000w
this was designed specifically for those
of you who run co280 grow space and
really want to maximize the light
intensity it has a 10 bar design for an
even light spread pulls 1000 watts from
the wall and comes in at 2.9 micro moles
per joule efficacy the recommended
coverage area is four feet by four feet
or five feet by five feet use discount
code mr groit5 to save on all spider
farmer products and i'll leave a link in
the video description section below
shout out to gorilla grow temp for
sponsoring this episode they have two
different size clone tents 18 inches and
24 inches the 18 inch clone tent is
designed to fit standard size seedling
trays the 24 inch tent which is the one
that they sent me is designed to fit the
super cloner 50 or two standard size
seedling trays they also have a clone
tent fan and filter which is designed to
fit perfectly in the rooftop micro mesh
compartment of both the 18 inch and 24
inch tents check out their website at
growstrongindustries.com
and use discount code mr growit for 15
off ac infiniti is a sponsor of the
podcast coupon code mr growit will get
you a discount on their products
i've been using their cloudline t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now and
absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high and low
humidity this greatly helps control my
indoor garden environment so the
temperature and humidity stays in the
ideal ranges i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit for discount on their
products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
mackie how you doing today
i'm good thanks how are you man i'm
doing great great thanks for asking
today we're going to talk all about
stealth growing so you are a gorilla
grower which is why you're hiding your
identity right now guerrilla growing for
those that don't know is someone who
cultivates on land that they don't have
the legal rights to cultivate on so it
could be private property abandoned
sites
areas that are being cared for so on and
so forth in order to do that you have to
implement stealth processes right so
that's what we're going to get into
today
but first how about an introduction can
you tell us a little bit about yourself
and how you got into gardening
of course
i live in scandinavia and uh i've been
gardening for uh pretty much
all my grown-up life i started my first
grow when i was like 19
now over 30 so i've been growing on and
off and mostly
outside
like real life style so i had a little
experience in the outside growing here
in scandinavia so just a quick
disclaimer we are not encouraging
anybody to break the law this episode is
particular for those who want to
implement stealth growing maybe have
family friends nosy neighbors that you
don't want to know about your grow so
that being said why not grow legally why
do you have to grow illegally where you
live
uh if you're serious uh
how it is here in the scandinavian
countries with a regulation
of the medical plants
you're not allowed to
[Music]
use it you're not allowed to grow it or
even have it on you so
that's why i
started to
do this gorilla type of growing and for
other reasons as well but
yeah i think it's
much better to do it yourself you know
what you get you don't get contaminated
products and
yeah it's easier yeah we had a
pre-meeting before we met today and you
had talked about contamination as well
is a big deal out there so
um is there dispensaries that you can
buy at or is everything just black
market out there
everything here is black market um it is
very restricted it's a very high um
you know you get
very big problems if you use it in any
way so
and because the black market is so big
here you get
really bad quality of products so that's
why i think a lot of people are starting
to implement more
guerrilla style of rome because they
know what they get and the black market
is just like that is a black market so
they
try to make the products way more and
stuff like that and you know get more
money out of people who don't know
anything about it so it's it's it's
about it's a bad market here i think
right now
so i gotta imagine that gorilla growing
is very common out there is that right
i think it's uh more common than people
might know here in scandinavian
countries especially in the summer time
because in the winter we can't grow here
because the climate is so cold and bad
you have a little bit better summer so
you can grow in the summer time here
okay that makes sense
so what is your overall style of
gardening are you doing indoors outdoors
or even soil or cocoa organic synthetic
what's your style yeah
uh if we're starting with medium i'm
usually growing in a soil
just mixing soil and
you know peat and perlite and also some
cocoa i have a little bit of lamb but i
don't use uh only cocoa or only salt so
it makes a little bit of both but i
never do hydro i don't know why i just
feel more comfortable to doing it in
soil
and uh regarding my growth style i grow
both indoors and outdoors on the winter
time winter months when it's really cold
here
i grow indoors of course um but then in
mid-may i uh starting to veg the plants
that i'm gonna put out in the summer
months so
i do both okay so you're vegging the
plants starting in may
and then when do you actually bring them
outdoors and plant them outdoors i
usually veg them for four or five weeks
right before the outer flowers go yeah
go into flowering
so they are pretty sturdy and they can
handle some hard wins here so then i put
them out so i batched around
eight templates in the uh mid of may and
then i put out them in mid june
and then then they get done in like the
end of july approximately and then i
have already
prevenged another 10 flowers or some
medical plants and then i put them out
so okay so you're doing multiple cycles
a year and you mentioned autoflowers are
you doing are all the plants autoflowers
yeah i usually do out of autoflowers now
because these summers here are uh pretty
short and the weather is not so
stable here in this canadian country so
all the flowers i think is the best best
just yet if you get uh some
quality autofocus they could handle
these temperature changes and um
i i there's some scandinavian companies
like northern seats that have great
outer floors so they
cultivate it for these type of
environments so they're perfect okay so
you mentioned you're vegging indoors for
about four five six weeks or four or
five weeks
so the plants are already flowering when
you bring them into outdoors then
they're going the remainder of their
life that's typically what like another
five six weeks until you harvest
um and you already have other plants
being started indoors at the same time
and so once those outdoor plants are
harvested
you're bringing those indoor plants that
you have
going at four or five weeks outdoors so
you're getting another cycle in
within the matter of just a couple
months there it's between harvests is
that right exactly exactly so i try to
get
at least two two cycles in one summer
around 20 plants
talking about a place to grow um how do
you go about determining a good piece of
land or a spot to grow in i usually uh
start by uh
going around certain areas on uh google
maps the first of all when i want to
find a new spot to grow outside
and i go go about it checking you know
the place and then i see if it's pretty
close to me so i can either walk there
or take my just take my bike
and get a backpack with water and
nutrition too so i can feed the plants
when they need water
and then i go and scout the place and
see uh if there is a little activity
around there not many people and of
course i don't want any houses close by
so people can see from inside of their
houses out and you know see me when i go
in and out of the the um
the area
that i picked
and um yeah then i just uh check the
area see how it is with the coverage of
bushes and stuff like that
it's hidden you know all that stuff so
how much sunlight are you looking
typically looking for that spot to be
able to get per day yeah i don't have uh
exactly i don't really count the hours
but i think at least like six hours i
think six seven hours i think it's
minimum here
um but i just try to see how the sun
goes when i'm standing it at the growing
spot outside see so there's not big
trees that cover the sun so they mostly
get sun you know at least half day you
know and during the time
outdoors
we're talking
june july
august
yeah what is the temperature and
humidity outdoors in the area where you
live or with the area where you plant
sorry
yeah it's uh
getting uh you know the humidity is
rising from the month to month but in
the middle of the summer it's around 50.
could be more if it's really really uh
humid here and really really hot
temperatures a really high summer day it
could of course go up to 60. around 45
to 50 i think it's i mean
on a regular summer day here are you
doing anything to camouflage the grow at
all so that nobody can see it uh i
usually um try to find a spot that is uh
[Music]
covered with uh not not big trees but a
little bit
like a little bit of bushy like a circle
uh area then i like get in a crowd
crawling like
two three meters in and then i cut it
like in a circle
so i uh cleanse in the middle and then i
plant
the medical plants in there so to speak
and then i try to go out through the
dishes
again so i just had a little bit of a
um you know a little bit of a spot to
have my plants in the middle so people
can't see through the bushes just
from above and i always imagine some
people actually doing like booby traps
too going as far as like atigan traps in
case anybody were to walk in that area
there needs like booby traps you set up
or anything to keep people away maybe i
should maybe i should like bear traps
and stuff but uh i haven't i haven't
done anything you know i think it's it's
going pretty good so so far so
do you worry about the smell at all
right so we know that these medicinal
plants they can certainly start to smell
that smell can
drift over to other areas
are you worried about the smell at all
do you do anything about the smell or
what uh i have actually
haven't got any problem with the smell
um
you can choose a strain that is a pretty
low odor strain like for example the
northern lights auto it's a it's a good
screen because it doesn't smell so much
if you are concerned about the smell
outdoors but where i usually have my
medical plants it is close to a big road
a bigger road and there's a lot of uh
cars and stuff like that so there's a
lot of
stuff going on in the air so it's pretty
hard you know and it's also pretty windy
there it's pretty hard for people to
notice any smell there so i haven't uh
have any problems with that but of
course it depends on where you put your
plants and how
the spring you choose how much they
smell gonna look look up the strain a
little bit beforehand you know be
cautious
of where you plant it
okay that makes sense
and then a problem that a lot of outdoor
growers face is pollination have you had
any issues with plants accidentally
pollinating your plants at all never
never actually i don't know if that is
just locked luck for me or um
what it is but i've never had a problem
with that when i'm wrong outside so
i'm pretty happy about that
okay
and then as far as kind of going back to
like the camouflage stuff and staying
hidden
um you know back in the day
we're talking 20 plus years ago in the
states there was huge crackdowns those
helicopters flying all over the place
they were coming down on these groves
they were looking from above coming down
once they found found these medicinal
plants chopping down plants
and really spending a lot of time
money
on doing this process
do you face any of that in your area are
there always helicopters flying around
actively looking for guerrilla grow
grows and taking plants down
uh no i never heard of
anyone that get uh
you know get in trouble that way you
never hear any helicopters where i live
here
it's not a big city where i live it's a
medium city in this game one of the
scandinavian countries and we don't have
these type of resources here i feel that
they're gonna do these type of big
operations just looking for uh
you know medical plants and stuff like
that so uh i've never heard of anything
uh about that
you know matter so i think you're
totally cool uh you don't have to worry
about that you know of course if you
have a very very
big scale operations outside with
like 500 2 000 plants
maybe you gotta be a little bit more
cautious of course but if you have like
10 20 something like that
i don't think you have to worry about a
thing you know
that makes sense so you're doing it on a
little bit smaller of a scale than some
of the other gorilla growers are right
so you said around 10 plants at a time
so yeah 10 10 uh approximately 10 15
sometimes you know
it depends a little bit about how the uh
the place is looking where i'm gonna set
them if it's big enough or how much do
they handle and stuff like that so do
you grow in the same spot year after
year are you switching up locations
every year
i i usually switch up locations um
because
just just for having a little bit more
caution you know
and this sort of people
you know
notice me going there every summer at
the same time and you know
just to try to be a little bit more uh
low-key and under the radar try to
switch it up um try different places for
different spots
see which spot is best you know how how
the plants feel you know stuff like that
so you do your initial
investigation i guess we call it right
your initial searching for a piece of
land
i'm assuming you're doing that in may or
maybe early june maybe a week or so
before you plant
from indoors you're into a plants plant
i'm outdoors is that right
yeah exactly
at that point your oil flowers you said
they're weak five-ish
they're pretty decent size i would
imagine how are you bringing the plants
in into the location without getting
spotted uh that's a good question i
usually take uh
like bigger plastic bags uh that i just
can't just carry and then i
either go with uh
my car and just put it
in the back seat on my car just go back
and forth a couple of times in hours
that i know
and not a lot of people are going there
so i try to make it as quick as possible
of course and not be in the location
for too long uh you know so people
started wondering what
that guy is doing in the bushes there
you know that's
to be a little bit weird but uh just big
plastic bags depending on how big the
plants
are you know i can have some uh you know
what they call it like a lot laundry
bags they're pretty high sometimes some
you know ikea bags
and stuff like that so it depends on the
height of the plants but
you know i'm growing usually out of
flowers and they don't get so tall so i
usually don't have
mega bags you know when i put them out
okay so you get the plants to the
location and then are you keeping plants
in containers at that time or are you
doing the transplanting process to where
you're digging down into the ground and
then transplanting from the containers
and planting into the ground
uh last year i just put the plastic
containers outside
just on the ground just for easy because
it was a pretty uh hidden
location that was uh i didn't have to
grow them down in the ground you know to
make it more stealth
so i you know
didn't you know started digging the soil
and ground stuff like that so it depends
a little bit uh how the location is
looking if i want to be more stealth and
if people can you know see through it
and maybe watch plants or see that
something's going on maybe i dig them
down
but uh this year i'm finding a good
location right now and uh i think i'm
just going to
put the put the containers out on the
ground
you know so make it easier for myself
you know
do you do anything for hardening off and
for those that don't know what hardening
off is it's doing things to acclimate
your plants that you started indoors to
the outdoor environment are you doing
anything for hardening off of the plants
mostly not but it depends a little bit
on the weather here if i have uh
you know if it's starting to be pretty
good weather a couple weeks before i put
them out
sometimes i can just put it on my
balcony uh some of those plants it is
really great weather
uh
so make them accustomed to the outside
climate a little bit more and the wind
and stuff like that but i usually don't
think about that as much um i
choose often plants that are pretty
sturdy that are known for
they can handle these type of not
optimal conditions that is here in where
i lived so
i haven't had any problems with that uh
to harden them and stuff like that i
think they um they
are pretty good you know when they're
ready and
yeah they could handle the switch from
inside the outdoors pretty pretty good i
think so okay and then once you get to
the location you have your plants there
how many trips back and forth are you
typically doing per week
in order to
you know get in there with maybe you're
bringing in equipment or tools
fertilizer
watering the plants can you talk to us
about all of that yeah um you know first
time then first time i get there i just
putting the plants there don't do
anything and then i get out as quick as
possible
then i usually wait for approximately
five days before i go there so maximum
once a week i i go to the spots and just
water them i have bottles in my backpack
two liter bottles pre-filled
pre-fertilized everything is ready so i
can just take them off you know out of
my backpack
and just splash it on the medical plants
you know as quickly as possible and then
i'm out again
so i just i don't like lurk around in
the spot too long i just do what i have
to and then i get out there
and get out of there as quickly as
possible so
every five days i would say i go to the
spot in the summertime but if it is a
really
warm summer and the plants of course
need more water
i might get there
every third day or something like that
depending on the weather of course and
then what are you using for fertilizer i
usually usually just
use one fertilizer it's a bloom
fertilizer it's nothing special it's a
brand from here it's a local brand
so i can't give any recommendations but
it's a very it has everything you need
and i don't use that before uh
the i think is the fourth or fifth week
so after five weeks i started to use
that on the on the plants but not before
i don't think they need it the special
outer flowers they're pretty fragile
easy to over fertilize these type of
plants
so i use a synthetic fertilizer when
they're starting to bloom
usually when i put them out the first
week
and then i use it every watering
until they're ready to harvest basically
so and now you're checking like a ppm or
an ec or are you ignoring those things
and just kind of doing the
um
every week feeding
every five days or whatever how often
you go to the site yeah i don't check
anything about that not ph nothing like
that they just try to keep it as simple
as possible uh just
taking the recommendations on the bottle
that i know
they can handle i've tried it before of
course
on the strain before so i know i don't
over fertilize so i know my measurements
how much they need and how much they can
take
and then i just mix it up with water and
then i'm out doing the thing i don't
use any boosters or any stuff like that
i just have a simple
you know good fertilizer for for the
blue stage that i think works really
good for me i use it even indoors as
well
and you know yeah it's it's pretty
simple but it works you know i don't
think you have to complicate it so much
you know if you have a
good uh like round fertilizer yeah basic
fertilizer so i can imagine that you you
you've brought in the nutrients there
and you just keep the nutrient bottles
there on site and so every five days
you're just using the bottles that
you've left there at that spot
the water i'm still trying to wrap my
head around because you you said you've
gotten 10 plants at a time
it seems like a lot of water would need
to be brought in are you doing multiple
trips
for water i usually i usually just do
one trip i just fill but i don't water
them that much i give them maybe like
50 centiliters 60 centiliters
of water to each plant so
i don't over water them i'm pretty
cautious with how much i water them i
think
for a seven to nine liter container that
i usually use for these outer flowers
they don't really need that much you
know
uh and i don't try to flush them too
much so they can hold the nutrients
in the container so i don't flush them
up every time
and you just have to use even more
nutrients so i usually have
a lot of two liter bags have a big
backpack just pressing them down
i uh pre uh fill it back home so i don't
have any nutrients at the spots so i
just pre-fill everything at home put it
in my backpack just go with my bike
or or my car sometimes but usually my
bike uh early in the morning
water them and then it's uh then it's
done for five days usually so okay and
then you said you don't do any type of
flushing um you'd like to just water in
so there's really no runoff happening
for the entire grow now what about at
the end of the grow before harvest a
common technique that we know of is
flushing right they'll flush the
nutrients out of the medium in order to
kind of force that senescence to happen
within the plants
are you doing a flush
before harvesting yeah i have i've heard
that a lot of people do that but i've
also heard that it doesn't make any
sense to the plants
if you flush or not that's what i've
heard uh
like later later studies now that
recently came out
from uh
like really good growers so i never
flush i don't care about that uh maybe
you should maybe you don't i don't know
i haven't heard anyone that could tell
the difference from the plants that has
been flushed and from one that haven't
been flashed but
i don't know it's up to each
uh each person to know if
they won't flush or not but i i usually
don't care about that you know yeah in
my opinion i think it's pretty good that
you don't flush
the reason why is one thing that's very
common with the gorilla growing is you
hear about people
using synthetic nutrients outdoors
flushing their plants
runoff of phosphorus and nitrogen going
to the local local streams close by and
then toxic algae blooms occurring it's a
huge problem huge problem around the
world actually and it's happening due to
these fertilizers overuse of fertilizers
so you kind of getting into more of a
precision thing not doing the runoff
it's really better for the environment
right you're not having those nutrients
run off and cause issues yeah exactly
phosphorus is
yeah as you said first phosphorus is
horrible to get down in the ground of
course as well
and then another thing you often see is
in gorilla grows is trash being left
around and now this is obviously this is
the mainstream media we're talking about
so they're going to film guerrilla grows
they're going to focus on the trash
left over
what's your stance on that are you and
you can be honest are you leaving the
trash hanging around are you collecting
the trash no i i no of course i think
that's horrible if you're going to grow
outside i think you have to be
responsible of course and don't pollute
the nature you know and uh
be a grown-up you know take your
with you and or put it in a trash bag
nearby i try to just take every bottle
and stuff like that with me when i go
home again just put it in my backpack
and down i'm going off you know so
it's not that i
stay at the spot for so long so i just
have my water bottles i water then i put
them down back in my backpack and i'm
out of there again so i don't have like
basically anything around there laying
around you know it's just a plan to
stand there you know you would think
that would be a tip for to stay stealth
right is to remove the trash because if
people see the trash people walk by the
area they see the trash that's gonna
you know attract some eyes towards that
way so resist uh so try to keep it
pretty minimalistic to take your
with you uh and you know be
irresponsible and that that's my advice
how do you avoid getting spotted i mean
you're going there pretty frequently
right every five days or so you're going
there
how do you avoid getting spotted are you
going at a certain time of the day where
maybe there's less population around the
area
or have you ever gotten spotted before
yeah i try to go of course times where i
know that a lot of people are either at
work or sleeping so
like five in the morning 4 30 sometimes
in the summer time i think it's a it's a
good
time to go there if you're gonna water
and um of course i don't pick a spot
that there is a lot of houses nearby but
uh there are three people of course
walking that could see you so you gotta
choose to be there at certain times you
know you have to like put your alarm
maybe early in the morning to uh
minimize the risk of someone seeing you
at the spot or maybe in the middle of
the night but i think it's better in the
in the early morning to do it so you can
see
where your plants are all right you did
mention a somewhat high of a humidity
early on in this episode you know at
high humidity days you're at risk for
things you know so your risk at bud run
mold powdery mildew are you facing any
of those issues at all has that happened
to you at all yeah it's happened a
little bit but uh it's you know
not not a whole plant you know not a
whole plant had some some buds that were
affected uh last year and i just cut
them off and just threw them away of
course
but
yeah you can't really do anything about
it you know you have to um
hope that everything is going pretty
good and that's uh summer is pretty
windy that also get a lot of sunshine so
it gets the air circulation
around the the medical plants that you
have planted outside and also maybe you
can choose a location that is not too
windy of course but have a little bit of
a air circulation so it's not
so closed off that they can't like
breathe and there's too heavy of a
too heavy bushes or trees around so they
it's suffocated basically but
yeah it's it's uh i think it's bigger
problem inside with bad ventilation that
is
outside depending on the weather of
course but
i think they're gonna be fine
so that's one problem the other problem
would be a very common outdoors is pests
um what do you do in order to prevent
pests from invading your grow outdoors
yeah that's a good question uh i usually
put
this copper tape around the stem of the
plants uh because we have a lot of
problem with snails here that likes to
chew on the
medical plants
so i usually just take a pet bottle like
if you simply do cola bottle or
something like that cut it off you know
like yeah this uh big so i just cut it
cut off a bit of the uh
bottle in a circle and then i just put
it around the stem in the uh lower part
and then i take the copper band around
i'm gonna put it on all the plants so
they can't like climb up
on the stem and chew on your plants you
know so that's basically the one thing i
always do and it uh it helps a little
bit
but of course you can't do
everything and i don't want to
spend too much of money on certain
things and pest control and
yada yada so that's the only thing i do
it's going to be pretty good actually
and now talking about plant training
flip it up a little bit do you do any
type of
training in all plants whether it be any
low stress training topping super
cropping filming any of the training
techniques at all
yeah i uh usually did more back in the
day uh with the techniques but i have
noticed uh that if you
i don't know if
this is of course some plants can handle
the family better than others but if you
for example film more tops on
autoflowers okay they get more branches
they get more bud sites and of course
but
sometimes i feel that the buds are
too like uh
they're they're not so hard what do you
call it
not so dense exactly so
the less you do to stress the plant i
think that's better of course you get a
little bit less of uh outcome some say
when they're ready
but uh yeah
maybe just some filming sometimes i do
but i don't really low stress the plants
i put out
maybe just filming something like that
something easy i don't want to spend too
much time
on it you know
to stress train them how big are these
plants actually getting before you like
when you harvest how big are the plants
yeah um as you know autoflowers don't
grow as big as uh for the period plants
so they're not huge monsters but uh
of course they grow a little bit bigger
outside than indoors so around 120 to
one and a half meters i think it's um
could be
approximately how big they get outside
what i've seen from my growth at least
but uh of course you can grow bigger oil
flowers and or smaller as well but
around there and then so you make that
decision to harvest the plants are you
harvesting
all the plants at the same time and then
doing trips back and forth on the same
day in order to
remove the plants from the site i try to
uh
harvest the same day
actually uh hopefully
of course they're the same strain but of
course they can differentiate how long
in the development the plants are but
i usually try to harvest the same day or
each
other day
uh to minimize me going front to back
front and back all the time you know it
makes my
potential that someone might see me and
also i don't want to do that
so then i just harvest them
every plants in one day hopefully and
then i put them down
in uh like black sacks
plastic bags bigger plastic bags then i
get out of there
and then i usually wait some days and
then i take the plastic containers with
me again
so i just clean the spots
a couple days later all right so then
you bring them back to your your home
let them dry exactly what do you
typically do for drying conditions
i usually have a spare room where i live
and then i have uh my window there
on a little bit half open
so and then i hang it
just straight down i have for the uh
what do they call it the cur the curtain
there's a pole a curtain pole and just
hang them there
and then i have a fan that's just
blowing uh through the room
uh so yeah and so i have some like odor
control uh buckets of some kind that i
do usually place out around them so it
doesn't
smell so much but uh yeah it works
pretty good actually so
it's very very minimalistic you know but
you know what what can you do
and so do you do do you do a wet trim or
a dry trim i always uh dry trim actually
i always stretch them i just take the
bigger
leaves off
first before i hang them up to dry so it
gets a little bit better aeration
between the the plants and the stems
they don't touch each other and stuff
like that
and uh then when they're dry usually
just five six days i think then they're
pretty good i've done
usually the same process putting them in
glass containers or in the other process
with curing
let's get deeper into curing so you're
putting them into glass containers what
size containers are you working with and
are you doing any of the the burping
process uh you know a common process
that's used
yeah of course i uh
how many liters are they i think they're
around
1.8 liters i have mason jar containers
with extra lid on top that i usually use
glass containers always
after six days before i've
cut them down and trimming the buds
after six days i put them down in the
containers and then every day i open
them for at least an hour first week
and then i close the lid again and then
the second week i do it less frequently
and just feel the buds
see how they react to your curing
process you know just smell them
look for eventual mold and stuff like
that and there if you feel
that they're pretty you know moist still
maybe you should keep the lid off for
longer so it's
up to each and everyone to just feel the
flowers and see how they react to your
your hearing process and um you know
so it's hard to give a recommendation
that um
i just
just go and feel and basically see
feel smells and i'll see how they react
are you eventually packaging
up
and
selling locally
or are you growing for yourself
yeah i mostly grow for myself and some
friends you know can
get something if they want but i'm not a
i don't you know self like big scale
it's just for me myself you know some
people take a beer to relax and i can
take something before i
go to bed to calm down sometimes if you
have a stressful life like a lot of us
do you know with work and family and
stuff so
it's just a relaxation for me it's
definitely relaxing that is for sure
yeah
all right so we went through just about
everything there in a nutshell um i did
want to ask you
for those that are looking to implement
stealth growing whether it be you know a
nosy neighbor that they want to hide it
from a friend family member do you have
any general advice for them uh
i think you should
first first of all
like read read a little bit about it
on the internet before you start
something get some knowledge before uh
be pretty cautious where you buy
the stuff that you need to do this
and
don't say anything to anyone if you're
gonna do this
the way i do it don't tell anyone not
your friends no one uh just keep it for
yourself do it
in your own spare time and don't over
complicate things and buy
a ton of fertilizers from different
brands you just want to sell your stuff
to make money
try to keep it simple
buy something from a uh you know
well-established brand that knows work
read a little bit about the company and
stuff like that
and you know scout the location and
everything like that beforehand a couple
of months before
looking people around or they're walking
a lot of people around your site
houses
you get easy access to the growing space
that you choose outside when you have to
get your car there and stuff like that
you know so try to keep it uh as close
to you as possible
minimalistic and be cautious of course
that's that's the
most important thing you know all right
lots of advice there so wrapping things
up uh any final words that you have
before we end this podcast i just wanna
say thank you for letting me uh into the
podcast it's been a been a pleasure and
um hope everything uh yeah i hope
everyone is growing some good stuff out
there of course and um yeah if anyone
wants to uh
have any or if anyone had any questions
they can just mail me you can put my
mail down in the description if you want
or
whatever just say hi you know i'm happy
to help if anyone has any questions
about
this style of uh growing so well mackie
thanks for coming on this has definitely
been um insightful uh something new
something different from what we've had
on the podcast before
thank you for reaching out to me and
suggesting this as a topic and your
willingness to come on
and
talk to us about what you do you know
stealth growing gorilla growing whatever
you want to call it my pleasure if you
enjoyed this episode click that thumbs
up button subscribe if you haven't
already every single weekend i'm
releasing a new garden talk episode and
i'd love for you to tune in to future
episodes mackie once again thank you so
much and hope you enjoy the rest of your
day thank you you as well man peace out
everyone
you