welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody if you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow you're tuned into to the Garden
Talk podcast this episode number 120 in
this episode I interview Chris from
Happy Hydra he's been gardening for over
20 years and is the owner of happy
hydro.com he was on the podcast once
before episode three yeah major
throwback there where he talked all
about the environment for plants growing
indoors this time around he talks about
Stealth gardening indoors he reveals
several tips and tricks in order to keep
things stealth if you want to see
highlights of these podcast episodes
search Garden talk clips on YouTube that
channel is dedicated to short bite-sized
clips of these episodes I also have a
gardening Channel where I have over 130
videos showing the plants that I've
grown in my garden I'll have that
channel linked down in the YouTube
description section below one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to a Infinity for sponsoring this
episode check out their instant potty
mix a soiless grow medium made from 100%
organic coca COA fiber it's buffered and
triple washed to maintain pH stability
and reduce salinity it comes in a 2 lb
brick which expands to fill up to a 3
gallon growt click the Link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their instant potting
mix and the discount code Mr Gro 15
works on both Amazon and their website
AC infiniti.com stash blend stash blend
is a 215 plant additive that can used
with synthetic bottle nutrients or in
living soil systems simply mix half
teaspoon of stash blend into a gallon of
water then water your plants with it
ingredients include corn steep liquor
seaweed extract humic acid beneficial
bacteria silica and Michael risle fungi
check it out at stash blend.com Link in
the description section below and use
the discount code the stash and we're
back welcome to the Garden Talk podcast
today I am joined with Chris from Happy
Hydro how you doing today doing well man
how are you doing doing good thanks for
asking it's been a while dude it's good
to be back I know right I was just going
to say you uh were the third episode on
Garden talk this was actually back in
January 2021 I dug this up we talked
about the environments for indoor plants
temperature humidity CO2 and air
circulation and that has over 258,000
views on YouTube alone and that doesn't
even count the podcast platforms because
we're on there as well which I never
expected and I actually had someone from
my hometown come up to me when I was
there like over the summer they're like
Yo dude I saw you on Mr Grow I'm like
what so that's funny dude it was uh yeah
man you've came a long way dude yeah it
and you've been around for a long time
at least our you know relationship I
think 2017 is when we really first
connected and you wanted to do a
sponsorship through me and you were one
of the first ones I had you and then
like I think one or two of the brands
actually reach out to me and once I
found out about you and really when we
sat down and had that first conversation
and I learned about you your vision
happy High
how you put customers First Quality
first I knew that it was a good fit and
here we are what five years six years
later and we're still like connecting
we're still collaborating and I'm still
a big supporter of happy Hydro so really
glad to have you on here today we got a
great topic we're going to be talking
about Stealth gardening indoors I
actually had somebody uh do stealth
gardening outdoors guy over in in Europe
actually and I had to like disguise his
voice he had to put a mask on it was it
was pretty crazy but indoor is going to
be a whole different Battlefield so I'm
excited to get into this with you yeah
dude me too it's uh it has been a long
time and I'm pretty sure when we did
that first um that first sponsorship I
don't even think I really had a website
yet it was just starting up you know on
Amazon I had like a basic website with
just like scissors and led Loop and
stuff but uh we came a long way now dude
like we've got everything you can ever
imagine on the site and um I'm going to
take this opportunity to shout out to
the boys and and girls um my friends
that I work with and you know I've known
these people for 10 20 years Matt uh
Aaron Brandon Nick lordes and Jessica
that's the happy Hydro team and and like
I I just feel like I wouldn't be sitting
here with you for the second time here
um if it wasn't for them so thank you
guys U if you guys uh if you guys ever
shop at happy hydro.com you'll probably
interact with any of these people so
they're doing a good job and we all love
what we do so great team over there I've
met a handful of them in person and
really really for the customer again and
for Quality you're doing great things
over there so keep it up but before we
get too deep into the topic we talk
about Stealth gardening here can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening well um it
started when I was you know pretty young
um first plan I grew uh in my bedroom
and I had tin foil on the walls it was
in the closet I was just watching
YouTube videos uh you know just one
plant you know I want to try to grow it
and I don't know a month in two months
in my mom found it ripped it all apart I
just walked in one day and it was all
gone I like bummer
dude tried getting it back didn't
work um but you know after that I just
was always intrigued by it um this was
back in you know 2014 15 16 17 um it was
a different landscape um and I'm in New
York where things you know just this
year uh within the past two years have
become legal and and and free I've spent
a lot of time and met a lot of people
who have had had to stealth grow so I uh
I worked at the hydro store for a long
time where I just got to meet so many
people and learn so much um so I'm
excited to share some of those stories
and some that knowledge I've learned uh
throughout the years about how to keep
your grow on the on the down low um cuz
even if it is legal you know some
landlords don't like it your neighbors
might not like it it's super smelly it's
not like it's not like just drinking a
couple beers you know you don't smell
beers Three Doors Down so I think it's
important even though um even if you are
in a legal State just to be respectable
uh to your neighbors and and just you
know landlords whatever everyone it's
it's an important thing to know I think
absolutely absolutely and you not only
have experienced growing medicinal
plants but you also have a vegetable
garden cck my from wrong which you have
a pretty extensive vegetable garden you
do I think it's mostly Outdoors youve
probably doubled indoors I'm assuming
can you kind of break down what you've
got growing on a little bit yeah um so
right now I have a 4x8 Grassroots fabric
pot in my backyard with a blue mat
watering system it's the uh soaker hose
uh blue soak system so basically it's
just hooked up to my hes um the fabric
back
has uh it's like a plastic liner in the
middle of it so it keeps the the
moisture content a little higher inside
of the um inside of the bed than a
typical fabric pot paired with the um
paired with the blue mats that are just
constantly releasing just the tiniest
bit of moisture um I've got a ton of
living soil and compost and top soil and
perlite um in there and and man dude
things just you're talking 8ot tall
tomato plants at the end of the year
it's just insane like unlimited amounts
of zucchini um and I really don't have
to do anything you just you set the blue
mat up you plant the seeds in the
beginning and it's just go time uh a
little bit of weeding but not much being
in the 4x8 bed so um I've actually
really enjoyed I've really enjoyed
growing in that for bed and growing um
Tomatoes cherry tomatoes
um I'm a huge fan of zucchini and squash
uh we do basil and carrots my son he's
two and a half he loves the carrots um
he'll dig them up three times and I'll
have to replant them and they'll come
out all like kind of mangled at the end
of the year but he's still stoked so I'm
I'm
happy and uh and yeah and then my wife
um she grew up on a farm and uh so she
has a ton of
experience uh growing flowers and just
being in green houses and stuff so it's
just like you know it's nostalgic it's
fun and I really can't wait to teach my
son how to you know Garden on his own
and and and just continue like I could
see myself adding more and more uh
raised beds and uh you know I'll sneak a
medicinal plant in that raised bed every
every once in a while nice nice yeah you
mention your son and and being able to
teach him to Garden in the future and as
you know I have a daughter now and I
same way I cannot wait till I can start
teaching her how to garden as far as
hiding those things from your son right
are you going to be kind of stealth
around him or you going to eventually
introduce your plants to your your
children at some point early on or what
so if I had it if I was um growing in
the house I would be very um cognizant
of odors uh mostly just odors you know
noise and everything else not a big deal
um but my philosophy really is to treat
it just like a beer or
alcohol um it's not for kids it's for
grown-ups and
so you know I don't really feel the need
to hide it but if I if I were growing
indoors just for the respect of my whole
family I would make sure that you know
odor is controlled all the time and um
which can be difficult especially when
you're opening your tent um you know you
could have your odor perfectly fine and
then you open the tent for 20 minutes
and now your whole house is is stinky so
there's some tricks that we can talk
about to um to kind of combat that
and and to kind of set yourself up in a
way that you can still work in your
garden but also have uh control over o
odors and and and to be stealthy yeah
let's get into that we can probably get
into that first but one thing I did want
to comment on just a followup is yeah I
feel the same way about as far as not
really hiding it from the kid but
teaching them that this is for adults
right it's something for adults maybe
keep them distance right you don't want
them be in contact with the the TR
tricomes or anything all of a sudden
they get all over the hands or anything
like that so all the toy all the toys
are sticking to their hands what are you
doing yeah you walking there they're
hanging all the things all over the plan
like a Christmas tree or something that
be pretty but no I I I totally get what
you mean by that and um I think that's
kind of a separate conversation is kids
and medicinal plants and when you
introduce to them and and teach them and
so on and so forth we actually had that
conversation on the from the stash
podcast I know you know Rob and pigeons
long time ago we talked about that I
thought that was a great conversation
but a whole different SE separate
conversation there let's get into
stealth growing and I think you brought
up the smell first let's talk about that
and then we could probably get into some
other things like how to get equipment
in and out of the house how you hide it
from roommates or your landlord and how
to hide light and so on and so forth so
for smell when you've got the smell
there right these plants do smell
particularly in the flowering stage
right even in veg you're going to have
some plant smell happen how do you go
about hiding the smell I'll start with
like the easiest kind of quickest but
laziest way and um and that is you know
say say the smell is just kind of out of
control you know you haven't been taken
care of it whatever and you got someone
coming
over and uh you know you just don't want
them you don't want them to know about
it you know maybe they maybe they know
that you consume but you don't want them
to know about light one up just light
one up clouded up and now they're just
going to smell that and they're not
going to know that you've uh you've got
a garden in the in the back bedroom so I
guess that's like number one easiest
laziest kind of
just but really it's uh it's tough It's
Not Easy because you know like I said
you open up the tent smell leaks out uh
you harvest how do you trim a plant
without stinking up the whole house I
mean it's not easy um but there are some
things that that you can do um but
before we get into those I think the
first thing we should talk about is um
negative
pressure so um negative
pressure is when uh you're say you're
looking at your grow tent and you have
your your fan it's sitting on top of the
carbon filter or maybe the carbon filter
is mounted and the Fan's uh beside it
and it's pumping air out um through the
ducting you'll notice that the sides of
the tent start to squeeze
in and when those sides of the tent are
squeezing in that means that no air is
leaking out through your zipper holes
through um the holes in the bottom of
the tent uh in the bottom of the tent
the mesh holes basically any hole um
because no matter how well a tent is
built there's always going to be a hole
whether you can see it or not that odors
can get out
so negative
pressure basically makes it so the
stinky air that's in the tent only has
one way out and that's through the
carbon filter where it's scrubbed of
odors and then out the tube
um you got to check that tubing for
holes if there's a hole in your ducting
um your whole your carbon filter will be
useless you got to check your
connections um where your ducting
connects to the carbon filter uh where
it connects to the fan you got to make
sure all those are tight and sealed uh
you can use um tape you make a special
duct tape um not like your traditional
duct tape but like the foil duct tape
that can that is heat resistant that you
can seal it up with but then it's like
you know say you do all that and you got
your negative pressure and everything's
good but you got to work on your plant
you got to open up the tent you open up
that tent there's not going to unless
your fan is you know a 12in monster
vortx vanan and a 2x4 tent you're not
going to be able to keep negative
pressure with a with the door open it's
it's not going to happen so there's ways
around that um one way is a lung room so
you you utilize either the closet or the
bedroom that your grow tent is in as a
quote unquote lung room so what you
could do is you could have a a 4in
carbon fan and filter inside of the tent
that is creating negative pressure in
the tent at all times and then inside of
the bedroom or closet that you're in you
can have a bigger fan That's rated for
whatever size the room is with a carbon
filter um exhausting out the window so
now you've got you've got negative
pressure twice you've got it in the
tent and then you also have it in the
room and you want to make sure that the
door is closed to the room uh when
you're working in there obviously but
that that should protect you right so if
you open up the tent you still have
negative pressure in the room so the
smell isn't going to leak out under the
door and you can work in there and then
you can close it up and you know once
you know a half hour after you close it
up if if you want you could turn off the
um carbon filter in the big room you
know you know and only uh run it in the
small room so I think that is really
kind of the biggest thing that uh that
people can do to really like have it
under control for for most of the time
um you have a little bit of experience
with this so is that something that you
ever tried yeah carbon filters are
definitely key I ran carbon filters for
many years now I don't even bother to
run them anymore to be honest with you
cuz I'm just pumping it out up into my
attic and it's being ventilated it out
my roof but I'm not really hiding the
smell I don't really need to hide the
smell much anymore what about aren't
there like gel products or something
that you can that come in containers
that people use have you used any of
those are those effective or incense
some people burn incense I've never used
incense for that I mean I've used
incense to cover up uh when I was
lighting up when I was 16 in my bedroom
but I don't think it I don't think it
tricked my mom to be honest with you
they don't smell that bad in the veg
stage um they do a little bit you know
what I mean like it's still it's it's
it's enough but it's not as nearly uh as
potent as the bloom stage and also uh
when I was doing a little bit of
research on this just to kind of recap
before the podcast I I found that there
are some um varieties out there that are
uh have lower odors like they're just
known for having lower odors and so
that's also something that if people are
concerned about they can look into
but the um the gel blocks that you're
referring to um Ona blocks is one of the
um this is basically the top brand and
they work fantastic they've got
thousands of reviews four and a half
stars um we sell them on Happy Hydro so
if anyone wants to look for them they
can take a look but um mostly if you
have your carbon filter set up properly
and you have uh some sort of lung room
kind of set up properly too you don't
need them um really until like your
Harvest and your trimming and and just
when it gets to a point where you know
it gets a little out of control when
you're harvesting and trimming um so
that's when you can you might want to
introduce something like these Ona
blocks that just basically overpower the
the odor with its own odor it's like for
breeze on steroids almost yeah I haven't
personally tried that stuff but uh I've
heard some good things about it what
about hiding the light something people
may say oh what are you talking about
light it's sealed up in the grow tent so
you're not really it's going to not
really be exposed but what about like
people just growing in a bed room for
example the window there might be light
leakage to the window there might be le
leage underneath the door and they try
to hide it from their roommates or
family members talk to us about hiding
the light one of the best tricks for
hiding the light uh from escaping
outside of the window um is to just have
like you know normal curtains in front
of the window and then you can build a
box out a 2x4 and plywood that just
comes out and around the curtain and
just install
that over top of the curtain that way
whoever is looking into the house you
know it just looks like normal curtains
there's no uh there's no black garbage
bag taped over the window or just
there's no nothing weird like that it's
just you know normal curtains so that's
one of the best tricks um otherwise yeah
you're pretty much stuck to just using
like some 7 mil uh Panda film you know
black and white to to uh to to to block
the light out or something of the sort
those are kind of those are mostly the
only options um and then even with grow
tents you know if you're you're growing
in a grow tent and you're having people
over grow tents leak
light um pretty much all of them leak a
little bit of light whether it's through
a stitch and a zipper or whatever um so
a lot of grow lights and a lot of this
equipment nowadays you can um control
from your phone with these automation
apps so if you know someone's coming
over or whatever and uh you can shut the
light off for a little while uh you can
turn your turn your fan down to its
lowest setting you don't want to turn
your fan uh off completely because then
your odors you you'll lose your negative
pressure and your odors will leak out
but uh you turn your fan down to its
lowest setting quiet it down turn the
light off
um and those are those are some tricks
you know yeah for me I use polyfilm that
you mentioned I have them covering my
window so it really does look black on
the outside but I have sunscreens as
well I'm in the desert and sunscreens
are very valuable out here during the
daytime you can't really see that it's
like a black sheet you know and during
night time you'd have to actually be
shining light through it in order to
kind of see that uh that black polyfilm
on the windows so that's what I use it
mostly use it for keeping the light out
of the room you know what I mean but
certainly it's it's good for for keeping
light from escaping the room as well and
for my doors uh what I use is on the
bottom there there right there's that
spacing I use draft guards so if you
search on Amazon twin draft guard it
basically is like a piece of Styrofoam
and plastic circular and it's the length
of the door and you basically just slide
it underneath the door so uh it prevents
any light or anything really from coming
into that bottom part of the door and
then what I did was cut up polyfilm
because the cracks of the door all
around the the edges there light was
coming in that way and so I would cut up
a piece of the polyfilm and just
basically cover cover it that way and so
when I'm opening up and closing the door
sure there's like a flap of polyfilm but
that prevents light from coming in and
it would work well for preventing life
from going out too so forg I'd mention
those things yeah no that's great and
that's that's kind of a good segue into
um into how taking this adventure and
starting to grow on your own can really
teach you a lot about
DIY um you can learn I mean Farmers
farmers are are plumbers farmers are
carpenters farmers are
electricians um they're everything you
know they learn how to do it all I
learned how to do a lot myself um
gardening and being a renter because
yeah can't just call your landlord if
something goes wrong you know so I
learned a lot of stuff uh on my own and
it's kind of a blessing and disguise
like in the in that time I was you know
stressing out like oh no my basement's
floating what do I do oh there's soil in
the Su pump okay I got to like clean
this out oh I got it work in you know
awesome or uh you know learning how to
deal with electricity and just
everything um it's been so valuable you
know cuz now I'm I'm renovating my attic
and I'm using these skills that I
learned um that I that I never learned
previously so so that's kind of cool but
I wanted to I wanted to reverse back to
odor because there's kind of like a
controversial thing uh that we didn't
talk about and that's ozone
generators ah okay so I never I didn't
even put those in our notes but ozone
generators we don't sell them on Happy
Hydro frankly I don't really know what
if they're dangerous if they're not
dangerous I don't know the interest I've
never done a deep dive on on ozone
generators I know you may have or you
may have a little bit of Noe I'm not
never used one not very familiar with it
just search for it on Amazon I see
there's one for 65 bucks the word ozone
generator sounds kind of scary you know
like is it generating ozone in my house
like should I be breathing it I don't
know I don't um I don't really know but
I know that people I have been in a
house where people have been using them
they do cover up odors but I think uh
before anybody goes and and uses those
they should kind of look into the you
know whether or not they're safe I guess
you know if they're selling them on
Amazon you would assume like that Amazon
would do their due diligence but you
know I don't really know I know there's
a debate and that's why I don't list
them on our website because I don't want
to you know Steer clear of any
controversy sounds like a good question
for the audience ozone generators has
anybody used them any experience with it
let us know down in the comment section
below go back to light real quick I
think you had a good story in regards to
light leaking I got a few you talk to us
about that I got a few which one do you
want the basement one there was a guy
who uh I worked at the local grow shop
right so that's kind of how I got my my
in um into this industry I was doing
some growing on my own um I went and I
just started hanging out at the grow
shop they got they got a shipment
delivered I started you know the one day
the owner was busy I just grabbed a a
razor knife started putting stuff on the
shelves I didn't even work there
um but it got me a job there and you
know I met all these people and this one
guy comes in everyone's telling stories
right cuz back then um you know there is
just less internet you know the grow
stores where you hung out and shared all
your stories had to keep things on the
low this guy's telling a story about how
him and his buddy rented a house and
they're growing in the basement and they
get it all set up and they they're using
some thousand watt HPS lights maybe a
couple of them they finish up you know
it's like one in the morning they're
exhausted they just spent you know six
seven8 hours building this grow room
they got you know the plants in
everything they go
outside and they go to get in their cars
to leave and they look back at the house
and there's light just pouring out of
the foundation through every single
cracken hole just bright yellow light
pouring out of the
foundation and I was like dude what did
you do he's like well I didn't sleep
that night for one um
luckily there was like a 24/7 Walmart or
whatever and uh they went and they
bought you know 10 cans of great stuff
that like foam spray and they went
around the whole thing and just had to
basically fill in the whole found the
whole uh fouret of foundation sticking
out from the ground to where the first
floor of the house starts they had to
seal it all up in the middle of the
night and uh I was just like wow man
that is just imagine that imagine like
putting in all those hours getting
everything set up you're getting in your
car you're like you're feeling like yeah
dude we're done and then you just look
overing coming out of the that's crazy
that's got to be a rare thing though
right cuz he said it was cracking in the
foundation I imagine that there bigger
problems there like what if water water
leaking in there too like flood in the
basement right if this cracks or what
probably you know I mean um I I think uh
I think when he I think when this guy
was looking for a house to rent he was
looking for cheap rent and he wasn't
really thinking
about you know the quality of the
foundation or you know obviously he
didn't even he didn't even line the
walls with poly or anything he just GW
it you
know which a lot of people would say is
a big no no um but everyone's a beginner
at some point so you make mistakes you
figure it out hopefully um hopefully you
learn fast and yeah so they went around
and they spray spray foamed it all in
and got all sealed up but yeah that was
that was a funny one so definitely
something to keep your eye on that's
somewhat unexpected you know yeah
checking for your light leaks going
outside just pretending pretending you
are your neighbor you know what are your
thoughts when you look at the house does
it look like a house that are is there
light leaking does it
smell uh I had another guy who used to
come in and you know the the the one day
comes in he's like you know talking
about clones and this and that and he
wants to trade some clones I'm like all
right cool I go over to his house man I
get out of my car oh dude I could smell
it from the road like it was kind of in
the country so the neighbors weren't on
top of each
other I could smell through from the
road dude and this was you know back in
the day it's not cool not good and I uh
you know I go in I'm like dude dude I
could smell that from a road he looks at
me
just me I'm like what about like he's
like nobody comes here I'm like what
about your
mailman what about like the pizza guy uh
what if a neighbor like knocks on your
door I don't
know that guy ended up getting in a
little bit of trouble actually um
because of that reason there were no he
didn't use any carbon filters and um so
yeah kind of a bummer that's brutal now
that reminds me of a story when you were
over my house and we were trimming you
help trimming I appreciate your your
help there that was I I love trimming
dude I just I want to sit down for 16
hours but we were sitting down trimming
and we got we actually live streaming
this too this is back when I I live
streamed trimming and I had my Mr Grow
shirt on and I get a knock on the door
and we're trimming probably 15 ft from
the door and uh obviously the whole
house stinks right because there a Fresh
Harvest um well the dry we're actually
trimming at that point but this it still
stinks right the whole house stinks like
you mentioned before I open up the door
and I quickly exit the door because I
know it stinks on the inside and the
FedEx guy is there and he's like oh here
sign for this package and then he looks
at my shirt he notices my shirt he's
like oh that's what that smell
is like what does that mean like does he
does that mean he knew who you were from
YouTube or no no I think he just like my
logo has like the leaf on it and grow it
and so like he put two and two together
there anyways it was kind of awkward I
signed for the package then went went in
there and I was like man H smells
escaping and I've had friends and stuff
come over before and like dude I can
smell it from the street like oh God you
know so it's like sometimes I feel like
I do need to do a better job of of
hiding the smell I think that's only
really been though Harvest you know when
I'm drying things are harvested things
are hanging for dry I think that's when
it really really stinks because it's in
when it's in flower I do have the
exhaust going up into my attic and out
the roof so you can't really smell it
down at street level but hey when I'm
harvesting I'm trimming on on floor
level well then um yeah unfortunately it
escapes all the way to the roll Road for
me dude next time we're just we'll have
to go on your
attic be crumped up in there
yeah um no I'm glad you brought that up
cuz I I one of my notes Here was um you
know if you're if you're in a place and
you're you're kind of tone align and and
you're you got your smell under control
and it's all good and you're you got it
under control while you're you're uh
opening the tent whatever but you know
when it comes to that trimming and
harvesting it's really hard to to to
control it and so sometimes the best
move is to just take it somewhere else
trim it somewhere else you know um
because it's it's tough uh you can you
can keep your negative pressure and you
can keep your car filter going and
everything but you know one small
mistake you open the door whatever and
it's
just so if you can take it somewhere
else to trim and Harvest and stuff
that's safe and secure and everything um
that's an option too good point yeah
because at that point it's really hard
to hide it from your roommates or family
members and and maybe we talk about that
next you know how do you hide it from
your roommates or family members people
living in the same house as you how
would you go about hiding it so this is
tough right this is a good time for one
of my one of my friends Ryan has this
really good quote and the quote is
there's nothing sketchier than a sketchy
guy acting
sketchy so the number one thing is to
don't act sketchy the number two thing
is if you're living with people who are
like aware you're probably going to have
a really tough time to to hide it I
mean I I don't want to say it's
impossible it's not impossible but it's
going to be really tough um and one of
the one of the ways that people are
doing it and I kind of just discovered
this when I was um refresh in for this
this podcast was they got these things
called space buckets did you end up
checking that website out yep I've heard
of space buckets and I saw that website
you sent me I never I never heard of
those and I was looking at them and
there's a whole radit Community about
space buckets and people are taking five
gallon buckets and they're just growing
like one little plant in this 5 gallon
bucket and they've got uh they'll hook
up a a fan and a carbon filter to it and
everything and so I think that's an
actual realistic way um to grow at home
without people you're living with
noticing if you're going to if you're
going to take a stab at it but still you
know you might have you might just have
to trim and harvest somewhere else
unless you can really figure out the
carbon filter negative pressure lung
room type strategy for the odors other
than the space buckets you know back in
the day there were there were these like
uh fake computer boxes they used to sell
you remember those oh yeah yeah they
didn't even come with a carbon filter
there was just like a there's just like
a a regular computer fan on the back you
know and they just can't even imagine
how many of those sold uh back in the
day but like even with something like
that like it's just going to leak smell
right out the back and it's tough to
control odors with a quiet fan too right
because the reason you got to use those
inline fans uh with the carbon filters
is because a a regular like booster fan
a small quiet fan doesn't have enough
power to get the air through the carbon
um the the carbon restricts the air flow
so much that's why you got to use one of
those powerful fans so so I would say I
would say this if you know
when someone at your house is going to
be home those are the times where you
want your light off um you want your fan
on a low
setting uh and those things go hand in
hand right because your when your lights
on your fan usually has to be on at a
higher setting to control the heat when
the lights off you can keep the fan at a
lower setting so you're getting a you're
solving the light problem by just having
it off during those period during that
time uh you get the lower noise from the
fan but it's obviously it's still on so
you get your negative pressure um if
you're not using a uh a space bucket or
kind of some little homemade hidden
thing you know they've got like stealth
closets and all this stuff
that some of it's pretty gimmicky um but
you know if you're going to use a
regular like 2x4 grow tent you know
maybe you can play it off as a clothing
just a it's just a a portable closet
Clothing Closet I don't know I don't
know how long you get away with that for
but you know you can try the Ona blocks
and stuff like that but even that might
be a little weird like you know hey why
is uh why is our one roommate's room
always smell like
this weird block odor like or like so
it's tough those are some things that
you can do to make it easier um reducing
the amount of things that you're
bringing in and out of the house so like
trying to reuse your soil or cocoa
buying things keeping it small buying
things in small quantities you know re
reusing your your uh delivery boxes um
to put things in so you can just you
know Walt them in and and and it's not
some like you know sketchy black garbage
bag or whatever things like that you
know you're not going to be able to or
you're going to have a really tough time
trying to Lug a CO2 tank by when you got
roommates um so just keeping it small
and maybe maybe this doesn't have to do
with roommates but you really have to be
careful about who you tell and who you
trust right every friend has a friend
that they tell your secrets to I'm sure
there's like a few friends in everyone's
life where they can like absolutely
trust but for the most part every best
friend has a best friend and secrets
just get shared so you really have
to uh choose who you're who you're
telling about it that's about it and and
and I guess like I guess the final kind
of thing to talk about when it comes to
roommates is is is are you a good
roommate are you being a good roommate
to your roommates do you uh clean up
after yourself do you respect them
between with not having it stinky and
not being noisy or whatever like it can
go a long way especially you
know say you are growing and your
roommate eventually finds it and you may
not want to even do that without talking
to them first but if you already did and
then they find out later and they're mad
at you that it it it might not be as bad
if you were a good roommate beforehand
but if you're if you're a pain in the
butt and and you don't have a good
relationship with your roommates and
then and then they find out that you're
growing in the closet well you're going
to be in
trouble so uh my my note was the
Compromise right um I think that's the
best thing if you can compromise
with your roommates ahead of time and be
honest and upfront with them so you just
don't have to hide it uh it might be
harder to do that with your mom or your
family but that's kind of that's kind of
my thought process on that and same with
neighbors right like if you're a good
neighbor and you're nice and you're
friendly and something goes wrong or or
whatever they get annoyed maybe they're
going to come and knock on your door and
give you a heads up before they do
anything crazy or you know good point I
know when it comes to keeping it stealth
from family friends roommates you know
people living with you I know plenty of
people have kind of built out sections
in their closet they built sections in
their basement in their attic to where
they've kind of boxed off areas a garage
as well but they've really boxed off an
area and made it so you can't really see
there's a door anywhere right so like a
Stealth door that they they're able to
kind of open up and then get in there
and of course hiding the smell and light
and all that stuff but yeah finding a
section in the home to where you can
kind of box off and prevent anybody from
even realizing that there's a an area
there I think that's probably one of the
most common ways to hide it from family
or or roommates yeah and that actually
reminds me of a of a guy um a different
guy from The Girl shop who's I had the
pleasure of going to his house and he
had a um he had a workbench that he had
built you know and it had a big giant
back on it that he hung all his tools on
but it was on caster wheels but the
Caster wheel were hidden with a with
like a 2x6 in front of them so you don't
you looking at it you don't even know
it's on Wheels but then he he goes up to
it he pulls it it opens up behind it is
a poly zipper door and boom you walk in
and it's just like whoa dude it was it
was really cool man it's like some 07
that's awesome yeah I've seen so many
creative things I'm sure there's a whole
there's probably a whole Reddit section
on keeping it stealth gardening I
imagine because people get creative and
it comes down to the DIY thing like you
mentioned before kind of learning how to
do things yourself it's fun it's fun man
you know like when I saw that door I was
like uh are we going to Harry Potter
land like am I going to end up
at what's on the other side here that's
funny so is there any other tips for
keeping it stealth when growing indoors
don't forget about the smell of your um
nutrients and soil and stuff anyone
who's walked in a grow store you know
you know that smell those are organic
nutrients and soils like like they might
not smell like a medicinal plants but
it's it's got a strong odor and so
keeping those things in your tent if you
have room or just in a place that has uh
Odor Control it's definitely a good idea
having one of your buddies come over who
knows uh what you're doing and just
having them like hey I want you to just
walk into my house and just like just
pretend like you just don't know that
I'm growing anything and I just want you
to to let me know like is there anything
do you smell anything do you hear
anything do you see anything it's always
good to get the the input of of someone
else because if you're hanging out there
all the time you know it might not smell
to you but it might smell to someone uh
who's not hanging out in an indoor
garden all day so yeah the being aware
of the nutrients and the smell
particularly with the organic inputs I
thought that was a good one there I've
used build AOL craft blend for many many
years and um one of the things in there
I think it's the it's see the fish meal
I believe is in there man it stinks it's
like really like once I do that top
dressing those first couple days it
really really stinks and so that can
kind of cause a red flag so yeah I like
that one good point there yeah totally
and it's often overlooked you know you
don't even think about it um cuz there's
so many different moving parts and stuff
that you are thinking about so it's easy
to overlook that one but another one I
have here is
traffic you really really don't want
people coming in and out of your house
uh all day long if that's where you're
gardening uh for many many different
reasons you know there's a there's a
another good quote don't poop where you
eat and I think that that kind of
applies to that really well so uh that's
another one and then something else uh
emergencies right we didn't really talk
about emergencies yet
and you know oh no the water meter guy
wants to come in and take a reading off
my water meter and I'm 7 weeks into
flower what do I do um you got to have a
plan for that uh you should have a you
should have an emergency plan uh written
out and and uh everyone who lives with
you should should know what the plan is
um so you can enact it if the Water Guy
does have to come in or uh you know
whatever and that's and sometimes you
know that's when you just light up and
the whole place just smells like a cloud
instead of a instead of an active
growing plant and oh maybe your plan
includes getting everything out of the
house you know a guy told me a story
once that um I forget what happened but
you know his landlord or whatever like
had to come to the house he took all the
plants out of the basement put them on
the roof and just had him on the roof of
the house while the guy was working in
the basement I was like that seems risky
but it
worked so that was a funny one um
another thing in related to emergencies
is if you're using like any type of
automated watering systems or you have
like a a reservoir of water going or
anything like that um making sure that
you're protected from
floods the last thing you want to do is
have uh a flood from your irrigation
system or whatever you know ruin the
floor or just you know create any
problem that you may have to deal with
your your landlord or or whatever just
anyone most grow tents come with a flood
tray which is pretty suitable I mean I
think they come up what four to 6 Ines
on each Edge um um I mean they can hold
a lot of water uh but if you're doing
like a whole bedroom or something you
can get giant tarps fold them in half
run them up the walls a little bit uh
nail 2x4s to the walls around to hold it
up you know and then you just have a big
giant flood barrier essentially and it's
uh it's really just an insurance policy
dehumidifiers
so obviously we know like there's a lot
of humidity that comes with gardening um
your water in the plants they're it can
just you can get a real human
environment real easily and and that can
damage drywall it can damage paint um if
it's not under
control and if you're uh renting a place
and you want to get your security
deposit
back you're not going to want to ruin
the paint in the drywall and stuff so
having a dehumidifier and just keeping
you know keeping that on your mind um is
another is another big thing and and on
that topic say you got to screw a bunch
of stuff to the seat ceing and and you
don't want to damage the ceiling or or
you got to screw a bunch of the wall you
can just screw a
2x4 that way you're putting one two
three four screws in maybe five six
screws in to the 2x4 and then you can
screw things to the 2x4 without damaging
uh the wall behind as much you maybe it
doesn't have anything with stealth
growing but for getting your security
deposit back and just having less you
know cleanup work to do lots of great
points there on keeping things stealth
when gardening in indoors Chris I
appreciate you coming on today uh I'm
sure there's things that we missed and
that we're going to be told in the
comment section I would love to read
those comments so if we missed anything
if you have any advice for how to keep
things stealth drop it down in the
comment section below I love reading
through all the comments and uh yeah
some really good stuff in there
sometimes I'm sure somebody will uh
mention the electric bill we didn't
mention that oh yeah we didn't talk
about electricity people who are worried
about the electric bill um we don't have
to go into it but I can tell you one
thing don't steal power
[Laughter]
well these days with the lights being so
efficient I mean if you're doing a I
think my bill when I'm running 210 is
like 30 bucks a month you know so it's
not too brutal back in the day when
you're running th watts and you're
running four five six lights well that
adds up right then it's hundreds of
dollars per month easily yeah those old
ballasts use more amps than the LED um
ball are using nowadays too so not as as
important these days days as it was back
in the day totally so let's wrap things
up tell the listeners how they can find
you and is there anything upcoming in
the future that you want to talk about
yeah totally so um if you guys want to
support us go to www.happy hydro.com um
we sell complete grow tent kits uh
including soil and stuff beginner kits
where you buy the kit and you're good to
go you don't need anything else uh no
complicated nutrient regimens just uh an
all in-one soil start to finish and a
little uh Bloom nutrient uh to go with
it uh we've got Grove bags which are
awesome that's a new product that's
doing great um Aaron just made a video
on the controller 69 Pro he went um so
that's on our YouTube channel you can
just search happy Hydra on YouTube and
you'll find Aaron uh he puts so much
time and effort into these videos and he
loves making them so if you guys can go
to the Happy Hydra YouTube channel and
give him a like comment
subscribe um you know all that jazz
he'll be stoked um comment on his mullet
he'll be even more stoked
um yeah what else are we doing dude
we're just we're we're continuing to add
more products to the website I'm
building some calculators so you know a
calculator where you can enter in your
uh the wattage of your light your
seedling phase the what dimmer perc and
it'll estimate how far to keep it from
the plants based on that stage um man
we've got all sorts of stuff going on I
could I could I could go on for a half
hour We're launching a merch store soon
too um that's where this shirt came from
oh and uh this beautiful
mug nice for those who uh everyone who's
a fan of the office got Michael Scott on
there and then you got the happy Hydro
logo on the back those that are tuning
in on the podcast platforms and can't
see but that's that's pretty cool yeah
it's funny the guys got me that for
Christmas it was uh it was fantastic and
I you know I'll say again when you're
shopping from us you're really you're
shopping from a group of friends who who
really care you know we've known each
other for 10 20 years we're not just in
this for the money uh we enjoy what we
do we enjoy being able to work together
it's a gift would not be possible if it
weren't for people um shopping with us
so if you need any Grow Supplies please
come check us out happy hydro.com
awesome we definitely have a link to
your website as well as YouTube channel
down in the description section below
also have as a pinned comment so you can
easily navigate to his website or
YouTube channel and give him a follow or
buy some products and I think I have uh
coupon code correct me if I'm wrong is
it Mr growt is that still active coupon
code Mr Grow it all caps here we go I
think it's What minimum spend of a 100
though right spend a 100 bucks get 10
bucks off I hate to have to do the spend
100 bucks but when we ship out a package
that's under 100 bucks the shipping is
10 20 bucks and it's just it's hard to
give a discount um but yeah Mr growt No
period just m r g r o i t $10 off 100 or
more perfect all right Chris thanks so
much for coming on today really
appreciate it and I hope you enjoy the
rest of your day it's always fun dude
appreciate you greatly and uh hey
congrats on all the success uh with this
Channel and all your other channels man
it's fun watching you guys uh you and
just everyone you're working with just
take off you know it's came a long way
since you had your original channel that
uh rip was taken
down yeah yeah you've been there since
the beginning man but I appreciate those
positive words there thanks so much
brother all right peace out everyone
catch you in the next episode