what's up everybody feel that don't love
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you'll watch on my extras channel this
is a 315 watt CMH girl light kit and
includes the Sun system 315 Neutron CMH
reflector philips master color 315 watt
3100 kelvin bulb and prism lighting
science at 315 watt ballast i'll link
this kid in the description section
below in this video I'm not going to go
over into the features or anything like
that I am just going to do a part están
it I'll use the Apple gmq 500 par meter
of measurements are taken MP PFD and
this meter measures 389 nanometers to
692 nanometers plus or minus 5
nanometers so if any light is being
emitted that is outside that range it
won't show up on this par meter and this
is just to give you a general idea of
what the power output is for this light
this isn't gonna be on to present
accurate I'm taking measurements in a
grow tent the reflective walls could
increase these numbers so just keep that
in mind this light is a flowering
coverage area of three foot by three
foot and I have it in a 4 foot by 4 foot
grow tent so I'm actually not going to
bring this sensor all the way to the
corner of the grow tent I'll try to keep
it at three foot by 3 foot space I'll
take three different measurements 12
inches away 24 inches away and 36 inches
away these seem to be the most common
light distances for CMH grow lights just
like all the other part test videos I do
I'll let them measurements do the
talking
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know by leaving a comment below
and again I have provided a link to this
grow light in the description section
below so you can learn more that's
pretty much it for this video guys if
you enjoyed it please click that thumbs
up and I will leave it at that thank you
so much for watching and until next time
peace
[Music]