coming up on garden talk and you want to
get
more purple then so first thing you'll
do is f2 you'll
take a sister and a brother you'll put
them together and that'll be your f2
and then f3 on the next sister brother
and that's fleel breeding all the way
down sister brother sister brother just
straight
but the word stable when it comes to
saying seeds are stable
means that they come out like a
monoculture that
99 of the traits that they display they
almost look like clones
all the progeny you can get them all
down to being all rude or alice after a
couple of generations of breeding or a
few generations
but to get it down to all them being
rude or alice you'll never get the
purple it'll always be recessive
against so you can take a male and
stress it out and run it long enough and
it will
throw female pistols and flowers and
seed itself
and all of your seeds that come from
that male will be
maleized
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 23.
in this episode i interview vader og he
is the founder of ocean grown genetics
and has been breeding for over 15 years
he grows a variety of plants such as
cucumbers
tomatoes herbs orchids banana trees
fig trees avocado trees citrus trees and
so much more
vader also has a youtube channel where
he has nearly 80 000 subscribers
and he's been uploading videos for the
past 10 years so
he's definitely an og on youtube in this
episode we talk about the basics of
breeding plants
everything from the nomenclature all the
way to how to make different types of
seeds
thank you to all the supporters on
patreon who contribute to this
information being made available for
free
on youtube and podcast platforms if
you'd like to support
the link is patreon.com mr growit
and there are different tiers on there
that unlock various rewards
another big supporter of free
information is our sponsors
let's give a quick shout out to them
first up is spider farmer
spider farmer is well known to produce
high quality led grow lights
at a price lower than nearly all other
companies they have
board style led grow lights as well as
bar style led grow lights
i've used both their sf 2000 and sf
4000 led grow lights in the past and i
got some excellent results with them
they also have grow tents an inline fan
and a carbon filter i will leave a link
to spider farmer down in the description
section below
and you can use discount code mr growit5
during checkout
for a discount on their products dutch
pro nutrients is also a sponsor of the
podcast
they are a plant fertilizer company that
has base nutrients
additives and ph regulators so
everything needed for proper plant
nutrition
they've been around for over 30 years
and their nutrients are available in
several countries across the world
i'll be using their base nutrients that
are formulated specifically for ro
and soft water they also have base
nutrients formulated specifically for
water that has some minerals already in
it
such as well water or tap water i'll
leave a link to dutch pros amazon store
down in the description section below
and you can use coupon code mrgrowit10dp
for discount on their products all right
now let's get to the episode
all right we are back welcome to the
garden talk podcast today i am joined
with vader from ocean grown how you
doing today
good how are you doing how are you doing
doing good super pumped to have you on
the podcast today
we're going to be talking about breeding
the basics of breeding plants
and i couldn't think of a better person
to have on the podcast for this
discussion really
i mean you've been around forever you
know i remember
watching you in 2014 i think is when i
first started watching you
and you've been around since 2011 is
when your first video came out so
yesterday i think it was june or july
11th so i think yesterday was
10 years on youtube it was the 10 year
anniversary so this
this is like an anniversary episode i
was going to call that out
congratulations 10 years
you have 469 videos currently on your
channel
uh over 80 000 or about to hit 80 000
subscribers
and all those videos combined have over
9.2
million views so that's truly incredible
man hats off to you for
really doing this for the past 10 years
it's it's just extensive
so great job it comes quick it comes
quick i don't even think about the
numbers most the time like the analytics
i know
others um even people on the team and
stuff like really nerd out about the
analytics i
sort of look past it and don't think
about it often then you hear the numbers
like that you're like well it does sound
like a lot
um but just really to me it's just like
you keep trudging right it's just it's
about the same work it's growing or it's
the same work you just keep going
um we've had years where like yeah
really active and then there's other
years where you know you take a slow
down you have other things going on in
life
uh it happens and but we're still here
and um
happy to still be here i mean we've even
been through little bits right we've had
channels deleted and youtube gave it
back
and just really with no guidance from
youtube or anyone so
still happy to be here and putting out
content when we can there's been a lot
of changes i think for everybody over
the years right you know even just with
life but
we're still making our way so still
still cruising through and still plan on
uh
keeping it up for the time being as long
as they allow us to keep
keep performing for sure for those that
don't know who you are can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
uh yeah so um yeah the kind of basic
little story is that um
when i was uh graduated high school
stuff like that i
joined the military um for different
reasons a couple of different reasons
but um ended up being in the military
for a couple years
got sick and resulted in kind of a lung
and bronchial issue for myself
um was peb what you call a physical
evaluation board so they
wouldn't allow me to stay because i was
going to take too long to recover and
they weren't even sure if i would
recover
all the way and it's pretty sick i spent
on and off a few months in the hospital
at a time in full
icu very similar to some of the viral
issues that you see
people going through at the time i had
um gotten something
uh very similar in the sense of like
that resulted in
my body than producing pneumonia
symptoms and all of that
so couldn't kick the virus that it was
at that time
got pneumonia over and over again so
they kept relapsing with it and it
damaged and scarred my lungs and my
bronchials so i got bronchitis and
lung scarring from it and was pretty
down about it and military was like
you're not gonna be
coming back right now like you're done
and i'd gone all the way down to
like 140 pounds at one point and that
was going from
like 240 pounds of you know having some
muscle on
so that like in a six month period just
way down then couldn't get weight back
up so when i got out of military
is about 180 pounds um and i'm 6'8 so
you know my
average good weight is 205 to 220 at
least just to be doing pretty good
kind of slip below that and a little too
thin so i still had some work to get
going
and they retired me and i didn't know
what to do i was on a bunch of steroids
um in 2001 and
just really feeling down i had been an
athlete my whole life
and wasn't wasn't sure what the next
step was right um
there were things like uh you know
medicinal
herb uh that you know pretty popular in
the culture around cali and everything
like that
derivative of hemp and in that
fashion it was offered to me during the
time to think about it
but i had always been an athlete and so
i'd always avoided it friends and people
participated um you know at a party here
and there i had had a beer
you know a few hops and uh passed around
some of that medicinal
but it never really affected me much i
was like oh it wasn't a big deal so i
never used it never really thought about
it
and i had seen some friends that of
course like you get in that kind of
culture some people
can abuse things really easily and so
that was always in my mindset
but got a military on a bunch of
steroids doctors didn't know what to do
and a friend of mine joked about it a
little peter tosh
bob marley right you know ha ha ha
here's uh asthma
and i was like oh i'll give it a shot
and so friend brought some over
and um tried it and couldn't believe how
incredibly just immediately
better i felt um even for my lungs
things like that even though i'd
scarring you know you would think that
it would be a
like a no-no especially to consume a
product um by like you know inhaling and
burning it
but ended up changing my life around
about the viewpoint of it
and so at that time period it was really
important especially for me to make sure
that i had
clean um product
because a lot of people especially in
unregulated markets can use right you
know you're fighting a lot of weird pest
issues things like that so people will
use products that
are outside of agriculture because
there's no regulation so it was really
important to me at the beginning
to be able to produce my own product i
learned that very quickly so
the one thing about that time period was
that it was harder to get your medical
and everything in cali at the time in 96
they had to open it up but 2001 2002
still really difficult had to go to like
one specific specialty doctor you had to
go through a bunch of stuff bring all
your records
multiple interviews ended up getting a
card and ended up being able to also
produce
and cali law you could produce for
yourself as well so
along with that i started producing for
myself pretty lightly for a couple of
years
and then it just kind of grew from that
point on but
and i ended up falling in love with us
not only the plant itself but plants in
general
agriculture and all kinds of
medicinal plants that do come along with
these concepts once you break your mind
free
of like a stigma of something you've
been told then it makes you realize like
well hey if we were told this about this
stuff then what other things out there
are there misconceptions for and so that
sorted me on a path
definitely more based in agriculture at
a large part of my life
gotcha and then you had mentioned before
we started
filming is that you've been breeding for
over 15 years now is that right
uh yeah so the first few years for sure
it was just for myself
i would just produce product or flowers
and things like that
to be able to make different products
and
try different avenues too you know
thinking about it um because there are
different ways to consume the products
or
make different products for it and
found you know what worked for me what i
liked and then
slowly though more friends because
you're doing a good job
of producing product um clean product
then more people would like some of it
and so
i just ended up sort of growing that
more and more and because
i did have the permits and everything
available or right i started with my
card and then kind of worked my way
through the system to see like hey
in my county in my area what can we do
can you bring that up more production
had some friends thought about it i had
really gotten into the online community
so
um people that know like back from the
overgrown days that's where i initially
started doing seed trading
so i started because i saw that going on
i thought well you know if you're a
farmer
like not only you can grow something but
you also want to breed it you also want
to
try participating in those future
generations
a lot with like the medicinal plant that
we use you can
propagate these plants through cloning
and so that's super popular
and it was super popular in our
community and um
in cali and in that industry as we'd
call it
but i still like you know you had to to
even get different kinds of phenotypes
different kinds of unique clones
you could have things that people had
found but you could also make your own
and so that's what started me on the
journey and i started
small by just using what they call
feminized breeding where
you take a plant and you hermaphrodite
it and then you'll use pollen against
another
particular strain style and then you'll
get something unique out of those
progeny
or offspring so that was my original
um sort of tiptoe in from maybe 2002
to 2006 taking things breeding them
finding clones and then releasing those
clones into the market
and slowly running sort of clone market
business as well
and it wasn't really for like producing
seeds that didn't come until later
by being able to share seeds with other
people maybe with friends and of course
seed trading online that's where
we were all doing it and there was
nothing wrong with it it was still it's
just
hemp seed right still a derivative same
species stuff so
there um being no cannabinoids things
like that
um that had regulation towards them um
especially for like us in the u.s then
that was our way that we could get
around that without having like live
plants or
live products and things even though in
our areas it was
regulated in in legal at least on a
state or county levels
okay so let's get into let's start with
some of the basic
terminology you know starting with what
exactly is breeding
so when it comes to breeding there's um
you're basically making offspring right
in nature we've got that
with animals and with plants with
animals
it can be a little bit different
obviously a little bit more complicated
with plants it's going to be i generally
call it a little simpler
you could argue theoretically a few
different um vantage and viewpoints for
it depending especially the species but
overall it's pretty much simpler in the
sense that
for plants you have monoisius and
dioecious audacious diocese i kind of
get the some people say it's tomato
tomatoes sometimes
um but these are the difference between
plants that have either the
both sex organs on themselves so
technically they can self
pollinate themselves although they
generally
will pollinate at different times you
take like maize corn
that is it tries to have its male parts
and pollen come at a different time than
its female parts on its particular
plant so another corn or maize will be
flowering its female parts at a time
which one near it will be flowering male
parts so it tries not to pollinate
itself so much
and then send it off to other things
although technically can pollinate but
they have both
organs and then dioecious right you're
going to have
um two different male and female plants
now some people get that confused with
like hemp because hemp can show those
traits
but actually genetically there's it's a
little bit of a difference it would be
considered a diocese plant so
it has both males and females which was
something really interesting for me to
learn at the time because when i first
learned about it
i actually thought all plants and
especially flowers and things of those
species that are near there
um like on the taxonomy when it comes to
botany were
they all were males and or
male female parts to be on one plant so
it was interesting to me and that was
kind of like the joke at the beginning
like oh
it's an alien plant because you know
there's true like males and true females
until i learned more about agriculture
and botany and then it turned out like
oh no you do find this around
quite a lot so it's just you get two
separations
for that for us then we have two
different sets we're going for
females and males and that's the
baseline of
breeding which we call true breeding or
many people refer to as regular
in our particular industry or community
with our plants
and then getting into i think it's
appropriate to talk about genotype
and phenotype now this is something that
i had briefly talked about
in a recent uh past podcast with
northwest j we talked about phenol
hunting
uh we described what it is there but i
think it's appropriate to talk about it
here as well in this episode ken
can you break down genotype and
phenotype for us phenos are going to be
what your progeny persists on so you'll
have different phenotypic
expressions per traits the genotype
itself is the larger
[Music]
genomics of a plant so and phenotypes
are kind of
we throw it around a lot i think in like
oh this is the phenotype
of the plant but what you're really
talking about when you get a progeny and
it's
it's a phenotype of it meaning it's
showing a phenotypical trait
so let's say uh color purple right you
know even though something like color
purple comes from really stress
and it comes from mutations for that um
but let's say you're just going for
color and you want something so you get
a progeny that has something
offspring that has purple in it you
would call it a purple phenotype but
it's really just displaying that
particular trait it's not the whole
thing itself it's actually only just the
miniature traits versus the genotype
which is
the whole thing in general for that
species if that makes sense
yep that makes sense and so kind of
taking a step back
just to kind of make things basic for
the beginners for introduction
male plants are going to produce the
pollen sex and they're going to release
the pollen sacs will open and release
pollen females
grow pistils and receive the pollen
through that ultimately forming a seed
within the plant's buds now there are
different generations
f1 f2 f3 etc etc
what is an f1 so yeah that nomenclature
is when you take
two different kids and you or two
different things in a species and put it
together so it can still breed right
like it's still the same
technical species i mean it gets kind of
it gets a little different because you
talk about like things like animals are
easy to
show like lions and tigers are obviously
different but they're close enough
that they can breed together and then
they're
at the same time kind of far enough away
from each other that when you breed them
together you get
weird things going on right everything
from sterility to gigantism and all
kinds of
uh funky stuff so they've gotten away
pretty far away but they're not super
close
where if you're talking about a species
like for us where we're using our plants
um
we're so close that we can move into
different
the same downward spiral is is really
within the same thing so like humans
like we're all
so similar that you can just mix this
like our idea that
hair is a certain way or skin or
different things
um they're really similar they're small
little changes to us they look like they
might be
um a wide variety of stuff but really
genetically we are so similar
that um these traits are just well
within the same species
so that's where like f1s and things i'm
talking about just hybridization because
all
all of our plants are hybridized itself
and so
you can take one that's purple and one
that's green and put them together
and then that'll be your f1 on that and
then your f2s your f3s
traits down these are fallible breeding
um generally what you're going to do is
an offspring and progeny you'll take
like you'll have two parents and then if
you f1 they're going to be two separate
parents right from two different zones
maybe they're on two different sides of
the valley
okay they've been developing far enough
away from each other but they're like
two different tribes
north side and south side so that is the
f1 north and south side together
then their progeny their offspring if
you take
a brother and a sister and you breed
them together because north side and
south side had two different traits
um you know purple and green then and
you want to get
more purple then so first thing you'll
do is f2 you'll
take a sister and a brother you'll put
them together and that'll be your f2 and
then f3
on the next sister brother and that's
fleel breeding all the way down sister
brother sister brother just straight
eventually you can back yourself into
corners um generally with like hemp and
stuff it's pretty well known you get
like f16 somewhere f12 to f16
and generally you'll get to sterility
and
probably some funky genetic traits weird
growth patterns all kinds of stuff
in between there so you can only go so
far without
f1 again meaning taking something out of
that lineup
and resetting it back to something a
little bit different so that's where you
get those
back crosses would be back crossing to
if we move into that
right which is really popular and that's
where it's much quicker to get to a
trait so you can easily back cross by
meaning you did an f1
and then you got something purple and
the north original
parent lineage was also purple so you
take a purple child and you back cross
that to the purple parent
and then you'll take a purple grand kid
and
change that back to the original parent
again so then you get down to like bx4
where you're like four generations down
but you still keep going back
up to your original parent which is your
your zero
or your p p ones so
that's where you get into like bat
crossing and then you get into
self crossing which is because with like
hemp for example even though
it has males and females it has we have
been able to breed it and it was showing
it in nature and naturally
where it will throw both male and female
parts
unfortunately the or this happens with
both
plants styles even monoissues or diocese
that when you self
the pollen from itself adds in extra
chromosomes so that's where you get like
x
uh or y xx things like that
so then when you get your future progeny
they're not what we call true breed
where they'll just have x y and xx
which is why it can get a little
confusing when people go to test for sex
with the sex testing because the sex
tests
check for why so you could say like oh
this is a y it's a male but it might
actually be a y
x x right or x x y so you're catching
the y
thinking it's male but really it's going
to if you grew it out it would look
female if you didn't give it any stress
it wouldn't show any of its uh like
hermaphroditic traits it wouldn't
it wouldn't show its selfing traits
so that's just something to think about
that chromosomes and those things aren't
all
equal in the way um that becomes like
very advanced right concepts and and
things get a little so without
digressing
into um weird theoretical or other
concepts
just keeping it simple um getting into
cell thing s1 s2 can
be really viable in a lot of situations
and help hybridize so it's another
technique that you can use in speed
against valial crossing which always
takes much longer
to pull the traits out especially when
two things are
vastly different so if you take
something like a plant that was from
equatorial
zone you know in colombia and then you
want to go breed that against something
that was natural in nature i'm very
close in the species but it was over in
northern europe
then it's going to be far more
hybridized
right your progeny are going to be way
more varied where if you take something
from equatorial columbia
and then you take something that was
over in peru and you put those together
they're going to be much closer you're
still going to call them an f1
when you breed them together but it
doesn't necessarily
mean that they're not going to be so
similar because maybe they had had some
crossing back and forth between the days
earlier
um they can be much more stable in a
sense as far as like a monoculture crop
um but you'll still call them f1s and f2
so it's something to think about when
people hear like oh this is an f1 i want
to stay away from those or
this is an f2 well something that's so
hybridized nowadays especially in our
industry and community
most of the time we've hybridized
everything so much so when we f1 things
they're still so many traits that are
similar that they're going to work well
together and you you may not see as much
variety
and then you just have to get to know
your breeds but that's why
you know 30 70s 80s there was a lot more
varied
production but over the years of course
we're all just interacting with each
other
and get passing around plants and
genetics that we've really
come to a place where we've gotten away
from a lot of those
extreme you don't find those as much
anymore because the production has moved
itself all around the world
gotcha and for the record i am not a
breeder i just want to make that clear
i did create a cross i did uh brisker og
cross with pakistan valley then you are
a breeder
learning so much from this conversation
here uh you know
the short 20 minutes that we've already
been recording i've learned so much so i
don't consider myself a breeder at all
or if you consider me a breeder i'm a
breeder with barely any experience
yeah experience levels but same with
myself and i'm sure that somewhere in
here somebody who has
um you know a particular level of
education will catch me on saying things
that uh
right like you know you're always gonna
do that even myself like i'm pretty well
up with it i can
handle it with the best um i have
friends who are phd
right like they straight up i can hang
with them and know a lot of concepts but
at the same time i don't always get the
terms and everything right and i think
that's important to note even for
someone like you as you're getting into
it don't get hung up on it if you kind
of messed up on a term or something
or even a concept as long as you have
the baseline of it like that's a great
beginning
you just keep working on it you learn
from new people but even i myself
um learn all the time so uh
but you're on that path and it is well
to call yourself if you started breeding
then you're a breeder like that's
to me that's the the same place you're
participating in something that most
people don't participate when it comes
to plants and
farming just in general that's a really
good point for sure
okay let's hop into the selection
process
so uh you know oftentimes breeders
they're gonna select
certain males or females we'll start
with males
they look at certain characteristics in
the plant
things that they're looking for that
they want to breed
within that cultivar so talking about
the male selection process
what are some characteristics that you
look for when you're selecting males
yeah when it comes to these kinds of
things i've always erred so it kind of
depends on on where
whether you know your your particular
strains or not
all right um if you're in one species of
a plant
once you know your strains more you can
make a variety of decisions based on
that but
always starting really simply like just
in a basic level you want to get into it
my i always lean into recommending that
you go for help
go for the health of the males
and you don't worry about um trying to
get into
the nitty-gritty of figuring out what
traits they're gonna pass on
um you're gonna be able to tell that
especially like in our
field um with the females it's the more
prized possession it's what people are
going for so you concentrate more on
what the females are to be displaying
and not what the males are displaying
because what you're going to get into
is dominant and recessive traits
so you could pick a male for example
that is showing purple
but when you breed it with a female
that has purple green um and then all
the progeny just turn out green
that is because there is a dominant
trait
right that is going to grasp on
and be it comes in ones and twos or
zeros and ones and that dominant trait
is going to overtake the recessive trait
it's just the way it works so you'll run
into that all the time with breeding so
that is why i say at the beginning
you worry about health of the plants
things like that
strength and stay away from worrying
about the traits themselves as much when
it comes to the males the females are
much easier to identify the traits
and then when you breed with them you'll
be able to then try keep picking
those females that display those traits
then
of course you can start doing with the
males themselves colors
um you know for hemp and things like
that when it comes to like trichomes
and stuff um and production then that
will lend itself over and it will if you
start picking
purple males that are real sticky right
and you want stickier
flowers on your females it's going to
lend itself over and you're going to
find
more dominant traits for it but i always
say get to know your plants first before
worrying about the specific traits
because of those dominant recessive
genes are going to be more powerful and
you're going to find
the visualization of being able to
choose that and understanding your
plants under females
much quicker and easier males are a
little harder to kind of
wrap your brain you don't see them a lot
you don't deal with them a lot
and they will display different traits
depending on what
strain line they come down and i know
that from experience that
certain strain lines i'm not worried
about if a male is tall
it's it's always a recessive trait with
the particular females i'm running so
i'm always
i don't care if he gets super lanky it
doesn't really bother me that much i
mean i don't want it extremely lanky but
it does
i will pick a linkier male that is
purple over
um a male that like oh i don't want it
getting too lanky so
i'll get it a little bit more green
because i just don't want to keep the
height down so you have to figure that
out that's kind of that artistry
experience that comes in uh play and
that's the hard part about time
then time comes into play and experience
so
shooting for males that are healthy
strong
that's the best way to go at first
because that will always bring up the
health and vigor of all of your strains
and all the progeny from that point on
even with females because we hybridize
stuff so much and so many people
in the industry end up getting seeds
from stressed out situations
things didn't go just perfect maybe
you're
breeding against clones that have been
around a long time
and they have slowly had epigenetic
drift as we call it
so epigenetic wise they've been
exposed to different environments and
different stressors and that has changed
their genetics so just like the twin
even with humans you take two twins and
one of them
grows up well super healthy and the
other one is malnourished growing up
you're gonna get different you're gonna
get that particular exact
clone in a sense right that identical
twin to
um one be displaying different traits
even later on in their life they could
have displayed either trait right
of being a little hunched back or being
standing up straight for example
but due to those stressors so when it
comes to clones
a lot of times and even seed batches as
people are doing
we sort of end up defaulting down into
things not being as healthy
and um one of the easiest ways to bring
up the health of stuff is just the pick
for
healthier plants in the beginning okay
that makes sense so if that kind of
makes sense in that real i just say
start start start soft
start simple gotcha now when i first
grow the male
i was really surprised by not only how
fast those pollen stacks
grew but how fast they opened up you
know so i think it was like around day
20 or something upon sacks were opened
up and pollen was going everywhere
um around what day of flower
do you feel it's best to kind of harvest
pollen or
collect pollen from males in order to
kind of maximize the amount of pollen
you're getting
because some people there you know let
me back up a second so some people are
actually collecting the pollen storing
it
and using it later and then there's some
people who are just putting a male in
with a female
and shaking it so as far as like people
who are collecting it what day of flower
was best do you think to kind of harvest
that pollen in my experience there's no
difference between pollen that is just
being released and pollen that's um
on a male that's been opening pollen up
for a couple of weeks
the viability and strength of that
pollen the genetics that they're passing
on
is exactly the same they're just doing
it at different rates you know they're
they're growing up they're the first
statements and are coming out they're
starting to drop pollen for the males
um the wind i mean you know with like
hemp for example like you know you don't
even need a pollinator like these or
anything like that right you just you
know the wind will just take care of it
um so if you're in a chamber or
something
that'll just all on its own um
get off an environment and the females
will grab it if you're collecting
then you don't have to worry about it
you can just do it right at the
beginning get enough pollen and you can
nuke that male and you don't have to
keep it around you don't have to waste
time on it
or anything like that so if you're just
doing pollen collection
then yeah collect as much as you need
right at the beginning and then you can
move on it will not
change the strength or any of the traits
by letting the males go longer they're
just going to keep producing pollen to
get more females because
plants grow at different rates
especially in nature so the plants know
that like hey you know they drop males
drop pollen from
you know they start opening up every two
or three weeks right you know usually by
week three males are totally blooming
and then they're gonna bloom until week
five or six and then they're just
they'll almost die off themselves like
after they've spent males are just like
and then they're down you won't even see
them last which is why we usually say
even if you're doing chambers or
something you can cut off your males
after week five or week six
and not even worry about it and then
once the males are cut out of the
situation
then the females will put a lot more
production and okay i'm not getting any
more male pollen
like now i'm really going to put that
production into the seeds and the
embryos
okay and then as far as like collecting
the collecting process i've done a
couple different ways i mean i've put a
bag over the actual branch
and shook it so the palm gets collected
in a bag you know cutting it off
you know bashing it down onto like tin
foil and then scraping it up is another
way
i'm using one of those like trim trays
you know that has a screen on it bashing
it down there so all the pollen comes
down below i found that
to be kind of the best way what
techniques do you use
to collect pollen yeah so your biggest
thing for collecting pollen because
pollen is gonna go inert really quickly
if it dries up
um and that's one thing to note also
with males just as like a side tangent
which is like if you have a male
um and it dries up or the pollen dries
up it's going to go inert within
like 72 hours if it dries it'll be dead
it won't matter you can see the little
yellow pollen around
you know on the edges but if it's dried
up and gone it's gone
and it won't be pollinating anything
else anymore so you want to
throw that into a cool environment right
um i'm guessing you
you either did fridge or freeze um the
pollen yeah i put it in the fridge and i
was
another question i was going to ask you
is the best way to store pollen yeah so
um cooling it down and keeping the
moisture level it's basically what's
going on with the fridge and cooling it
then you'll you'll get
six months or so out of it um often um
getting into longer period freezing then
you need to freeze it
and then um normal fridges work okay
you know you're lucky to get a year year
and a half out of that pollen um
you'll need to get into like minus 80
environments um
to be able to store pollen for longer
periods of time and then of course
any time you freeze it because we all
know this water expands
i'm just like a human being or you know
you put ice you put water
in a glass inside your freezer dice
expands breaks the glass
same things happen with cells so when
you go to dethaw stuff
if it wasn't frozen quickly enough it
can actually like the expansion
will will happen and when you go to d
thought it will create more problems
with moisture
and damage the pollen itself so it's the
d thought process that ends up being
hard
which is why yeah if you want to be able
to kind of move into a
similar round like on the next round you
know you're going to use that pollen on
the next round but you just want to save
it for
a couple months then just throwing it in
the fridge is generally a better idea
one of the things you want to do for
oxygen is oxidization
or oxidization and everything is that
you want to get the air out as much air
and getting out enough particles so
like you're saying putting it over a
screen and just getting the pollen
itself and keeping out a lot of the
larger
cell structure the stamens and you know
leaf matter and things like that
is going to help in that storage process
without inviting any
other because there's moles and fungi
and everything like that floating around
bacteria floating around and those
bacteria and everything and
and fungi's will eat away and start in
the d thought process or even inside the
fridge right
so you want to cool it down enough where
you don't promote that kind of
warmer situation where you'll get like
fungi's and things
to grow and keep it nice and clean so
screening it
getting it into a container of some kind
and then getting the air out which is
why i'm more of a fan of yeah
whether you get it onto a plate or tin
foil like you were saying or whatever
different techniques are and you kind of
shake some
and you scoop it up a little spoon get
it into you can put it into vials things
like that but it's harder to get the
oxygen out
where with like a little baggie you can
if you store them in bags you can even
just kind of press the air out right
and just get most the air out and then
that will help with long-term storage
so getting the air out and then keeping
the natural moisture level it was at
cool down then you're going to create a
good environment for that pollen to stay
moist enough where it's viable
but doesn't degrade and doesn't also get
eaten away at some kind of pest
good info really good info there let's
move on to the female
selection process so we talked about
males now let's talk about females
so you said it was a little bit
different of a process when you're
selecting females
how do you select females what's your
process um the nice thing about females
is that you kind of
can i still lend myself away and again
different people can have different
techniques i
encourage people to have different
techniques um for what they do so just
because i do something a certain way
um doesn't mean it's the right way to go
about it or do it
because i'm have such a heavy background
in creating clones um
trying to find specific traits that are
expressed
and finding unique things then i will
hunt or what we call pheno
phenol hunt out females and then use
those as my base
line now whether i get into fleel
breeding or i just use back crossing
quite a bit um and that work lends
itself really well
for like our particular like medicinal
style
or hemp braiding and stuff that uh yeah
for females
i generally go to hunt for you know what
i would want to
run as a mono crop i find something that
would be great to run just as
propagation for clones
so you clone a bunch and then you run
all whole tray or a whole room
just in that one crop so i'll find
things that i
to me are something i would love to grow
in larger production
and then we'll take that as our baseline
and then use that either for allele
crossing um f1 style crossing and
hybridization
or we'll use it for back crossing into
future generations to try and stabilize
those traits
into being when you grow the seeds out
hopefully
or eventually if you get it right you
can get those seeds to basically what
they call stable
and not to be confused with i know the
terminology a lot people are like oh
they're stable like as if they're stable
against hermaphroditic traits
which is true it can be stable against
the maverick traits but the word
stable when it comes to saying seeds are
stable
means that they come out like a
monoculture that
99 of the traits that they display that
the girls are displaying
they almost look like clones that would
be stability or true stability
so we're getting closer to stability and
a lot quicker with back crossing
so start with some baseline thing um and
then you just you're back crossing to
those
you'll end up getting down as long as
you don't run into some weird odd
mutation um and everything's pretty
healthy
then you can get those seeds by bx4 bx5
um there's some nuances in there and
some things that we do see depending on
what
back cross generation it is and depends
on the particular strain line
but usually by bx 6 or so you should
have a pretty stable run of just seeds
and then so now you have seeds in the
same way you could produce
just those clones by propagating but the
nice thing about seeds unlike clones
is that seeds can stay viable for years
without with just some decent storage
and still get perfect propagation
so then it just kind of depends on you
know what
way in agriculture do you want to hold
moms clones or seeds things like that
okay and when it comes to the actual
pollination
process right i feel like if you're if
you're trying to pollinate a female too
early you could
mess things up if it's too late you
could kind of mess things up as far as
like
your overall yield on seeds or however
you want to say it
around what day of flower would you
suggest you know what do you think is
like the best day to pollinate
so i'm a big believer in nature and for
how many seeds the plants produce
for the average person going into this
you are going to get
so many seeds that you should never
really worry about trying to do what we
call
seed production runs where you'll
purposely grow the females out
to like week three before even setting a
male into flowering
so that way by the time the male opens
up and starts producing pollen at his
week three
the females are say at week six and we
all know that a six week old female is
going to have a lot more flower sites a
lot more pistols a lot more calyx sites
to be able to absorb pollen
and you're going to be able to get more
seed out of it
to me it one it depends on the strain
and two it's kind of negligible i mean
there are so
many seeds that it's it's not really
that much more production to me i think
that would be something i would talk to
um when it comes to production for
facilities
when facilities are trying to do it so
if i were counseling that then we could
start eating the nuance with particular
strains
but even when you're first breeding and
you just want to keep things natural
again back to the healthy and strong
thing
if you put males in with the females
they know that
they are sending out signals to each
other right
they're picking that up and the females
will grow just with a male in the
vicinity you will see them grow
slightly differently because they know
that there's a male there and they are
bumping themselves up getting ready for
it
um the other way is that they will
they want to get seeded and so they'll
start putting out
and you we can smell it in terpenes
right the females will start putting a
lot of production into like trying to
basically be sexy
and um that to me lends itself more to
like they want to get
seeds in and you can get a lot of
production but i find
healthier better phenotypes from females
that like had a male and they were ready
to go
right at the same time period because in
nature the males are going to grow in a
field
with the females randomly or in the same
environment under the same
lighting system lighting times or photo
period times excuse me
so they're going to get the same basic
signals from those environmental
conditions
to start up their production on whether
or not they're going to be
getting seed or not getting seed so i
think it stresses out the females a
little bit
more uh when you hold that back from
them and it's fine when we're just using
the female flower product and that's
what we're getting it for we're using it
for a specific thing we've bred them to
have these
big fat flowers for example right or
same with cucumbers and stuff
we've bred them to get real big and not
have any seeds
bananas um examples et cetera
so you kind of have to look past like
what we've done for breeding and whatnot
and what's really stressing the plan
out and overall that is a stress so
getting the males in early when you're
just trying to find the best things
is always my recommendation is what i go
for is just let the males get in there
naturally because the females are still
going to produce
more than enough seed even when you're
doing production on a personal level
i find that to be the best way and then
also logistically it just makes it much
easier
so everything kind of lines itself up to
just like get the males in with the
females
and let them have a party that makes
sense i was going to ask you about
yield now generally speaking i mean you
can you can veg a plant out fill up like
a four by four space and then
pollinate that plant you're gonna get a
lot more
seeds than you would a smaller plant
right
so kind of generally speaking you know
do you have a recommended size plant to
pollinate and like roughly how many
seeds can potentially yield it from that
size
yeah of course again strains or as
you're kind of like pointing like
strains are gonna dependent i mean how
big they are different ones do
it's just like female just when you're
even going for flower production for
that kind of thing with like total sense
of mean no seeds
right um you're going different strains
are going to lend themselves to
different training techniques
obviously with breeding you start
getting a male into something like a
chamber
then you're not gonna be able to train
them out as well you're gonna get to a
point where if they're locked in a
chamber you can't get in there and like
strip down certain families and still
try and promote certain kinds of growth
it's gonna be a little bit more
difficult challenge unless you're doing
the
pollen collection gonna do bagging of
certain branches um but even then if
you're doing that kind of technique well
you're not going for tons of seed you're
just trying to get enough
uh seed variety out that you can go and
experiment and find some different
phenotypes
okay gotcha let's get into feminized
seeds so becoming more and more popular
right you have regular seeds which can
be
they can end up being a male plant or a
female plant you have feminized seeds
which
are supposed to be always female that's
going to happen but they're supposed to
be so how would
feather knives they're supposed to be
displaying
just their female traits so um that
that's what they're attempting to do is
get them there now hemp itself has a
natural mutation somewhere along the
line we don't know exactly where like
we have been going in and out of
production for
hemp for thousands of years and there
are things that like in the 60s and 70s
when all the hippies went out and found
all the crazy stuff that was still out
and around or near farms and
you know vietnam or somewhere and some
of them were wild
well they weren't really wild if we look
back in the genetics of these plants we
can tell that they had gone through some
kind of selection process and
humans were involved in moving them
towards different kinds of traits in
those areas
so it is a crop that we have had our
hands in for a long time
even when it has gone back to wild this
so they do display these traits of what
we call
hermaphrodite right traits where they
will um
just like uh plants that have
just have male and female parts they'll
kind of do the same thing
um so we can basically leverage that
trait this hermaphroditic trait to and
this is where we get into
even those females though um will still
have chromosomes
that are displaying both um xx
y so both an x and a y chromosomes
this is why if you give them a little
bit of a stress they're much more likely
to
show those traits but even the
males and females that you get in true
breeding still have this stress trait
in their genetics and most likely from
the
nature we can imagine you get to the
fall time a female's there
self-preservation there were no males to
pollinate it at the end
it'll it'll pollinate itself frost is
coming it'll throw out some male
male sacks pollen will come it'll
pollinate itself
and at least it'll keep that thing going
into the next
year the next season after the frost or
whatever it is wherever that environment
is
so that's where we can theoretically
like imagine that that's where that
trait comes from
and so we're trying to leverage that
trait by then producing
um plants that will only show female
flowers a trait for only displaying
female flowers
and we don't have to worry about that so
that's where we
get into the feminized breeding that's
why it works that way
and it works great if you're super
healthy and you're super good about your
selection
then you can absolutely feminize as we
call it like this branding term
into seeds unfortunately a lot of people
in a lot of breeders and places
just don't take the time to one make the
proper selection to get down
to make sure that like they're stress
tested everything like that and it takes
a lot of time it's one of the reasons i
stay away from it i've done a lot of
that for pheno hunting
to go find strains out of clones and to
make clones
because you can find a clone out of
feminized seeds right
that has all the traits you want doesn't
show the hermaphroditic traits
is really strong and so that's easy to
pick so i don't have to go that far down
in fem breeding to find good clones and
then be able to then maybe add some
males back in there re-hybridize out the
genetics kind of get it reset
but still grab those traits that are
dominant mostly
for those particular strains in
other places though if you give them the
stress people may see like oh in their
environment
they smashed you know two females
together and one of them they
hermaphrodited for feminized seeds made
femme seeds
in their um environment it seemed fine
they didn't get any aphrodite traits but
then
tons of people are reporting back that
they share those seeds with that they're
having issues
and so that's where you run into this
issue over and over again where
sometimes
people love femme seeds they never have
any problems it's all great good
breeding was done
great selection was done and then in
other places
it wasn't maybe even good selection was
done but in their environment so you
have to really
expose them to a lot of different
environments to be able to
figure out whether or not those traits
will be expressed
where for myself yeah i stick to a lot
of true breeding because
even if those are in strains that we use
those kinds of traits
they definitely aren't displayed as much
and they seem to be healthier and be
able to get through a lot more stressful
situations
by having the variety in that genetics
especially with the way
excuse me the way that we've hybridized
the entire species itself so much
that's really interesting so you touched
on how feminized these are created
autoflowers another popular type of seed
or plant
how are those seeds created so
autoflowers come
from part of the species the taxonomy
for that
right is that that is a ruderalis
so it is related to hemp or is hemp but
it is started going off in a different
path like a lion and a tiger
um we were so they're farther away from
each other
versus like if you go and look at lions
or um even killer whales like for
example
there's two different kinds of killer
whales there's like the northern
hemisphere ones that hang out and then
there's the lower hemisphere ones and to
us by eye you might not notice the
difference
but actually if you study them they've
sort of started to bridge away from each
other
and one is smaller than the other one
have a little bit different social
interactions etc
but they're not totally different with
something they can't breed so same with
lions right like
lions can be that way too you think like
all lions are the same but actually
there's some different depending on the
zones and where they are
like in say africa for example where
lions are in different place
environments
they've gone away from each other but
you take those lines back together and
you'll there's still lions versus a
tiger which is all the way out
so i look at like rude alice is like a
tiger
you sort of you get into breeding that
with
um what we've made selection for for so
long on our production
that we've had a lot of hand in you're
going back to something that
has a slightly different genetic makeup
now autoflowers are in
zones and they were pulled in a place
where they will flower automatically
regardless
of your photo period so photo period
doesn't affect them that's the trait
that comes along with them
so what the advantage of that of course
is that if you pop a seed
it will vegetate itself up no matter the
light you could give it 24 hours of
light
it'll do that for three four weeks and
then it'll just start flowering and you
can leave it on 24
hours of light and it'll keep flowering
so that is a great trait for somebody to
be able to just you know throw a plant
um in their backyard or on a porch or
something
and it makes a lot of sense you don't
have to worry about photo periods
the issue with this is that it's
really hard to get again we're back to
dominant and recessive traits
to be able to pull in the trait so if
the progeny or the offspring
you breed with it with a ruderalis male
for example there's just you know it
could be a female or male but we'll just
say a root or else male
and you take it against your favorite
at-home medicinal
strain some of those progeny
are going to come out reuteralis
or autoflower and some of the progeny
won't it will depend on what's dominant
or recessive now
um some of the traits with a particular
strain maybe
a bunch of them come out rude or alice
and a bunch of them don't come a
ruralist
and that's where you have to do the
breeding to get it in in my experience
with reuter alice because of the
genetics and the way it's been worked
it's
really tough to get like flavor profiles
color et cetera structure because
that you want that you love out of your
photoperiod plant
into an autoflower plant because
the dominant traits for autoflower may
always go against it being purple for
example
so sure all the progeny you can get them
all down
to being all rude or alice after a
couple of generations of breeding or a
few generations
but to get it down to all them being
rude or alice you'll never get the
purple
it'll always be recessive against and
that's just one
example of something that you could and
will run into when
breeding with that verse if you do
feminize seeds right and you sell
something or self it against another or
at least put female
male hermaphrodite pollen onto a female
all those seeds are going to be
that way so it's much easier to get to
you won't see that
with feminized seeds right well it's not
like with feminized seeds some of them
turn out to be male and some someone
turned out to be feeble no no they're
all gonna
majority wise show that female trait
but um when it comes to reuteralis
you're talking about something
completely different so
then you really have to worry about the
recessive and dominant genes to get that
and that's where you get that battle
where some people are like oh i ordered
rudolph seeds and like
some a couple of them were but most of
them weren't even that
and they wouldn't they're not photo
they're just regular photoperiod plants
and that's because the work wasn't done
to make sure that you got those traits
along with it and to stabilize it so
back to stabilizing
a particular strain which is going to be
much more important when doing
autoflowering
and autoflower breeding to stabilize
everything especially for
that particular trait because that's the
trait you're looking for
gotcha yeah i was going to ask you who
uh you know
there's more and more people reaching
out to me saying that they
they got autos but they're not actually
autos and i i honestly feel bad
it seems to be the same breeders uh
first number one i won't expose anybody
in
in this video but uh is it you know
a lot of these home growers they just
have one space to grow in and if you've
got
a plant that's not actually an auto and
you need to flip it to 1212 what do you
do like there's a lot of people that are
just
they're stuck at that point so um yeah
you touched on
how that can actually happen so it's
just you know
not stabilizing and so on and so forth
it's just uh
it's sad to see some of that stuff
people it kind of seems like things are
rushed
in a sense just to get it out on the
market you know so
you know that and that's the age-old
problem even before rude or alice
um autoflower had become fairly popular
over the last years um 10 15 years and
it's really taken off
that's the same problem right we get
with feminized seeds where people get
complaints like oh well i'm everything's
from mapper dieting at week six i can't
even make it past week six and then
suddenly
it's showing its trait that normally
would show at week 12 or something
in in like a normal true female um it
would still throw that hermit
hemophilic trait show to try and
self-pulling itself under stress
but instead it's overtaken and now you
can't even get past week six with those
progeny
without it um flipping over and then
also kind of a fun note
about plants just so some people just to
kind of get in your idea in your head
when it comes to true breed you can also
do this to males
so you can take a male and stress it out
and run it long enough and it will
throw female pistols and flowers and
seed itself
and all of your seeds that come from
that male will be
maleized they will majority show the
male trait and come out as males
but then they'll be throwing female
pistols and things so if you see that in
your males and everything then you know
like
okay this somewhere along the line this
has kind of ended up happening and it
happens with tons of strains i've run
across because i too
standing on the shoulders of giants i'm
working with gear
right like even if it was a long time
ago at some point i started with gear
that
i have no idea what the history is of it
i'm i'm told to certain things i can try
and look it up from
the names and from where it comes from
in that time period but
you never quite know where along the
past something happened
but that's kind of a fun weird thing
about like feminized breeding is that it
also goes the other way too
super interesting i didn't know that
yeah that's really interesting
cool well we can go on and on and on and
on but we're gonna we're gonna wrap
things up here
can you uh tell us how the listeners can
find you and what you've got upcoming in
the future
oh yeah um we uh we're in california
um we run i have run a company called
ocean grown
uh for quite some time the best way to
find
us is we either run on our discord or
you can just go to our website
it's purely educational site no issues
with that
you can find information about where to
find different kinds of products or what
the available producers are
and then i also have a youtube channel
that i've been running as we mentioned
it's just vader og or you can type in
vader vision um it's kind of like the
show that i run through
that uh production so over on youtube
you can
find me there and some resource
videos available and then if you want to
talk to us though or even get a hold of
me a little bit more you have questions
about things
in the community our discord has been um
i used to be big on forums
so i loved forums unless you used to be
able to find me but i've gone away from
that with the newer technology
um into a much more simpler platform
that allows a lot more access so
even if you can't just talk to me you
can talk to people in the team
that are going to be able to help you
out so over at our discord ocean grown
discord and then also you've got a
podcast that you're a part of now huh
you want to talk a little bit about that
growers workshop
oh we've started running a podcast yes
for girls workshop we usually get the
community together
um we used to have a show growtube a lot
of people uh know and that was great to
be able to get a lot of people in our
particular community together
um that is still there to a degree
although we've kind of stepped away from
it um we have some issues with youtube
and banning channels and deleting things
so this time around very similarly we
have created a podcast where we can talk
about these subjects
but keep them available for information
that youtube's not going to remove it so
we try to start this podcast where we
can still talk a little bit
more openly but with the right
nomenclature the right
language to express the information out
there
so growers workshop is uh the podcast
we've been running and then there is
some idea and plans for
um also that's where we've been putting
like build out
stuff chambers things so for people who
want to like be able to do breeding
and you want to be able to have a
chamber area that is going to be good
enough not to let pollen out and
pollinate you know
some females and stuff right nearby and
this can work for orchids and all kinds
of stuff
but these um that is a great place also
to find that kind of information
and it's less it's more grow wide and
same with um
i do do like permaculture
we do hydroponics outdoors for veggies
for all kinds of other things so
that kind of stuff is also a resource
for those looking to do
that kind of stuff but it's slowly
building it's new so
if you go over there and it doesn't seem
like there's too much information we're
new venture that we're working through
cool i will link vader's channel
down in the description section below
and also the growers workshop i'll link
that channel down
in the description section below if you
enjoyed this video please click that
thumbs up button the thumbs up button
helps so much
it helps us to reach more people also
subscribing
if you are new to the channel hit that
subscribe button on youtube
every single week every saturday i
release a new episode unless
susan decides she needs to manually
review it then she uh
then it usually comes out on sunday but
typically every weekend we have a new
episode out
apple podcasts if you're listening on
there please leave a rating
and review we have 79 so far so we're
getting real close to 100
thank you to everyone who has left a
rating or review on apple podcast so far
and lastly sharing this so sharing this
is probably one of the best things that
you can do
reddit is a big area you can share it
facebook groups there are a lot of
facebook groups that you can share it on
uh thank you to everyone who shares this
podcast so
vader thank you so much for coming on to
this podcast it's truly been an honor
i'm
so thankful for you to come on here and
thanks to doggo he's the one who kind of
connected us
to make this happen got to give him a
shout out so absolutely thanks for
having me on and um and of course and
for anyone listening like at
drop questions on whatever platform
you're watching it on
i'm sure i will rotate back through i
can get into more detail i can even be
prepared with some research if somebody
brings up something
theoretical or just something that they
want to know about um there's it's
really tough in these kinds of podcasts
so like yeah keep it within an hour or
45 minutes um because i can tangent
really quick into other
kinds of concepts so keeping that kind
of baseline so hopefully we knocked out
the
the beginner stuff but um absolutely get
down in there and
ask away and i can i will definitely
rotate back through i had a wonderful
time
absolutely well vader thanks again and
uh
hope you enjoy the rest of your day
absolutely you too i'll see you soon
[Music]
peace
you