welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden hey everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned into to the
Garden Talk podcast this episode number
146 in this episode I interview Chris
from crop culture he has been guarding
for 5 years and is big into crop
steering which is what we're going to
get into in today's episode he talks all
about the basics of crop steering
everything from what crop steering is
types of crop steering climate lighting
irrigation and so much more if you want
to see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks Dave Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
humidifiers which can help increase the
humidity in your grow space their
humidifiers have 10 different levels and
spart control features such as VPD and
humidity programming so you can get
precise humidity control click the link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about their humidifiers
and the discount code Mr Grow 15 works
on both Amazon and their website AC
infinity.com stash blend stash blend is
a
215 plant additive that can be used with
synthetic bottle nutrients or in living
soil systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi check it
out at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the stash Mars Hydro check
out their new 2024 LED grill lights
first the SP 3000 this cite was designed
specifically for Greenhouse cultivation
they also have the SP 3000r model which
is a red supplemental light 650 to 665
NM they have the vg40 40 W light which
is for seedlings and veg and the vg8 80
W light which is similar to the vg40 but
for a larger grow space go to their
website mars-hydro
docomo to save on any of their
products and we're back and I'm joined
with Chris from crop culture how you
doing today I'm doing great Chris thanks
for having me yeah thanks for coming on
today we're going to talk all about crop
steering so you actually reached out to
me several months ago and wanted to be
on the podcast to talk shop and I like
talking shop and you gave me some
suggestions for things that we could
kind of get into and lots of good topics
to choose from but I really narrowed it
down to that crop steering one because I
think that's becoming more and more
popular these days amongst folks I get
more and more questions about it and
yeah figured we would dive into that one
this time around and talk about your
experience doing it but first can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening yeah
absolutely um so uh the way that I got
into gardening was actually through
growing and I'll
explain um I think that my story and why
I started growing is very relatable I
think to most Growers that are coming um
that are coming into the uh the scene
nowaday and they're they're going to um
they're going to dispensaries and they
are having really poor experience after
Poor experience and they're overpaying
for product that is overdried and it's
and it's rushed to the shelves and it's
stale and it's flavorless and it's it
has no effects and you're spending
hundreds thousands of dollars and at a
certain point you say enough is enough
and fortunately Illinois went legal back
in 2020 and that was when I decided to
jump on board with it and I did like
most people and I went and Googled uh
you know best place to buy seeds and
Best Equipment and and all those things
and was ushered into you know the uh the
Corrals that are in place with SEO to
make sure that you're landing on white
labeled seed banks and and the and the
the big brands that are paying the top
dollar for o so um I like many went went
and bought all of those those
recommendations and and had uh really
poor results actually surprise surprise
uh with with the first couple runs but I
really enjoyed the the growing aspect of
it the N the nurturing for something
living and it inspired a curiosity in me
to want to get better at this and that's
kind of just in my nature to when I pick
up a hobby I want to be the best at it
um or the best that I can be and uh I
went through exhaust of lengths to to
get more knowledgeable on this plant and
start to understand it at a biological
level and It ultimately led me to living
soil and uh specifically Bill the soil
and and Jeremy Silva um I really
gravitated towards his message and um it
really aligned with who I am as a as a
person and um I started digging deeper
and deeper into living soil and that's
what led me to gardening because
gardening is to me in my mind is a much
more it's a uh it's it's a much broader
term um and to me there's a spiritual
element to it as well but uh I started
growing all sorts of things outside and
we my wife and I collect house plants
and
we amassed this huge collection of house
plants that we had to you know dwindle
down to just the the rare and exotic
ones because you know everybody can go
get a snake plant or you know all you
know money trees and things like that um
but uh it so the the gardening has
stemmed from growing medicinal plants
indoors and um I've I've taken the grows
out doors and it is deep in my
connection with nature my appreciation
for the balance that uh that exists in
nature and uh it's really just been a
beautiful Evolution so uh yeah it was
really just a a constant dissatisfaction
with the dispensary Market that led me
to growing my own medicinal herbs which
led to you know gardening many other
things fruits and vegetables and flowers
things that bring me a lot of Joy that's
awesome and I know you've gone so far to
do a couple different things in the
industry that's notable number one a
podcast you've got the Growers hangout
you're a part of that one if you can
talk about that for and then also the
crop culture box can you talk to us
about those things yes absolutely thank
you uh so um I started a podcast weekly
every Tuesday with my friend Aaron um
support dope people and Pete of heisen
tur brothers and it is a
community-based uh platform where we uh
you know try to provide value to to our
uh viewers and we're trying to bring
guests and experts on that um you know
are bringing a unique perspective and uh
it really does cater to newer Growers
and uh not to say that uh you know
experienced Growers can't find benefit
we've had people like miles from weed to
taste good uh speaking about living soil
and fermented plant extracts and we've
had Eric from Thrive Yahweh who came on
and talked about the value of laop
bacillus and uh and his products and it
was just an amazing Deep dive into the
science of it and
it's it's been a really a really fun
thing to do uh to be able to share the
things that I do in my garden the things
that I've uh experienced a positive
benefit from with people to uh to see if
that's something that they would like to
adopt and uh and do it themselves and as
it relates to uh the crop culture box so
crop culture again was uh again again
stemming from that uh that whole
dispensary thing and when I started
growing I as a collector myself uh pop
culture being a very important part of
my life being a a child of the 80s um
and being you know growing up through I
don't even think it's arguably the most
um profound uh time in American history
when it came to pop culture and um I
incorporate a lot of those things into
the business so what crop culture is um
is a premium uh thoughtfully curated
Growers box that releases quarterly
their theme boxes where I partner with
the the best breeders in the industry
and the best brands in the industry and
I do the research to make sure that
these are the best products and these
are things that get my stample stamp of
approval and um I am able to leverage um
you know wholesale pricing with my
partners and I pass those savings along
to my customers these boxes are truly uh
an unbeatable value and the reason why
I'm able to do this is because I have uh
I have a really good day job that I'm
very fortunate for that it pays the
bills and it affords me the opportunity
to kind of do this as a uh a creative
Venture and uh give back to the
community which I feel is given so much
to me and um not being a very
financially driven person I would rather
pack more value into the box because at
the end of the day I want something that
I would be excited about I have a very I
have very Discerning taste and I want
every single person to open their box
and be blown away by what they received
and you always are going to get much
more than what uh you know what I
advertise I always under promise and
overd deliver um and I work with a lot
of upand cominging breeders as well they
might not be the featured breeder for
the Box because I have to leverage
recognition and things like that um but
I I they send me packs and it's a
platform to to help them grow as well
and and share their genetics with people
and uh get them you know engaging with
these breeders and helping them grow so
it's really been a a beautiful way to
harmoniously bring together breeders and
Brands and um it's not a competitive
thing it is just this everybody can
benefit from it awesome good stuff there
all right let's get into the topic
before people start complaining in the
comment section let's do it crop
steering break it down for us a lot of
beginners tune into my show as well what
is crop steering yeah so crop steering
in a nutshell is taking um the way that
we refer to it is taking your indoor
garden and altering the variables of
your lighting your climate and your
irrigation to steer the outcome of your
plans and uh your phytochemical uh
profiles in your in your plants so your
uh your canabo flavonoids T Turpin we
are trying to
influence yield and flavor and potency
essentially with crop steering and then
there's a couple different types there's
vegetative steering and then generative
steering first off what is vegetative
steering what is meant by that
vegetative steering and the difference
between that and um generative steering
is generative steering is uh triggering
the light cycle for photo period plants
so this is where you are uh you are in
an indoor environment switching your
light cycle to 12 hours on 12 hours off
to trigger that flowering cycle there
are things that you can also do with
that light cycle in terms of the light
duration and intensity to also influence
the the outcome of uh of your plants but
um
with in the vegetative uh in vegetative
steering this is where we are going to
be adjusting inputs like our humidity
and um our lighting to and as well as
our irrigation to influence how our
plant grows how vigorously it grows
there are ways to slow down growth if
you're like me and a really bad at
planting your grows and sometimes run
into a situation where you have small
plants that you don't have anywhere to
put and you have to wait for your tents
to open up there are ways that you could
safely and do it without minimal with
minimal impact to your plants reduce the
growth of your plant and have it pick
right back up as soon as you get it
transplanted so that is basically what
we are what we're going to be talking
about today are some of the experiences
that I have had adjusting those various
um inputs to have dramatically different
results in many of the plants that I've
grown out over the years you mentioned
having a slow down plant growth and it's
uh kind of laugh a little bit because I
actually released a whole video on how
to titled how to slow down plant growth
and that definitely raised some eyebrows
for sure but the thing was I was going
on vacation right and I didn't want to
come back and have the plants grown into
the light and so yeah there are things
that sometimes you do need to slow down
plant growth but uh that's definitely a
separate topic there okay so good
definitions on both of those things
let's get into to start we we'll break
down each individual thing you talked
about climate and then light intensity
and irrigation let's start with the
climate and I think one of the things
that come to mind is the temperature day
temps versus night temps so can you kind
of break it down for us like what are
you typically aiming for for day temps
what do you aim for for night temps what
impact the has on plant growth so on and
so forth absolutely so um this might be
a little controversial
but I kind of like high high
temperatures um when I am in veg when my
plants are I would say 3 weeks old all
the way through up until week six of
flower I like high temperatures I am
completely fine with my tense tense
reaching 90°
92° as long as you have adequate
humidity for the uh for the phase of
growth that your plant is in adequate
air exchange and air flow so I have I
have a 4x2 living soil bed in a 4x2 tent
and um I often have troubles keeping the
uh the temperatures down in that tent
I've had issues with with heat stress
there is a a healthy amount of stress I
think is acceptable and actually needed
in every plant's life I think to bring
out the best Expressions because let's
face it we're we're trying to this is
biomimicry when we're talking about
growing indoors if you look
outdoors in the in the in the summertime
you go outside to if you're growing an
outdoor plant and it is 95°
outside your plant is praying why is
that and your hum you know the humidity
might be 40 40 % out there um I think we
we try we try to attain these these
perfect temperatures and humidities and
VPD is obviously something a lot of
people pay a lot of attention to I pay
attention to it but I have a a very go
with the flow type of approach where I
just go into my my garage and I react to
how my plants look and um there are
there are things that um so so we talk
about high temperatures later in flow I
want to be very very careful because
like you said you have newer Growers you
have to have adequate air flow in air
exchange if you are going to have higher
temp uh higher humidity levels I am fine
if it's 90 90° and 70% humidity week six
flow my plants are loving it at that
point um so you just want to you just
have to keep in keep in mind you have to
keep that ratio uh ratio appropriate and
making sure that if you're if you have
leaves overlapping each other you're not
getting moisture pockets and things like
that so there are things that you just
have to be aware of but um you know
higher temperatures you're going to get
you're you're you're going to get higher
yields and your plants are going to grow
more vigorously um especially in veg uh
you you have nice high temperatures nice
high humidities your plants are going to
grow very rapidly um so like I said I I
tell people all the time when they ask
me questions I say it really depends
because there is no one- siiz fits-all
solution to this and uh or when it comes
to advice because everybody has
different growing parameters and
different mediums and inputs and things
like that so I I try to speak in
generalities and and add caveats as much
as possible yeah I try to do the same
thing because you know over the years
people have complained because uh you
know like oh that's not the right
temperature that's you can do this
temperature instead and it's like yeah
you can you can do 90° Fahrenheit like
Chris is doing right or you could go
down and do 75° right so it's like
you're still going to get to harvest but
yeah I'm looking at the vpg chart right
now 90° in flow it calls for 64 to 68% R
so it's pretty high higher than a lot of
people would go in the flower stage cuz
they don't want to do that humidity but
don't want to risk mold I should say but
uh you can totally get away with it
especially if you have that air flow now
I'm usually running about 82° fah and
then I try to drop at after week five
six of flour I'm trying to drop it down
a little bit to try to conserve some of
those tpin right the flavonoids yes 100%
and actually I have a a really perfect
example of that we try to work on uh our
weakest variable right so I grow in a
garage and I'm at the mercy of the
outside temperatures and often times the
the hard the things that we can't
control are are are the hardest things
and uh it's it's not always about the
your environment inside your tent that's
important it's a lot of times what your
outside is that's driving those in
inside conditions so um it is not ideal
I do want to be very very clear to have
90 Dee temperatures in week six of flour
that is not ideal uh and as you drop
your temperatures there are other things
that you're going to see happen tpine
preservation is incredibly important um
you're going to see uh your anth thein
is going if it's if it's present in gen
in the genetics your PL your plants are
going to get you know burgundy and
purples um and you're going to get that
beautiful fall Fade with the cooler
temperatures um but uh I actually grew
out a clone two clones of Lumpy's apple
fritter uh lumpy cut of apple fritter um
and I wanted to do I do a lot of side
by-side testing I think there is a
tremendous amount of value in doing
testing for a home grower um because
it's low risk and by failing You observe
what caused it to fail and I feel you
learn from those failures so it is an
important part of the the growing
process is that failure um but then also
sometimes you have happy uh accidents
and and really interesting things happen
uh when you least expect it so I grew
out this uh this apple fritter uh Earth
boxes for both um and I grew one under
uh about 600 par which is typically the
range that I prefer for my flowering
plants 600 to
900 uh is kind of I I don't push my
plants very hard because I don't
supplement
CO2 um so at the lower intensities I
observed uh the plant's morphology was
very different the uh the flowers were
larger they were um they were firm but
they were not dense and they had a lot
more Tricom coverage versus the ones
that I grew in another tent at around
1100 uh par and uh all the same inputs
uh but the buds were smaller they were
much more dense um less tricomes and the
flavor was completely different
completely different um and I even grew
it out a third time with even less light
in a in a 2X two tent and I got where I
got gas the first time I got grape the
the the next time just wildly different
all from the same clone just by altering
light intensities so now you can look at
let's experiment with
UVB uh I mean there's been studies
showing that there's significant tpine
production increase with uh with UVB in
small amounts uh in the day or using red
light uh when you when you put your
plants to sleep to help ease them into
into sleep uh there are all all sorts of
really cool things that we could do with
uh light intensity and and U and color
frequencies and things like that to
impact um our our end result as well
that a really good example of how
different climates will yield different
results right you mentioned the two
different clones you had and different
environments and two completely
different outcomes so great example of
that one how about day length now that's
something that people talk about when it
comes to crop steering talk to us about
that I've done a few things when we're
talking about um indoor
controls uh you know I I do have uh AC
Infinity lights that have the the the
daylight uh the sunrise sunset feature
I've experimented with that I wouldn't
say that I've done it I've gone done any
like true side by-side comparisons with
that by any means but um what I I did
notice on the few times that I have kind
of stepped my plants down vers uh so
going from 186 to 14 hours on versus
going straight to
1212 um I have found a gentler
transition you can make the argument
that the plant doesn't care and if you
flip it to 12 it's going to adjust and
you're just going to have more time
where it's going to be able to produce
at at a you know our generative phase
but um like I said I've I've tried I've
tried it numerous times it's some I
think
there's we may never be able to quantify
it but at the very least you'll save
energy and that's not a bad thing but
when we're when we're talking about
light duration we have to talk about DLI
um um and for anybody who is listening
that um hasn't measured their their
light intensity um not saying you have
to go buy an expensive meter they have
uh very effective meters um as apps on
your phone and they have little
attachments you can get on your phone
and they get really really close to some
of the higher quality um light meters
out there but it is super important to
um have your Baseline to know where your
plants are and how much light they're
getting because when you drop your your
lights from 18 hours to uh of light to
12 hours of light your plants uh think
of it as a battery your battery is not
going to fully charge if you keep your
light uh intensity at the same uh at the
same rate um at that at that lower
duration so um you have to scale it
appropriately so uh definitely start
measuring par uh ppfd if you if you are
not um because I I think that is one of
the evolutions of the hom grower is kind
of like the next step to to Really um
honing in your grow and having full
control uh or better control I should
say of uh of your outcomes so um yeah I
I I would say uh th those are probably
the things that that I've I've
personally experimented with and and I'm
currently doing is just kind of stepping
down the light but again it's I don't
know if it's something I can necess
necessarily say definitively like yes
this is making a positive or negative
impact one way or the other got it and
you mentioned the par range that you
typically aim for 600 to 900 ppfd and
flowering I usually do the same range
there I think it's a good General range
but like you mentioned DLI needs to be
factored into it I have a DLI calculator
up right now and this pretty easy to use
if you Google it I'm not sure if folks
in listening in have done this before
but you just put in your ppfd so I put
900 and then time hours that would be
how long the lights are on for 12 hours
that's a 38.888421100000
and that's one thing that we kind of I
gu skipped over a little bit when we
were talking about climate do you have
anything to add about CO2 like are you
supplementing CO2 is there certain ppms
that you're aiming for how does that
factor into crop
steering so um that is actually one area
that I haven't uh that I haven't gotten
into because I have I've taken into
account the opinions of Growers that I
know that have supplemented CO2 um and
measured it uh as well as people people
that I really respect in the industry
that uh that supplement CO2 and I think
for my style of growing it is it I I
determined it to be an unnecessary
expense because like I said I am not
pushing my my lights very hard I know
I'm leaving yield on the table I I I
definitely know that but as a hom grower
I'm okay with that because I really am
prioritizing the flavor um over over uh
the yield of course I like to have both
you know we love to have it all but but
um you know that that's just kind of uh
really depends on what your priorities
are as a grower and if you need to
monetize your medicinales then you know
and prioritize yield then you know
that's uh your prerogative and um you
know it's probably financially
beneficial too then it probably pay for
itself but uh yeah it's just it's just
not something that um really fits with
my growing style yet but it's not
something I am against testing in the in
the future if the opportunity presents
itself yeah I've experimented a little
little bit with CO2 in the past nothing
too crazy those mushroom bags and the
canisters which a lot of controversy
about those on whether or not they work
I have a monitor so I was able to see it
was elevated I'm no longer using them
you know just like you I'm a small home
grower I exhale CO2 and that's enough
for the the home I live in the plants
where I am but it is certainly worth
mentioning I know there's a study out of
Utah State University where they did PPM
levels of CO2 up to 1,400 and they saw
30% increasing and yield due to that so
it's definitely worth it to increase CO2
supplement CO2 if you are looking for
yield but not everybody's looking for
that and I'm not too sure how that if
adjusting the CO2 up and down would
affect the plant in some way like if
people use that in crop steering in
order to try to control the growth or or
whatever so I guess that's something
that uh going have to do some more
research and figure out yeah it's very
interesting because um I mean
essentially what you could be doing is
um you're stressing it it's there's
there's going to be a stress response
and it's not too dissimilar to the way
other plants are um are steered where
they will flip the light cycle between
uh generative and vegetative and um use
that to actually increase yield you
wouldn't do that obviously with with
medicinal herbs because they would they
would freak out and rev and you would
have all sorts of issues but um yeah
theoretically it's it's not too
dissimilar to that so we already dove
into light intensity a little bit uh you
touched upon sunrise and sunset but
there is one thing I want to add to that
so there was a study from Dr Bruce bugby
again coming out of US State University
where he tested sunrise sunset that
feature of gradually giving the plants
light up to full power versus just
blasting the plants full power when the
light cycle comes on and what they found
was that there was actually faster
growth when you just blast that light to
begin now when I had mentioned that in
videos in the past the podcast episodes
in the past you get people in the
comments are like okay so the growth
rate is better when you're blasting
light individually versus the sunrise
sunset but is there other triggers
within the plant that is happening
during that Sunrise Sunset and I think
that's an a question that isn't answered
yet so fig I'd throw that out there for
folks you know that's one thing that
when it comes to cultivation we don't
know everything yet scientists is still
uncovering things so some beginners
might be listening this and be like U
seems to be some conflicting information
yeah there's it's loaded with
conflicting information in this that's
the fun part is kind of diving through
and trying to figure out what works and
what doesn't experimentation on your own
and stuff like that but the discussion
should still kind of go on and yeah fig
I'd mention that even though we don't
have a clear-cut answer on uh on that
study yes absolutely experimentation man
like don't be afraid to just just try
something you know like what's the word
that can happen you you might lose a
plant you know like but you might gain
invaluable Knowledge from that from that
failure too I think when you when you
could see something go go bad you you
can learn a lot from that you know so
yeah like just the troubleshooting
aspect of it and researching why things
are are starting to you know have a
certain reaction One Way or Another yeah
it's all very interesting but experiment
absolutely all right let's move on let's
dive into irrigation so this is a key
thing that is done while crop steering
like you mentioned in the beginning of
this episode we've got irrigation volume
we've got frequency and timing we got
dryback talk to us about irrigation I'll
kind of just give you the microphone
here and drop some knowledge on us sure
so as a
grower um new or experience watering is
I think the hardest part to get down and
it's especially important uh and I will
speak to a lot of these things through
the lens of living soil because that is
what I have the most experience with but
I think that it's there's also wider
applicability with this as well
generally speaking um there are there
are things that we could do when it
comes to how much we are watering and
how uh frequently we are watering to
drive uh you know growth of our plants
or stunt it um more more frequently I
think people suffer from
um I think there is a a common
misunderstanding of when we're watering
what is what is overwatering it is not a
thorough saturation of your soil that is
causing the overwatering it is the
thorough saturation and the constant
saturation is the frequency that is
becoming the issue and your plants don't
have a way to breathe so um dryb backs
are incredibly important and that's why
in living soil when we as living soil
Growers have to we can't let things get
too dry obviously we have to maintain
this this perfect balance I think for us
it's very important to have uh some sort
of a a way to measure so getting some
sort of a meter to to to measure your
moisture is I think very important um
whether you're me measuring your
moisture at the bottom or the top uh
doesn't really matter as much because
the way that I see
if you're able to learn the patterns of
when your water your plant needs water
and when you uh when your plant needs to
dry back you'll you'll be able to you
know those percentages you know the Ean
flow that's the most important thing to
do and we can I mean we could talk hours
on on watering practices um but the dry
back in flow so again biomimicry blatant
flour if you're Outdoors growing less
less rain you go your you the the dog
days of summer it's drought-like
conditions right your plants are um
they're they're going into a
preservation mode where they're not
going to grow as rapidly um and when you
are in an indoor environment you want to
do this a similar type of thing they're
not going to be drinking as much later
in flour so watering less and less
frequently um again late in the late
stages of of flower is what you're going
to want because I think you see if you
if you look in a lot of Growers Gardens
and you see a lot of the leaves that are
kind of you they got the curve generally
speaking that happen from overwatering
and a lot of times it happens late in
flour because you're pumping it with
water you want to give it all those good
nutrients that you're giving all those
those supplementation with your ferments
and and and other things like that you
need to start backing that stuff off
starting around week week six or so
depending on the cultivar again it all
depends if you're growing a sativa
that's a 22 weer you don't need to back
off just yet but if you know if you're
growing a hybrid Inda something that's
like a you know eight or nine weer I
would say week six is around the time
you're going to want to start pulling
that stuff back because your plants
going to drink less and uh you you you
don't want to get to a point where you
drown your plant and you do stunt your
uh your flower growth uh because I have
I have done that numerous times I'm I'm
constantly struggling with finding the
the right balance for watering it's uh
because I I grow in a bunch of different
things I grow in a living soil bed I
have Earth boxes and I have autopots and
they all have nuances to their watering
practices so um the amount and frequency
very important another thing that I have
found very satisfying in of late having
a friend that's local that um has been a
uh that miles from fermented plant
exract was uh a mentor too he's uh he
has his own ferment company so I have
access to a lot of different types of
ferments and I have tried so many
different types and what I have found is
that there are a couple in particular
that do an amazing job of being like an
all purpose F ferment because um the the
typical uh I
guess process with fermentation is
you're trying to encapsulate a moment of
time of whatever you're fermenting what
I mean by that if it's um hemp leaves
for instance that's coming from the the
vegetative phase of of a plant your
fermenting that you are going to be
getting more of the nutrition and things
that are prevalent in that phase of the
of that
material's uh you know life cycle when
it was harvested conversely with flowers
or fruit things like that those are
going to have higher uh you know pot
like geared more towards your flowering
phase and they may have tra you know
smaller amounts of nutrition like
phosphorus and potassium um although we
don't use ferments really for for
nutrition it's just kind of an
unintended benefit of it being there um
but Peach and Willow
um I've tried confrey is is amazing for
uh for veg and pumpkin is awesome for
flour but I find Peach has given the
most robust flavor in all of the
different varieties that I have tried it
in and um I think Willow is kind of a
kind of a sleeper um I think um I don't
know that I I could speak to why
performs so well but um there were there
were visual differences in my plant's
Health when I was using the willow uh
again I I I do it when I when I compare
clones I I run clones so I can do a true
AB test uh so when I when I say these
things it's not me testing these
theories on multiple cultivars or even
multiple phenotypes U they're usually
you know they're they're from clone so
um it's you could you could definitely
see a market difference between the
different types of fermentation so for
people that haven't experimented with
ferments I highly recommend ferments as
uh as something that you could start
incorporating into your watering regimen
very safely um and uh you will see a a
visual difference in your plants in a
very very short amount of time uh
ferments are awesome definitely where
it's at I'm going to have to check out
your buddy's website there and probably
pick something up try out going back to
irrigation real quick one of the things
you touched upon was moisture meters I
think that's a game Cher for a lot of
folks here I think that's one of the
struggles of beginner Growers is dialing
and watering medium being too wet or too
dry now sometimes it's good with the dry
backs right it does help the plant but
if it's unintentional well then it's not
good and I'm waiting for AC Infinity to
release the moisture meter if you're
listening to AC Infinity release one
because that's going to be huge and send
me 12 because I'll them and I will use
them a lot of people are using them I
know there's the Eco wit one blue matat
I have a blue matat one right now the
blue mat moisture meter very expensive
though it's like 85 bucks for just one
meter so hopefully it's more affordable
options on the future but it'd be really
really cool to be able to just look at
your cell phone and see what the
different moisture levels are and then
get alerts when you need to water I
think that would be really really cool
in the future that's on my My Hope list
yes yes yeah mine too I have a couple on
my short list for AC
Infinity but dryb backs one more thing I
want to dive a little bit deeper into
because we have folks who are doing this
using synthetic bottle nutrients and
that's a little bit easier than doing
with Organics Organics you can kind of
run into issues if you are doing these
dry backs I think it's commonly known
now that with Organics using organic
inputs you're relying on the microbes to
actually break down those inputs and
turn them into usable nutrients for the
plant and if there's no moisture in the
medium or if it's too dry those microbes
actually kind die either die off or go
dormant and then you need to obviously
res saturate the medium in order to kind
of get that thing going again so if
you're doing crop steering and using
organic inputs how would you go about
doing dryb backs so I'm actually going
to use um the autopots as a as an
example because um the autopot is and
actually this could be applicable to
basically any sub irrigated system but
I'm going to I'm going to speak
specifically to the auto pots um so in a
living soil setup I'm running the xxl's
which are 13 gallons these are very tall
pots they Wick very well um however uh
you will not be able to Wick all the way
to the top so if you are top dressing
your amendments then you are going to
have to alternate top watering when uh
when you were um to make sure that we're
breaking down those amendments so
perfect example was today I actually
went in and shut off my reservoir
yesterday to make sure that the
everything was starting to dry back so
as the Water started to uh to you know
go down um I have an opportunity then to
top dress and water from the top and I
will do this alternating probably every
every week or so um just to make sure
that the the top never gets um too dry
but also making sure that um you know
I'm able to start breaking down the
things that I'm adding in because just
by me throwing it in there even working
it in the soil it is not going to be
efficient it really um or or adequate
rather it it really does need to um to
have that uh that top watering part as
as part of it um
so I would say the dry backs are are
immensely important because you you
don't want to have half of your your pot
highly saturated because you had your
Reservoir going and then you start top
watering as well your plants will will
hate you for it um and it will take a
while for it to recover um and depending
on how far along you are in flour it may
not fully recover um you know and it
might impact your your yield so um I
think just being Ultra aware of um you
know how much water you're putting in in
the frequency um and make sure that you
know you do have that that dryback uh
especially if you're doing a sub
irrigated system uh it's really an
important part of the process good tips
so we talked about climate light
intensity and irrigation there's some
other things that people do when they do
crop steering which kind of doesn't
really fall in the categories I guess
this next one probably could which is EC
or PPM I know some folks will actually
adjust the EC or PPM specifically when
using like bottled synthetic nutrients
talking Organics with the inputs a lot
of people aren't even looking at the EC
or the PPM right do you have anything to
kind of talk to us about when it comes
to EC or PPM and crop steering so um I
have an expensive EC meter I stopped
using it about 3 years ago uh I was uh I
I actually I did start in soil
uh regular organic soil was not organic
um and and did go to Coco for a while
and and did the synthetic nutrients for
a while but um
definitely what I was spending far too
much time in my garage mixing water and
I was away from my family for far too
long um so when I learned of living soil
and one of the highlights being hey you
don't need to measure things as much and
you don't need to pH your water it's
important to pay attention to your pH I
mean especially if you're adding things
like
you know um highly acidic things or
highly Alkaline Things you definitely
want to be aware of it but I don't
measure it uh and um I I also when
you're when you're working with Organic
um inputs I I found at least the
products that I have worked with They
Don't Really spike your EC so even
though I'm adding you know scoops of you
know Green aminos and you know build the
FL uh build the bloom and um you know
maybe some coconut and and other things
my EC is staying relatively low I am
also using an RO water system out of out
of necessity which which really does um
help in my situation I have well water
on my property I know that there are
many people that have this situation as
well my PPM uh of my water and my um my
pH naturally is like a 9 pH and was like
1,000 PPM it was it was crazy high crazy
high it's unusable because as soon as I
started adding stuff it would it would
put me over 2,000 it was you know it was
the danger zone at that point so I got
an RO system just uh not a whole house
it's just under my sink in the kitchen I
fill up 5 gallon uh uh buckets you know
or the the five gallon um jugs I should
say from the grocery store um and uh I
have three of those and I have them
sitting out in my in my garage they kind
of get uh to room temperature because
water temperature is also important you
don't want to put super cold water in
there so it gets to room temperature uh
it's a little bit more tepid and then it
also um any any types of it also levels
the pH um as it sits out it kind of
stabilizes right at around seven so at
that point um for me personally EC is
just not much of a concern understood
another thing that's lumped into crop
steering but isn't talked about as often
I'd say is defoliation and plant
training so defoliation we're really
talking about like pruning for example
pruning the plant or plant training you
know the topping fimming low stress
training those things are resulting in
the plant having internal changes right
stress response redistribution of
hormones so on and so forth can you talk
to us about those things pruning and
training and and crop steering
absolutely um so again it all really
depends on what your goals are for me
personally as a photographer my my
primary objective for the genetics that
I run is to maintain a beautiful main
Cola so I can have something that is the
most photogenic thing
possible I also have again I can't
necessarily back this up because I
haven't done side by side tests yet like
expansive um experimentation but in the
limited experiments that I have done
when it came to plants that I have
topped versus ones that I haven't I've
actually found my yield to be better on
the plants that I don't top and when
people see my plants they are actually
surprised when they find out that I
don't top because they I'm able to
achieve a very even canopy and I do that
by sometimes I'll bend over the the top
cola if I am running if I know that a
strain is going or a cultivar is going
to stretch on me or if I'm already in a
situation where I know height is going
to be an issue I will very gently train
over that that uh your apical marem and
your other branches are going to grow up
and you're going to have a nice even
canopy you're going to uh accomplish the
same thing that you would with with um
topping I really do believe that the
yield is better when you don't top I
find that my buds are bigger and more
full when I don't top when I top I get
uh and the perfect example was the trop
Cherry number eight from Relentless
genetics that I grew I grew a this was
their cut I know what the cut looks like
when uh when it is not topped I topped
it and got a bunch of smaller beautiful
buds but they were dramatically smaller
they didn't fill in quite as much they
were spaced out and again I can't say
definitively it was because I didn't top
or did top but I have found in you know
my limited experience that not topping
um definitely does help with with uh
with the yield but I will also use uh uh
monster cropping I I I I love going in
or you know super cropping I'm pretty
aggressive with it you know depending if
it's early on and flower even if I crack
off one eh you know Only the Strong
Survive you can move on um but you can
also you could tape them too and and
they'll they'll be perfectly fine as
well um so when you get uh when you do
the the super cropping when you're
taking and you're bending an aggressive
45° angle um your plant is going to
readjust to that over time and grow up
into the light but it's going to form
this really fat knuckle right at that
point where you bent it over and it's
going to improve your um nutrient uh
like your your Highway basically things
are going to be uptake uptaken quicker
uh from again from my experience so uh
that's a that's another uh great way to
not just manage uh manage your canopy's
height in an emergency
but uh to also improve your yields um
but then also I think uh there are
things that we could do to um to
strengthen our stems um because early on
in veg uh being a home a house plant
grower uh I know the importance of
having wind and uh when you have like
climbing climbing house plants uh they
need support plants are not too
dissimilar in that where you are going
to have to have um a gentle breeze on
them when they're young so that your
stems uh start to grow more rigid and
stronger and then as the plant gets
older and those those stems have
developed uh you know they're they're
much stronger you're preparing for
larger fruits so our buds that's that's
what we're trying to get those those
bigger buds so uh making sure that um we
if we're if we're not adding poles or
some sort of a a support mechanism
um you know early on make sure that you
have um have a gentle gentle breeze on
your on your plants at all time to make
sure that they're they're going to grow
up strong to support those buds getting
deeper into wind or air flow I think
that's a good transition here is some
people are actually using that and and
trying to stress the plants to get a
better result now I'll tell you one
quick story is I had a tent full of
plants and the plant that was right next
to the fan was much frostier than some
of the plants that were away from the
fan so yep I think of potential
windstress was helping to trigger some
of that secondary metabolite production
but uh I can't find a whole lot of info
online about kind of wind stress or air
flow and how that can actually benefit
the plant do you have any background any
information on that that kind of fill
his in on i' I've experienced the exact
same thing Chris uh so um I I'm actually
experiencing it right now with a pure
Michigan that I'm running I just because
I'm in a in a very small 10 I you know
three plants running in a 4X two um the
the fan is right up against it and those
buds are the frostiest I I'll actually
I'll I'll upload a video later just to
show it because um I think that there is
something again we may not be able to
quantify it just yet we may never be
able to but we know right we we see it
ourselves and um I know that we are all
trying to have like this image of
perfection like we want to have all the
leaves are beautiful they're all
colorful they're all praying all the
time and the reality is is by the end of
our grow they look Haggard and beaten
and weathered and they're like good God
put me to death we just have to keep in
mind we are not growing leaves we are
growing flowers and the leaves are are
there to be an indicator of plant Health
they could be something that can show
you uh that there there might be an
issue that you need to address there
obviously our solar panels and and they
provide transpiration and all of these
but um we are not growing leaves um we
we're growing flowers so don't be too
discouraged if uh if your leaves aren't
perfect um if you get the wind burn or
or you know you get some curling from
overwatering or anything like that you
know learn from what may have caused it
but also know that you may have had an
unintended benefit from that with that
stress response and we may never know
great Point well we are coming up to the
hour mark here let's wrap things up now
can you tell listeners how they can find
you and what you have upcoming in the
future yeah uh so uh you could the
easiest way to find me is on Instagram
at crop culture uncore box do be careful
there is a uh a a known scammer out
there who is using um my exact profile
and everything with a second uh
underscore under between culture and box
so you'll see a little elongated line do
be careful of that the big tip I don't
use telegram so uh if anybody tries to
say tell you to tap into the telegram it
ain't me um so uh if anybody has any
questions for me about the Box about
growing I am uh very accessible always
willing to help people so please feel
free to reach out um and then also you
could visit the website crop culture.
net and uh see the things that I have
available there I uh have a new box that
I'm going to be launching um October 1st
I'll be announcing that on um on or
around September 1st got the new burito
align to and got some amazing products
in this box that I'm super excited about
and I think people are going to be
really pumped about as well so um yeah
those are those are the two main places
and uh I appreciate you letting me come
on and and speak with you yeah thanks
for coming on I'll definitely have link
to Chris's Instagram down in the YouTube
description section below so you can
easily navigate to it want to give AIG
shout out to our patreon supporters
patreon.com thank you so much for your
support your support Keeps the Lights on
here in the studio I'm going to put it
on the screen right now the folks that
are in the producer tier thank you so
much for your support what did we miss
what can else can be added to the
conversation or what do you do when you
crops steer let us know down in the
comments section below i' love to read
through the comments and see what you
guys got growing on Chris thanks so much
for coming on to the podcast once again
this was a great talk if you want to see
Chris come back for a part two let us
know put part two in the comment section
if we get enough votes there we'll uh
we'll have them back on and we'll crank
back into grow talk sounds great I
appreciate it Chris thank you all right
thanks so much for tuning in everyone
I'll catch you in the next episode peace
out