coming up on garden talk 25 episodes
deep
i want to talk about how the podcast is
doing and what's up coming in the future
bricks in a nutshell is going to
improve your flavor it's going to
improve your nutrition
it's going to improve your shelf life
and even have some ipm
benefits to it it's going to be lower at
night
because again it's sending some of those
sugars down to the roots for the
microbes for exudates so
you'll see that your brix levels will
drop at night growing methods do play a
role in this
it's found that organic growing tends to
be
a little bit more conducive to higher
brix levels it's a good
assistant to looking at the health of
your plant
it's not necessarily you know the doctor
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 25
25 episodes deep i read a stat recently
that said
90 of podcasts don't make it past
episode three
and of that remaining 10 percent of
podcasts 90
of those don't make it past episode 20.
we're at episode 25
we made it before we get into talking
about bricks with our guest today
i want to talk about how the podcast is
doing and what's upcoming in the future
but first i want to thank the sponsors
who helped make this podcast possible
thanks to dutch pro for sponsoring this
podcast dutch pro products are now
available in several countries across
the world
for those of you that don't know dutch
pro is a plant fertilizer company that
has base nutrients
additives and ph regulators they have
different formulas of base nutrients for
if you're in soil
or if you're in hydro or cocoa they also
formulate their base nutrients for if
you're using hard water
or if using ro or soft water i will
leave a link to dutch pros amazon store
down in the description section below
and you can use coupon code
mrgrow10dp for a discount on their
products
spider farmer is a sponsor of the
podcast coupon code
mr growit5 will get you a discount on
their products
they're most known for their led grow
lights but they also have other products
such as grow tents in-line fans and
carbon filters
i've used their sf 1000 sf 2000
and sf 4000 led grill lights in the past
and i got some great results with them
i will leave a link to spider farmers
amazon store down in the description
section below and don't forget to use
coupon code
mr grow at 5 for discount on their
products
all right so the very first episode of
this podcast if you listen to it on one
of the podcast platforms
then you heard my vision for the podcast
i did not say what the vision was for
the podcast in the first episode on
youtube so i want to reiterate my vision
for this podcast right now and i'm going
to read it
my vision for this podcast is to talk
with growers from all over the world
both beginners and experts and seek to
learn more about what they know about
gardening
i'm not going to judge people for the
way that they grow and this isn't a
debate
i'm simply seeking to learn more about
the guest and what they know about
gardening
and how they do things in their garden
my vision is for these conversations to
not only help expand my knowledge
but you the listeners knowledge too i
feel like that vision
we've done it so far here up to episode
25 but there's one thing i'd like to add
is that this podcast is for
all plants i don't want to narrow down
the scope to just that plant that we all
know and love
many grow techniques are the same or
very similar from plant to plant and i
hope that incorporating all plants into
this podcast will help inspire you to
grow other plants such as vegetables
fruits or even house plants i feel that
all plants should be treated the same
now
youtube doesn't agree with me on that
one i'm sure there's some people that
are listening that don't agree with me
on that one but i believe all plants
should be treated equally i understand
that laws need to be changed in the
future in order for that to happen
but i do see that happening sometime in
the future may not be in my lifetime may
not be in your lifetime
but sometime in the future since this
podcast is for all plants
it's a clean podcast youtube has rules
and guidelines that need to be followed
in order for the video to not get
suppressed no excessive swearing
no excessive use of certain words no
smoking
no showing certain plants if we can
follow those rules then the podcast will
stay in good standing
and we can reach more people it's also
kind of done as a big
f you to youtube we'll follow the rules
that you put in place
we're going to keep fighting the fight
thank you to everyone who is
understanding on that avenue
let's go over some numbers the 24
episodes released
so far have over 1.5 million views
combined on youtube
and 30 000 downloads through podcast
platforms that's incredible
you made it clear that you want this
podcast to continue not just by those
numbers
but in the comments section as well so i
will continue to do this podcast
top three episodes of rob from cltv that
episode has 235
000 views the episode with pigeons 420
has 234
000 views and the episode with welcome
to the grow 10 has over 164
000 views that is way beyond my
expectations
and i'm super thankful for that by the
way i'm sure there's some of you that
don't know this but i am part of another
podcast with rob and pigeons
it's called from the stash you can find
it here on youtube i'll put a link down
in the description section below
and it's also on podcast platforms as
well future guests
let's talk about them i am so excited to
bring you
some of these guests coming up next week
is brian mason the soil doctor
we talk all about soil testing after
that you'll see guru from the dude grow
show
dude from the dude grow show and the
last one i'll reveal is mark boutwell
from
perfect gardens incredible episode i
have the next two months worth of
episodes already planned
and some of them already filmed as well
so i'm super excited for what's upcoming
in the future
okay i have rambled on enough let's get
into today's episode
in this episode i talked with chad
westport some of you may know him from
his show
called the homegrow show which airs
twice a month on youtube he has been
gardening for 12 years
and he grows a variety of plants such as
tomatoes
carrots garlic onions micro greens
medicinal plants
swiss chard cucumbers and more in this
episode he talks about the importance of
bricks
he talks about what bricks is how you
measure it how to increase it
and more big thanks to all of you that
support this podcast through patreon
if you'd like to support you can do so
by going to patreon.com
mr growit alright now let's get into
talking with our guest
and we are back garden talk podcast
today i am joined with chad westport how
you doing today
i'm doing excellent man thank you for
having me yeah happy to have you here
got a good topic today we're going to be
talking about bricks it's not something
that uh
not something we really hear much about
at least on the home growing side you
know my audience
i think is kind of just like me home
growers indoors
mostly and bricks isn't a topic that
i really hear about often and i'm glad
to have you on here so you can explain
all about bricks and the importance of
it
and and so on and so forth so thanks for
coming on
usually what i do to start the podcast
is
an introduction so can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
yeah my name is uh chad westport and uh
i've been gardening
for quite a few years now um this is
something that i've had a
passion for many
many years uh kind of my background
is a lot of traditional gardening
your vegetables outside um i've taken a
lot of this knowledge i've moved it into
kind of medicinal plants you can apply
that there
and to kind of further that i jumped out
of my
previous life in audio engineering i
went back to school
i did sustainable agriculture and farm
systems
program and that really taught me a lot
of knowledge
that i feel i can use going forward in
this new industry
and it's great because a lot of the
things just like bricks bricks is
you know a couple hundred years old
basically
um but there's a lot of things applied
in um traditional agriculture
that we can use here and so that's the
kind of my background
it's gone for a full full circle
sorry uh from starting out as just the
uh
experimental gardener to uh having fun
and knowing a little bit more with it
nice nice and i know i think i first
heard about you
was from your show so you have a show i
don't know how new it is i feel like
it's somewhat new this year i believe
but it's a home grow show that you have
uh and that's on the weekends is that
right
yeah it's it's on saturdays it's every
first and third saturday of the month
and what i really wanted to do there was
give everybody exposure to different
styles and different methods
i'm not going to be the person to just
to subscribe to
you have to do it this way i've seen it
done many different ways
and that's what i want to get out to
people because there are there's people
in different climates you know different
soil conditions
some people aren't even using soil and
you might find something that works
better for you
or you know you can see what's smart
about the next person and apply it to
your own style so
that is my goal with that show yes we
have such a similar mindset
i think i say in my videos all the time
about there's so many different ways to
do it
it really comes down to personal
preference a lot of the time
and yeah i mean oftentimes people say
hey that's the wrong way to do it
really it's just an alternate way to do
it you're right
so um but i will link chad's show down
in the description section below so you
guys can click on that and tune in
on saturdays so cool all right let's get
into the topic today which is
bricks so tell us what is bricks
and why is it important well bricks
in a nutshell um it's going to
improve your flavor it's going to
improve your nutrition
it's going to improve your shelf life
and even have some ipm
benefits to it so bricks
is commonly associated with sugar levels
in a plant and you hear a lot of it from
the wine industry you know you got to
check the grapes the nice grapes make
the nice sweet wines
um but it's more than just sugars
bricks is really a measure of sugars of
course
but also vitamins minerals proteins
and other solids inside of the plant
sugar being the most abundant obviously
but having good brix levels again
is going to lead to healthier crops
better crops harvested at the right time
and kind of for what we're talking about
uh
ipm a good or a plant with good brix
levels
is going to stand a better chance
against pests and so that's why it's
pretty important for what we're doing
gotcha now how do you how do you measure
bricks
okay so bricks is something where you're
gonna take like
the sap or the liquid from um sometimes
you can take it from the fruit uh
directly from like a grape say
or if there is no fruit you can use leaf
samples so you kind of crush up your
leaves and you get a little bit of the
sample
and you get that liquid and you put it
in what is called a refractometer
the refractometers are what you use to
measure the bricks levels
they come in all shapes and sizes and
price ranges you can go
anywhere from like twenty dollars to two
hundred dollars buying a meter
a lot of them you can get our handheld
which is nice because again if you're
going out into the field and you're
measuring bricks levels on crops
you have something that you can bring
with you you can do it right there on
the spot in the field
so if i almost say it's almost kind of
like a little telescope
with the uh recorder mouthpiece on one
side
how it's kind of like hollowed out and
that's where you put your liquid in
so you get your liquid you put it in the
refractometer and it shines a light
up through the liquid and based
on you know doing this a number of times
the way that the light refracts or bends
through the liquid
is how they're able to tell what your
brix levels are
gotcha i'm looking at a couple on amazon
right now i actually had a few
on my wish list been meaning to buy one
of these actually just haven't pulled
the trigger yet
one of them here is 17.99 it looks just
exactly like you had explained it
and then there's one another one which
is
a hundred and forty nine dollars and so
there's some definitely a big price
difference like you had mentioned
this 149 dollar one looks like it has
like a digital
readout on it so do you know anything
about like just the price difference
you know digital readout versus just the
regular one
is it worth it really for a home grower
to be spending 150
for a bricks refractometer i don't i
don't really think that you need to go
overboard with this it's a good
assistant to looking at the health of
your plant
it's not necessarily you know the doctor
that's looking
at everything combined so i i do say
it's important but i don't think you
need to go
overboard either kind of like you said
there are the digital displays which yes
they're going to be more accurate
um than than a moving dial
and and really the levels that we're
talking about
um i guess it depends on how much the
hands on the dial are spread out because
if it has like a plus or minus
of three uh for the margin of error
that three can actually make a big
difference kind of from the
not from the bottom of the scale but
from the top of the poor
section to where the optimal section is
is really about five points so
again it depends on what the plus or
minus is on that readout so spending a
little more
is beneficial for that aspect um another
thing that you'll find
too probably with the 150 dollar versus
the 17
is uh bricks was measured or calculated
to take place at 68 degrees
so and just how the refract the
refraction
of the light works is meant to be at 68
degrees
and a lot of these will take that into
account do the math and then show you
the accurate number
some of them won't there's a chart
online you can go
type in your error temperature and all
that and it you figure out pretty
quickly but that
also is probably a differentiator of
cost
okay and so when i'm taking measurements
and just back up i know you you briefly
explained it is
you're basically going to take off a
piece of the leaf now correct me if i'm
wrong it should be
one of the newer leafs on the plant and
then you're basically going to squeeze
it what would you use to like
squeeze it and get that sap or whatever
to drip
off some sometimes if you are breaking
um like the petioles
the stems going to the leaf you can get
some sap out of that
um also times there's you know depending
upon the sample size you need
uh pistol and mortar kind of crush
stuff up that way it takes a lot more so
you're doing a larger sample size in
that case
but yeah usually uh if the plant has
been hydrated
uh recently you're able to kind of crack
it off there
uh on the stem from the leaf and you can
get a good sample
okay and then as far as
the ideal brix level or bricks range
that you want to be in i've heard
uh one of the things i've learned from
harley smith shout out to him
i took his master growers course last
year and he had mentioned that
plants with a brix level over 12 pests
won't even recognize it
so what is the ideal brix level or range
yeah you you've nailed it 12 is the
ideal level that's kind of the goal
i've heard you know medicinal plants
ranging up to 15
potentially 18. i haven't verified that
myself
but 12 really is the good goal and like
i said earlier you know
five points distinguishes from ideal to
the top of the bad points so seven when
you're at seven
and down that's when things aren't
looking too good
so staying at 12 is ideal and there was
a study that was done
where one field was treated and had high
bricks
it came in at 12 the field next to it
didn't and it had low bricks
and there were insect pressures that
came
leaf hoppers i believe it was and they
totally bypassed the field with the
higher bricks went to the other one
and so a study came out based on that
that if you have 12
you're basically invisible um that has
kind of that's been
not necessarily disputed but it's been
argued that it is
not a magic number but again
if you and and here's the kind of the
crux of it
insects and diseases like weaker plants
so if you have a field of healthy plants
next to a field
of unhealthy plants insect pressure is
going to go to that unhealthy field
and so that's kind of what happened
there it wasn't necessarily the bricks
itself
that made them leave it was just like
hey this is an easier target let's go
over here
so what can folks do to increase bricks
levels say they're in that danger zone
right
what are some of the things that they
can do in order to increase and get up
to that 12
or above four bricks level well
it all kind of starts in the beginning
with your original plan
growing methods do play a role
in this uh it's found that organic
growing
tends to be a little bit more conducive
to higher brix levels
and one of the key components in both
cases there is just the microbial
activity and a lot of times in the
synthetic
based diets
it doesn't give the the you know the
ideal
or the conducive environment for those
microbes to grow and thrive
and do what they need to do um so
by growing organically that is going to
help you because
you know the microbes are there the
fungi
is there the organic material is there
and that's that's gonna kind of help
everything really
um in a nutshell there's also lighting
um dli or you know the intensity of the
light
that's important too because we know
that you know
proper lighting drives photosynthesis
photosynthesis creates sugars in the
plants
and again sugars relates backs to bricks
so
by having good and proper lighting it's
more photosynthesis
it's more sugar for the plant and that
can get distributed
uh to different areas and for different
purposes
so yeah kind of kind of starts with the
the soil microbes
um calcium is another important one
and and i'm leaving cal mag off of that
magnesium does come into the equation
here but i'm just saying calcium at this
point
because calcium it helps build stronger
cell walls
in the plants and you know that
increases the movement in the xylem and
phloem
the more things coming up uh because
sugars and bricks
it's it's a two-way street you know the
sugars and stuff are coming up
uh through the root zone and from the
plants and the photosynthesis
but they're also going back down the
plant
at night um to feed the microbes
so kind of a symbiotic relationship
there
again that's that's you know it's kind
of important
um getting the right amount of
calcium in there is important
you don't want to overload it just
because hey it's good it builds
thick walls i'm going to have amazing
stocks on all my plants
there are antagonistic properties to it
you know if you have
too much calcium in there you're likely
to lock out
phosphorus or potassium and then that
creates
a different kind of problem because
diagnosing plants for me is always one
of the trickier things because
is it truly a deficiency you're seeing
or is it a
lockout situation due to
you know the ions the cations and ions
from other minerals
or just a ph problem so
yeah that that kind of gets uh
gets tricky when you're trying to
diagnose them so don't put on a whole
bunch of calcium just because i said it
was good
uh like everything there is always a
balance so you don't want to lock other
things
out and so you separated calcium and
magnesium and you know calm a lot of
people just
uh say cal mag and they think that's a
nutrient in itself
when really that's just the name of a
product right there's calcium in it
there's magnesium in it oftentimes it's
nitrogen in it as well
so talking about calcium in particular
do you have any recommendations for just
straight calcium that they can give to
their plants
um yeah i mean in kind of like an
organic
type method there's a lot of different
options you could use um gypsum is a
good one
uh gypsum is something that doesn't
really affect the soil ph
so that's always kind of nice and that
is something that you're probably going
to add in
while you're making your mix if i were
to
you know spot like a little deficiency
or if i wanted to top dress something
in an organic method there is a wca
which is something i saw from chris
trump
uh i i don't know if it's jadam or or
which
farming method it came from but
essentially uh calcium bicarbonate
that is shells so there's you know
eggshells
oyster shells crab shells all those
different ones you can use
at home a lot of people have eggs so you
essentially
and i believe it's one part of eggshells
to 10 parts of white vinegar
you mix the two and i'm glossing over
this of course but you mix the two you
let it sit for about 10 days
it extracts the calcium from the shells
and then you can pour it on
and that's a good organic treatment that
you can use at home
and you know for for synthetic growers
there's always uh
there's a lot of bottled calcium out
there
and again even if you are doing
synthetic i wouldn't shy away from
you know calcium bicarbonate methods or
uh
gypsum either so always good now when
should
uh measurements be taken right so
you know i'm sure there'll be
homegrowers here that are going to go
and buy a brix refractometer and they're
going to be measuring
uh taking measurements you know should
they do it every day
should they do it every week should they
do it
at morning should they do it at night so
if you give us a little
a little background on when uh and how
often measurements should be taken
yeah that's that's a great question
because it does have an impact
on the readings you're going to get you
want to
to start out you want to do it at the
same time
every time you measure it it's going to
be lower
at night because again it's sending some
of those sugars down
to the roots for the microbes for
exudates so
you'll see that your brix levels will
drop at night
if you're outdoors know again with like
row crops
um if it's a cloudy day
you'll have lower brix levels again
light defects
can affect bricks but yeah
you can do it as often as you want to i
don't think you'll glean much if you do
it on a month-to-month basis
um not terrible lot changes on a
day-to-day basis
but weekly i think is a good idea
you could do it you know maybe every
four days if you're a data freak like me
and you like plotting charts and
doing all of that stuff but yeah
basically doing it once a week
i prefer to do it midday that's the best
time to do it and
like you kind of alluded to yes make
sure you're doing it at the same time
every time you do it otherwise it's just
going to be inaccurate
for your purposes good advice definitely
some good advice there
now you wrote a pretty extensive article
on
dude grow show website i'm looking at it
right now for those that are tuning in
on
apple podcast spotify you can just
search google
it's called high science what the brix
an explainer of bricks and soil health
so pretty long here you get into details
i know we went over
quite a bit here in this talk but
there's one more thing in here
you talked about how during
photosynthesis chlorophyll
manufactures sugars it also says that
humic and fulvic acids are a great way
to make iron in the soil more plant
available
can you talk to us about specifically
about
humic and fulvic acids and kind of how
this relates to bricks and how you know
it can increase uptake and so on and so
forth
yeah um so the humic and the fulvic
acids they act
within the soil as kind of like
chelators
they help basically i mentioned earlier
the ions cations and ions they
um from like calcium will have and part
of me for not being
overly scientific here but you know you
can all picture like the oxygen molecule
it has you know the bubble with a little
stem and another bubble
it's kind of the cations and ions the
positive and negative charges that we're
talking about
and sometimes nutrients will
see each other bind and then they'll
lock each other out so
the humex the phobics they kind of blind
everything to that so that also kind of
relates to amino acids i know you
mentioned that in the article here as
well can you talk to us a little bit
about amino acids
yeah amino acids are great amino acids
are essentially the building blocks of
kind of all life
and the amino acids uh create protein
and to create that within a plant system
or the plant structure
that takes sugars so if you're using
your sugar energy
and amino acids to build protein then
you have less sugar
in there for higher brix and other
things that you're going to want it for
so by adding these amino acids you're
really kind of
not cheating the system but you're
you're taking away that draw of sugars
or in the energy form so by adding those
amino acids
you get the protein and similar to the
uh the humic and fulvic acids
um it can act as a chelator um
basically making more of the nutrients
available
in the soil to the plant and they're
able to move around more freely within
the plant
so that's again another very important
aspect
the calcium is kind of building the
walls the phosphorus is the truck
driving everything around
and the hum or humic fulvic acid
uh are the things that are helping blind
it to
freely get to where it needs to go
gotcha
okay so is there anything else in
regards to bricks that growers should
know
or maybe do you have any advice for
somebody who's kind of new to bricks
they're just starting measurements for
the first time what advice do you have
yeah i want to say that brix is a good
reinforcement of a lot of times what you
can see
with your eyes you know if your plants
are looking healthy and you check your
bricks and it comes back around that 12
level
that's great if you're looking at the
plants they're not looking
healthy you check the bricks it's at
that five or six range
you can almost infer from that that
you're having an issue with calcium
so that's an important thing to know and
to kind of help you
on the road to improving your brix
levels
it's not the you know it's not the
end-all be-all of
of what's in your soil it's not going to
isolate specifically
what nutrient is in what ratio something
uh like a sap analysis
test uh can do that for you but bricks
again you you want to know what your
brix levels are
because it can indicate the nutritional
levels
in your plant uh it's also going to
indicate you know how good your uh ipm
can be or you know avoidance of pests
so it's important to know it's it's
another tool in the tool belt
good info there for sure well this has
been a quick straight to the point
episode
lots of good information packed into
just 25 minutes
so i definitely appreciate your time and
your knowledge that you dropped here
today kind of wrapping things up how can
the listeners find you
and what do you have upcoming in the
future thank you
uh you can find me i am on instagram i
am chad.westport
and uh i guess you heard it here first
breaking
um chadwestport.com will be
up and uh it's up with a temporary page
right now but it will be going full bore
soon you can find me chadwestport.com
and i got my shows uh every first and
third thursday
or wow first and third saturdays
of each month on the scp02
channel oh i'll get that right one of
these times and that comes on uh
2 pm pacific standard time so do please
come and check me out
we we talk about you know doing the
grows at home and all the different
styles you can
you can do it with so we enjoy ourselves
over there try not to get too serious
you know serious business
well i will leave a link to chad's
instagram
down in the description section below
also will be a link to his show
i'm not sure if there's a playlist for
the show or if i should just link to a
individual episode but i'll have
something down in the description
section below for you guys
if you enjoyed this video click that
thumbs up button really the like button
is
going to help reach more viewers it's
going to show up in people's recommended
feeds
is what it'll do subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already
we release episodes every single
saturday
unless susan needs to manually review it
then it'll be on sunday
typically youtube sometimes doesn't like
this podcast so that's why there's a
delay in release
from time to time apple podcast if
you're cheating on that tuning in on
there
please leave a rating in review it's
another thing that helps with ranking
the podcast ranking and helps reach more
listeners so and then lastly
uh sharing sharing is caring right if
you know somebody who would benefit from
this information please share it
reddit is a great place to share it
facebook groups is a great place to
share it
or just share it to your friends
individually so thank you to everyone
who
shares this podcast well chad thank you
so much for coming on to the podcast
today this has been
a great episode i definitely learned a
few things
and yeah i hope you enjoy the rest of
your day thank you
thank you very much you have a great one
yourself
[Music]
thanks
you