coming up on garden talk water
temperature and environment temperature
is critical for this plant especially
during this rooting stage you need that
higher warmer temperature to encourage
the root growth i like to keep a rooting
hormone in my sops every time there's
definitely three stages of rooting the
first is callus the next is striking and
the third is searching
you know in theory if your plants are
green to begin with and they turn purple
in your rooting stage yeah you gotta
adjust what you're feeding and what
you're saturating your trays with and
more than likely you gotta you gotta
match what that plant previously was
getting start reading the backs of
labels of products and bottles what the
actual active ingredient is feed what
the mother plant you cut from was being
fed
you don't want to change it up
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 60. in this
episode i interview paul also known as
clone coach he has been gardening for 10
years and offers online clone coaching
i'll also be launching a nursery
marketplace for licensed cultivators in
california in this episode he talks all
about how to be successful when cloning
plants thanks to all of you who support
this podcast through patreon if you'd
like to support you can do so by going
to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to gorilla grow 10
for sponsoring this episode gorilla is
well known for their quality grow tents
they have a super strong frame thick
canvas density and a height adjusting
roof
it comes with a one foot extension kit
and a two foot extension kit is optional
so you can grow even taller plants
they also have the light line same
quality as the original gorilla grow
tents but with a few key design changes
go to their website
growstrongindustries.com
and use discount code mr growit for 15
off a big supporter of this podcast is
ac infiniti they sponsor this podcast
and i use their products ac infinity now
has gardening tools and accessories such
as heavy duty fabric grill pots
trimmers grow room glasses drying racks
plant ties and trellis nuts
they also have all of the equipment
needed for a ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr grow it during
checkout for a discount on their
products
all right we are back welcome to the
garden talk podcast today i am joined
with paul the clone coach how you doing
today i'm doing well man how are you i'm
doing great thanks for asking um so paul
is an expert when it comes to cloning so
i figured i based this episode around
that
there's so many different ways to clone
and it can be a bit challenging at times
to get clones to successfully root
depending on the method that's used so i
really want this episode to reveal some
good best practices that will help the
listeners be successful cloning
before we get into cloning that deep
let's do an introduction can you tell us
a little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
yeah absolutely um
i've i've been gardening since kind of
like my late teens you know as a hobby
just plants always interested interested
in me
um you know i started back in the day
just by
kind of getting seeds from chili's and
stuff that we were eating and you know
propagating them germinating them and
then um putting them in uh little pots
and stuff and growing that same plant
and eating peppers that we had for
dinner so kind of showing the rest of
the family hey you know all these seeds
that are inside could become other
plants
so just had hobby gardens you know
growing up and stuff but always had a
love and a passion for
for plants in general and um yeah you
know earlier in my career i was
traveling a lot so i couldn't have a
garden because i was always gone so i
was kind of always uh you know kind of
in the back of my head but finally when
i um you know stopped traveling for work
i was able to you know garden a lot more
so it's it's always a good passion it's
good therapy and i encourage others to
do it awesome good stuff there
um so let's get into
just some basic questions to begin
i do have another cloning episode on
this podcast if anybody's interested
we get real deep into the process kind
of step by step on how to take clones i
believe if you search my name mr growit
and then clones or how to take clones it
should pop up it's with trey strums from
cltv in this episode right here we won't
go over the
the beginner type details uh but it will
certainly involve a lot of the details
needed in order to be successful in
various ways
the first question i have for you is
why is it important to take clones from
a healthy mother plant it's everything
really um you know the the importance of
it is uh that the fact that
the mother plant and your clones they go
hand in hand so anything that your
mother plant is experiencing good or bad
you're going to show it in your clones
so you know clones you always want to
have the best start possible because
your your crop is essentially writing on
that so
taking clones from the healthiest mother
plants being
you know
no stress no environmental stress you
know fully acclimated to their
environment fully fed nutrient wise you
know no deficiencies
that's going to give you the best
possible product on the next stage so
you know cloning from a healthy mother
plant is is vital and it's it's the
first step to producing the best
possible stock you can so if you do take
if you do happen to have a plant that is
showing assigned deficiencies maybe
you're starting to see
nitrogen deficiency to begin
and you can't wait around you got to
take those cuts that day
can the person still be successful is
that clone still going to root so on and
so forth and if that clone could recover
and then turn out to be a usable plant
or do you just totally recommend that
the plant has to be 100 healthy in order
to take clones off you know if if life
is working against you you have to cut
off of that plant when it's not in the
best stage possible you got to do what
you got to do right
rooting is one half or one portion of
creating uh you know a proper clone
so the plant can still root if it's a
bit deficient
now
the top half of that plant the stem and
the new growth and the leaves are going
to show its deficiency a lot more so you
can get the plant to root but you're
going to take a lot more time an extra
week two weeks to bring that plant
health
back up to a stage to where it's
acceptable to move on to the next stage
so
usually if that's the case you'll have
roots on the bottom but as you move up
the stem you go from green to purple to
purple darker purple and then your inner
nodes are going to be really tightly
spaced and there's really not a lot of
developed growth when it comes to your
new leaves or anything like that so it
can root you know this plant's amazing
it will root
but you will suffer as far as your your
canopy and your leaves and uh your
structure goes so
you know take that in mind
okay that makes sense and we'll
definitely get into purple and red stems
later on in the episode that's that's a
question i have slated for that because
i know that's a common question but
first
tips on the cutting process i know this
is a very broad question right
but kind of to narrow it down a little
bit is there a certain time to take
cuttings like does the plant need to be
a certain height for example
and then what part of the plant i heard
that uh you know there's differences
between taking cuttings from the bottom
part of the plant versus the top part of
the plant can you talk to us about that
yeah i mean some good rules of thumb i
mean you want to take
cuttings off of a plant that's been
growing for i say about 14 days
undisturbed undisturbed meaning no
topping no pinching no bending
just want that growth to to be
undisturbed for a good 12 to 14 days
before you cut that growth
which is you know nine times out of ten
gonna be off the top of the plant right
beneath your lights if you're in an
indoor setting um you know cloning from
the bottom of the plant in an indoor
setting that's not getting direct light
so your your your stems are going to be
a lot thinner um you know your plants
are not going to be as developed and
it's not as not as hardy once again it
can and will root but your clone is
gonna be just a little bit weaker a
little bit you know behind everything
else that is not used to the intensity
of the light and the food and kind of
the the rapid activity happening inside
the plant so
it's best recommended to have your plant
grow for about 14 days
take off uh the growth that's been grown
right underneath the lights there and um
have
as many as much um
cross-contamination practices in mind so
you want to have clean scissors
um or clean scalpel clean razor blade
clean anything
when i say clean you want to use
products um that actually
get rid of viroids and viruses and
anything like that viroid being
like the main thing nowadays and then
you know alcohol doesn't kill the viroid
um you know according to all of these
studies and everything that that are
being done
so you know an easy product that
everybody has access to is bleach
10 bleach
um you know a 30 second to 1 minute
dwell time is about what they recommend
so not a quick dip and a rinse there
actually has to be a dwell time on the
surface of your tools um in between
plants and stuff so
cut off the new healthy growth and keep
clean uh tools to to make those cuts off
your plants so you're saying isopropyl
alcohol which is very very common that
people use to sterilize their equipment
you're saying that's not sufficient it's
not sufficient as far as a viroid goes
being hoplite and viroid which is a
really big concern
and a lot of commercial grows nowadays
so i mean it's good for other practices
but you know generally speaking too if
we take a step back
you need to wash a surface before you
sanitize the surface
so if the surface has debris or already
has plant material on it or has any
buildup on it and you just dip it into
alcohol or anything else
you're not getting to the surface of
that tool
so alcohol takes you so far but a clean
surface and the right product will
guarantee you better success as far as
your tools go
that makes sense
so after you take that cutting right but
i guess size of the cutting is one thing
i kind of want to get a little deeper
into
generally speaking i've heard about six
inches at the minimum certainly it'll
root with you know smaller than that it
can larger than that what's your take on
the size of cutting to take
so
if you're using traditional domes uh
humidity domes that's a seven inch dome
on average so you don't want your plant
to be touching the top of that dome for
14 days you know accumulating humidity
and condensation on you know that fresh
growth up top so you want to be about an
inch below that
so that you know and you're going to
plug in your stem into your cloning
media about an inch or so
so that
six inches you know an inch goes into
the media and you have um you know a
couple inches of play with up top so six
could be a little bit short
once you plug it in and put it into a
tray so just above that um
six inch mark is kind of where you want
to be and it's going to be dependent on
the development of the plant
and kind of the the new nodes and the
fan leaves coming off of it so i like to
base it on the the top nodes
and the newest growth down to the bottom
of the stem on a nice cutting mat you
know line my my new growth there my stem
at the bottom there's usually a 45
degree angle on your cutting mat get a
nice clean cut
and you know it's not gonna be perfect
and that's okay um because you have a
little bit of play within the dome and
when you're treating the entire tray as
one as one canopy a little bit of play
quarter inch here half inch there is
just fine in the grand scheme of things
so just over six inches it should be
perfect for a seven inch dome
so you sterilize your scissors you've
taken that cutting
some people dip it into a rooting
hormone although that's an optional step
right would is there a particular type
of rooting hormone uh that you recommend
uh maybe talk about like liquid versus
powder stuff like that i've tried uh
there's a few out there there's a
handful out there right and you know
there's new um hormones coming onto the
market as well
but they all have that same active
ingredient which is kind of what you
want to
start reading the backs of labels of
products and bottles what the actual
active ingredient is in your products
and what strength and or percentage um
is in that product so for rooting
hormones endo
endobiuric acid iba and i think there's
a few different strains of iba
which i think like a liquid will have
one strain or two strains combined you
know powder will have you know the other
one and gels um have an indole
endobiuric acid as well
my personal favorite is clonix it's been
around forever um you know it works i
know there's new products out there and
i want to give them a shot i want to
give side by side
and you know see how they do
some say reading hormones are are
optional but it's just a staple in my
sops so it's just you want to help
trigger um you know rooting and striking
the roots and that's what that hormone
does
so
you know why not give you know the plant
everything that needs for that short
period of time you're expecting it to do
you know a lot of a lot of growing you
know creating a callus striking roots
creating a root zone you know and all
this stuff during the rooting process so
i like to keep a rooting hormone in my
sops um every time
so after you dip it into that rooting
hormone
it could go into a variety of different
things right so um you could actually
put it into a cube you could put like a
root riot cube is what i'm referring to
um you could put it into rock wool you
could put it directly into soil or cocoa
which is what i often do i just do kind
of like the lazy man method i don't want
to go and buy the rock wool or cubes
directly into the soil do it takes a
little bit longer to root uh from my
experience but it still will root under
the right conditions
or they skip all that and they just do
aeroponics aeroponic cloner um another
broad question for you can you talk to
us about the differences between those
things and how
the success rate can vary and so on and
so forth
yeah absolutely um i mean as a general
statement the the environment needs to
hold
a certain amount of moisture
and a certain amount of oxygen so that
ratio is what the the stem and root zone
really needs to to begin its reading
process and to go throughout its reading
process
so as long as a good ratio of moisture
to oxygen
that's why you know you could do it in
cocoa soil and all these different
medias and the plant will strike roots
and will grow and will do its thing so
that's kind of the the rule of thumb and
what is needed on a basic level um now
as far as different methods go like
aeroponics i used to do that back in the
day um
but it's a bit finicky it's it's like
any other aeroponic system or and or
hydroponic system or deep water culture
system where if there's any variation in
your parameters
you're more than likely going to have
issues so if a timer goes down or if the
water chiller is not chilling water or
any issues like that happen you have
very little room for margin for error so
you really need to have
you know close eye on your system to
ensure there's no hiccups throughout
your your routing process so it works
that moisture oxygen level gets created
in that environment in the aeroponic
system
but if your temperature's off or
anything like that you could have some
issues and there's not an easy way to
recover from that
um the different types of media
rockwool is a traditional one it's been
used for who knows how long and it works
it works just fine
and especially if you're going to go
into another rockwool cube that's where
you want to start off with it's a great
it's a great starting point
it's got a good moisture to oxygen ratio
um you know most people squeeze the
cubes
to
for whatever reason they have in mind
but i don't i you know i say they come
from the manufacturer with a certain
ratio that they could hold so much
moisture and not hold anything more than
that so i don't squeeze any of the
rockwool cubes like most people do
any cubes really
oasis cubes is like a floral foam so
it's another um
good slab to use but it's very delicate
when it's dry like pulling it out of the
box it just falls apart when it's dry
it's it's so delicate but once it gains
moisture and you moist and you
saturate it it's good to go and it holds
its place and stuff and it's a it's a
good media
now
there's also the root rights like you
mentioned and i think that's a great
option
for like hobby growers and or people
that aren't doing too much production
too often
and i say that because you know you
still have to manually
um you know saturate the cubes and then
fill in your 50 cell trays or however
many um you know cells you're doing in a
tray you have to manually plug all of
those individual cubes on a small scale
it's not a big deal but when you're
doing commercial scale that's a lot of
labor that is wasted
so on a commercial scale my personal
favorite are the ihort trays the xl
trays to you know narrow down they got a
few products but those come pre-filled
so that 50 cell tray comes pre-filled
with a coco coco based media with a
little bit of perlite and
some some
just way to keep it keep it compact so
when it you could break it down like
soil
but it holds its its shape when it's in
the cube and it's in the tray and stuff
so that's my personal favorite because
it comes pre-filled and you save a ton
of labor when it comes to the commercial
scale
so you could you could clone and root in
most
most medias
just just gotta work with that ratio of
moisture and dry backs and oxygen and
stuff to encourage the root growth yeah
i know temperature is another thing that
kind of you got to keep an eye on
particularly in soil or cocoa is
primarily like i mentioned what i clone
in or stick my clones into i've had
issues where
i didn't really monitor the temperature
it was too low you know what i mean and
it was on the ground and
it just it wasn't high enough
temperature in that medium in order to
promote the growth
so that the plants started to die off
you could see the leaves started to
become yellow
and then and then i went and put a heat
mat on it common thing that people use
heat mat underneath it
and then it recovered you know all it
needed was just heat that's it yeah so
uh heat mat is another thing worth
mentioning that uh if you're having
trouble getting that uh the temperature
to where it needs to be
heat bat is definitely uh something to
look at yeah and i wouldn't recommend
you know throwing the tray on the floor
it's because it's the coldest spot in
the room especially if it's like a
concrete floor or something like that
it's the coldest spot is and it's the
closest to your root zone or where
you're trying to create a root zone
hence you know the issues you just
described will will definitely happen
you know um so you know keeping it
elevated off the ground
you know getting a good you know
temperature is critical
um you know water temperature and
environment temperature is critical for
this plant especially during this
rooting stage you need that higher
warmer temperature
to encourage the root growth and um
you know get that root zone and get get
activated so
so the rooting process it's three stages
i was doing some digging on your youtube
channel and uh sorry video you talking
about the three stages of rooting can
you talk to us about that
yeah there's definitely three stages of
rooting the first is callus the next is
uh striking and the third is searching
so and the catalyst stage happens in the
first few days of the rooting process
and essentially your stem is going to
form a callus it's going to you're going
to see thick
almost scaly bumpy
growth come off of your stem and that's
the first stage and that's where that um
rooting hormone helps aid in this
process as well
but it's going to create that first
callous state so your stem is going to
form
you know callous all around that and
you'll notice sometimes too like if you
cut off of uh a fan leaf or something
like that and you you leave a wound that
it'll start to form a callus there too
if the environment's right because the
plants just want to form and do that um
stage
from the callus you're going to strike
roots and these are just tiny little
nubs that are just like little spikes
like a little just little spikes coming
off this callus that are just beginning
that root striking stage and that
happens uh between like days four and
seven
um kind of the middle stage of rooting
and um
after the striking stage is a searching
stage and is essentially where you're
creating your root zone so you're
encouraged you're encouraging the root
growth and searching to to show
the roots a bit more in the root ball
by uh by doing these dry backs and by
reducing moisture levels so that the
roots are forced to search for water and
in doing so they're displaying
themselves they're creating a bigger
root zone and they're out there actively
searching for water um you know coming
in contact with the root inoculant
that's in your slabs coming in contact
with the nutrients and
that's what will get you through your
your process a lot better so
there's three stages of rooting and if
you're having any issues with rooting
and you tear apart one of your cubes you
could see what stage it made it to or
did it make it past
and so with that you could help diagnose
where you're you're having issues so if
it's not even creating a callous and you
know you realize hey yeah the
temperature was too low and i put this
heating mat and all of a sudden it's
formed a callus now striking roots
you're able to diagnose where your
issues are um if you form the callus and
struck roots but they're just you just
don't see any roots on your cube and you
know i had to break it apart now there
are some roots where you know why aren't
they showing on the outside
well on the later half you got to
encourage uh the roots to search for
water so increase your dry backs reduce
your humidity levels so that's where you
could kind of use those three stages of
rooting to help dial in um you know your
whole process
so moisture content super important um
the initial soaking i want to dig a
little bit deeper into that
you know the root right plug some people
will soak them prior or the rock will
soak it prior and then you mentioned
kind of squeezing it out and how do
people dial in that moisture content and
also i want to wrap ph into this because
some people will make sure that water is
a certain ph that they're soaking that
cube into can you talk to us about those
yeah with ph you want to start a little
bit lower than general so if you're
feeding your your plants normally about
6.0 ph and some cocoa or something
you're going to start a few points below
that so about five eight or so
if you're in rockwool it's kind of the
only one that you need to go even lower
than that about five six even five five
especially for that initial soak
and it's even recommended on it on the
packaging so rockwool because it starts
a little bit lower everything else just
want to be about 5758 just to
encourage that that that acid in the
rooting hormone and everything to
to help the whole process you know
strike roots as far as saturation goes
i don't like
squeezing
the the cubes for a few reasons
if you squeeze a cube and i squeeze a
cube it's going to be different the
third person squeezes the cube it's
going to be different again so you need
consistency when it comes to producing
clones on a mass on a mass scale
especially commercially you need
consistency it's it's paramount so
having someone do something manually
eliminates that like you you can't three
people can't do the same thing you don't
get the same results and you know the
the manufacturers create this product
that could hold so much moisture but it
can't hold anything more than that so
you know i like to just saturate it
completely 100 percent
and that's the moisture that it carries
on to about halfway through the rooting
process because it you don't need to re
saturate that media or anything like
that just give it a full saturation with
the right levels of nutrients and root
inoculants
and that's what will carry you through
the first two stages of rooting and then
get you into
uh feeding and drying back on the second
half of the rooting stage you said
nutrients as well what nutrients are
they
is recommended for that so traditionally
you know previously for years everybody
fed your
fed their clones of very little food
you're talking
0.5 ec
very very very little food um because
their the mindset was these are babies
they can't handle a lot of food you got
to give them very little food
and the results that they would get were
stunted growth they would need a week to
bounce back after the rooting process
you're creating a deficient plan
essentially
so as far as nutrients go
my rule of thumb is to feed what the
mother plant you cut from what's being
fed
you don't want to change it up because
if you want the same type of growth that
you were getting from that mother plant
and that growth was hitting all your
check marks
you want the same thing because you're
going to put that back in the veg and
create another plant that looks just
like it so if you change the food up
well now this plant has to get used to
something different maybe doesn't have
everything it needs now it's slowing
down
so my rule of thumb is whatever the
mother plants being fed
for the initial soak it's 50
half of that and then get it into that
regiment that it was being fed
previously and that's how you'll get the
get your clones to look just like the
day they were cut
so that's another part of the sops is
you want your clones to look just like
the day they were cut you got to mimic
that same type of food and environment
to get it to to that point in 14 days
got it that's good to know
environment let's talk about that
temperature relative humidity they
certainly have an impact on rooting as
well right what's the ideal temperature
and relative humidity for the cloning
process so
we start with the mother room that's
going to be about 78 to 80 degrees and
about 65 humidity so nice breezy warm
summer day
um
you want i like to harden my clones off
to that environment so if you could
clone in your mother room that's uh
ideal you know you don't always need a
separate room with all this extra
humidity and a whole new environment you
could use the same environment that
plants came from because when you put
that dome on it's going to increase your
humidity it's going to increase your
temperature and you you're playing
you're adjusting this micro climate
within this dome
in order to encourage you know all these
uh stages of rooting
so and then once they're fully done
they've been acclimated to the same
environment that they came from which is
ideal environment for veg so if you know
if you're a commercial producer and
you're setting it off to another grower
well it's been acclimated to a perfect
veg environment that could go into any
other veg environment and thrive so you
don't need to have a big swing of
humidity or anything like that so
high 70s 78 80 and 65 humidity um the
environment will will be perfect for
your for your trace and then co2
something that isn't talked about too
much when it comes to cloning but
i know there are some concerns from
people using domes in particular that
they're going to deplete the co2 within
the dome
is there any can you give us our
thoughts on that and maybe some
suggestions on how often they should be
opening up the dome or opening up the
the slots in the zone the dome for
aeration purposes for for co2 um
you know i've never really been
concerned about the internal co2 levels
in the dome um you know feeding co2 to
the mother plant the mother stock
i like to match the par levels
so if you're you know running some you
know 630 watt cmhs it'll give you about
five to six hundred depending on the the
height or the canopy level um and you
want to kind of want to match that so
about 600 ppm as well of co2 nothing too
intense if your humidity if your
temperatures and stuff go up or your
light intensity goes up you could you
can increase your co2 as well for those
mother plants
um
but as far as the domes go in that
little environment
i never like to and i used to do this i
used to you know keep the little vents
closed the first couple days
and you know always do trial and error i
found that's not a best practice i never
want to close that dome 100
um because i i've put meters inside
these domes to really read the internal
environments and with cracking the dome
you saw plenty of humidity
um that the plant needs during the early
stages and yet you're not suffocating it
you're not trapping it so there's still
a little bit of of of airflow and if any
excess hot air needs to rise it has
somewhere to leave
so
i don't like to keep my my vents closed
at all for any period of time really
it's not something i encourage or
recommend okay i personally live in a
very dry climate i live in the desert
like i mentioned
currently live in las vegas and it gets
super dry here uh 26 is what i'm seeing
right now on my meter so very very dry
now when i go to clone i do use the
domes
to increase that humidity in that grow
space
and when i do have those vents open
it like gets rid of everything and my
humidity drops what would you say is
like the lowest humidity that you can
successfully get rooting to happen i
mean i feel you as far as the dry the
dry weather goes i've been down in palm
springs and we're we're you know 10 20
humidity it's it's ridiculous you know
my sinuses feel it all the time and
stuff too um
but you know if you're in the
environment that the mother plants are
in you know you got some humidity there
but within the dome if you have a full
canopy within the dome those plants will
transpire especially with the moisture
as well in the cubes that will transpire
and give you enough humidity to to fill
up your your dome worth of humidity
without having to spray the dome
or you know be able to crack the the
domes and still hold humidity so if
you're
and when i say open i don't mean you
know all the way initially you know just
you know quarter the way just make sure
it's not 100 closed
but if you're still losing all of you
your humidity i would look at how much
uh how many how much plant material you
have in your tray is it a full tray is
it half a tray because if it's a full
tray and a fully saturated slab and the
vents are cracked slightly you should
hold you should create enough moisture
within that dome um you know to to do
that so i would just say you know fill
up your tray as much as you can
with as much plant material and that
should help you there and if you have to
close your domes a hundred percent
because it's just not holding um
not you don't want to keep it closed for
more than you know 24 hours you want to
still exchange that air burp the dome
you want to let those plants breathe and
get some fresh oxygen get some fresh
co2
and and get rid of the the stagnant and
stale uh condensation and humidity
that's being built up
gotcha that makes sense
and then lighting for clones i think
there's some common misconceptions about
lighting for clones
i want to hear your thoughts on that
when do the clones need light how much
light so on and so forth um i like to
keep them on a 24 hour schedule
um you know you can do 18 six like like
you do your normal veg plants
but what i don't like about that is
during those six hours you've just
changed the internal parameters of your
dome you've increased humidity you've
reduced temperature because you're not
getting a little bit of ambient
temperature from the light
so you're changing your parameters
within your dome for you know a third of
the day um
throughout throughout the entire process
so for lighting keep the lights on 24
hours a day
that's my recommendation and four foot
um you know leds or or you know led
lights you know a couple of them on a
four by two tray you could house four
trays on there
six to eight inches above the the dome
it should be spot on um and that should
be enough light to create the
environment you want within the dome
and then when the domes come off they
could still veg underneath their light
still intense enough to to get some
vegetative growth
if they have to sit for the weekend or
so something like that so for lighting
you could go as easy as something off
amazon four foot leds and you know start
there or you go uh get some luxe led
um four foot lights as well
i don't personally like like the purple
um lights
i've i've tried them and i just didn't
get the same
growth that i wanted out of them um so a
cool blue spectrum
is is what i prefer versus like a deep
red or anything like that okay that's
pretty straightforward
let's get into some of the problems that
can happen purple stems red stems talked
about that in the beginning of the
episode let's circle back and get into
that
what do purple and red stems mean and
how do you get them back to green
you know if if they started green
and they went to purple
you didn't you didn't feed strong enough
in your rooting stage
so
if your mother plants were purple to
begin with you're not feeding strong
enough there so it's just going to
extrapolate that problem in the rooting
process
so
you know in theory if your plants are
green to begin with and they turn purple
in your rooting stage yeah you got to
adjust what you're feeding and what
you're saturating your trays with and
more than likely you gotta you gotta
match what that plant previously was
getting and that should that should
address your problems um
and there's some purple strains that are
just you know genetically a bit more
purple stems and that's why i said if
they start purple and that still met all
of your other uh you know parameters as
far as this being a healthy plant then
that's just you know a purple stem
genetic and it shouldn't be anything to
worry about um
but it's it's usually just a deficiency
um if you're also getting like yellow
growth
on your new newly developed leaves like
stunted yellow growth that's usually
micronutrients usually iron and zinc and
things like that so you know up your
calmag cow mad cow my cow mag right um
up those micronutrients and it should
address that that stunted uh growth as
well so you know because purple stem
you're more than likely gonna also have
the stunted growth as well up top that
that short internode space
that um underdeveloped leave
and um you know the yellowing and in
your in your leaves as well so they
usually go hand in hand which just means
these plants are hungry these plants are
hungry you're babying them too much up
the light up the food and and get them
uh get that root zone to start up taking
all those nutrients and give it a little
bit of time and it'll bounce right back
i think a lot of people don't know that
the cal meg does often i can't speak for
all of them but there are a lot of
calming formulas that include iron for
example include some
macronutrients so you mentioned that
those could potentially be i'm sorry
micronutrients so those could
potentially be the cause for it so yeah
when you mentioned calmag that's uh just
wanted to mention that point as well
yeah definitely not iron is i was trying
to think of it when i was speaking but
it slipped my mind but they got that
iron and um we'll definitely address all
of that and you know should get rid of
your purple stems and your yellow growth
which you you shouldn't accept really
once again if your plant stock to begin
with was healthy and green and getting
everything that needs you really
shouldn't accept the fact that you plan
to turn in purple or yellow
in the rooting process it's just not
necessary
what are some common mistakes that
growers make when cloning some common
mistakes they uh they just kind of let
it cook right they they ah you know
close the domes up let the humidity
increase and they just want to
they want to give it too much humidity
on their own by spraying the domes
keeping them closed you know not
touching them for for days on end
that's a big mistake right and it's like
they they assume that this plant needs a
hundred percent humidity for five days
straight and it just doesn't and that's
that's a huge mistake you'll start
getting all of the pathogen issues
you'll get stem rot you have your leaves
falling over and then when you start to
acclimate them to you know your normal
reduced humidity environment
you're going to get a bunch of stressed
out plants your leaves are going to curl
up it's just not going to be it's not
going to like the big shock and humidity
so
you know that's that's a big issue that
that uh most growers you know do
so
i like to reduce my humidity gradually
not started too high once again never
and we acclimate it down to that uh you
know mother room environment that's 60
65 humidity
and you know with those
um at a certain stage daily burps so
you're removing that dome you're wiping
off the excess humidity and you're
putting that dome back on and that
shouldn't be more than you know 15 30
seconds if you're taking your domes off
for minutes on end especially in the
first few days it's another big mistake
it's just there's just they haven't
developed the root zone to hold that
moisture and drink that moisture up yet
so earlier on you want to take off your
domes for very small amount of time but
you still need to burp those domes and
get rid of the excess moisture from your
domes later on you can leave them off
for a little bit longer because they've
already got some roots and they're
really being acclimated a bit more to
the environment so
that's a big mistake just just
uh you know don't give them too much
moisture in the beginning just let the
plants breathe let the plants breathe
so if clones aren't rooting what are
some of the things that growers should
look for or do
um i mean you got to take a step back
and look at your environment first right
you know trust but verify all your
sensors
you could even get small sensors that go
inside the domes and really see what's
happening within your dome
look at your your your temperature your
saturation of your media as well your
procedures
you got to really look at everything
there's not too many aspects to cloning
but the aspects that are there are are
very critical and you have to be
consistent with every step
so if you're getting inconsistent
results and you have a team of three
four or five people cutting plug-in
you should really go one-on-one with
them and just and
watch and observe and see if they're
really following all the sops or if
someone's taking a shortcut or someone
left some plants out you know during
lunch time for just too much time and
all these little things that kind of
come in mind when managing a team uh you
know in a nursery the cross
contamination problem that you spoke
about before is something that can
really really do some damage you know
especially when you're working on one of
these commercial facilities i mean i've
seen pictures where
a person uses the same pair of scissors
for example and all of a sudden they cut
clones for a thousand plants and those
thousand plants
had a virus or a viroid and so they look
like complete crap and that's a lot of
plants to mess up right when you're
looking at thousands of plants hundreds
of plants or thousands of plants it
could do some serious damage there
talking about cross-contamination a
little bit more you had something on
your instagram which i want to bring up
here
which is you have a solution
uh particularly for the hormone gels to
prevent cross-contamination can you talk
about that solution yeah absolutely
um so tradition traditionally
uh when plugging clones
most people have always gotten a shot
glass filled that up with a rooting gel
and had that uh you know by their side
as they're grabbing the stem dipping it
into the shot glass with gel and
plugging it into your tray
but what that's doing is creating one
one central point for all of your stems
to cross-contaminate and just if there's
any issues with one plant it's being
cross-contaminated against everything so
you know taking a step back
just just kind of getting creative and
say you know what could be the solution
what's the problem the problem is
they're sharing that same cup that same
gel and you've got multiple mother
plants and stuff
so what's the solution well we still
need gel in the stems right we don't we
can't share them
but uh you know just in in racking my
brain and brainstorming a little bit
i came up with a
a solution that i put the gel inside of
a ketchup bottle a squeeze ketchup
bottle
and all of the the cells and the trays
have pre-made holes for your stems so
that fit perfectly for the squeeze
bottle so i just give it a little
squeeze and i'm filling up the the cubes
the cube holes the stem holes with the
gel versus uh sharing the cup and
dipping everything individually in that
shared cup
so now that stem doesn't share anything
else it goes right into its own cube
with its own gel
and doesn't share anything else and you
repeat the process and all of a sudden
you're not sharing the gel anymore so
it's it's critical for when like you
know you have an issue or you you know
you're you're suspected of having a
viral issue anything that's really
transferable uh physically which that
gel will just house all of that so that
ketchup bottle tech whether you know
whatever we want to call it here it's
it's uh it works and it's enough to like
create you know
a new solution
and you know that may trigger a
different solution or something else in
the future but for now it solves a
problem as far as sharing that cup of
gel right it solves that problem that's
a really cool solution i'm glad you
shared that with us today because uh
the first time i've ever seen it
previously you know you'd always pour
fresh and you never reuse you never
poured back into the bottle was like hey
i'm doing good right i'm not i'm not
reusing gel and stuff but it's like
you had a you know when you're in a
facility and stuff you have to get
creative and you have to be cost
efficient too
i mean a squeeze ketchup bottle on
amazon is a couple bucks i mean and as
far as time goes you know i was talking
to the the staff that i previously
managed and it was it was easy it wasn't
too much of a
burden on them as far as procedures go
time goes labor goes it's a quick step
they're doing 50 squeeze squeeze squeeze
and squeeze you know a couple minutes
later boom they're rocking and it saves
them saves them a bit of time and quite
honestly it it's
it's better because once you uh once
that that cup of gel gets used a little
bit it's kind of you know stems are
coming from liquid so there's always a
little bit of liquid on the bottom of
the stems that goes into the gel and
that doesn't allow the gel to cling onto
your stem very well so you have to put
more gel that's drier so it clings to
your stem so that solves that problem as
well because once you're bringing a
little bit of moisture into this gel cup
the the effectiveness of that gel
clinging to your stem is like almost nil
cleaner faster safer cheaper yeah it's
like and some people were like oh you
know it looks like you're using too much
gel and stuff
look that's that's an easy adjustment
right and if you pour an eye pour you
know into the the same thing we may be a
little bit different
but that's an easy adjustment you can
make for all the benefits you gain that
we just described yeah i'm definitely
gonna have to buy a ketchup bottle or
two
all right so kind of getting towards the
end of the podcast here we went over a
lot a lot of good tips talk to us how
can the listeners find you and what do
you have upcoming in the future
yeah absolutely um instagram i try to be
active on there as much as i can so uh
clung coach
on instagram uh my youtube channel is
barely getting its its wheels moving
i'm learning how to do all this video
recording editing you know script
writing it's it's a lot to take on but
uh it's something that i have on my
agenda so on youtube clone coach as well
and um you know so i offer uh rooting
program and clone coaching so you know
in the nursery end of things from a
commercial scale you know i've been
cutting plugging and selling clones
since 2015 so i i understand the
managing aspect the production aspect um
you know the market aspect and
everything else so
you know that clone coach program will
get you the best clones ever in 14 days
and in the future
for the licensed california market i do
have a nursery marketplace in the works
so
that that should be coming up fairly
soon and i will be excited to uh to
reach back out and talk a bit more about
that that's exciting and that's really
cool that you offer one-on-one
consulting i was on your website and saw
that i know a lot of people don't offer
that but that's really cool that you do
so if anybody who is tuning into this is
looking for consulting
definitely check out his website and you
can sign up for that so
awesome
well thanks paul i appreciate you coming
on click the thumbs up if you enjoyed
this episode subscribe to the channel if
you haven't already every single weekend
i'm releasing a new garden talk podcast
so stay tuned i would love for you to
tune in to future episodes
and yeah thanks so much paul we will uh
believe it i appreciate you having me on
here this was this was a blast and uh
yeah let's uh anybody out there
struggling with their clones let's get
you some results sounds good all right
until next time peace out everyone
[Music]
you