i don't actually use water in my cloning
process because
i'm pretty assembly line with it when i
take clones it's
in in you know to where they're going
the only thing i do after my 45 degree
angle is a light light abrasion
actually upward on the kind of
surrounding stem
area from that 45 degree angle and even
with aeroponics if i wait too long and i
mess around and i have hydro plants
that transition into my cocoa blend with
peat
is a little bit of you know they get a
little wonky on me you know they might
shoot a yellow leaf or two they might
get a little
upset with me it's the quickest way if
you can get it dialed in if you
if it's not dialed in and you're having
fluctuation
and everything it can be a headache and
make you feel like you don't know what
you're doing
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and this is garden talk episode 9. this
episode's guest is
trey strong's he is most known for his
youtube channel cannabis lifestyle tv
which currently has 278 videos that have
over
11 million views combined and 124 000
subscribers he is also the host of
elevated chef which is in a fuse cooking
show andy owns a hydroponic shop in
michigan
in this episode we talk about the basics
of cloning all the way from
how to cut clones the environment that
clones should be put in
different ways to clone and more before
we get into the episode
i'd like to give a quick shout out to
our sponsor big thanks to happy hydro
for sponsoring this episode
they actually recently launched their
own youtube channel and they're posting
videos on a weekly basis
aaron who's their host he puts a fun
spin
on grill light reviews they're also
doing part tests unboxing videos
and how-to videos do me a favor and show
them some love go subscribe to their
youtube channel be one of the first
subscribers to that channel i'll link it
down in the description section below
and of course you can always check out
happyhydro.com for popular brands like
ac infiniti grows choice spider farmer
chiltek gorilla blue mat and more
that being said let's get into the
episode
all right we're here what's up trey how
you doing man
doing all right brother i'm uh excited
to be on the show today thanks for
having me
yeah thanks for coming on uh you've been
requested by a few people
and um of course you're part of the cltv
family you know you and rob are doing
big things over there i had rob on
actually the first episode which was
last year
and uh you know on that episode i think
is the ones where
people like oh we need to get trey on
here so finally got you on here for once
so thanks for coming on
yeah of course yeah well i was gonna say
time flies because i feel like that was
like
last month you know that he was on and
uh you know
on your channel and i but i've seen it
i've seen that video
pop up quite a few times so you know all
i can hope is that i
i do uh some some some sort of
uh diligence to him who came before me
representing
the cl fam so you know um yeah
no pressure yeah of course
uh okay so to start um for those that
don't know who you are can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into growing
yeah so uh i'm trey
i'm passionate about family cannabis and
culinary
um so all subsets of my life come
from those passions and obviously
is why i have been dedicated to
cannabis lifestyle and canvas lifestyle
tv and all the things that have branched
off from that but really i've
always from my first interaction with
the plant i've
been like the plant not necessarily the
flower but the plant
have been
fascinated by it i guess you know it's
like the closest thing
to a hobby
that i have but for the longest time it
wasn't really you know something you
outwardly was like yeah my hobby is
growing cannabis you know
um it's cool to say that i've i think i
can
proudly say that we've been a part a
small part in that footstep of like
breaking the stigma and having it be
kind of
somewhat normalcy to you know have that
small at-home garden and just figure out
on how
different ways to tweak it and make it
better um
which is what i've been doing for the
past decade so
yeah i mean i that's me in a nutshell as
far as cannabis and
and you know obviously if any of you
have you know watched the channel you
know
um i have a good a great relationship
with
culinary which i've melded with cannabis
many many times over which i also feel
like is
another subset of those two passions of
mine so
and you also have a hydroponic store is
that right
yeah we uh north shore is hydroponic
and holland hydroponic outlet one in the
same
we're located in the west michigan area
west west
west coast area so
yeah we got four locations along along
like a 60-mile strip
so we've been helping people stores been
around 11 years i've been a part of it
for about seven
and that'll put you through the trenches
you know
of just like even if i wasn't growing
kind of the do's and don'ts and
the the wii's and won'ts you know so
that's been it's like an apprenticeship
almost in a sense again because you are
in a time that it wasn't as trendy as it
is now
um so i you know of course you you
have those instances where
you know people are kind of driven for
one sense or another uh
towards gardening and so you find that
kind of
ugly side of it but there's a really
great gardening community
out of it as well and i think what's
cool and i'm sure it's like that with
like the automotive community or
any niche uh interest right
is um you kind of have to work your way
into it
and and and your name is really all you
have to go by
is what the community says you
are good at or not so good at so
i haven't had too many bad reviews
in the sense of that community so
for me that's a sense of pride for sure
and
you know i think that's why people come
back to us because you can get you can
get gardening grow equipment from
anywhere
um but the knowledge that you seek for
your garden at the time of need
you know that's what makes you so much
of an influence
on not only youtube but just the growing
community
and you know that's what's going to kind
of speak volumes over time
that makes sense cool all right let's
get into the
topic today so let's talk all about
cloning
so i have a variety of people that watch
my channel right beginners
intermediate advanced i feel like it's
more geared towards
i feel like a majority of the audience
are beginner-like so
in this episode i really just want to
kind of cover the basics maybe we can
get into more advanced things in a
different episode
but let's cover the basics so um first
off
what is cloning well
it's essentially uh keeping around
whatever form of plant you have um
and essentially by cutting off a piece
of that plant and
and trying to have that established
roots or
you know a root zone so that you can um
keep keep whatever it is you got going
so
yeah i think that's in the simplest form
cutting off a branch
and rooting it is really what it comes
down to so
at what point do you clone i mean do you
take clones in early veg
late veg flower when do you take clones
um i would say
you know when i went that question i'm
like well like mid veg
that's not you know i'm not not papa
bear not mom and bear
or not baby bear a middle bear so um i
would say
i like to have a plant be well
established i guess
before i i i take a clone
so i would i would say i'm a mid veg not
early veg because
i feel like and they you know depending
on you know the resiliency of your plant
you may not need that long a time
and again depending on what kind of
plant you're cloning i'm sure
everyone has a little bit different
of a sweet spot but for me i would and
i would say mid veg i usually do mid veg
as well
you can do it at any point right early
veg you can do it maybe like
i would say probably the earliest i
would ever take clowns is around day 20
25-ish you know i mean that would be
like real early to take clowns
for me you can definitely do it in
in late veg you can do it in flour as
well some people don't know that you can
actually take clones and flour it's
called
monster cropping and then you have to
actually go through the the re-vegging
process so it takes a little bit longer
to to get back into that re-vegging
process and take off but
you can certainly still take clones
while in the flower stage it's just
just not really ideal because it takes a
little bit longer than that so
yeah i saw that option not for me
not personally and we um just
uh touched on this actually on our live
i believe on tuesday
you know there's this if you you know it
can
again be whatever i know certain like
orchid strains
or even um there's a customer of mine
who
clones conifer trees and he gets like
six hundred dollars a clone and he'll
take like 600 clones and he'll only get
six
though you know that's like not the
greatest succession rate but
um i would say i just don't want to go
through that much time and effort and
energy unless
it's like the cream of the crop worth
that monster cropping and um
revenge time because the revenge time
can be quite a long time completely
agree it's situational right so some
people aren't going to have the space
um you know to have an 18 6 light cycle
a veg light cycle going and a flower
cycle so maybe they
they put all their plants in a flower
then they realize hey this fino is
awesome i want to keep it
so at that point maybe they you know
they cut clones at that point
um you know late flower to kind of keep
those genetics around so
yeah i agree with you it's definitely
situational for sure
so can the plant be showing deficiencies
when you clone it
well you you bring up a good adjective
there situational which i feel like is
going to be kind of
a couple of these answers for me um
which it is
you know again those those trench in the
trenches days
that i mentioned like just shown me like
really
and i guess that's great because we've
built a community and kind of a
existence on this but there's no one
answer right
um i i again if it's if it's a phenotype
or
a cultivar that is just
and i for whatever reason don't have any
other way to keep it around and it has
an issue
it's it's showing signs of stress it's
you know maybe has
some sort of pest issue
i'll clone it you know if it's coming to
kind of a tea in the road
if i had my you know perf if i had my
perfect situation
i would wait for it to be healthy to
bounce back
because obviously those issues are only
going to translate down into that
generation
and so it's going to be dang near
impossible to
kind of supersede those issues if they
are so severe
but you know if if a plant is showing me
signs of that
it's probably not something i'm keeping
around to be honest but again
depending on the situation um
yes but like initial answer
no yeah i think there's a i think that's
a common argument
is um if the plant is showing any type
of deficiencies it's showing a sign of
weakness
you don't want a clone i think general
knowledge is you don't want to actually
take clones at that point now
i've read quite a few books and one of
the things i have some notes here
one of the books that i've read i'm not
sure if you're familiar with it the
gross bible
jorge cevantes grow his bible so
actually in
that one quote clones
quickly develop a root system when the
stems have a high carbohydrate and low
nitrogen concentration so there is an
eye game out there that
if you're a little bit deficient in
nitrogen you're actually going to root
faster
which i thought was really interesting
now i've never put it to the test i
haven't done any side by sides or
anything like that but
you know for those people who think that
any sign of deficiencies
is a weakness and you shouldn't clone at
that point there is actually some
evidence out there or
people out there experts in our field
out there that are saying that
if it's a little bit deficient you know
particularly nitrogen
that's actually a good thing and
actually speed up rooting well
and i was going to say when sometimes
when you take a clone they will
obviously show signs of nitrogen
deficiency so almost
having a plant that might already be
established to that you know might do
well
you know because depending on you know
the length of time it takes your
plant to develop roots you know it
usually you're not hitting it with a
bunch of food it's not having a
bunch of access to resource necessarily
so you know
it's almost like you know a kid that's
been in the streets already
you know so it's like they're going to
survive a little bit better you know
i guess i've done no side by sides but i
have been in that situation where
actually a couple months ago i had i
didn't have to shut down the garden but
i had to revamp it and i had some
genetics that i wanted to keep around
but they were a little stressed because
i was
pretty focused on my greenhouse at the
time and so
you know i took those plants that
weren't so great and i
cloned them out just to keep the um
cultivars around and
they cloned so i i mean you know jorge
knows
quite a bit i i'm familiar with the
bible i've obviously referenced it a ton
i think it's like the bible i haven't
run it from like cover to cover but
you know i've definitely referenced it
and that's interesting i mean you don't
think about these things
that you've done necessarily in the in
the garden until you
you know are talking about it so makes
sense
now for probably one of the most uh
beginner questions
very common beginner questions i guess
i'll say
can you clone an autoflower plan
oh yeah i went into my own conversation
with this question like
off camera well first of all
um autoflowers man i was gonna say
because i've never done autoflowers
because
that's my initial like nope don't do
that you know don't grow that here
um tough
man i have done them the ones that i've
grown i have not been very impressed
with they were just kind of there and
they did their thing
i have done a couple sun grown as well
um and where that's where i feel like
they have the most value
personally for the region in which i
uh grow as well as the type of gardener
that i am
um i've heard of people doing it
i haven't personally done it i don't
personally run autoflowers
i'm gonna try to get better with that
because they didn't they haven't
actually done anything to me personally
but it kind of feels like it because
when you dedicate time and energy to a
plan and it comes out like charlie brown
christmas tree you're like what the heck
is going on here but that's uh kind of
what i
you know i'm that's the type of guy i am
too like
i didn't do so well with him i will
probably
pick up that challenge again you know if
the situation
uh opens itself to it but
as far as me cloning autoflowers no i
have not
can you there has been people out there
that have successfully done so
i don't believe that that's what they
were
inceptionalized to do though they were
they were developed to do exactly the
opposite
of that to to to be planted to grow
to bloom and to die that is what they're
meant to do
how you tweak that cycle is very
pertinent
and i haven't gotten it down yet
personally so um
but there are gardeners out there i have
a couple customers that that's all they
grow and
and they love it and they're they're
doing pretty well from what i can see
so yeah i think technically you can um
you can
clone an autoflower plant now is it
ideal to do that
are you going to get a great result you
can get a high yield high yield from
doing that
probably not right because if you're
cutting a clone say you cut a clone
around day 25 right
typical autoflower is going to start
flowering around what day 30
day 40 or so it's on that a certain life
span right
it's not like you control the amount of
time it's in veg
by the light cycle like you do with
photo period plants right so
if you're cutting a clone around day 25
off an auto power plant
you can get it to root for sure you can
get it to root
now the thing is it's going to be
flowering pretty quickly because it's
not sensitive to that
it's not you know photoperiodism so you
might have a small plant
so then it's like well is it even worth
it to clone autos or not
so technically it's possible but yeah
you got to ask yourself is it is it
really worth the time
is it really worth you know the space
maybe it is for some people i'd love to
know for those who are viewing this have
you cloned an autoflower plant before
is that something that you practice let
me know let us know down in the comment
section below
i'd love to hear it i'm sure we'll hear
somebody that says oh yeah i clone all
the time
yeah yeah i mean there are those not
anomalies in the system but like i say
there's
gardeners out there that make things
happen that i don't see
in the the mass percentage or popularity
but it's
definitely you know done for sure
so when you do cut clones does the clone
need to be a certain size
do you have like do you cut a certain
size of a clone
or what um
yes would be like my golden boy answer
but like do they vary
yes as you heard me mentioned a couple
minutes ago
i've taken whole plants and turned them
all into clones so that
you know the side the size
differentiation there is going
to vary um
ideally um when i clone i take
same size clones so that they all grow
evenly
um is my thought process behind that
or why i do it in that method
but it kind of varies too if i have
different
phenotypes or cultivars next to each
other in the same cloning bed
then they vary no matter what
size i take them at you know certain
genetics are going to
root faster and grow quicker
i had some plants that were in my
aeroponic clone
that pretty much turned into hydroponic
plants so it's um
it's not impossible uh to to have
success i would say
uh without keeping it the same size i
think it helps you
if you try to um just like in cooking
you know you want to cut things to the
same size so that they all cook evenly
when you have it more uh kind of rough
it's going to cook that same way so
that's a good answer i think for me
generally what i'll do is
you know roughly maybe six to eight
inches is what i'll cut
for a clone roughly now there are people
but people out there who have
cut off two foot branches and then clone
that i mean it's possible right you can
do that
i i have i have it depends on if i'm
breaking down a plant
if i you know just trying to to take an
even
i i try to be even about it but it's
situational again i'm going to
steal that word from you for this
episode but
yeah i i try to i usually will cut
like a decent size off of the plant
and then shorten that into a clone so i
go for fairly that same size but they
some of them vary you know got it now i
know you said that you've taken
clones from an entire plant before right
but generally
what part of the plant you take clones
from my
entryway into cloning was you know
bottom of the bottom of the canopy
you know or lower half of the plant and
so that's where
i try to start at but sometimes
i would say sometimes majority of the
time when i'm taking clones i'll look at
that plant and then
also start to like prune that plant so
if there are
certain branches that i'm going to
discard anyway they might become a clone
in the process
so there are those times but most of the
time it's because i'm
snipping you know clones off of that
branch already
so usually the lower half of the plant i
would say
is like my 80 go-to unless i'm
breaking down a whole plant got it yeah
so you can definitely
um you know just back up a minute you
can definitely take clones from any part
of the plant if you want
but i am going to actually quote jorge
cervantes again you know in his book he
has just this section on cloning and
i remember when i first read it i was
like wow i didn't know this i didn't
know this i didn't know this
and and one of the things was clones
from the lower branches
root the easiest because they contain
more of the proper hormones
so that's what it says in there so
basically the lower part of the plant is
apparently the easiest to root has the
newest hormones
middle part of the plant easier easier
to root next to oldest hormones and then
upper part of the plant
most difficult clones to root oldest
hormones that's coming straight out of
his book so
i thought it was interesting i figured
i'd bring that up i'm not sure if a lot
of people know that or not
um there is some stuff in his book
that's inaccurate so
i can't say that this is 100 accurate
but um
yeah that's what it says in there which
i thought was interesting right now
there's
there's so much information out there
and i i think too again
because i grew my i
in gardening terms i grew up off of
jorge cervantes and ed rosenstein
and guys who learned strictly off of
them
um but again that was a different time
that was you know almost two decades ago
so i think there's just been so much
more revelation and
information and science done um that
any plant you know that that cuts across
more than
just ones we may be talking about um
it's
there's a lot of things like you say
that can be inaccurate now or debunked
in a sense but um because that same
thing i've had clones root from the top
of the plant
did they take a little bit longer i mean
i didn't take a record of it but
probably so
interesting stuff now when you cut the
clones a common technique is to cut it
at a 45 degree angle
do you do that at all or i do
yes that's
you know when i go to take that longer
piece of the plant and i snip it down
that's when i make my 45 degree angle
and the benefit of that is the only
information bank i have is from my
mother
who ran a floral shot for many many
moons many many moons before i was a
thing
and where i get a lot of my
kind of green thumb from and every time
she would
bring for us flowers into the house
which she always had to have
she would always cut it at that same 45
degree angle you know every single stem
and i think you know it does expose
surface area
but how she explained it to me is there
a for for those plants that they were
able to
more readily uh drink or eat or like
go for resource in the base that they
were in
i think the same thing applies when
you're talking about taking a clone is
you wanting a fresh as
most as you can get it as close as you
can get a sterile
part to that plant to start that root
zone from
um so that's my two cents
now there's a common technique of
basically at the end of the clone
to split the end uh and it supposedly
gets more roots that way that's a common
thing
another thing would be to scrape off
like the inch or two
of the bottom of the clone again to kind
of help with surface area help with
rooting do you do any of those
techniques at all or
i do not and and i
and there's nothing wrong with it i
think people do
there's definitely gardeners out there
who get success
from doing that i
i wasn't ever taught that from my kind
of obi-wan
into into gardening um but also
i just i the time or two that i've done
it it's
so much stress on the clone that i
haven't seen good results come back from
it i haven't seen it
be beneficial to one my rooting time
or two just overall health of the plant
um
i have had a couple people help me clone
and when they
they've gone to do that and i'm like oh
it's like pretty nerve-wracking um but
no i i i the only thing i do after my 45
degree angle is a light
light abrasion um actually upward
on the um kind of surrounding stem
area from that 45 degree angle
and then i dip into my
rooting hormone a rooting compound and
um go from there so
uh yeah that's worked for me
it's it's i think it's just enough
ruffling on that edge to get that oh
crap we need energy here
which is what you're creating when you
when you take that clone
um but it's not so much that it's hard
for the plant or
for the potential plant to recover got
it yeah i usually i usually scrape the
bottom
inch or two at the very bottom um
you know the hopes that the roots would
be popping out of that place i've seen
them i've seen it happen before you know
as they ripped out you can see roots
coming out that way so
i think it's beneficial so that's that's
typically what i do
i don't think i've ever from when i can
remember i don't think i've ever done
the split at the end
um i don't think i've ever done it
before but maybe i have i don't know
well yeah every single plan i've grown
every single thing i've done
right exactly we didn't we weren't
recording every single
time that we did it we were just i mean
a lot of my early garden career was
throwing crap at the wall and hoping
that what it stuck
but it's um i think we can both agree
that
the scraping of the light abrasion is
beneficial
um how you go about that i guess i
wouldn't say i the only thing i would
say i don't do personally is like
completely scrape it down to kind of the
meat
which is what i think could be
translated from the question
um not that you can't do it you know
plants are pretty freaking resilient
it's kind of crazy what they go through
with what we put them through or
otherwise so you can
do it successfully i think as far as
like cutting into that
like upwardly and not just doing the
scrape or doing both
but i think favoring one or the other
you know
it's just a lot for the plant to recover
from nafta cut the clone
it's generally advised i mean just about
any resource you read online it's
advised to
immediately put that clone into water is
that something that you do
you know what are the reasons why to
potentially
dip it immediately into water um
i got the answer here if you need me to
give it to you
yeah go ahead and give it to me all
right
um so you want to prevent air from
getting into those hollow stems
it's called embolism so basically it's a
bubble of air that gets trapped in the
stem
when that happens fluid stops and then
the clone dies
so that's why it's generally advised to
just stick that clone directly into
water to prevent that air bubble
from getting into the actual hollow stem
so that's my understanding of it yeah i
mean learn something new every day
what i know is that again it's it's
keeping it sterile
i guess i didn't know exactly about the
the air bubble
effect but again to me it's a
contaminant factor
you know and i i understood that fact of
um like you're taking these clones you
want it to be sterile from the cut
all the way until it's in whatever
medium you're putting it into
and that can help one of the people who
was helping me
take the clones was making the cut
actually under water
and you know cutting it upward and
things like that and
i just no i ain't got time
i i have success without doing all that
the only
thing i would say i use water for is if
i'm
hey these need i need to take clones of
these
uh cultivars so let me take the branch
off and stick them in a solo cup of ph
water until i'm able to take the clone
that's when i will kind of soak my cuts
in
water i don't actually use water in my
cloning process because
i'm pretty assembly line with it when i
take clones it's
in to in you know to where they're going
i don't have like a
a span in time where i have to
necessarily worry about that
and i know some people instead of going
into water instead of dipping it
directly into water as
quickly as they can they'll goes
directly into a rooting hormone
right so what is a rooting hormone uh
that was what i was gonna look up but i
believe it's like
in burritic acid or
something along those lines i mean i
know the homie goblin he uses just like
um aloe vera um and i know there's a
couple of
of gardeners that practice that actually
i know there's some people who don't use
a rooting hormone at all
but what is it um look it up because i i
know i butchered that word but
it's some sort of acid in in a
gelatinous form more or less
yeah quite simply it's something that's
gonna help the the clone root faster
is really what it comes down to there
are several different types
um we won't get into two details a
little bit more advanced but
naa iba dpi
those are three different i usually use
the iba ones
then you've got the you know the liquid
solutions versus the gel solutions
versus the powder solutions
are there any ones in particular that
you usually do
oh man uh
i guess what also what brand now in
particular i don't have a particular
brand
the reason i chuckle is because certain
customers are so dead set on like clonex
oh you don't got clonex and i'll have
root tech instead
you know just because sometimes the
inventory varies right
and um it's like lucky gym socks to me
i'm like it's
it's rooting gel what is the difference
you know like when you get a new clone
or you get easy
or yeah easy clones version which is a
rooting compound i've tried dyna i've
tried root tech i've tried cloning
i haven't i don't think i've actually
ever even used
clonex cloning gel i haven't because
it's purple and it weirds me out
but um yeah i mean i've had success with
all the ones i've mentioned um and i
don't
i don't see a difference personally you
know coming from
a guy who runs a hydroshot four days out
of the week i don't
there's no difference to me personally i
think the only thing i would add to that
is i usually use like the the liquid of
the gel
i feel like the powder um you know
sometimes it doesn't get
directly onto the bottom of the clone as
nicely as the the liquid of the gel does
see i feel like that's eluded me because
i've had customers come in you don't
have any rooting powder and i'm like
no like that's a dated in my opinion
form of
of taking clones i i don't even stock a
rooting powder
the the closest thing to a rooting
powder i have is great white you know
shout out to them
and because once i dip into my rooting
um rooting hormone
um i then will roll my my clones into
great white
so it almost creates like a paste on the
end of
um my clone which is also
why i don't use any water or anything i
feel like everything that gets sucked up
into
that little situation ship right there
uh
is you know a combination of that uh
rooting hormone and and great white
because great white is like
powdered sugar it cakes okay so there's
several different methods
for rooting right you can simply cut the
clone off the plant
directly stick it directly into the
medium which i've done in the past
of course using you know rooting
hormones or what you just talked about
you can stick it in rock wall you can
use root riots
aeroponics you can actually stick that
clone directly into a cup of water and
leave it in the cup of water and
actually root in that water what method
do you typically use
well i haven't ever had
roots come from just sticking it in
water i know people who have but
i have not had that amount of green
thumb action
personally but other than that i've done
them all
well except for grow dan i haven't
personally done it but
my brother who i garden with now he he
uses them
and they're just like any other soilless
cube
i i think there's a little bit of
technique when you're talking about
soaking them
i started my cloning career in riots or
soilless peak cubes
i find those to be personally one of the
more
beginner friendly or
less vulnerable ways to clone
personally the only difference is kind
of how i've graduated to how i do it
used to just
take them out of the bag take the clones
stick them in there and go
now i will typically soak them in a
solution that has some form of great
white or orca
in it because like i mentioned i do the
dip and roll in my aeroponic cloning
um that does not work so well when you
go to shove something into a peak cube
with a hole that's really tiny
so i just make sure that the great white
is just already absorbed into the
puck or the peak cube
and then go from there
aeroponic cloning
when she works she's a beaut when she
doesn't it can really be
a punch to the gut um that's uh
my other like binary relationship with
any kind of
hydroponics it's like it can be great
and
if it's bad it can be very bad um but
if you can get it good it is like one of
the most streamlined ways to clone
i think that they're happy that way
when you're talking about the other
spectrum just like taking it off of the
plant and sticking it into like some
sort of dirt
i've done that too um
i've done that when i'm like if you make
it you make it
bye you know that's that's kind of how
i've
how i've done that form of cloning
personally
um but i know a lot of gardeners who
that's just how they do it
um again a plant is so resilient it
you know you can have success with it in
any of those forms of that i've talked
about or
you know drop in the comments maybe
other ways that you've cloned i know
customers who clone on the plant you
know um
so it's there's a lot of different forms
but
you know going back to just sticking it
in the in the
dirt just like cutting it when you're
making that cut up the plant it's a lot
for your plant to overcome so
your your root time your root
development time
i just have found personally to be so
far extrapolated from
kind of the more primitive way of going
about it
that that's not how i practice
my gardening because it would just be so
stunning and and not
consistent and not perpetual and that's
the whole reason that i
got into cloning is so that i could keep
certain cultivars or phenotypes around
that i could
keep the garden perpetual and keep
growing and keep hunting and
and flowering so um
i think aeroponics are have been the
best in that sense the most streamlined
um i have had certain phenotypes that
just do not take to that well
so you have to venture into other areas
whether it be sticking it straight in or
or
using uh soilless cubes
so it's situational
can we get like five cents every time
you say that um but
yeah so i i think you know when you're
talking about preference aeroponics for
me
and right next to that you know tried
and true for me is
is gonna be the soilless peak cube um
i've had people see or seen people have
really great success in the grow dance i
just always used to call those things
black magic because it didn't make any
sense to me
because they were not always as popular
as they are now with instagram and
everything
but um i think what's nice with those is
it allows you the ability to go into any
kind of medium
so that's the other thing is like when
you start a
clone in a peak cube you can go in the
soil
fairly well going into hydro okay
with grow it and i've seen them
that that transfer shock be a little
less and even with aeroponics if i wait
too long and i
mess around and i have hydro plants
that transition into my cocoa blend with
pete
is a little bit of you know they get a
little wonky on me you know they might
shoot a yellow leaf or two they might
get a little
upset with me um versus
having that transition be more mild so
again it's it's genetic plant dependent
but
gardener-dependent but yeah
all right so digging a little bit deep
into aeroponics what should the ph of
the water be and do you actually use a
solution
like you mentioned clonex earlier i'd
use anything in the aeroponic machine as
far as solution
solution uh for me it's just
a little a little bit of orca
and not really not when i when i when i
initially set up my my cloner as time
goes on
i'll add um clear as i'll add
a little bit of clonex solution um i
just
i had some i had some issues with my
with my 32 site and
and i never used to you have to use
clonex
but my plants or my clones have
just seemed to again maybe because it's
having that little bit of food in there
giving them a little bit of energy
to use for what they're doing but that
has seemed to help me if i add that a
little bit later on along with
some sort of beneficial microbial in
there usually
some liquid form again i i used to do
great white in there i used to have a
whole
not concoction but i i felt the need to
dial it back
you know simplify it because i wasn't
seeing the same success results that i
was
from you know blending i had like kalen
and great white and
this and that in there and like while
all those things do help your root
process
like they have a time and a place so
i've just found
that that has helped me like to
gradually add it not make a big old
solution that i'm running
from jump so is it a specific ph that
you do or
no um yes sorry uh
i i try to stay around six i used to
have this like
battle where i wanted to be at 5.8 but
six is good got it and then i know for
aeroponics
some people just have the sprayers on 24
7. some people put it on a timer so it
comes on every so often
what do you do for that personally i've
never put my
my aeroponic cloner on a timer i do know
a couple of grower buddies who
uh one of them he has it on a timer he
sees
he doesn't see good results if he
doesn't have it on a timer so he stays
with that method pretty consistently
another buddy uh put his on a timer
thinking
okay i'm gonna this is the cheat code
right and he just
it wasn't really successful for him uh
so he ended up
kind of taking that element out um
yeah i i just keep them running i i just
those
those pumps in there don't like i
personally i don't i haven't seen them
like to go on and off and off and on i
even when i'm not using my clone or have
it running
uh it's got just a solution of um highly
concentrated
hydrogen peroxide in water but so it's
just cleaning itself constantly but i
don't let those
pumps dry up or dry out because and
obviously if the pump's coming on it's
not going to dry out but
those things are just so so finicky so
okay now
typically what light cycle do you place
to clones under
18 6 24 24 0
12 12. um
i think people do that right are there
people out there that put it on 12 12
i think they do it for a short period of
time and then they they switch to 18 six
i believe or veterans oh okay okay i
think yeah
let us know in the comments if you do it
right right no i i'm 18
and six the only kind of like light
schedule they're on is when
they i'm that first week i kind of tuck
them away from the light
because i just don't feel that they need
direct light
you know um i have a small
uh chiltek led mini so like it's perfect
for
cloning and i turn it down but i even
like [__] the
cloner away from it just so that it's
not
directly in that light you know
obviously season's depending because
like temperature and things play a role
but
um i've just found that they
it's almost like you know you take that
first week to sleep from recovery or
whatever
you know like they don't need it right
up under there and then once they
you can see that they're you know i
throw them under there and give them a
decent amount of light on that 18 and
six so
yeah i usually do 18 6 too and that was
my next question is how much light
do you typically give the clones and
then you know talking about spectrum is
there a certain spectrum that you like
to give your clones in particular
yeah i i i was running under their mini
red
and i mean i had results i there wasn't
a single problem but just the
the the you know whatever we
excuse me uh plant guru in me
was like there's a reason why you have
veg and bloom spectrums
you know as a guy who runs a hydrostar
i'm just like okay
you know so what's up with your guys's
blue speck so
because i just i feel like if you're
if they're more established plants you
can play around with different spectrums
and even like
uh infiltrating some more red spectrums
right because
as spring like the almost time that
we're in now
comes around you get a bit more of those
coming in than you do from winter you
know even or
for instance right um so i don't think
it's the worst thing in like
uh mid to late veg but early veg i like
to have that
that blue green springy spectrum
so got it yeah when it talks about how
much light typically
you know if we're talking par in ppfd in
particular i usually aim for like 200 to
ppfd for my clones a little bit less
than that
actually get away with with the rooting
process as well now as far as the actual
spectrum
i do like to give it a blue i mean we
know that blue inhibits cell division
that's going to lead to tighter node
spacing
that is something where you generally
hear that
for the veg stage you want more blue in
the spectrum for
the flowering stage more red in the
spectrum i typically do go up more on
the blue side of things when i'm
when i have clones underneath it now as
far as the environment let's get into
that a little bit
um in your environment what do you
typically aim for the temperature
and the humidity to be when rooting
clones
so for like when i'm rooting my soil
cubes
it's a little bit different for me than
when you're when when i'm running my
rooting in my aeroponic corner just
because when i'm
rooting with the soil cubes i keep them
underneath the humidity dome
almost the entirety that they're rooting
so that
environment that they're directly in is
probably closer to you know the tropical
environment
80 degrees and you know 70 degrees or 60
degrees humidity
so because i'm spraying it every day i'm
i'm keeping it very moist in there so
they don't have to search
for uh water of any sort
uh and then with my aeroponic
and with any clone i should say like
the the environment should should should
match that to a degree
dialed down you don't necessarily have
to keep i don't keep a dome
over my aeroponic loner i i do know
gardeners who do
um i don't personally but i then want to
keep that area very
inoculated to that germination like
environment where it's
you know 70 78 degrees
and pretty humid because those little
ones love
that type of like just you know
encapsulated environment
you know to do what they need to do so
temperature i usually aim for is between
like 75 and 82 degrees fahrenheit is
what i usually aim for when i'm when i'm
rooting clones
uh humidity you know above 65 percent um
you know up to up to 90 for the like the
first day or so for the first 24 hours i
mean if it's 90 95 percent
for the first 24 48 hours um i've
actually had pretty good luck doing that
as well
and as i read in books as well as a
technique uh but yeah kind of above the
is kind of what i've had best luck on
now some people i know they monitor also
the the temperature of the medium
i like i mentioned briefly earlier is
cutting a clone stick it directly into
the medium that's kind of my primary way
of doing things it's just
easy for me i don't have an aeroponic
clone or anything um
what i usually aim for for a soil level
temperature or soil temperature
is between 72 and 82 degrees fahrenheit
i have tried to probably the biggest
fail
um is whenever i try to clone and all of
a sudden the temperature is
too low when it's in like the soil the
medium temperature is like in the 60s
it just it doesn't root anywhere near as
fast
like you'll keep the plant somewhat
alive but
it's just not going to ruin and you'll
see deficiencies at least that's been my
experience
doing that so i know you said you mostly
do the aeroponic side of things
is there a specific water temperature
that you go by well i was gonna say it
but i didn't want to
jump into your question too far but um
the temperature above
shouldn't drastically be different from
below
if your below temperature is drastically
above then you know you have these weird
plants that try to
you know shoot their roots upward
because the roots want
you know again that inoculated warm
environment so for my aeroponic cloner
i try to stay in that like 70 to 72
degree
water temperature anything lower than
that
i have slowed root growth i i have no
root growth dependent and that's why
it's hard like to use the aeroponic
cloner
successfully in a hundred percent
capacity
and like the dry uh hot
because you have the heat on winter you
know or cold
dry winter and then you know in summer
i usually have great success clothing
but you don't necessarily need
to to be doing that much in the
summertime so
um it's kind of a give or take but i
would say
you know i use you know water bottles to
regulate in the
in the summertime when that pump creates
too much uh
warmth in the same sense you have to
stay kind of regulated to get
those roots exactly how you want them to
be in the time
that you want to be when you're talking
aeroponics and
you know sounds like you're having the
same um
you know having to regulate with soil
and with
the root cubes
for i don't pay attention to temperature
too much but i just
stress to myself and my customers that
you keep them moist because once they
dry out
it's just so hard to recover from that
yeah this then that's what the seedling
mats
are very helpful um you gotta be be
careful because i've
placed my uh cups directly onto the
seedling
mats and just fried my roots right it's
just it becomes too hot
there is a temperature monitor on some
of these seedling mats
so you can get more accurate as far as
what it is but
your seedling mat if you have one
without the the temperature monitor on
it
you know placing towels in between that
can help
so you don't fry your roots because it
won't root if the temperature is too hot
right
i put a i screwed myself in an aeroponic
because it was cold and it was on a
metal surface
and we insulated but it was still too
warm
so um while
it would have been too cold without it
it was too warm with it and we got
root sludge and it was not good so makes
sense so it is definitely important for
sure
so generally speaking how long does it
take for a clone to root situational no
no
no no um
depending on cultivar the only that's
the only reason why i say that that was
my only
i don't know it depends uh when i seen
that question
just probably personally because right
now i'm having an issue with my wi-fi
um she just
does taking her sweet time i tell you
what whereas i have
other uh cultivars genetics that just
you know they're almost like too quick
you're like well dang i needed like two
weeks
before you were ready you know so it's
seven days like i'm not ready you know
so um i think that's pretty typical
seven to
seven to 14 days some people like to say
seven to ten
and it really depends on what a root is
to you because like
certain people will think that what i
call like the color flowering
of the root or the stem uh where it's
just about
just about to shoot out those roots
they'll call those roots
i call roots roots so i mean that just
depends on who you are
because even once i see roots come out i
wanted to be well developed
before i transplant them so that makes
sense i think the method also will will
determine how long it takes to root
right if you're
sticking it directly in the medium i
don't think i've had roots
any sooner than 10 days i mean 14 days
is typical
for when you can tell the plant has
rooted and now new growth is starting um
you know sticking it directly into the
medium now with an aeroponic loaner i
mean
can't you get something some people get
roots in like six days or something like
that six
yeah i've heard four days
so it's like i don't know i'm like i
don't know what kind again black magic
you're using
[Laughter]
but i mean they could just have a really
good environment
i mean it just can can come down to that
it's not nothing they're doing it's just
you know
the the the genetic or phenotype they
have is just a
quick rooter and a quick cloner and they
have the perfect environment or
you know maybe they just are really that
good but yeah aeroponics
that's why i say it's the quickest way
if you can get it dialed in
if you if it's not dialed in and you're
having fluctuation
and everything it can be a headache and
make you feel like you don't know what
you're doing
so for sure well i think we covered a
lot in this episode
so let us know how can the listeners
find you and
what do you have upcoming in the future
oh man
uh well definitely check me out on
instagram
[Music]
troystrongs420 check out elevated.social
which is all things and like i say
culinarily derived and
that's kind of what i've been focused on
more recently i have
a couple of igtv serial series that
we're starting up as well
over there um obviously check me out on
canvas lifestyle tv
um as you guys already know because mr
growit is rapidly becoming a part of
that family as well
um so happy to have him there as well
and uh
yeah i mean i'm everywhere man shouldn't
be too hard to find my face especially
if i'm being requested on a channel that
uh you know i've only popped over to a
couple of times you know
so that that's what's up and i just
appreciate everybody and and be sure to
like and support this channel
comment engage that's you know how you
can support and and appreciate you as
well
mr growit thanks man well i will
definitely link your channel
and your instagram down in the comment
section below well in the comment
section
description section below i always say
that i always mess up
um and uh so yeah feel free to head on
over there give him a follow
subscribe to his channel and uh yeah
thanks again trey once again
for coming on to the show today
appreciate it oh yeah you guys
know what it is you know i sign off with
the stay lifted because that's what we
do
peace man
[Music]
you