i always dry out my soil
and i'll take it out of the bags i'll
throw it into like a big like uh
like tub wear tote you know like one of
the really big totes
i'll dump it in there and then i just
slide it under the exhausting
on the side of my tent so that it's just
constantly drying out
that soil most of the time i only feed
from the start of veg to the end of
flower a lot of times i only feed two or
three times
the whole grow i can't remember the last
time i fed in veg
you top it down too much you gave it too
much food it's too late already you
might as well just start over
you know with a non-stunted plant that
you haven't
run over with a truck calm down about
all the small stuff
as long as you stay out of the plant's
way it's going to be fine you're going
to get through it i promise
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into my talk channel
this is garden talk episode
five i actually had a viewer request to
put this onto
platforms that host podcasts so apple
podcast
spotify has podcasts google podcasts i'm
going to put this garden talk series
onto those platforms apparently if
you're just trying to listen on youtube
on mobile you can't actually just exit
out of the app or else the audio
completely cuts off so
having this garden talk series onto
other platforms will allow people to
tune in and be able to do other things
while they listen in got a great episode
for you today
a lot of you out there have actually
requested for this guest to come onto
the show he goes by
welcome to the grow tent he currently
has a little over 20 000
subscribers on youtube and we sat down
and had a great talk for
almost an hour here so i'm super excited
to bring you this episode today
before we get into the episode i would
like to give a shout out to our sponsor
our sponsor for today is happy hydro
happy hydro is an online gardening store
from buffalo new york
that has supported my channel for
several years now they take pride in
their product selection
their customer service and should most
orders the same day
they have low prices and shipping is
free if you're making a purchase over 25
dollars
so head on over to happy happyhydro.com
and i'll leave a link down in the
youtube video description
so if you're tuning in there you can
easily click on it alright now let's get
into the episode
welcome welcome to the grow tent how are
you doing today
good to be on here yeah thanks for
joining me i actually had
probably like eight or nine people
request you to come on here
really so i'm super pumped that you came
on here and i'm sure the audience you
know
particularly those people are going to
be really happy that you came on here to
join me today so
thanks for coming on yeah no problem i i
really love this community
it's uh as far as like you know
in youtube there can be a lot of toxic
communities i have not really found that
with this one of course you know you get
the occasional trolls or whatever
but for the most part this community is
it's just fantastic
you know i i love all the commenting the
people everybody's just trying to help
everybody out
trying to get their plants better i just
love it absolutely
and that's one of the reasons why i
started this show or
podcast is really to you know interview
growers from all over the world
and kind of understand how they do
things you know there are so many
different ways to grow this plant
and um you know your style is going to
be different from my style it's going to
be different from
you know the other person's style other
people's styles so um
you know being able to talk with you
today discuss
your growing practices you know other
people's we other people will be able to
listen to this and potentially gain some
ideas on what they can do to implement
into their gardens um so yeah it should
be pretty beneficial for
for a lot of people out there yeah i i
would say i have a a pretty different
style than most my main focus whenever
i'm growing
is and especially whenever i'm trying to
tell everybody else how to do it is
is strictly simplicity i try and
and get it down just to the just to the
bare knuckle part of it
because what i was figuring out whenever
i first started the channel is everybody
was
so stressed out in the emails
i was getting from them and i'm just
like look you gotta relax
i was like this is a slow process you
can't be in there
all hyped up and angry and stressed out
about this i said you're taking the
completely wrong approach
and that's when i was like all right if
i can just oversimplify this
it you know it'll help a ton of people
out which is one of the main you know
those main reason i wanted to start the
channel was just trying to
you know to share this plant in my
knowledge with it
as much as i could with everybody else
that makes sense makes sense
okay so uh maybe for the viewers who
don't know who you are can you just
you know tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into growing
all right yeah uh everybody run a
channel called welcome to the grow tent
and uh once again we do a simplistic
approach on growing
uh i have really really bad adhd
and anxiety type issues so
i never really liked buying
stuff that i didn't know where it came
from
what was done to it before i got it
uh one of my things with the adhd though
is i will run off on tangents so if i
start to do that you're gonna have to
you have to bring me back you have to
reel me back in
because uh it's like fireworks going off
in my head almost 24
7. so you'll hear me in the videos i
tell myself to calm down
focus because i just it's like a runaway
train that's
picking 15 different tracks at the same
time
so my main thing was with my anxiety is
i genuinely don't really like talking
about it but with my anxiety is
i never really liked just buying stuff
from people
you don't have any idea what they put in
it what they did to it
uh you know i'm not a big person that
that likes taking
medications either like you know dr
president prescribed like
xanax or whatever and it just would mess
me up for like
11 or 12 hours at a time
and i i felt like my head was up in the
clouds and
somebody else was doing stuff down here
on the ground
and i didn't like it this on the other
hand
i i can grow it i know what's been in it
the whole time because
i'm the one that did it i just liked
that approach to it
and you know i really like all you know
the different strains and everything if
this one's a little bit
you know too head rushy or to something
i can switch to a different strain
and find you know kind of like that
perfect balance
for me that was my that's my favorite
part about that's why i got into growing
it
the control and then because you could
buy something from somebody it doesn't
mean that's what it is
they can tell you whatever you want but
that doesn't mean that's what you're
getting
now i have the control i can do it all
myself
i'm a big control freak basically what
it boiled down to
that makes sense makes sense cool um so
yeah everybody
you know everybody has their own goals
when it comes to growing right
some people go for yield some people go
for efficiency you had mentioned
simplicity
was a big thing on your end some people
in beginners and they just want to get
to their first grow and and have healthy
plants
you know besides the simplicity thing
which you already mentioned do you have
any other
goals in mind you do chase after a high
yield or
i i really don't because it's not like
i'm selling or anything i'm growing for
me
the yield i've found just comes
with with the more you stay out of the
plant's way
the less i like to say the less you do
the more you get
and the the less you get out of its way
the less you heard it
the yield just comes the yield will come
uh i grow more than i could ever hope to
smoke
you know it it says i'm not selling it
and it's just for me
you know every time i pull down the five
by five it's two pounds
and i run perpetual growth so it's
constantly
until i got my trimming machine it was a
nightmare of trimming
all day all night just constant trim
jail
all the freaking time so but it's
it i don't ever chase the yield i find
that
usually by chasing something you get the
opposite
so i like to just you know natural
simplistic ways
that stuff will all come and i i really
don't like how the new people
they're so hard on themselves whenever
they're starting out
you know that another big thing i get
with my emails is they're
like i'm it you know week three of this
or week two of that
my plants don't look anything like you
know what i'm seeing on the internet
here or this guy here
i'm like these guys have been doing this
forever they have so much more
practice than you they know what they're
looking for
they know what their plant needs it's a
repetitive process
don't get so down on yourself you know
people they mess up the first time then
they quit and sell all their stuff
be patient calm down relax
it'll be all right right yeah i'm in the
same
same boat as you i just grow for myself
i don't sell the dispensaries i'm not a
caregiver or anything like that
um i actually i live in a state where
i'm allowed to gift
in the bill that actually says you're
allowed to gift it and so i actually had
a friend in town yesterday
and he came into town and i had a nice
jar for him
and he was his eyes lit up and he was
super pumped
super pumped so i love to be able to do
that and um
yeah i just gift more and more that
would be awesome i've had a bunch of
people
because just from you know they'll pick
up cues here and there and they figure
out where i'm at
and uh they've had a bunch of people
trying to to get me to do the
the caregiving you know asked me to be
the caregiver
and i was like man if i had if i had
more time i was like but everything's so
packed and everything in here already i
guess
i guess i could start to do it and just
not even grow them plants just give them
you know i got so much excess it's not
even funny so i mean i guess i could but
i just i never have taken on that
responsibility of being a caregiver
for somebody else yet i probably should
but i just haven't because we don't have
that gift thing here i can't just
give people gift people stuff that would
be awesome though
yeah yeah for sure so let's let's uh
let's talk about your
uh uh your current growth setup okay
so can you tell me a little bit about
your setup like you know what size grow
space
lighting some of the equipment you have
so on and so forth yeah this is going to
be a long part of the conversation
i have a a dedicated room
in my unfinished basement that i had
built just for growing
so everything runs off its own has its
own breaker each tent has its own
breaker set up
everything i have a 14 by 16 room
that i had finished in my basement it's
all insulated drywall you know offended
nice
it's a nice room i never finished the
drywall but it is mudded and taped
and uh but i have four stations i have a
germination station you know monte dome
with a little two foot t5 over it
uh i have two veg areas which are
two by four tents which will be coming
down soon because i have some three by
fives that i'm going to be putting up
that uh a new sponsor sent me so i'm
gonna have to take down my old two by
fours
and then i have a 555
gorilla tint that actually some of my
awesome patreon members
sent to me because they were tired to
hear me complain about my old tent
which was a 5x5 it was a 555 and it had
one entrance just the front
well i like to scrog plants so only
being
i would have to lay down on the ground
and slide
under the the canopy to work on the
plants in the back it was a huge pain in
the butt
well i guess my patreons got so tired of
hearing me complain about this one
entrance
you know five by five is a decent sized
tent that's 25 square feet
oh yeah of of canopy
well my tents fill out i fill them out
side to side front to back
the whole thing there's no open space in
my tents whenever i'm in flower
so there was no other option except
laying on the ground
like a freaking snake and charming my
way back through the
through the buckets to get to the back
and i just got so sick of it and they're
awesome they sent me a gorilla tent
which now opens the whole
you know the whole thing opens like 180
degrees it's like a dream working in
there now
but uh yeah that's pretty much the
extent the two by fours will be coming
down
and uh uh light rail uh the company
light rail they just sent me uh their
tents
with their light rail system so i'll be
uh doing those in the future grow series
uh as far as lights go i used to be
a huge hugely against led lights
and it really wasn't about the light it
was mainly about some of the
information that was out there on them
you know people just put them too close
and they're
miniaturizing miniaturizing their plants
and stuff like that but i have been
growing with them lately
they work fantastic they work great i'm
i'm actually pretty in love with them
now
um i have a 16 bulb t5
from bad boy or quantum whatever it used
to be called they're both out of
business now whatever it is
and i actually have that in my 5x5
because a 16 bulb t5 is freaking
gigantic
you know it's like a little over four by
four
in area just by itself but i have that
in there
is that for veg only or do you flower
like that too flower with it wow
i was flowering with it just for content
to show people that
it doesn't matter you know what light
you got you can do
whatever you want with it yeah and i've
got a really good video it's
uh two pounds of plant finished dried
plant
from t5 from fluorescent lights is what
it's called
and i just kind of wanted to show people
that you know whatever you had
you could finish runs with
and uh that was that was kind of the the
reason that i bought that giant
that giant t5 light and for new people i
like to tell them to get
t5s they are the most forgiving light
that you could that you could be under
and uh
will it cost you some end yield of
course of course
t5 spreads it out but at the same time
if
if you're burning your plants up it
doesn't matter how nice of a light you
have
if you're killing your stuff by blasting
it with too much light too soon it
doesn't matter what you have
you're killing your plant the equipment
it doesn't matter anymore
so you know i just kind of but i grow
with t5s
leds i don't care i'll grow with
anything i don't i'm not i don't i'm not
picky
whatever i have if that's what that they
want me to grow with i'll put that in
the tent
i can i can figure it out i like how you
mentioned that you do it for content
because
that you know a lot of a lot of viewers
don't really realize
that some of us content creators will do
certain things specifically for
content you know so you yeah exactly
like with like co2
i don't hardly ever run co2 but uh like
tnb they had contacted me in the past
just because i already can grow the
plants will produce so much already when
i add co2 to it it just ups my yield
and i have i don't need it you know i
just don't need the extra but
you know if somebody's gonna send me
stuff and and pay me i'll put it in the
tent
but i don't i don't need the co2 because
i already get enough yep but you know
contents content i like trying to try
and be as honest as possible
whenever i'm on that whenever i'm
whenever i'm on stream i figure there's
enough
uh you know lying on on videos already
not just in this
in any that's it's anywhere so i try to
be
upfront and honest with people i don't
like to tell people my plants
are a young age when they're actually
way older
i don't like to do any of that i'd like
you know if they they're three weeks
they're three weeks if they're nine
weeks
they're nine weeks you know i just try
and be honest and up front with
everybody and have a good time
yeah makes sense now what about some
some other equipment so maybe um you
know
how many oscillating fans are you
running inline fans you have to run a
dehumidifier a humidifier
uh with the uh let's see on the big
tent obviously it's gonna have way more
fans than the littler tents on the big
tent i have uh
two six inch fans that sit at the top
just kind of keep some
air circulation up there and i have an
ac infiniti
uh the six series cloud line whatever
the one with the controller is
nice i think that's the s series maybe
well there's the t6 i believe is the one
with the controller okay then it's the
t-series s-series is the manual one i
guess
so it's the t-series with the controller
and i got that up there
i tell you what i didn't even put the
pre-filter on it because the filter
looks so freaking cool you know they're
black and chrome i
couldn't bring myself to put i was like
this is going to shorten the life but i
was like this thing looks so cool i
can't cover it
right it's all black and chrome looking
on my pants
it's beautiful but i got two fans you
know two like six inch hurricane fans
sitting up top just attached
just pushing the air you know
circulating some air i don't like dead
space air i have a tower fan
i think a tower fan is probably my
favorite fan
for groves i put them right down there
in the canopy
it has a blade of air that as the plant
gets taller you know that air
circulation
it stays just it has that straight
column of air
that constantly goes through the canopy
i think a tower fan is probably my
favorite of all the fans and then i have
like a 12 inch fan that just stays
underneath the canopy
and just rotates around down by the pots
i don't want stale stagnant air
and water anywhere together so i just
want constant air circulation
um as far as relative humidity this is
where a lot of people on youtube yell at
me i just don't
i don't ever you know in the summertime
it's way different than in the winter
time
and i don't like adding uh humidifiers
or dehumidifiers or anything
unless i'm drying if i'm drying and
curing it's really the only time i pay
attention to
relative humidity i get a lot of flack
on that in my comment section
there's a couple videos where i'm taking
hammers and just blasting apart
high grow meters i'm like you just don't
don't even worry about it unless you've
got problems
you're fine you know so i get a lot of
flack on that but once again
we're bringing it back to simplicity you
know they get so stressed everybody gets
so stressed out
about oh well my room's only 60
relative humidity and they were trying
to get to 40 percent
stop stressing out about it relax is it
the end of the world do you have mold
problems you got any kind of problem no
all right don't worry about it
you got problems you have problems
showing up okay now we can worry about
it
you know i just i try and de-stress
every situation that i can and simplify
it as much as i can
can that stuff help you in the future
yeah but when you're starting out
you know relax calm down
keep it simple simple man i try to do
the kiss mess
kiss method with everything nice
now you do grow in soil coco coir
hydroponics
i am strictly soil uh what i like to
tell everybody
whenever because i do focus on like
brand brand new people is who my channel
is mainly focused at
it's it's less steps that you have to do
because
i transplant all the time so every time
i tell people every time you transplant
you're feeding the plants again so if if
i can get you
to transplant your plants appropriately
most of the time i only feed from the
start of veg to the end of flower
a lot of times i only feed two or three
times the whole grow
i can't remember the last time i fed in
veg they it
ro water and cal mag is basically what
they get
all of veg and then whenever i
transplant them into flour into their
final pots
i'll go from like so i started in veg
and happy frog and then whenever i go to
[Music]
flower i'll put them in to ocean forest
and i just let that run out usually it
lasts till about week
three of flower before i start to see my
runoff dropping down
and then i'll start feeding them well if
i've made it to week three of flour and
i cut off nutrients at week six of flour
and then i'd let them just coast out on
what's in the what's in the leftover in
the pot
and you know let them fade out naturally
it's
one less thing that new growers have to
concern themselves with
is the nutrients because the amount of
questions i get
on nutrient schedules oh my goodness
i'm like listen i can help you avoid all
of it
i'm gonna let just just transplant
constantly
into you know as soon as you outgrow
your pot put it into a new one
that's break you've just fed it again
you don't have to concern you don't have
to get so
worked up you know i did a video where
i'm taking all the nutrients i'm just
throwing them off the table into a trash
can i'm like hey
just you can if i can tell you a way to
eliminate
30 of your headache why wouldn't you
take it
because it's gonna come out great now
can you add stuff in there
as long as you're not burning your stuff
up with too many nutrients
yeah can it will help of course but
whenever you're brand new
the less steps you got to do is the less
often you know it's the less chance you
have to mess one of them up
that's it you know simplicity once again
that makes sense
yeah so uh happy frog in the beginning
and then you'll eventually work your way
into ocean forest
uh one thing that was interesting about
that is that you said you get all the
way up into week
three of flour so my question for you
now is
what size grow pots are you using like
um i do transplant multiple times you
start in like a solo cup then go to like
a one gallon then to
like a five gallon or seven gallon or
what what are you using for yeah
i actually start in root riot plugs okay
whenever they're in the germination dome
uh and then i'll move into solo cups
after like three weeks in the queue i'll
move them into solo cups
and then i i hate the solo cup stage i
over water them i can never get the
feeling right it seems like
i'm constantly messing up in the solo
cup stage so i want to keep them in the
solo cup stage for like a week or two
and then i'll just transplant them right
into a one gallon pot once i'm in the
one gallon
i feel at home i'm good i know my
weights i can pick them up i know when
to water
i know how long they i know what they
play i know what they need when it's
once they hit one gallon i'm smooth
sailing once i get them out of the
out of the dome out of the solo cups and
into the one gallons and a weight just
drops off the back of my shoulders once
i'm out of those terrible solo cups
but i'll go from the one gallon and then
depending on where i'm going to flower
them out because some sponsors
like uh you know want me to flower veg
and flower
in their tent so i can't always come out
of the two by four sometimes i have to
stay in
the two by four four veg and for flour
so that's going to determine what size
pots i'm going to be in
and it's also going to depend on the
number of plants i'm running
if i'm running if i'm in a two by four
and i'm running
you know three to five plants i'm only
going to put them in
in three gallon pots if i'm running you
know two plants or one plant i will
transition from a one to a three to a
five
and i don't ever go over five gallons
even if i'm in the even if i'm in the
big one
five gallons is a is a ton of soil could
i step it up maybe
to a seven i just don't want to deal
with it
i don't want to deal with that much soil
you know the bigger pots
bigger water you know it's more water
it's just it's just more and more more
i dislike more i want less less less
whenever i'm doing something
that makes sense so i assume that uh
well i shouldn't assume but
um are you in plastic containers all the
way through or you is your final
container like a fabric pot or whatever
you know
it actually depends on what i have if i
have fabric pots
i put them in fabric pots i'm not once
again i'm not
i don't really doesn't bother me either
way i'll do
i'll do plastic one gallons plastic
three fab i prefer
fabric but if i don't happen to have any
which happens to me quite often actually
the plastic pots you know rinse out and
you can use them again
with the fabric pots i found a really
simple way to to get them out of there
is i just
razor knife around the edge of the thing
and just peel it off like a banana
because the roots grow into it so much
it can make it a pain in the butt
but the bigger plants like with like if
you're in a three gallon or something
the last thing you want to do is be
trying to peel that thing off you know
pull that
get that thing out of there with the
roots all grown into it we're going from
a three to a five
uh so for my final i usually try and be
in a fabric but if i don't have one
i don't really it doesn't bother me
either way so
i do prefer the fabric though
because like whenever you pull one out
of a fabric pot
you don't have the coiling of the roots
around there because they grow they hit
the edge of the pot
and then they air prune themselves and
then they grow out differently
when you're in the plastic and you pull
them out it looks so much
cooler because you pull it out you got
just the
roots everywhere it looks fantastic you
pull them out of the
fabric and it's just like a big bundle
of dirt
mess yep yep but it does it looks way
cooler coming out of the plastic but i
don't i mean i don't really care either
way i'll
i'll do it in both yeah i'm the same way
i use both plastic
and uh fabric pots whatever whatever i
kind of have on hand or feel like using
for that grow and yeah like i mentioned
before it's for content right if i'm
doing the same thing over and over and
over again and all my videos well then
people are getting bored of my content
and click off so trying new things using
new methods
just to show the audience that it can be
done so many different ways so yeah
i mean like i usually i'm always like
scrog the plants out that kind of stuff
uh i did a video series where it was uh
i called it the punji pit of death
series it was all the bamboo stakes
i didn't use the scrog and i just i
tried to control them and hold them all
up with the stakes i hated it
but you know i i like scrogging my
plants out i like that
once again the level of control i get
from it
is uh i find it way more to my liking
than with the punji pits it's just
they're a lot harder to control without
the scrog there to keep everybody tied
down
because i like uniformity i like the
control of it i like everybody
even and flat across my grill
it definitely helps maintain an even
canopy when you're bending those
branches down you just have that flat
net to kind of tuck things up here and
stuff for sure i love it
i think a lot of people the downside
they say is like okay now what do you do
you have to like crawl
under in order to kind of water the
plants behind so it does have like a
downside on that avenue right it does i
actually uh whenever i had the tent with
only the
with only the one entrance uh i had a
system of
metal poles that i would hook onto my
water jug and i would just slide the
poles through the
through the canopy to the back ones and
water it those days are over
the uh my you know my gorilla tint opens
completely up so i can get to the plant
i mean it literally the
it peels to 180 degrees and just the
back wall is the only one that stays up
it's the
most fantastic thing not like a little
door that opens the whole tent just
peels off the whole sides
it's fantastic it's worth every penny
uh so you mentioned watering what type
of water do you use use
reverse osmosis tap water well water
distilled
my tap water here before my water
softener is 430 ppm yeah mine is 485
yeah yeah after the water softener it's
almost a thousand
so mine i i was using just gallons of
distilled water
and uh and i was there's just so many
trips
to the grocery store getting gallons of
water i just broke down and bought an
ro machine once again best money i've
ever i don't like to spend
crazy amounts of money on everything
because i like to try and keep it simple
of course
but there's some things when you're
growing like that tent
uh that are worth every single penny
there are some things that you just need
like buying a proper ph and ppm pin
just do it you don't want to be
constantly messing with stuff wondering
if it's right
or not there's certain areas just spend
the money
it's worth it yeah i agree i have one of
those ro systems underneath my kitchen
and uh you know not only use it for
drinking water clean drinking water
you know i don't have to buy a bottled
waters anymore so i saved money there i
did the savings
the calculation just calculating what i
would consume in bottled water versus
my ro system i spent about 250 dollars
per year on this system right there all
right yeah exactly right ro system i
think was like 175 or something like
that so
that's why one year it's an expensive
piece
and whenever i'm talking to new growers
uh it's an expensive because they when
they think of spending money they want
to spend it on their life
and i'm like i'm telling you this ro
machine
they're worth every penny i don't care
you know whichever one you want to get
they're fantastic i like once again the
control
it brings me i know exactly what that
plant is getting so let's say you've had
300 ppm or 250 ppm from your tap water
what is it
i mean it's probably calcium magnesium
but you don't know there's a lot of
fluoride or whatever else in there too
i just like knowing exactly what i'm
giving my plant
i think they're happier because of it
yep yeah i agree
i can build my nutrient profile not
whoever
so what do you use for nutrients uh you
know
basically whatever's on on sale but it's
mainly just
general hydroponics three-part okay
that's what i started with i know it
really well but
once again if you know if a
of a place came on board said we want
you to use our nutrients
you know i figured out it's not a big
deal a nutrient profile is a nutrient
profile give me a week with it i'll have
it i'll have it squared away
now you following the general
hydroponics nutrient schedule that they
put out on their website or do you uh do
a half dose or what do you do for that
depends if i'm growing autoflowers
i don't give them full doses of anything
ever
i'm 50 to 20 i'm 25 when they're when
they're little and i'm 50
when they're older and i don't feed them
every week
because once again i'm in soil i don't i
don't need to
uh with the with my photo periods i do
grow them rather big healthy plants
i'll follow it if i'm feeding that week
i'll just follow whatever the
whatever their chart says and then uh if
i need to add
you know add to something else or mix it
up a little bit i will but generally
once again i keep it simple got it did
you monitor
like the ph and the ppm or ec values at
all or
i i'm super strict on my ppms i don't
ever like feeding more than
if my bigger plants more than like 600
650 at a time
i found that whenever i go over that
i'll start to get my you know the tips
my leaves will start to turn that brown
and start to get a little nutrient burn
uh but then again it's you know
feeding is just it's not something i do
a lot of you know i have
bottles of nutrients that i've had for a
year or two they'll start to crystallize
on the bottom before i
get through the if i buy the big bottles
they'll start to crystallize on the
bottom before i even get through it
just because i you know growing in soil
you just it's a step that
you don't have to pay that much
attention to because you're not feeding
a ton
um the main things i really like is i
i constantly give microbes my
mycorrhizae
i will go through uh a bunch of this
stuff
you're doing a soil drench with the
mycorrhizae are you uh just drinking
sprinkling on the roots uh well i do
both both i do both like whenever i
transplant
i'll sprinkle it on there i'll maybe
throw some granular version
in the in the pot whenever i transplant
or
and then any time i'm watering i feed
the i give them mycorrhizae every two
weeks
from the from the start till week six of
flour
every two weeks they get more drenched
mycorrhizae and then i just throw some
like floral blend or some kind of like
you know plant food you know or some
kind of food for them to eat
maybe uh the occasional blackstrap
molasses you know something to keep them
happy
and you know just keep it simple what do
you use for um
do you use a particular brand of
mycorrhizae or just whatever you have on
hand or what uh you know it's great
white
great mainly that's pretty much what
every all the growth stores around here
have i'm pretty lucky i have like seven
grow stores within a 40-minute drive of
me
it's been pretty fantastic since the uh
since our state went legal the amount of
gross stores it used to be
i had to just order it and now they're
they're freaking everywhere
and they're you know the grow stores are
a little bit more expensive but i
happily
go to them i gotta you know i like
supporting the business
and in local brick and mortar shops so
i happily go into all of them and buy
different stuff
at different ones but it's mainly great
white you know
a little black strap and some in some
general hydroponics three part
uh what i use the most of it's probably
a cal mag bottle
or the and then towards the end of
flower mag sulfur i burned through that
stuff
so fast you know it it goes through 100
times the rate i use
the regular npk stuff now for the
blackstrap molasses
um what do you use what do you do for
like a dosage per
gallon of water for example i you know i
just get it i just pour some in
okay i can measure it i just get a
couple glug glugs and call it a day
i'm not you know big on you know being
super strict with that kind of stuff
because yep
it's not who cares if you give it a
little bit too much you know so the the
microbes to get a little bit extra fat
yeah and then just kind of go back to
the the ppm
um you mentioned 600 ppm is that
going in and do you measure the runoff
ppm as well or
yeah i measure both because i like to
see where my plants are at
if you know if you've got if your plants
are getting starting to get too low
usually
any time when i'm in flower because i
don't really pay attention to it when
i'm in veg because they're constantly
getting transplanted
anytime i'm in flower and i see my
runoff start to dip below like 800
i know it's time to feed if they're up
anywhere
over 1200 1300 i just let it go until i
say my
my runoff start to drop then i feed them
which isn't very often
so because i transplant a lot got it so
you do a runoff test you don't do like a
slurry
test at all no man i literally just
stick my ppm pin down into the whatever
my runoff water is
and see where i'm at it's worked good
for me so far
i don't uh i don't i don't get too
complicated with it
which ppm pen do you use just a cheap
one off amazon or what
uh you know i have one on my website i
don't actually know the brand it's all
you can find it at uh
welcome to thegrowtant.com oh okay cool
and then uh ph do you monitor the ph
going in or run off or this is another
thing i get yelled at
about uh i'm not very strict with my ppm
i'm in soil i have i you know i did a
couple of ph
you know um as long as it's above
5.0 and below 7.0
i give it to the plants what i found was
it didn't matter i edited it all at 6.9
for like a month
and my runoff would still come out at
like
5.8 6.1
whatever i'm just not that strict with
it it's one of the things i get yelled
about
in the comments so often they're like oh
you got to be between
6.1 and 6.3 that's the golden spot
am i great man if i'm not saying don't
if you want to be
that strict with it what do i care i'm
just
showing you what how i do it if i'm
above if i'm at 5.1 i feed it
if i'm at 6.9 i feed it
you know i pour it in there it's just
not something i
you know i stress too much over
i don't want to be adding i'm like up
i'm adding up to
put some ph up in it i went over 6.3 now
i got to put some ph down
in it and i'll put some alkaline in the
i don't wanna you know
i'll leave all that rollercoaster stuff
alone i got tired of dumping out buckets
of water
i just uh you know i don't concern
myself too much with it if i'm into my
range
that i like then i give it to it if not
then
you know then i'll add some stuff in
there
yeah particularly for growing in in fox
farm soil uh
you know one thing i noticed is that a
lot of these bags are coming in
low they're coming in at like five point
something ph
yeah yeah you know how many people work
i've had them in like mid force wow
yeah um and so me personally i usually
just feed in at like 6.5 6.8
ph and then it'll slowly drift up over
time and of course things like the
microbes will adjust
the ph and the medium as well over time
but that's interesting that you
will feed in uh in within you know 5.0
to 6.0 ph
because um you know typically that's
said to be a little bit too low when
growing in soil but
um you know that you're having success
with that and i've actually heard about
other people doing that as well with
with a lot of success
yeah you know i've i've done it both
ways and i've
i've done it where i went in at 6.1 to
6.4
you know constantly super was super
strict with it
i never noticed an end yield difference
and i was like well let's try it the
other way and then i did grows where i
only came in at like 5.1 to 5.3
you know i was super strict with it down
low and i just
i didn't notice a difference the only
thing i noticed was
that what the soil would do with the
runoff
would change just a little bit you know
they kind of make their own environment
and they make it the way they want it
and they're happy as long as you don't
you know
fry them with like a with like a 4.0 or
something that gets everybody angry with
you
because i did try that i was like well
how low can i go there is a limit
stay out of the force yeah yeah they
were not happy
right um okay so let's uh how about
temperature what temperature you usually
aim for
if i'm comfortable in there i'm fine
with it
if you know 70s 80s you know
whatever you know once again it's not a
thing i'm terribly strict with
i've done that video where i'm smashing
the high grow meter up i'm like if it's
too hot for me in here i don't want to
be in here
so i stay out of it just keep them
comfortable
that's what i like to say if they're
coming if i can be comfortable in there
they're comfortable
and we're fine because uh once again the
emails that i get with people with the
the ph are you know phs in there but the
relative humidity and the temp and
they're freaking out they're putting
heaters in there and then running air
conditioners in the daytime and heaters
at night i'm like
unless you live in some kind of crazy
climate don't worry about it
you know stop stressing so much about it
i'll get you there to the end yield
just relax calm down
we can get through this i promise i live
in a desert climate so like summertime
for example i have to actually implement
a um
air conditioner it's so expensive and
actually try to take off like
um july and august potentially just try
to like not grow
just because it's just so much easier so
much less money you know spending on
electricity consumption yeah um but uh
but yeah i do regulate i aim for about
leaf surface temperatures kind of what i
read to be ideal
now of course the plant is going to grow
in a different range than that some can
actually take a little bit
more than that yeah some can take
less than that just fine i do have a
heater in my
grow space i don't like to go below like
60 uh
fahrenheit and even in the 60s i see
like some um
you know the the purpling streaks in the
stems for for
in the low 60s fahrenheit yeah so i i do
regulate
on that avenue but um but yeah a perfect
example
about how you can get away with not
doing uh
those things you know the plant will
still grow yeah it's still gonna grow
just stay out of its way
you know if you're not if you're not
blasting it with too many nutrients
smoking it with you know you know
flipping on the lights to full power
when the plant's still little
and you know watering just soaking it
down with water every single day
you'd be surprised how well they'll just
keep going yep
yeah whereas now can you eventually
up your yield by by honing in on some of
these things more
of course but once again my channel is
focused at
very beginners where i'm just trying to
get them through i'm trying to get them
through
they've been getting maybe five to ten
percent of what their plants
could yield and if i can bump you from
five to ten percent up to seventy
percent i've never had a single person
that was mad at me
yeah i've mentioned certain humidity
levels on my channel in the past
and um you know i'm just like you where
it's kind of just a general range for
beginners because i do have a lot of
people that are following what i do
and um one of the things that a lot of
people are are shifting towards
is vpd right so i'm not sure how much
you know about vpd
but vpd is a differential scientifically
proven
method for um humidity and uh
typically that calls for a higher
humidity and i've gotten flack on my
channel in the past where i had said
like
i can't entirely recommend that people
chase after
vpd because it does call for high
humidity in some instances and if you
don't have that air circulation going on
if you have stagnant air if a fair
fan dies overnight like it's happened to
me you can get powdery mildew
very easily yeah bud rot and completely
ruin your your crop if
you have mold in your buds for example
and that's what happened to me so
that's kind of my point with it is don't
chase vpd whenever you're a beginner
once again i'm speaking to beginners if
you've been growing for 10 years
keep doing what you're doing but if
you're a beginner
mold's going to ruin your grow way
faster
than vpd because if you're a beginner
most likely
you're going to over water your plants
everybody does it you can't really
i don't know everybody just does it but
powdery mildew
is going to ruin your entire garden way
faster than if you're
not paying attention to keeping your vpd
perfect
i get yelled at a ton about that on my
uh i generally don't even talk about it
uh so co2 uh you think you mentioned
earlier that you don't do any
type of co2 you don't do anything it
makes
it it ups my yield by about 15 to 20
percent
and i already get too much to begin with
so what am i gonna do with an extra you
know four or five ounces
whenever i'm having trouble getting
through the two pounds i just cut down
anyway
so i i generally don't run it if a
sponsor sends it in there or if i want
to show people
the kind of the benefits of adding it in
the videos then i'll put it in there but
other than that
not really got it now what about plant
training you had mentioned you you like
to do a trellis nat
uh you use steak sometimes do you do any
you know low stress training
super cropping um what do you do for a
train plant training
i am well scrog whenever they go into
flower but my main
plant training techniques is topping
filming and super cropping that is
my bread and butter that's where i
that's where i get all my plant training
from
i'm just i'm not a big fan of uh the
wire ties and stuff
i found with with topping my plants uh
they grow so many branches so fast i
didn't really want to have like
30 wire ties running around the plant
just because
the plants will branch out so fast so
fast
so i'm mainly just topping and super
cropping i'll top the plants super crop
the top of the
top half of the plant down to let the
the lower half catch up
and usually after a few weeks you know
two or three weeks of that they're ready
to flip the flower anyway so
uh now what about i know actually i
didn't i don't know this but
um i think you're primarily indoors
you're only growing indoors you don't
grow
yeah they don't let me grow outdoors
here it's funny they're like if you want
to grow outdoors you have to build a
building
and to grow outdoors i'm like well
that's called indoors and i already have
it
um so so indoors let's talk about ipm
um now indoors we have the luxury of of
not having to do
as much yeah we can kind of get away
with doing doing a little bit less when
it comes to ipm
do you do anything in particular to
prevent pests
uh yeah i do actually a couple things
the the main thing is i
always dry out my soil whenever i get my
soil out of the bags
if i don't dry it out there's i've got
videos of it i'll take it and i'll get
it out of the bags is the first thing i
do because those bags hold in moisture
and i'll take it out of the bags i'll
throw it into like a big like uh
like tub wear tote you know like one of
the really big totes
i'll dump it in there and then i just
slide it under the exhausting
on the side of my tent so that it's just
constantly drying out
that soil and when that soil gets too
too dry anything that was like fungus
gnats or anything were in there
they lose their food source so they
either die or leave
so that's the first thing i do is i just
air out the soil
you know every day every couple days
i'll go in there and i'll stir it up
under the vent big big tip here pull it
out from under the vent before you start
stirring it up
otherwise you get giant clouds of soil
in your face
so pull it out i stir it up mix the wet
stuff back up to the top
and i slide it back under there i let it
i let my
prep like that go for about a week so
before i know i'm gonna
transplant i'll i'll get my soil i'll
get my
my new soil and i'll put in those totes
and start drying it out
the next thing and pretty much the only
other thing i do is i
i get i get yelled at about the way i
say this word because i mess it up every
single time
diatomaceous earth diatomaceous earth
yeah yeah uh it's like
adding razor wire into your into your
soil so after i transplant i top dress
with the diatomaceous earth and uh i
don't
i think over watering is what leads to a
lot of your problems with with bugs and
stuff like that
and i don't ever over water unless i'm
in solo cups
uh then i still over water and uh
because i just hate them
with the diatomaceous earth in there and
uh just
keeping big green healthy plants knock
on wood i've
been i've never had a a problem since i
started doing those just those two
simple things wow yeah i just actually
got some diatomaceous earth
for the first time i've never used it
before so i'm gonna have to potentially
use
uh steal your best practice there and
literally the best thing ever
yeah i do it i do it in my live stream
so i do a lot of my transplanting videos
just on
on my like on like a live stream and
everybody was like what is that yellow
bag
that you have sitting next that you're
mixing in because i transplant the you
know the plant into the pot
and then uh they're like how much you
use that's like i don't know
can i just grab a handful of it and
sprinkle it all around the pot and then
top dress it in i'm like that much i was
like i don't measure it i just throw it
in there
it's not like it's gonna hurt anything
but it's literally like
adding razor wire into your soil
and like if i have a time where i've
i've been slacking in the garden and i
haven't had time to dry my soil out
i actually just take a bunch of handfuls
of it throw it in the tote and just mix
it throughout
all the soil not just top dress with it
so i use it pretty much you know
anytime i'm i've got new soil got it but
it's really interesting
it's really interesting that you dry out
your soil like that um
you know it's a pretty good tip uh you
know i
some of these bags of soils come with
with pests right
almost all of them almost all right
because i grow
i grow in fox armor as well and um it's
it's kind of a hit or miss for me
some bags like i'll plant in and then
i'll be growing the plant all of a
sudden fungus gnats
start to arise so i'll have the yellow
sticky traps and then i'll dry out the
soil while
you know while the plant is growing i'll
just dry it out yeah you know won't
water the plant to the point where it's
kind of underwatered and then
water the plant and then um you know
pretty much off of like
one drying out yeah they'll be pretty
much gone yeah correct they will leave
instantaneously the second they lose
their food source
with drying out and if you dry them out
too much all the eggs and stuff die so
if you dry them out just one time
they leave now if you start over
watering again
they're gonna you know more will come
back i promise you they will find out
they will they can smell that you know
algae and stuff that's growing in your
in your soil and they will come back
but just by drying it out
i've found that i've eliminated the
problem because there's been times where
you know i watered one time two days
later i had fungus gnats come out of the
dang thing i'm like
i'm like if they're already in the bags
i'm like there's
no other explanation and once i figured
that out
it made the world of difference i
haven't bought a sticky trap in
years hmm yeah do you do any sprays
for ipm or not i have a bottle of
sns-209 that i opened up one time
whenever i was
uh whenever i first started growing and
since i've started drying the soil out
and adding the diatomaceous
earth got it i got it since i added the
diatomaceous earth uh
i just call it de usually on the stream
so i don't get yelled at about the way i
pronounce it
uh since i did that that bottle of
sns-209 just kind of
sits on the shelf but another thing is i
don't bring anybody's clones into my
garden
i think that's the biggest transfer of
bugs that people get and once they get
into your house it's almost impossible
i'll spray the whole house down with
azamax i don't care
what i don't ever bring anybody's clones
into my garden there's nothing but i
don't ever hear nothing but horror
stories from that like oh yeah i
wouldn't got these clones and now i have
spider mites
everywhere i'll burn the house down if i
ever get if i get spider mites i don't
want nothing to do with it
that's funny yeah a lot of people don't
uh realize how well
it how well it works to just keep things
kind of clean so for me personally uh
between grows i'll literally wipe
everything down with like a
bleach cleaning yeah i do bleach
solution and i i
every tint every light every fixture
every chord
i'm very once again i'm in my control in
uh
adhd my adhd pays off in this part of my
thing because i'll sit there and i
detail orient clean
everything in between grows now while
i'm growing
i do get messy through the week because
you know working
regular full-time job coming up with
content
shooting it editing it and then like you
know i have my family also
it's you know it gets hectic through the
week and then sundays i spend cleaning
up
nice i get a couple more questions for
you before you end this
so um new growers you work with a lot of
new growers
primarily your new your channel really
focuses on the beginner
yeah what advice do you have for someone
who is just starting to grow for the
first time
calm down don't spend a ton of money
you on the certain things you can but
don't spend a ton of money right off the
bat
so you kind of figure out if this is for
you know for you you don't need to go
out and buy a two thousand dollar
light right away calm down about all the
small stuff
as long as you stay out of the plant's
way it's gonna be fine you're gonna get
through it i promise
and if you ever run into any problems i
put my email up in all my videos
i get about a thousand emails a day as
anybody can imagine
anybody that puts their email up in
every video on the internet
not all of them nice but most of them
the majority of them are nice
uh and i try and work through them as
much as i can
but uh if i don't respond to you in a
few days
send it again because it's been buried
but uh just relax would be my biggest
thing
don't you don't need to be in your tent
ten times a day
leave it alone i tell it to say that all
my my videos all the time i said leave
it alone
it doesn't need you on top of it
constantly messing with it
all day long just relax
leave it in there pretend it's a fern
in your kitchen how often do you pay
attention to it you don't you're like oh
it's getting kind of droopy
i need to i need to do something with it
now you got to do a little bit more than
that but i'm just you know
i'm just telling you you know just leave
it leave the heck alone
it's a plant but do what it's going to
do right
yeah just kind of relax and you're going
to be able to start to read
what the plant needs i would rather have
you do way too
less than way too much because it's way
easier to fix way too less
than it is to fix weight too much you
know once you you know
you top it down too much you gave it too
much food it's too late already you
might as well just start over
you know with a non-stunted plant that
you haven't
run over with a truck yeah i always i
always chuckle a little bit i i have a
forum on my website mr growth.com
forum and i have people you know freely
post up questions they have or grow
journals and so on and so forth and um
there's been times where people have
commented they've just you know their
seedling just sprouted
and they get panicky so quickly they're
like oh
last hour you know my leaves were at a
90 degree angle
and now this there it adjusted 30
degrees and
i don't know what's going on with this
what's the problem
don't look don't even look at it don't
even look at it
leave it alone just my biggest thing is
that first week i don't even open the
dome
i i leave the dome on and i tell
everybody i go don't open
it for till the next week as soon as
they pop the ground pop out of ground
that's day one of your seedling stage
now and and just leave it alone just
don't even open
the dome you keep the dome on there
you're not gonna have to water it they
don't need anything
from you because what's going to happen
is you're going to touch it and you're
going to break it
because you've got giant man hands and
you're going to snap that little thing
and you're going to hurt it there's
nothing you can do to it that it can't
figure out how to do on its own
just leave it alone so you mentioned
youtube welcome to the grow tent
um is there any other areas where
they can find you any other social media
that you want to shout out uh yeah i've
got
uh instagram it's the same welcome to
the grow tent
uh i stream uh on twitch every friday
and sunday
uh i'm a little bit i'm kind of animated
in real life but i'm i'm a lot more
animated in there
um i kind of take on a ric flair
personality you'll hear me
in my videos all the time uh big
wrestling fans over here in this
household especially the nature boy
shout out nature boy the rolex wearing
but you can find me on twitch on friday
and sunday nights 10 p.m
eastern we have a lot of fun and anytime
i die which is
quite often whenever i'm playing warzone
happens all the time
anytime i'm dead or in the lobby they
got a live chat on there i sit there and
answer
hours and hours and hours of grow
questions
all friday and sunday night on the
twitch it has the same
kind of live stream that you would have
on youtube and i think i actually tagged
my youtube into it so i broadcast there
too
but you can ask your questions right
there and i just sit there and i go over
them all night
half the time i die because i start
reading the questions while i'm playing
and i get yelled at by my teammates all
the time but uh it's a
we just have a lot of fun you can hang
out with me on twitch i of course i do
have a patreon
just it's a great little site i do love
the patreon members it's a great
community we got a discord on there
that are for the patreon members it's uh
fantastic
i just love this community and i have a
lot of fun doing it nice
is there anything else on your channel
that you have upcoming that you want to
talk about
or uh you know right now we've got our
granddaddy uh
uh purple that we're growing in the 5x5
i've got my gpm which is my giant purple
monster my own stream and we're going to
cross those two together
i am going to get the purple into my
giant purple monster didn't come out the
first time
so i'm going to breathe this purple the
purple into this thing plant
so you can follow us along as as i go
trial and error through the
trying to become a breeder and you can
see me do that we have uh
gross coming up on like rail light
movers uh the people there send me brand
new tents that are just designed
for their light movers we've got that
coming up and uh
you know just me constantly yelling at
myself
to relax and slow down and and uh
deal with all the people that like to
yell at me on youtube
well welcome to the grow tent thank you
so much for coming on to my channel uh
this has been a great talk
i think this is kind of a refresher for
a lot of people especially the beginners
to who are trying to overcomplicate
things
um you know to hear somebody with
experience that really
takes a pretty big hands-off approach
with a lot of these things that
you know are constantly being fed to
them that they need to narrow down and
be real specific on
yeah yeah i'm the opposite uh
i have the four stations going at all
times and there's times i don't go in
the grill room for you know two three
four days
at a time just because i know where
everything's at and they don't need any
help from me
i go in there i do my topping my my
super cropping whatever
i know when they need to be watered and
i just don't spend a lot of time in
there they're just in there growing all
by themselves so i'd like to take credit
for it but it's just nature
just doing its thing all right i will
link his channels down
in the description section below so you
guys can head on over there
and um hit that subscribe button on his
channel show him some love
maybe even leave a comment on it let
them know i sent you over there
you know i've been a big fan for a long
time man i've been watching you're
watching your channel for a while
oh thank you thank you cool i hope we'll
be able to do some of these talks again
in the future definitely
come back on at some point so yeah if
you have any questions for welcome to
the grow tent that maybe i didn't get to
here i didn't think of leave them down
in the comment section below and then
yeah next time if you come on again i
can ask some of those questions
yeah yeah always cool it's a pleasure
man all right thanks a lot have a good
one
all right
[Music]