welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned into the garden
Talk podcast this is episode number 112
in this episode I interview untrained
astronaut he has been gardening for 2
years and grows the build-a soil way
which is what we're going to talk about
today we get into what he uses for feed
ings waterings environment conditions
and so much more if you want to see
highlights of these Garden Talk podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube that channel is dedicated to
short clips of these podcast episodes I
also have a channel where I have over
130 videos showing off my garden which
I've actually received some comments
recently of people who weren't aware of
that channel so fig I'd mention it here
today I have a Linked In the description
section below one of my goals for this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the general public
that being said I'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that goal possible thanks to AC
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
their grow 10 kits are incredible you
get their ion board LED grow light their
grow tent which is currently the
thickest on the market their ventilation
system clipon fan and their controller
69 to control it all you also get their
fabric pots trellis net plant ties and
trimmers definitely a good price for all
that you get in the kit I'll have a link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about these tank kits and
the discount code Mr Grow 15 works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infiniti.com stash blend I've been using
stash blend for over a year now and it's
awesome one of the things that I really
like is that it saves me money it's a
whole bunch of different inputs in one
so I no longer have to go out there and
buy a silica bottle then a separate
seaweed bottle beneficial bacteria then
a separate one for microle fungi all of
that plus more is in this one blend go
to stash blend.com to learn more about
it and I also have a link down in the
YouTube description section below thanks
to Mars hyro for sponsoring this episode
check out their grow tents which have a
high reflective inner myar a smooth
heavyduty zipper and double flap
protection to prevent light leaks metal
poles for enhanced stability and a 1680d
canvas density there's also a viewing
window with double layers of cloth so
it's easy to observe your plants without
opening the grow tent check out the
website at mars-hydro
docomo Mr Grow it for discount on any of
their products and their products are
also on Amazon I'll provide a link down
in the description section below and we
are back welcome to the Garden Talk
podcast today I am joined with untrained
astronaut how you doing today I'm doing
pretty good how about yourself doing
good man thanks for asking so we met uh
quite recently actually we met inperson
at MJ biscon 2023 and uh wow that was a
good time huh I liked how they broke it
up between like the um cultivation side
and then they had like a retail and
consumption side so it was a little bit
different than previous years was that
your first year going that was my first
time ever going yes that was uh it was
really exciting and I didn't understand
at first that it was brok into two
divisions and uh after a while of going
through it I'm like man I really thought
it'd be bigger then bam seeing the whole
other side was huge huge yeah massive
1,400 different boots and um yeah you
can definitely spend three-day event you
can spend all three days just going
around from boot the booth and see
what's going on and what they got going
on so it was really cool and it was
really nice to meet you there man we're
like Rare Breed in a sense Growers I
remember going into LA and uh into the
high-rise Mansion I'm sh to the
high-rise crew and there was like 50 or
100 people that were like within the
house throughout the night and like
everybody I talked to nobody was a
grower like they I was like yeah I'm a
grower oh you're a grower wow that's
awesome man big props to you like I
don't know how you do it but like
meeting you and like just it's good to
link up and talk shop you know indeed it
is it is that was amazing out there and
it's so cool seeing all the different
people and I I met a couple different
Growers but now that I'm thinking about
it I think you're kind of right like
everybody was more so there on the
different aspect like the sales part you
know yeah it's super wild but uh but
let's actually start off with uh thas a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening oh uh I'm
untrained astronaut nice to meet you
guys I go by Astro um I grew up around
the weed world uh my father has grown um
plants since I was a little boy and I
remember walking around on a dirt floor
and uh that was just you know some of
the earliest memories I have are him
growing plants down in the uh Cellar
underneath the house and it kind of it's
weird how it all went I didn't really
care much for uh plants at the time
being of that age obviously but as I got
older I just you know still didn't
really wasn't until I was in my like mid
20s that I really started getting in it
really heavy and uh from there I've you
know I've always seen my uh father
cultivate but I never truly learned I
just you know I was more so into the
sales side of things too in my mind like
I was you know at that time as a younger
kid I was trying to move things and
whatnot and uh it wasn't until later in
life when I had kids myself that I
discovered that I didn't want to go the
illegal route anymore that I just wanted
to pursue this this passion that I have
toward plants uh and go ahead and jump
into it so I dump my life savings into
my first grow room which was a uh 12x 12
and that ended up producing about 8 lbs
on my very first harvest and uh I I do
understand you guys aren't like uh going
for yields or anything and it's not
really that I'm going for yields it's
more so that I'm just trying to I'm
really trying to push these plants to
the limits to see where they go and so
that's kind of you know how the origin
became growing up around it and seeing
what I could do with the world when I
enter it so man that's awesome
underneath the house you were saying so
like that had to have been a crazy
ghetto setup huh it was it was that was
such a a crap neighborhood it was crazy
though I do remember playing with a
staple gun on the floor but I was so
young because we moved into the house
that we grew up in when it when I was
the age of five and so that had to have
been you know pre so prior to the age of
five so I don't know when you actually
are supposed to like recollect memory
but I guess that was prior to the age of
five you know what I mean so but then he
grew AK-47 in the uh the closets
downstairs I remember him growing Hydro
in the garage and you know he had those
Sleek little setups to where you
couldn't tell he had closets that were
blocked off so you go in the bathroom
downstairs and you're taking a dunk and
uh you look over and there was a closet
there but it's kind of like drywalled
over now and that's because you know
AK-47 was real popular at the time and
he had to have a way to do it and so
that was that was you know it's
something that I've always been very
very familiar with but it wasn't until
recent that I really got into learning
about it that's wild yeah back then you
had to be it very secretive right you
had to hide things you had to have these
areas that were closed off so it
couldn't really be identified that that
was what was happening so hold different
world now you can be a lot more open
with it which is which is fantastic so
so what's your grow style like what uh
you know what are you doing are you in
soil Coco Hydro you indoor outdoor like
what's your overall style I do indoor
organic and it's the build soil way I am
such a big fan Jeremy Silva was the
first YouTuber that I began watching and
that is like the smartest man on the
planet like between you guys I don't
know what the heck um you guys are both
brilliant with this stuff but I've
learned so much from him in particular
due to the fact like I was able like I
said earlier to produce 8 pound of my
first girl ever and that was I really
solely credit like Jeremy Silva like all
of his videos I religiously watch them
before going to bed I played it on the
TV and that's just you know how I did it
every night and so it was like the
moment when it went legal I just seen
this all happening I knew this was what
I was meant to do dumped my money in it
fell in love with it even more so than I
thought and then I did YouTube and so I
got these cameras now and I'm doing this
I'm having so much fun with it like I
just I'm just trying to document my grow
and stuff and uh you know hopefully if
uh if I learn from something that maybe
I could share it with my audience and we
could all learn together because I think
a lot of my people know that I've only
been growing for 2 years and so I'm
still experimenting and learning myself
that's awesome yeah and I will have a
link to your YouTube channel down in the
YouTube description section below so if
anybody wants to uh follow him click on
his channel can easily get to it and
then hit the Subscribe button and yeah
I've tuned into a few of your videos man
you definitely got some good stuff so
definitely looking forward to see in the
future oh yeah the the MJ biscon you did
you did one on MJ biscon you did one on
Cowboy cup dude I'm so excited
because uh yeah I've just been
practicing you know how it is with
editing you've done it it's just an
addiction very timec consuming that's
like another passion in its own I fell I
fell into another Rabbit Hole when I
fell into growing in YouTube you know
cuz then camera equipment and then
quality and then editing it's addicting
man all of this is so fun so let's get
into the build of soil way I want to
know more about this particular way of
going about it what's your soil mix and
then what fertilizer are you using my
are all reused they were 3.0 and then I
top dress I use um say I use build-a
flower that's the top dress I use and so
obviously build a soil 3.0 I do worm
castings from builda soil as well I use
uh about a cup of wake field biochar or
biochar and um Earth Juice High Brinks
molasses or high bricks molasses I use
for uh like um what is it microbes and
stuff I'm using like uh rootwise um
that's a um what is the word I'm looking
for biological Bloom support full
spectrum soil um inoculant that's the
word I was looking for inoculant um and
so that's what I'm using for my macrobes
and uh what else hope I don't miss any I
know recharge is in there for sure
recharge is amazing I also use Roots
Organics grow Bloom and Bloom booster um
rootwise obviously terrible packaging
but um what else I I wrote a list and I
put them up here just so I wouldn't
forget but oh build-a Bloom of course
build whm amazing one right there and
craft blend so the 3.0 build of soil mix
I'm familiar with that for my
understanding correct me from wrong that
won't last you throughout the grow it's
not like a true super soil to where you
just plant in it and then you're good to
go for the entire grow cycle but
eventually nutrients deplete from that
medium and then you need to add in more
inputs which you mentioned the inputs
that that you're using there so are you
first of all what size container are you
in and then when does your first top
dressing happen um I do top dressing
generally every two weeks or so um I
tried Las gr trying to go a little bit
further out to see what the results
would be if I let them go a little bit
more hungry for my own eyes to witness
I'm a Hands-On learner for sure and it's
not the results that you want that I've
learned in a larger bed of soil they do
go through it quite well so um I was I
am currently top dressing every two
weeks uh what I do is I do a compost te
one week and then I do a top dress the
next week on routine on a Wednesday and
so that way it just keeps them fed and
it keeps it so simple I use a compost
tumbler so it's kind of like you know
taking a tote and throw it in a washing
machine it just spins it around and you
don't necessarily have to do that I just
do it for the added effect of it's you
know mixed in pretty good and then I
just walk around with a cup like a red
Solo cup and just kind of equally
distribute it amongst the beds I have
two 90 gallon beds in my main 12x 12
room I've got uh 4 15 gallon bags in
there as well and that's all the build
of soil way and then in my basement grow
I have two 90 gallon beds I have two 15
gallon bags in there for the 10x10 and
then in my 5x5 I've got one 15 gallon
bag under um just a light and a charcoal
filter and actually no I'm sorry I was
actually bringing that up because I
wanted to see what I could do or test
myself but um I've got a 2x4 grow tent
it's a Gorilla Grow Tent and I've got a
15-gallon in there with a bathroom
exhaust system and just a light and
bottles of water just so I can learn
from the bare minimum like I want to be
able to grow plants with nothing and
then learn from that scratch all the way
to the top because I I started out
investing everything I had and I just
kind of I don't know I I felt like I was
missing the the proper foundation for
Learning and so my basement was my
chance to really grow the knowledge by
just bare minimum growing and really
hone the skill which I'm nowhere ever
near you know what I mean but I'm
definitely uh having fun with it so that
being said I do have a 4x4 with the 15
gallon in there as well and um that 2x4
and uh hlg sending me the Scorpion
Diablo X so I'm going to start another
one up so there's going to be another
4x4 with the 15 gallon in there just for
that one uh light so that's what I've
got going on now but uh quite a few it
feels like huh but I don't grow a lot
per bed I grow one to two plants even if
it is a 90 gon bed I just want to make
that one plant the happiest it could
ever be and as big as it can get and
then all I I'll lollipop them I've been
watching the northern scroger lately and
that was due to high again wrenching
them all the time and uh it was just
interesting to know that he goes in
there every day tucking like that and I
was just like wow you know what no more
weaving let's just go with the tucking
and I've had fa fantastic results I've
had so much fun with it here soon I'll
be putting out some footage of uh the
grow room and the uh work that I've been
putting in in there man that's awesome
yeah a bunch of different grow spaces
you got there and different beds and
containers and so all of them are using
the build of Sol 3.0 and then you're
going in and doing the feedings when do
the feedings start do you go like what
30 days or something before you actually
start doing the feedings or you just
like plant two weeks later adding in
fertilizer and then so on and so forth
like you mentioned it is
uh just play it and then 2 weeks later
that is when I start doing it after
transplanting into the bed um even after
harvesting I still continue to top dress
you know and so that way they just go
into it um so everything really never
breaks routine never breaks cycle
whether there's plants growing or not
like currently uh the 10x10 in my
basement is honed out for you the chill
out OG that you supplied me with at the
MJ biscon I have specifically dedicated
the 10x10 just to growing out the chill
out OG so this is my first time sexing
plants by the way and uh I'm really
excited to have the learning opportunity
especially the learning opportunity
being with your strain your genetic that
is exciting as hell man that's really
cool to hear that's awesome for those
that don't know I have a a cross I've
been working on for several years now
it's a Brisk gr G cross with Pakistan
Valley and uh named it chillo OG and uh
every time I hear somebody growing that
up it's just that Warmness feeling that
I get and then seeing it on Instagram
and and so on and so forth that's
awesome but now it's really cool that
you're dedicating a whole area to that
and I can't wait to see how it turns out
for you now for the feedings you
mentioned every couple weeks are you
come across any toxicity issues at all
it seems like pretty frequent feedings
at first if I felt like it it's just you
know taking their taking their suggested
amounts and really just sticking with
that and not doing anything over and um
I feel like jumping into it I was never
accurately taught to feed correctly I
was more so like he was doing his whole
life and everything but he was doing
Hydro he jumped into organic at the same
time that I started growing and um so it
was kind of learning experience for both
of us and the way I had learned through
him I felt like was just uh it was a
little bit too pungent like they were
getting some toxicity issues like maybe
it was uh too much honestly I I can't
remember the
but um afterwards I did just dilute my
stuff down a little bit and really
started reading the labels and
understanding you know overfeeding is
bad now it is I mean I think that's a
common misconception people think that
hey it's organic it's going to get
broken down over time slower the plant's
going to upake what it wants when it
wants it type thing but you can
absolutely have too much that have
broken down that cause toxicity issues
um particularly nitrogen toxicity I
think that's probably one one of the
most common ones that you see in organic
Gardens from over fertilizing so I was
just curious because it did seem like a
little bit more frequent than what I've
heard other people doing I personally do
it uh every 30 days I'll do a top
dressing I use the craft blend from
build the soil and I do one cup per
plant I've used other Blends in the past
but we were talking about the build AO
away here but what I used with build AO
is a craft blend and it's super easy you
can use that all the way out through uh
from Veg all the way through flowering
and um I've also used build a bloom
which you mentioned that you use had
some good results with that as well
definitely and I think the regiment that
I'm feeding on is um it's more based
upon that I have so much or so many beds
of soil you know that I have to feed so
frequently maybe it's just uh they they
love it right now I feel like I've had
the best coloration in the leaves that
I've had ever before um everything is
turning out really really well they're
super super happy and I it's just
they're in veg right now so I'm trying
this regiment and I feel like you know
prior to this I was doing uh probably
about you know roughly every 30 days or
a little bit more just kind of
stretching it out like I said earlier to
uh learn just what'll happen if you
don't feed as much and uh I and I kind
of just shot a little into it with the
two weeks maybe it is a little bit much
um but I'm going to run consistency this
grow and uh if I don't think that it is
going to turn out you know something
like desirable I won't do it again I'll
start going back to the monthly area
maybe and just keep it tight on that you
mentioned you're growing larger plants
anyway so larger the plant the more
nutrition it's going to need so yeah it
makes sense now the additives you
mentioned rootwise and the microbial
inoculant how often are you using those
the rootwise um using those about every
or every other depending I use about
every other um what is it uh compost
t-ix and then what about watering you
know that's a common thing that I think
a lot of folks struggle with
particularly with Organic where it's
ideal to keep the medium moist at all
times so the microbes are active and you
get proper breakdown however hand
watering can be a little bit challenging
right letting dry outs in between has
some benefits so some people do that are
you handw watering or do you have an
auto watering system going how do you go
about that ah I love this topic this is
going to be fun I uh am an absolute fan
of the Eco with soil moisture sensors oh
my goodness they are the best things
ever um allowing me to see what the soil
moisture level is at all times that is
just being able to play God and I
absolutely adore that so thank you build
soil thank you Jeremy Silva uh for
pumping those videos out that led me on
to them I've got one here somewhere I
was going to show
it these are your Lifesaver if you're
new to Growing let this be the game
changer for you this is like the best
thing ever if you're growing in larger
beds and such it's it gets a little bit
hard to tell how much water's in in
there and so with those that really
changed my game cuz I feel like prior to
them I was overwatering and that was an
issue that I wasn't really you know too
familiar with my very first grow but I
think one of my plants did come out very
Anor robic in comparison to what you
know the other ones came out really like
Stout perfect and then it was a learning
experience on I overw waterer definitely
but um and I apply that with a Gard hose
I've got the blont system I I just
haven't put it all up yet and that's
that's the only thing uh finding the
time to get that all installed in there
is what I'm really just waiting on at
this point I love the blue mat system
that moisture meter I'm going to have to
search for it because I haven't even
heard of it I use the the blue M
moisture meter right now so I I am using
a moisture meter I think moisture meter
is one of those things that uh more
people probably should use you know it's
one of those things that a lot of people
don't use and it makes the job so much
easier I can't remember the video that
it was on but they always recommend
getting aam tensiometers it's something
that DET it detects the water levels in
your soil and they're really pricey and
I was about to purchase some but then I
realized I can get the soil moisture
sensors and they save me a lot of money
that's why I was so excited about those
personally um and in the blue mod I've
seen that they came out with those and I
haven't tried them yet what are your
views on those do you like them I love
them yeah it makes things so much easier
dialing it in you know you just get the
soil to the moisture level you that you
want that's ideal
then you install those carrot systems in
and then as the medium dries out just
drips down onto the medium and keeps it
at that consistent moisture level so
game changer for me um and then you're
just filling up a reservoir you know I'm
not going through hand watering
individual plants everything's all
connected to one reservoir so super easy
for me what do you got there me showing
on the screen right now you can see the
plants are at 37% 36% 35 and 35 and then
I can switch back and forth between Grow
rooms and uh I could check the stats
through all the uh days it's got like a
calendar on there and it also keeps uh
tabs on your vpds of your room even so
it's kind of like so many things in one
I love it and so I put uh I didn't just
make one video I made the first one and
I was like man I don't feel like that
did it justice so I came out with a
second Eco it video just to really pound
in how I was like and I'm one of those
people that I'm not sponsored by them I
just genuin feel like that was the the
single-handedly best thing that I did
you know what I mean that really changed
my grow uh other than you know all the
work that I've been doing with the
trellising lately but really trying to
just get it all canopi perfectly but
that was a game changer that was really
a game changer getting getting a hold of
those yeah I'm looking at it on Amazon
right now Eco wi 37 bucks and there a
10% coupon you can get show they have
sales and stuff and so there's just one
here do you have multiple of them for
each container or what do you
uh you can hold up to eight sensors per
Gateway and so you'll have to buy a
Gateway let's just say that's like a
Smart Hub right there that's going to
collect the information and send it to
your cell phone and then the
transmitters are what go into the soil
and so you can at all times see it
updates every minute so you have up to
the direct minute as to what your plants
levels are that's awesome yeah I'm
definitely going to scoop one of those
up for sure sounds like it's a
Improvement compared to what I'm doing
right now with the blue mat moisture
meter I have to go into the room and see
where it's at and it's really only good
for one container so yeah got to upgrade
stuff there for sure I love them now
also for watering one thing I wanted to
ask about is you mentioned it's out of a
hose are you filtering the water or do
you just have like a really good water
source I actually had a room built on
the side of the house and I only bring
that up due to the fact cuz I have a 55
gallon that's outside of it and then I
have a 55 gallon that's inside of it uh
and after watching one of your videos
recently I've decided to start phing my
water and so um the I don't filter it I
actually that one fills up through the
garden hose and then I've got a heat rod
in there so if it gets really cold out
it doesn't freeze and then I pump it
into the garden which goes through a
water chiller and then I've got bubblers
in the water at all times I use wedding
agents and I use a little bit of the uh
oh what's it called high Shield I think
and so I mix that in the water supply a
little bit as well and uh I don't have
any filtering going through it
necessarily I do have a couple like
layers of uh I think it's like a mesh
filter that goes over the pump before it
goes through the sprayer nozzle but
that's just for smaller stuff pretty
straightforward and then you said you do
pH your water so you got to have some
sort of when I checked it today before
doing the or was uh yesterday actually
but it was like
8.8 and then I dropped it down to about
6.5 somewhere around there but not okay
so comes up high to begin so safe side
yeah there's a lot of you know this is a
Hot Topic there's a lot of organic
Growers are like oh you don't need a pH
at all just boom water in no problem
right and then they swear by it but some
folks have high phes you know you said
you have in the eights I mean that's
pretty high so just about nine I can
imagine some people what they'll do is
they'll PH down in order to safeid it
and that's what I did and I learned that
from you and
Rob that's right I remember now I think
it was him talking about it if I'm not
mistaken yeah we made a video on from
the stash not too long go about all
about that maybe that's what it was from
and then do you know what the EC or the
PPM of the water is to begin or you have
a TDS tester to me measure that or no
nope never done it before in my life I
can't wait to learn after this because
I'm totally looking that up yeah it was
just kind of interesting to know like
what's in your water source to begin I
have a very bad water source here my tap
water comes in at like 485 PPM and
that's a 500 scale TDS tester and so
that's High I mean the AP EPA there's
like warnings if it's over 500 they deem
it like not safe for drinking if it's
over 500 PPM so I'm like right there on
the line I've tried to use my tap water
before and uh unfortunately there's a
lot of sodium bicarbonates in it and
that stuff just builds up in the soil
and high ph and it just it cause so much
issues so I have to filter it you know
I've used regular just filter through
the britter before I've used it uh now I
use AO I just want to try to get as
clean as possible and then I used the
waste water from the Aro in my outdoor
Garden I some people have to filter
their water other people they're lucky
they don't need to I mean I've talked to
so many people who are like yeah my
natural PPM out the Taps like a 100
that's great you know it's all stuff
they can use calcium the iron you know
so on and so forth it is lucky so I was
just curious to see how your water
source was to begin and uh you know what
the pH came at it and were you adjusting
things or not oh and I just remembered
earlier when you were asking about
whether I sprayed um I do the top
watering uh with this really extended
garden sprayer so I can fit it under the
trellising and after I do that I wait
until they're into flower for a little
bit and I begin using the bottom water
feed that way the roots will start
building up down there too and and
correct me if I'm wrong but I was going
to say I think I watched an episode
where Jeremy Silva was talking about how
he likes to water on the top layers for
the initial of the gardening and then as
it goes into flower and progresses he
then begins watering from the bottom to
start building Roots down there as well
and then you know try to get your whole
bed like all roots and stuff and
basically they could when you go to
plant something they could tap into the
canals and just use the same root system
for a while as well so that was uh
mainly I just spray on the top then I
did the bottom after flowering maybe for
a week or so that's interesting yeah
build the soil away yeah I've seen
Jeremy do just that talk about that
watering from the top bottom watering
you know yeah I know he has Earth boxes
which is the bottom watering I have
tried to use organic and do bottle
watering through the auto pots didn't
have good luck and I think it's I live
in a very dry climate I have to say that
in every video and every podcast episode
but it's difficult for me to keep that
top layer moist and I've added mulch
layers um cardboard covers to try to
retain that moisture back then maybe it
wasn't staying as moist as it should
have and I just had problems you know
not having enough nutrition because of
the breakdown just wasn't there but
people swear by doing top dressing and
still just bottom watering and wicking
all the way up and making sure that top
layer is moist and they're getting the
breakdown they're being successful so I
think I need to kind of circle back
around and try the bottom watering with
Organic inputs top dressing and um see
if I can do it successfully cuz last
time you know now springing up the top
layer and stuff like that try to keep it
moist but I only go so far and there's
additional work there and so on and so
forth so I love to know in the comments
actually for those folks that are tuning
in on this that do grow with Organic
inputs and top dress or any of you just
bottom watering right not doing any top
watering whatsoever how what's your
experience with that let me know cuz I
want to see uh let's see if there's
other people struggling with it or if
it's just just me well the cool thing
with those Eco wits is they actually
notify me if it gets below 20 per s or
20 per 7 when it gets below 27% I get a
notification on my phone and before I go
to bed I never let a pot or bed or
anything get below
29% uh basically I just wake up in the
morning and I top them up to 42% that's
what Jeremy recommended and uh I've had
nothing but amazing results with that
it's been so fun except for the one time
I went out there and I had first got
them was really excited like a kid on
Christmas and I'm just watering and all
this stuff and I had one in the wrong
bag which equaled all of them being in
the wrong bags and I'm watering this one
it's like it's not going up in water
right and then all of a sudden I
realized they were in the wrong bags and
I had overwatered the other one and it
was like 60% that plant I think became
Anor robic after that
that was a huge learning experience and
so just make sure you put them in the
right bed and label them correctly and
they'll be the best things ever they
really are so cut dry simple you just
shove them in you're done and and you
sold me on that I'm going to have to buy
one of those right after this and try it
out that sounds like a big upgrade
sounds sounds like it makes things a lot
easier let's move on to environment
conditions so temperature humidity CO2
air
circulation what do you do for those
things just you know start wherever you
want on that one oh I'm a fan I love
vpds uh that was one of the first things
that I began to learn just the
importance of them and uh that was one
of the things that really caught me that
Jeremy Silva was able to translate to
where I could actually understand I feel
and then I came up with my own varant of
how to word it and I feel like it helped
a lot of people maybe uh when I put the
video out it hit like 5,000 views of
inst or instantly on that one and it was
uh basically just describe or explaining
it as like basically vpds are just a
distance between temperature and
humidity the further apart they are the
higher the number the closer they are
the lower the number like 70 or like
70% humidity is going to be like a
0.75 you know what I mean and it's just
a good like way of looking at it and so
I keep the troll Master System in my
mango uh I keep the vpds around 0.8 to
0.9 all the way up until the third week
of flowering and then I really start
cranking it in that's when I start
trying to drive the race car to my
room's full capacity uh I start cranking
the lights up I get my power meter to
about uh maybe like a th000 within the
like fourth week or so and then just
kind of I tune it up basically getting
it like a
1.25 on the uh vpds and then kind of
just from there as to weeks four and
five I think I go into like a 1.4 or 1.5
on the vpds just kind of really pull
them out to get them stressed at the end
there and you know
just kind of cater to it but that's kind
of the reason I like to do uh the room
the way I do instead of a Perpetual grow
I do all simultaneously they're all
growing uh from the same age basically I
basically like to cater my vpds to
towards the specific age of the plant if
the plant is coming in there as a
younger age I don't want to have harsh
vpds like 1.5 for instance I would
rather have vpds of 0.8 and with the
Perpetual grow you don't always have
that luxury due to the fact you're going
to be catering toward the plants that
are in their Prime the ones that are
going to be you know you're trying to
really stress out to get them to really
you know pop and so it's just a it's a
mixed bag it's kind of like a catch all
for a doctor's office you know like
everybody's coming in there for all
these different problems but there's one
doctor to handle everything and that's
kind of the way they're treating the
room I feel you know and so with the
basement grow I basically I've got the
knwa system and the NWA system is
phenomenal it's got a really easy to use
uh VPD chart that'll also show you if
your lights are on in there uh really
easy to you know manage the app some of
the apps can be difficult if you've got
you know like other brands and stuff
you'll see that their apps I don't want
to say any specific names but their apps
can be a little intimidating or
confusing when it as to niwa their app
is actually extremely easy to use
because they have a um a recipes chart
and the recipe chart saves your recipes
so you could just go in there and you
could put in cure and drying and that
way it saves every time so next time you
use it for your dry room boom you just
click on cure and drying or you can use
it in mango label it mang gr and have
presets already made for it and so your
vpds will carry over and uh then in my 8
by8 I'm running 60 and 60 on the curing
so in my uh dry tent I'm curing them at
about 60 and 6 in there for 6060 method
yeah very common there now backing up to
VPD you know I have some folks here that
don't really pay attention to VPD
they're more old school I'm I'm in the
same boat whereas like I still
temperature humidity you know I kind of
look at the VPD and I have my controller
set up for VPD so I stay within the
ranges but like what's the temperature
that you kind of get up to at the
highest and then same thing with like
humidity do you know like what it kind
of adjusts to for the different stages
of growth or yeah um usually running
around 76 to 78 in there all throughout
the vegetative state um I usually keep
the humidity not too far apart from that
it'll be around um maybe 65 or so in
there on humidity and then as we go into
later stages I will begin to stretch
those things apart you know I'll really
let the temperature go up because I'm
running CO2 which allows me to get up to
around 83 in there and I don't want to
so I try to keep it a little bit lower
than that I keep it around 80 1 or so
and uh I just uh start slowly pulling
away the humidity I get it down to
probably down to 60 maybe maybe 65 is
somewhere around there and then the
temperature will start to go up too as
the grow progresses that is got it yeah
so that makes sense as far as um
matching that up to the vpg Chart seeing
the dark green range what you mentioned
for temperature and humidity kind of
it's in line from what I'm looking at
right here I look at the pulse grow.com
they have a great article all about VPD
and they have different charts for the
different stages of growth so if anybody
is looking to learn more about VPD and
see the different charts you can Google
pulse VPD charts and it's going to give
you uh there's a first one's the charts
second link is the guide very in-depth
guide talks about daytime VPD nighttime
VPD and so on and so forth so really
good stuff there now you mentioned CO2
can we get into that a little bit can
you kind of break down like what you do
for CO2 using a tank or or what I use a
uh CO2 generator I'm running propane
underneath of it and um I love it I
consider it steroids for my plants and
it allows you to drive your car a little
bit faster it allows you to uh really
push them and uh they got a little bit
more strength to them but in order to do
so you generally will want a sealed
environment or else you're just going to
be expend you're going to be leaking
your CO2 out
constantly um but I run typically I'll
keep it around 1,000 and then I'll bump
it up like a 100 or so each and every uh
week that goes by until I get to 1,500
generally like um I don't do the fuzzy
logic or anything I just try to keep it
consistent as like uh around like 1,400
and then a little bit higher so that it
doesn't exceed 1500 just because you
would be wasting it if it does they
can't take in any more after 1500 if I'm
understanding that correctly that's
another thing that you mentioned the
frequent feedings well there's a
contributing factor right you're running
CO2 it's going to drive your plants
faster to like you mentioned uh and it's
going to need more nutrition in the
medium so yeah that kind of brings it
full circle and kind of makes sense to
the more frequent feedings I was
wondering if I was wrong whenever you
brought it up earlier and you you
brought up the 30 days and I'm like man
I guess I am feeding a little bit more
like why is it that I'm having to feed
so much and that could be a big variant
into you know that well there's so many
different ways to go about it and the
the 30- days is just kind of a general
guideline I think like on um I've also
using the kiss Organics nutrient pack I
believe on the instructions it says top
dress every 30 days I think it says on
the build of soil instructions too if I
remember correctly but uh General
recommendation I've done every two weeks
before in the past but I found no
difference going from every two weeks to
every month um so I just been sticking
with every month and I don't supplement
CO2 I mean I grow smaller plants than it
sounds like you grow you had mentioned
you grow larger plants so um yeah
there's so many different ways to go
about it yeah it's interesting to hear
the different ways you know your your
way of doing it yeah I started out with
it and so learning how to do it off the
rip was a big thing um it was a fun
procedure and I did find out the troll
Master is phenomenal for that and uh I
love that system it makes it so easy to
manage just hop on and change your CO2
levels whenever I've got exhaust fand in
there in case it gets a little too high
or excessive on it so definitely like
when when I'm in the working cuz I've
actually got dual exhaust in there so if
I'm in there working a lot and actually
breaking a sweat I then begin producing
a lot more CO2 and I'll see it actually
hit you know nearly like
22200 and that's when I'm like wow cuz
the dual exhaust kicks on it it's pretty
neat you know and one exhaust just
wasn't doing it like it wasn't flushing
it enough to keep up with the amount of
breathing because my room is so airtight
and so I had to go ahead and do another
one through the ceiling actually with
all the grow lights running are you
running in any heat issues where the
Heat's just going too high and then you
got to exhaust that out and you're
losing some of the CO2 or or no boy it's
been a learning curve on that one buddy
that it has I uh I struggled at the
beginning of that one I was so excited
when I was like okay I'm going to put
five scorpion Diablos in one room and
they're all going to have UV bars and
then 16 AC Infinities no one thinks
about oh my God it gets so hot in there
so quick it was Unreal it it like it
broke my last uh my last um mini split
and so I mean me too but still anyway
it's uh I had to replace it with the 12K
mini split and it just it wasn't keeping
up and during the process of doing so I
had two 10,000 BTU AC units in my room
to substitute the mini split while I was
down and being installed and it still
wasn't enough it actually was still
getting almost to 90 in there and I had
all of them dimmed down and everything
it was such a catastrophe when the AC
unit went out but now I've got a brand
new one in there and I'm really excited
about it it's actually keeping up really
well but boy when you crank those lights
up everything changes it is seriously an
entire different ball game um the
temperature can Elevate literally 10 in
the blink of an eye if you're not
monitoring it closely at times you know
and that's where I'm so open or I'm so
happy to have trollmaster because that
has safety netted me the whole way
through uh if if uh if it gets to a
certain temperature in there my exhaust
system will kick on and so that way it
will uh definitely flush the room and
then at the same at the same degree it
also could detect if the boards get more
than I think 92 or so and then it'll
shut the light it'll dim the lights down
and so that'll also reduce the
temperature in the room and uh but yeah
having that many lights in there is
definitely uh a lot to negotiate or to
navigate that's the word I was looking
for yeah sounds like it could be a
serious problem I've run into heat
issues I think a lot of people have run
into heat issues you know not realizing
that the heat was going to build up that
quickly and then uh and then the
temperature being too high and then you
get exhaust and balancing is is easier
said than done you know balancing the
environment conditions there so keep a
backup fan that's one thing I've learned
a big fan that could really haul some
wind like a little bit like all right so
the the floor vacuums you know they lay
on the floor basically they shoot
outward you get one of those they'll
throw the wind out of there Open Your
Door up and do that just to vent your
room as fast as you can but that saved
my butt during that procedure or that
process
got to do what you got to do right
definitely so I want to ask about some
more problems you've faced and how you
corrected them talking about the build
so away you mentioned your newer grower
couple years under your belt what other
problems have you kind of run into and
what Solutions did you do to correct
those problems bugs they're the devil um
and diet ous Earth it is also the devil
um just because and I know everybody
loves diet mous Earth but you
I don't know maybe I was excessive but I
hate cleaning charcoal filters
constantly and that it gets everywhere I
mean it's everywhere you can't get it
out at time when you have a larger room
it's it's definitely something to Veer
away from in my eyes um but yeah it
definitely forever I feel like I had had
to clean my charcoal filters
continuously when I was using it I
stopped it uh it'll fill up your AC unit
filter it'll fill clog up everything it
feels like were you putting on your
plants or on your soil no no no yeah on
the soil okay you can put on the soil
you can put it you know on the floors if
need be and they always recommend that
too but that's just another thing you
know it was just going airborne huh it
was going airborne and getting up into
your filters everywhere yeah that that
stuff's it's have you used had that
problem that's interesting like what do
you how do you use it how do you apply
it I would just sprinkle on top of the
medium you know cuz fungus knats is one
of the things that I ran into I run into
pretty frequently particularly when I'm
grabbing a new bag of soil if I need to
grabb a new bag of soil now these days
I'm reusing my soil and kind of worked
out those fungus kns I don't have them
as much but diet tomati is something
that you know quite a few people use for
battling the fungus NS that's why I got
them initially until I discovered this
little hack all right so you know
mosquito bits I'm sure you've heard of
them oh yep use those to as well yeah
but uh I take my water supply and I'll
take like a plastic glove and I don't
know if this is the best thing but I'll
put the mosquito bit or bits into the
plastic glove and I'll tie it off and
poke holes in it and throw it into my
water supply and it literally killed
every net um in my either of my girls I
have zero Nets none they can be tough to
battle my way of going about it right
now is you obviously yellow stickies
right those definitely help catch the
adult ones that are flying around but
Mammoth can control man that stuff works
so good like I spray that thing and and
it knocks down the population and then
of course the The larva hatches and then
more kind of fly up spray do another
application and then uh you know two
three applications and they're prettyy
much gone for me so that or also Dr the
amazing Dr zes is another very works
very very well those are the two that I
really like Dr zes is awesome I love Dr
zes any other problems that you've come
across mhm yeah a couple uh spiderm
they're man they're something you just
really really want to get on them and
you know check your plants every day you
know be out there make sure you're not
getting them and if they if you do get
them get on it really really quick
that's all I've got to say cuz when I
was out in Vegas with you guys spider BS
took over an area that I just didn't see
in that downstairs garden and so that's
why it's all cleared out for your grow I
just said screw it they were all in
vegetative state and I just hacked them
down there you know nothing really
special so um spiderm that was my first
time with them and I was just like wow
it happened so fast I was like cuz when
I first noticed him we were about to
head to Vegas and I was spraying for him
and everything and uh
I went out there and got back and it
they took over like a whole section
immediately it felt like while in that
one you know two-day period of time it
was just the whole corner of my garden I
was like no I'm done with this so uh
I've I've uh
began actually what I started doing was
the rotation between different uh
whether it be I think it's called I
wrote it down plant therapy but I think
it's from Lost Coast is the is the is
the maker of it but yeah plant therapy
Dr zes uh Captain Jack's dead bug those
are all awesome and if you take the
three of them and do them in rotation
that way you don't get zombie
mites but uh I had no issues especially
with that new AC Infinity uh mister have
you tried that thing yeah that thing's
awesome man the pumpless one battery
operated just sprays consistently that
thing's incredible that thing is
gold that thing is so great the Mist
level is stupendous like I got a couple
other ones I got a Ryobi One and uh it
was on Amazon for $17 and uh it was good
but then when I got that I was like wow
it saves so much time I have a lot of
big plants and all that foliage it's
just a lot to cover but when you have
something like that that was pretty cool
that makes it a lot easier so I'm able
to keep up on it with a lot more ease
now makes it so much easier man those
pump ones I mean GE to spend time
pumping and then the the pressure it's
built off of pressure so like you have
reductions in the pressure and it sprays
inconsistent problem solved with the AC
Infinity one consistent the Mist levels
really well yeah it's it's awesome I
love it do you do sunrise and sunset
have you heard much on it no I I stopped
doing the sunrise sunset I used to do it
back in the day but ever since Dr Bruce
bugby mentioned that uh they did a study
on it and they were just measuring the
rate of photosynthesis and he said that
the plants that had the lights come on
immediately was able to take the photons
the photosynthesis rate was able to be
up there so I've just been going with
the lights on right off the bat ever
since I heard him say that dude that's
cool as hell what about this other one
I'm hearing I love it uh I took my son's
sound machine I took it apart and uh I
made a little noise machine it it had
lights on it I took all the LED lights
off so that I could use it in the night
time but I have Birds tripping in there
constantly to help with like opening the
stamatas like uh you you been get any of
that yet anything or have you dug into
it yet I have not heard about birds
chirping opening the stamata that's uh
that's a new one for me right it just
sounded so interesting and so I'm trying
it now I my son's sound machine he
didn't need it anymore and it has this
option for birds and so I was like all
right I pulled it apart took the LED
lights out and I put it in the grow room
and it sounds like amazing in there like
a rainforest there's just Birds tripping
all the time in there so people are like
watching my
videos I'm watching of I'm sitting like
I hear birds tripping the whole time
well if uh if you guys watch the videos
and see that or hear that that's what it
is that you're hearing is uh my son's
old sound machine yeah that's the new
one for me bird strip and I hear about
uh people singing to their plants you
back in the day they like yeah they
swore by if you sing to your plants
they're going to grow better and come to
find out it was just exhaling the CO2 so
you're giving more CO2 to your plants so
that's why they were doing better oh
yeah it's not so much the singing people
were playing music and stuff
playing it loudly some people say that
hey that's not doing anything at all
it's got to be a jet engine you know
sound in order for it to actually make
an impact but I don't know I've never
really tested that out to be honest with
you hell yeah I figured if anybody would
knew or if anybody knew it' be you so I
was like a I figured I'll ask him but uh
yeah it could be one of those Bro
Science ones I think it was actually
like on a uh I probably just seen
something on Facebook going by you know
what I mean it's like oh yeah the birds
chirping opens the stamatas or something
like that but I definitely want to look
into it I think it was um
corn or that was playing music too
that's that's yeah the jazz music the
guy growing corn who had a bigger crop
than his uh neighbors and they were like
what did you do differently he's like I
started playing jazz music yeah so
that's fun to think about yeah that's
funny like to see more information about
the the birds chirping one right all
these different techniques and styles
and theories it's it's crazy to see what
they come up with you know so many
different ways to go about it like I
said and just so many different things
that you can do within the Gard I love
it love hearing about it loved hearing
your style this time around we talked
about the build of so way how you're
doing that we hav't got into like
environment conditions and some problems
you faced and been a fun episode talking
to you tell the uh listeners how they
can find you and what you have upcoming
in the future oh a whole bunch of stuff
well guys I'm on Instagram untrained
astronaut I'm on uh YouTube untrained
astronaut uh my Tik Tok though it's uh
the untrained astronaut I have a lot of
stuff in store luckily um I will be in
La for February 10th for the American
Autoflower Cup hosted by hayan uh that's
really exciting I talk to them we're
going to get some content while I'm out
there not only that but um what was it I
don't want to draw a blank on it oh uh
hlg uh they messaged me about doing a
video for the Scorpion Diablo X so
that's really cool that means uh
mediocre product reviews will be back
yeah buddy really excited I'm so glad
you had me on man I appreciate this is
cool as hell man and my dad like I I
think I told you I was out there he's
he's a big fan of yours and he's like yo
you're gonna talk to Mr Grow it I'm like
yeah
yeah it's so neat man so thank you for
having me on I really appreciate it yeah
no problem man thanks for coming on it
was great meeting you and I'm sure I
will cross path again soon whether it be
at some other event or MJ biscon I don't
know if you're going to be going this
year 2024 but I go every year so already
got my see you out there yeah there we
go awesome yeah cool all right so once
again I'll Have untraded astronauts Link
in the description section below to his
YouTube go over there sub to him watch
his videos comment on his videos let him
know that Mr Grow sent you that you
heard about him from the garden Talk
podcast all right we'll leave it at that
peace out everyone have a good one catch
you next week see you guys later