hey what's up everybody welcome back to
my channel picked up this seed cleaning
machine not too long ago some people
call it a seed sorter and figured i'd
make a quick video showing you how it
works it's actually a few different seed
cleaning machines that you can find if
you search the internet this is a larger
design it's about three feet tall and
that works really well but i think i'd
go for the more compact one so here's
what it looks like it is pretty small in
size the dimensions are 18 inches wide
12 inches tall
and nearly 6 inches deep and i have it
just resting on two 5 gallon buckets so
pretty convenient basically the seeds
will be sorted into one bucket and the
plant material will be sorted into the
other bucket the plant material does
need to be very dry and completely
crumbled up so seed should be separated
from the plant material not really
connected to it because you're going to
place it in the machine it's going to go
down into the machine and the fan is
actually going to blow it from the left
up and over that'll be the light plant
material that goes into the bucket on
the right and then seeds are heavier
they're dropped down on the left the fan
that's connected to this is an ac
infinity fan just connected to my wall
outlet it's my first time ever using
this seed cleaning machine so i'm going
to start out by using it at medium speed
now different plants have different size
and weight of seeds so depending on what
seed you're working with you will adjust
the speed with the variable speed
controller okay so here i have my plant
material it's all broken up the best i
can i've got this little piece of wood
here it's actually a skewer just so i
can push the play material down if
needed and here i go i'm emptying the
plant material into the machine
and you can see the lighter plant
material is actually being blown up over
and into the bucket on the right and
then the heavier seeds are actually
dropping down into the left bucket all
right so i ran everything through you
can see some of the plant material is
actually blown out didn't actually go
all the way down it was stuck there
because it's so light the wind was just
kind of pushing it outwards looks like
we have one area here where seeds were
stuck so this design is certainly not
perfect all right removing the seed
cleaning machine here is what the bucket
on the right looks like the bucket with
the plant material and you can see a
whole bunch of underdeveloped seeds
and then the bucket on the left has all
of the good seeds well should be good
seeds i'm sure it's not perfect but you
can see a majority of the seeds are nice
and dark and there's a high chance that
they are viable just for testing
purposes i am going to take the bucket
on the right with the plant material and
all the underdeveloped seeds break it up
a little bit more with my hand i'm
actually going to dump it out onto a
screen and then break it up with my hand
i'm going to run it through the machine
one more time and i'm going to see if
there's any developed seeds that went
ahead and got launched over to the wrong
bucket okay so i ran it through again
you see the plant material in this
bucket and then the seeds in this bucket
looks like there are some clearly
developed seeds i know the color is
going to be real tricky so you can't
fully say it's underdeveloped just by
looking at its color some seeds may
still be like a gray color but still be
viable yeah i poured it out onto my
screen and just separated the remaining
ones by hand overall this machine is
going to save me a ton of time it
actually already did save me a ton of
time i could have been sorting this by
hand for hours i decided to invest into
this machine i'd love to know your
thoughts on this let me know down in the
comment section below if you're new to
my channel i would love to have you
subscribe this is my garden talk channel
i have my garden talk podcast on here
that is every single week sometimes i'll
do q a videos those get scattered on my
channel as i have time and every once
while there'll be a topic video that
shows up on this channel as well on the
outro card here the video on the left is
one of my recent q a videos and the
video on the right is automatically
generated by the youtube algorithm
thanks for tuning in everyone and i will
catch you in the next episode