they said within the study that not
using nutrients for the last 14 days
resulted in
no difference in yield potency terpenes
mineral content
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and i'm back with another video if this
is your first time seeing my face i
would love to have you stick around and
subscribe
this is my garden talk channel to where
i mostly do discussion videos topic
videos
i also have some grow like test videos
on this channel as well and then have a
separate channel which is my main
youtube channel
where i show off my plants let's just
get right into today's video
this is probably going to be my most
disliked video the reason why is because
this topic is highly debatable we're
going to talk about flushing
and by the end of this video you should
know some of the truth behind whether or
not flushing is actually beneficial
now when i'm talking about flushing i'm
not talking about flushing
mid-grow sometimes you'll have to flush
mid-grow depending on if you're using
synthetic nutrients for example
maybe you have overfed your plants and
you need to flush out some of those
nutrients
maybe you have a salt buildup and you
need a flush maybe your ph
is off some people flush because of that
i'm not talking about flushing midgrow
i'm specifically talking about the flush
that happens at the end of the grow
cycle
so when your plants are almost ready for
harvest some growers will do
what's called a 14 day flush now not
everybody sticks to that 14 day flush
some people do 10 days 7 days five days
and then you got some people who don't
actually flush their plants at all
so there are various opinions and people
have their own reasons for why they like
to do a flush at the end of the grow
some things i've heard about is flushing
to reduce the amount of nutrients
that are in the soil and also in the
plant so that the
overall final product has a good taste
smell and the ash when smoking is more
white
instead of a gray or black some people
say that flushing
reduces the harshness in the final
product i've also heard that flushing
increases terpene content thc content
there's many many reasons why people
flush their plants
and up until now there hasn't really
been any scientific studies
on this process so in this video i'm
going to talk about a recent
scientific study that was done on the
flushing process
at the end of the grow and they got a
ton of data and
shows whether or not flushing is
beneficial or not
so let's talk about the study so first
off this study actually came out several
months ago
it's not brand new information some of
you watching this probably already came
across this study
but i know a lot of my audience is new
growers so i'm pretty sure
a lot of this information is going to be
new to a lot of my audience so this
particular study was done by rx
green technologies and i got some notes
over here so you see my eyes
shift over here i'm just referring to uh
the notes that i have according to the
study
i want to make sure that what i'm saying
here accurately reflects what is in the
study now i'm also going to have a link
down
in the description section below to a
web page which goes over
the study entirely so what exactly did
they do in this study so they use the
strain
cherry diesel for the study they use
their own nutrients
and the plants were grown in coca-cola
and they did four different flush
periods they did a 14-day flush
they did a 10-day flush a seven-day
flush and
zero-day flush and each flushing period
had 12 plants so they had 12 plants that
did a 14 day flush
12 plants that did a 10 day flush 12
plants they did a seven day flush
and then 12 plants that day didn't flush
at all flour and fan leaf samples were
collected from each flushing treatment
on the first day of flush and the day
before harvest to quantify
concentrations of essential plant
nutrients
after harvest the plants were cured
before determining final trimmed
flower weight terpenes and thc
concentration
they even took the trim from those
plants and evaluated that they evaluated
the trim
for thc yield and the appearance of the
extract to determine smoking flavor and
characteristics
samples of each flushing period were
distributed to industry
experts in a blind taste test i want to
know where i sign up for this blind
taste test because it sounds like a cool
job
each participant received one sample of
each flushing time without knowledge of
its treatment
participants were asked about their
personal flavor preferences before
tasting after tasting participants were
asked to rate the sample of the flour
harshness of smoke and the color of the
ash data collected during the course of
the trial
were analyzed statistically to determine
whether flushing times affected
smoking quality flower weight or the
chemical characteristics
so those are the materials and methods
used for this study now let's talk about
what their results were
so they mentioned in the study visual
differences in fan leaves between
flushing times were apparent the day
before harvest
plants flushed for 10 or 14 days had
leaves that were more yellow
necrotic and dry than plants flushed for
0 or 7 days
the color of the 14 and 10 day flushed
leaves
indicate a greater breakdown of
chlorophyll in the plant leading to
reduced greenness
that right there is key that's something
that i want to discuss
at the end of this this is something
that
well yeah i'll just save it to the end
as for yield thc
and terpenes overall there were no
significant differences between
treatments for flower weight
thc or terpene content here are the
charts
showing the average weight per plant
average thc percent
and the dominant terpenes they also took
flower samples
taken the day before harvest and
analyzed it for the content of essential
plant nutrients
that's one of the things i mentioned
during the introduction is a lot of
people say that
flushing your plant you flush out those
nutrients from the medium and the plant
and that's one of them that contributes
to a greater smoke
they state overall there was no
significant change in the mineral
content of flower
as a result of different flushing
treatments here are the charts which
show the nutrients
flower concentration percent for 14 day
flush
10 day flush seven day flush and plants
that weren't flush at all
extraction results trim from the cherry
diesel was sent to an extractor
to determine extraction yield and prefer
characteristics of the wax
plants flushed for 14 or 10 days had the
highest extraction
yield compared to the seven or zero day
flushes
however the appearance of the wax for
the zero day flush
was preferred over the other flush
periods the zero day flush was the
clearest
so what they concluded on this part is
although increased flush times resulted
in higher extraction yields
the finished product was not as
desirable for extraction now remember
this is a commercial facility
i myself i'm a home grower when it comes
to wax
the clarity of the product for me
personally
i'm not going to be upset if one thing
of wax is a little bit darker than the
other
but on a commercial side of things it is
something that
apparently they look very closely at
let's talk about the taste and
smoke characteristics of the flower so
the cured flower was evaluated by a
group of
industry experts it'd be interesting to
know who these industry experts actually
are they don't mention it in the study
unfortunately so they evaluated for
flavor and smoking characteristics in a
blind taste test
overall the duration of the flushing
period had no impact on flavor
smoothness of smoke or color of ash the
seven day flush period had the highest
bad rating and the zero day flush had
the highest grade rating
most panelists rated the flavor of the
samples as okay or good
the 10 day flush had the highest ok
readings and the zero day flush had the
highest
good ratings most panelists rated the
samples as either earthy or sweet
so it doesn't actually say how many
panelists there were
you know was there two people was there
four people was there ten people
definitely think that was some important
information that should have been said
here
taste test panelists rated the ash color
and smoke quality of each sample
ash color was predominantly black or
gray smoothness of smoke increased with
decreased flushing time
although it wasn't significantly
different i'm going to read their
overall conclusion
word by word i don't want to miss
anything on here in a first of its kind
study
arc screen technologies evaluated the
effects of a flushing period on
yield potency terpenes mineral content
and taste characteristics
of mj flower overall the length of the
flushing period
did not impact yield potency terpenes
or taste characteristics of mj flour
taste test results indicated a trend
towards improved flavor and smoke
quality with the zero day flush
while there were no significant
differences in nutrient content there
was a trend towards increased iron and
zinc and flour flushed for 14 days
the result of this trial indicates that
there is no benefit to flushing mj flour
for improved taste or consumer
experience okay so that is what they put
in their study
so what are my thoughts so the very end
of the study the last
sentence that they put here is the
results of this trial indicate that
there is no benefit
for improved taste or consumer
experience okay improved taste
consumer experience got it but if we're
talking about flushing as a whole
they did list off some benefits in their
study right they said within the study
that not using nutrients for the last 14
days resulted in
no difference in yield potency terpenes
mineral content and taste
characteristics then why use nutrients
for the past 14 days
if you're not feeding the plant for the
last 14 days well then you're saving
money on nutrients right
and you save time by not mixing
nutrients i know in a commercial
facility
they have different processes it's
probably well streamlined
here for me as a home grower mixing
nutrients
definitely takes a little bit of time
right there are some synthetic nutrient
lineups that have three bottles that you
mix in and some have up to 10 bottles
that you mix in so mixing all those
bottles within water and then giving to
the plant
is definitely time consuming and doing
that versus just watering
well you're so definitely saving time
with just watering and like they said
not feeding nutrients had no impact on
yield that's one of the arguments that i
hear pretty often
is if you're not feeding the plant all
the way up to the end
then those last couple weeks you're
potentially losing yield this study
proved otherwise
so that's one thing now let's talk about
the harshness i'd like to know what is
the humidity or
the moisture content within the buds you
know as homegrown is one thing that we
hear pretty often
is that if your hygrometer is around 62
within the jars then the buds are at the
ideal level
for consumption now on the commercial
side of things they don't measure that
way
from my understanding they use a
moisture meter and they actually stick
it within the bud to find out what the
moisture content is
within the bud i don't know too much
about the process so if anybody works in
a commercial facility and can explain
more
please let us know down in the comments
but yeah i mean the drier the sample the
more harsh it is going to be on the
throat
if it was around 62 percent rh you know
in the jar with the buds
that's going to be a lot less harsh than
something that's more dry 40
30 rh that's definitely a contributing
factor to harshness
on the throw when smoked so i'd like to
know what the samples what the moisture
content was
what the humidity was in the jars that
they were sampling
another thing is how long did they cure
the buds for before they consume them
on the homegrown side of things we dry
our plants then it goes into the curing
process
now oftentimes i hear that you want to
do at least two weeks in the curing
process before you smoke the buds
even at that point i feel like i can
still taste some of the chlorophyll
i personally wait until 30 days into
curing before i consume
and even at that point i can still taste
some of the chlorophyll according to
leafly
it takes six months to a year in order
for those buds to have the true
taste and smell so how long they cure
for is definitely a contributing factor
to harshness in my opinion
and one of the things that they
highlighted in the study which i said i
was going to refer back to at the end
was the color of the 14 and 10 day
flushed leaves indicate a greater
breakdown of chlorophyll on the plant
leading to reduced greenness so i'd like
to know
was it a faster cure for the plants that
were flushed
14 days 10 days versus the plants that
were had a zero day flush for example
that's really the main reason why i
flush my plants
if the chlorophyll breakdown process is
happening while the plant is still alive
and you harvest a plant where it's
mostly yellow leaves
that should be a faster cure than if you
harvest a plant with all green leaves
so that's one thing i really think that
if they included the chlorophyll
breakdown they had that
sort of measurement within the study
that kind of would have been the icing
on the cake
but they didn't measure the chlorophyll
amount during curing so
i have to save that for another study i
just want to say that i think it's
awesome that they did this study
and that they're sharing the results
with the public i personally don't think
that we can truly conclude that flushing
has
zero benefit but i do think that the
study is absolutely a step in the right
direction so thank you to rxscreen
technologies for doing the study and
sharing with all of us
i'd love to know in the comments section
below what are some of the reasons that
you heard to flush at the end of the
grow
what do you think about this study if
you currently flush at the end of the
grow
after hearing this information are you
going to continue to flush or are you
not going to flush anymore i personally
love to read studies about this
so if any of you have any links to any
studies that have been done
it doesn't have to be about flushing it
could be about any grow process
please link them down in the description
section below and maybe i'll make a
video on it in the future that's pretty
much it for this video guys if you
enjoyed it please click that thumbs up
and i will leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
peace
[Music]
you