coming up on garden talk the ai is it is
people training those systems then
everyone could have the power of those
expert opinions via computer vision
without a person actually looking
personally at their plants one of them
would be a ph either increase or
decrease you typically don't need both
you'll find you want to correct one
direction only i built six scales which
are all wi-fi enabled or part of the
system and every minute they report
their weight
you really shouldn't actually have a
clogging issue if you always have a
pre-filter by the way for your pump
automation is there to help you to
enable you
and to do a lot of the things that you
don't want to do
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 37. in this
episode i interviewed simon the creator
of the plant studio many of you like to
automate your garden in some way whether
that be through auto watering
environmental controls there are so many
different things you can do to automate
your garden in this episode we talk
about the future of gardening complete
automation simon has developed a way to
just about completely automate your
garden so you the gardener can be hands
off most of the time thanks to all of
you who support this podcast through
patreon if you'd like to support you can
do so by going to patreon.com mr growit
before we get into it i want to
acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of this
podcast who helped make that goal
possible
big shout out to dutch pro for
sponsoring this podcast dutch pro is a
plant fertilizer company that has been
around for over 30 years they have base
nutrients and they also have additives
such as pk boosters root stimulators
calmag silica a nutrient optimizer and a
foiler feed they also have ph regulators
to help ensure that the nutrients can be
uptaken properly i will leave a link to
dutch pro's amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr grow 10dp for a
discount on their products
thanks to spider farmer for sponsoring
this podcast they have board style led
grow lights bar style led grow lights
grow tents
in-line fans and carbon filters they
also have complete grow tank kits which
include lighting a ventilation system
grow pots a trellis net a timer
and a monitor for both temperature and
humidity coupon code mr growit5 will get
you a discount on their products and
i'll leave a link to their amazon store
down in the description section below a
big supporter of this podcast is ac
infiniti they sponsor this podcast and i
use their products
ac infinity now has gardening tools and
accessories such as heavy duty fabric
grill pots
trimmers grow room glasses drying racks
plant ties and trellis nuts
they also have all of the equipment
needed for a ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr growit during
checkout for a discount on their
products all right we are back welcome
to the garden talk podcast today i am
joined with simon he is the creator of
the plant studio how are you doing today
great thanks thanks for having me chris
yeah thanks for coming on my voice is
still a bit raspy apologize for that
luckily simon will be doing most of the
talking in this episode so you won't
have to deal with my raspiness yeah i'm
excited for this one today uh we're
going to talk about the future of
gardening so complete automation you've
done quite a bit of work with an
automated
system
box whatever you want to call it an
indoor growth setup called the plant
studio and before we get too far ahead
you're going to be talking all about
that today and just automation in
general that can be applied to you know
homegrown in particular i feel like
before we get into the details on all of
that though can you tell us a little bit
about yourself and kind of how you got
into this space
sure yeah my name is uh simon romanski
i'm uh live in massachusetts i'm
originally from england that's where my
accent comes from uh i've been growing
for a few years
i
i think i got into growing i mean i'm a
technical person so i think i got into
growing when i was um in disneyland i
think it was that it was epcot and
there's a ride called the living land
which is a ride that goes through a
greenhouse and i remember looking at
all these different methods of growing
and
it just looked very technical and it it
just i was blown away by it and in
particular i remember the aeroponics uh
section they had these plants on the
this track that would uh revolve around
and they would be suspended they're just
holding the plants and the roots are
just dangling in the air then they would
take them through this little chamber
where they would get their
mist their water and nutrients basically
and i i just was blown away the fact
that you know plants could even be grown
that way so i think the it's always been
the technical that interesting uh you
know different side of growing that i
found interesting and really what got me
started at least um i do think a little
differently after growing uh it's not
all about the hydroponics i'm definitely
a fan of lots of other you know living
soils and things like that so um but
that's basically where i really think i
got my my start from
nice nice and i know before we started
recording you talked about how you went
to school for is it engineering uh
mechanical yeah or software engineering
or can you talk to us about that
yeah i went for um it was information
management and technology and basically
it's almost it's a went to syracuse um
and
it's a cross between computer science
and management so uh i always say i
don't consider myself a programmer more
of a developer so i like
making solutions with technology as
opposed to just
you know
i don't write the uh the drivers for
stuff and all the the super technical
stuff but there are so many tools and
frameworks and apis and things out there
that i love kind of
putting stuff together in order to solve
problems so that's that's really that's
what i went to school for and it you
know it's it's been a fit for me ever
since gotcha you talked about what you
just mentioned it kind of relates to
what i used to do i used to work for
amazon.com worked in the fulfillment
center for eight years i was actually in
their support side of things too working
with worldwide operations but one thing
that they do in their fulfillment
centers and i'm sure there's some people
watching this that have worked at amazon
or work at amazon right now but
they pound in your head like the process
improvement side of things like
streamlining so my mindset has always
been like how do we make things more
efficient how do we automate things to
reduce the amount of labor hours that
are are put towards a process
yeah so
that was actually my first job was and
um
was working in fulfillment i worked at a
fulfillment center
and i like the
um
the order and inventory management
and and the back end seeing the packages
and the orders and inventory came in and
basically what i did for this company is
i kind of webified them um it was uh
dating myself a little bit it was a
while ago where people were still like
that the internet built some people
didn't even have uh dedicated internet
access uh you know continuous internet
access and um
i basically had something uh wrote
some web tools and a web application to
allow clients
to
look and check on inventories inventory
and orders themselves without having to
call the customer service rep because
when i started all these calls were
coming in i thought that's crazy why why
are you calling you should be able to
just look that up yourself
so that's kind of where i began was
really fulfillment and again i just like
the
solution providing i like going back in
the you know in the warehouse because i
worked in the front office and
seeing
were those pack slips or did it make
sense for
the pic pack ship part of the
fulfillment and so yeah that's
similar also with the with the
fulfillment
yeah so definitely some similarities
there and then you took those skills and
now you've applied them to horticulture
which is pretty cool can you give us a
high level overview of the plant studio
that you have created
yeah i'm sure it's a
it's a cultivation machine and it's
basically there to control
everything above the ground and below
the ground it's not really ground
pots or chambers or whatever your grow
method is but
basically root zone and uh environment
above
and the whole point of it was really to
automate as much of the time consuming
stuff as possible because i you know
when it comes to watering i would forget
or if i'm away or if uh you know did if
you're doing hydroponics and you're
wanting to monitor the the ph or um
water levels and temperatures and stuff
like that so basically i did it so that
i didn't have to spend as much time
doing the stuff that i didn't enjoy
doing i i didn't mind the plant
manipulation stuff but i don't like the
stuff where you have to constantly stay
on top of it or you know having to go
and manually change things in the room
environmentally
in order you know because
you know that the temperature's too high
the humidity is off or something like
that so that was that was basically my
i always say i'm i'm inherently lazy but
i'll also go way out of my way to try
and automate and to simplify it for
myself gotcha and actually on your
website i'll mention it right now so
people can check it out if they want to
and kind of get a visual of what we're
about to dive deeper into
it's www.plant
s-t-u-d dot io it's plant studio but
it's
you don't even need the ws it's plant
stud dot io
and so it
couldn't get the dot com but uh you know
i kinda like the dot io makes sense in a
way because it is all about you know
input and output so it's plant studio
with the dot before the io so check that
out if you are interested in that i'll
have in the link in the description
section below on youtube so you can
easily access that there's a great video
right on the home page which talks about
just a ton of things within a very short
period of time
about all this automation so let's let's
dive deeper into this let's start with
the grow area what size growth space is
it you know is and what is the plant
studio made out of
um well so the grow area is it's a five
by nine and it has um
uh
so basically a two light setup and uh
it's
eight feet tall because high always
becomes a big issue when growing you you
a lot of people especially indoors are
limited by the height size i'm pretty
fortunate to be able to have you know
pretty high ceilings um the overall
dimensions inside the the grow machine
is five by 12
but the that extra
three feet of space is there to
accommodate you know the air
conditioning dehumidifier fans and
and uh basically the equipment that
helps manage the environment and gives
me some space to actually to you know to
get inside the the machine uh to
tend to the plants
and um that the machine itself is the
the box itself is made by um from
insulated panels that i came up with
it's basically
wood that is
sandwiches
some high density insulated foam and
then these panels slot together to make
um you know to to make a well insulated
um and sealed box so they um you know
it's not your typical stick construction
like frame where people frame it and
then put it up and then insulate it
these are like panels okay so this is a
sealed environment just to confirm it's
a sealed environment you don't have a
an intake vent an exhaust fan
everything's just kind of recirculating
within that environment is that correct
yeah yeah i i actually uh i learned this
the hard way because
my initial grow um
was um
i didn't have any i wasn't considering
any kind of air circulation i mean
that's that's how clueless i was and i
went away i came back and um i was
growing tomatoes in the in the early
days and i basically came back and it
was just a horrible stink
and
i didn't know i thought something was
rotten and basically i realized that
when you
um
basically uh
drown or just deprive the plants um not
drown actually it's like just remove all
the co2 from the air
uh they are not happy just like we
wouldn't like you know getting rid of
our oxygen and they just make an
a crazy smell so when i smelled and i
realized i go oh
i i need to change the air then i
realized i had two different choices
and you can either and that's a lot of
the choices it's like do you circulate i
mean do you do you have a sealed room or
do you um circulate and bring in the
outside in uh environment
and um
in the end i just decided that a sealed
room is just much easier to control
and to maintain
because
i'm not pulling any i'm not dependent on
an outside environment that i'm then
pulling into that room
sometimes it might make sense it's
cooler outside i can bring the air in
and it could cool it down and it's to
the humidity builds up quickly and
sometimes you go well we've got to pump
the air out and get rid of that that
extra humidity
but then
um
again you're dependent on that outside
environment
so the trade-off though is then if
you're dealing with temperatures
typically you're going to be dealing
with cooling um because the lights put
off heat it's insulated so now you have
to cool
the heat of the lights you have to cool
that excess heat that comes off the
dehumidifier
because it does still put out heat just
despite the fact that it's got the the
cooling side you know it overall
generates more than it um removes
um but again the benefit was also
controlling the environment not pulling
any pests or any pathogens potentially
in
the down
the tricky part is making sure that you
can size the equipment
so that it is able to deal with
say
late stages of growth where your plants
are big and they're putting off a lot of
um they're transpiring a lot there's a
lot of humidity
and um the lights are full bright um
cranked up
and um
you know that that's that's a little
that that was a little tricky but um i
would say that my my one tip is as far
as
people being able to size correctly you
take take the wattage of all the things
that you have in that box
and then multiply that by four
and then whatever number you get from
that
is basically how many btus you would
need to
remove
that you would get so for me
about 3 000 my machine running at full
capacity uh with both lights on uh with
the air conditioning and the
dehumidification running and when i'm
running the large dehumidifier
there's about 3 000 watts max that that
runs so 3 000 times 4 1200
12 000 excuse me and 12 000 is
considered one ton so i i have a one ton
mini split and it's actually
more than capable of cooling because
you know with your watts
that is for also heat watch the the
like light a lot of that is going into
your photons and it's not coming off
directly as as heat so
it's good to over more oversized you
don't want to go too big but you
definitely have to make sure that you
can keep up with the the heat and the
humidity in that in the you know sealed
room that makes sense and just to
reiterate you said two lights that
you're running the leds
and according to your website that they
come in at 2.3 micromoles per joule so
you got some good efficiency there i
know people going to be asking this can
you tell us what diodes and driver
you're using for those lights i you know
i don't know i've had these for a few
years they're the fluence um
spider
the spider x plus and
they don't actually even make these bars
anymore which is almost unfortunate
because i
i'm definitely a big fan of the bar
style light fixtures
because
i believe it's
most closely represents the sun
and when it comes to like uh penetration
of the light for your plants
if you've got my whole ceiling basically
there's like 16 bars that go from the
back to the you know all the way across
the grow area and
the sun is basically like a giant beam
coming down it's not it as much as a
spotlight it's a point
as far as we're concerned the photons
are coming um
they
they're not coming from a point um
it doesn't it's
it makes a lot more sense and
um
the other thing i liked with the leds um
is that you can get them a lot closer to
your plants um i i
depending on what style of leds that you
use
it will vary how much
how many how much your photons drop off
based on the distance
because the fluents don't have the
lenses on these
the diodes
i find that the the drop off in your ptm
ppfd is really
um
if the photon rate drops off a lot
if you just for every foot you you bring
it up
so you know i do play around with
dimming the lights but then also being
able to bring the lights
down closer to the canopy
using less electricity generating less
heat less air conditioning to require to
cool it
but again towards the end those lights
are just
just cranked up and uh the plants they
they don't care they they want as much
as you can give them
gotcha that makes sense a couple more
things about the actual equipment and
setup before we dive into the actual
platform so with the sealed environment
generally speaking i think a lot of
people know this is you gotta run co2 i
believe you're running co2 tanks
inside the studio you probably have a
you must have a humidifier dehumidifier
can you talk to us about the equipment
and then also air circulation can you
talk to us about how all of that is kind
of
set up within the space and how the air
circulation is achieved in there yeah so
um
uh the the co2 side of things i have two
tanks uh that sit outside they uh piped
in and the co2 which naturally drops uh
there's uh two tubes above the fan which
sits at one end of the which is the
machine side of the the system side of
the studio
that
blows the co2 and circulates it around
as it's needed i have a sensor that can
be raised and lowered um
manually from the machine side
that i keep at basically canopy level
so that co2 sensor is basically i'm i i
do run elevated co2 levels um
which is a big benefit of having a
sealed room
and the other thing is that
because the room is so well sealed
that for an entire grow i won't
use maybe 10 pounds of co2
and i think a lot of people struggle
with
tanks saying well you know i'm burning
through tanks all the time but when the
room is really well sealed
um it's it's
very it's a minimal
overhead um i did have one at one
situation where my tank did run out
and um what i ended up doing was you
know i have a secondary tank when it
detects that one tank is is you know
when when when the tank is on
and the system sees that the co2 levels
aren't rising it will then assume that
that tank is empty and then flip over to
the
the secondary tank because again you
know what happens if the co2 runs out
and you don't want to just change out
your co2 before it totally depletes just
uh just in case because you know you've
got extra co2 in there you might as well
use it until it's gone so i i have the
redundancy in the on the co2 and the air
circulation currently i have a fan that
um
an oscillating fan and it's a small room
and it does really well at keeping
pretty good airflow in there i also have
a carbon filter
and it is they it pulls the air from
lower down
um and basically goes up it's it's a 10
inch pipe and then shoots that air
over the over the plants also so it's
kind of constantly stirring
but even with those two systems i find
that i think i could improve on air
circulation so my now my next upgrade is
i will have
two tubes going along the sides
on the floor and along the ceiling which
are connected
for the entire length of the box and
then i'll be circulating the air from
either
from the underneath
and and pulling the the cool air from
underneath bringing it up to the the
ceiling and um
sending it out that way across these
long pipes so it's not just blowing out
goes down the pipe and then comes out
all the holes in the pipe to give more
of a
trying to get more of a laminar flow
because they said with co2
for the plants to really benefit from it
doesn't need
a lot of agitation but it just needs
constant air movement and it's the
stagnant areas within the canopy that
become the problem uh it doesn't always
require just big fans blasting
everything just enough slow movement um
and and the plants uh supposedly fine
that's what that's what i've been
reading i always i do a lot of research
and then i come up with um try and come
up with a solution to see if that
actually helps and i'm still playing
with the idea of am i going to take the
air from the top
bring it down to the
floor
and let that you know hot air will that
rise
or would i be better off doing it the
other way around but
it's easy enough to flip the direction
of the fan and i'll be experimenting
with both ways and
figure out which which works best i
guess okay so that's co2 and air
circulation now for the
humidifier and dehumidifier that's
controlling your relative humidity and
also the heater and the air conditioner
that's controlling the temperature are
those pieces of equipment
inside the box or is it outside the box
everything is inside because everything
except for the co2 is inside the the
tanks for the co2 are external so that
and that gets uh pumped in i mean
um
all the electric work um is i have an
actual a sub panel on the outside and
then conduit that
goes into the surface mount boxes um for
the outlets and even those
are sealed um with foam
so that no air escapes
um
so yeah the dehumidifiers inside that's
also one currently i'm still using
your regular a regular dehumidifier and
i found that i um
when the the plants were smaller i did
better using a smaller
dehumidifier um so that it wasn't
cycling as much and then as they get
bigger i switched to a larger
dehumidifier and then if if when when
you can also the great thing with the
box it can also be used for for the you
know
post post harvest and in the drying
phase and when it that happens then i
actually switched to a um desiccant
based dehumidifier which is
uh able to deal with the cooler
temperatures
it doesn't have the volume
but you can have a much cooler
temperature and remove
um
i found it's just a lot more efficient
at for power usage and it just works a
lot better so
i also am planning on incorporating a
larger built-in ducted dehumidifier
um
so that um
again to to give more control uh you can
get dehumidifiers these days that are
wi-fi based so you can see if it's
getting you know if your humidity is
getting too high you could remotely go
in and and lower that
and
again with the bigger systems there's
always um a
control panel interface where you can
then take some electronics and i could
then take my computers my environment
controller and have those directly
control
the dehumidifier rather than just having
it constantly on and turning it on and
off with turning the the outlet on and
off which can be done but isn't really
an ideal way of of doing it gotcha we'll
get deeper into the environmental
controller and the
studio platform in a minute here last
thing i want to cover is can this system
be used for soil cocoa and or
hydroponics
yeah yeah because
really the the environment itself
which is just your your air temperature
humidity and co2 levels doesn't really
mind what method that you're using to
grow
uh aeroponics was my initial because i
thought
well it's a great way the roots get tons
of oxygen this way and i don't have to
deal with the media
at all
and so
that's one less thing to deal with
and i've had great success using
aeroponics um and it's it is kind of a
crazy way of growing because you you
missed the roots for for three seconds
every three minutes
and besides that they're just dangling
in
the dark
and you know this is high pressure
aeroponics this is not like your typical
cloner that has those little ray red
nozzles um just
spraying constantly this is a highly
atomized um mist
with um
special nozzles and it's that that it's
very fine and the mist
um the emitters are at the bottom and as
they
uh they fire they would they
they they circulate and it really swirls
around inside and it stays suspended for
a while before it even settles so it's a
great way of basically touching all the
different like all the the parts of the
route and getting great coverage um but
again i my last my last grow was in
cocoa which was just a departure i
wanted to try something different
because i didn't want these big chambers
and plants locked into a chamber i
wanted to have some flexibility of
plants and being able to actually move
them around
and
so i did a coco grow
and um my but my next grow is actually
going to be using a living soil and
i've got uh
a whole different a whole new system set
up that that i think is going to be um
interesting to see
you know what what i can produce
using uh using that setup gotcha that's
pretty cool that you built in the
flexibility to be able to use the
different types of mediums like that
right because they are
they are certainly different
in numerous ways
and you've incorporated the different
ways
within the plant studio platform so can
you talk to us about uh plant studio
platform
yeah that the platform this is the
almost the hardest part to understand of
the system because it's the
this is where it's like my my background
as a web developer
is um it's the computers and there are
basic there are three computers inside
the or
in
three computers for the gross system
one of the computers is controlling the
um
the lights the temperature the co2
humidity managing basically everything
above the you know it's that when do the
lights come on and off
um
and you know what's your nighttime
temperature
um
and uh what co2 levels you know turning
the co2 uh making sure the co2 doesn't
run at night time
um
so that that's the the environment
controller the reservoir controller
separate system totally non-dependent on
the environment controller
that has the
manages or monitors the ph
your ec
temperature the depth
um sensing all the different um
attributes of the of the reservoir and
the way it actually does that is
i have a circulation pump and it pumps
through
uh pvc pipe and that's where the sensors
are so instead of putting the sensors
actually in the reservoir itself
it circulates the reservoir
and
senses those
variables the values um
as it does so
and uh the idea was also
when i do um dosing and and things like
that it also serves as a the circulator
is also a mixing system
and it makes it easier to if you wanted
to switch something out um and also with
the reservoir level going up and down
how do you you know keeping your scent
making sure your senses are always in
the water is obviously important
so the um the system is able to fill and
drain itself automatically and this was
something that was this is one of those
ones where i just got tired of trying to
you know i didn't want to carry buckets
around and empty it that's the pain that
is hydroponics and um
so the
um
it can drain almost totally empty the
reservoir but also when it fills it i
can then specify
how much i want to put in and i actually
do everything based on liters instead of
gallons and it's not because i'm english
because i did grow up with you know i do
i do think of everything in gallons but
when it comes to dosing
everything seems to be done in
milliliters i mean sometimes you would
get those tablespoons or you guys a
tablespoon is that a teaspoon and it get
you know but
now it's all milliliters and you know
liters a thousand liters so it gives you
a better idea of proportions
um but again it's been great that when i
go to fill it up 25 gallons is maybe
close to about 80 liters or something
like that so i just say 80 liters
it just puts that water in and then i go
and dose from there and so you know the
dosing side of the reservoir controller
which again is this little computer
controls
i have five
pumps and they you can choose whatever
liquid you want to
mix in and typically you'd have your
a and b
multi-part nutrient and then maybe some
micro or i have a cal mag
and then you'd have one of them would be
a ph
um either increase or decrease you
typically don't need both you'll find
that you got a drift in one dir you know
you you want to correct one direction
only
so you know one of them is a ph
adjuster and the other or all
nutrients or additive um
based and those inject
in line with that circulator so after it
goes by your temperature your ph and
your ec
there is and you'll see
in the video it's the the clear acrylic
piece of pipe
the
the drops going in that's dropping into
the circulation
of the um
of
where the you know where the sensors are
basically
so
that's the the
um you know the the reservoir controller
and um
what's nice is with the computer part of
it then is like i can then specify a
program and saying all right
at this time empty the reservoir put
this many liters into it
dose this much into it of a
wait until you see that the ppms has
stabilized so that you know that it's
well mixed and then once you see that
the the ec has uh stabilized then going
to your next uh your b nutrient and then
once that's stabilized you could specify
time or say let it see if it's
stabilized before doing the next one and
then it goes along and then with the ph
again you can i
a lot of it is just algorithms different
algorithms for ph
and um
but the whole thing is basically
set my reservoir up
so that it's ready then to feed the
plants
so that's the reservoir controller
totally independent of the environment
controller but then for the human side
of things now that that's the control
it's like the human interface that's
where you can manage its base uh pretty
basic i can go in and turn the lights on
turn the lights off um with the you know
and i could
turn the fans on circulation pumps and
what have you
um so that's the that computers to
control it but then also to monitor it
because
all this information every single minute
the system reads
every value
and so in a day i'm getting about 40 000
data points at every minute what is the
temperature what's the ec what's the air
temperature what's the co2 level what's
the depth of the reservoir
what's the the
air conditioner or the the watts of the
dehumidifier because i track the power
usage of things like the dehumidifier
because that enables me to see if i've
sized it correctly if i see that thing
is peaked and running all the time then
you're going to need a bigger
dehumidifier
or it's set up incorrectly where it's
short cycling because
uh something's blowing on it or it's
it's just not moving the air properly so
the the human interface part
is
again it's gathering the data but also
it's what and again you can see in the
video it shows that the graphs it's what
i'll put up in my bedroom up on the tv
and i'll be you know live streaming you
know i have here's exactly showing you
know gauges what what my current ph is
and if it gets too high
it can send off an alert but it also
changes so i have everything kind of
green when things start going red that's
a problem so um also with this human
interface component um computer
it allows me to go back at any point in
time of the grow
and see exactly at that stage
what that environment was
so it gives me history for analysis so
every grow i have all that information
it might seem overkill to say well you
don't need to do it every minute
but with some of these systems and these
time series databases and things that
they have out there
it's
it's not that much information it's not
a hide a 4k video that's streaming it's
got more bandwidth in in probably a
minute than you'd you'd have in an
entire grow so
um
if you can gather that information why
not have it and again it's very easy to
then go back and with the you know with
a mouse i can just select a certain time
span
and it shows me all
the stage all the um the readings from
all the sensors
at that point in time and i think it's
just a a really useful thing to have so
that's really what people and i spend my
most time
using is the human interface the other
things just do their job i'm not that i
try and you know they they manage the
system gotcha you uncovered a lot there
so
you have a lot of control with this
plant studio platform i mean guys check
out the video that is in the link in the
description on the website you'll see
exactly what we're talking about what
exactly what simon just explained with
the graphs and so on and so forth now
for the reservoir controller you said
that's controlled on one computer and it
really sounds just so hands-off i know a
lot of people are probably listening to
this and their their ears are really
perking up because
it completely automates feeding entirely
and you can have several different
bottles hooked up to this
and it can dose and it can wait
for things to be stable then it could do
the next dose and then wait and it's
just i've never
seen this level of automation before
you know particularly on the homegrown
side of things i know there are some
commercial operations that are automated
i don't know how automated they are but
for the most part the fact that you can
actually
control the water levels right your
hands off on the water level your hands
off on dosing nutrients your hands off
on ph
right
and then you're even hands off when it
comes to your environment completely
because you have an environmental
controller i was going to ask you where
the probes are located within the space
but you have a you have basically a
controller of probes that hook up to the
environmental controller that's going to
automatically turn on and off your
humidifier
dehumidifier
air conditioner heater in order to
control those those measurements right
those variables
where is the the probes located for like
co2 and temp and
that's the one that is hanging i have
conduit that goes uh from the en
environment controller
which is it's just to the left of the
the wall mounted mini split
and
it basically goes along the ceiling
right into the middle
of the grow area
so
as i uh basically
that's not automated the raising and
lowering of that that sensor but that
sensor is the temperature humidity and
co2 sensor on on
um
on a wire basically
so that is hardwired to the environment
controller itself gotcha and then one
other piece which i don't i think you
might have briefly covered it is it's
shown in the video
is it automatically is calculating your
energy consumption and putting a dollar
sign to it right so it's telling you
literally it's having a water how much
water you're using putting a dollar
amount to it how much you're spending
for water
nutrients dollar amount electricity
consumption dollar amount
so you're getting down to that granular
level that will vary based obviously on
where you live in in the new england
water here is is pretty cheap um
california i know that's that's a
different story and the the electricity
is the the biggest
resource uh i do try i track the the
electric the co2 usage the water and the
nutrients because you know how many
milliliters you put in of each nutrient
i also have a database saying this is
the nutrient i got
i spent this much for the nutrient and
it has this many milliliters in it so i
know on a per milliliter how much is
that nutrient cost on a per milliliter
basis
so when i feed it i know how much that
that feeding even cost uh you know my
electrici my electric cost
when it is really cranking for me here
is about five dollars a day
is my is my cost and by having a sealed
room the ac and the dehumidifier are
kind of close to half
the other half of the lights
so that is the price that you pay
i have been thinking about you know ways
of you know using the winter uh the cold
outside can i use that as a means of
dehumidifying or cooling without
directly bringing that air in using some
kind of a chiller system and and making
it more efficient
however
for simplicity's sake having everything
in the room just um is definitely the
way to start um in a sealed room i think
it's a good way of starting you could
always go to air
exchange if um if it makes sense if the
environment is conducive
to that
but again i'm about knowing that it's
totally controlled and not being able to
have an excuse and saying well that was
a hot day and all the humidity has been
killing me i don't i you know this this
box could be run in any environment um
as long as the ambient environment where
the reservoir is obviously doesn't get
below freezing you know i can i have a
heater i have a chiller for the
reservoir which is outside of the
uh the studio box itself
so that that um
that's something that again i'm
constantly
trying to improve the efficiency
of the resources used for growing
and you know that's why i'm also
uh excited to try out the soil doing a
soil grow next
because um you know
my last grow i i
decided to put each plant on a scale
and
this is going to ask you about next is
if we could talk about the scale side of
things that's pretty mind-blowing as
well yeah so and that that's even
changed from from
that grow until now
initially the
the idea was how do i you know when to
water plants a lot of people would say
well you you pick them up and you you
get a sense of how you know the weight
and um gives you a better sense than
just trying to stick your finger in the
top and feeling how dry the soil is
and
so i built six scales
which are all wi-fi enabled or part of
the system and every minute they report
their weight
so when i
fertigate
i was using these covers
that have two misters in them and it
would water all the plants at the same
time
and
it worked great in the beginning
but
and and the nice thing is i could see
also by doing that that all the plants
were actually getting water if one of
them were to clog i've never had a
clogging issue you really shouldn't
actually have a clogging issue if you
always have a pre-filter by the way for
your pump i'd always recommend you have
to put a pre-filter on the pump
that really almost
mitigates um clogging issues
and um
so
all the plants i could see would be
getting
liter a few a couple liters when that
when they were smaller and it was very
accurate they all got the same amount
they their weight would all increase but
then as one plant would
um overtake and have different water
requirements of the other now i'm like
well i don't want to give them all the
same amount of water one needs more than
the other so i'd end up taking some of
the misters and i'd say hey give it to
this guy so he gets extra and he gets
one less because there's two misters per
plant but now you're going away from the
whole automation thing
so my latest setup that i actually
haven't run yet is a
manifold it's like an irrigation
manifold but um
but it's also why it's controlled by the
reservoir controller that can say
send water only to this plant
so now i can water each individual plant
um separately
and what that's going to allow for
is
you know you can try different
experiments i could let some plants if
they're all cloned then that would be
almost ideal because you could really
then understand different watering
patterns and how they affect those
plants do you want to do a deep watering
less frequently
small watering more frequently
and
the other part is that also because it
ties into the reservoir
i could then potentially
um
mix in the reservoir
a different mix
potentially for each plant so i could
put in
and i'm actually gonna have to downsize
the reservoir a little bit if i'm doing
on an individual plant basis
but by with a smaller reservoir i can
then mix up some nutrients send it to
plan a
and then i can flush that out or you
know empty empty um you know give it all
everything that's in the reservoir empty
it out and then
for the next plant
give it a different nutrient and maybe a
different quantity so again you could
then set up different
uh tests experiments for all these
different plants and that to me is a
great way of doing your uh phenotype
hunting because you obviously you know
you start with your genetics but
different
nutrients
what works for some might not work for
others
and this way i think it's a good way of
automating staying consistent because i
think a lot of people when you're
growing they go well i'm not going to
mix up a different batch for each
different plan but if it's automated
it doesn't then let the machine do the
work you don't you just sit and watch
and get an idea of you know what effect
that has that's still coming down to the
person to look at the plants to see if
it's a happy plant or not and um to see
what kind of results you get and that to
me as far as the gardening that that
seems like that's the the enjoyable part
of it
that's so cool that's really really cool
so the last piece i wanted to have you
talk about which is really fascinating
is the imaging computer you have that
inspects the plant health can you talk
to us about that
yeah so that's actually a separate
computer it's uh it's really a small
computer that i had hooked up to an old
slr that that i had and um you know the
they just you want a a good camera with
a good lens is gonna take much better
pictures and um
so
it's set up so that every 10 minutes of
the plant
plan of the plant's life
they have their picture taken
and the idea is that it only takes their
picture but it also stores it
on that monitoring computer
so
every at any point in time not only
could i go back and say what was i
feeding or what what was the ec and ph
but you can also see how the plants
looked
and the thing that i actually found that
i mean originally i did it because i
thought it was just kind of cool i i was
like everyone likes a time lapse i don't
know if you've seen the um amazing fungi
uh
showing on netflix and all those time
lapses are just uh mesmerizing yeah and
the the cool thing is i think
when you feed your plants
you can't see how they're doing at that
point of that how they're responding
but if you put it in a time lapse and
you get to look at them
over that even over one day you know you
know you've got your six pictures an
hour
and in a day you get to see
did they seem to respond well or not
because people seem to have a good sense
of a happy or an unhappy plan and
definitely seeing the growth
you can watch it within one day it's
pretty easy to see growth
just even at a 10 minute interval
pictures so again it's partly for i
thought it was cool
but i found it really useful so then i i
am able to run a script and at the end
of the day it can it can just generate
that day's time lapse or i could say
give me over the last three days or from
the beginning of the grow until now so i
watch time lapses all the time just to
get a feel for the plants and you know
just because it's kind of cool to watch
also i guess
yeah that is really cool i don't do as
many time lapses as i should a lot of
people like to see the time lapses in in
videos and i don't do many of them i've
only done a handful of them i know
there's a lot of content creators that
do a lot of time lapses but that's
really cool that you're able to add that
into your automated system and you know
for planned health purposes so you can
see how well your yeah is doing as far
as the health of the plan yeah that the
other part is um i should have mentioned
is
it's also a great way of
again if you have a high enough res
picture being able to take something and
then maybe identifying
plant issues that you're having
deficiencies uh over watering is that
underwatering like sometimes you can
look at a plant and you get a sense of
that so
that's also something i continue to grow
i do want to get it so that i can
getting closer on the individual leaves
so that you can start to identify
what you know what might be going on
with the plant itself uh from a health
standpoint so that's that's the other
aspect i think is useful uh ideally i'd
love to tie it into some kind of a
computer vision where the system can
kind of look and go
that looks like you've got a calcium
deficiency that looks like that's um
you know it's been over watered or
underwatered or that whatever the
problem may may be
and um again i i know some people might
say well you know that's going to take
an expert a person
in order to be able to identify that but
people have to realize too that with the
computer vision
a lot of that stuff and the ai is it is
people training
those systems
so it's really is a person
takes pictures and they say
this is this problem and this looks like
that problem and after you've given the
machine enough of those
it gets better identifying it itself so
then everyone doesn't have to be an
expert on that you can have experts who
have identified these issues and then
that
gets then everyone could have the power
of those expert opinions
via computer vision without a person
actually looking them personally at
their plants so i do think that the
ai and the machine learning stuff
is is a fascinating and definitely a um
we'll definitely be seeing a lot more of
that um and it's it's already been done
quite a bit also nice nice
so when will this plant studio be
available and you know how much does
something like this cost
it's it's not currently available um
unfortunately um it it and
it's something that
it's difficult because it requires it's
a large
box it's a large machine but also
requires um an electrician
to bring in um
you know a circuit
i have a
30 amp 240 volt
circuit going to a sub panel
and again i'm not an electrician so i
have to have an electrician hook that up
if you have the mini split depending on
the distance that you're running it
you might have to you you have to have
someone come in who has
access who can charge it with the um
required refrigerant
to get that going so it's it's kind of
like you know putting an addition on a
house or something you need like these
these subs to the who can all do their
part um
you know to to get everything going um
it's not to say i wouldn't like to get
to that point
um and that is also why i've made a lot
of the like the the reservoir controller
itself
i made i didn't want to cut out with
wood so i actually got a cnc machine
learned to use a cnc machine designed it
had the cnc cut all the parts out and
then put it together
so it was a perfect fit so it works well
for replication i've never replicated it
again using that yet i've still because
i i've been getting into the details of
the software and stuff
but um
you know and it
it's it'd be pretty expensive because a
lot of the components that i use are
really good but one thing you have to
keep in mind is
you need good sensors to get good data
if your ph sensor is not accurate
it's garbage in garbage out
so you you need good quality information
and
if you want the efficiency of
the air conditioning you need something
that's going to be have a high seer
rating it'll cost you less to run it
you could do it
less expensive units and stuff
so um i know it's not exactly answering
your question
but it is something that i i do think
about and i um
i you know i am um
definitely definitely working on it for
sure gotcha yeah even if it was just
individual components you know whether
it be the controllers or even like the
software right i'm sure people would
loved i'm sure people are listening to
salivating how the software is
and how uh you know automated it can be
you know just if it was a plug-and-play
version where you could attach your own
equipment that you have in your growth
space to the software i think that would
be extremely beneficial so hope to see
something like that in the future
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future
um
my email my easiest ways to email me is
my email simon
romansky.com that's
uh s-i-m-o-n at roman ski.com
plantstudio
dot planche.stud.io
is my uh website
and um i'm planning on doing i want to
do more
social media and and interact more with
people like minded people out there or
even people who could compliment what i
do i i don't consider myself
to have a green thumb
i am able to automate and i i've learned
a lot from youtube and uh listening to
shows like yours as far as the the more
the cultivation side of things but i you
know my angle and my what i bring really
is the the systems and the the
automation to it so
you know i'm
basically just i also want to help
people understand that automation
it seems complicated
and some people go well it's also prone
to error and if that doesn't work then
then it's gonna you know then then
what's to happen to my grow
but i think most people will find that
is there to help you to enable you
and to do a lot of the things that you
don't want to do
you know i'd say don't carry a bucket of
water from one to another even something
as simple like using something like um
some of these diaphragm pumps you can
get for 50 bucks
that has a built-in pressure switch so
you can stick a hose in a bucket
and it self primes it pumps the water
and sends it to where you want to be use
something like that don't don't make it
hard on yourself
so use some of the stuff out there
make your and enjoy it more i would
start at least monitor and get get an
inexpensive camera to look at your your
grow
and you could even pan over to a
temperature and humidity sensor that's
just a standalone sitting there and now
you can remotely see it and you can get
these cameras for like 35 bucks that can
pan and tilt and they want you to get
the subscription for it but if you're
just doing a live view to check on your
plants and see what the current
environment is
why not do that it's a very inexpensive
way of being able to kind of
have some remote
access to your grow and to give you some
hopefully comfort that that everything's
going well so you know that that would
be my
advice um for people and again people
feel free if any of this is interesting
and would like to reach out to me you
know please do so i'll leave a link to
simon's instagram page on instagram as
well i'll link that down in the
description section below and also a
link to the website will be down in the
description section below if you enjoyed
this video click that like button if you
haven't already subscribe to the channel
release episodes every single weekend
i'd love to know in the comments section
what type of automation do you have in
your garden let us know down in the
comment section below lastly if you are
tuning in on apple podcast please leave
a rating and review we are coming up to
i believe 200 ratings and reviews so
almost there need your help to get there
and thank you to everyone who has left a
rating in review so far simon thank you
so much for coming on to the podcast
today this has been an eye-opener and a
sense to know that there is this
automation being worked on and things
will be easier for people in the garden
you know particularly indoors and i'm
excited for the future so thanks for
coming on and thank you so much chris i
really i appreciate
you uh having me on to talk about this
stuff and um thank you thanks a lot it's
been great
absolutely all right enjoy the rest of
your day
you