welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned into the garden
Talk podcast this is episode number 129
in this episode I interview Dr TSA saldi
she is a chief science officer of Tumi
genomics and is an expert in molecular
biology with the focus on on RNA biology
within this episode she talks in detail
about a pathogen that has infected a
large percent of both commercial
facilities and hom gardeners around the
world everything from what the pathogen
is how it's transmitted its symptoms and
so much more if you want to see short
clips of these podcast episodes search
Garden talk clips on YouTube I also have
a gardening Channel where I show the
plants that I grow I'll have both those
channels linked down in the YouTube
description section below one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
information about in to the general
public that being said I'd like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible thanks to
AC Infinity if for sponsoring this
episode check out their controller 69
which can help automate your
environment's conditions it'll
automatically turn on and off equipment
to help control the temperature humidity
VPD light schedule and even the
oscillating fans click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about the controller 69 and
the discount code Mr Gro 15 or works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infinity.com stash blend stash blend
consists of several ingredients in one
so you no longer have to buy individual
bottles it includes corn steep liquor
seaweed extract humic acid beneficial
bacteria silica and micro risal fungi it
can be used in addition to your
synthetic base nutrients or be used in
living soil systems simply mix it into
water and water your plants with it you
can get it at stash blend.com link in
the description section below and use
the discount code the stash and we are
back welcome to the Garden Talk podcast
today I am joined with Dr tasa saldi how
you doing today I'm good how are you
doing pretty good thanks for coming on
to the podcast today today we're going
to get into an issue that's wiping out
commercial facilities around the world
73% of commercial facilities in the US
have been infected and just in
California alone 90% of cultivation
facilities research tested positive for
this viroid
what we're talking about today is hop
Lon vroid it's actually pretty scary you
know for a number of reasons which we're
going to get into in this episode but
first let's do an introduction can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening yes
absolutely so um my name is H tasa like
you said I am the chief science officer
of Tumi
genomics um so my background is in
molecular biology and um specifically in
a type of biology called RNA biology um
and what my background looks at is how
the the shape or the structure of
certain molecules can impact um cellular
metabolism and um so this is pretty on
point for um hopon vroid um because this
particular pathogen enacts its um
pathology based on its uh
three-dimensional shape or its secondary
structure um and so that's what I did by
graduate postdoc work on um so uh we
founded our company Tumi genomics a
little over four years ago and um we
moved into helping cultivators um
identify pathogens and um especially
this particular
pathogen um maybe about three years ago
um and basically we had somebody who was
running a nursery contact us and ask us
if we could help them identify this
particular pathogen um we were all
molecular biologists actually working on
um we started in cancer and then we
moved into covid um but we agreed you
know we could definitely help um
identify this as well um and once we
realized the breadth of this issue and
how critically you know um cultiv the
cultivation industry needed to have good
Diagnostics um more research to
understand this particular pathogen um
we kind of found our home as a company
and so um that's what we've been doing
for the last three years is um you know
research collaborations with Academia
with industry as well as developing um
you know reliable Diagnostics and even
some on-site testing to help cultivators
identify this thing um and and keep
their uh operations safe awesome so what
exactly is hopl and Vare break it down
for us and mention how does it differ
from other pathogens yes absolutely so
um hop plate and viroid and viroids in
general are um one of the strangest and
I would say most interesting organisms
if you can even call them organisms out
there so um most organisms contain um uh
well almost all of them except for
viroids contain an inside part which has
their information so that's like your
DNA or in viroids case it's RNA which is
a molecule very similar to DNA but on
the outside of that information is like
a coding that keeps the genetic
information or the DNA RNA safe um from
the outside environment um and that
outside coating is generally made of
proteins or fats or both um and that's
that's um the same if we're talking
about funguses bacteria or even viruses
they all have um a coding like that so
viroids are incredibly unique in the
sense that they basically say I don't
need any of that protection stuff and
they're just literally free floating
information so um when you think about
viroids it's much more helpful to think
of them like um like an inert molecule
or contamination at a crime scene
instead of like a living
organism um and they're incredibly
incredibly small um and this makes them
very very contagious um and very easy to
pass from plant to plant um they are
very specific to land plants so for the
most part except for a few kind of
outlying Publications viroids are
exclusive to plants so they can't hurt
people if you were to consume a vroid or
you know smoke something like a tobacco
cigarette or something like that with
vroid in it um but they can be
incredibly damaging to plant development
and especially plant flowers got it now
people are hearing the word vroid and
I'm sure there's uh quite a few people
out there like viroid you mean virus so
totally different and you kind of
explained it is there anything else to
be said in regards to the difference
between a virus and a thyroid yes
absolutely so because thyroids are so
incredibly uh simple they don't actually
have the ability to do any type of
metabolism or even information to code
for a metabolism that allows them to
replicate so viruses have a unique
biology to them um which is why we can
make things like antivirals for example
because they're targeting something that
is different in in viruses than in the
organisms that the viruses infect but
viroids are so incredibly simple that
they don't have um that unique biology
so everything that they do is hijacking
the biology of the plant which makes
them incredibly difficult to Target
because it's very difficult for the for
whatever we're targeting to
differentiate between um the vroid and
the plant's normal biology um and so
that's why as opposed to a lot of other
things um there aren't really any
effective treatments or you know
anything that would would specifically
Target the viroid um at least yet so
they're very difficult to treat because
of that wow and taking a step back and
looking at the big picture what's the
economic impact from this vroid outbreak
yes yeah so um it's huge um there's an
estimate that uh for cultivation
facilities um acoss the board there's
more than a $4 billion loss um annually
and that's you know those estimates are
just mostly what's going on in the
United States um we found at Tumi
genomics that this particular vroid is
present on pretty much every continent
um we've tested plant material from
Canada um Africa Asia Europe um and it's
it's pretty much everywhere um and like
you mentioned at the beginning it's in
70 to 80% of cultivation facilities
ities um and you know you can see up to
a 30% loss uh with plants when they are
infected with this which um you know
accounts to a huge amount of money and a
a pretty prevalent risk for every single
cultivator out there so um it's it's
truly a pandemic at this point um in the
industry that's incredible um mostly on
the homeg grow side of things I think a
lot of my audience is but we do have
folks that are in commercial facilities
for example but y I can only imagine
what the impact is on the homeg grow
side of things yes there is a lot of no
testing happening you know particularly
I know that we're going to get into how
it can be transmitted I know seeds is
one of them but um yeah it's got to be
widespread amongst so many folks and
they probably have it they don't even
know that they have it right yes
symptoms let's get into that next plants
that are infected with hopl and vroid
what are the symptoms that you can see
on the plant yes absolutely so HL en
vroid has U we call it what it's called
as plyopic which means that there are a
ton of different symptoms um and it it
basically affects every system um of the
plant so different things that you can
see um it affects uh the the growth of
the plant so you can see the uh stunting
of the plant it also can affect the
shape of how it grows so as opposed to
like a normal Al 45° angle of the
branches coming off that main stem when
plants are infected with hopl and vroid
the stems tend to come out more
horizontally um you can see uh leaf
chlorosis misshaping leaves sometimes
the leaves will
overlap um sometimes they'll look too
shiny or depending on you know the
Pacific specific cultivar you're looking
at they can also um kind of turn a
little yellow or curled up um rooting is
another uh major issue for plants that
have hopl and vroid they tend to root
very slowly um and the root ball itself
is reduced in uh density um so if you're
you know if you if you plant a clone and
it's trying to root and it just taking
forever that's a really good sign that
that particular plant may be infected
with hopl and vroid um and then of
course it also affects the development
of flowers on plants and so the flowers
tend to be
underdeveloped um reduced in Mass um you
know reduced in in chemicals and things
like that and so um it it it kind of
takes down every system of the plant um
and it it it renders it you know
whatever whatever especially if you're
looking for medicinal properties from
that particular plant um those those uh
different chemicals are not being
produced and so the plant is not nearly
as useful from that standpoint wow so
hits the plant all over and yeah some of
those symptoms that you mentioned can be
done by other things right so you
mentioned like closis for example
there's a number of problems that happen
where you get yellowing leaves you know
hotblade virro is one of them Leaf
overlapping was an interesting one I
actually had a plant that had leaves
overlapping and I was like oh no pop PL
and vroid because I had learned that in
the past and so I actually got that
plant tested and it actually came up
negative so I was a little bit surprised
by that because I hadn't seen that in
any other cultiv ours that I had grown
but yeah the overlapping leaves was was
a really interesting one and then uh wow
root development slower smaller root
ball underdeveloped flowers stunning a
growth there just so many different
things that this vroid does to the plant
yes yeah but now I should mention that
um one of the trickiest and most
Insidious things about this particular
pathogen is that while all of those
symptoms are
possible um it's possible that either
only some or none will manifest in the
plant and so even if you're looking at a
plant and you're like oh this plant
looks great it looks super healthy
everything is fine um it's still
possible that um it's infected it's
definitely possible that it will appear
asymptomatic during the early stages of
growth and you're not going to notice
any changes until that plant goes grows
up into maturity and goes um into flower
and then often you'll see those symptoms
then and so it's important to understand
what the symptoms could be but it's also
important to realize that you may have
an infected plant and it it looks pretty
good and so the only way to be sure is
to get that test like you said so how
does hopl and vroid spread and what
measures can gardeners take to prevent
its transmission yes yes so hopl and
vroid like most viroids is spread um
primarily by mechanical means um so that
what this means for the most part is
it's spread most efficiently by us so if
you are trimming your plants for example
um and you uh take those scissors you
trim a plant and then you move to the
next Plant and you don't clean those
scissors first that um the sap from the
potentially infected plant can um infect
the non-infected plant and so that's
that's the most common way that hopl inv
vroid is spread um other potential ways
that it's spread um it can be spread
through the water so hopl and vroid can
Slough off of root cells or the root
cells Slough off and contain hopl and
vroid um there's a lot of HBL and vroid
and infected plants in the root tissue
and so if plants are sharing water like
if they're in a clonal tray or you're
doing some sort of flood and drain or
some system where plants are sharing
water you can uh transmit it like that
um it can also be transmitted through
seeds so there there's several studies
out now and we've also conducted a study
um showing that seed transmission of
this um in medicinal plants is somewhere
between uh 20% to
50% um it can also be transmitted in the
pollen to a smaller extent our our
numbers put at around 5% of the time if
a male is infected it can um cause the
seeds to be infected as well um and then
the final way the potential way is bugs
so this is research that's just coming
out of CSU um here in Colorado in Fort
Collins showing that there there are
bugs um I think their research was done
on aphids if I'm correct that um are
capable of transmitting hopl and virid
from plant to plant so um pretty much
the seeds water and anything that moves
plant sap from one plant to another is a
potential way that this thing can spread
uh through a facility or you know
between between plants in a in a home
situation so it's extremely easy to
spread yeah it is very it is very
contagious and it's it's very Insidious
because you can spread it and not notice
for several Generations like if you're
cloning a plant um sometimes you're not
going to see any symptoms until like you
know the second or third cloning and
then all of a sudden everything goes to
hell and you don't understand um yeah
and that that happened to us it we have
plants as well well and um before we
knew about this I think like everybody
else out there all of a sudden you know
the plants weren't weren't flowering
correctly they didn't look right and we
had no idea what was going on so it's it
happens all over from huge cultivation
facilities down to you know someone
who's who's growing at home wow and
that's where testing can be so important
and we're going to get into testing here
in a little bit but first I do want to
ask you how long can viroids survive for
yes yeah so um even though they don't
have that outside protective coat that I
was discussing they're actually
incredibly robust um the the shape of
viroids is it's a circle so it's like
closed at the end and it's kind of like
Velcro so you can think of it like a
velcro Circle that's smooshed onto
itself so it's more like a rod shape
than than some sort of free floating
like a noodle or something um and that
shape affords um a lot of stability so
studies right now show they only went
out to 24 hours but they're definitely
stable for 24 hours or more on most
common surfaces so that would be wood
plastic metal cloth whatever um they can
survive for uh up to 7 weeks in water so
um if you have water that's been sitting
around and you keep putting plants in it
that's um a potential spread there um
and they can last for um 3 months or
more in dried up plant material material
so it's really important that if plant
material falls on the ground or you get
sap on something that you're cleaning
that up right away um and then in seeds
we've we've tested seeds at this point
that were more than 2 years old um and
it does it does tend to decrease in
frequency of a of a Seedling that's
infected over time but you can still you
can still transmit it in the seed for a
long time years so it's very stable
incredible yeah I actually listened to
one year talks actually a couple of your
talks at Utah State University when I
attended there for cultivation
certificate that I have and um I took
notes on your talks and uh yeah you
nailed it on there a couple other things
you mentioned there was uh greater than
90 days in fermented compost and then
you also mentioned several months in
soil or growing medium yes yeah wow yeah
Y and it's part of the the hardest part
about soil is that HP and viid is
incredibly High concentration in the
roof and so when you're removing plants
from soil it's really difficult to not
leave some root material behind and so
um that's that's one of the hardest
things about growing in soil is is that
you it's difficult to remove those
infections once they once they've
established in there now are there any
plant species or cultivars that are more
susceptible to infection yes yes so hopl
and vroid um so in the wild so in nature
it has a pretty narrow Host range
compared to most other viroids um it's
uh infectious obviously in hops that's
where the name came from um it can also
infect stinging nettle and it can infect
um Industrial Hemp so um in lab settings
they've shown that they can also infect
uh things like uh pea plants and tomato
plants there is yet to be any um uh
literature showing that that's happening
out in nature but it is a
possibility um we also just completed a
study um looking at the susceptibility
of different cultivars to hopl and vroid
um and what we found was it was pretty
interesting there's some cultivars that
are incredibly sensitive so they're very
easy to infect they have really
pronounced symptoms um and there's a
huge amount of yield loss when they're
infected um there's also a battery of
cultivars that are what we call
resistant which means they were
difficult to infect the vroid didn't um
rise to a very high concentration until
like the very end of the plant's uh life
cycle or or when it's like finishing
flowering um and then there was a few
outliers um which I honestly find
slightly scary that were tolerant um so
there these were plants where they had
an incredibly high level of infection um
super easy to infect spread very quickly
but the plants didn't show any obvious
symptoms and there was no yield loss so
um it's great I mean it's wonderful to
have those plants because then you don't
notice any problems but they also are
basically a trojan horse so you might
think everything's great CU that plant
doesn't have any symptoms but then it
spreads it um to everything else so um
it it can go all over the map depending
on cultivar geez now in regards to test
what are the current methods for
diagnosing HL viroid infection in plants
and are there any advancements in the
detection technology yes absolutely so
um so the first important point about H
virid and viroids in general is because
they are only that genetic information
the only type of test that is capable of
detecting them is um basically a
molecular test if people were used to
thinking about covid there was the
antigen test and the molecular test
which was the PCR so for viroids it has
to be one of those molecular tests um
and the major the two major types of of
tests that are out there right now
there's a few exceptions to this but the
two U tests that you're most likely to
run into are what's called a PCR test or
um an isothermal amplification or a lamp
test um so uh both of these tests the
way that they work is they they find the
vroid in a tube
and um once it's identified the test
creates a ton of copies of the viroid so
if you if your there's two copies in the
tube what the test will do is make four
copies then eight copies then 16 then 32
and on and on and so at the end of that
uh copying you can have billions of
copies and then it's easy to detect um
the difference so they both do that PCR
and lamp the difference between those
two is that PCR um is a much more High
complexity test it requires very
expensive equipment that can cycle in
temperatures and it generally require
specialized expertise to understand the
results um lamp tests on the other hand
are much simpler they all run at a
single temperature and so that type of
test or isothermal amplification is
really appropriate for like a onsite or
an at home type of test um currently uh
PCR tends to be more sensitive more
accurate more reliable um and lamp tests
um Can often throw false positives false
negatives um you know and and a lot of
them don't contain an internal control
which means that you you can't tell the
difference between a failed result and a
negative result um
so what we've been working on at Tumi
genomics is kind of addressing that
particular issue um because what we what
we've been working on is trying to give
an option to uh you know people that
want something at home or on site that
can allow them to find the vroid in
their plants um but with a test that has
the type of accuracy and sensitivity
that you would need to be competent um
so one of the things that we just
launched at Tumi genomics is an onsite
testing platform called Tumi glow so
it's based onpo isothermal amplification
but um what we've able to do with that
particular test is increase the
sensitivity to the same range as the PCR
um the accuracy to the same range is the
PCR and it include an internal control
so um if you can tell the difference
between the test is negative and I
forgot to put plant tissue in the tube
or something like that so um yeah we're
really excited about about releasing
that or or having people uh look into
that because I think this can be a very
powerful tool in fighting back against
this path
that's awesome sounds convenient for the
average hom grower to get testing done
now like I mentioned earlier in the
podcast I actually got a test done on
one of my plants and I like to walk
through the testing process with you if
you don't mind sure so if I remember
correctly this was last year I had to
take Leaf samples off of I believe two
or three parts of the plant assume I
think it was top and bottom maybe middle
and also I had to take a sample of the
route as well and then send in for
testing can you kind of walk us through
that is that just for PCR or is that for
the isothermal test or what's the
testing process what would a hom grower
do to submit in a test yes absolutely so
um so uh to submit a test at least with
Tumi genomics um so we have specialized
collection tubes that we mail out to
people um the reason we do this is
because those tubes contain um a a
buffer in there that stabilizes the
sample so we don't have to worry about
stuff to grading it doesn't have to be
sent on Ice nothing like that um when
people are collecting samples so we used
to actually request that people collect
some samples from the foliage and
samples from the root but we've recently
switched to just requesting root um the
reason this is is that we've done um a
pretty comprehensive study that was then
confirmed by a bunch of different groups
that the most reliable and accurate
tissue to detect this particular
pathogen is in the roof
so um in the foliage if you're looking
for hopl and vroid you have a somewhere
between a 12 to 60% success rate
something like that um in The Roots at
least in our studies and what it appears
to be in the other studies is that um
it's close to 100% if a plant is
infected you're going to find it in the
root first it has the highest level um
and it's the most reliable spot so um
when people are uh testing it with the
PCR um they'll take root tissue put it
in a tube close it shake it up and
that's all they have to do they'll mail
it back to us um we can run the PCR in
the lab and then send them results um
for our on-site test it's exactly the
same we require root tissue for hopl and
vroid specifically you put it in the
tube close it Shake It Up um and then
you take some of that liquid out put it
in the reaction yourself let it sit in a
heat block um for some time and then you
know look at the look at the tubes and
um if you if it's positive the tube will
glow red to Yellow somewhere in that
range either red orange or yellow
depending on the the vroid load with
negative it'll glow green and if the
test didn't work it just won't glow at
all um so for both situations we focus
on root tissue because that's um your
best chance of catching it if the plant
is infected okay and then what's the
cost for testing yes yeah so um right
now for the PCR test um for the uh the
cost is $25 a test um we do have bulk
pricing if people want to get a bunch of
tests but the base cost is
25 um for the at home test those start
at 18 but come down very quickly um you
know if you buy uh multiple tests or or
buy in bulk so um yeah it just kind of
depends on which of those two options
you like better but those are the
pricing for those okay yeah 25 bucks
isn't bad I actually the other company I
went through was doubl in the price so
I'm GNA have to go through you for now
hunt so that's yes Tumi genomics. and
then you can c order tests I'm looking
at it right now do you do any tests for
anything besides hop lighton byid yes we
do we do we test um we also test for
ferium all the pathogenic forms of
ferium in medicinal plants as well as
the pathogenic forms of pythium in
medicinal plants and so those are root
pathogens that um quite honestly can be
just as damaging and in the case of
ferium perhaps even more damaging than
hop PL and vroid um and if you have if
you're growing indoors then those three
are the most likely 99% of all of your
pathogen issues um so we have we also
have tests that you can order one test
and it'll test for all three of those at
once which if you're if you're bringing
in a plant um you know whether it's you
whether you have a facility or you're
you grow things at home it's really
important to test and make sure that
it's not infected because the you know
the amount of time you're going to spend
you know months and all this material in
your personal time growing it um and
then to have it you know dieye a ferium
or or not produce well because of hot
plant um it's absolutely worth getting
tested um we do off also offer a whole
battery of viruses those that are known
to infect um uh medicinal plants those
are much more common if you're GR
growing outside so if you have a big
buck issue or you're growing you know
even in your backyard or something like
that then those are are significantly
more common because they're spread by uh
insects um and then we can also test
water growing medium and air so if
you're having an issue like if you have
a facility and you you have some sort of
fungal issues and you think that it
could be in your water we can help you
with that as well or in in cocoa or
growing medium or however you're growing
it um so the in lab we have a whole
bunch of different things that we can
help you with okay awesome good to know
now talking about strategies for
managing or controlling hopl and vroid
right so it's infected a plant what do
you do from there yes yeah so um
unfortunately in the case of hopl and
vroid there is no um cure there's
nothing you can spray on the outside of
the plant um to like make it go away or
fix it or suppress it um if you have a
plant that is highly infected your two
options are to either um toss it or to
submit it for a process called uh tissue
culture um which basically means that um
they clean up the plant by putting it
through a series of you know um tissue
culture steps um tissue culture does
work not 100% it doesn't work on every
single cultivar and it's a very
difficult procedure so um I know that
there are you know at home tissue
culture kits and things like that this
is probably not one of those situations
where um you'd be able to do this at
home um the best way to prevent it uh or
the best way to deal with it is to
prevent it allog together um and that
just involves not being afraid of it per
se but being aware that it that it's out
there and that there are certain steps
that you need to take to keep it from
entering into your facility or your home
or spreading from plant to plant
honestly this is one of the things that
really prompted me to clean my trimmers
every time between plants you know and I
was doing it a handful of time you know
now and then you hear about it you hear
it's the best practice going to prevent
pathogens and virus from spreading and
so on and so forth but you know as a
homeg grower you just go plant to plant
trimming doing your your your training
high stress training or defoliation or
whatever and using trimmers and not
cleaning them from plant to plant but
now knowing that the H vroid is present
cleaning the trimmers between every
single plant is something that I've been
doing religiously now yes and uh very
important yeah just to confirm what you
should be using for a solution now some
people say Okay isop Purple alcohol
that's going to be good enough other
people say no isop pural alcohol isn't
going to kill off the vroid you want to
use a bleach cleaning solution instead
and dilute it at a one to 10 one part
bleach 10 parts water what's your
recommendation for that yes absolutely
so um when we're talking about viroids
isopropyl alcohol or any alcohol is
probably the worst thing that you can do
um so it's not effective at all in
killing viroids and it actually um
alcohol is one of the things we use to
stabilize uh free floating genetic
information in the lab and so um it
actually increases the transmission of
the vroid from plant to plant if you use
alcohol so um when they they did these
studies um in I believe it was tomato
plants with a vroid and they showed that
if you do nothing absolutely nothing
there's a 75% chance if you don't clean
those scissors of spreading it if you
dip the scissors in isopropyl and then
cut the plant it goes up to
95% so um just throw the isopropyl
out use it for something else because
it's um it's not a good idea for viroids
and to be totally honest it's not 100%
effective on bacteria or fungal
pathogens either um um so you're exactly
right if you're trying to limit the
spread bleach is incredibly effective um
and that's that 10% solution that you
were talking about which is one part
bleach nine Parts water um when you are
going to get bleach you want to grab
that bleach bottle from the Super
Walmart or whatever and make sure that
it has 6% of sodium hypochloride or
higher so that would be the active
ingredient um and then when you get that
bottle home put a date on it and at 6 6
months uh you should toss it and get
another one because the activity will go
down over time um It's very effective at
killing vroid so all you need is 60
seconds um it's probably less but we
recommend 60 in case there's like goo
and stuff on the scissors that it just
needs to sit in there um and then the
viid is completely
deactivated um usually I recommend if
you're trimming a bunch of plants just
have several pairs of scissors you can
just grab one the others are in the
bleach when you're done with one plant
you put it in the back then you grab the
next one in the front um and so you're
always you always have a supply of
scissors that are clean um it it is kind
of CTIC on your cutting tools so if
you're concerned about them or they're
very valuable to you put them in there
for 60 seconds and then move them into
like a a cup of water tap water is fine
um that will that will keep them from
rusting very good info I appreciate you
sharing that with us yes absolutely now
you mentioned earlier it can last up to
seven weeks in water and IV Vision those
folks that are doing deep water culture
for example like a recirculating system
so hypothetically right if one of their
plants has up plade vroid it's in the
roots it gets dispersed into the water
all the plants are kind of being
infected there are there any best
practices in regards to like changing
out the reservoir or is it pretty much
like almost immediate and there's no
kind of getting around it as far as
infecting the plant via the water in a
deep water culture system
yeah so um there's no way to stop the
virid from sluffing off the root tissue
and then entering into the water and
like you said it's very stable in the
water um the amount that is going to
come off those roots is going to be
really dependent on how infected that
plant is so if it's a lowlevel infection
then obviously your risk to the other
plants is lower if the plant that is
sing off hbling thyroid is basically on
fire with thyroid then um a massive
amount is going into that water and your
chances of infecting the other plants is
much much higher um recirculating
systems deep water culture that's very
difficult and honestly if you're growing
that way the the best way to protect
yourself is to just make sure that any
plant you put in that system you test
first um that it's negative for hop
latent and honestly um pythium and
ferium as well which also spread
incredibly easily in water pythium is a
water mold it loves the water so um it
on those types of systems prevention is
critical I mean it's critical for
everybody but for for those types of
things it's even more important that you
test first okay so I got to ask what are
commercial facilities doing about this
right so they they have an effective
plan are they just killing off that
plant and all their plants and starting
fresh are there some commercial
facilities that are continuing to grow
out the plant because you said you know
there is a reduction in yield but
they'll still be able to get to harvest
and it doesn't harm the consumer you had
mentioned earlier it's like there's no
you know when you're consuming it when
you're smoking or whatever it's not
being transmitted to a human for example
so our commercial facilities are they
killing off plant population and trying
to keep their facilities clean or you
finding some facilities are actually
just like oh well okay let me segregate
this plant to a different room let me
continue to grow it out and then I just
won't keep any of the Clones off of
these plants yeah so that's a great
question and the answer is it's kind of
all over the map um and part of this is
because there aren't clear regulations
for cultivation facilities on how to
handle this kind of thing um you know or
or guidelines either and so um we work
with some facilities that are incredibly
diligent about testing everything gets
tested every mother you know just very
very on top of it all the way to
facilities that don't to test it all um
and just aren't concerned with it um if
you if there's a cultivation facility
where plants are identified that have
hopl and vroid um we have helped these
facilities deal with this issue without
having to basically you know blowtorch
everything and start over um and so the
the best way to deal with this is to um
consolidate your genetic Library so that
um you have two to three plants of each
cultivar um um and you segregate those
plants into a different space in the
facility which we call like the Garden
of Eden or your like nuclear stock um
and those plants are tested religiously
and protected from the rest of the
facility so um what you can do is slowly
move plants from your genetic library
that are clean into this special Garden
of Eden while you continue your
operations Downstream and some of those
plants may be infected um but you
basically kind of let them fall off the
end and go into flower and you're slowly
building up this genetic Library um and
eventually all the plant material will
come from this Garden of Eden and um it
will start clean and hopefully stay
clean through the entire process um
there are definitely facilities that
they don't have a choice they have to
flower the sick plants because they have
quotas to meet and it's a business and
they have money to make um but a lot of
times you know if you you
you know getting like lower quality type
stuff it's probably infected um because
it's it's incredibly common so that's
that's what if you if it's you know the
lower quality kinds of things it's
probably because it's infected with hopl
and virid okay and then on the homeg
grow side of things would there be any
different advice like what advice would
you have for those gardeners who receive
a positive test for hot PL envid on one
of their plants in their Garden yes so
from a homeg grower perspective because
because tissue culture is so expensive
and extensive um I would just get rid of
it it's not worth your time or your
money to grow that plant um and we we
did do a little experiment ourselves
where we just went out and bought a
bunch of clones and um just to see what
you know what we would get um from a
from different spots and um pretty much
every single one of them was infected
with something um now granted we were we
were probably picking ones that didn't
look terribly happy but um if I would
definitely when you bring in any type of
new material test it right away
quarantine it don't plop it right next
to your favorite plants or your favorite
strains or cultivars test it first in a
separate area um if it comes back
positive just go back to where you
bought it and say hey plant is sick with
something I you know give me another one
or my money back or whatever um but
whatever you do do not start growing
that uh with the rest of your plants
don't start sharing tools and water or
whatever until you confirm that it is
negative um and just to be incredibly
safe I would try to get two negative
tests um two to 3 weeks apart 3 to four
weeks apart some are in that range just
to make sure that um they didn't have a
low level infection in the
beginning it's just not worth growing it
if you calculate the amount of money it
takes to grow up a plant your time and
and the lights and the electricity and
the nutrients and then what you have to
do if it fails you know and and and
doesn't produce any any you know
medicinal properties then it's just not
worth the money to not test got it and I
should asked this earlier when we were
talking about testing but are you able
to test seeds yes yes we can we can test
seeds as well um and seeds are an
interesting thing because um the the the
flower of the plant tends to have one of
the highest levels of vroid and so um if
you have a package of seeds you don't
have to test you know all of them it's
you know because sometimes they're
pretty expensive for one package so one
seed from that package um is sufficient
for us to determine whether or not they
were they came from a mother or a father
that had hop PL and thyroid um but I
would I would definitely test uh your
seeds as well because that's another way
that it can get into your your garden
great to know is there anything else
that we need to know about hopl and
vroid um you know I would say just that
um I think there's a lot of fear out
there right now in the industry about
this particular pathogen um and it's
important to know that um this isn't
something that people need to be afraid
of um this is just something that people
need to educate themselves on understand
how it works um understand how it's
spread understand how to prevent it um
and then just put those uh systems into
practice you know make sure you're
keeping everything sterile and clean
don't let anything into your garden
unless you've tested it um if you're
growing a lot of plants routine testing
is probably a good idea um you know you
know if you're just growing a few you
know in your house or your garden then
you know at least test them before you
start growing them to make sure that
they're going to yield what you're
looking for um you know just remember
prevention is the smartest way to go
about um uh keeping this thing at Bay um
stopping it from entering in the first
place is a whole lot easier and a whole
lot cheaper than fixing a problem after
it's happened so um yeah there's a
solution to it there's no reason to be
afraid of it just um protect yourself
and uh you know it's it it's manageable
some good advice now there are many
other pathogens whether it be a virus a
vir viroid that's out there that can
infect a wide scale of plants right yeah
we won't get into them here but can you
kind of leave the audience here with a
little bit of cliffhanger what are some
other like pathogens out there that
people can look into and research like I
know there's beak curly top virus
there's lettuce mosaic virus there's
tobacco mosaic virus do you have maybe a
few more that you can list off that
people can look into yes absolutely so
some of the other viruses that have
published evidence to infect medicinal
plants are um like you mentioned beet
curly top virus lettuce closis virus um
uh tobacco streak virus Alfalfa mosaic
virus um um tobacco mosaic virus a lot
of people are afraid of this one um
there's no published evidence that it
infects medicinal plants naturally and
no published evidence that it can cause
symptoms in plants in in medicinal
plants so
um um I would say that those four that I
mentioned are the biggest threat current
um they're all spread um almost
exclusively by insects so this is
something that's much more like I said
on point if you are growing plants
outside um other potential pathogens um
especially viroids that exist in hops um
which have the potential to jump over
into other plants are um apple fruit
crinkle vroid pop stunt vroid and
crackling bark vroid so all three of
those um while there's no evidence there
in uh medicinal plants right now it is
highly possible that those things um
could uh jump across species so what's
most important is that you identify a
lab um where you're where you're getting
things tested that is kind of monitoring
that stuff and has the scientific chops
to um develop tests quickly if those
things become a threat in the industry
so um yeah once basically the the
important thing to remember here is no
matter what you're facing if you prevent
entry if you're careful with
sterilization if you're paying attention
you can protect yourself from both the
known pathogens as well as anything that
might be coming down the pike um it's
just important to put those Protections
in place and um it'll be all right all
right well so much good info in this
podcast episode today thank you so much
for coming on here this is actually a
topic that we haven't gotten into on
this podcast yet so I'm really honored
to have an expert on here that can break
it down for us and give us all the
details and what we need to know and how
to test symptoms and all that stuff so I
appreciate your time today can you tell
the listeners how they can find you and
maybe talk about some things that you
have upcoming in the future yes
absolutely so um you can find us at
toomics.com we are also um on Instagram
at tum genomics uh LinkedIn
um you can go to our website um there's
all sorts of ways to get a hold of us
you can send us an email there's a phone
number there's even a live chat um if
you just want to plop in there and ask a
question about hot PL and vroid I'm
always happy um to just help out with
with questions you know even if you're
not ready to test you just want to
understand the process better um please
reach out and get in touch with us um
you know like I said things that are
coming out or just recently came out
would be our onsite testing platform
form um so you can also reach out to us
and ask us questions about that like how
you know how to obtain it and understand
it a little bit more um we are also
working on developing um hopefully uh
soon uh what we call a Next Generation
sequencing type diagnostic so um what
this can do for you is instead of you
knowing what's wrong with your plant you
can say this plant doesn't right I'm
going to send in some tissue and we can
basically agnostically look at it and
tell you um what's there so you don't
have to know that it's hopl and vroid or
know that it's lettuce chlorosis or
whatever um we can we can kind of test
for everything all at the same time so
that's something else that we're we're
hopefully coming out with soon so um you
know people can just look for if they
don't know what's wrong they can look
for whatever so um yeah those are the
those are the things that hopefully will
be out in a reasonable period of time
awesome I'll definitely have a link to
you down in the YouTube description
section below so people easily be able
to navigate to you thanks so much once
again for coming on to the podcast I
really appreciate it and hope you enjoy
the rest of your day yes yeah thank you
so much for the opportunity to speak
with you and uh you as well have a
wonderful day peace out everyone catch
you in the next episode