thanks to spider farmer for sponsoring
this video spider farmer is running a
420 sale on all of their products and a
bigger sale on their se series led grow
lights the sc3000 sc 5000 se7000 and
sc1000w are all on sale on top of their
discount you can stack my coupon code to
save even more so for any of their se
series grow lights use coupon code mr
grow at eight to save eight percent more
and for all other spider farmer products
use coupon code mr grow it five to save
five percent more these coupon codes
work on both their website and amazon
links are in the description section
below and the sale ends on april 24th
have you tried the peanut butter breath
cultivar if so how did you like it yes i
did i actually really like peanut bread
breath so i actually got i was gifted
from thc titan from square one genetics
he actually started his line i don't
know if a lot of people know this but he
actually started his line with peanut
butter breath cut i believe it was a cut
he started with he ended up getting
making into an f2
and then he took that f2 and started his
line i believe i need to get him on the
podcast sometime and then go through his
story there but i got his f2s that he
created a peanut butter breath they were
awesome i ended up getting one that
changed color to purple this is on my
channel if you dig back you can see
beautiful plant real dense all the way
down to the bottom i love a cultivar
that there's that density down even the
lower part of the canopy right so you
might not do all the lollipopping that
you should have done but those lower
buds are still really dense not all
cultivars do that i know there's select
cultivars that do and then as far as the
smoke it was a very chill narcotic
effect which is dumpster something i
really like so i highly recommend peanut
butter breath i really do did enjoy that
cultivar what's your thought on using
molasses during flour do it yeah there's
nothing against it i mean feeding in the
microbes right my thoughts on using
molasses as far as frequency i
personally like to just use it only in
flour i've used it throughout the grill
used it you know every other week used
it once a month used it every week just
generally speaking like my own
observations it seems like if i start
the plant on molasses young
the plant looks great you know after the
feeding the plants praying up towards
the light beautiful clearly healthy
clearly happy but eventually that kind
of goes away i feel like if you use it
too early in veg
so that's why i personally like to use
it in
flower mostly even all the way up
through flush through that flush period
and all the way to harvest plants seemed
stuck in time was growing good then the
leaves got darker and the leaves grew
smaller than before what could it be
and it could be so many different things
i mean there's so many different
variables
on it right
uh nutrition
if you're using synthetic nutrients
what's uh one of the first things i ask
folks that are asking for for help is
what is the ph and ppm oftentimes folks
will do a runoff test so they run water
through the medium collect the runoff
water and then put their ph probe in
there or their tds tester to get a ppm
measurement
and then that that can tell you quite a
bit
you know sometimes it might be that the
ph is out of range and you're not
getting the proper nutrient uptake
that could be stunting it um you could
have over-watered there might not be a
you know lack of oxygen in the root zone
that could stunt growth not enough light
that could slow growth
so there are many different things that
it could potentially be
if i had more information on kind of
what you're using for
you know nutrients lighting like
distance ph ppm runoff measurements i
might be able to give you a better
answer there first autos when would you
say top dress in happy frog with worm
casting russells on top i don't know
what your use i'm gonna assume you're
using some type of blend at this point
worm castings rice hall
there's got to be something more than
just worm castings
i'm assuming at least there should be i
would recommend that there's there's
some type of blend
typically what they'll do is you know a
lot of folks will have their initial
blend of the medium with the nutrients
then about 30 days into the grow
depending on the plant size depending on
the size of the container so and so
forth there's a lot of variables but
generally speaking about day 30 or day
40 they'll top dress again some people
go as early as day 20.
top dress again
then flip to flower and then 30 days
into flower
they will do another top dressing
and then depending on if you've got uh
you know if you're growing an eight week
nine week ten week cultivar or one of
the cultivars that are longer than that
you might want to do another top
dressing so pretty much generally
speaking every 30 days roughly some
people do every 20 days
some people do every 40 days depending
on what blend you're using so on and so
forth but roughly every 30 days is when
a top dressing should happen
what would be the lowest wattage to grow
you can get away with
less than that there's a hundred watts
is what a lot of people getting away
with a lot of these grow lights that are
for a two foot by two foot grow space
they're just putting 100 watts of led
over that and they're able to get away
with that i'm not really sure
what size growth space you're in if
you're in a larger grow space then more
watts are warranted there
roughly four to 500 watts of led in a
four by four space those are just some
rough numbers there how long before you
start feeding with fox farms so fox farm
trio i'm assuming you're talking about
there check out their feeding chart if
you started with an amended soil
typically you can get a roughly 20 30
sometimes 40 days out of that amended
soil depending on
what size grow pot it's in and then at
that point you would start feedings and
usually what i'll do is i'll check the
runoff measurement ppm some people go
after ec
they'll track that instead yeah check
out their feeding chart go by the road i
would say go buy the ratios because they
formulate their nutrients with a
particular balance in place
if you have an imbalance of nutrients in
your medium more
of one nutrient and not enough of
another it could
cause a lockout to happen you can see
deficiencies
so it's very very common so yeah check
out the feeding chart around 30 40 days
that's probably probably when you'll do
your first feeding do you have an update
on the ac infinity pole fan how do you
like it they're still not available
no issues so far i'm running four of
them right now so i run two in each one
of my tents i have a two by four and a
four by four they're working fine i
think the main issue with those
oscillating fans that clip onto the grow
tents from other brands
is the fact that they had their wiring
run through the actual
with the case through the actual piece
that connects to the grow tent so as the
fan was oscillating the wire was just
rubbing up against the side and it was
shortening it out so that's why you hear
about people who
like their tents have gotten on fire and
stuff like that it's because of the
design now ac infinity their fans that
clip to the group tent those ones are
actually
the wires like off to the side so it
doesn't even go through the actual
casing or whatever so yeah it's still
working great i like it a lot and there
was somebody who actually was several
people who complained about the light on
the back that light actually turns off
so um that's just on temporarily and
then it ends up turning off after like
i don't know five or eight seconds or
something like that i think why do some
growers claim a fox fire motion force
burns seedlings i've never experienced
that have you i i mean i get minor burns
sometimes some cultivars but it's not
really detrimental to the grow i've had
one plant that i can remember that was
detrimental to where it just looked like
nitrogen toxicity and the leaves were
just terrible i think i have it on my
channel my main channel somewhere if you
guys go back to the sour diesel
this had to have been
said to have been like three years ago
roughly that's really the only one
defino just couldn't take it i mean sour
diesel from my experience when i hear a
lot from a lot of people is that it's a
very sensitive phenom when it comes to
feeding
so finicky
you're going to get some genetics just
like that but now i use fox farm motion
for soil i've been using it for
over 10 years
and
i like it what's your thoughts on way to
make edibles i usually do the oil or the
butter mostly oil done in a crock pot
kind of letting it soak in the crock pot
i don't have the the recipe memorized or
anything like that but
yeah i usually do oil and then use that
within the edibles i think in one of
your talks with dr bugbee you discuss
using green light during the later phase
of flowering
should increase
trichome production could you refresh my
memory on the specifics so it's not
green light green light is something
that's used but
you usually hear of uvb as the one that
increases trichomes now what dr bugbee
had said is that there are some studies
around it
but it was
i don't remember the exact word but
something like inconclusive
meaning that they couldn't say for sure
that it did increase trichomes now
somebody else had replied in the
comments and said that there's some
other study out there but he didn't post
a link so i'm not really sure if there
isn't actually another study or somebody
just just saying that have you grown
hydroponics if so what's your thoughts
not yet dwc not yet my concern and i
have a garden talk podcast episode with
somebody who does dwc and rdwc
my concern was that i live in too hard
of a climate
water temperature needs to be controlled
and needs to be under don't quote me on
this i think under like 75 degrees
fahrenheit and my natural just
regular temperature can be 75 to 80. so
i just have a feeling that i'm going to
struggle when it comes to water temp now
i know i can get a chiller
my concern is that's more energy than me
just being a small home grower it just
doesn't seem like it's worth it but i do
want to try in the wintertime one of
these times any good tips for welcome to
the grow temp pfg purple frost giant
it's somewhat of a heavy feeder in my
experience so don't be
too conservative when it comes to
nutrients particularly i'm talking about
precision feeding with bottled nutrients
i guess you could say right you might do
a little bit more than a half dose
generally speaking depending on the
nutrient line you're using so on and so
forth but
i've found that i've been able to give
more than just a half dose there have
been times where i gave a full dose
particularly in flowering so watch the
feeding and might be a hungry one i'm
not sure
what generation the pfg is but i assume
there's going to be some
variation in feedings depending on
phenotype as well the heavy feeder in my
opinion on the two that i had can we
hear the og 4x4 face it's uh that's fine
yeah every time i say four foot by four
foot people think i say it weird i don't
know i said it really sound weird it's
my accent so i'm originally from boston
and um i kind of have the accent a
little bit on some words it went away a
lot but four foot by four foot
i guess that sounds weird too to some of
you
can you give any advice on auto pots
do's and don'ts yes
so i haven't had the best luck with
doing organics in auto pots and there
are people out there that'll say oh i've
everything's been fine for me for me
personally
top dressing nutrients and using the
auto pots
didn't really work out well in my
expectations if using synthetics it'll
probably be a little bit easier for you
because the auto pots it's working it's
wicking up from the bottom right so
you're not doing any top watering so
keeping that top layer moist where the
amendments are for organics and
breakdown was difficult for me and
that's even having a mulch layer on top
of it even having a
a cover crop on top of it to try to help
with water retention and keep that top
layer moist so i wouldn't recommend
using auto pots organics with auto pots
but some people do so you may want to
try it synthetics should be good the
copper disk make sure you're using that
make sure it's inside the pot i think
some people actually got away with
putting it outside the pot like kind of
in the the bin below or whatever so that
make sure the roots don't grow out from
the bottom and clog up your auto pod
that's happened before to people been
using ro water but cost may become an
issue how can i remove the chlorine from
tap water that's a good question
aro i'm you must be going out and buying
ro yeah it does add up consider getting
a one friend of the sink that's what i
have i don't know if you have the space
for it or not but i have it under my
kitchen sink and i have the uh just
basically have one gallon containers
that i pump it into but some people will
do a five gallon bucket and then they're
just they'll put it into a five gallon
bucket but removing chlorine from tap
water as long as it's chlorine and not
chloramine
make sure it's chlorine first often
folks just let it sit out 24 hours 48
hours having sunlight on it will help
speed up that process for the chlorine
to dissipate but yeah a lot of people
just let let it sit out for 24 to 48
hours and then the chlorine is removed
from the tap water now i recommend that
you get a water report and have somebody
take a look at that to see if there's
any other issues so the soil doctor for
example is somebody who i recommend that
you take your water report to i think
going through logan labs you might want
to actually send a water sample to logan
labs have them test it get the result
then talk to the soil doctor and he can
give you some really good information
about if there's any sort of
contaminants in there that's going to
impact your plant
or he can actually
tell you what type of like what you'll
need in your nutrients as far as
elements because a lot of tap waters
have a lot of calcium in it
so if you're using a nutrient solution
you won't need as much calcium as one
example but yeah just let it sit out for
24-48 hours i think that's typically
what people do do you use silica
throughout the grill i do yeah it's safe
to use throughout the grow there's so
many benefits for celica
now short answer yep i use silica
throughout the grow does freak show have
a traditional skunky smell or something
different uh you know it's more of like
a at least the cultivar i have is more
of like a lemony type smell
it's funny i was uh
moving the
freak show from one tent to another and
i had it like all over my arms it was
flopping all over the place the buds are
just they're so heavy that they're
flopping all over the place
and uh i had it all over my arms and i'm
just like smelling myself and it's it's
definitely more of a lemony at least for
the finos that i have do you feed the
whole time with auto pots i assume
you're talking about with synthetic
nutrients it's really hard to give you
that answer each nutrient line is going
to be different me personally i've been
able to do like a
quarter dose of nutrients in the
reservoir and unfortunately each
cultivar seems to be different each
phenotype is different so you could get
different results as far as like the
health of the plant if you're feeding
nutrients from one reservoir going to
multiple phenotypes you could see
different there there have been times
where i've shut off the valve
let the plants kind of dry out sometimes
just add in water top feed water for one
or two times then turn that valve back
on for the autobots going on so that's
one thing you might want to consider if
you feel like
you you are potentially over fertilizing
so something to keep in mind can i
transplant from roots organic soil to
fox farm absolutely i don't know if
you're talking about like starting in a
one gallon container for example or solo
cup of roots organic and then going into
a new container that has fox farm in
there absolutely no problem what i hope
you're not talking about is like
starting in a one gallon container with
roots organic
taking that plant out shaking off all
the medium breaking up all the roots
getting rid of that medium then going at
a fox farm i don't think there's any
need to do that i've seen people go from
soil to cocoa that way
and the plant was not happy at all so i
wouldn't recommend that but you can
absolutely go from
roots organic to fox farmer vice versa
no problem did you completely move on
from earth dust nutrient line i wouldn't
say that i still have a bunch of earth
does nutrients i plan to use in my
outdoor garden i've just been really
liking the craft blend you know i only
have so many plants so
nothing against earth dust took
definitely took me a while to get used
to it and learn what that guy was doing
i wish there was more instruction back
when it first came out but once i got
the hang of it yeah things were things
were dialed in just got into coco does
the ph go up over time with cocoa unlike
soil that's a good question it's hard to
say
because it really depends on what else
is in the cocoa like for amendments for
example what are you using dolomite lime
is one of the things that that drifts it
up so if you have dolomite lime in there
it will definitely drift up and the
plant is going to release acids in order
to control the ph a little bit right so
if your ph is too high the plant will
actually release acids into the
rhizosphere you know lower the ph
particularly to grab some of the
elements that aren't available at that
ph iron is a good example of that 6.5 ph
or lower is typically where iron can be
uptaken by the plant so if the peaches
higher than that
it's going to send out acids to lower it
so it's able to to grab that iron now
coco coir in particular is known for a
high cation exchange so talking about
cat iron exchange capacities basically
think of it like a buffer a lot of
people explain it as you've got your
piece of media
cocoa and you've got all these particles
that can stick to it and so cation
exchange capacity is just like the
capacity it has the ability it has to
stick to those particles you hear about
how cocoa a lot of people have to go
heavy on the calcium and magnesium right
it's because it has a high cocoa has a
high cation exchange capacity things are
going to stick to it that calcium
magnesium so that's why a lot of people
buffer cocoa with calmag prior to
planting in it
rinsing rinsing and buffering that helps
most of the time as far as does it go ph
go up over time
i found it does if you're checking the
runoff ph but i found it doesn't really
impact the plant i personally go for a
5.8 ph of the nutrient solution going in
and then i ignore runoff ph
for cocoa because yeah you know when i
first started planting it
what went in for ph is what measured it
came out
however over time what went in it i got
a
a number that was way up there and then
i read it online did my own research and
people say ignore it ignore it as long
as the plan's looking fine you're
putting that
5.8 ph going in
you're going to be fine so that's kind
of what i've stuck with over the years
[Music]
you