coming up on garden talk there is so
many different chemical constituents
that plants construct
to manipulate their environment in soil
whether it be the biological populations
whether it be ph
in the rhizosphere all of these things
are all part of it over watering can
look like so
many different things and what's
happening is
you're creating an environment and where
bacteria that isn't conducive to the
health of your plant
is able to colonize and grow a lot of
the bacillus species
they have the ability to encapsulate
their dna into an endospore
and those endospores they create like a
wax coating
they're really resilient there are so
many
products out there that are so
overpriced
or have such small colony forming units
that they're going to be uneffective
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 16.
in this episode i interview brandon rust
he is the owner of bokashi earthworks
which is a biological fertilizer company
that specializes in microbial inoculants
he has been cultivating for 20 years and
he currently owns a
40 acre farm in oklahoma great episode
that i have for you today
this is more of an advanced discussion
where we talk all about microbes
some of the things that we talk about in
this episode are ideal soil temperature
for microbe activity
we talk about large swings that can
happen in the micro population
the rate of microbe reproduction and a
whole lot more
click the thumbs up button and subscribe
to the channel if you haven't already
if you're listening to this podcast on
one of the podcast platforms such as
apple podcasts
please leave a rating and review and a
big thank you to those of you that
support this podcast on patreon
if you would like to directly support
this podcast you can do it through
patreon
the link to that is patreon.com mr
growit i also link it down in the
youtube
description section below before we get
into the episode i'd like to give a
quick
shout out to our sponsor happy hydro
happy hydro is giving away a chilled
tech growcraft x6 led grow light
all you have to do to enter the giveaway
is to click the link in the video's
description section which will take you
to gleam
gleam is a giveaway website that tracks
the entries when you get there
you'll be able to enter the giveaway by
visiting the happy hydro youtube channel
and then while you're there click the
subscribe button and that's it
you're then entered to win the chill
tech growcraft
x6 led grow light good luck now let's
get into the episode
all right here we are brandon rust
welcome to the garden talk podcast how
are you today
i am wonderful busy as always but
uh happy to be on another podcast and
spreading uh the information that i've
accumulated over the last
20 years of cultivating yeah i'm super
stoked to have you on here i've seen you
on so many different shows i mean
before we hit the record but you'd
mention you're on over 100 different
shows or podcasts
live streams whatever which is awesome
and the amount of information you give
to the community here is extensive so
first off thank you so much for for
doing that service because you've been
helping out
hundreds of thousands of people if not
millions of people throughout all these
videos
and so on and so forth so thank you for
that um
now for the people who you know there's
got to be some people in
the audience here that don't know who
you are so can you introduce yourself
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening
sure my name is brandon rust i'm from
san diego but i currently reside in
oklahoma
i started cultivating medicinal plants
20 years ago i was a teenager 18 19
years old and i had uh
some og some older guys uh show me
how to cultivate uh back then we were
doing hydroponics
i've since moved to doing living organic
systems
and if you guys are interested in any of
the the work that i do
you can find me at rust.brandon
and you can find you know
links there to my company bokashi
earthworks which is a biological
fertilizer company i specialize in
microbial inoculants
for nutrient cycling soil health and
fertility and integrated pest management
and then i also own a 40 acre farm
uh out here in oklahoma with my partners
awesome and then i actually googled your
dame before we met up today
and i think the third link down if you
google his name brandon rust the third
link down goes to herbage
mag and there's actually a written
article about you kind of your story so
if anybody's watching this wants to
learn the next level down about his
journey here over the past 20 years
is definitely a good read it's only
about a page long so
but definitely worth the read for sure
cool so i think it's appropriate to just
start with
the soil food web you know that's
actually something that
hasn't been discussed yet on my garden
talk podcast off of any of the guests
so let's start with that maybe if you
could take you know roughly five minutes
or however long
it takes to kind of talk to us about
what the food web is and
somewhat a basic or beginner friendly
type way
sure i'm sure that most of your viewers
are familiar with
you know the food web something that we
got to see in elementary school you know
what eats what
what's higher up in the food chain soil
food web is that same exact thing
for the soil and the species
that interact the way that they you know
release mineral nutrients and it's
basically just the the diversity of
different
types of microorganisms micro and meso
fauna
um and then macro uh
macro uh flora and fauna as well as
arthropods
earthworms so you know it's a it's
it's complicated but really it's it's
not it's basically just
that there are certain things that do
certain things
in the soil and they feed off of each
other
they work you know synergistically and
symbiotically
with each other basically it is the
the web of life that perpetuates
life and that's all we're going to be
talking all about microbes today so
we're going to talk about the biology
uh we are going to definitely get into a
little bit of chemistry here
um which has warned everybody i'm a
beginner when it comes to chemistry so
some of the stuff actually might go over
my head which it might go over so my
audience had as well
but it's okay because we can always look
back we can always do additional
research
and so on and so forth so it goes over
my head
i consider myself a really intelligent
person i read
tons of white papers i read literature
all the time
the complexity of these systems
is to be able to really have a firm
understanding
you have to have a really good
imagination
yeah absolutely so chemistry and then
you get into like biochemistry
and then you get into you know we might
even touch on linux
yep you know so much it's endless almost
it really is and that's one of the
reasons that you know soil science
is so intriguing is because there will
never be a point
where i come and say oh i can't learn
anymore
it'll always be a journey so i'm just
taking people along with me as i go
and that's what makes it fun for sure so
a lot of my audience does use synthetic
fertilizers right synthetic nutrients
and
we often hear about salt buildup
resulting in problems now when we're
talking about salt
we're not talking about sodium chloride
right the table salt
uh so what exactly tell us what exactly
is salt from like a chemistry standpoint
well when we're looking at
typically when we are looking at these
systems in soil anyway we are looking at
chloride and sodium na
what happens is there are certain
chemicals that are biologically
available for the plants
to utilize for the specific functions
whatever they may be for
in these natural systems you have what's
called oxidation and redox
potentials and essentially certain
elements are biologically available and
we see this like
for in ph right but there's more to it
we see it in ph and that is going to be
certain things are available
there's a bigger picture to that
and typically when you're using
synthetics
they're taking a chemical that can be
absorbed
by a plant but it's also in a chemical
formulation
to where it's not going to
um where it's not going to be affected
by
the oxidation and redox potentials
of those systems so
inherently you have kind of
a dual you have two systems right these
organic systems which
you know we still use things like
mineral salts
but they're not synthetically created
right the ones
when you're you can get the same effect
with with either but what happens
is with synthetic
fertilizers you're human accumulating
a lot of chemical compounds that are
going to
interfere and have antagonistic
relationships with what you're trying to
absorb
right and also oftentimes these
chemicals are in
such high quantity that they are
are grossly over applied
when you grossly over apply a synthetic
fertilizer it can adversely affect
the biology of that soil
but it can also affect
the abiotic nature of that soil
which is anything that's not related
all the different stress factors that
could be that aren't related with
biology
so like the weathering when you have
those types of chemicals they can tie up
soil they can tie up nutrient they can
cause
anaerobic conditions when they uh they
dry out
really uh easier
they don't hold moisture as well so you
have different conditions
that eventually accumulate and it's not
to say that this can't happen also in
organic systems because it totally can
you can accumulate things
like chloride and sodium
in these inorganic systems as well
and they'll compile and again what it
does is causes antagonistic
relationships
it hinders microbiology from being able
to procreate and reproduce
and it also comes at a great cost
to environment in the production of
those chemicals
gotcha now i guess one of the ways that
i was kind of explaining and
to try to make it a little bit simpler
terms i guess you could say
is you know when you have these bulb
nutrients you're mixing it with water
it's
somewhat like binding to that h2o it's
going into the soil right
and then the plant is uptaking it or
it's staying there and the water is
evaporating and then you have what's
left over is an
ion i believe and then that ion isn't
available to be uptaken by the plant
so my question is are microbes able
to access that ion at that point and eat
that ion
or when you have a
when you have a large accumulation
of antagonistic
cations in your soil
it's going to make it so the plant can
absorb that
bacteria microorganisms
fungi yeast they all have
amazing abilities to
break down almost anything that is a
hydrocarbon compound
so if it is you know i guess
any or anything in organic chemistry
because i guess organic chemistry it
doesn't necessarily
have to be natural in nature they can be
synthetic but when we're talking about
organic chemistry we're talking about
anything that is a hydrocarbon
compound that being said
there is a microbe for
every compound because the amount of
microbes that we have
vary in such a huge specie of diversity
and when we're thinking about at least
when i'm thinking about microbes
i'm thinking of it kind of like
varieties of medicinal plants some will
have
a lot of different effects right
because of the metabolites that they're
producing or the
the chemical constituents that those
plants produce
microorganisms are very similar in that
they all produce
different chemical constituents some of
these these are their secondary
metabolites just like the plants produce
so what we'll see is there are some
bacteria like uh phosphorus solubilizing
bacteria
they release an enzyme that's able to
release phosphate the only plant
available source of phosphorus
from inorganic mineral compounds
from rocks from things like
calcium phosphate or calcium bentonite
or uh you know
we'll ask tonight there's so many
different
types of calcium and when we're looking
at calcium
as a chemical we're not just looking at
ca right it's always attached to
something like
c-a-s-i-o you know calcium silica
or calcium phosphate or you know calcium
silicate
a lot of these elements that we use
in organic farming are usually attached
to something else all of the mineral
sulfates
it is a mineral it is considered a salt
right
because it's soluble in water
so you can take almost across the board
there is something for an organic
situation
if you need to make up for a deficit
that is immediately available
and i know that's you know i've heard
people say oh you can't
get things immediately in organics and
that's absolutely not true
there's a difference between what you're
putting in right if you're using
a mineral salt and organic mineral salt
you can do the same thing you can hamper
a system the same way you could
by over application in a
you know chemical system as well um
but when you're using something like a
meal anything that has a meal
attached to it whether it's feather meal
bone meal
kelp meal those are all things that
biology is going to have to utilize to
break down to release
into the system anything that has a
sulfate on the end of it
potassium sulfate iron sulfate zinc
sulfate
these are all mined minerals that come
out of deposits whether it was like in a
volcanic eruption
a natural seabed mine that dried out
rock quarry they're mine mineral
sulfates but they're water soluble or
they have more
solubility in water now they don't all
have the same solubility
right magnesium sulfate aka
epsom salt has a way higher solubility
than let's say calcium uh
calcium sulfate or gypsum we're talking
about a huge huge difference
so you know when we're talking about
uh salts we're talking about things that
are soluble in water
which you have to be careful of too
because we're talking usually talking
about
a cat ion and there's three
there's four but there's three cations
that we're looking at
specifically for you know when we're
farming
and that's calcium magnesium and
potassium
there's also sodium n a but that's
antagonistic to all three of those
so we want sodium to always be as low as
possible because it's a
it is a salt it's a cation and it's
antagonistic and it'll cause
block out or lock out even if you have
adequate amounts of everything you need
in your soil let's say your soil is
perfectly healthy and
balanced well i guess it wouldn't be
balanced if your soil if your
sodium was up but let's say everything
else was good but your sodium
is really high what's going to hap
what's going to affect
what is mostly going to be affected are
those what are going to be affected are
those
major cations the thing the plant relies
on for the majority
of its biomechanical processes
gotcha that's very interesting stuff
there for sure now in some
organic gardening books it's mentioned
that feeding synthetic nutrients
are going to kill off the microbes
however on online sources
like there's this gardening myth website
it says that that's completely false
feeding in synthetic nutrients you're
actually feeding the microbes
so is it true that feeding synthetic
nutrients are going to kill off the
microbes
if so how fast do the micro populations
die off
when feeding these synthetic nutrients
well
so i don't have any actual data that's
going to say this is exactly
what is happening and you know i'm a
data driven uh
cultivator that's how i how i do uh
all of my agronomy i look at what's in
the soil and stuff
when it comes to biology
biology is it's it's pretty resilient
a lot of these species have the ability
to endosporolate which
encapsulates their dna and they can
survive in extreme conditions whether
it's
high or low ph ranges high and low
temperature ranges
and all different types of
abiotic and biotic stress factors
that being said it does hinder biology
when you're using a bunch of again
you're talking about
an organism's inability to use what it
needs what people
don't understand is that bacteria
microorganisms
are very similar to plants
i mean plants wouldn't exist if it
wasn't for
the relationships that they co-evolved
with with the different microorganisms
and the the microorganisms also require
a diet
right it's not just nitrogen and calcium
right they need iron they need manganese
they need a lot of the same
elements that plants need and again
if you go and throw a bunch of stuff
into a system that's not
balanced it's not just a plant that's
going to be adversely affected
it's going to be the biology of those
systems how can they
sequester any type of nutrient
if it's just downright not available
because there's this antagonistic
relationship going on does that make
sense
gotcha yep so not only that but
from my perspective and from you know
what i've seen there are
certain species of microbes that can
tolerate those high salinity high saline
types of conditions but because
microorganisms are so fragile which is
kind of like
you know some species will be able to
survive those types of conditions what
are they
well you have to do your research we
know that certain species of bacillus
bacteria
are can still function really well in
high salinity conditions
we know that there are certain strains
of trichoderma
that do this there are there's like
microbes for [ __ ] everything
but when we're talking about specific
microbes that are that we're utilizing
in agriculture for
specific reason whether it's to
whether it's for their production of
selective target antibodies
or whether it's because we want them
to we're looking for an enzyme
production
that they produce we'll eliminate that
because we need to
we need to have conditions where we can
promote the types of microorganisms
that are going to boat that best
benefit that specie of plant
in the environment that it's in gotcha
that makes sense
and kind of piggybacking off of that
talking about getting into like large
swings in micro population that's never
a good thing right
you know generally they say that if
you're flushing your plant for example
you could be flushing out a lot of those
microbes if you're over fertilizing you
could be killing you know you could have
that large swing
in the population large ph fluctuations
is another thing that i've heard could
potentially
hinder you could have a large swing in
the micro population as well
are there anything else or yeah talk
about that stuff
a little bit so temperature
ph hydrology those are going to be your
three
main components when it comes to
which type of microorganisms are are
abundant in soil but also
plant species and
which type what kind of
of photosynthesis are they releasing
into the soil what type of eggs are they
because when we're talking about
plant exudates there are
there are there's the science that's
going to come out on this is going to be
[ __ ] insane dude there is so many
different chemical constituents that
plants construct
to manipulate their environment in soil
whether it be the biological populations
whether it be ph
in the rhizosphere all of these things
are all part of it if you go too low on
ph some species will completely die
off if you go too high if you're if you
over water and it goes anaerobic
and you don't have the proper biology to
start with
you could say goodbye you know there's
when we're talking about explosive
populations
you know let's say that your plant's not
let's say your plant's struggling a
little bit
right and you're like oh i can't figure
out what it is
i see this all time just from over
watering
over watering can look like so many
different things
and what's happening is you're creating
an environment and where
bacteria that isn't conducive to the
health of your plant
is able to colonize and grow so let's
say
that this is kind of like the beginning
right you have this thing happening
you didn't catch it and then you go like
you think it's a nitrogen deficiency so
you go
hit these things with a bunch of amino
acids right
like soy hydrolysate what you're going
to end up doing
is you're going to compile the problem
that you have because you just added a
complex carbohydrate
to a living soil system where the
predominant
microbe is something that's going to
kill your plant and you just gave them
something that they love
so it's those types of
i guess scenarios
that that biology can make a huge
difference
let's say you you have a root uh a
flat full of of clones that you're
rooting right and
you over water them and there they
become waterlogged right and all those
roots become
anaerobic man how long is it going to
take for
you to recover with that and then let's
say you go ahead
and plant those things and you're like
oh
again they need this or that and you try
to add something to the system
and it just it throws it further
to the left and not where it needs to be
you know what i mean
yep absolutely let's move on to
ph up and ph down so i get so many
comments in my comment section
with a lot of people really scared to
adjust the ph
you know um you know ph down for example
a common thing that's used for that is
phosphoric acid
ph up for example a common thing that's
used is potassium hydroxide
potassium carbonate
the common thing that said is if we're
using these things we're killing off the
microbes
in the medium or you know are we
eradicating the microbes in the medium
from
a few drops or a few milliliters of
you know potassium hydroxide potassium
carbonate
phosphoric acid you know if so what what
if so
do we know what the impact is on that
well
the again because one of those three
things i said earlier was ph large ph
fluctuations
are going to definitely affect the
biology in the soil
or what species can you know
exist but if you're like
you know if your soil is at like 6.3
and you're like oh i want to get it up
to 6.8
and you use you know first of all you're
not going to be able to do that
by ph your water right so
ph for water is usually
done for hydroponics typically
with organic growers they are already
starting off with a good source of water
that's not high in sodium or
bicarbonates
and if you're where you shouldn't i mean
if you're running hydro
there's some cases where
biology might be important like maybe if
you're doing a cocoa system
where those are going to be a little
more conducive to biology
but you're not looking for
you're not looking for like biodiversity
in these types of hydro systems right
because if
if that was the case then why are you
even using
synthetics in the first place microbiol
uh microbes don't work as well
in synthetic systems as they do in
organic living systems so that being
said
if you're you know running like
cocoa or hydroponic system where you're
having to adjust ph
and you're worried about biology you're
probably looking you need to be looking
at
specific types of microorganisms that
can help that's that particular system
out that aren't going to be
affected by those types of swings
as far as ph in soil
typically if you're using a good clean
source of
water that's low in bicarbonate and
sodium and chlorine
chloride sorry chloride
you shouldn't have to really worry too
much about your ph
as long as the soil ph is where it needs
to be
because the soil will buffer
the ph of the water as
long as the water is clean
if you have a bunch of bicarbonate in
there and you keep adding that in
adding that in adding that in it's going
to slowly raise that ph
up not only that but it's going to
antagonize
your catio cation balance and the
ability
for calcium magnesium
and potassium as well as even your
other cations from your micronutrients
which is going to be copper zinc
iron manganese the only
one that's not a cation i think is boron
and you know some of the other ones that
i didn't mention but out of those ones
out of the
the five major ones major micronutrients
that are
that are responsible for a lot of the
enzymatic processes folding of proteins
and rna
in the biomechanics i think the concern
for some of the folks that
are growing in soil is that they're
starting with a water
source that's like a 7.5 or an 8.0 ph
and they're worried that that would have
an impact and so
adding in that few drops you know two
three drops of phosphoric acid to get
that
you know ph down you know they worry
about about that
so that's why i bring up that question
okay um
and then just kind of touching on
organic ph adjusters
versus synthetic so we talked about like
phosphoric acid for
ph down and then potassium hydroxide and
potassium carbonate for
ph up some people
okay since you're mentioning those
particular chemicals right
phosphoric acid and uh potassium
hydroxide
okay so a lot of people who probably are
using
organic or who think they're growing
organically
there is a lot a lot of these
so those aren't organic chemicals but
they are
used consistently across the board a
number of products anything from like
nectar of the gods
those types of products where they're a
liquid nutrient
what typically they'll do they'll take
something like bone meal
and they'll they'll dissolve it in the
phosphoric acid
and so they're using an inorganic
process
for to to release organic
substances that'll stay in a solution
same with uh potassium products you know
there are potassium products that are
labeled as organics but they've been
so that's one one of the things though
those types of things
in small amounts don't don't
hinder biology it's those it's those
huge swings
and then also if
if your home grower and your ph is high
go and test your water and see why it's
high because typically that means
you you have bicarb bicarbonate and
sodium
in your water okay so and if that's the
case you sh
you should be using a filter or using
distilled water
or you know you should be what happens
in the systems is
things can go fine for a really long
time
but you compile problems slowly
it's why i tell people you shouldn't be
feet you know i know a lot of organic
growers um
i was one of them that used kelp meal
constantly and ocean inputs
and it's like after you compile all of
these things over
run after run run after run dude your
sodium
and your chloride are [ __ ]
skyrocketed
it comes from the ocean let's think
about this for a second
you know like the ocean is full of
[ __ ]
salt so
not only that but you have to remember
too heavy metals can compile the same
way
so even if something has a small amount
of heavy metals but you use it
consistently
consistently and consistently it'll
build up over time
so when some growers are saying you
should be using baking soda for a ph
up versus you know potassium hydroxide
or potassium carbonate
or using lemon juice or vinegar for ph
down
instead of phosphoric acid you know
would you agree with that would you
i dude it's not it's
the amount that you're applying for that
like okay so let's say i got a 50 gallon
reservoir right
and it i need to take it down by
0.8 the amount of whatever i
am adding in there is
just not going to be enough to really
like mess that up it's it's when you
have these wide fluctuations
you know when you have way over
watering and then way too much dry back
and what you know
it's consistency is kind of key
that's why the the you know the blue mat
systems work so well if you have
something that's
consistent all the time you know what to
expect
i love blue mats i actually just started
using them and uh
they're awesome so good um so one thing
i learned in
i think you touched upon it is that
different microbes are going to function
best to kind of different ph values you
know is this true
and then kind of what is that ideal ph
range you know for soil and i guess for
hydro that
people should kind of stick with so
here's the thing right
the the soil ph range
that okay it's such a weird it's such a
weird thing to address
because there's an optical there's an
optimal range
for you know uh soilless media and then
there's an optimal range
for uh for you know medicinal plants
but the ranges for ph for different
types of
bacteria different microorganisms is
all over the place depending on species
right it's like typically
all plants on earth will
are between five five and like
eight at the highest usually i mean
depending on
you know the type of soil that they're
in but blueberries are
something that is acidic
they like acidic soils and there's other
plants that like
little more calcareous soils so
or higher ph soils um i mean
that's you can say that about plants you
can't say that about microorganisms
because there are microorganisms that
prefer
to have an incredibly low ph
range well there's some that have will
only function in a in a high ph range
there are
some microorganisms that will not
function at all in the presence of
oxygen
there's some that are foculative they
can function in high or low and there's
some that only function in high oxygen
environments
microorganisms are so abundant
and they have so many different ranges
but what i'm looking at for the types of
microbes that i use it depends on
what i'm trying to do with it
this product right here from my company
bokashi earthworks
which is a consortium of
several different bacillus species uh
non-purple surf sulfur bacteria right up
pseudomonas pollustrius
and also a photo and also yeast which is
saccharomyces cerevisiae
also known as brewers yeast very that
yeast is very common it's found in soils
it's found on fruit
if for this particular product if the ph
doesn't go below 4.5
it won't stabilize you know so
for this specific consortium
although they can operate
in a wide ph range from like 3.5
all the way to like 8.5
if i want them to do a certain thing and
stay have viable spore
it has to be at a certain ph right so
where they're suspended in solution
they're all alive and they're waiting
for
the opportune environment to where they
start
procreating microorganisms very strange
like this
small things can can change
what's going on we also know that there
are certain microorganisms that we can't
even
you know we can't culture in laboratory
settings they only exist
in in nature and they can't be grown
and cultured because
their nutrient requirements think about
it like this
if you had a medicinal plant that had
this
really crazy wild nutritional need
and it was not typical to what you
usually want
and it's just all over the place and you
would have to figure out exactly what
this is and it was only this one
special mix that you would never find
anywhere else for any other plant in the
world
is the only thing that would make this
thing grow it's how it is for some of
these biology
for some of these microorganisms in
these biological
systems some of them will only exist
well a certain specie of plant is
present and it's giving
and that plant is releasing a
photosynthetic and exudate into the soil
that's going to sustain
the nutritional needs of that specific
microorganism
gotcha good information there for sure
so let's talk about
um kind of the soil temperature in
in a sense so one thing i've learned is
that
the lower the soil temperature in the
medium the slower microbes move
that being said what is the ideal soil
temperature for microbial activity
you'd be surprised 84 to 98 degrees
wow for most species you know what's
really interesting
when you increase your
vpd and you're running high temps high
humidity
in soil systems you get way better
nutrient cycling capacity your
phosphorus is gonna is gonna cycle
better
so will some other things this is what
i've seen from
data that i've collected right and it's
like
this this is why when you
think at least when i think of
how to culture a microorganism you know
you have certain environmental factors
microbial incubators are typically used
to culture different types of spore and
those ranges are usually between 84 and
98 degrees depending on the species and
the bacteria or
fungi whatever it is that you're
culturing
now they there are different species
that do better at
higher lower temperatures like we talked
about earlier higher lower humidity
but what i've seen in soil is that when
you have higher temperature higher
humidity
this the everything works better
as far as nutrient cycling capacity
when it when you're seeing how things
fall into solution
especially for phosphorus um so yeah
soil temperature
we got cut off for a second but um so
you know i'm looking at things from you
know how do you
how do you grow microbes and usually
you're looking at higher humidities
higher temperatures
and when you and the same thing applies
in these systems when you have the
higher
humidity and higher temperature you're
able to retain more moisture
as long as you have a really like for
these modified soil mixes that most of
us organic growers are using they're
highly porous
so that maximizes the gas exchange
capacity of that soil
which means there's a lot of oxygen
there's
it's able to retain the moisture while
still having a lot of oxygen and have
those higher temps it allows for
these populations of microbes to really
you know
really cycle it just increases their
activity
um you can kind of see this too
if you go and say you mixed up some
fresh compost and some
amendments maybe some like alfalfa stuff
like that and when you put it into your
tote
you know to cook you get the mycelium
you get all the bacterial and fungal
growth all the mycelium mats
you know when you're and it's because
you have those those nice
warm conditions when everything starts
to
cycle right when there's a lot of food
for them to sequester and there's a lot
of things to be broken down there's
plenty of carbon
plenty of nutrient that those
environments usually warm up
and it's because of all the activity
they can get too hot
obviously we've seen that with
thermophilic
compost where it heat you know gets too
hot i've actually seen compost uh
light on fire before um
but yeah those those temperature ranges
seem to do better with the higher
humidity and higher temperature ranges
obviously when we're growing a medicinal
plant we
don't usually want to exceed a leaf
a temperature of 84 degrees
unless you're able to you know really
maximize that environmental condition
where your nutrients
are all on you know they're sufficient
and balanced and then you also have
supplemental co2
your vpd is in range um
if if it's not if you go higher than
those temperatures
it has a hard time with some of the uh
the enzyme mechanics of of
photosynthesis or not photosynthesis but
with the creation of a
chlorophyll and you really have to
have everything dialed in if you want to
you know maximize that but
ideal range man if you can run your vpd
a little bit higher without going over
and kind of keep your humidity up but
consistent because one of the things
that
you know will cause bacteria to grow bud
mold particularly is if you have
huge fluctuations again it's that those
fluctuations from where
you're consistent vape vpd and it either
drops
or it goes too high consistency is kind
of
key is what i've seen as long as you
have consistency across
the board things seem to function
pretty well gotcha yeah because
you know soil temp isn't something
really that a lot of people talk about
you know since the soil temp has such an
impact
on microbial activity should we be
monitoring it more closely like
would you consider the soil temp just as
important
or even more important than the canopy
or leaf surface temperature
it's a really good question and it's not
something that i've really done a lot of
science on i haven't really delved
into what's happening at different
temperatures
you know i haven't even really taken
soil temperatures to be honest so it's
something that
it peaks my interest definitely and it's
another data point that could be taken
into consideration what we're looking at
things like the soil test saturated
paste test the leaf tissue and the sap
testing
you know how is soil temperature
affecting things
um i'm usually not looking at soil
temperature i'm usually looking at
rh and temperature and
you know those are the things that i'm
mostly looking at surface temp on the
leaf if we're
using leds led is a little bit more
complicated
in my opinion gotcha okay
so switching up a little bit so general
question here
when the soil dries out microbes go
dormant right
it's kind of like a sleep state for them
do some actually die
at that point if the soil dries out or
no or like when you've rehydrated kind
of they wake back up from that dormant
state
yeah so there are different
microorganisms that are going to be
ubiquitous to the environment they're
all around us
those types of microorganisms will
reestablish themselves
however if there was like a specific
microorganism in that
system it could potentially be
uh eliminated unless it has the the the
ability to endospore late like we talked
about earlier so
some varieties a lot of the bacillus
species they have the ability to
encapsulate their dna into an endospore
and those endospores they create like a
wax coating
they're really resilient different type
of biotic and abiotic stress factors
and that's what makes them such a
prevalent species
in soil and so when they do dry out
um if you have large microbial
populations what will happen
is you have a lot of
tiny tiny little microorganisms that
create these wax coatings and that's
what causes
soil to go hydrophobic so if you've ever
seen a really really dry soil you pick
it up throw it on water it floats
it has to completely rehydrate until
that soil
will actually sink and it's because and
so it's the same thing same thing could
happen
that's really what you are going to be
more concerned about because you can
always re-inoculate
or you know those populations are all
going to naturally come back
once you rehydrate that material the
problem is
it can be really difficult to rehydrate
soil that's gone hydrophobic
and oftentimes it takes something like a
surfactant
so you can get that penetration into dry
spots
so that's that is really the main
concern with
with you know letting your soil dry out
but yeah
it'll come back you know there are
microbes
in that soil they will continue to be
there
some of them will die out here's an
example right anything that's going to
be uh
like an anaerobic species which is most
your most your pathogens like your
fungal root pathogens
are going to be optim they're going to
have an optimal operation
in in low to no oxygen conditions
so if you let your soil dry out and
there's no more
oxygen in that soil you're going to be
eliminating a lot of that
that species do you recommend
folks use a wetting agent every time
they water
no no no no it's not necessary no it's
not necessary i
i mean i don't ever use a surfactant in
less
and less it's like uh
ipm foiler or if your soil's gone
hydrophobic
okay interesting yeah i've heard
recommendations to just use it every
time because it doesn't really cause
harm it would help
the soil in the long run but so i was
just curious on that one
well well here's the problem if you were
going to use this i i i don't know if
this you know this is just my thoughts
on it really
if you're going to use a surfactant like
yucca or something or
every time that you're watering
i would uh assume that at some point
unless you're really letting a i water
every day you know so for me
if i were to use a surfactant every day
it would be a kind of
cost-effective it wouldn't be
cost-effective it'd be waste of money
but also you know
what that does is it basically makes
water wetter
and when we're in a system a living soil
system
where we want to have the maximum amount
of gas exchange
i don't want to create any anaerobic
conditions in my soil
so over watering or
you know i would think that if you did
that constantly over and over every
watering that you could
could potentially create problems
but it's never something i personally
experienced because
the only time i use a surfactant is for
coverage for ipm foilers
or again for hydrophobic soils
got it that makes sense um okay
inoculating the soil so how often should
growers be
inoculating the soil i mean there's some
growers out there that
two three times a week they're
inoculating they're using mammoth p
they're using
um you know great white then they're
adding some recharge and
you know can you really go overboard
with these is there a general
recommendation
for how often you should be using them
you can definitely go
overboard on your bank because a lot of
those
things a lot of those things are
expensive man
you know what i mean and great point
look i'm gonna tell i'm gonna i'll tell
you what guys
everybody that's listening there
i i collect data
all the time and
i do a massive amount of research
there are so many products out there
that are
so overpriced or have such small
colony forming units that they're going
to be uneffective
and then you need to be asking yourself
what's the purpose of this inoculation
if you don't have a clear and concise
understanding of what the purpose of
or what metabolites those specific
microorganisms do then you shouldn't buy
them because
there's so much misinformation dude and
i see it all the time even by
professionals
and i have a certain style and i'm not
saying that my style is the only way
because there's more than one way to
skin a cat but when it comes to
empirical data that is replicated over
and over and over again
i'm looking at specific microbes for
specific jobs
i don't use mycorrhizal fungi i don't
use mycorrhizal fungi for a reason and
that's one of
the huge ones right i will be able to
tell all your audience and my audience
after my next harvest whether or not
there is even an association with
uh in arbuscular or an endomycorrhizal
fungi
because there's tests for that now so i
can see if there's an endomycorrhizal
that has penetrated into the root itself
what i've seen over and over is that
the cost to inoculate with a lot of
these things
i don't get any return on it it doesn't
do anything
it doesn't do anything if you have a
healthy balanced
soil in fact i've read research
which has shown in different plants
that the symbiotic relationships between
mycorrhizal fungi can become parasitic
when the plant no longer
requires what the benefit
is that that so let's for instance let's
say your mycorrhizal fungi is releasing
phosphatase or a
phosphorus solubilizing enzyme into the
soil
and that's its job so this plant
releases a photosynthetic
that is geared for that microorganism to
keep it around
in an exchange it'll release the
phosphate that the plant needs
now let's say that that's all good
in some you know agronomic field
setting where you're growing a crop
in field conditions but let's take that
same scenario and we put that in a
system
where all your nutrition is adequate and
you have
adequate phosphate what ends up
happening
is the plant no longer requires that
symbio that once
symbiotic relationship to cycle that
phosphate into
that phosphorus in the phosphate the
biologically available form
and so the plant stops releasing that
photosynthate
now this thing we're talking about we're
talking about
um an organism that has or could have
possibly infiltrated every single aspect
of this plant's
root system and then that plant stops
releasing
what it needs it has control of its
whole root system what is it going to do
it's going to take what it wants because
it can
microorganisms can do amazing things
and matthew gates sink angel
on ig who's a great ipm
specialist we talked about
you know how easily these types of
relationships can switch
and something that might be mutualistic
can become parasitic
very quickly it's something to take into
consideration
you know we don't have science and
all the data for you know what i
particularly cultivate
however moving forward as i'm able to
collect more data and more
types of tests are become available
we'll be able to see how
how these work right
i prefer trichodermis trichoderma
bacillus subtilis combination
and that's because the trichoderma will
will colonize
the root without causing an
without a uh
it's not a it doesn't go into the the
cell itself
bacillus subtilis will and the
trichoderma will
will facilitate that and they have this
mutualistic
partnership together where they're able
to
eliminate almost all fungal pathogens
and it's because of trichoderma's
high affinity for iron the metabolite
that it produces
is the highest iron affinity chelating
compound in nature and that's the city
of force
what i've seen in organics is that iron
is very very hard to fall into solution
in a biologically
available form fairies iron fe2 plus
it oxidizes so easily in a ph
range from 5.5 to 7 that as soon as you
add
something like iron sulfate which should
be an immediately available
form it oxidizes into fe3 plus
so having a high iron affinity microbe
that can reduce or i guess oxidize
fe 3 plus intefarious iron and make that
biologically available
you're going to have a greater impact on
that plant's photosynthetic
capabilities so where
when to inoculate and what what to
inoculate is i think more important you
want to be able to add the right
microorganism that is going to do the
right thing
i personally i inoculate this
product weekly but i'm also creating a
new product because what i've seen
is that by using that specific product
weekly
that that purple non-sulfur bacteria
it's a photosynthetic bacteria
and it's releasing nitrogen
into the soil so if i have adequate
nitrogen
i want to stop using that at a certain
point
so what i'm doing is i'm constructioning
a different consortium
that's more geared for phosphorus
and micronutrient release as opposed to
phosphorus and then getting the added
benefit of the
photosynthetic bacteria that are adding
the
nitrogen in really really good stuff
there
for sure one last thing i want to get
into before i let you go i know you're
extremely busy person
talk about the rate of reproduction for
these microorganisms so
compost teas often used to extract
microbes from compost
and then there's the brewing process
where there's microbes are reproducing
what do you know about the rate of micro
reproduction
you know you can either talk about like
the compost teas versus just adding
compost
into the soil and letting them reproduce
there
and you have any tips for faster
reproduction besides what you mentioned
earlier
uh it's gonna vary it's really gonna
vary um
you know something that might be really
persistent in soil might not do so well
in water um you know so there's so many
different factors when it comes to
when it comes to culturing microbes and
it's you know really
only the strongest microbes are going to
be able to
to survive so if you're using a complex
carbohydrate like molasses
you go and do some compost tea i
wouldn't go you know you you have a
certain temperature range right that we
talked about
those are ideal for the production
you also want to make sure you know it's
so tricky man it's such a hard question
because like
like i like my microbes i wouldn't
oxygenate them to reproduce them i would
solid state ferment them
right there it's it depends on what
you're trying to go for
and and if you're just doing compost
teas for just a general biology
i mean you're just guessing anyway so i
mean
brew it don't brew it longer than 36
hours
that's my advice 24 to 36 hours is
optimal if you're going to do compost or
amendment brews
i personally do not use compost teas i
will use compost teas for bioremediation
for
land you know for agronomic settings but
that's because
those things are already so deficient i
can add
so much into it in any amount and it's
still like
i could still add more in most cases you
know because we're
building the soil health and fertility
they work great i think there's a huge
disconnect
between soil science for
agronomic crops for like earth for like
farming on land
and then using modified growing mixes
because me
personally i don't use things like
earthworms in my
or crop covers at scale it doesn't make
sense
what happens when you add earthworms to
a system that you're monocropping
it turns all that organic matter into
castings which creates compaction in
your soil so you have this
really really really light soil from
that has great
gas exchange to this really like heavy
poop warm poop you know
which means you're gonna have to add a
massive amount of aeration you're gonna
have to add a massive amount of calcium
amendments
to break that open and break that apart
so i was totally disconnected
now that i'm collecting data and i'm
monocropping
for just my medicinal herbs i i take a
different approach
you know i'm not trying to do all this
crazy stuff i'm literally just
maintaining sufficiency and balance in a
system
when it comes to my when it comes to our
outdoor
and tilling the land and bioremediation
and using microbes and compost teas and
composting
and crop covers all that yeah and it's
the reason is because what we're
starting with is something that
is not very good soil structure is not
good
aeration is not good organic matter is
really low
nutrient density is really low probably
have problems with sodium
you know so these are the things that
we're looking at
and and why it's so important to have
like your soil food web science for
agronomic crops for like food crops for
like moving towards the future
when i'm talking about something that
i've already created
i've mixed the proper aeration i've
mixed the proper nutrient into it
i don't want to do anything else to it
it's almost like i've taken
like you know something that would have
maybe taken
50 years of bioremediation to get to
this point that i have in a bed
or a pot i don't want to change it now i
just want to maintain sufficiency
imbalance i don't
you know i will put in the selective
target microorganisms that are going to
have
pgr responses
or that are going to you know be there
to out compete any types of pathogens
or to cycle nutrients but i'm looking at
target specifics
in these modified systems now when we go
out of that realm and we're looking at
soil systems we're looking at
biodiversity
we're looking at organic matter crop
cover
gotcha whole different world whole bunch
of
good stuff there for sure you can get
really deep on that level
so awesome well um yeah wrapping things
up how can listeners find you and what
do you have upcoming in the future
yeah so we are
ramping up outdoor production on the
farm i'm working on some new microbial
products
i'm trying to kind of get
i'm trying to get an uh building for
bokash i've been doing out of my garage
forever and i just
i can't do it here anymore there's a lot
going on i am
always in motion i am always doing
something you can find me at
rust.brandon on ig
you can find a link to black label
organics my farm bokashi earthworks
my corporation and
i also do private consulting too so yeah
for soil samples right so if somebody
would get a soil sample they can contact
you
and you would kind of consult them on
that avenue
yeah so i work with like very few people
actually um and the reason is because of
my time and also because i'm usually
working with owner operator
farms and
we're looking we're you know we have a
specific goal in mind i don't typically
just do like oh hey somebody wants a
test
i'm gonna do it um i do however
you know i'll help people out man like i
i was talking to a guy on instagram
and he's like dude can you look at the
soil for me he's like i just bought this
fresh soil company in oklahoma and i was
like
dude like this is this is terrible
like this is like they literally took a
bunch of pete
and then put some pearlite in it and
then sold it to you like there's no
nutrition in this
it's it's completely empty so i you know
i dm'd the company and said hey i'm
you know i'm a private consultant and i
don't know what's going on here either
maybe you
gave this guy a bad batch of soil or
maybe you guys don't understand target
levels but
he can't grow this he can't grow in this
and this is a
a small family farm this guy's relying
on this soil
you know for his livelihood and it's
like dude
it's frustrating dude i hate seeing that
because that dude would have been
screwed you know but i'm gonna help him
out i'm gonna get him all
dialed in and you know
he'll be able to be productive makes
sense
makes sense i will leave a link to
brandon's instagram down
in the description section below so you
can easily click on that and
give him a follow on ig brendan thank
you so much
for coming on to the podcast today it
has truly been an honor to have you on
this podcast you have revealed
so much information here in this this is
something i'm going to definitely
re-watch and
have to take notes for on myself because
there's a lot of stuff here that i
didn't know
and now i'm a stronger grower because of
you so
thank you for that and uh yeah i'll let
you go
and uh hope you enjoy the rest of your
day thanks man
uh it's always a good time when i'm able
to help and share so
i appreciate you
[Music]
you