what's up everybody feed I don't know me
my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're watching my extra channel VIPRE
specter sent me over their brand new
grow light the p1000 LED grow light and
in this video I'm gonna unbox the unit
and I'm also going to do a part test on
it this is one of five LED grow lights
that Viper Specter is releasing in 2020
they also have the P 1500 LED grow light
the P 2500 LED grow light the VP 1000
LED grow light and the VP 2000 LED grow
light I'm not going to go over all of
the grow lights features in this video
but I will link all of the grow lights I
just mentioned in the description
section below okay opening up the box
and it looks like I opened up the box
upside down oops
first thing I'm pulling out the box here
is rope ratchet hangers here is their
user manual it includes safety
information specifications about the
p1000 P 1500 P 2500 and some suggestions
on how to use the light there's a small
card here which says what to do if
you're happy or if you're unhappy a 6
foot power cord a wire hanging kit and
of course the fixture for the part test
I'm going to use the apogee MQ 500 power
meter this meter measures from 389
nanometers
- 692 nanometers plus or minus 5
nanometers and the measurements are in
ppfd this test is done just to give you
a general idea of what the power output
is for this light
it's not gonna be hundred percent
accurate I'm taking measurements in a
Grove tent and the reflective walls
could increase the power numbers so just
keep that in mind this core light has a
flowering coverage area of a two foot by
two foot and I'm taking measurements in
a two foot by four foot grow tent
I'll do my best to keep my par meter on
one side of the tent I'll take
measurements at three different
distances twelve inches away eighteen
inches away and 24 inches away all three
of those distances are recommended in
their user manual this girl leg does
have a dimmer on it for this part test
I'll keep the dimmer at 100% at 100%
this unit pulls 101 watts from the wall
at point 8 3 amps alright let's get into
the measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
I've also linked all of the viper
specters new twenty20 grow lights in the
description section below
so check that out if you want to learn
more about any of their new grow lights
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and I will leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]
you