what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you watch am extras channel but
respecter sent me over there P two
thousand LED grow light and in this
video I am going to unbox the unit and
I'm also going to test the power output
I'm not gonna go over all the grow
lights features in this video but I will
link it down in the description section
below so you can learn more about it
okay
first thing out the box is the fixture
after that there's this card which tells
you what to do if you're happy or if
you're not happy here is the instruction
manual this includes information such as
safety information information about the
p1000 the P 1500 and the P 2000 and it
also includes some usage suggestions
we're going to use these suggestions for
our part tests it comes with two rope
ratchet hangers one wire hanging kit and
the last thing here is a power cord for
the part test I'm going to use the
Apogee mq6 20 extended rage part meter
this meter measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers and the measurements
are in ppfd I do these part tests just
to give you a general idea of what the
power output is it's not gonna be
hundred percent accurate I take
measurements and grow tents which have
reflective walls that could increase the
numbers so just keep that in mind this
light does have a dimmer on it for the
test here I'll set it to a hundred
percent for all the measurements I take
the measurements according to the
manufacturers recommendation in this
case that's four feet by three and a
half feet for the vegetation stage at 24
inches away and three feet by three feet
flowering coverage area at 20 inches
away I plug the p2000 LED grow light
into my kilowatt meter and it shows one
point seven two amps pulling two hundred
four watts at the wall alright let's get
into the measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comment section
below I have provided a link to this
girl light down in the description
section below so you can learn more I
also did a part test on the p1000 LED
grow light I'll link that video in the
outro card and I'll leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time pace
[Music]