what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're watching max's channel here i
have the viper spectra
xs 1500 led grill light and in this
video i'm going to unbox the unit
i'm going to test the par output and i'm
going to do a heat test on it
i'm not going to go over all of the
features that this grow light has but i
will leave a link down in the
description section below
so you can click on that if you want to
learn more about the light okay first
thing out the box
is the fixture next is a wire hanging
kit
power cord a set of rope ratchet hangers
a card here which shows you what to do
if you're happy or if you're not happy
and then lastly is an instruction manual
for the part test i'm going to use the
apogee mq620 extended range parameter
this meter measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers
and the measurements are in ppfd i do
these part tests
just to give you a general idea of what
the power output is it's not going to be
100 accurate
i take measurements in grow tents which
have reflective walls
that could increase the numbers so just
keep that in mind the flowering coverage
area is
two feet by two feet and i'm taking
measurements in a two foot by four foot
grow tent
i'll do my best to keep my par meter in
a two foot by two foot space
i'll be taking measurements at three
different distances 12 inches
18 inches and 24 inches i've plugged the
led grow light into my kilowatt meter
and it shows 1.23 amps pulling
147 watts from the wall all right let's
get into the measurements
[Music]
so
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comment section
below
just a reminder that there is a link to
this grow light in the description
section below
so you can click on that link if you
want to learn more about the light
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up
and i will leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
peace
[Music]
you