what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're watching my extra channel this is
the vibe Osun 315 watts EMH grow light
and in this video I'm going to do a
power test I'm going to use the apogee
MQ 500 power meter this meter measures
from 389 nanometers to 692 nanometers
plus or minus five dianna meters and the
measurements are in ppfd I'm just doing
this we can get a general idea of what
the power output is it's not going to be
hundred percent accurate measurements
are taken in a grow tent so the
reflective material could increase the
power output so keep that in mind also
this light has a flowering coverage area
of three foot by three foot and this is
a four foot by four foot grow tent so
I'm not going to be going all the way to
the corner of the grow tent I'm going to
try to keep it in a three foot by three
foot space I'm going to take
measurements at three different
distances 12 inches 24 inches and 36
inches these are pretty standard
distances for CMH grow lights just like
all the other parts as videos I do I
will let the measurements do the talking
[Music]
what do you think about these
measurements let me know in the comments
section below a link to this girl light
is in the description section below I do
have more PARCC test videos coming out
here soon which one do you want to see
next I have the green sunshine company's
es 300 the solar extreme 500 by
California light works and I also have
the Sun system 315 watt CMH grow light
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and that we'll leave it at
that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time face
you