coming up on garden talk if i feel like
i'm off on the schedule or the plant is
showing signs of like under
food or too much food then it gives me
an immediate idea of like how much i
need to either dial back the fluoroflex
or give them a little more any kind of
training method that's out there i
probably tried it with an auto and i
don't see any significant difference
but honestly after like a year of doing
that and just seeing what was coming out
of heaven's town running 18-6 and then
seeing what was coming out of my tent in
24 i felt like there was no there was no
real difference if you are planning on
transplanting them it's on a timeline
you have to keep that in mind all these
like theories i i guess against autos
when they're like don't tap don't do
this or don't do that all it comes down
to is two things your timeline and your
genetics
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 54. in this
episode i interview hi again many of you
know that from their youtube channel hi
again which has nearly 20 000
subscribers they're both very big into
growing autoflowers and that's what
we're going to get into today thanks to
all of you who support this podcast or
patreon if you'd like to support you can
do so by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to spider farmer
for sponsoring this episode
spider farmer has recently redesigned
their sf series led grow lights in the
old version the samsung diodes are close
together resulting in the light being
more focused towards the center of the
coverage area in the new version the
samsung diodes are spaced out resulting
in a better light spread across the
coverage area i will leave a link to a
spider farmer website and their amazon
store down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
growit5 during checkout for a discount
on their products thanks to dutch pro
for sponsoring this podcast dutch pro
products are now available in several
countries across the world for those of
you that don't know dutch pro is a plant
fertilizer company that has base
nutrients additives and ph regulators
they have different formulas of base
nutrients for if you're in soil or if
you're in hydro or cocoa they also
formulate their base nutrients for if
you're using hard water or if using ro
or soft water i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code
mrgrow10dp for discount on their
products
ac infiniti is a sponsor of the podcast
coupon code mr growit will get you a
discount on their products
i've been using their cloud line t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now and
absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high and low
humidity this greatly helps control my
indoor garden environment so the
temperature and humidity stays in the
ideal ranges i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit for a discount on my
products
we're back welcome to the garden talk
podcast today i am joined with hi again
how you doing today hey
hi guys
[Music]
glad to have you on board so this is new
for me usually i'm only youtubing one
person at a time this time i've got to
interview two people at a time so
something a little bit different for
this podcast but i figured why not you
know you guys come as a team there as a
group yeah we are a package deal yeah
there we go packaged we are it's pretty
much the beginning we've just
learned to grow yeah
we bounce off each other so it's hard
not to you know yeah it's just not the
same when one person is gone you don't
get the dynamic that
is that's what i figured so
so yeah let's talk about some
autoflowers we'll talk all about
autoflowers today i want to get deep
into it really find out what you guys do
in in the garden but first let's do an
introduction can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and kind of how you
got into gardening
um i guess that starts with me because i
um as like i
was telling you before i've been
observing you know um the growth of
plants in my whole life even though it
wasn't legal um you know and it's always
been something that i've been interested
in and even just growing plants in
general
has always been pretty interesting for
me
so when it became legal here in michigan
it was almost a no-brainer for me to
just like
to try it myself because obviously i
i'm a user of the plant and um and i uh
and it's just something that i just knew
that i was going to be interested in and
um so i started growing my myself and um
that's and like really right in the
beginning is right when i met neil so he
just kind of jumped on along with me
yeah and when i when i met her is when
she was growing and i of course when it
came up in michigan to vote for it like
heck yeah i voted for it and it passed
and everything and it kind of fell by
the wayside like i wasn't like gung-ho
about growing but i was like i voted for
it because i was like heck yeah it
should be legal and heck yeah
maybe i want to grow it someday but then
after i saw her growing it kind of like
got me excited about it and then i had
ordered her some seeds for her birthday
uh some sour diesel autos and then that
was like our introduction to auto
because i didn't know there was a
difference when i ordered them i'm just
like yeah auto sounds impressive yeah i
didn't even know they i had no idea that
it was even uh there was even a
difference in plants when he ordered
them we had no idea yeah but we just
kind of fell in love with the autos and
then that you know we started growing
those and started the youtube and that's
kind of what got us into
i guess where we are we just thought hey
you know as beginners we we wanted to uh
show show
you know really that if we can do it
anybody can do it like
if
and
we don't know what we're doing you know
we started we had no clue so it's almost
like we wanted to show people that if
if they want to they can do it yeah so
it's just kind of kind of snowballed
that's awesome yeah it does take some
learning right some patience in order to
do it but definitely anybody can learn
how to do it i think
yeah so that's really cool how both of
you kind of came together like that so
you guys are you in the same garden
right what's your style of gardening are
you indoor outdoor are you soil cocoa
hydro
organic synthetic
about to open the can of worms here
um
well we started organic
and and that was actually at my house we
actually don't we actually don't live
together yeah so
in the state of michigan
we can have 12 plants per household so
we actually have two different growths
yeah so we can afford the luxury of
basically you know we're we see each
other as much as we can we live like an
hour away from each other so it makes it
hard to make the content and stuff like
that but we're doing the best we can but
basically like heaven has her own grow
which is the five by five and then i
have like the four by four so we're not
necessarily growing the same stuff or
styles we've been like going crazy you
know trying all these different things
that we can uh and just having fun with
it so we do have like our each our own
grow that we're both like involved with
but not
directly i guess because you know it's
not like i'm i'm growing more organic
and actually lately and um neil's
actually
ending one of his first runs with
with uh synthetics yeah i was we were
both doing organics i actually started
with organics i've been using nature's
living soil i've actually tried dry
amendments
and i really love that and actually i
get to learn the plant and what it's
telling me i feel like
and i get to learn it at an accelerated
rate with autos yeah
um because every plant is different
every plant's showing me in a different
way and i have to learn okay this is
what that means with this kind of
phenotype so i feel like i'm learning at
almost an accelerated rate with autos
but
i mean
i'm growing organic so you are actually
yeah
how you're growing i started to doing
the organics we were kind of doing the
same thing like dry amendments and like
what we saw like watching mr canucks and
like all the videos we've seen online uh
but then i so i tried that for basically
the last year um and then switched over
recently to try coco and like floor flex
and synthetic newts i mean it's like
completely different you know like i'm
not use it's a whole different thing but
i almost kind of like it in a way so you
know it just gives us some flexibility
to try different things with our grows
um and you know we're always just
bouncing ideas off each other and we're
actually doing um something on our
channel right now we're actually
documenting right now
um we're trying to the same strain in
one organic one six
synthetic so
um hopefully everybody can follow along
they'll be able to yeah it's a really
fun
fun one you guys can follow along with
so for autos in particular
container size is a big thing right so
some people will start in a small
container you know small solo cup and
then they'll transplant up into
different size containers some people
are adamant that you should be starting
in your final container right so they'll
start like a a three or a five gallon
grill pot and then they'll keep that
plant in that container for the entire
life
what container size are you typically in
and do you do transplanting like that or
what
i think you should start this one
yeah
well i i actually am for the transplant
and i actually have a couple reasons why
i do that
um
but
i i don't think i'm really just totally
one side or the other i just feel like
the transplant is just easier for my my
lifestyle um
honestly
i don't feel like putting it in the
final pot or transplanting it is doing
too much of harm but i do think that
there is that fine line there's a time
there's definitely a time where it gets
past where it
it's it's an auto so it's on a timeline
you have to think about that throughout
seed to the end no matter what anyway
um
so
for me i do the transplant
but i do that because sometimes
seeds don't make it
and i don't want a whole pot that i made
up and you know i'm i have a perpetual
grow so it's almost like that pot will
just sit around if it doesn't have
something in it
so for me
it's easier to just wait that
nine to 11 days
before i transplant them to make sure
but for neil i think
you do it differently yeah so heaven's
pretty much always done starting solo
cups and then transplant into final pot
i've pretty much always gone like i'll
germinate them and i just do the paper
towel method like ghetto style but it
works good so i'm sticking with that so
i just wait till it's got a pretty good
tap root on it and then put it in the
final pot uh and that's the way i've
pretty much always done ours but we've
seen so many comments about like oh you
can't transplant or don't start in a
small thing with autos like honestly
over the the year or so that we've been
doing the channel and it grows like
heaven's autos that she's always done
solo cup to final pot are you know
huge the huge ones ones that turn out
five feet tall and are just insane uh
and it's you know she transplanted them
and people are like oh you can't do like
i feel like there's definitely some
myths and things uh but we're just we
try everything like we don't care we'll
see what happens but again as with autos
i just feel like it's on a timeline even
even the transplant is on a timeline
no matter what with autos it's on a
timeline so if you are planning on
transplanting them it's on a timeline
you have to keep that in mind
i agree yeah you're definitely going to
do it on time because if it does come
root bound in that small container it
could lead to a certain growth which
like you said it's on a timeline you
could get those little baby
a little one night yep so you do have
there is a yeah there's a time where you
if it's too late
but there are benefits too so i've done
both i've
you know started in the final container
and then i've also done the solo cup and
then transplant up i haven't done enough
to really have a solid opinion on it you
know what i mean i agree actually i did
try that one time i did try that we did
the so yeah one more one
one video
it was a it was like a three transplant
without all that
the plant itself was very healthy
actually it just didn't get very big
yeah but it never ran out of nutrients
like it was always it was
it was always okay it did i mean it
ended up being pretty flame actually
yeah because i assume you're probably
transplanting into soil that has amended
with some sort of nutrition in there so
yeah as you're transplanting up you're
basically feeding the plant in a sense
right because it's a new medium on that
one and then some people will swear by
transplanting because they want the
opportunity to have access to the root
zone to sprinkle microbes on there right
so mycorrhizal fungi is one of them that
is an extension of the root zone it's
going to help with nutrient uptake and
that's best applied when it's directly
onto the roots so some people are like
yes transplant always transmit they're
hardcore transplanters because of that
reason alone so there are so many
different ways to go about it i was just
wondering how you guys went about the
autos you know so yeah we love it we say
you gotta grow to know so if you're
curious freaking try it you know i i
haven't tried all the methods there is
out there to transplant and honestly i'd
like to try more um so if people have
techniques that i haven't heard of you
could totally throw them my way
absolutely yeah always welcome
especially in the comments section of
this video if you're tuning in on
youtube comment section share some best
practices i love that i love when people
are able to share their experience on
how they do things because others can
read and learn and potentially implement
in their garden so that's one thing i
love about the community let's talk
about plant training a little bit so
we'll start with topping
topping autoflowers that's another uh
controversial thing right you can't top
autos you can't tell auto some people do
it some people swear by it
what are you guys stance on topping
autos
um
i feel like if the plant wants it yeah
it it
it definitely depends
completely i feel like
on again the the timing of it
and
in genetics yeah
i mean
in my opinion when we've i mean we've
stopped how many we talked a lot we
tried a bunch in groceries we tried
multi-tops just single tops
yeah i feel like what we found for autos
that seems to work the best is like if
it's one that is over performing or like
getting tall really quickly like after a
round it has like five nodes we'll
usually top it only once because we've
tried like you know topping multiple
times it just always seems to cause more
stress than anything so it seems like
you know early on maybe day 25 to 30 and
just if you're gonna tap it just a
single single time uh on the main one
that's what what we seem to works about
but we've definitely done both and you
know so definitely some perform and turn
out great it gives you a really even
canopy and like you know we usually do
trim off also the bottom nodes early um
instead of topping i feel like taking
the bottom nodes off um seems to do a
lot better for the plant because the
bottom nodes never end up being anything
substantial anyway that's what we've
noticed so we always like that's the
first thing we chop actually like like
the earliest probably day 20 23 we'll
cut the very bottom two notes because
they never really end up growing out to
be anything so it's like get rid of them
as soon as possible give it a little
time to recover and if it is still
beasting out
then then we would usually do a top yeah
yeah but again with autos it's on a
timeline yeah yeah i know some people
who have you know some of these genetics
are just so vigorous so vigorous
especially if you put them in the right
media like an airy medium with cocoa and
you get that all that oxygen the root
zone it's just real optimized vpd co2
all that stuff
where they're running into height issues
right you think of autos you think of
them being real small and stuff yeah
some people want to top autos and for
height reasons and also to reshape the
plant right once you top that apical
meristem that that main chute it's going
to promote growth on those lower
branches so it'll help with kind of an
even canopy and stuff like that so there
are benefits there but the the folks on
the other side are saying yeah any sort
of stunt growth on autos anytime you
talk is gonna reduce your yield so i
think that's another controversial thing
where you just gotta do it and try it
out for yourself right you gotta uh yeah
i'm not necessarily
i feel like all these like theories i i
guess against autos um when they're like
don't tap don't transplant don't do this
or don't do that
um
all it comes down to is two things
your timeline and your genetics
that's it i mean
when you really come it that's what it
is
so when people say don't do this so
don't do that i mean
where are you getting this information
from how do you know
because you didn't try this strain with
that you know you
you can't really say we we've noticed
that the
auto genetics aren't definitely as solid
as like photos so you know the one that
we're gonna do stuff with is that one
that's like performing like ridiculous
and it's like shooting up super tall
like real fast and it's like well we
better do something about that you can
pretty much either only tie it over or
you can tap it but it usually if it's
growing so vigorously that we think that
way you know it's gonna if you top it
it's still gonna do pretty good like
it's gonna recover quickly and just keep
growing like nothing happens i don't i
don't know if i prefer the topping
method but we don't every time it just
kind of plant dictates yeah what we do
yeah now how about low stress training
that's something that's often done in
order again to get an even canopy and
help with even coal size across the
plant and stuff like that and it's very
common with autoflowers do you do low
stress training at all
oh yeah yeah we do we do um the tie over
method um we use a big i'm a big fan of
the garden stakes because they're easily
positionable and you can start to train
it even if the arms aren't or the
branches aren't to the edge of the pot
like some of the tie-down ones i don't
know it's just easier to move around so
we've been using the garden stakes
mostly um and the basement autoflowers
training bags those are bottom two we've
been using those uh but you know we'll
either usually tie it over or just like
light branch stuff um kind of some more
tie overs lately as we try and like
control the height and try and get a
really even canopy without stressing it
too hard so that's usually tying it over
at an earlier age or maybe that's what
i've been that's what i've been
implementing
recently in my grow is just
the tie over
but
i don't i don't even know if it really
it helps necessarily yield
um versus just letting it grow on its
own i don't i don't necessarily think
that i think that the plant's going to
give you what it's going to give you
in in
[Music]
that's just my opinion because i've i've
we've tried low stress training i've
tried christmas treeing it i've tried
topping
i've tried i mean any
any kind of training method that's out
there i've probably tried it with an
auto and um
and i don't see any significant
difference
um i would say
if anything maybe low stress changing
maybe tying it over would give me
better light to my bud sites but other
than that
i'd see no real benefit
behind like yield that's interesting you
say that i've uh kind of the opposite in
a sense where i've grew
now of course we're talking from seed
different phenotypes each seed so
everything's gonna grow differently it's
gonna depend on what generation they're
on and stuff like that but i had 10
autoflowers all the same cultivar and i
did some of them i did love stress
training on some of them i just grew
naturally christmas tree style and the
ones i did low stress training on
actually yielded more than the normally
chrono ones that were growing christmas
tree style so i'm i'm personally a big
fan of low stress training but like you
said everybody's everybody's different i
think it does come down to genetics for
sure it's just it's so hard to measure
especially since they're all different
phenos like there's no there's no
cloning of autos like you can clone an
auto but it's not really uh that
beneficial since it's on that timeline
like you mentioned you're not really
gonna get too much out of it as you
would if you were to just plant a seed
and grow that so
yeah i do think you definitely can see
better results though when because when
you do tie it over and train it um you
know i'll all depend on genetics and how
the whole grow goes but if you can get
even like uh penetration to the whole
plant rather than the top down because
like we have the par meter we've tested
like the top of the plant versus your
bottom nugs hundreds of pars difference
between that you know so if you can get
it as even impossible and then control
your light like you of course you
you should have better yields because
everything is getting the same it's not
like just the top dogs are getting the
best light everything down is getting
just kind of the lower part that's not
gonna you know you're gonna be more
lucky but i found that when we do when
we do our autos like
when when you start to stress train like
that or do your training i feel like the
plant just focuses its energy on a
certain few
and it just does that no matter what it
doesn't yield you more in the end it
just gives you maybe better flowers and
that's just in my opinion i guess maybe
people might have different opinions
yeah grow it and try it find out but i
do think that i i love low stress
training because again you do get better
flowers out of it and
i don't know about yield but
um if you're looking for a beautiful
flower like i do i i love stress
training all the time it's my preferred
way we're always
changing up what we're doing i mean i've
been liking it though yeah i do like
dying over it definitely makes it fun
now how about defoliation of auto some
people like to go in there and pluck off
leaves you know for whatever reason they
they do it whether it be increased
airflow throughout the plant or in order
to get light down in into the canopy do
you defoliate if so what's your method
for it
yeah i've kind of gone to primarily like
leaf tucking um at least early on i know
some people like gung-ho about chopping
but i don't know i feel like i've kind
of fall back to more leaf tucking as
much as i can but there's definitely
certain autos that are just way more
busy and way more bushy and it's like
you have to go in and start like just it
gets so thick like you're going to be
prone to issues and you know i i always
at least try and trim out the bottom
portion at least the bottom third to get
the airflow and kind of keep everything
good you know trim up the bottom side
branches and then just selectively i
could just kind of groom through it to
make sure like what i want to be exposed
is we actually just put a video out of
one of our defoliation
um
but again like he said i try to leaf
talk as much as possible until
my leaves are covering bud sites and
then i'll just get rid of them um i know
a lot of people will
try you know to leaf talk as much as
possible but i just find sometimes it
just ends up hindering the plant
so you gotta really just just read your
plant just
you know you gotta
you gotta become one with your plant
absolutely
let's flip it up let's talk about
nutrients so what nutrients i i know you
said you were organic
and so
what nutrient line are you using and how
often are you doing feedings
me well since i recently switched i've
been using floraflex with coco and
man i'm just following the schedule
dumping dumping the water in and it's
going amazing it feels like cheating it
feels like teeth growing it is cheating
let's be friends the scientists have
already figured it's too easy it's been
flawless it's beasted out there's one in
there that man i don't it's not even i'm
not even gonna call it an auto because
it's at day 74 and it's like barely
starting to bud uh so i'm probably going
to run that thing over the snow blower
tomorrow yeah we're going to probably
have
there's going to be a cool office slow
motion
you know
but it's just taking too long so i'm
like yeah
forget that one
so you liking the floor flex
yeah i actually i think it's pretty
great like i'm not really opposed to
organics or synthetics but i mean
simplicity
uh you know it's easy to follow i don't
like you add it to my tap water and then
the ph is perfect like all i do is mix
up the powder it's not fair and dump it
through the cocoa and you know the big
thing is just watering more with cocoa
definitely compared to organics and what
we were doing so heaven's been running
organically like
i
currently i'm running at nature's living
soil which is an organic mix and i just
mix that with hp
the pro-mix pro-mix and um i also use
some worm castings and then i add the
harvest hero
uh a little perlite to make it a little
bit more airy just because that we
seem to find the autos like it with at
least something in there to make it more
airy if it's a cocoa or perlite or both
or whatever you want to throw in there
so um that's what i've been running and
i
i think i'm dialing it in pretty well
it's taken me quite a while
to
really figure it out but again i feel
like
i'm learning in an accelerated race and
every phenotype is different and it's
it's it's hard it's hard with autos yeah
i mean it's easy but it's hard at the
same time
that's like one thing for people getting
into autos like yeah they're fun and
they're accelerated but there's like
also kind of no second chances
oh yeah you've got to learn it and move
yeah because the plants are going to
keep going like it wants to go so if
you're ready with nutrients you're not
especially like learning with dry
amendments which take time to break down
so you got to be okay with just letting
things go yeah like it's it's a learning
process maybe that's why the floraflex
is doing so well because it's like
immediate feeding like it's not waiting
for this to break down always did it
break down a week later than i wanted it
to when the plant needed it yeah it's
just like floraflex i'm just like
dumping in what it looks like it needs i
feel like as a new grower and doing it
organically is so hard because you have
to understand
that you need to understand the soil and
not only the plant and a lot of people
don't understand that you're not only
reading the plant you're reading your
soil
and this is something that i've like the
microbes in there it's like i've been so
resistant really to learning about my
soil and more about the plant and um
i i feel like
that's something that i need to be more
aware of and i need to advocate really
more for because
i haven't been doing it it's a
relationship yeah it really is so with
organics like i said you're not only
reading the plant you're reading the
soil and you need to know that your soil
is also
healthy
and if your soil is not healthy your
plant's not going to be healthy
so those are things that i've
man need to overcome as far as like an
organic grower i think that's a great
way to put it i mean they need time to
break down right so those worm castings
that you're adding in and the nature
living soil that whatever amendments are
within that microbes need to break those
down first and put them into a form
that's available for the plant to uptake
right so it does there's a little bit of
waiting period there so you know if
you're seeing a deficiency
then you might want to have move on to
something that's kind of more fast
acting versus like a top dress of
amendments you know what i mean yeah
exactly and i think we definitely had a
learning curve where we were learning
that like we were just using dry
amendments and we're hitting issues and
it takes too long for what we're trying
to mix in to get to the plant like how
can you you know how do you correct all
these different issues immediately with
autos because you have to you know so
it's like it's a learning curve but it's
a fun one like we've never had any so
awful that we just throw the whole thing
away you know it's like something always
good as lease is coming out even though
we're still learning so it's fun to try
new things and learn every time
and we've just been having a blast with
it
yeah
so for the
you said nature's living soil and then
worm castings when do you typically
apply the worm castings and then also is
there any other amendments that you're
adding throughout the grill
um well i've
been doing right in the beginning of
flower
um which is i would say like around week
five or six
i
would start doing uh its flower girl
which is a
top dress with nature's living soil
i've started doing that
but i actually started something new
where i've been amending it with the
regular nature's living soil first
and then the next week doing
um the flower girl which is new and i
think it's working for me yeah but um
but then i then i just tap dress it
every week and allow it to feed the
plant throughout the week every now and
again i'll give it some molasses and
some recharge just to make sure they're
good but
that's probably
maybe
once
to twice every two weeks
so uh
but other than that we just water okay
that makes sense that's the organic side
and the kneel on the synthetic side with
the floor flex are you following their
feeding schedule that they have like
that i know they have different ratios
for the feeding schedule are you doing
like a full dose with that or what
yeah so they do have a um autoflower
specific schedule that you can get from
floor flex it's basically just like half
of their photo feeding schedule like
half the amounts pretty much it looks
like um so at first i thought you didn't
need calmag because i saw like a bunch
of them said no cal mag like mix but
those were i realized later all for
photos um so i did find that though when
i was growing the autos i did see a
little bit of spotting like brown spots
uh crop up but i just started giving a
little bit of calmaggin that went away
immediately um and i've just been kind
of tapering that off now that they're
kind of heavy into flour because i feel
like what's in the spoiler alert they
look amazing yeah it's going ridiculous
like i'm pretty sure it's probably gonna
be at least six ounces from just the
look of it and it's you know just the
very first run i was definitely under
feeding for a while um because i wasn't
sure like do i just start feeding the
floraflex immediately at seedling i was
like that seems like it might be spicy
so i started it in like a cocoa loco uh
mix and then for probably the first two
weeks i just gave it water because i did
give it like i did like a one gram of
floraflex for a gallon uh and then that
seemed to get him a little yellow and
heaven's like maybe just let him go
naturally because they do have you know
enough in them to get them at least
they're like their first little set of
leaves it's like just the seedlings so
the cocoa loco does have some stuff so
pretty much i just been starting in the
first two weeks with just water and then
i'll start feeding the floraflex at the
chart which is like 2.5 and it's been
it's been going great so got some
mofisto started they're beasting out so
i'm like oh man once again what are they
gonna look like
and then so you're feeding all the way
up
into flour are you stopping feeding like
some people will stop feeding like a
week or two before they harvest yeah and
then do like a flush period do you do
any of that or what
um on the schedule it has like a flush
period for the last week so it has the
newts right up to like the week before
flush which it kind of tapers off and
then you start your week of flush and
then done um but you know i i've been
kind of just like we've grown enough
autos like i can tell they're staged and
like they're just entering flower
they're just doing this so if i feel
like i'm off on the schedule or the
plant is showing signs of like under
food or too much food then it gives me
an immediate idea of like how much i
need to either dial back the floraflex
or give them a little more um and you
know so that's what that's just what
i've been doing with this first run and
it seems to be working great like almost
zero issues literally just water
that's kind of not fair
yeah it's it's gonna be sitting here
watching him do so good and i'm like man
i'm struggling over here that's why i
think the organics like in learning that
way makes you a better grower because
you have a better understanding of like
how to correct that stuff in the soil
where it's like
synthetics or what at least the system
i'm doing it's like dump more of this or
that you know less more you know so it's
not like i'm really learning anything
about
i guess how the plants grow or the soil
and the microbes and all the
relationships it's totally different
style of growing something i guess you
think about when you start growing oh
yeah it is yeah it's it's completely
different so many different techniques
when you're talking about synthetic
versus organic for sure i mean we go on
and on and on about that if we really
wanted to but yeah but we won't
yeah
that's a whole nother conversation
but on the
synthetic side of things a lot of people
do is they'll monitor the ph
is there a specific ph range that you
typically aim for or are you hands-off
when it comes to ph
um for synthetics wise it's been pretty
easy like um i've always says on the bag
like keep it between six and seven i
think so it's pretty wide range i'm just
recalling i'm not 100 sure uh but
basically my tap pretty much comes out
at seven almost exactly right around
there um and i've been checking it all
the time after i add the floraflex and
mix up my gallons out of my feed and
every time after i add that it's it's
like ripe 6.3 6.25 6.4 so i've literally
just been dumping it at what it ends up
being and but it's always been like
right in that range and the plants seem
to be responding amazing like it's
that the stock of the thing is like
super duper huge i cannot believe how
big it is i can't wait to chop this
thing it's going to be oh my gosh
yeah it's going to be a it's going to be
a fun one
and so do you also do a runoff
measurement for ph or just you only
monitor the ph going in
i only monitor the ph going in i haven't
i haven't had any issues yet to where
it's like oh man maybe i should flush it
out to clean the salt or something like
i always like water at least till a
little bit runs off every day but not
enough to like flood the bottom of the
pan like i pretty much got it to where i
water and it will drain off like just
enough to where because they're in air
pots has a slightly raised bottom um
just enough to where it's not flooding
out and it's sitting in its own water
pool so i've just been watering like
that and keeping them like moist and
you know as they get bigger you
definitely have to water more i've
noticed especially with the cocoa
because it's like the plant's so huge
it's just sucking the pot dry and it's
like oh got a coat so i'm gonna rig up
an automated watering system here i got
some of the rings um and then i could
just mix up like a big tub of freaking
floraflex for a week and just be like
set it and yeah i cannot wait for this
it's gonna look dope yeah it'll be fun
well it'll be easy which is the main
slide more time to edit videos and you
know should definitely be able to save
some time there for sure now heaven on
the organic side of things ph do you
monitor ph at all or what do you
typically do for ph
okay actually this has been a
conversation we've been having a lot of
weeks we about to have a conversation
um
so
i've always ph i've always ph to 6.5 um
even before like i was having a ph pen
and i was trying to ph to 6.5 i was
trying
um
because i always knew that it was
important but
i
didn't really understand why until i
really started understanding you know
the plant and how it uptakes nutrients
um
and a lot of people with organics will
say well well don't don't even worry
about ph don't worry about it don't
worry about it well
so in this last two
two runs i want to say i hadn't been ph
and i've actually had been running into
issues near the end of flower
because i hadn't been phd my water to
and i usually do it
you know with
a range between 6.3 and you know 6.8 and
i try to get it around 6.5
and that's even when i have nutrient or
if even if i'm like molasses or calmac i
always ph my water
um
and these last few runs i hadn't been
and i actually was running into issues
with uptake of nutrients i i feel like
that's what it is because all of my
plants were showing different signs um
you know of different
nutrient deficiencies in excess and i
was like what is going the only thing
for me that would cause that is a ph
imbalance
um
and i just obviously made
that deduction so um because all my
plants were just so different
um so i've actually
my last run was starting to do the same
thing and i'm like you know what
i
i've admittedly never checked my soil ph
until this week because i was like i've
always been told it'll just balance
itself out
while
i
checked on my beginning balance for my
unbalance and it looks like it creeped
up it must have creeped up because i
wasn't pha
um so
for me i don't know if it's so much of
ph in your water but making sure your
soil ph is on
so if your soil ph is too high then you
should be ph in your water lower
um so
if i just feel like you should just be
checking your soil ph because it's
something that i hadn't been doing and i
know i'm rookie mistake
but it's it's a real thing and i've had
to actually learn that the hard way i
hear a lot of people saying ignore ph
when it comes to organic as well but
really your your water source has to do
with it has a lot to do with it i mean i
fell in the same trap ignore ph
and when i was growing organic my water
sources at 7.5 ph so i was putting 7.5
ph water going in and my soil ph drifted
up over time and it was a lack of
nutrient uptake because the ph was so
high i know some people
had their water sources like over 8 ph
it's like
yeah mine actually fluctuates throughout
the year in the winter it's different
from the summertime in my area so i'm
not sure if that's um for every area but
i feel like
at least checking your ph and making
sure it's in a certain range yeah and um
but your soil ph is i feel like the most
important yeah i've always had best luck
you know adjusting the the ph of my
water making sure it's you know within
the
you know 6.0 6.5 range if it's on the
non cocoa i usually go 5.8 and then i'll
i'll water in but there are things in
the soil that's gonna adjust the ph as
well right the microbes can adjust the
ph the plant can release acids that can
increase the th for example with iron
for example if the ph is so high the
plant will release acids to lower the ph
so then it will be able to actually
intake iron so
you know there are several different
things in the soil i didn't know
something i learned quite recently
from a scientist actually so that's
awesome
right that is amazing and i mean they
got to survive yeah
yeah so
so there are things beyond just your
your water source
of ph that's going to adjust the actual
ph in the medium so how about ppm or ec
are other measurements that growers
commonly make do you do it on the
synthetic side of things
yeah the floor flex schedule does have
like a recommended ec for each stage too
so it gives you not only like how much
you should be weighing and adding to
your water per gallon um what you see it
should come out to so you know i've been
i have an ec meter i have a ph meter of
course i'm checking i still even though
it's always been like within that 6 to
six point five range easily just just
straight mixing it right out of the tap
i still been checking the ph anyways
just because i'm still always curious if
there's a drift um and the ec's always
been pretty much
bang on with what they suggest so i've
i've literally just been you know i i
feel confident enough now with the auto
watering system like i can just do the
recommended amounts with
my straight tap water and
it should just basically be maintaining
unless i don't i the one thing i haven't
tested is like long terms like mix it up
let it sit for a week like if i'm gonna
mix up a bucket for a week's worth of
watering at a time like is the ph gonna
drift over time in that bucket yeah i'm
gonna measure it and figure out if it's
doing that because then i'll have to
maintain basically a mini i don't want a
huge reservoir i just want enough to get
me at least like four or five days in
case i'm at heaven's house or we're like
going to chicago for cannafest like
i want to make sure everything's not
going to die
you know
yeah
that's like that's a great experiment
i'm actually i'm into that yeah but from
what i've seen it seems to maintain
heaven do you do the monitoring of ppm
or ec at all when growing organic
never no never
i don't even think so it's very
hands-off i just find that
if your ph is on um
if the plant
is healthy um it's gonna it's gonna take
what it needs yeah there's a there's
definitely something to uh less is more
especially with autos and you're just
learning it's easy to get into that's
there for it to take it's easy to get
into that too much love syndrome where
you're just trying to do too much at
once like with an auto like if you're
new just like take it easy like you know
if you're using bag nudes from the store
and you're getting some fox farm like
you know just water that baby
the first like you're gonna at least get
to four or five weeks on just that you
know don't go crazy you know it's easy
to get out of control and get in there
and start wanting to add stuff and do
this and
you know i completely agree yeah it's
definitely when you have that bagged
soil that's enriched with nutrients it
can be a lot easier and then you know
you definitely don't have to feed
right away for sure
let's let's switch it up let's talk
about harvesting autos i know there's
quite a few people that struggle to
identify when the plant is ready to
harvest
what do you both do when it comes to
harvesting autos like how do you know
when to harvest
well
we have a saying 84 out the door so
i mean that's really our general
timeline we're not going to say that
every plant's at 84 days you chop in
like that
it's more of it's more of a guideline
than an actual rule
um
but we i mean just like any photo
really yeah we're looking at the
trichomes we're looking for usually
around 15 to 25 amber it just kind of
depends on the plant what we're feeling
for it how how the whole plant's looking
but definitely we want to make sure the
trichomes are cloudy we've found if we
chop it when they're too clear just ends
up being like you get more of a jittery
effect um
than what we're looking for so we just
find like at least i like a little bit
cloudier with some amber definitely not
just on the very top buds but like
throughout the plant yeah
but we found most autos seem to take you
gotta look at the tricom i've spoke to
somebody recently talking about autos in
particular and he brought up something i
thought was very interesting he had
mentioned that with autos in particular
he found that some genetics don't really
amber up takes extendedly long time
bananas will shoot out prior have you
come across that in any of the autos
that you've grown where it's just it's
not turning to amber although the plant
looks like it's done
um not really i don't think i've seen
that either with the genetics that we've
grown i mean we've had the banana and
then like bananas and stuff but i think
that was more or less you know running
it too long yeah
and not even just running it too long i
the the light situation wasn't great the
you know humidity situation wasn't great
at the time when we had experienced this
so
i'm not sure if that had anything to do
with it or some feeding issues we could
have been doing like stress will cause
them to herm and
manner and i've definitely definitely
probably stressed some one from a ph
issue from a pen that was way out of
whack uh and that was my own fault for
not uh preventative and like calibrating
it but you know
autos are susceptible to that kind of
stuff heavy stresses because they are in
that race to the finish like they're
just trying to survive and they're just
like on a beeline to the end so but as
far as the flower itself um i think it's
just like you know any photo flower you
look at it i mean if you look at an
autoflower versus a photo flower i mean
if you're not looking at the entire
plant i don't know if you'd be able to
tell the difference
okay that makes sense i just figured i'd
bring that up because i heard like i
said i heard that from somebody else i
thought it was super interesting so i
figured i'd talk to somebody who has uh
probably grown more autoflowers than me
i've only grown probably about two dozen
autoflowers total so i don't have that
much experience with with autoflowers uh
but i i hadn't heard that before
i yeah i've grown a lot more than this
can't wait to see you do them at these
tails and see what you think of them
because we think they're pretty
impressive yeah should be awesome
light cycle
what light cycle are you typically using
for auto some people do an 1860 some
people doing 24 some people are doing no
darkness 24 hours on and no hours of
darkness
have you do you stick to one light cycle
or you've tried several or what well
neil's tried a couple different kinds of
light cycles i've always done 18 six
it's always just kind of been a
no-brainer to me because i don't
autos don't thrive it's been proven they
don't thrive about anything more or i'm
sorry less than 18 hours of light
um but
[Music]
so it was a no-brainer for me to just do
that because
obviously electric costs money
so
yeah um so i just started out with that
but neil's tried different life cycles
yeah i pretty much since i started so
when when like the two by four videos
started like early on in our channel
like that was basically the grows at my
house uh and i started with the 24
because i was like oh more light more
yields yeah you know and uh but honestly
after like a year of doing that and just
seeing what was coming out of heaven's
tent running 18 6 and then seeing what
was coming out of my tent in 24 i felt
like there was no there was no real
difference like i didn't see any
substantial difference between the
yields from her plants and the yields
for mine so i'm like well what's four
hours more or you know whatever amount
of time rest for the plants you know
lower electric bill and um you know if i
was to tell somebody new like just go
18-6 because you're going to be making
mistakes you're not going to be like so
good at growing that you're maxing out
this plant's genetics and potential
where you could actually maybe see that
a yield difference um i feel like you
know 18 6 unless you're really killing
it or you're a really good grower you're
probably not going to notice anything if
you if you're a really good grower then
you should already know the answers
yeah
i gotta agree with you i think there's
18 six generally i've tried both 24 0 18
24 uh light cycles and i didn't see much
of a difference except for my
electricity bill which was which was
higher with
yeah exactly yeah my personal opinion it
wasn't worth it but i'm sure there's
people that are gonna comment on this
video and say what you kidding me
24-0 i got
24 hours yeah i totally got four more
ounces and maybe you know maybe they did
like i feel like some of these people in
this deep water culture that can just
make these plants go crazy like yeah you
probably would see a better yield
because you're you're nailing it you
know but like
it's gonna feel the same way with co2
though by the way yes
[Laughter]
yeah i mean there's so much more that we
could talk about but we're going to kind
of wrap things up here i did want to get
some just general advice from you too
for the folks that are beginners growing
auto flowers right what general advice
do you have for folks that are that are
just getting started with autos
just know that
when you make mistakes just treat it as
a learning experience because when
you're growing auto flowers
and i'll say it forever but you're on a
timeline
so
that is always something you have to
consider so when you're growing autos um
just take every experience as a learning
experience and move on and just know
that you you can if you can do it i can
do it i'll just say that yeah
i'm i'm sorry i'm high if i can do it
you can hide again
i don't know i feel like it's such a
it's a crazy question but if you're new
and you're thinking about getting into
it like you're obviously going to be
leaning towards like you know some
certain style of growing because
basically you know everybody has their
own way of growing and you won't know
until you grow so just
start doing something and figure it out
along the way like community is amazing
it's super fun it's a fun hobby anything
you got to start somewhere yep and
you're pretty much always going to end
up with something you know and it's
always going to be better every time so
just go for the gold good advice
so tell the listeners how can they find
you and what do you have upcoming in the
future
we're hiking on everything luckily so
instagram
youtube here we have the channel so you
know all kinds of fun auto adventures
trying all these different crazy things
we're trying to figure it out uh having
fun uh we're gonna be at canafest in
chicago april nine and ten so if any of
you guys are gonna be there say what's
up it's gonna be a blast
we're up for our influence of the year
not sure exactly what that means yet but
uh it's very exciting it's gonna be fun
and there's a bunch of people said
they're gonna be there so we're like
heck yeah we're going chicago we'll take
a train and
meet a bunch of people but yeah we have
our lives every sunday i'm sorry every
other sunday um and that is on youtube
and twitch
so we out here sweet i'll definitely
have a link to your channel down in the
youtube description section below if
you're listening on one of the podcast
platforms just search for them hi again
search that on youtube you'll find them
they'll pop up if you enjoyed this video
click that thumbs up button
if you uh haven't subscribed to the
channel please do every single weekend
i'm releasing these garden talk podcast
episodes and i'd love for you to tune in
to future episodes
neil heaven thank you so much for coming
on today this has been this has been fun
this is a real cool laid-back
conversation and uh it's definitely fun
to hang out with you guys know
yeah thanks so much for we're big fans
of you yeah we love it so thanks for
having us on thanks so much man all
right take care everyone see you in the
next episode
[Music]
you