we have a lot of folks who are shopping
for grow lights right here in
2025 what should Growers look for when
purchasing a grow light well that's the
the question is uh is right off the bat
is uh what it's kind of like it's the
the map you know where are you trying to
go is where you're going to try to get
you know so like let's say you're in a
tent and uh you're inside your bedroom I
mean right off the bat we've kind of
nixed HPS out of the the picture you
know not going to be able to grow with
high-intensity Lighting in a in a small
tent atmosphere it's is you have to air
cool that's one of the things that's
really uh got me educated on this like
even 10 years ago is you know growing in
a pre- environment we stacking lights
together in a small room they all had to
be vented hoods so we'd run air through
the hoods so we'd remove all that heat
and the byproduct of that is you were
cooling the bulb and so color
temperature like you you'd have like an
more orange uh uh number
uh for the HPS and that's that number is
it's an actual temperature color is
temperature and so when you're lowering
the temperature of the bulb to its
actual spec operating thing you're
losing a lot of spectrum and so I
started learning like why is it my
friends that like have like gavitas
strapped to their ceiling and their
giant basement are getting what you know
the same gen we'd all share genetics
back then it was it was tougher you know
there wasn't all the SE a lot of the the
the genetic Banks were over in Europe
and stuff and you'd be ordering bur off
the back of magazines like it was sea
monkeys or something you know it wasn't
wasn't a lot of trust as far as like the
system so it was really relying on the
community so we all share genetics we
find things that we we liked we got the
Forum cut of the of the cookies like
back back back in the day when it first
came out and I'm noticing these guys are
getting way better results than I am and
the only thing that was different is I
was venting them and then turns out as I
started educating myself sure enough I
was losing a lot of spectrum you're
losing a lot of power that's supposed to
be hitting those things so if you're
choosing I would say uh there's a lot of
controversy controversy right now about
HPS versus LED and one of the things
that's very very interesting is genetic
expression phenotypic expression I work
with The Jug guys The Jug dealers over
at New Millennium nutrients and uh jiren
always likes to say phenotype is
genotype times environment so you and I
have the same cut we got the same
genetic profile but you put it outside
and I put it in a tent and they're going
to express differently and so I always
wondered where did all the things that I
loved in the 2000s where did they go I
still I still get the the name some oh
here's the strain you want and they give
it to me and it's got the name and it
looks kind of like it but it didn't
taste the same didn't smell the same
didn't didn't quite look the same what
happened was it was it genetic drift you
know was it all the Clones are being
abused or people lying is it not the
thing that I did and then as I started
meeting more people more trustworthy
guys that are ogs in the game I started
getting the real stuff I'd get the real
cuts from the real people they still
didn't Express why is that and so I
started digging in another hole in
knowledge and I realized oh it's because
they're not grown under vented hoods
with GH nutrients packed together in a
tiny room VPD out of control like even
bad growing conditions if there's a a a
phenotypic expression that you enjoy the
only way you're going to get it is
through an quote unquote an inferior
growing process because what plants were
selected under is what they will Thrive
under especially if you're not running
things like if you get a genetic and you
just take clone from clone from clone it
will acclimate to your environment but
it will never it it's code is locked but
when you uh take something and you breed
it like if you back something and you
self it and you self it against itself
and you the genetic remains it shuffles
the deck and I always remember that
family that I grew up with they were I
was friends with the the old the middle
the youngest brother well the oldest
brother he was like a genetic copy of
the mom the middle brother was like a
genetic copy of the dad and the youngest
brother was like a direct split and I
started understanding like oh okay there
it when I was dealing with plants I
started getting okay recessive genes I
see what's happening it's like some of
the grandparents come in some of the mom
comes in different eye color different
skin tone different hair color it's like
okay I get it and then you take the twin
brothers and you raise them in different
places and they're going to act
completely different twins raised in the
same room finished each other's
sentences yet twins raised across the
country can have surprisingly different
lives it all started coming together and
this comes back to lighting where one of
the biggest things that you can do to
change your environment is the lighting
so if you chose an HPS versus LED one of
the things that really makes LED
Superior Superior to HPS is that you
don't need the cooling for a a watt is a
watt so if I have a th000 watt LED and I
have a th000 watt HPS technically
speaking more light there the same exact
heat but the LEDs produce more light for
that heat so your output is there so
it's not that LEDs are cooler or you
know there's more efficient so a watts
of watt a watt of heat equals x amount
of BTUs and you're going to get what you
get turns out that when you measure
things like Leaf surface temperature
right when you go in there with a little
a little thermometer gun and you point
at at the leaf the you need to run your
room slightly hotter with LED because
there isn't that infrared there's almost
no infrared that when you see those red
diodes in an LED that's them trying to
stick some red in there because they
don't come with it whereas HPS uh High
Press sodium just kicks out the IR
that's why you could feel the heat
coming off it that's why if you go to a
restaurant you you'll see the IR heaters
you'll you'll have something that isn't
glowing it's not red it's not hot you
know to to like visually hot there's no
color coming of it yet you're getting
blasted with this this heat that's
coming off of it and that's the just a
pure IR lamp that's hitting it you think
that uh that wouldn't have a you know
we'll just I'll raise the temperature a
little bit but what is kind of
interesting is that's the leaf surface
temperature
it actually affects like the the the
biotic structure of what's going on like
heat stresses and things even though the
there's micro boundary layers that your
plant creates that's why we like a lot
of air flow and get them going and it
breaks those micro boundary layers
across because it it it's just got this
micro layer of insulation we'll call it
and so you want to knock that all off
and so just raising the temperature of
your room doesn't necessarily get the
plant leaf surface temperature all that
much higher whereas if you're bombarded
with that IR it gets it way higher I was
like oh so even the things that we kind
of consider not valuable in growing oh
it is affecting the metabolism of the
plant this is why I'm not getting that
that diesel expression I want that 2003
diesel you know like uh lifestyle Rob
and I when we were hanging out in Vegas
you know we're just the right amount of
Boomer Millennial that uh we remember
that 2003 diesel baby where to go it
still exists you just have to grow it
wrong according to 2025 standards got it
yeah I feel like these days particularly
in the Homegrown Market that I feel like
a majority of people are going with LED
versus the hid you know hiid that
whether bhps or MH or even CMH falls
into the hid category high intensity
discharge but yeah as far as what to
look for when purchasing a grow light I
think first thing right off about is
coverage area what area are you trying
to cover if you're looking for a 2T X 4T
coverage area well you can filter it
down by there and then you can kind of
get into the granular details of what's
the power output what does the light
spectrum look like and then you can even
look at like the diodes drivers people
get really really deep into what's the
btu the heat output so there is a lot of
different things that people can look at
go to the full episode by clicking the
outro card here or click the link in the
description section below catch you in
the next video