what's up everybody feed that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're watching extras channel in this
video I want to talk about why I tend to
grow smaller plants I've been on YouTube
for a while now and most of my plants
are what I consider small and from time
to time I will get somebody to comment
on my videos and criticize or I guess
make fun of me or try to make fun of me
for growing smaller plants and not
really realize that that's what I'm
trying to do and so first what do I
consider small plants I consider a
medium-sized plant a plant that takes up
about two feet by two feet wide of grow
space with training and you know is two
and a half to maybe three and a half
four feet tall is like a medium sized
plant so anything smaller than that is
what I personally consider a small plant
now some of you may comment on this
video and say you're growing a medium
sized plant I think a smaller plant is
this that's fine everybody kind of has
their opinion on what size is small
versus medium versus large but I do like
to keep my plants smaller sometimes they
do training on the plants which make
them make the structure even smaller
than if I were to just let the plant
grow naturally and also aim for a
shorter veg time and that's gonna be
another thing that kind of keeps my
plants is small so why why do I do this
well for me I am a home grower I grow
just for myself I don't sell the
dispensaries I don't do any black market
stuff it's just for myself and I do have
a plant limit so in the state that I
grow in I'm allowed to grow twelve
plants max that's it twelve plants I see
one of the problems that I personally
have just growing for myself and this is
I'm saying it as a problem but I think a
lot of you gonna say that's a good
problem to have which is yielding out
too much for me to consume for example
if I were to grow twelve plants and grow
them out so they're medium sized let's
say they're three foot plants and let's
say they yield four ounces per plant
so twelve plants times four ounces that
equals forty eight ounces which is three
pounds three pounds is going to take me
a long time
consumed by myself so just hearing that
it might click for some of you okay so
that's why you grow small plants
my strategy is this I don't care about
biomass at all I don't care about maxing
out grow space I'm just looking to yield
around three ounces per plant that's all
I really need and most of the time I
don't need to max oh my plant count at
12 I can really do a growth cycle with
just six plants and then that's enough
for me to consume for several months if
not longer and I also like to grow of a
variety of strains so when I'm growing
out these smaller plants typically
they're all different strains and people
have been watching my channel for a
while know this but I get a lot of new
subscribers and a lot of people who know
my growth style so video like this where
I explained it is is overdue I guess so
if I can yield around 3 ounces per plant
per strain I'm gonna have a variety of
different strains to kind of work
through I also focus particularly on
quality instead of biomass again some
people are just going for yield they're
vegging out their plants for a long time
to looking for these large clusters of
buds me I aim specifically for quality
you know a lot of these newer exotic
strains are lower yield errs you know
you might not get as much biomass but
you're getting real smaller compact buds
that are just covered with trichomes and
you know I like strains like that but
there are people out there who don't
want that they actually prefer biomass
so different strokes for different folks
is what my friend Rob over at CLTV says
I think that applies to what I'm saying
here by the way shout out to him I've
got a shirt on here right now but yeah
that pretty much explains why I grow
smaller plants and I'd love to hear from
you watching this what's your overall
strategy do you go for yield do you try
to maximize your space or do you not
worry about maximum outdoor space or
getting a yield just kind of grow your
plants for quality let me know what your
overall strategy everybody's different
everybody has a different approach to
growing let me know what you do down in
the comment section below and I'll leave
it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time face
[Music]