coming up on garden talk i myself have
never
had increased yield from topping in auto
and these days i'm really trying to
focus more
on feeding the soil rather than feeding
the plant a lot of this stuff is just
kind of subjective as again what you're
doing what your goals are what your grow
area looks like they're great for
concentrates as well a lot of people are
actually growing them because of the
fact that they grow so fast they're able
to turn them around and press them and
create concentrates right from the
flowers if you're in a really small area
and you've got a ceiling
max height then you might consider
smaller pots you definitely in my
opinion want to transplant them well
before the stretch everything that's
alive has a will to survive you know
even microbial life everything wants to
live
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 49. in this
episode interview turret grower he has
been gardening for five years and
specializes in growing autoflower plants
in this episode he talks about growing
autos everything from starting soil
feedings environment conditions when to
harvest and more thanks to all of you
support this podcast or patreon if you'd
like to support you can do so by going
to patreon.com
mr grillet before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's podcast who helped make that
goal possible thanks to mars hydro for
sponsoring this video mars hydra has two
new led grille lights the fc8000 and the
fce8000
both grow lights are 800 watts and will
work great in a 4x4 or 5x5 grow space
the fc8000 has two versions one with
samsung lm301b diodes and one with
samsung lm301h diodes also the bars are
detachable both the fc and fce8000
are very suitable for co2 growers a link
to the website is down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr growit for discount
on their products big shout out to ac
infiniti for sponsoring this podcast ac
infiniti is well known to produce high
quality products and provide excellent
customer service they have the thickest
grow tent on the market today
in-line fans with a controller that can
automatically turn on and off according
to specific set points they have
seedling mats trimmers drying racks and
several other products that you can use
in your garden i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
grow it during checkout for a discount
on their products a big supporter of
this podcast is dutch pro they sponsor
this podcast and i use their nutrients i
have been using their base nutrients
formulated specifically for auro and
soft water i also have been using some
of their additives like calmag silica
and their root stimulator called take
root they have a few other additives on
top of those and ph regulators coupon
code mr grow at 10dp will get you a
discount on their products and i'll
leave a link to their amazon store down
in the description section below
all right well back
welcome to the garden talk podcast today
i am joined with chad but some of you
know him as direct grower how are you
doing today
hey man i'm doing very well how you
doing doing good good thanks for asking
excited to have you on finally have you
on my podcast i had you on my live show
i was on your podcast so now we got you
here on my garden talk podcast we're
going to be talking all about autos
today so becoming more and more popular
autos i mean it's just about every day
where somebody hits me up and has a
question about autos and you have a
whole podcast based around them so i
thought you'd be a great person to have
on and talk about autos kind of your
experience with them and and so on and
so forth so we're going to get into so
much stuff in regards to autos today but
first one of the things i like to do
with every guest would be an
introduction so can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and kind of how you
got into gardening yeah man first i just
want to say thank you for having me on
i'm really honored and i appreciate it
um
i got really passionate about gardening
probably about five years ago uh before
that um i've been around like my
grandparents who gardened a lot um
vegetable gardens a lot of irises and
and just different plants and trees
around their property
kind of grew up a little around that and
that's kind of my exposure to it and but
i wasn't really interested until about
five years ago and it's when i realized
um how much you know certain medicinal
plants could help my tourette syndrome
so um
my online name often is tourette grower
and that's because i have tourette
syndrome my 14 year old son also has
it's a genetic thing that runs in
families
and it started when i was a a young lad
probably nine or ten and uh
would just kind of do weird stuff with
my eyes and things like that and it
wasn't until my early 20s that i was
actually kind of diagnosed with it
so there's other things that come along
with that
anxiety
ocd are very popular things that go
along with tourette syndrome so
yeah when i discovered how well
medicinal plants could help me
and you know of course along the way
just other things about different plants
that that we like um i began
uh using those those plants and um
quickly realized that uh it's pretty
expensive to source those plants from
other areas and so
i thought well i'm just going to start
growing my own i had a little bit of
garden experience just being around my
grandparents and stuff so
i started growing autos somebody handed
me a handful of auto seeds
someone local to me and so i just began
popping those and germinating them and
learning and
growing and researching and
you know as i said it's one of the
co-morbids of tourette's is ocd so i can
become pretty obsessive compulsive about
things and i think gardening was one of
them but more in a positive way you know
and
yeah i just started searching around
actually and i i love podcasts including
yours and so i was searching around for
podcasts revolved more around autos and
more around the home grower and not
necessarily
commercial grows
and there wasn't one so uh man i just
decided to start my own and that was
back i think in 2019
or 2018
and uh that's how that came about
and since then for the last five years
i've just really been
uh plugging away just learning and uh
and gardening and
just being a part of the community that
exists you know and just um jumping in
there and letting that iron
iron sharpen iron as they say you know
growers coming together like you and i
are right now and just talking and uh
taking truth nuggets and learning and uh
it's a great community so um
that's pretty much it man yeah i'm in
located in southern california i was
born and raised here um married we've
got five kids and uh busy life yeah
nice nice i'll definitely have a link to
your youtube channel down in the
description section below and also your
podcast i'll link that down in the
description section below as well we did
a we did an awesome episode on
harvesting drying curing and people just
thought it was a good one so i'll
definitely have that episode linked down
in the description section below as well
so
yeah and i actually um i'm still
yesterday as a matter of fact i i got a
message about that episode and uh how
much they learned and how much to help
them so uh now that you mentioned that
so thanks for coming on man i appreciate
it that's so cool to hear so let's start
with your style of gardening i know you
primarily grow autos i think you only
grow autos you can correct me from wrong
there but are you indoor grower outdoor
grower do you grow in soil coco hydro
organic synthetic what's your grow style
when growing autos
yeah so i do primarily grow autos i do
have
my first photo period seeds that have
sprouted they're just a few days old so
i will be going down that route and
experiencing that but
i also primarily grow indoors
i grow in
grow tints i have two two foot by four
foot grow tents by six foot high
just led lights and
one of them i've got an auto pot system
set up
and i know you're familiar with that
that's just an automatic gravity fed
watering system that feeds the plants
from the bottom up
and then in the other tent
i just hand water in pots and um
i've only had two tints for
just under a year so i don't really have
a a certain
you know
system going with the tents or anything
like that but basically one's just hand
watered and one's automatically watered
um one of them i
typically grow my own personal herbs in
and the other one i actually um
i chuck pollen i don't want to say a
breed i chuck pollen and um and and
produce seeds so one of one of them is
kind of set apart for that and the other
one is set apart for
um my own medicine
and then as far as soil um i grow in i
guess we can we call it soil but it's
it's really a a grow medium right it's
uh you know uh we call it soil but it's
peat moss based you know like typical
potting soil
with perlite and a little bit of compost
added in
i do prefer to grow organic i went
organic a couple of years ago
about three years ago and
i
kind of dabbled a little bit in the
synthetics as well
um but i find myself really being drawn
to the organics and really nerding out
on
the soil food web and microbes and
things like that so i'm really
really kind of treading down a path
right now of getting deeper and deeper
into
organics
but as far as right now
i just grow in
an amended potting soil you know with
right now i just got dry amendments by
down to earth i just mixed them up and
did a super a super soil type grow like
a sub cool um you know
type method that's what i'm doing right
now previously i was using nature's
living soil concentrates those worked
well for me too
and then um i'm also going to be testing
out foop
sent me
a little beginner line of their their
entire product i don't know if you've
heard of them so
they're an organic bottled nutrient
company
and it's called food f-o-o-p
and it's basically made from fish poo
and they've got a bloom and a veg and a
sweetener and and things like that so um
they just sent it to me so i'm just
going to be testing that out
and
seeing how that goes
so i i really do um i'm pretty i'm an
organic guy and and as time goes by that
passion and that style of growing is is
growing for me itself i just i keep
getting more and more into it
right now i'm getting into some natural
farming practices and trying to learn
some different things with that
just made my own lactic acid bacteria
serum i did my first indigenous
microorganism collection i just made my
own
water soluble calcium
by roasting eggshells and soaking them
in vinegar for a week things like that
you know save money and uh
and and resource my food waste and just
things like that you know totally going
going down the organic rabbit hole for
sure
that's awesome so let's dive into autos
i think we should start with the pros
and cons to autos i know you have a
whole video on this on your channel
really good video actually show them my
youtube recommended feed i think it blew
up um because youtube's been
recommending it everywhere they still
recommend it even though i've watched it
but there is a lot of pros to autos and
there's a lot of cons to autos right can
you talk to us about some of the pros
and cons to growing autos
yeah absolutely man um
i mean some of the pros to start off uh
they grow really fast and i think that's
something that attracts a lot of people
to them
um from the time that they sprout
from the soil um you know often times
within
70 75 days on average they're they're
finished from the day they sprout
some of them even earlier
some of them will you know be done
within 55 to 60 days some really fast
ones and still get fairly large as well
and
you know some of them some of them will
go 90 days but for the most part they're
just super fast you know you pop them in
the soil and once they germinate they
just take off like a freight train
and uh and within
you know 60 to 90 days you're harvesting
your plant
that's definitely
definitely one of the cons or the pros
i'm sorry
another pro is that
it's a day neutral plant
so which means it doesn't require a
specific light cycle to flower
so it doesn't matter if you are under 18
hours of light or 12 or even 24 with no
darkness
they'll flower regardlessly based off of
genetics and not based off of
a light cycle whereas a traditional you
know traditional photo period plants of
any species uh you know they require a
certain amount of of light and darkness
to trigger that flowering in them so
that's
that's a pro and it's a pro to a lot of
people because if you've got some room
if you've got a veg tint and let's say
you've got a corner a space or a spot i
mean you can throw just throw an auto in
there and
let it go if you're you know growing
tomatoes and peppers and whatever else
you're growing and there's a couple of
areas and you want to throw an auto in
there like why not fill up the space
um so you know things like things like
that are beneficial
they're great for concentrates as well a
lot of people are actually
growing them because of the fact that
they grow so fast they're able to turn
them around and press them and
and create
concentrates right from the flowers
so it's a super fast turnaround they
provide a lot of oil and resin and stuff
uh that your traditional photo period
plants
will produce uh of course you know
depending on genetics but um but yeah i
mean for the most part
you know they're just as just as
powerful
as long as you get good genetics you
know and and they just grow they just
grow really fast man
another thing that's great about them is
if you keep them all under the same
light cycle and you've got one area with
one light cycle you can just do a
constant perpetual grow of different
ages
um
you know they they actually will take a
lot less light and that's not something
i'm really familiar with um i think
that's something that maybe
is better
chatted with with dr bruce
[Music]
but as far as the dli and stuff with
with autos um
i'm not sure what that looks like but
but i do know in general i think they're
going to require a little less intense
light because it's on for say 18 hours
instead of 12 so your dli
is going to change with that for those
light nerds
that's about as far as i can go with it
unfortunately because i don't know much
about that but
those are some of the pros
of growing autos there are some cons
there are cons to them absolutely for
sure like anything
i think the biggest one being that they
automatically flower that that could be
the biggest con and i think it's a lot
of these things are subjective right
like depending on
who the grower is and and what they're
looking for and what their style is and
what their goals are
but the fact that it automatically
flowers can be a problem especially for
a new grower
um if you encounter any deficiencies
let's say you're in you're in a
vegetative stage let's say it's it's
been two weeks
let's say you're like in a potting soil
of some kind maybe like a fox farm happy
frog it's pretty popular potting soil
for people to start out in
that potting soil in particular is it
can tend to be
more on the inert side i guess you can
say there's not a whole lot of compost
or worm castings or humic acid and like
all that different stuff there's not a
whole lot of it in
happy frog as as compared to ocean
forest say with the fox farm brand
so if you sprout in something like that
within a few weeks the plant's going to
run out of food you're going to be
showing deficiencies
if you're not um
purposeful and proactive about
feeding that plant or making sure that
you're set up for that next stage and
you show deficiencies you don't have a
whole lot of time to correct those
because the plants going to end up going
into flower on its own and of course
once you see the deficiencies
you know what what's happening in the
soil has already happened and you're now
just seeing it
in the leaves so
that could be a problem you know if
you're if you're learning to grow and
you're running it or even if you're an
experienced grower you know and you run
into deficiencies
it's going to be an issue for you
because you don't have that time to slow
down and fix it and say you know i'm
going to wait another week before i flip
into flour i'm going to wait another two
or i'm going to train it out a little
bit more
you don't have that that that
opportunity and i think that could be
one of the biggest cons
one of the biggest cons to it
i think the second largest
con would be that you can't clone them
and so if you find a cultivar that
you're in love with or that you really
liked or that uh helped you in some way
um
you can't just clone that and keep it
around uh you now you can clone it now
let me be literal here
you can clone it
um
and it'll root but it's not going to do
anything for you the best that i've ever
seen done
was a friend of mine in san diego
and she um cloned it twice she cloned
her original and then cloned that one
again and just had kind of this
consecutive harvest but each clone was
smaller and smaller
so as you can imagine that's
a waste of time i mean in my opinion
unless you're like really in love with
that strain
so you can't clone them
um
another con right now at least is
there's
there's a lot of bad genetics running
around when it comes to autos in general
a lot of facebook backyard um
you know
pollen chucker bro breeder
uh genetics and you know some of them
are okay you know not everybody is like
that so i don't wanna
you know speak i don't wanna paint a
wide brush for everybody but um
my biggest caution would be to stay away
from these facebook groups man um
because a lot of these facebook groups
you got guys on there you know selling
their uh you know there's their pollen
chuck seeds for 50 bucks for five of
them you know and
they you know only two of them sprout
one of them's
a female and that one is just wanky and
doesn't get anywhere and you just gotta
be have discernment like with anything
and just be careful but that's a con
there's a lot of crazy genetics running
around right now
um
and i think another con and i kind of
touched on this already but uh is that
they may not be the best to learn on
you know they may not be the best uh
plant
to learn on um and for the reasons that
i spoke about a bit automatically
flowering because with a photo period um
which ironically i've never grown until
now but with a photo period
you know you have that opportunity so i
think those are uh probably the biggest
bullet points as far as pros and cons go
yeah i think you touched upon a lot of
good ones both pros and cons you know
one of the things that you mentioned is
if there's any sort of stunt growth
while the plant is in the vegetation
stage you could potentially impact yield
right it's going to negatively impact
yield if you have a stunt growth it's
going to automatically flower
so i agree with you it might not be the
best for new growers to start with
autoflowers right you have much more
control with photo periods so yeah i
think that's that's a big one i feel
like because of that
because that stunt growth and the
vegetation stage could negatively impact
yield a lot of people are planting
autoflower seeds in the final container
they're avoiding that transplant process
right so my question for you is what pot
size do you grow autos in are you
starting in a small container and then
transplanting your way up to a larger
container or you just starting out in a
large container and avoiding that
transplant process altogether
i do both
to be honest with you and it's just
simply because i just
get itches up my butt and i like to
experience at things and experiment you
know what i mean i just i just i do both
for the most part i start in the final
container
um you can transplant autos but you do
have to be careful and you do have to do
them um
at the right time to avoid that stunting
you know you definitely in my opinion
want to transplant them well before the
stretch
um you also want to transplant them
before they get too root bound in their
container so for example if you start in
a solo cup
typically and i get this from my friend
dan full duplex
typically when those leaves hit the
outer edge of that solo cup
your your the roots of that auto is most
likely hit the bottom and just starting
to kind of circle around down there
for some odd reason and this is
totally anecdotal with just me and a few
people we just all kind of agree that
for some reason if they're when they're
started in a really small pot if you
don't transplant them quick enough they
will become root bound and they'll it
for some it seems to trigger them in the
flower a little bit earlier almost like
anything less than one gallon now i'm
not claiming that scientifically i'm not
claiming that as bro science either i'm
just kind of some of us have been like
that's that's interesting you know
so you want to
um
you want to get it out of that that solo
cup if that's what you're starting in
once the leaves kind of hit that outer
edge i use that rule of thumb for any
size container i start in
sometimes i'll start like in a half
gallon pot that's what i did recently i
started in half gallon pots i was kind
of doing a miniature final hunt so i
started in small pots
once the leaves hit the edges
the plants had showed sex
and so
i went ahead and just transplanted the
ones that i wanted to keep and move
those ones forward if you don't
transplant them in time they're just
going to end up getting root bound and
they're going to end up going into
flower and then if you transplant them
you're just going to really stunt them
even more so transplanting is possible
and and it's and it's it's it's very
doable it's just you really got to pay
attention and kind of
do it at the right time
you know because that it just it's going
to keep going and it's on a time
schedule you know the clock is just
ticking and ticking and ticking and
ticking so you don't
you don't want to mess that up you know
some people are going to claim that
transplanting is is beneficial because
then they have the opportunity to
sprinkle some mycorrhizal fungi onto the
roots right it's going to attach the
root system be an extension of the root
system help with nutrient uptake so
transplanting be they're able to
sprinkle directly onto the roots i
personally like to do like a third cup
of worm castings put that in the bottom
of the hole that's going to definitely
help with beneficial microbes you know
and it's close to the root zone so i've
had good luck doing that
that's a good idea what size container
are you in five gallons or even seven
gallons or what all over the place man
so in my auto pots they're 3.9 gallons
but i'm considering upgrading to the 6.6
gallons i think they are
and the reason being is is because they
end up running out of uh out of food and
top dressing is challenging and stuff
with those because they're bottom fed so
typically three
3.9 gallons for the auto pots
in my other tint if i'm if i'm doing
like any type of pollen chucking or
anything like that i usually grow in
small pots so that i can
sprout a bunch of them and
kind of weed out the ones i don't want
and if not then i actually like to put
two
ten gallon pots in a two by four tint
and just grow two
just two of them in that two by four
tent um
is is great too because in a ten gallon
pot
you know i can mix up a super soil and
it'll have plenty in there to get that
thing through those whole life with a
true a more true water only
and uh
and it'll you know they'll fill up
a two by four tent easily to two plants
in a 10 gallon pot so i'm kind of all
over the place man to be honest with you
okay yeah you've tried a whole bunch of
things there yeah i just i'm always just
doing different stuff you know but um
but as far as like pot size and what i
would suggest i mean in my opinion it's
a lot of this stuff is just kind of
subjective as again what you're doing
what your goals are what your grow area
looks like um if you're in a really
small area and you've got a ceiling
max height then you might consider
smaller pots
you know
[Music]
just things like that yeah for sure i
want to back up and go back to your
starting mix you touch base on it a
little bit and you mentioned that you're
mostly in peat mixture with perlite
you're using down to earth nutrients can
you be a little bit more specific on
like you know what's your ratio of peat
aeration
and what specific amendments you're
mixing in to begin with
yeah so
i'm actually um right now i'm actually
using bagged potting soil this last run
i actually used ocean forest because i
had three or four bags laying around i
plan on getting away from that
just to save some money but
from what i understand that's a typical
you know
333 of um you know like peat moss
compost and then a narration like
paralyte
i would like to get away from perlite
because when i hand water it all just
kind of tends to float to the top
i'm thinking of going with rice holes
because of their
their aeration quality as well as you
know that they break down provide silica
to your plant but
there's been some talk about
something um
i don't know man like something i forget
what it is but there's been some talk
about how they can produce some type of
negative chemical or something if i'm
not mistaken but i don't know
so the the potting soil it's already
bagged up and then what i did this round
now what i usually do is i've been using
nature's living soil and so that's just
a concentrate that they provide to you
which is basically like a bunch of dry
amendments already uh kind of cooked up
you know by the microbial life and it's
readily available it also has microbes
in it that's typically what i would use
before
and i would just add that to a happy
frog or an ocean forest
or pro mix or any of those those potting
soils you add that to like the bottom
third or mix it thoroughly and it's
supposed to be like a pretty much a
water only all the way through
um what i'm doing now is i've switched
gears and i bought all of the um dry
amendments uh to make my own super soil
from down to earth
and this is my first time doing it
so i can't really speak as to how it's
working or anything like that i've just
got some seedlings that just sprouted up
that are in their final pots in that mix
but what i did
was i just mixed that into the bottom
half and then the top half i just did
ocean forest so the idea is and some
people say ocean forest is too hot for
autos
i have never had one auto have an issue
so
um i mean to each their own uh but
that's just been my experience so um i
start seedlings in that stuff with no
issues so on the top half of my pot i
have got fox farm ocean forest
and i did add perlite um i like to add
you know quite a bit i like to have
really really really well draining
aerated soil
and so um the bottom half is
ocean forest with the uh dry amendments
mixed up inside of them
and so basically you know my seed will
just pop up and it will grow in that
ocean forest and when it's in the plant
is mature enough and it's a little a
little more established it'll hit that
super soil and it'll begin to use that
to uptake those nutrients that the
microbes have been breaking down for the
last couple of weeks
so that's kind of where i'm at right now
i'm not sure if i'm just going to keep
going down that route
i'm considering
getting into purchasing like a two foot
by four foot bed
and getting some peat moss and some rice
holes and some of my own compost and
make start starting my own living soil
uh indoors but that's i've got a lot to
learn when it comes to that and i don't
want to just pull the trigger on that
without doing my my research first you
know because i don't want to waste my
time it's uh it's an investment
you know yeah you mess things up then
you mess things up and
your overall result might not be
what you anticipated unfortunately yeah
so let's dive a little bit deeper into
nutrients right so we talked about your
starting mix when you're not doing the
super soil method that you talked about
right you're just using bag soil
eventually the nutrients are going to
deplete in the medium right so this is
going to highly depend on the pot size
right if you're in a larger pot size
with more soil more nutrients in there
it's going to take longer for that plant
to work through it versus a smaller pot
size let's say a three gallon grill pot
for example so say you're in a smaller
grill pot and you need to feed the plant
you know you need to feed the plant the
nutrients i know you said you're organic
what nutrients i think you mentioned
down to earth what nutrients are you
using and when are you feeding
okay so typically
i did mix um so prior to my
dry amendment grow that i'm doing now
like i said i'd mix nature's living soil
so then that would have
enough nutrients to get me through
usually
until you know mid-flower
um and then mid-flower is is when i
would um start to see deficiencies or
run into issues
and um so with with autos a lot of times
you can get through your veg without
adding any veg nutrients if you really
don't want to
and depending on what type of soil
you're in a lot of people like will grow
an ocean forest for example and then
when their autoflower goes into bloom
um they will then just begin adding
their bloom nutrients or top dressing
you know bloom
type dry amendments
and stuff like that so but what i would
do is um i would let the plant grow
and then
uh what i like to do now is right when
it starts to go into flower
and
what i mean by that is
you know when when the flowering spots
are starting to you know really spit out
some of those um white pistols and stuff
at that point
i like to top dress
and begin feeding teas
so what i'll do is
when it starts to go into flower um
nature's living soil makes this product
called girl flower power and it's made
for bloom and it's of course it's
something that we can make on our own
but you just sprinkle that on top and
maybe etch it in a little bit and water
over it and let that you know kind of
get in there and that'll begin to break
down and feed the plants and then i also
like to brew teas
whether that's just an earthworm
castings tea to add microbial life
itself and some nutrients
or nutrient teas right where your your
plant is actually being fed in organic
tea where it can uptake certain things
right away
it's a benefit of the girl flower power
is that it contains microbes and and
diverse microbial life but it also has
readily available nutrients for your
plants because it's already basically
those dry amendments have already been
cooked so to speak have already been
broken down and readily available forms
for the plant
so between the top dressing and a tea
um
you know the top dressing i like to
sprinkle a little bit on and kind of
water it in and then let it let it go
for maybe another week and then sprinkle
a little more and just little bits at a
time and then just feed teas and let the
tea go to work and uh that'll usually
get me through um you know till the end
so it's not a lot not a lot really not a
lot of feeding going on
and these days i'm really trying to
focus more
on feeding the soil
rather than feeding the plant um with my
own kind of grow technique and what i'm
into so and you know it's it's i i tend
to focus more on
the quality the end quality and the of
course everybody wants volume um you
know i i prefer my my my my red
delicious apples to be huge if i if if i
can you know i want to enjoy it you know
but i i'm more concerned about the
quality of that apple as well or the
quality of the herbs as well
and i try not to just push for size um
in looks and things like that i try to
really dial it in because i'm using this
stuff
as medicine you know more so than
recreational um
so i try to
you know just focus on the in quality
and as far as um you know terpenes and
and different things like that
that are going to help me medically so
growing organic works great for that
because i'm not trying to grow monster
plants or trying to push anything too
hard
it's just not my uh just not my thing
yeah i totally get what you mean
let's uh let's switch it up let's talk
about environment for autos right so
what temperature and humidity do you
typically aim for when growing autos
the same as photos
typically i mean really anywhere if i
can keep it anywhere
really if i can keep it around 50
through the whole grow that would be
great i do try to tailor it a little
more earlier in its life i try to get
the humidity up right now i've got some
seedlings and i've got the humidity up
to about 70 percent
um
when they begin to grow and get a little
bit bigger um i'll drop that down
personally i try i try to mess with the
humidity it's difficult for me because i
live in a pretty arid dry environment so
the humidity can change very fast as far
as declining for me
so i i'm constantly battling to keep it
up to keep it up
so if i can just keep it at around 50
basically through the whole grow and
maybe drop it a little bit during flower
which is really easy for me um then i'm
happy yeah that's but you know to be
honest man
um i've grown them uh outdoors during
like right now during the winter it's
january i've had plants out there um a
couple of years ago right now in
southern california and you know it'll
be 60 during the day
and drop down to 32 30 to 29 sometimes
at night and if i don't have too many of
those nights of that freezing
temperatures
i've grown some some pretty good looking
large plants outdoors in the winter in
the cold
it's not too humid here so i don't have
to worry about any type of rot or
anything like that
and uh it's you know it's and it's sunny
it's sunny southern california so but
you know
i do try to
to dial it in man as much as i can you
know in my indoor environment of course
to to just get that extra little umph
you know a lot of people don't know that
these plants are resilient right there's
an optimal range for conditions right
and then there's a tolerance range so
there's a large range that these plants
were able to survive in right so cold
nights are common outdoors and the plant
still survives you know it's within
their tolerance range
yeah i think that tolerant range is is
wider than a lot of people think it is
yeah and temperatures you know pretty
much the same as photos um i do like to
run warm if i can
i prefer to hit like 80 maybe even up to
82. some people think that's a little
warm
but in my environment i noticed that
that kind of tends to have the best uh
fastest growth for me
um and when you're using led lights i
think there's might there may be some
science to that of being able to run
things warmer or something i'm not sure
but um
yeah you know environment um the more
that i can dial in my environment uh the
better
my plants and more healthier my plants
are going to be and going to grow so i
do try
to dial it in but you're right man i
mean these you know plants they want to
live
you know they just want to live
i've got a mandarin orange tree that i
was gone for eight months caring for my
grandma and when i came home
it was almost dead i had only been
coming home like on the weekends
sometimes and uh
i ended up just chopping that thing
about four inches from the soil and i'll
be darned man i came out there in the
spring and that thing had little green
leaves on it and now that thing is about
six and a half feet tall
and it just those little sucker leaves
grew and i braided them and it was
really cool man but these plants won't
they want to live they're like you and i
they want to live every everything
that's alive has a will to survive
you know even microbial life everything
wants to live and uh
so it it's it's um they'll do well man
you know they'll do well in environments
i've i've grown them like in the in the
rain and just all it's not ideal but um
i've done it
you know yeah a lot of people that are
okay with the you know just being in the
tolerance range but there are some
people that want to really dial things
in and be in the optimal ranges let's
talk about co2 co2 is something that's
often supplemented when growing indoors
do you supplement co2 at all i don't
um
and i'm i don't because i just i'm not
educated on it and i'm not sure as far
as like you know an exhale bag or a tnb
naturals um no i don't
um
i'm not educated on that really as far
as
how that works and and being able to add
more light and
and things like that um i'm not
convinced necessarily
that that those products really do
anything um i don't understand it uh if
someone can explain it to me i'd
be great but um yeah i just i don't
supplement uh co2 just because i'm not
i'm not convinced that it that it works
you can cut that out if you've got like
any type of deals with anybody dude
like tmv natural or somebody yeah i just
uh i'm just not i just don't uh i don't
supplement co2 i've used the tmb
naturals canisters i used for quite some
time and i actually did put a co2
monitor in the room and it actually does
work there was often times where it
averaged on around 800 900 ppm and of
course it's going to depend on how much
you exhaust i was exhausting
intermittently i also now i start using
the mushroom bags
and so i use the exhale bag the mushroom
bag i have it hanging above the plants
the top part of my grow tent and within
a couple weeks that whole substrate was
really inoculated i mean the whole
thing's like white at this point and i
don't have my co2 monitor in there i
have one of the older ones we have to
actually hook it up to the wall and it's
like this big basically the size of
softball for those that are that are
listening in on one of the podcast
platforms there really needs to be more
companies releasing co2 monitors i mean
i'm about to talk to ac infinity and be
like dude if you guys release a co2
monitor it'll fly off the shelf because
nobody has co2 monitors right now that
are affordable right i mean i know pulse
has one but i think theirs is connected
to like a it's like a 500 device because
it also has like par and it has
temperature humidity all that stuff
worth the money you know because you can
actually measure par so for a lot of
people they say it's worth the money but
you know i'd really love to see a
standalone co2 monitor that hooks up to
your app so you can see the different
levels throughout the day along with
temperature and humidity i mean soon i
mean if you're a company listening build
you know make it right now because
that'll that'll for sure fly off the
shelves i'm confident of that one
yeah i think that would help everybody
out you know and um i by no means in
saying that they don't work i i just
personally was was i haven't been
convinced but i mean you've got a co2
monitor and you're you're monitoring it
and it's up but
um you know i've got some some friends
who have done the same thing and it
shoots up to eight or nine hundred but
but within 24 to 48 hours it's it's back
down low and it doesn't hike back up um
even when they're shaking the bottles or
and stuff like that so um i just
personally just haven't pulled the
trigger on it but you're right man a
monitor would be great you know an
affordable one so people like me can be
like well let's try this out for myself
you know
exactly exactly
how about plant training let's get into
that a little bit it's a highly debated
topic right we talk about some of the
types of training so low stress training
i think a lot of people do with
autos in particular definitely helps
with kind of having those even colas you
prevent that
you know the plant growing christmas
tree style and have one big main cold
that's at risk for for bud rod mold to
get in in the middle of it due to lack
of air flow so on and so forth so low
stress chaining is very very common
topping is one of those things that are
very very debated right we touched upon
how
you know any stunt growth
is going to negatively impact yield but
there are some people that swear by
topping and you know doing one top at a
certain point and they swear that they
get a bigger yield off of it what's your
stance you know on on training we can
even get into super cropping do you do
any low stress training super cropping
topping any type of plant training when
you're growing autos
so i've never super cropped
but i used to top every single auto i
grew
and
you know my stance really is whatever
works for you that's my stance that's
usually my stance on a lot of this stuff
um
i think that topping has a place
for me
again this stuff is subjective for me
topping
is is good when it's needed as far as um
ceiling height maxes and stuff like that
i started out in a two by two by four
tent a four foot ceiling height in my
opinion unless you're growing like micro
greens is really low
and so um
the plants would grow up into
dangerous areas in that light very
easily
when you you know if you've got a pot
down at the bottom that's taking up a
foot and then the soil level starts and
then you've got to stay
let's say you're you're you know you
let's say your light in particular you
need to stay at least 18 inches away um
you know that only leaves you so much
space
so that's why i topped you know
you can
indeed top autos
uh you can top them at whatever node you
want the question is is it going to be
beneficial for you
and um
so let's break this down into a couple
of different categories here as far as
yield
i myself have never
had increased yield from topping in auto
now
i can't say that with absolute certainty
because like we talked about earlier i'm
unable to clone
an auto and do a side-by-side comparison
you know if we could clone one
and then have two identical plants top
one not top the other grow them the same
and see what happens that would be great
but we don't have the benefit of doing
that with autos because you can't clone
them correctly
so
uh in my opinion
and based off of my experience
i don't see them giving you any giving
me any more yield uh that could be
grower error that could be my own uh
grow techniques that could be something
i did i'm not pumping full of uh
of of synthetic nutrients i mean if
you're in dwc
um there's so many variables that could
play into this you know but in general
yes you can top
if you're topping to get more yield
that didn't work for me it doesn't work
for a lot of people if some people say
that it does work for them then maybe
maybe that method of those people that
it's working for is kind of where people
need to flock to and build upon
for me in my method it doesn't really
produce any more yields for me
so i think there are other reasons to do
it
so like for me ceiling height another
reason to do it there's a guy on
instagram named green75
he tops and hacks and bends and ties and
trains these things
like they're just yarn you know what i
mean and um he does it because he wants
to shoot for
all colas and not necessarily
popcorn fluff and stuff all along the
bottom um
so
i'm not sure it gives you more yield
for me it didn't and for a lot of people
i know it doesn't i prefer to just grow
them naturally and do some low stress
training i think low stress training is
great
it doesn't really stress the plan out
and the biggest yields that i've gotten
if i had to compare and i had to make a
guess was from low stress training
um a topped plant
uh an untopped plant and then a low
stress trained plant the lst one uh has
i i've gotten the biggest results out of
and that was actually just simply kind
of bending the plant over almost and and
letting it grow
uh horizontal and letting the side
branches grow up and i just ended up
with these huge like just spear cola
shooting out all over the place
um
but a lot of times these days i just let
them grow and
it's just because i'm fascinated with
their natural state i do like to you
know shave the legs so to speak and
lollipop a little bit and get some of
that larf on the bottom but um but for
the most part i just like to let them
grow but
it's a debated topic man it is um can
you top absolutely of course you can
should you
well that's like i said that depends
solely upon your your your experience
your goals uh your environment um
all those different things that's just
my subjective opinion on it though
how about defoliation some people like
to strip their plants basically naked to
where they have just a few leaves on
each branch are you doing any type of
defoliation techniques on autos
not unless they're really leafy and
bushy
not unless a leaf is really in the way i
do a lot of tucking i like to tuck the
leaves and get them out of the way um if
it's a really really leafy plant and it
just looks really wild and nuts then
yeah i'll defoliate it a little bit i
try not to do too much at one time but
i like to just kind of
give the plant
what it needs to the best of my ability
to
get the best genetic expression out of
that plant as i can that's kind of my
goal gotcha
a few more things that i want to get
your input on so a few questions do you
flush before harvest or give your plants
a period of darkness before harvest and
then along with that when do you harvest
okay
if i'm growing in it with synthetic
nutrients then then i do flush
um
and but i don't really grow
synthetically anymore so no i don't
flush
growing an organic sometimes the plant
will naturally fade sometimes it won't
as far as when i harvest i mostly pay
attention to trichome development as
well as
i look for the pistols um kind of like
we talked about on on my podcast i look
for the pistols to recede kind of curl
up and kind of want to go into the plant
turn orange or brown or whatever color
they turn
of course i like to see the flowers
themselves uh kind of fatten up a little
bit
and uh i pay attention to trichome
development
it's a really weird thing with autos in
my experience um
and i hear other people say this as well
man it's really weird uh they don't go
to amber trichomes a whole lot
um if you're waiting to get like a 50 50
you know like you do like some people
want to go crazy like 50 50 amber cloudy
on a photo period like autos a lot of
times they won't do that you'll just be
waiting around that thing's done and
ready to be harvest
so
i typically just wait until i see
growth slow
sometimes though i think you said like
sometimes they'll even stop kind of
uptaking a lot of water as much as usual
um i wait for those pistols and i just
wait for the trichomes to be mostly
cloudy and uh and and nice and you know
milky and cloudy and uh and i wait for
some amber usually i'll get five to ten
percent and at that point i tend to
harvest um that's pretty much my
preferred
area of harvest probably even with a
photo as well
so
gotcha that makes sense
well this could have easily been a two
or three hour podcast episode there's a
lot of things that we didn't cover maybe
in a feature episode who knows might be
a part two who knows yeah anytime
but definitely appreciate you you coming
on tell us how can the listeners find
you and what do you have upcoming in the
future
yeah so you can find me uh my
hub basically is instagram that's kind
of where i hang out
you can find me there at torret grower
also autoflower podcast those two
accounts
same two usernames on youtube
[Music]
you can find me there as well and this
year
i'm just diving more into organics
more into natural farming techniques i'm
going to be documenting uh how
to produce your own seeds at home just
to have your own plants to grow not not
teaching how to breed or anything like
that
i'm going to be
just trying to share and document how to
grow for
inexpensive
real cheap and use resources from around
home and
that's pretty much it man i'm just uh
looking forward to continuing to
be a part of this community man and uh i
appreciate you having me on brother
really appreciate it yeah no problem
i'll definitely link chad's channel down
in the description section below if you
tuned in on youtube also link that
episode we did together on your podcast
that'll be linked down in the
description section below i would like
to actually make that your most viewed
episode so if the viewers here could do
me a favor and click on that episode
give it a listen guide and comment let
them know
that i sent you over there and let's see
if we can get it the most viewed episode
on your your channel there so sweet if
you enjoyed this podcast click that
thumbs up button if you're tuned in on
one of the podcast platforms like apple
podcast please leave a rating and review
and if you are on youtube subscribe
every single weekend i'm releasing a new
podcast episode with a new guest so
thanks chad appreciate you coming on and
i hope you enjoy the rest of your day
yeah you too
[Music]
you