how about your daily routine how has
that changed having from basically no
equipment to having topof the-line
equipment um it's a lot more Stressless
I don't know if that's a word or term
but yeah um I I hand water so that's a a
thing that I still haven't figured out
um but other than that I I feel like I
can leave town for a couple days I can
leave town for like 2 3 days if
especially like you know grown in soil
you have a
2day in between watering most of the
time especially with like the medium I'm
using I don't have to water every single
day now that I'm in flour I might have
to water every other day but um yeah I
feel like growing in soil and with the
controller to hook it up to Wi-Fi so if
you go to Disneyland and you want to go
to Florida to visit your family or
things like that I still look at my
stuff I still see what's going on if you
have anybody in town you can have them
go do what you see going on oh this is
going on um hopefully I just to do this
it'll work that's huge um before I was
kind of just like scrambling I felt like
I was the only one that could fix any
problems I couldn't go out of town I
couldn't like there's no way like nobody
knows my problems nobody knows what can
be fixed but now it's kind of like a I
don't want to say automated cuz there's
like the new like automated system but
it helps me control myem I've like I've
been saying this ter a lot with my
friend I talk about growing and it's
like full control no offense to like
companies growing Autos or anybody that
grows Autos but I don't personally right
now because I really like full control
when
it um I want to know how many days of
veg I can go for I if plant just decides
to do what it wants to do I want to know
how many like if uh right now I have one
gallons in my T I want to know that I
have this many one gallons the bare
minimum I'm always going to put the bare
minimum at developing uh 28 you know at
the
lowest 28 um at the weight of each one
gallon I'm just going to you know I'm
not going to high help if I know how
many I have and I know how many that
can develop then with the auto you could
never really calculate or predict those
thing with um photo periods and having a
system that is controlled that word
control become so much more like you can
control every single thing that's going
on even when it comes to like cutting
clones you kind of can control how many
days going to take the Roots come out
well a little bit of it is hope but if
you know what you're doing you can fully
control it wow having that controller
like you mentioned where you can
basically go into an app on your phone
and be able to not only see what your
conditions are but you can control the
different pieces of equipment through it
there as well that's a game changer yeah
that's crazy I felt the same way when I
went to like the AC Infinity system
using their App instead of kind of being
blind I spent so many years without that
and it is kind of nervous leaving town
because you don't even know like you
just hope that your plants are going to
be good to go you hope that the the
environment conditions are going to be
solid that the lighting is going to turn
on like it should and turn off like it
should you know so yeah that's
definitely uh definitely a huge game
changer that's another thing I forgot um
before you guys came I was having a
problem with um my lighting like I um
was using like the old like spin wheel
timers and and you know it happens I did
it wrong I was probably high but um I uh
W winded back my timer to where somehow
it was a couple more hours of light than
it should be it didn't turn off or it
cut back on and um literally things were
starting to Revenge everything had those
rev uh branded everything like every nut
it was wild but I wasn't able to catch
that because during those times it was
out I wasn't going to open that door I
was like just no way I don't need to go
in there like P up but um now that I
have the controller I don't really have
to worry about that I will say if you
are new to the controller at all and
you're setting up the controller by hand
I don't think anybody should do that you
need to use the app because there's like
the left and right button sometimes will
change settings that you don't even
notice and your lights might cut back on
and the only way to change that is in
the app I've had to happened to two
different people I've seen on Instagram
and I personally messaged them and
they're like y thank you like this is
wild I didn't know that was the thing
but yeah go to the full episode by
clicking the outro card here or click
the link in the description section
below catch you in the next video