what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris
aka mr growit and i'm back with another
video in this video i want to talk about
security cameras in your grow space
specifically the light that security
cameras admit
so i had a grower reach out to me
recently and he had mentioned that
he has security cameras in his grow tent
and he swears that
his plants won't hermie because of the
security camera the light that it emits
i personally do not come across this and
i don't really have the knowledge to
know
whether or not this type of light from
security cameras
will impact plant growth or not so i
figured i'd reach out to a lighting
expert
and get their opinion on it so i hit up
dan from the green sunshine company
and got him on to a zoom call and here's
what he had to say
okay dan how's it going thanks for
joining me tonight
hey chris how you doing pretty good
pretty good thanks for uh thanks for
coming on um i got a good
lighting question for you something that
might actually stump you love landing
questions
so i i've had somebody reach out to me
quite recently
and his plants uh turned out to be a
hermaphrodite plant
and what his theory is
is um he recently found out that his
security cameras that he has in his grow
emit light so a lot of people don't know
that security cameras they emit light
ir light infrared light is what they
admit he
is uh confident that that turned his
plants
to be a hermaphrodite i want to reach
out to you because
you in particular because you own the
green sunshine company
you have a couple different grow lights
and one thing that you're real known for
and it's on your website
is the emerson effect and the emerson
effect for those that don't know
is basically it's a combination of ir
light as well as other lights on the
spectrum
results in faster growth photosynthesis
but i are alone i'm not sure if that
would actually trigger
the plant to do anything so i want to
kind of reach out to you today and get
your
uh thoughts on that one sure yeah that's
a really
great question because it's gonna help
you understand
how plants respond to light and
what i think is important to understand
is the plant has several
systems inside of it that may get
triggered by light
so you might think hey we're giving the
plant light
and like it is going to respond the
plant actually has several systems
inside of it that will
you know respond to light like whether
it knows it's going to sleep uh
using it as energy to grow it will
respond to it like a signal and also use
it as energy
so there's a few different things that
are going on here so
so so let's start with photosynthesis so
photosynthesis
um pretty much if you have a broad range
of light you know from
blue from uv to infrared if it's joined
with other colors it will
create growth um on its own only the
colors in the par range
will create growth if it's a single
color so if i was looking at a security
camera
if it would affect growth or not it
probably would not
just in terms of an intensity standpoint
so it may not be significant for any
sort of growth it's because it's not
significant
the other thing that touches on your
viewers question was the hermaphroditing
and uh there we're getting into the day
night system
okay so and that's the phytochrome
system so that is sensitive to
mostly blue light and red light
so that's exactly why you can go into
your grow room with the green
light and your plants don't wake up
because that green light is is not
picked up by that system so that system
doesn't even see it and it doesn't even
know
there's any light it may use that green
light for photosynthesis but it may not
wake up
so green light's interesting like that
same goes for infrared light it does not
wake up the phytochrome system so and
it's actually used infrared light is
used to put plants to sleep faster
so if you you can you can buy like
infrared pucks and turn them on
right after your lights turn off it'll
actually help your plants go to sleep
faster we won't get into the specifics
so
infrared at night is actually a good
thing like if you ever have like a light
flash in your room you want to dose your
plants
infrared so it'll make them go to sleep
even faster
so i took a uh you asked me this
question ahead of time and i
you give me a heads up and i actually
went back here into our office and i
took a spectro
uh uh i have a little apogee instrument
and i took a reading here and you can
see it's in the like 780 range
in grow lights normally uh what's
effective for growth is like
you know 700 720 740 and then after that
it really drops off
so this wouldn't really affect um growth
so much
um it i'm actually not sure if this
would affect the phytochrome system so
if this alone was in your grow room it
wouldn't be a bad thing
now if your light had like actually you
when you were viewing it if you had any
visible light that would be bad
especially if it was blue light because
generally blue leds are
very intense and that is the that is the
signal that your plant actually looks
for like that's the truest signal your
plant looks for for
the presence of light so blue light is
very bad
for any sort of day night thing so in
short
if you look at your security camera and
you can't visibly see any light
you're probably okay and if you see
light
definitely cover it up and then know
that your infrared sensor might be
somewhere else
so there's two two sources of light like
the indicator of the saying it's on or
the infrared sensor that
lets you have night vision so hopefully
that answers the question
uh did i miss anything chris do you have
any questions that i might have
missed no but i do have a follow-up
question that brings up a good point so
you said any other light
on top of that right so if there's a
status light
on the actual piece of equipment and
that's one thing that i've run into
before is i actually had a status light
for my humidifier
and my heater i have to cover them up so
those
just to confirm those will actually
cause your plants to
hurt me out if the those were to go
towards
um you know during the dark period yeah
you you never know so basically
always cover cover those up because like
even if it doesn't like why take the
chance so yeah cover those
uh status indicators up especially if
it's blue
cool that's pretty much it thanks dan i
really appreciate it
uh thanks chris have a good day thanks
you too okay
so there you have it hopefully this
information has helped out some of you
who are wondering about this
and i'd love to know in the comment
section for those of you who have
security cameras in your grow space
have you ever had plants heard from them
or you think have heard from it
let me know down in the comment section
below for those of you who need one i do
have a coupon code
for the green sunshine company anything
on their website use coupon code
mr growit and you can get a percentage
off and by the time this video is
released
they have just released their v3 version
of their grow lights the electric sky
grow light i'll link it down in the
description section below
and i'll leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
peace
[Music]
you