I want to get into pests next let's
start with IPM things you could do to
prevent pests what do you do in that
case I've had problems in the past and I
had a bad bag of Coco in the past that I
had to deal with fungus
nuts and to get rid of that I had to use
a mosquito bits so something that I had
to water into into the into the Coco
every day for at least about a week till
I got rid of that but I normally keep uh
sticky traps around now so that's always
a good monitor like just to keep an eye
on things it's not going to stop you
from getting them but it's going to tell
you if you have a problem or not [ __ ]
SNS are such a pain man I battle them so
much they seem to come and go so often
it can be certainly be frustrating when
you have a a crazy outbreak it doesn't
sound like they have been too crazy for
you though have you come across any
major pest infestations whether it be
spider mice thrips anything like that at
all no just the fungus luckily that's
all I had I guess you know they say
you're not a real girl until you get
spider Ms and stuff so I guess I'm not a
real girl yet I'm still learning yeah
I've never heard that
before yeah I heard somebody say that at
the girl shop the other day okay I guess
I'm not a real girl yet I don't know
what I'm do I guess I guess agree to
disagree on that one I know people who
have been growing for five plus years
and they've never come across pest so
that's great call them not a grower
exactly right like come on man uh that's
funny I'm glad to hear that you haven't
come across any major infestations it
could be such a pain man I had uh I had
aphids Outdoors one time and it was so
disheartening it was on actually my bok
choy and I went in there it was Harvest
day and I was like ah going to harvest
some bok choy the first time growing it
I was super excited it was purple lady
bok choy so it was like completely
purple and then I went to go Harvest it
and I'm just just loaded with aphids
kind of like borrowed in and it was just
H it was disgusting I was like oh no how
the heck am I going to eat this stuff
you know well that's one of the things
about growing outside right is like you
can't really control too too much what's
going on out there Outdoors is a whole
different Battlefield now are you doing
anything as a preventative like sprays a
lot of people use sprays particularly
like in the veg stage in order to kind
of deter pest or prevent pest from
coming in do you do those at all or no
no no I haven't had so yet so I mean I
know everybody everybody's telling me to
go ahead and just get some preventative
maintenance going on before it happens
but I haven't had the chance to
experiment with any different type of
phray yet but I'm always willing to try
something all right pretty
straightforward there I'll keep my
fingers cross that you don't come across
any infestation yeah we'll hope for the
best on that Avenue yeah go to the full
episode by clicking the outro card here
or click the link in the description
section below catch you in the next
video