hey what's going on everybody BC
bubbleman here on my 29th wedding
anniversary went to go find some dabs
lost my last jar of good dabs decided oh
my God I still have the 2023 10th
anniversary special from concentrated X
so I'm not sure how many of you are
aware of concentrated X the hash maker
concentrated Evolution awesome guy great
hash maker great feno picker great
single Source grower well some years ago
a year ago now or so he sent me this
which as you can see is number one of 20
I've had a great relationship with him
over the years and I I I like to say I
helped Mentor him in learning how to
make hash and selling him bags and kind
of being a good buddy to him uh he sent
me one that's supposed to be
refrigerated he sent me another one um
that I guess is supposed to be frozen
maybe I can't even remember this one
definitely feels like it's been the
refrigerated one this one feels like
it's been more just at like
refrigeration and this one's more like
uh you know Frozen temperature like
freezer temperature so today is my 29th
wedding anniversary thus the cut on my
chin for shaving and trying to look nice
for my wife and I want to smoke some
nice hash today and for whatever reason
I'm I have jars don't get me wrong I
have jars of hash but there's nothing
spectacular really you know that's like
the utter the the highest level and I
thought on my anniversary I should be SM
smoking something high level so without
further Ado I'm planning on opening
these for the first time I have no idea
what is in these I have no idea he sent
me the two boxes uh they are marked one
of 20 both of them so you can see that
right
there and it says uh extract Pack Box
one of two this one
says flower and berries box so let's
open up the flowers and the berries
first love the custom uh packaging from
concentrated X I think that's absolutely
spectacular try not to uh ruin the tape
too much and see if we can't just slide
this box out of here nicely without
destroying it I don't think it's going
to happen I think we're going to have to
do a little bit of
Destruction uh let me see let me see let
me
see oh there we go that's helpful that's
helpful wow look at this this is so nice
holy [ __ ] it so we're going to throw
that off to the
side and we're going to check this out
look at this concentrated Evolution he's
got his little sticker there he's got
flower and berries pack if you want to
check that out that looks pretty pretty
cool it's showing the reflection of
everything off of this so I got to go
back a little bit you can still see the
phone reflecting in there it is what it
is let's get a
little cut on the scene here little tool
and just kind
of clean the resin off of it first I
guess open that up now I got Sticky
Fingers all right so flowers and
berries we got the beautiful
concentrated
ax and then we've got this right here
look at how nice that is my goodness I'm
not going to lie this might be the first
flower that I've smoked in a very long
time
oo oh beautiful
beautiful got a really nice flavor
profile on that see if you guys can see
that
nicely hand trimmed very fresh it had a
nice seal on
it and then he gave me some berries so
I'm not sure these are um oh well let's
read what he says here what do you get
when two longtime Legacy producers get
together and throw down okay so it's
concentrated Evolution and snakes in
something very special ain't nothing
short of Epic the strawberry banana
Ultra premium collection would not exist
had it not been for the inspiration and
contribution of my good
friend snakes
in made to the
project for the unintimidated snakon is
a true legend for the uninitiated is a
true legend a Pioneer in the solventless
scene who under the West Coast
Collective and melts in banners brought
some incredible whole plant fresh frozen
and Ros into the community over the
years under the snakes and banner he
continues his legacy track
record what I have personally
experienced by the best edibles in the
nation I think you will agree once you
get to try the incredible member
berries so these are the member berries
and that's from I'm guessing from Adam
I.E Melton now
snakes lovely handcrafted using our
strawberry banana full spectrum 25 U to
160 U live rosin these member berries
perfectly complement our strawberry
banana flavor please consume and dose
responsibly each time they are small But
Mighty well that is beautiful I'm really
liking that I'm loving I'm loving that
gift from both of these guys thank you
so much concentrated X this is
absolutely beautiful and wonderful and
I'm going to start eating those member
berries today it might even be some of
the first flower that I roll up and
actually smoke in a joint in over 24
years I can't imagine um you know paying
homage any other way to you for this uh
really quite spectacular gift so I'm
just going to get sticker back in
here there we go and now let's check out
my favorite one the concentrated pack oh
baby not going to lie I'm pretty excited
about this I don't know if this one's
going to slide out for me like the last
one didn't but I can always give it a
shot o look at that I'm able to get that
one
perfectly perfectly and that way we can
keep all of this exact the way it was
boom it still looks like the Box
wonderful I'm pretty excited I'm not
going to lie not going to lie keep
refrigerated well I did homie I kept
this Frozen the entire time not just
refrigerated but actually
Frozen and uh super stoked dude haven't
had some concentrated X in a while and
this is what we got
inside box number
one of
20 and it
says 10th anniversary special
concentrated Evolution so concentrated X
has concentrated the evolution of course
he's well known for the DNA genetic
strawberry banana it's one of my
favorite um this is really nice I didn't
even notice that he put this beautiful
coin in
here um that is just spectacular 10th
anniversary had a little coin
made you can see right there as well as
some stuff let's see what that
says 2013 to
2023 very cool little Tricom got the
little Integrity Farms guy it's got a
nice little explanation of the cultivars
right here uh that are going I love the
the glossy finish on this you can see
whenever I hold it up it actually shows
me reflecting inside from my phone
that's filming me right now well let's
see what we got we got a couple of
jars one G each we got one G of the 120
U full melt jar strawberry banana and
then we've got a 1 G U of the 120 Micron
live hash Rosen strawberry banana so
I've got two of these here a damn I
guess I better turn on the
denail it'd be weird to do this video
and not have a little dab so we're going
to do that get the dunk tank and the
marbles out get the
uh get the TP slurper into the pipe
right boom boom boom got a little turb
Slurp in action and then we're going to
drop that right
into the universal heater which is right
here so give that a few seconds to heat
up it takes usually no more than a
couple minutes I'll turn on the Temp
Tech and uh just want to shout out
concentrated X this is a really nice
gift dude and I apologize for holding on
to it for a whole year before I actually
opened it um you you've been nothing but
a gentleman and a scholar you've been an
absolute bubble ambassador of the
highest level for a very very long time
and I want to say that uh I personally
very much appreciate you I love the
packaging with Integrity you got the
Integrity Farms there you got towy on
there that is such slick nice looking
packaging wish I could do it in the
legal end in the legal world but I'm
guessing uh South Park would probably
sue me if I put things like this on my
package but uh just going to give it the
old thumbnail
twist
and oh my goodness it's deep in there
but you can see a gram of just
spectacular strawberry
banana live hash
rosin for the
win thank you brother this will uh
this will be very very well
enjoyed I will tell you uh we're going
to open up the bubble now as well I love
getting concentrated X bubble if it's
never been warmed up it's usually just
in perfect
Tricom um isolation separation just pure
heads sitting on top of one another none
of this uh you know globbed into one
piece it usually happens within 5
minutes of leaving it at room
temperature which Hopefully this wasn't
enough time we'll see what we we got
here oh yeah Jesus
Christ pure heads looking absolutely
[Music]
phenomenal what do you say to that I
know what I say to
that thank you for thinking of me bro I
would have been happy with number 19 out
of 20 or number 20 out of 20 the fact
that you sent me 1 out of 20 was special
and I'll never forget it I'm going to
hold on to this packaging I'm going to
eat the member ber I'm going to smoke
the rosin I'm going to smoke the bubble
uh I'm definitely going to be enjoying
uh the flour as well which is not
something you'll hear me say very often
and I love the little coin I think
that's really cool dude and I've just
been super stoked to be a part of um of
your journey a part of your journey
so I don't know where to start I guess
I'll probably start oh jeez how do you
not start with a full Mount bubble how
do you not start with the full melt
bubble it's just uh let's see if I can
get a little bit out without uh ooh my
God yeah this
is this is
insane this is absolutely
insane so we're going to Chisel some off
going to drop it into my hand a little
bit and then we're going to
make with just with the warmth of our
hand I'm going to take that that little
bit and I'm going to put my thumb on
that give it a little
twist and it just disappeared
basically oh
baby we'll get that onto the end of the
Dabber it's not a huge dab but it
definitely shows that there is a quality
there that
is really second to none so I'm going to
end up smoking this whole jar got a
little party to go to tonight butth for
now we'll start with a little tiny dab
Maybe I'll dip that in there and get a
little bit more of the fresh headies on
there that sounds like a plant isn't
it oh yeah that made it a little bit
little bit nicer I just coated it in
more pure
heads more pure heads oh in the
meantime we get this
sitting make sure it's in my
freezer I have a little free are sitting
on the side of my
uh that's not the right
way okay you know how sometimes you go
to put a USB in and it's like no it
doesn't oh this USB has been
crushed that is probably why that is not
opening
huh there we go I got
it I got
it boop boop boop boop boop boop boop
boop boop
perfect so we'll just put those in there
for now that's how you preserve
incredible quality hash uh
as as you receive it once again dude
Second To None I've never been given a
nicer packaging the boxes the jars the
coin um it's all just spectacular really
dude it is really just spectacular what
is that oh all right so let me just make
sure we got that
and we got
that that is on point I got my coin
right
there which looks like it's sealed in
this piece of plastic and you can't even
open it oh no you can open
it you can open
it w that is seriously pimp dude holy
[Laughter]
Christ wow dude now that is next level
I'm going to take a page out of this
book and I'm going to create some of
these super cool coins for the bubble
man brand down in America and we'll make
it a special thing where you can uh you
know acquire one uh through I don't know
if it'll be a type of contest or what
it'll be but I really got to say that
that
is a level of class I have not yet seen
in the hash world so once again shout
out to concentrated X you are the man uh
shout out to Melton for putting together
the member berries and shout out to D
now for producing such a lovely little
unit that uh I'm guessing I'm probably
in line for a nice little dab here dab
is going to absolutely crush me which I
love I'm very happy about
that um yeah I turned off the the alarm
on my dab right so you won't hear it go
off but it is at 550 now so bubble hash
I'll always hit a little bit warmer than
rosin Bona petite if you're joining me
I
mean let me tell you
something that right there is what it
was always about for me that
almost what wants to close up your
throat
it wants to make you close your eyes it
wants you
to go in in a very very very deep way
just dunk tanking my Banger here give me
a
second I've been in I've fallen in love
with full out bubble from the day I
first tried it and it's not to say that
I don't absolutely love and appreciate
the rosin I think rosin is spectacular
it's a great way for us to take our
bubble that is subpar non full melt
bubble
and get it into a product that makes it
and elevates it to a point where it's
still very beautiful and I've said this
before rosin really seems like a dessert
to me that seemed like a five course
meal the quality of the
high and the the insulation of the high
and how sort of thick and and deep that
it goes it's not a surface High it
really is like a four to five course
meal the
flavor was the most incredible
strawberry banana if any of you know DNA
genetics and you know the cut strawberry
banana you've probably seen a variety of
phenos the pheno that concentrated X has
picked and found um is spectacular truly
the photo right when you see how bright
the bananas and the strawberries look
that is what it tastes like it's very
very profound it overtakes your palette
very quickly my favorite part of it is
on the exhale where I can't even
describe what I feel in my throat but it
almost feels like the way you feel right
before you pass out unconscious right
before you lose Consciousness that sort
of maybe it's a surrender I'm not sure
possibly um as you're exhaling that full
melt bubble it left very little Chaz on
the Banger I mean it cleaned in the dunk
tank very clean I do have a little bit
of cleaning on this Banger to do it's
not quite as clean as you know you've
got a little bit of build build up of
oil here that doesn't get cleaned in the
Banger um that doesn't get cleaned in
the Banger basket sorry got a nice
little high going on yeah that was
wonderful that was exactly everything
that I remembered I've never tasted a
better feno of strawberry banana and
I've never tasted a full melt bubble uh
made from that particular fenal that was
anywhere near uh what I I I just smoked
now so concentrated X my hat is off to
you brother uh thank you so much for
this kind gift I've repeated myself 20
times because I'm just at a loss for
words it's such a kind gift uh I look at
it as an honor uh you're a true bubble
Ambassador spreading the word through
the quality and through your fenos uh
hunting uh keep it up dude keep it up
2025 it's going to be a great year for
you I I know that and I look forward to
uh getting a hang out with you one of
these days soon uh to everyone else that
was watching go follow concentrated X on
Instagram give him your support the
guy's incredible and uh May the full
melt bless your bowl uh sooner than
later peace out