[Music]
all right welcome everybody happy 4/20
we're here I'm here with lost gardens
Sean who was with us in Barcelona and my
Orca and we are now in Vancouver and we
are heading down to the Vancouver 4/20
event which should be pretty good it's
usually pretty kick-ass
we're just on Butte and coming up to
Davey here where one of the cannabis
culture shops is and yeah just we're
gonna go have some bowls go puff some
puffs Karev's it sound good
looking forward to it yeah
[Music]
you
go find D for 20k down there somewhere
city was near this stage
[Music]
are you unsure but like a homie
rebel but your
[Music]
you
it's crazy it just goes on everything I
want to be in here anymore let's go this
[Music]
all right what's up everyone welcome to
bubble man's world I am backstage at the
4/20 event here in Vancouver with my new
puff coke peak I'm gonna hit up a couple
of friends so let's yeah let's move
through the crowd here and see if we
can't find some people to pop on some
full melt with us hey there's one right
there alright she's up number one red
factor in the house it's gonna hit that
puffs go we just turned it on so I
should vibrate here in about ten seconds
maybe a little less waiting anxiously
but not torching that's nice
oh that's full melt in there by the way
yeah nice rip of foam out it's a vibrate
[Music]
boom there goes his grip there's more
it's more where that came from
[Music]
well [ __ ] yeah puffs kopeeks right there
or perfect flat 421 just in the house
here close to the porta-potties where he
always hangs out with cuz he's the [ __ ]
[Music]
cuz I gotta know if I like that know the
[ __ ] in a good way good
here's one right there what the puffs go
hold this nice little bit down in there
high school
look for the dabber down and all kind of
don't do that don't do that that's the
one thing they tell you not to do let me
damn it off with this u-turn yeah there
you go there you go see that right into
the bottom there's holes on the top so
you don't want to ever scrape on it yeah
there we go we'll put this on want me to
take this and this from you
onto it and the dabber one sec one sec
we got to go one two it vibrates then it
takes about 10 to 15 seconds and once it
vibrates in your hands
you rip it oh no there it goes
[Music]
little rasa which one was that
Oh be Ripper I like the sound of that
creative apps little mini dabbers wicked
man
oh yeah liquidy you still got a good
amount
there's a session but you to that you
can go like one more beep and then it'll
it should keep it bought these and cools
down otherwise doesn't stay hot the
whole time but you definitely got one
to tiptoe what do you think I don't have
a kitchen
alright Marymount marijuana man split so
lost gardens Shawn is in the house for
his dad just heating it up now
PUF going
[Music]
PUF code
oh it smells great West Coast collective
rosin from bubble hash beautiful
vibration so Johnny B's about to hit the
puffs co first time I'm thinking faded
little where is my bike rosin in there
where's my my waiting for your waiting
for it to vibrate my mind vibrates in
your hand which is gonna be very soon
you'll hit it I can see it starting to
smoke whoa
[Music]
happy 4/20 yeah
puffs going with Johnny be
that thing is really cool careful of the
carb cap it's balancing on the top there
vibrate and again that's okay know what
it does yeah this is letting you know
you're getting wicked rips turn adapt um
no no just giving you a nice little dab
it's no bigger than what you take off
addy now
how'd you like it a little bit fantastic
the great gardener on the other side of
the fence they're gonna hit the peak I
put a little I put in some where's my
bike cross and it'll vibrate it buzz but
it doesn't look like it's hot oh really
yeah looks like it's not through the
fence that's the og right there
this is Prohibition 2.0 it's legal but
with lots of rules I can't get through
more rules than ever before going right
through the fence but don't worry he
brought his lawyer to the dome
that was tasty tasty you gonna roll up
some joins cookie hey you went to get us
bracelets you never came back take what
you want and then give the rest to the
dinosaur no it'll vibrate in your hands
and then when you're done give it to the
dinosaur there you go she's actually in
there puffing right now that's a
vancouver 4:20 right there for you even
the dinosaurs are puffing ridiculous and
it hits like a champ I have to say the
little puff coke peak hits like a champ
right I like it a little carb cap this
just balances nicely on it
my sweetie
[Music]
don't you always finish it off for
everyone
[Music]
you
yeah
[Applause]
alright I'm here with Jodie Emery on the
stage and 420 she's about to hit the
puffs go peek for the first time we got
John and Roy in the background and he'll
Magnusson
awesome it has it vibrated yet oh yeah
perfect
there we go Neil Magnussen cannabis
activists extraordinaire here at
Vancouver it's gonna be singing for us
in about 20 minutes he's ripping on the
where is my bike
and the puff coats my bike where is your
bike where did it go
[Music]
on stage with mr. cookie everybody is
about to hit the puffs go Pete for the
first time so first it buzzes and then
you buzz
double bus a bad little unit hey very
nice a puff coke peak right there mr.
cookie long time cannabis activists here
in Vancouver one of the first people I
know that blew up making butane and then
became super [ __ ] bubble hash
oriented from your lessons
[Music]
now we're gonna do this in a very
organized fashion so nobody gets
trampled and nobody gets hurt
all righty that proves that we're really
really high but we're still capable of
doing something like this without
anybody getting hurt so this is how we
do it every year
okay everybody that ground has been dry
there's only been a little bit of
drizzle on all day so the ground is dry
we need a pathway that goes right from
the middle all the way to the first tip
there and then we need a path down with
joints even come walking out the first
thing you're gonna do is make a path so
I need some foam head to organize back
that way take everybody take two steps
back that way we need a path that goes
all the way to the end all the way to
the end down the middle and
approximately that way hey you're a big
guy you can walk the world
[Applause]
we can reach the stage
[Music]
[Applause]
who
[Music]
[Applause]
I think they're gonna smell this and the
rest of it Cooper it's going to get a
whiff of how free we are here
[Applause]
[Music]
think of the Ottawa legalization yours
got it sucks
hey Daniel I see one say a few words
crazy moment in time
but it got there good champagne well
champagne goes thank you all
[Music]
[Applause]
where does they gather for that we
forget encounter with the earth gallery
[Music]
it's 4:20 every day at my house twice at
my home
[Music]
[Laughter]