hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
just wanted to invite you all to the 420
Art Gallery gathering tomorrow in
Vancouver British Columbia right in the
city center I'm going to be there with
John B from medtainer and we're going to
be selling a whack load of products
we're going to be carrying uh some
Skillet tools and some oil slick all
these different cool stackables and the
micro stacks and the Slick balls and the
oil slicks I've got bubble bags of
multiple varieties I'm going to be
bringing one gallon lights eight bags
for 90 bucks I'm going to be bringing
the standards 5 gallons and 1 Gall bags
both in eight bag kits and uh we'll have
you know just a bunch of cool products
to check out but more importantly the
mothership and the denail are going to
be there and uh well we'll be doing a
lot of
this little dabby Doodles this is some
of that fiveyear plus Master cush and I
figured while we were showing I might as
well do a little
dab
so hopefully we see you tomorrow April
20th Vancouver Art Gallery I'm looking
forward to it peace