[Music]
hey guys bubble man here just heading
down to the 420 uh Gathering down at the
Vancouver Art Gallery running a little
bit behind it's about 8:00 in the
morning and apparently John's been down
there since 7 and it's been a
free-for-all it's real hard to get a
booth space but uh I'm not worried
personally cuz wherever John and I will
be will be the Melt of dry sift and
bubble hash and you know that's going to
attract all the right people so we're
going to head down there now and we'll
see you when we get there C for
[Music]
now nice e and seconding season with ch
Beast Mr Officer man what you want from
[Music]
me come over
here don't no
fear
out I was Ying down the L and bck up in
Old Lu and ask on
my I say it's the
[Music]
good I
knoww when
[Music]
never this is tradition a to the wise
and in Afghanistan Indian and Pakistan
not to mention African the
best burning by the rivers
ofon everybody
[Music]
I've been
steing my eyes
got and I don't got
no can I do for myself
[Music]
medtainer John dude dude 420 happy 420
man happy 420 bro just got here down to
the 420 festivities with John we've set
up our booth a little bit there's about
70 booths here there's going to be a ton
of people it's going to be awesome we've
got blls we've got hash we've got our we
got cash we got our everything we got to
Puff we got our little boo set up John's
brought his medtainers I've got just a
few products we not we're not going
overboard but uh we're going to have fun
looks like if we avoid the rains today
it'll be a real nice day so so stay
tuned for some 420
celebrations all right so we're here at
the 420
celebration everyone's doing their thing
lots of people set
up bu
$100 and $60
per sh
someone's going to buy it I would turn
it all into hash
myself there probably about 20 G of hash
on
that total I got to get you in the
camera now what's up dude Freddy how you
doing man
I'm in there too Freddy's on Bubble
man's world awesome right on and I just
pumped into him because of this dude
behind us with big bags of weed is that
funny we bubble box the [ __ ] out of that
wouldn't we oh yes we would so how you
doing doing man
excellent all locked up
oh [ __ ] walking it out you can buy
Purple Kush clones you can
buy I
there thank you very
much things we don't have a garbage
so much baked goods what's up
skull fish [ __ ] dude good to see you
man is this your boo yeah just checking
out with Bradley and Victoria all right
Bradley and Victoria making things
happen some glasses yeah local glass
blowers from the island a little skull
piece there shate glass yeah we made
these right here all right hey bubble
man
yeah bubble man's in the house guess
they're set up the
stage setting up a little stage action
excellent good
[Music]
stuff only that but we have everywhere
that we
[Music]
can bring a good to
me somebody call name
the take smoke take it
daily want
me
necessary we smoking
smoking didn't CA no father G to the
world
yes when we're smoking smoking
s shouldn't no
[Music]
morning
ohel have that I got
purple
mastero got
organic sh depends on
you I like them all they give me
doar
smed Nock
the that was
[Music]
beautifuls this the Bob Marley
shirts let's go guys all right all right
we Marley and the Marley and the H
Harley
yes we're over
here right guys we're at the 420 Gallery
here Vancouver and I got a couple of
cool friends that just came by what was
your name again Blake Blake Kathy and
Kathy and Blake and Kathy just told me
something that I'm going to get them to
repeat for the camera so our commitment
to Bubble Man is that we're going to
make our first batch of bubble within 6
months and then we're going to practice
for 6 months we'll be back here at 420
next year and we're going to show them
our bubble so in one year I'm going to
see your bubble that's right all right
I'm holding you guys to it oh yeah man
awesome right on
guys they're coming in a Year John with
bubble with bubble we'll be here I can't
wait to smoke that bubble dude all right
this whole crew of [ __ ] mad men just
showed up they got the mother ships we
got the little mini Hitman here I got my
Mothership right uh right here below the
table so I guess we're having a
Mothership party so
that's what's happening right now which
one thanks bro how's that delicious how
of the great Gardener
action through the mother ship is that
what that uh I think I gave you the
Afghan that was The
Afghani so tasty dry
sift on the mother ships and the baby
cakes how about this little guy Dosa oh
you Haven T it yet you going to get one
[Applause]
now oh another mother ship over there oh
another mother ship over
there do we have like four mother ships
in the house here
I like this it's the 420 session ready
before 420 here at the medtainer Fresh's
Booth fresh frozen fresh
frozen yeah buddy discussing about how
fresh fren hits those receptors so
perfectly oh yes yes pain management
right there this is Mothership Central
here the Mothership the rigs have
arrived monster dabs here at the uh
bubble B fresh headies
Booth these guys are hitting a little
bit of the three-way cush OG Bubba and
master how's
that perfect has for the mother
ships oh
yeah the finest things are here at the
420 Gathering grilled
cheeses mini doses
[Music]
[Applause]
all right ready to hit
[Music]
little bit of rain out on 420 here on
Vancouver we are safely end the tent
doing our
thing yeah okay
they haven't stopped since they got here
I like these
guys what do you think of that fresh
frozen that
watermelon
amazing
delicious yeah buddy
[Music]
a you have a
minute much
here we go
I I
[Music]
have time being what it is number one
[Applause]
[Music]
one well I'm at the Grilled Cheese Truck
I think I'm at the right spot
here where are you guys located hippie
Easter on the corner of how today 420
enjoying enjoy life enjoy awesome come
check out this truck everyone they've
got it going
on say hi all right who just walked in
what's up everybody right on the house
of the great gers in the house fored
smokers oh yes John in the house look at
that the little prize the Dabo first
place awesome Spanish Dao yes I'm
recognizing it right away that's it's so
warm too all over is that what it
is
yep yeah buddy hold right on let's uh
have a
session all right Matt the great
Gardener has shown up and he's got
Barbara Bud dry sift and he show showing
these guys that brought the motherships
and uh yeah we're just having a great
420 here it's [ __ ]
[Music]
great oh yeah that's a
stuff uh the infamous want one what do
you say when the great Gardener asks you
back behind bubble man's booth at the
420 Art Gallery Gathering hey you want
one what do you
say [ __ ] yeah hell yeah [ __ ]
yeah we're going do a double hit
[Music]
first one of missing oh I know I know
I've been texting them pictures I'm like
cuz we got the 10th floor up in the
Georgia so I got like overnight the over
I'm like yeah it's all right I'm like of
course it's like
no
[Music]
[Applause]
pry the pre 420 session going down hard
at the back of the Medan fresh Hy
Booth yeah Grill
cheeses these guys know what's
up I wanted to film this cuz it was uh
the Jabo first place piece that the
great Gardener won with the Barb cash
that he has right here and this is the
little piece that he got in Barcelona so
we're going to rip that hat with him
right here right now 420
Vancouver 420 yeah man happy Easter it's
weird not being in a
garden feels like there should be a big
tumbler behind you they let me out from
time to time not very often though not
very
often get away the timing is right you
can get away for 8 hours
[Music]
[Applause]
that was a
dab
[Music]
ho the taste of that was Unreal
like0 like a candy
DT GG plus GG plus is right that was I
don't take hits that big very
often so smooth I should be on the
ground dying right now as I was hitting
it I thought oh this is going to get
rough I think this small pipe has a lot
to do with to really B the small
concentr p
still going hard here at
420 $10 for
one first up mother ship
Taurus with the honey bucket
[Music]
oh
yeah excellent
[Music]
this just people getting
H oh yeah I
[Music]
want to buy that come
on Dr David Allen just showed up we're
going to be doing an interview with Dr
David Allen uh later maybe tomorrow
after the noise subsides but this guy
right here has an incredible amount of
information about the endoc canabo
system and we're going to be sharing it
with you on Bubble man's world but as
many of you know and if you don't you
really should
Mark was arrested on Canadian soil by
American police with the Drug
Enforcement Administration to face life
in US prison for his mission to legalize
marijuana and even though he ran for
office and paid his taxes and never left
Canada and he was recognized by all the
media 60-minute CNN Wall Street Journal
Rolling Stone everyone knew what he was
doing but he never went to the US and he
faced death death in prison in America
for his mission to legalize marijuana
and right now he's finishing his last
three months three months until Mark
emry ends his prison sentence and comes
home mark emry the prince of pot will be
home this summer and in the time he's
been away the Harper government has put
you in more Harm's Way than you may even
know mandatory minimum
getting rid of personal Gardens under
the medical laws so much more harm has
been done by Harper than we can even
comprehend but when Mark comes home I
promise you that he and I and all of you
I hope will join together for our
political revenge and get ahead of
America Legalize It federally here
Legalize It all throughout North America
set examples for the world to follow so
no one ever goes to prison for pot
again 420 is a day to celebrate our
culture celebrate our music our art our
symbols our language our rituals and
history we have so much to celebrate
here with a lifesaving world changing
plant and yet we must protest
prohibition we must remind the world
that every person here today
faces prison under the laws that do
still exist even though we get days like
this to have fun so celebrate cannabis
but protest prohibition join sensible BC
so we can change the laws here in our
Province and set an example for the rest
of Canada to organize get inspired get
rid of the Harper conservatives and get
marijuana legal here in Canada thank you
so much for coming out please support
the booths and the sponsors go to 420
vancouver.com and #y photos 420
Vancouver come on down to canvis culture
and we'll see Mark here at the art
gallery this summer for his welcome home
celebration thanks a lot happy
420 give it up for Jody
Emery it was just about then I started
to wonder what's it like to be a hippie
for the day
so we picked up a young bunch of South
suff oh yeah we went rolling down that
Highway
69 and it told me he was headed down for
Toronto and then I could share his smoke
and dring his wine yeah I'm a hippie for
today Martha dear I'm a hippie for today
don't you fear Martha yeah you know that
I am strong and I won't be one for long
besides I I don't like wine as much as
fear
you rolled him a cigarette he called it
a
roofer he L it up and he said to I said
I got my own brand of explor day in my
pocket thank you son but by then the cab
was filling up with
smoke there was white
L on the
highway wide lines and all the city
and there was B lines on the road
side like there's white lines in my
brain my heada started feeling kind of
fuzzy I said what the hell you think
you're smoking in my truck boy he said
he found this plant growing down by the
roadside well felt good to me so I said
what the [ __ ] boy I'm a h for day Mar
here I'm a hit me for today don't you
fear Mar if you don't see the other side
of life semi trailer ride well then you
just ain't a goddamn man who SE goddamn
clear
well he told me he knew some girls down
in Miss aaga he said free love would
make me feel just right yeah I told him
I had to be in Hamilton by the next
morning but I reckon we could stop there
for the night oh yeah and them girls
were pleas as Peaches just to see us and
they said come on in boys have a little
to or
to and then later when Harvey and Lloyd
were finished with them they showed us
just what them hippy women
do and there was white
light on the bed
host white lines in the
sky there was white lines on the table
they made red lines in my
eyes was feeling right as rain the next
morning like a double action to My
Island free as I left my bu standing
down by the roads side got to thinking
what the hell's become of
me I know my livs are traveling out on
the highway oh Martha you're as sweet as
you can get but I'm thinking it's just
great to be a trucker is I smoke another
Hipp and
[Applause]
cigarette all right one's
got bubble yeah and we're rocking
sublimator hits of bit exactly we're
jacking stage power thanks to Adam and
his uh lovely we as well oh Jack and
Stage power this is for Theiss only I'm
going to let you know throw some in no
no throw some in for me I'll just hit it
are we hitting the sublimator though oh
sure you can thr theator yeah dude push
some of that into the
sublimator you do you need a
Dabber all right just bumped into my
buddy Juan he's jacking stage power got
a sublimator plugged in right here and
we're about to take a rip
than thanks to Adam yes thank to the guy
thanks to
[Music]
Adam wow had be dribbling there a little
bit awesome dude
all right let's continue down the road
and see what's going on
here it just goes all the way around
there you are we'll start off by making
fun of me I'm such a [ __ ] idiot he's
like look at my 450 up at my cookies
anybody want the cookies dude do you
think he needs cookies he went he put
420 on his window and it's 450 he put it
backwards
yeah we don't need no stinking cookies
we've got
Barb yeah we've got
Barb all right I that's pretty funny
dude I'll hold it or hide it or whatever
pocket
it the way it goes we're going up to the
room for the view of all of
this all right so we just walked through
the lobby we're going to go up to the
10th floor here and check out this view
from the 450 room we're going to fix the
sign now 420 420 okay by 450 I looked up
at it and I was like I don't know dude
it looks fine to me it's it's been like
an hour but why is it 450 all
good H let's go this way that was
feeling
it so although we are in Denver I'm
surprised it was that did you book this
a while ago or last
minute uh yeah just wor a like we that's
amazing they had the room facing
the 10:05 if you want to know for future
references oh wow what a great little
room
[Music]
sweet we get that white balance
[Applause]
organized oh sorry bud Excuse
me yes I'll let you get by I'll get this
chair out of the
[Music]
[Applause]
way isn't that incredible guys that is
Vancouver 420 at about 3:35 p.m. less
than an hour away from 420 there must be
10,000 plus people down
there holy
Christ that's
cool well the fact that it's you guys
too it's just like of course yeah of
course of course you have a [ __ ] room
up there yeah and exactly I kind of
didn't want to be the guy to beg you to
come up here but the sign was is just
like it was the sign clearly you need to
go back up to your room like do you need
a [ __ ] sign to to show you how badly
you need to go up to your room look
there's a sign on your door on your
window and it's wrong it needs to be
changed all right let's hone in on the
uh the Famous Cannabis
activists oh we've got Jody Emory
marijuana man and Dan Larson and John
Conroy with his wife and a bunch more
people everyone's there I remember her
name is
Sherry oh this camera is
[Music]
nutty there's the fresh Hades
Booth St
India all right we're at the Vancouver
Seed Bank this is the place where people
ask me where they can buy the great
Gardener gear all the time you guys got
it we do you guys got the seed bombs
even brought with yeah they brought a
seed bombs we're having those awesome
Vancouver Seed Bank the great Gardener
stuff it's double sided there's oh yeah
yeah flip it
over boom yeah even more Dr Atomic host
of The Great gardener Jordan's still
around added like way more jeez e yeah
all the old guys like solar Warrior ice
cheese lemonade cookies and brownies six
items $20 FX and
match someone in Canada is going to
prison and saying goodbye to their
babies and their wife and their family
so the war goes on and don't forget it
because you're here to celebrate but
many people like my husband Mark Emer
are not and many others are behind bars
so
year this
year local dispensaries have helped out
with the kickdown we got thousands of
quality
drugs thanks to Mother Nature for
shining on us here in 420 and all ring
on
us give it up for the vancou police who
do not arrest anybody for cannabis
and without any further Ado we'll get
these ceremonies underway sing it with
me if you know the words are over
here oh
canabus the sacred plant of
peace pot junkies we have to make a path
starting about right here that goes off
and you go spread up spread out this way
spread out that way make a path right in
front of
make a path and then make another path
that goes off in that direction and goes
off in that direction and the reason
we're going to do this is it's easier to
get you the free weed if you make a path
so if you want free weed to be thrown at
your head make a path one that goes that
way and one that goes that way someone
should be out walking the path so that
uh it's for sure being made is it can I
get like a
volunteer where's bir he usually does it
good job of this B where are you B but
the buds are going to kick your butt so
there's a tremendous good marijuana here
hey Jeremiah can you walk that way try
to walk that way okay Jeremiah's walking
that
way yeah you know what a te looks like
yeah that's right and make sure he can
walk far all the way to the end there
and then you going to get pot on at you
I'm going to instruct the baked and BC
girls not to throw marijuana at anybody
who standing up so if you want marijuana
thrown at your head sit your ass
down yeah yeah yeah so once the ladies
all have like a handfuls of buds and you
ready to go okay start walking the path
so that we can get you all distributed
far and wide we want to get you to the
edges of the crowd so those people down
there who are sitting down get high all
those people down there who sitting down
get
high 15 and it's time for uh giveway you
we're sitting down yeah I see them I see
them there we
go free joints all right I see you I see
you free joints I see you I want to get
you
high tell me when you go thr 18
17 16 15
14 13 12 11
10 9 8 7 6 5 4 3 2
[Applause]
1 oh
blood yeah woo
w we
got
yeah yeah and
[Music]
I 4 20 in
Vancouver
[Music]
yeah some call it Marana
excuse me
[Music]
brother happy bir
yeah brother marijuana man in the house
here at 420
vanc [ __ ] nice to
[Music]
see batter is running out you get the
idea Vancouver 420 keep watching Bubble
man's world all right so Jon and I just
bumped into this gentleman who's making
this uh lemon extraction doing an
extraction with no chemical solvents
whatsoever and he's
producing a
shatter
so wildly has a bit of a smell like the
lemon which is a turine that you can
find in campus in fact as well as
oranges and grapefruits um there's going
to be more on this we're going to take
some photos of it we're going to have a
session maybe next puff Wednesday yeah
we're going to S and we'll show tell you
guys more about this and uh we'll talk
about it and see what you guys think
interesting very
well all right we're here at my booth
with Matt and Horatio the guy who's
doing the
uh these shatters with um lemine they're
just starting to get a of what makes
each chemical appropriate and they
don't medine
it's hex they're going to ask for your
business there's the dry Street and
everybody can do it utan wouldn't be
chosen the way our society set up that's
why it went that
way like no for each man to have for
himself like home for
[Music]
you D TR that 4
20 he's taking a dab with the great
Garder
hey 420 dabs with the great
Gardener all right all right that hi hob
ho that's what we say hey ho hi ho hey
hi ho
ho hit that bowl it's
450 it's
450 here by
520 oh [ __ ]
[Music]