hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and uh welcome to the house sound man
Sun is going down and it was so
beautiful I thought I want to share it
with uh with my YouTube uh family so up
goes the phone in goes the case I ran
around a little bit like a maniac trying
to catch it before the sun went down but
I thought what I would do is for those
of you that follow uh me on Facebook uh
at
bubbleman um you saw that I was cleaning
some dry sift today so I've got myself a
little bit of dry sift here three little
varieties there people were asking
what's what um these are two both from
the same I clean this contaminant out of
this this this is really nice and melty
um and it's a hash plant this one over
here was a little bit of Barb that I had
left not not the best Barb but a long uh
I think it was a a 1our spin so I
cleaned a tiny little bit about about
out of that as well and it's mostly pure
heads there might be a little bit of a
hair or some contaminant here and there
if I get under it with the scope but all
in
all quite happy with everything so once
again as I've shown many times on uh on
Bubble man's world you see this is my
dry SI
and you see that when I turn it upside
down that it's stable you see that that
is stable powder and I just put this on
here I don't know maybe a couple hours
ago and of course what's most impressive
is that you can see that it's just
powder as I scoop up a giant dab got the
egg right
here and uh well why don't you guys grab
a piece grab your rig and let's do a
little the Sun is setting
rip
oh hey had my my head turned over so you
couldn't see but closed both my eyes
that
rip really lovely
enjoyable such a great time to be out uh
in the house Sound area every time uh at
around this time as the sun's going down
it just seems like the water always
calms right down if it was a a Blustery
Day windy day um the the the the waves
kind of chill right out and you can see
out on the water that the waves are
quite calm right now
got a helicopter flying by here in a bit
maybe we better do a helicopter dab what
do you guys
say try some of that barb nice little
big dab of the
barbola M with the sun behind it that's
nice so we got quite a bit of helicopter
traffic up here as I am on the way up to
Whistler anyone that's flying to
Whistler in a helicopter goes right past
my house and then of course we have
search and rescue in the area seems to
be that yellow helicopter is out more
often than we would like to hear
it yeah unfortunately people get lost in
the mountains up here all too
often they go into the back country
without the proper gear uh they don't
let people know that they're going into
the back country and these are all
things that when you live in an area
like British Columbia but it's very
important that you do these simple
things that you leave a note or a phone
call or a message or tell someone
directly where you're where you're going
cuz you can get hypnotized by the Beauty
and the problem with getting hypnotized
by the beauty is it can get deadly
pretty darn fast so I wouldn't be
surprised if the way this helicopter is
flying that it's going to be the yellow
search and rescue
helicopter well fingers crossed we did
just have a girl on Whistler Mountain
gone for 3 days she went into the
backside of crystal chair down blackholm
ended up into the back country of the
singing past which is OBO cowboy and
eventually she ended up on Wedge
Mountain which was two whole mountain
ranges over uh up on the way to pton so
pretty scary very happy that she that
that story ended the way it did and the
reason that story ended the way it did
is because we haven't had a winter we
just have not been getting snow we've
been getting precipitation but we've got
such warm weather that it's uh it's just
affecting some of the winter fun as you
guys have probably seen my channel would
have a lot a lot more snowmobiling and a
lot more snowboarding and ski flying and
all these things if the snow was up
there for us to enjoy
so and what a beautiful sunset I think
I'm going to take one more rip go back
to the original that barb was really
tasty it's unbelievable how loud uh the
Barb is let see what we got there can we
see that
one kind
of sun dabs maybe I'll use the
Sun can I get in front of it there we go
try to get the sun to heat the
bowl all right we're
there sunnd
dabs sometimes you got to AB
them all right guys awesome 420 s with
you by the time this is today a good
day keep me content Intoxicated by the
in scriptures CH to
[Applause]
all
think I