[Music]
hey what's going on everyone welcome to
Bubble man's world I am here in
Vancouver on April 20th the 420
celebration we're actually getting some
pretty decent weather it looks like the
sky is blue out here and I'm just
actually here at high integrity glass
art with beautiful pieces of glass
everywhere no joke so I figured I'd do a
little quick little shot showing you
guys what is up as always high integrity
glass art set in the bar for fat
Glass Pelican case after Pelican case
after Pelican case after Pelican
case
so all right so here we are with three
just spectacular little pieces been
hitting the Mike gong throughout the day
here and it's just been real nice hits
like an absolute champion
fits in the hand real nice just need a
proper Banger for
that got a real cool looking classic
Mike gong marble on the back
there really
sweet we'll put this one
aside then we'll get into the Dosa
incredible overlay work on those
lines really
sweet
and then over to this team Japan tube
which is pretty much Next Level not
going to lie this team Japan tube for
the
win
incredible incredible Matrix
of work here really really talented
artists pulling this
off
got to show you the bottom on this piece
too CU it's just spectacular and yes I
do see the down stem in it
bro what's that the signature y yep
that's
incredible
wow it's next level dude I mean I just
actually got really really really close
on this marble I went right into the
pattern with the camera and you wouldn't
have believed what it looked
like on the neck on the neck I know yeah
I was trying to get close on that one
and it's it's a little bit harder to uh
focus on the St on the stacking look at
that though just imagine the amount of
time that goes into that W it just went
through the pipe to the other
side oh my
God
[Music]
incredible
boom happy 420 everybody here's the
peanut brittle this is some seedsman
Haze and it's very very very very very
very very
tpol it's just greasing right out as you
can
see and I'm actually dabbing something a
little bit different some of this this
is Ghost Train Haze actually it's not
what I'm dabbing sorry to say I'm
dabbing this no this over here is what
I'm dabbing this is some old
[Music]
Congo quite stable quite lovely I'm
going in
low temp down AB s for the
[Music]
win the little mik
gong so
sweet next up the Banger hanger for 420
dabs did you 420 out there flat 4 I 420
I did dude you're so dark yes thank
there we go Legends of Hashi she just
came into this is your making an
appearance on the 420 edition of Bubble
Man this is what d420 is doing
yeah so I'm just uh walking to 420 with
FL 421 and we noticed this beautiful
chahul exhibition that uh has been here
in Vancouver for quite a while hey yeah
like how long well I don't I can't even
remember but at least over a decade oh
yeah for sure over a decade and what
were you going to say about it as we
were well they just it was one of the
first real uh glass installments in
Vancouver right so for someone who loves
glass as much as I love glass all for sh
dude it's super cool I want to get a
picture of you in front of this thing
all right I'm going to get my camera
out here we
go all right let's head over to the
beach dude all right let's go for
208 beautiful day in Vancouver today
it's gorgeous well I mean was so shitty
in the morning and now I'm in a t-shirt
so I love it now yeah very lucky for the
uh 420s I have to say our 420 Community
has been uh rather lucky today it's been
raining and raining and raining and
today it's just blue blue sky earlier it
rained a bit it's like one of the first
sunny days at all in like what 3 or four
months right like for
real all right so we've uh picked it up
again here Flav and I are just walking
down the street just started walking
into some sort of 420 friendly looking
folks not as busy as it usually is
that's for sure weather definitely the
weather today though right bet a lot of
people come out now that it's sunny it's
nice now 420 could get
busy could get
busy a Polie don't seem too overly
concerned with what's going on no this
guy's like what do you want me to do
they're all smoking reefer you must
arrest them I'm not arresting [ __ ] these
people can do what they
[Music]
want quite a bit of booths man I'll
definitely say that much oh
yeah
oh yeah it's bigger than last year is it
oh yeah wow go towards the stage that's
pretty loud and obnoxious but we can do
it we can we
will well that's not too bad we're
[Music]
close we got to figure out how we're
going to get down
there
all right well Johnny's way up by the
stage yo shout out to my sponsor one
time West Coast for having me
here I think the boys are out there on
the
bewhere this next track is called faces
it's title track on my next project
faces like right here yeah right here oh
thank God I did not
want man I brought the right y when I
point to Y that need you to help me with
when I point Y not
here John's not at his Booth all right
all right next two tracks keep that in
mind what up Caribou how you feeling do
[Music]
hey yeah we try to
get
[Applause]
Johnny
V dude what's up
brother here what's that are we going
where we going I want to get a shot off
the
[Music]
stage
like Fu dubious you'll be going dude
almost 420 with d420 K up on the
stage [ __ ] ripping [ __ ]
this yeah let's show them the
[Music]
crowd
happy man happy T20
vanc thank you for being at our Festival
of
defiance so this is the big joint
giveaway happening right
[Music]
now walk down right to the end Carly too
get to the end there's some people there
look very stressed out not relaxed at
all the nice thing about cannabis is it
makes you relaxed hungry happy inspire
and
[Music]
focused and in the right mindset for
gathering in large numbers and
protesting Injustice and creating a new
world inside the dying husk of the old
[Music]
one and some important facts to remember
are nobody's ever died of an
[Music]
[Applause]
overdose trying to get it over there
nobody's ever died of an overdose
there's no real withdrawal symptoms to
speak of except you miss it now hold on
a sec we're going to try to light these
all at 419 at the same time so that we
have a big cloud going on all at
once what time we got
now it's 4:3 we got 7 minutes left make
sure everybody has a joint in their hand
and everybody has a lighter nearby so
that we can light them all at 419 which
is happening in exactly 5
minutes 5 minutes time have the biggest
420 ever
smile smile smile at him yes here's Jody
Emery the persecuted cannabis
entrepreneur and activist
extraordinaire to say a few words right
before 20 get ready and we'll light them
all at the same time at
4:19 happy for 20
Vancouver the sun is shining the people
are smiling and we're here to celebrate
cannabis but we're also here to protest
prohibition because while we get to be
here today free a lot of our friends are
behind bars and still being arrested
every single day so it's up to us to
take a stand while we're still free I
face life in prison myself I might not
be free for that and we're not stopping
till we get it we are going to keep
breaking the law out in the open till
all the PLT laws are gone all the flower
criminals are
free we're not going to stop until we
have export and import rights
to yeah we want marijuana tourism we
want fun and breakfast
[Music]
that's why we want the marijuana drive
through window just like
Starbucks and we don't want to be
limited to 30 G we want we don't even
want to be limited to 30
lb We Don't Need No
Limits what time we
got we're getting close more minute left
let this is beautiful you're beautiful
don't let anybody tell you you're crazy
or you're stupid
you're intelligent you made a smart
choice to use cannabis over alcohol
caffeine and other harder
drugs congratulate yourselves you are
part of the true north strong and
free two minutes all right we still got
2 minutes left cuz everybody got their
lighter okay we're going to do this all
the once you got to show them what
organized crime really really means
we're organized crime we're
proud We are so organized we manag to
have this go on every year with no major
injuries no major issues just a little
bit of litter that the city sometimes
forgets to pick
[Music]
up no problems other than red eyes and
dry
mouth and you know what we don't need to
talk for that we can handle that well on
our own thank you very much all right
about it ready to do the countdown yeah
we're getting close are we getting there
what's the time what's the time Johnny B
what time we got now we got 418
418 it's like end wait a second
here8 David one minute warning one
minute warning one minute warning 60 59
58 57
56 getting there 20 19 okay Jody wants
to speed it up cuz she's impatient 20 19
18 17 16 15 14 13 12 11 10 9 8 7 6 5 4
here we everybody one
[Music]
[Applause]
happy yeah
buddy that's what I'm talking about
right there flame
on it's getting a little bit foggy over
here oh
[ __ ]
people you
feel how you
[Music]
feel
fantastic you see
it SM it up it's 420 smoke
we
hey hey we got a lot of people to thank
for this event here weeds glass and
Gifts Health lifestyle dispensary my
Pleasant medical
bu a panorama of the crowd at the beach
and you can see the difference once the
joints got lit
unreal where you living dude in bellam
yeah nice
Bellingham you know in
1998 I picked up a marble Slinger on the
side of the road hitchhiking on the way
to the gorge fish shows and he was with
this other dude Jason Lee [ __ ] Leo
and so these are the dudes I end up
picking up and hitchhiking uh and going
to the show with and we tripped out
together and uh hey let's walk over this
one we tripped out together you know
dosed and whatnot but uh dude I'll tell
you man that was the beginning of a
beautiful relationship in the in the 9s
to for the Bellingham crew that was like
Pedro and Zach and Eli and Drex and
Slinger Marcel yeah so many great
blowers like this so many great blowers
and right across the board they'd come
over all the time they come visit me and
take 45
minutes kind of went away for some
years so happy 420 everyone back at high
integrity glass art just chilling out we
are uh exploring the beautifulness of
this particular rosin 120 Micron Congo
rosin and uh that must be an HD product
no yeah so Heavenly days pulled that
[ __ ] sweetness out and let me tell
you I'm ready to dab it
so shall
I
sure gentle
gentle
oh yeah this is great all right we got
the Banger hanger Mr Dosa in the house I
got my own timer so I'll do that this
time relieve you of timing
duties oh you thought it was out could
be see we might get 20 seconds out of
it heating up the Banger
hanger see how it just hangs there
lovely
all right stop reset start been a nice
day all in all pretty good got the
volcano kid in the background there
doing his own thing and uh he gifted me
some very lovely dab mats from the oil
slick boys these are photographs of
pieces that he took and so very sweet
you can check him out on uh Instagram at
volcano
kid and uh you can check out high
integrity glass art at high integrity
glass art on Instagram so let's go here
for the Congo 120 Micron rosin that's
what I'm talking about rosin that is one
particular Micron not squeezed out of
every gland head that you could squeeze
off the plant and mix them all together
but pulling off only 120 heads and
processing that I'm sure that's going to
give a very lovely flavor here we
go
[Music]
wow someone larm is really go off he you
hear that the city's wild it's loud
volcano kid in the
background hey
look I'm squashing your
[Music]
head
low temp for the
win hey yo
[Music]
baby the timber Ro feel good give me
a one man man real purpose of the weed
that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that's to
the
Mind purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose have the weed let
I view the
time it is not here to check the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
ding been traving to King mil
hours like fresh vation with
[Music]
trees give me one Bigg and if
bigger me pass pass
[Music]
pass I make pass pass pass and
then could that up the now before me
like BL thatz
and pass that pass that pass that
now after the weed that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
you the
time we is not here to trick the mind
it is only here to do its purpose of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying well iine the road be some cops
setting
up TRS man man we tell me offs and F
upon their SC to intervene in my brains
that and behind you scene me and my team
have another
25 then we smoke it half
[Music]
clean my
now pass pass
then I make Po pass pass pass and then
[Music]
pass pass
pass I make
[Music]
pass