[Music]
all right all right here we go live
Facebook
session requested by my friend Allison
who said I wish you were live right now
and I said all right done so here we are
we're live this is the Allison Gordon
Facebook session and uh I hope you're in
here Allison Gordon I don't see you but
Jared scully's in the house so I will
say hello hello to him and uh I guess
it's time for a little session I got
this little Mothership piece here this
little guy here a little sub 8 in Klein
with a honey bucket lemon drop on there
and I figured why don't we have a nice
little session welcome Dustin helders
and welcome Jared Scully and welcome
resin beautiful beautiful resin which we
have no shortage of here plenty of the
good stuff right there yes yes welcome
John baylock CJ Tracy I think it's time
what do you guys say what do you guys
say should we do this should we get a
going on should we make it happen a
there's Allison look she finally showed
up for her special for her only Facebook
live session at least uh you made it
thank you Mason very very excited this
uh this is the new Mothership Allison so
this this this rip is going to be for
you right here so let's uh let's get
this going here I've got my dab already
TP dipped over here in some Jack Frost I
believe we went into Jack Frost turpins
have a whole selection here beautiful
beautiful hope to see some of you guys
in Spain in March I'm going to be coming
in Spain and I may may may may may may
may be selling a mother ship while I'm
there so if you're there come by my
booth check us out we're going to have
the Sasquatch guys there we're going to
be with Javy from medical seeds and it's
going to be pretty much uh a wonderful
epic experience so come to Spain I think
it's going to be fun I excuse me for
turning on this torch I know it's going
to be loud and obnoxious but uh it needs
to be done so let's see if we oh
actually before we do that let's do this
real quick and get this
timer that I wanted to get on my
computer oh I hope you are coming to
Spain it's going to be very good got
Davin solo rigs I do not have any Davin
solo rigs all right here we go we got
this timer
launching activity timer boom it's nice
to have the timer on my phone I use it
all the time but I got to say when I'm
as for those of you that don't know when
you're heating up this quartz it's very
nice to know how long you heated it up
for which tells you how long you should
cool it down for and then makes for the
cleaning to be very uh much easier
recently I looked at the price of this
particular dial just with this quartz
Banger which is the MEAP pot which you
can see there with the seat of Life
carved into the bottom of it um very
expensive for this little unit
$850 without the bucket or the ofc so
you want to take care of these things uh
welcome Manning uh Michael Manning from
Blue River welcome welcome I guess
really all there is to do now is see if
that timer actually opened up because if
it didn't I'm going to have to figure it
out where did you go
timer I can't even see the timer I know
I just added it oh there it is activity
timer oh there we go so I guess I bet I
got to set this thing I've never done
this before so uh bear with me while I
figure out how to um
set the lengths oh there we go 25
minutes that seems a little bit long
let's go with 55 seconds how about
that
55 trying to get this done here sorry
guys I'm not really discussing hey
welcome Roy Richardson in from Cambodia
yeah it's getting crazy Justin it is
getting [ __ ] crazy there's no no
doubt about it let's see if we can start
this 0.1 okay so d d 55 so that'll be
fine all right so let's get the show on
the road I want to have a bom rip with
you do 25 minutes yeah that's a pretty
long one welcome Johnny Joan Andres
Rodriguez and Christian Bureau you were
just in time bro we're just about to get
this [ __ ] party
started sorry about how loud the torch
is I know it's
obnoxious I got my bomb cleaner right
here that I'm going to show you guys
this new cleaner that I've got which I
showed on hash Church the dark city dark
uh glass dark dark crystal glass from
Mick out in Ontario so yeah let's just
get this nicely heated
up and uh yeah once you get it nicely
evenly heated
up then we will hit start on the timer
Bing and in 50 seconds or so I will have
my dab and that's how how you do it
right there ladies and gentlemen I
dipped my turbs let me tell you good
good I'm glad that the audio wasn't so
bad I know that often torches just pick
up terribly on uh on these microphones
so real dabbers understand the Sound
True Story right there well I have
ordered myself up a nice glass Dabber
from sherbet don't know if you guys
check him out on Instagram but he's
pretty good dude what's my next big
project you know right now I'm actually
looking online for buildings in
Vancouver to lease or purchase space to
do a huge bubble Man's World Experience
Vape Lounge high-end Glass Gallery to do
high-end glass shows um really nice
restaurant and you know whatever it can
be from there basically all right we got
6 seconds left so everyone ready see if
I can get this a little straighter so
you can actually see the bong
rib
I love the vapexhale don't get me wrong
I usually have it plugged in and ripping
it out but after getting this piece
recently I just can't say enough about
it yeah it's an exciting uh idea you
know so here's the cleanup see how dirty
we got here we're going to give it a
little cleanup with uh with a
Q-tip but you'll
see there's
still some dirt in there okay so what we
do is we
dip in this cleaning solution right in
there nice amount on there now this part
will trip you right out cuz we're going
right in here and this shit's going to
Bubble Up and froth
up and it basically cleans the quartz
like nothing I have ever seen
any cleaning agent do and it's
completely natural you can drink the
[ __ ] it's based on like coconut oil and
kunga oil and it is [ __ ] killer I
will show the cleaner again absolutely
just uh make sure hey Mark sorry I'm
late don't worry Spencer we're happy
that you finally made it buddy we've
been waiting for
you so a couple
more and then you can see just how clean
I got
that you see that guys
so amazing amazing cleaner and I will
show that again right away no alcohol it
is exceptional resin lifting
power Dark Crystal glass so what it is
is it's non-chlorinated water it's uh
Kanga oil processed coconut extract
processed kelp extract and processed
extract of sugar cane so they got some
method that they're they're doing with
it but I'll tell you what there's no
smell there's no taste even once you
clean it off most most of it's water and
so the water steams and I guess it's the
oil inside the water while it's steaming
that lifts and picks up the resin so
wipe the outside of your bucket yeah I
wipe the outside of it sometimes not
always when it gets you know when resin
uh surrounds it a lot I take this little
guy and I'll just give it a nice outside
clean probably every like second or
third rip so will that help with my
shower head for reals I missed what you
were asking about your shower head but
man I'll tell you I am loving this tiny
little mother ship you see how big this
thing is I think my torch is almost
bigger than it very small little
dude we know how to talk and clean them
well whatever I'm just saying this stuff
is great [ __ ] and I'm sharing it with
you whether you like it or not I love to
clean glass I'll tell you it's it's to
pay a lot of money for quartz and to I
want it to be new every time I hit it
and it's a bummer when you ruin it when
you burn too much material on it people
hit it hot they they don't clean it
properly so um I wonder if I soak you
know what it could Spencer there I have
seen some thermal shock do some pretty
incredible things you can heat the stuff
up and boil it and then put um bangers
into it and it'll he's got videos on his
Instagram it just picks the resin right
off the glass what's the size on it Mark
uh this is
7.9 7.9 for this one so it's what they
call a sub 8 and definitely for people
that are looking for you know he
Mothership glass it seems that a lot of
people are looking for smaller than
taller pieces 9 in and up you're
certainly not going to get the same
amount of people bugging you for um a
piece as 8 in and Below straight up
straight out of the ship T burping I
like that TP burping look you know I'm T
burping over here too got my flavors you
want to see what flavors we have in the
house today we're going to start off
with some stard dog from Blue River
extracts right there stard dog super
cushion incredible flavor on that Sunset
sherber I can't even describe this it's
so nice it's so unique I just
uh yeah it's got this cushy also very
deeply cushy but something different
like very flavorful then the Tangi what
needs to be said about the Tangi it's
Citrus explosion it's so citrusy it's
just amazing everyone that smells it
whether they like cannabis or not will
have something nice to say about it oh
wow that's so nice so yeah we have a big
appreciation for that
then we got the
Clementine the Clementine is very
different in the sense of it's a citrus
it's similar to Tangi but it just has
these completely different undertones
following that Citrus blast that you get
when you initially um smell it and then
of course the Jack Frost I mean who
doesn't love some Jack Frost if you've
never have it you got to get blue
river.com Blue River extract.com ships
to
Alaska M so there's the Jack Frost very
happy with that very happy with um the
New Order of tpin that we'll hit the
website here in the next week or so and
just uh been loving it up TP dipping
bong ripping [ __ ] Yan as d420 K would
say on hash Church my mom was tripping
the other day on why my house stunk like
citrus I bet she was I bet she was yeah
dude trust me I've tried so many
different cleaners this thing is really
good I was impressed with it i' I
haven't you probably noticed if you've
watched my channel for any amount of
time that I've never out of all the
years I've been smoking these have I hit
from these Mothership um quartz bangers
because I always felt like it was too
fast to destroy them and for the value
like like I said 850 just for this
quartz and dial that becomes so
expensive that you want to be able to be
able to take care of it so I just got
this cleaning solution I carry it around
in these 4.5 MLS a bottle is is huge 650
MLS but what I think I'm going to do is
I'm going to probably put you know 5 mls
in each one of these put a nice little
sticker on there and sell it with a
little pack of Q-tips and just sell it
for like a buck or something not to try
and make money but just to try and like
get people access or maybe I'll make a
bunch of free samples of these with the
first couple of bottles and I'll just
send them out to people and say hey look
if you like it you know where we're at
and if not uh thanks for trying any
thoughts on Colorado's Social Clubs
coming soon I don't know I don't spend
any time in Colorado I do have a lot of
friends there but I really don't have my
finger on the pulse at all I barely have
my finger on the pulse in Vancouver and
I only live 25 minutes outside of that
City so um I feel that Vancouver is
blowing up though you know for our scene
it's like so many dispensaries there's
vapor lounges I think it's time for a a
real high-end place to come in and offer
something that nobody else is offering
so yeah red congales is good Karma's
[ __ ] is good um Sunset sherber is good
lavender skunk is good there's so many
good ones what's go what's up there Mike
Micron Mike Micron in the house I think
it's time for us to probably Blaze one
more Bowl this is the Allison Gordon
session she requested this so I think
everyone should at least say hello to
Allison or perhaps something else of
sorts but she's in the room this is her
Facebook live that she requested so you
should at least thank her probably for
if you're enjoying this particular
Facebook live she's the reason it's
happening right now
all right
so TP dip bong rep little bit of
rosin I think we're going to go with
some Clementine this time
around hello there holf BX is that
you Mr
Bishop yes everyone say hello to alisan
Alison's a very helpful person very good
very nice very
kind and uh yeah I'm sure I'll be seeing
her well who knows when I'll see her
next probably sooner than later March
maybe or Rob's about to join you on this
hit well right on say hello to Rob as
well everyone because he's probably
sitting right next to Allison and uh
they're both top notchers in my book and
uh I think that if you're going to join
me on this one Rob let's make it
happen let Heat this up a little bit see
what we can do
oh
skiing oh my God that's awesome well
how's it going Rob shout out to you
brother this uh this rip is for you and
Allison and it's TP dipped like you
wouldn't believe so let me tell you
you'd be all over this like uh and it
wouldn't give you a migraine headache
cuz let's be honest that's [ __ ] oh
here we go let me hit this timer real
quick boom I like having the timer app
on my computer that's real nice where
can I find that Mothership mothership is
like Mothership glass.com there's a
bunch of different resellers depending
on if you're in Canada or America
they're all over America on the East
Coast West Coast interior Canada there's
a couple one in the west coast here high
integrity glass art one on the east
coast which is like uh high priority
glass art or something like that but
um yeah yeah or join a Mothership for
sale group on Facebook you can also
punch in Mothership glass for sale
hashtags on Instagram and find all sorts
of different pieces uh it's good to get
to know you know to not be too much of a
newbie before you buy it but they do
have it set up so you can buy them used
pretty safely if uh if you go about it
the right way how do you like Frenchie's
agitator machine it looks pretty
high-end yeah I mean I haven't seen it
myself yet but uh it looks like a double
jacketed uh stainless steel sink I've
been working on my own stainless steel
unit uh for a while so I haven't had any
comments really cuz I don't want to give
up what I'm doing myself but we've been
working with the patent owner to produce
a a large scale uh commercial industrial
water
extractor
yeah row is where I get a lot of my
glass for my high integrity glass art
but there's also tons of people selling
you know like row would not be able to
get you you know a Taurus or an egg or a
Klein or there's many different ones
that he doesn't have right now but you
could potentially find them in these
Mothership groups they just might be a
little more
expensive I'm buying a peace off row
tomorrow in fact
quite excited about that I'll be showing
you guys that one on the next Facebook
live I sold my Taurus recently
so uh good solvent list you know
wherever they sell West Coast
concentrate would be one good start you
could go check out Sunrise Wellness
Center because I know they sell pretty
fiery stuff from concentrated X and
Heavenly days uh mostly raos and I think
maybe a little bit of dry
sift so you can check that out Sunrise
wellness and then I'm not sure if you
could you might want to hit up uh West
Coast concentrate East Coast
concentrates and find out where they
sell their product in Vancouver what
shops Etc cuz I don't know the names of
the shops but I know they make fire
material this is some West Coast
concentrate rosin that I've been
blasting here and so if it's good enough
for me I think it's good enough for you
as
well that's what I'm saying I want to be
your next door buddy all right well
that's cool you just got to buy a house
next door to me
welcome Brandon Collins I hope all is
well with you and
yours I mean I wish well upon everyone I
hope you guys are having a good holidays
I know hash Church 118 is coming up and
I don't know how I'm going to fit it in
on a Christmas morning might have to be
a Christmas Eve thing maybe a Christmas
night thing haven't figured out yet but
uh I'll figure it out maybe I'll look up
uh the juice for Santa and find out if
they can offer me any advice cuz my
friend Alice of course is uh one of the
she's the East Coast head of the chapter
juice for chant Santa #j for Santa and
that is a personal joke between the two
of us and of course all of her friends
as well check her out on on uh Facebook
Allison Gordon she's in here right now I
know she is happy holidays juice for
santz right on ah I hope you had a good
rip there Robbie I didn't get to hear
back from you but I don't know if you
were dabbing or rolling up a joint or
whatnot but uh I hope it will was good
I'm surprised you don't have a
solventless dash I'm definitely
surprised you don't have TPS the TPS are
just like important to have in the
pocket might have to uh make a little
Christmas donation over that way hey
Merry Christmas Justin and Angel Merry
Christmas how about an all day has
church just leave it open oh my God I
think you could do it for about nine
hours that would be over the top just
put the link on my Facebook and let
anyone who clicks on it come
in that'd be quite something quite
something
indeed yeah yeah for sure Jared you know
for me I don't care how many live people
watch I think it's cool when seven or
eight or 900 people are watching but I I
do these shows even if like three people
watch this just knowing that other
people were going to be watching later
so that's cool I just had my Christmas
dinner with the fresh headies company
that was a beautiful thing all my
employees take them out for a beautiful
dinner let them bring their spouses or
special someone's you know give them all
nice bonuses and and just uh yeah we
shared some nice Vibes tonight and had a
really nice dinner with uh with the team
with fresh headies it's the crew we've
had a we've got a good team going here
so company's almost 20 years old if you
can imagine bubble bags have been have
been sold around the world since 1999
and we're entering 2017 so there's only
a couple more years before we're in the
20th year of fresh headies and Bubble
Bags you're most welcome Johnny Morrow
I'm glad that people are enjoying it
dude I can't believe
that that we're still doing it two two
years plus later to be honest I just
think it's unbelievable but uh hey if
everyone's loving it if everyone's
enjoying it and the people most
importantly the panelists are willing to
come on because we all have very unique
personalities you know you'll see some
people who used to come on aren't coming
on anymore and people that have never
come on or coming it's just a fresh you
know you just you got to keep the the
seats moving and keep the people coming
in fresh because obviously um that's
what makes it exciting meeting new
people you know how much did hash Church
changed when Indra came on or when Dr
Natasha came on or when you know all
these different people that just started
making appearances it's really great I
appreciate it yep hasr is incredible in
that sense Merry Christmas to you and
your bubble bags well thank you I agree
Spencer it was very nice to see Andre
made put a smile on my
face I think it's great he loves hash
church it's given him a renewed Vigor I
know that he really is excited about it
I know that he likes being recognized I
know that he likes the respect that
people are giving him and in my opinion
it's super welld deserved I mean the
guy's a
super awesome conscious incredible dude
who also happens to have given so much
to the community and has incredible
stories there's lots of inspiration to
be had listening to Indra let's just say
so I'm I feel Beyond blessed that he
decided to come on to Hash church and
share all of this with us same with
skunkman Sam you know this [ __ ] these
guys haven't done this before ever in
the history of their lives they have
never gone out and put themselves out
there the way they're putting themselves
out there on hash Church the way they're
sharing their stories all of these
things I'm not sure if he did hook up
with subcool he said he was going to I
should try and uh I should I text with
Indra almost every single day so I'll uh
make you know it's Todd says it all the
time like I don't know how these guys
all became my friends but I kind of feel
the same way you know to be able to text
with Indra and Skype with Sam and
Chimera and Rob Clark and all these
wonderful people that are really just my
peers and my friends from the last 20
years you just don't realize it when
you're in it and then you look back and
you're like wow like I've known these
guys for 20 plus years like this is a
pretty this is a pretty cool thing and
so and so there it is on this Monday at
9:55 I don't I don't even know what the
what is it December 19th it is that was
pretty good he was recognized by his
voice exactly
Norman I think that's so cool that that
happened I really it made my hair on my
arm stand up I was so happy for him like
as I'm happy for you know Todd and etan
and Tony and all of those guys that give
their all and share on hash church and
deserve to be recognized by their peers
and the people that are watching them
and enjoying them it's nice to be able
to First you know they're super humble
dudes so approaching them is nothing
meeting them is only going to be pretty
much an enjoyable
experience and uh yeah it's just uh well
deserved yeah well I could have hash
Church mark emry on hash church I'll uh
I'll have to invite him and jod on
Jody's been on hash Church before I'm
not sure Mark ever has been I meant to
have him on and talk about prison and
whatnot and everything but uh I'll
definitely hit both mark and jod up and
put a you know a personal invitation out
to have them on hash church and see if
they want to come talk about the
Montreal etc etc as I'm happy to have
people like Hillary black uh and you
know Joel from the one of the main
Growers from Aurora or any of these
other people stoked stoked to do it most
thank you Allison I will tell Miss
bubbleman happy holidays from you
absolutely good that you're liking it
Chate and Robbie it's is not too shabby
but uh I have to say I think I'm going
to go and chill out now I've had a
couple of good dabs I just rambled off
like 28,000 words probably going to go
get a drink so I can
swall oh there we go I can't I I came
back says my connection's weak I don't
want to move I can't believe I made it
back I went Frozen for a long time there
I was kind of tripping out guys I'm glad
that I made it back back because I want
to have a good video Welcome Stevie
Hughes I'm glad that I make it made it
back for you my voice would make a good
narrator for a
documentary all right okay let's do that
someone do a documentary and then serve
me up some words and I'll read them and
I'll be the uh the narrator yeah I froze
but I stuck with it I didn't want to let
you guys go I felt like you know what I
feel like if I push through and I move
around my office a little bit which I
did cuz I'm holding my phone now if you
noticed I brought you guys back I
brought got you guys back oh yeah I'm
back that's right because you know what
no weak internet connection is going to
stop bubble man from talking to the
people out in bubble man's world and you
are those people and I appreciate all of
you and I wouldn't have been able to say
hello to Alexander rety so I'm so glad I
made it welcome Alexander and Ben warden
in the house L Elling all the way to the
bank bubble man is too much bro I
thought it was my connection it was my
connection woot wooot okay let's have a
hoot hoot I hope you don't mind Stevie
but I am hitting the lemon drop Mega pot
it's rare but it's happened bro I
finally got into a little bit of this
torch action so don't hate me yeah we're
back we're totally back I mean the full
part is on are you kidding me we're
going to do a little rosin dab and we're
going to do a little TP dip I think this
time we are going to TP dip into
oh let's say Sunset sherbet one more
puff we are having yes everything is
very well Alexander very very well we're
dipping into the sunset sherbet we just
hit some Clementine before that I think
it was Jack Frost before that or Tangi I
don't know it's all it's all a blur bro
it's all a blur I need to get some new
like little the this thing is so heavy
it just
closes or falls
down all right God this smells good like
coffee and I don't even like
coffee nail is escaping yeah I know
Nail's trying to get away on me it's
like don't you do that don't you try to
get away oh I'm getting her done lemon
drop the OG original UV reactive color
good eye Spencer good
eye I don't know if they will you know
it's possible I definitely want to open
one in Vancouver if I did this Bubble
Man space and it was a high-end gallery
and had the restaurant and had you know
Bubble Man World maybe like a studio
where I could film out of uh a nice
little restaurant it would definitely
have a Blue River store and it would be
the first I would suspect in North
America that you could uh that you could
purchase Blue River tpin in a little
special area of the store where you know
we'd have well-trained people that could
explain the different tpin show you the
chemical makeups offer you vape exhale
pure tarine rips without
canabo and uh yeah I think it would be
really pimped out so something I've been
talking about with a potential
investor all right I don't usually torch
that long for those of you wondering I
was just really cleaning I'm obsessive
compulsive with cleaning this nail so
it's uh it's the way it
is love the idea yeah right you know
like have a real nice high-end little
like clean tarping Corner have the Vape
Lounge have you know the shop that sells
all the hash making tools maybe build a
hash lab that's almost like a room
that's you know like a walk freezer with
a big glass window where people could
come in and be like oh bubble man's in
he's making hash right now you can walk
in and you can watch him or we'll have
it playing on TVs in the in the place
where I'll be dry sifting or wet washing
or making Ros and I'll have it set up
with mics I'll be able to talk and
explain and give tips as I'm doing it
and then of course people if they're
inspired by it they can either buy those
tools or they can go home and make their
own tools for that that matter you know
me I'm still going to share all my ideas
with you I'm going to tell you how to
get it down I'll tell you the screen
sizes I'll do I'll tell you whatever you
need to know know I want to be inspiring
and I want to make hash in public and I
want to I want to be able to do that in
this space so it's something that's uh
um I don't use the torch more than the
Dil actually like at all I use the Dil
like religiously even on planes I got
that ship Plugged In For
Real
I know you will
Allison tell me that space wouldn't be
amazing tell me people wouldn't travel
to be like I heard there's this
[ __ ] in Canada that has this
space that's like a pimped out Vapor
Lounge he's got a studio in there for
filming with a green room he's got this
hash lab that's in a walk-in freezer
with a giant glass window that you can
go up and look right in or you can watch
it on giant
TVs beautiful Vapor Lounge
high-end glass Art Gallery super
high-end Art Gallery with special
Mothership shows team Japan shows you
know Marcel and Jason Lee shows whatever
marble Slinger and Paco [ __ ] or a
Philly show with all the Philly artist
like something that would be super
inspirational for the entire Community
but instead of being one single
component that might not be enough to
keep it really flourishing and Alive add
all of those components maybe do a
Facebook or a a live YouTube you know
Robert when I'm in there making hash
once a week or something have it as a
subscription base the that serious
people that really want to get the
information because uh I'm ready to
start giving it out again and I'm ready
to start doing things that are a little
bit different than most the things that
I see that are being done I'm back in
the game I want to do this I think
Vancouver is a great spot to start I
could see it happening in La soon after
and of course I mean I would love to
push the bount boundaries and have some
small little private type thing in
Whistler that would be just amazing but
we'll start with Vancouver and we'll see
how it goes I'll tell you I put three
years into the melting point and um I
think yeah bubble man's world exactly
I'd like it to be called Bubble man's
world but the gallery will be the
melting
point or uh the you know all of these
different aspects that I've been
thinking about since the melting point
cuz I first had the melting point back
in 2003 when I had my raw food Cafe my
Vapor Bar my high-end Glass Gallery A
lot of these things I've already done
like over 10 years ago so Vancouver
British Columbia so yeah A Bit of
Everything Under One Roof a really
amazing Immaculate space that was built
to fit all of these things high-end I
don't want Coca-Cola and chips I don't
want it to be like your average Vapor
Lounge I want it to be something that
people can really feel comfortable going
to the way they would uh a nice
restaurant so that is a little bit into
my mind of some ideas that I've been
having figured I might as well share it
with you guys and get a little bit of
feedback it's something you could see
coming in the upcoming year
2017 and uh yeah you know Spencer I
would definitely talk to all my glass
friends that had beautiful glass and try
to bring them in to be a part of it in
some way shape or form at least for the
gallery aspect to make sure all the best
glass in the world was in there I also
like the idea of the gallery buying and
selling glass you know having a good
chunk of money put aside so we can buy
heady pieces to put in the gallery with
without having anyone's [ __ ] on
consignment and being able to sell that
[ __ ] at any rate that we want to without
a rush so pretty damn cool everybody I
should finally let you go that last rip
was wonderful but my beautiful wife is
waiting for me and as you know with
children we only get a very few hours
every night to hang out and chill out so
I will thank you all for your time
hanging out here in bubble man's world
and uh yeah thanks for letting me bounce
my ideas off you guys and thanks for
your positivity you know for the most
most part you guys are all pretty damn
positive I don't see too much negativity
very often in the room so I do thank you
for that have a great night everyone and
happy holidays if I don't talk to you
before uh the big day uh and if I do
well we will talk to you soon peace out
and this is brought to you care of
Allison Gordon she was the inspiration
for this chat so give her a thanks peace
out
everyone