[Music]
what's up
everybody in Kingston Jamaica with my
Breen
prophecy positive unpr prophecy you know
I mean
life prophecy yeah
man I you love give thanks prophecy
we're super happy to be here as always
we're uh we're going to be heading up to
the mountains to Stone Hill studio ktis
and I believe some from France and some
French yeah so that connection you know
and keeping the rout where the road
supposed to be spreading the love and
the message you know what I mean one
vibration you cry I cry when you my
people i s your pain I can feel your joy
I'm longing to see you know rest
the I couldn't be happier myself right
now to be here with prophecy rolling
through Kingston and heading up to see
ksai and these other just incredible
inspirational musicians you know I
brought the Drone so hopefully we get
some really cool Drone footage if they
allow it and uh yeah yeah we'll just
keep showing you guys a little bit of
the cruise and uh you're with bubble man
in Prophecy blessed love blessed
love driving through Kingston with
prophecy listening to prophecy make it
pay attention listen to the
[Music]
words don't make it
happen let's make it
happen don't make it
[Music]
we could never
make but I return I saw
[Music]
this my door saying don't
go we could never make
it
yeah we going to make it happen W dude I
feel blessed right
now don't say
[Music]
that in the heart of the B I
see they sh fighting a strugle each
day if they sh
the reason why I R to the
spirituality to become so subversive you
know yeah so you call me spiritual AR
will
see great spiritual
advice so greatly said wild though hey
M greatly said it's yours prophecy
you're the word
Smith p and pass p and pass
halfway tree
[Music]
is the place to
be gu
[Music]
I
can't I'm wondering if you're feeling
the same oh my baby
girl over and over again I got this
feeling in my heart my baby got to
[Music]
understand all right we're just pulling
up so a question for you prophecy yeah
what you know as a Jamaican artist you
know a Roots artist what do these guys
that we're about to go see mean to you
guys like Ken Booth and ksai these these
Elders these guys mean everything to her
now because they are the root you
understand I say um
more so these are the ones who really
take us in their arms and and and really
say come on Prophecy come on Uprising or
come on you know we make you welcome in
their inclusive yes you say right
welcome in their inclusive era yeah you
understand me and they have a wider
sense of realization who is you and what
is what and how we here to really help
with this journey that they have started
so you know just R far again these is
the real deal you know what I mean the
real deal I know I feel it I'm very
excited to uh to check out this studio
and to see ktis it's been almost a year
same with uh as long as I've seen you
last so I'm very much looking forward to
[Music]
this
same all right so we are up up up in the
hills
we're remembering where we are which is
the best part it's not always easy to
remember where you are in
Jamaica don't have the same sort of
ways oops dead
end back
around pretty nice properties up
here it's nice that you guys can make
music in a on a beautiful property you
know yeah yeah yeah that looks nice see
jez
soe the mind all right they're here in
Kingston with ktis finally linked up
with ktis eye it's been a year ktis yes
sir it's been one year full one the
crew we Kos all right here we go yeah
man this is p rice B from the uprising
roads S A
represented for the highest grade of
herbs
see go ahead
[Music]
you got ktis directing him in the
background pull it pull it pull
it yeah you see that man higher than the
sky
see double rainbow over the mountain oh
my God that's awesome maybe I should fly
the Drone into
it yeah double rainbow over the
mountain good eye ktis good
eye here this is Rainbow Valley
Valley we sometime have five different
rainbows two going that way from down so
going so one coming across and then one
coming
so
right the other day I happened to to see
one that was on the trees and on the
land just you can't you have to get up
to see all L it does and I'm up here and
this thing is down there and I'm saying
blood CL if I could have fly fly right
[Laughter]
[Music]
rainb see the
possibility because the end of the
rainbow was always this Mystic thing see
y but the way I see it in a rainbow Ark
on the trees over the land down there
and like about a 50t spread why when it
was I 90 minutes
[Music]
B and take a SE
because I had
a I remember coming into town
[Music]
all right guys so I am here at the house
up in the hills the kis invited me to uh
I didn't want to pull out the camera
right away until I got to know everyone
and I wasn't sure if they were working
on an unreleased studio album they got a
couple of guys here from France that are
just doing some incredible things and in
the yard is in the house a big part of
the crew and ksai and all these great
people being a part of this feels really
great to be here with prophecy we just
flew a little Drone footage which I'm
going to show you right now it's my life
it's my life it's my
life and it's your life it's your life
it's your
life but if we come together for one
[Music]
life we're coming from behind
behind spiritual
Warriors are on a
mission showing the world
of spirit let you un Warriers trotting
from
behind trotting forward at this
[Music]
time so let's turn let's turn the
tables yes I and I come turn the
taable turn the Paradigm around yes de
program and
[Music]
reprogram free
mankind spiritual un
Warriers are on a mission
showing the world
of spiritual un Warriers tring from
behind ding forward at this
[Music]
time read the mindset of the people chaa
children true true children seeking for
the vi the way
go I and I come to freedom freedom with
the light in the can
[Music]
you and
warriors are on a
mission showing the world of
a spiritual Warriors dring from
behind ding forward at this time
spiritual
Warriors are on a
mission showing the world I'm
a spiritual Warriors tring from
behind ding forward at this time
[Music]
right now just a little bit of uh
pulling back that really sort of Epic
scene of showing our environment uh
didn't have much of a battery and the
Drone was giving me a few um errors so
what I think I'll do right now is have a
quick dab with all of
you a quick dab with all of you let's
make sure I can do this
here all right there we go get that
light behind my head and you actually
might be able to see me just had a
really beautiful vegetarian um stew soup
I guess you if you will which really hit
the spot best food I've had since I've
been here my stomach feels so good had a
bit of a tummy ache since I got here not
eating the right things so give thanks
to Jamaica give thanks uh to all of the
kindness and um you know Hospitality
that I always receive when I'm here with
the band in the background we're going
to go see them right away for now let's
dab it
[Music]
up
beautiful all right let's go check these
guys out
[Music]
what do you should
know you
[Music]
so sweet and
SM I want
[Music]
last one that's one
what's up
prophecy you ready for another dab
[Music]
oh [ __ ]
are the intro come
[Music]
TR
it
[Music]
wait yeah exactly exactly right
next nice one
[Music]
small
yeah maybe a million give a million
[Music]
one two three
and okay
yeah ready sit
down one two three and
[Music]
go
mer
[Music]
true
you
ready 1
two
okay
start one two
[Music]
la
[Laughter]
[Music]
a
en
[Music]
well it's been a good evening sitting
around with these
gentlemen very nice puffing
tough eating some delicious ital
food listening to great
music give thanks kis
you come my brother very very blessed to
have been invited today thank you so
much for inviting me
here you can't find the lighter then
have a dab it's a thing I can't [ __ ]
find a lighter it's a thing have a dab
you'll find your lighter telling you see
even just have a see look at that have a
we have a
d oh yeah here we
go hot
[Music]
she's delicate
he
[Music]