[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and I wanted to give today a quick shout
out to the good people at ID daab I just
received this in the mail and I want to
thank you guys this is my drop down it's
got a couple of uh couple of little opal
marbles there you can
see really nice little unit and I'm
about to throw it in the Fab bag right
now you guys can check these guys out
actually at id.com and at Instagram uh
idab so you can check those guys out and
I'm really stoked because I've been
waiting waiting to use my silicon
carbide nail Flav told me it wasn't
really a good idea that I was going
directly into it so I really needed to
get on this drop down game this is my
first drop down so I really want to
thank you guys the silicon carbide nail
is going in I want to thank the guys at
denail for setting this up because I
don't know the guys at ID daab it was
Brian and Stevie who sort of put the
word out for me and let them know that I
was looking for a nice drop down for my
fab EG and uh well that's just a real
nice drop down I got to say what do you
guys think look pretty good make you
guys feel a little bit better now that
the uh the titanium is not directly in
my joint of the Fab EG so I've got it
turning on heating up as we
speak
so I think we'll
go with the last of Johnny
bees
Jamaican gave him the Lamb's bread my
seedling from 19 and A2 years ago 1995
when I was married in Negril I collected
some seeds on Orange Hill Hill uh up
past the cliffs in the grill there and
uh I brought those Seeds home I kept
those seeds up until May of 2014 in
which I cracked eight of them but only
one actually cracked seven passed away
one became the female that I am now
about to smoke out of this lovely drop
down and the silicone carbide nail so
just thanks everyone you know it's a big
beautiful cycle of friends helping
friends to make all this work and uh
when you see a 20-year ccle come into
effect I mean where do you think the
guys I dab guys were Stevie or Brian
from denil were were 20 years ago you
know they were probably playing around
in a playground somewhere maybe even
still still in diapers I don't know
those guys if they're in their 30s or if
they're just in their 20s still but
awesome that you guys could come this
full circle around to this Lamb's breed
20-year-old Strain coming back I mean
Mothership definitely didn't exist back
then so there's another thank you all
right we're up to temperature here
got a nice
700 got it set uh today to about 710
people ask me all the time why I have
different settings sometimes it's how I
feel sometimes it's my hash some hash I
prefer a lower temp some hash I prefer a
higher temp sometimes the wax membrane
is a little bit thicker in which case we
uh you know we don't mind a little bit
of a warmer temperature to get that that
oil boiling out of there oh the piece
feels pretty good in my hand I got to
say looking great great out in the
sunset there you guys think fabin it Fab
tabulous Sun's going down behind the
trees here real quick so I guess we're
doing a sunset rip are we
good close I want to wait till that
temperature gets perfect before I hit it
I'm going get my little Dabber out that
they also sent me from denail this is
the uh Dabber the C uh the carb cap I'm
sorry that works with the carbide nail
so the silicon carbide bowl is enormous
actually they sent me a lovely uh uh
Dabber and I'm going to go get it real
quick all right there we go look at
that the ID dab carb cap and it actually
is big enough to work on the Cary nail
and it comes with a Dabber as well I've
got the dry sift sitting here on the uh
Skillet tool so I'm going to use that
but we'll transfer over to the carb cap
when we're done the
rip
man does that tastes
incredible man 710 de Fahrenheit on the
silicon carbide nail it's doing a light
smoke it's very very tppy that was an a
wonderful turp rip like I said with the
silic on carbide got to crank that nail
up a little bit more if you want to get
that real Smoky
hit but that was just real nice the
silicone carbide is cool too because
what little res what residual that it
leaves it's just a matter of giving it a
light
scrape blowing it off the nail and the
nails clean again so I got to say once
again thank you to the good Folks at I
dab
on Instagram they are
idab check out
dna.com to check out the good guys at
denail you can use bubbleman 10 as your
discount code to purchase any products
from denail and they'll give you a nice
little discount and uh yeah go check out
idab as well
because they seem to be good folks they
seem to make good products and they seem
to be connected to good people like Dil
so I like to keep it in the family thank
you guys so much I'm going to finish
this video off with one more r
and I think what we're going to go
for is a little d420
K OG
Kush so let's take a nice big fat rip of
that shall
we all right here we
go
awesome really nice good thanks for the
drop down give thanks for for the unity
in the community come on guys I'll leave
you with the sunset
[Music]
peace