[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm not going to lie I finally went out
and got a new camera and kind of see the
box over my shoulder there all right so
we are starting with this video with the
new for 4k
camera and see what kind of quality we
can share
here it's beautiful all right so here
you can see the quality difference in
the camera I'm a total idiot guys I
apologize for recording this I don't
know how I had it set on the lowest
setting uh pretty ridiculous optical
zoom on this thing as well if you see
I'm zooming in several kilometers away
I'm hand holding this so there's no
tripod or anything thus the little bit
of shake but for that kind of zoom and
to see that clear I was quite impressed
with the quality so uh you guys should
expect better things to come from the
new 4k camera on Bubble man's
world uh the new Panasonic uh 991 xcw or
something little 4K unit pro suumer
model not too expensive not too
inexpensive hopefully you guys are going
to be enjoying the quality on this and
it's got some pretty cool options uh and
new things with picture in picture and
being able to use multiple smartphones
to record and put that inside the
picture so we'll probably end up doing
that eventually but for today just a
quick little video uh went and saw the
guys at Sunrise Wellness here in
Vancouver the other day uh Dom great guy
had a nice little session with him
really liked his education that he was
laying out to the customers that were
coming in it's definitely a shop that is
carrying a higher uh quality that you
see generally and he gifted me a small
little bud here which is the Gorilla
Glue number four uh cross with the 09
cookies nice little package that it came
in as well that was open and not going
to squish the bud type of thing I've
already Vaped a little bit of the bud
and I've
squished just a tiny little bit of it as
well it was a nice size Bud that he gave
me so too bright there oh yeah that's
maybe a little bit
better still getting used to this bright
bright light off the top of the camera
here let's
see I guess you can't really see it that
way
but anyway a nice little bite by anyone
standards got the sasquash press behind
me all lit up and ready to go we're at
about
238° right now I'm going to grab my
parchment real
quick got a piece of parchment
all pre- ripped just got to give it a
fold and then I generally break up the
bud and make it kind of long nice little
buds
pretty decent
quality and I'm still oh it's back on
all right so let's crack this open a
little
bit not raising it too much I'm not even
going to give it the the pre-
squish make sure that lever's
closed get over here to the to the air
compressor
bring her down
[Music]
slow now she's squishing I can hear
her oh yeah squishing
nice we're going to open it up and check
out what we
got
[Music]
all right
so let's get this squishing on so we can
show you what we got
here all right so this is what we got
out of the
squish it's just a first squish there's
plenty left so I'll fold it all up into
a small ball all right so there's a tiny
little dab of what I
collected couple of little pieces in
there one little partic I see in the
bottom right there as I turn
it very nice quality looking though I've
already had a dab so I know it's tasty
Gorilla Glue number four let's press it
again and see what we get all right so I
broken the the piece up and I'm going to
squish it in this little sort of pen
pancake stack pancake stack Tech so we
got that in
there can't really see it but the stack
is in there I assure you there it is
there she
goes let's get this
[Music]
happening how's that for a
squish got much more efficient on that
Squish and this thing really laid out
the juice like what I knew it would was
willing to lay out so right there is why
you want to do a couple of squishes just
in case you're not super efficient at
first you might want to uh it's worth
doing let's collect this all right so
we'll just get rid of a couple of
little little bits of
[Music]
contaminant all right let's let's
collect this up and see how how how well
she's
collecting sorry you guys can't see that
very well I guess
it's and we'll get the second
batch
all right so you can see this is real
sappy sticky stuff almost
shaty but quite sappy once heat it
up and let's see what we got here always
excited to see what we
got nice little dab right there not too
shabby at all all right so yeah nice
little dab that came out of that right
there can see the first dab
right right
here and if we want to get
fancy and we want to show you both dabs
simultaneously we can do that as well
let's see there you
go camera and Camera new camera right
we're going to be playing around with
all sorts of things hope you guys
enjoyed the short video and uh yeah
maybe I'll finish it off with a bong rip
shall I I think so all right so there's
the second press right there
and there's our first press it's a
little bit of contaminant in there
but it will sit on my
nail so yeah let us do a dab here which
one should we do should we hit a little
mixture of both I think so and there's
our little cake almost looking like
there's still a little bit of goods left
in
there all right well I finally managed
to get myself that little dab dipped in
I will have you know some cherry AK-47
Blue River tpin let me tell you about
these
oh my goodness these are some special
special just making the rip at first I
wasn't sure if I had dipped it and I
smelled it I was like I'm not sure if
I've dipped it obviously you have not
dipped it when you're not sure that
you've dipped it because when you have
trust me you're going to know as this
right now is wreaking up the entire area
around my face right now got my torch
all heated up the Mother Ship here torch
here did it all off camera got it all
heated up the bucket set and uh got my
carb cap dab in hand we're at about the
48 second Mark if we were hitting the
quartz we'd be probably hitting it right
about now um but because it is the
ceramic from hive the brother ship
actually we're going to wait a little
bit longer I usually go a minute and a
half to 2 minutes on on the uh on the
ceramic so probably going to trade my
clear one in soon here my mother ship
bucket little honey bucket gold dial get
that traded in maybe get myself a
colored one and that's the one that
you'll see me using I think here in the
near future anyway we're at about a
minute and 40 uh a minute and 30 seconds
I think we're good to go
[Music]
now just a lovely flavor on those tpin
let me tell
you got a pretty damn sweet temperature
on
that not super super low temp but
definitely
puddling I like to catch it at the
closest level of puddling that I can
without wasting too much of my rip and
knowing that I'm still getting a really
full flavored full bodied um hit so
thank you guys for watching that I've
got a little bit of this rosin left go
check out Sunrise Wellness I'm hoping on
doing a video with those guys where I go
down there pick out a few different
flavors of nuggets maybe a couple of
hashes and then go home and you know
puff them and give you guys a little
review I was really happy with the
quality that they had and uh there's
just not many dispensaries that I'll
avidly jump in behind behind and say you
should go there I think they're all
great for Access but for me because of
the way I use cannabis is basically for
the highest quality that I can find I'm
really OCD about the the the level of
care that was taken to grow it and you
know whether it was grown organically
and whether it was
grown you know if if they've been
spraying spraying it in any way shape or
form as a processor not even as an end
user I immediately have a problem with
it because I concentrate those terrible
things with my good things that I'm
extracting so that doesn't work too well
either anyway I'm just rambling now that
was a quick little video Sasquatch shout
out to those guys soil grown s and
hopefully the quality of the videos just
gets better and better I also changed
the lights in my office I put three new
beautiful lights in and you can see this
really bright kind of light that
surrounds me now as opposed to that
really terrible yellow light that we
started with at the start of the video
anyway we'll see you next time on Bubble
man's world hope you guys keep pressing
those Buds and may the full mouth bless
your bow sooner than later peace
out