[Music]
like
Panther very cat as I just sna my Fe
like twisted up and upside down ouch
why' you say that yeah I just Jinx
[ __ ]
hater being a good kitty I thought very
catlike hey guys welcome to Bubble man's
world a happy day here when d420 K comes
through the door good to have you buddy
good to be here bro good to have your
ship in the house dude yes dude D 420k
with the ball rig come on who set that
up um a high high integrity glass art
and who well I I helped out by just
introducing you but high integrity glass
art brings the motherships in he let he
let me know when these these when there
was one that's true I
did was was made sure that that I had a
spot to get one and uh [ __ ] a I had
to jump on it no matter what dud I need
toy I need to hit your ball rig right
now give her
I'm going to uh we've got a bunch of
things we want to do actually today how
do that sound that was the the wow I was
going to say wasn't the
bom made me laugh twice so I'll tell you
yeah boom little ball
rage yeah I love I love my mother ship
too like she what she do she uh she gets
I'm going to hit some of your gift from
many times ago oh nice uh ball rig
it
else I like all three of them they all
have a different level of
carburation this one's got a hole there
this one has a tiny hole right on the
top one's got a bigger one on top
okay Beauty you should probably hit that
as
well we'll give you a little bit of
Horatio Seven
Star T City T City yeah t City you can
let us know how you like
it
boom so
yeah we're actually going to be heading
out for a dinner here in the near future
we're going to be hooking up with row
from high integrity glass art have a
little Easter dinner out at a nice
restaurant but before then D thought uh
you know de and I thought we would do a
a little video cuz we hadn't done one
for a while puff some bowls show off the
new ball rig and then uh I guess do a
little bit of rosin because there's not
enough of that being done in the well
you know I uh I want to see exactly how
we're doing this properly with with some
really good
dry sift dry sift yeah and without
without me doing a few tests on it
because I'm really I'm really partial
about wasting any bit of my dry sift if
I'm not knowing the tech proper
technique and makes sense I I I put too
much time into it I think it's why we'll
do very you know I mean it always looks
great to do a big ball and get a good
amount but we'll do smaller amounts and
we'll just do exactly cuz it's just too
valuable of a product so yeah I got the
fresh hes uh rosin screen the uh
pressing screen blotting screen whatever
you want to call it 25 micron it's a
nice new clean screen so we'll probably
just go right into the corner
here create a
little a little dish and then uh I guess
we'll get a little a little rock of this
dry set absolutely man give her don't be
shy
clean for
me all right so let's see what we got
here all right it's not too much by any
means yeah nice little piece twist it up
real tight in the 25 micron we'll turn
on our little hair straightener
here and then we're going to use the uh
dabbing screen
yep it clean had just a little bit of
rosin left over on it from before and
basically fold that over the same way
you would with
parchment like along that lines right
there yeah and
then now with the parchment paper or
with the slick sheet the oil slick sheet
that's a slick sheet that's the Teflon
Pap uh sheet stuff with both of those
you have to be more careful because the
heat is so much closer to direct
this thing is so thick and it absorbs up
a bunch of the heat you actually have to
give it a press for longer like if I do
a 5-second press with parchment paper
I'll easily do a 10 or a 15c press or
two 7 Minute presses uh with this with
this
amount see some gooiness out of there
already oh it's
coming it's just right off the bat
holy that's that's that's
beautiful
right wow check it out so that uh we
could probably and we will probably
press that out at least one more time
and get another a chunk of it but yeah
take your Dabber and uh pick some of
that
up am I going to buy hair
straightening yeah I'll be in my hotel
tonight doing this dude my hotel doing
it h the egg oh thank
you I'm going to be a little big little
bit of a big to there no problem I'll
gladly take the smaller to well there's
lots there I know take a I can't wait to
see what D thinks of his full melt OG
cook dryft yeah full melt OG cush 99%
ratio heads squeezed with a hair
straightener
into an eight star full
melt now what I'm mostly interested in
seeing is if he gets the Head Rush that
I first got the first few times I smoked
rosin made with really nice sift or hash
it was a different kind of a rip that I
got from just you know normal a normal
same size rip of hash just was
different we'll see what he has to say
here in a
second boom boom
boom
wow flavorful got to photograph it dude
very flavorful right like
uh feel kind of kind of like really good
honey oil from what I used to remember
right but uh but
not
interesting not like a cleaner it
doesn't have that harsh piece right here
where you you remember smoking over you
know this hash real well though don't
you yes exactly yeah but but it gave me
a a total like I made oil out of it
honey oil out of it or shatter or
something like that you just did did and
uh you literally just did good flavor
and a good Buzz interesting isn't it
yeah it it creeps up on you it just
started
[ __ ] I'll tell you it sure is
photogenic uh I've just been
photographing rosin all
day and man it's
pretty right birdie holy sure
is nice
right yeah let's get a couple of more
Nies
here what the
glass your
turn on that's you're going to have to
hit that one like that whole the rest of
it I think you should those things I'm
used to hearing fall over those little
quartz pieces yeah and I don't even
worry about them so much like on the
base of my Mothership and stuff the
titanium ones I worry about when someone
puts a titanium one on my bowl and then
leaves it I worry about it just going
like this it's such a hard thing yeah
that if it touches this you know for
sure it's going to oh yeah you don't
want that no you really don't that's why
I use the quartz more often than not
this one was the Super nerve racker cuz
it gets hot so if you're holding it on
there for a long point of time it gets
hot and it's just pure
titanium so I guess I better take this
rip you just got yours it was nice and
tasty it was beautiful and don't be shy
take a nice big one oh trust me taking
it all yeah do it do it all just ch well
I said to do it actually earlier just do
it test do it now do do it do it all
right yeah dabs up okay thanks
brother very much
one just turns
already this turn Complete
Water wow that was
uh once again like almost made my eyes w
clothes that was really really really
nice rosin with high-grade dry sift and
bubble hash who would have thought it we
would have thought it and indeed did
than
it it's uh it's a nice day it's it's
cool it's cool that it happened it's
pretty neat for sure how it's all come
along and how it's just so many people
are now doing this simple little process
are we going to do another squeeze on
that we can
yeah see what you get of on just to show
the
difference
yes let's do
it okay keep my eyes off her she's a
[ __ ] sexy little little lady this
thing come close yeah
yeah we should probably do a photo
shoot clean them all up put them up on
the deck with the straight Fab the Fab
egg the Taurus the ball rig make a nice
photo yeah it
would calendar shot look at the calendar
poster poster type the calendar last
month was the the piece that high
integrity glass art had me post that
they were
selling still no buyers as of yet just a
bunch of oh I know the one with the
marbles on beautiful
pip yeah
they're a real treat to smoke out of
they really
are there you go
B the glob out of there still that's
pretty
good it's pretty
good you might be able to do a third one
even but yeah it's like you know half
the amount that time came out not too
bad whatsoever just to give you guys oh
the show don't want to skip the audience
they're all wondering what is it they're
looking at over there just a little Ros
and
smile I'll show you guys the photos as
well of
course and uh yeah there it is man dry
SI turned into Ros and not too shabby
you got to admit something different
very
potent yeah you know for the hit one
thing I noticed too is how long it lasts
when I take a rip of the rosin compared
to a rip of the bubs of the dry sift
it's very long lasting it's um it's a
treat absolute treat it's so much a
treat I don't want to hit it again I
think you should going I'm going to hit
it in my honey bucket do
it honey bucket it
upst I saw the kid Nathan or whatever
his name was he posted it on for sale
yeah and uh they they said they have a
timer on there
on on their quartz yeah but it depends
on what you're hitting you know longer
leave I I would leave it longer for this
type of product which is an oil but like
say if you were hitting dry s for full
melt I would hit it within 10 seconds 30
to 45 seconds um if it's an oil like a
rosin but really within 10 seconds I'll
drop it on there if it's full melt or
dry sift or wet
wash how was
that
Holy that's awesome isn't
it yeah dude super stoked on this whole
process coming out and being popularized
a way to make shitty hash uh great Hash
a way for me to access a dab out of Bud
almost the whole thing yeah I just
wanted to photograph that last little
bit
it's
good
sweet I love
it man got to love the oil slick pad for
for doing the the rosin technique on I
don't think I'll use parchment or Teflon
sheet again to be honest it's just comes
off the easiest I've seen from the oil
slick pad and I like the way it
insulates the Heat and allows me to
really press with more pressure and more
heat than I would nor normally be able
to do with just parchment or the uh
slick sheet yep yeah very good well I
think uh that's it for now we're going
to go eat some delicious food and uh
continue on puffing our brains out
always a pleasure having d420 K come
down always a pleasure to be here
brother and I'm sure we're going to be
uh we're going to be seeing you again
sooner than later yes summer time's
coming we're going to Springs here I'll
be riding my bike now watch Wicked yeah
got to get the bikes insured and uh I'll
be joining in on a lot of that fun too
so yes thank you guys for watching
Bubble man's world and uh we'll see you
soon peace peace
[Music]