[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
it is indeed puff Wednesday but before
we get started with puff Wednesday we've
been called out we've been called out
and not to make a batch of full melt
fresh Frozen bubble hash even though we
have ice and water even normally I if I
have ice and water in my hand I'm making
hash guys it's true this is a terrible
waste of ice but it is it is for a
really good cause for an amazing cause I
did a little bit of research on ALS
today I'm going to put into to the
comments of this video where you
yourself can donate we are going to call
three of our friends out yes we are
we're calling out well we're going to
start off right now with um Urban Remo
Urban grower Remo we call you out we
also call Matt the great Gardener out oh
and and finally last but certainly not
least DK d420 K we're calling you out
for the ALS challenge John and I are
going to do this we got the ice in the
water oh wow we have would you like to
dump one on my head first you know
what see you know what I'm taking it are
you taking it I'm taking it joh I don't
know if iing like even pick this one up
I'm taking it give it to me
it full
bag here we go one for Johnny
B now it's time for denail
rips the best way that's nice that was
nice that was nice it's refreshing it
cleans your hair up
magnificently wow all right so soaked as
I am I think I'm going to get a rip here
without too much fail Johnny
B I would also look into canabo therapy
for any one of you that has been
diagnosed with ALS I don't know much
about the the combination of the two but
I sure know that canabo phyto canabo
seem to sure do a lot of good for a lot
of people I guarantee it's going to help
you in some way or another alleviate
pain help you [ __ ] better who knows but
uh it's guarantee you're going to help
you all right guys that was our
challenge we hope the guys we called out
you have 24 hours 24 hours guys peace
peace well that was fun