[Music]
please oh my god but this isn't fun oh
my god I [ __ ] cannot believe it holy
[ __ ] this is [ __ ] up
with my detailed exposed
Oh
[Music]
oh I could just cry I could just hey
guys welcome to bubble man's world and
welcome to I'm Saddam I'm here at the
hotel crowds in the Polsky in my room on
the main canal here and just really just
super stoked to be here I'll tell ya I
got here I got a little excited I set
everything up I was ready to have a hit
with you guys and then I looked and I
realized I plugged in the D nail only
into a converter and not an actual power
like it doesn't convert the power it was
more like it changed the plug but it
didn't really change the power so this
has happened to me many many many times
and what happened is that boots this
whip so I pushed this whip and I boots
this bowl because it works with that
bowl so this bowl again is fine it just
needs to get another perfect sized whip
for it how ever the guys at D nail have
sent me this other whip with a much
smaller hole and a much smaller bowl so
it's a little smaller of a bowl than I'm
used to hitting off of but I gotta tell
you to have something as opposed to
nothing is huge so I'm very happy got
some beautiful sweets junk dry sift here
that's just ready to pop and good
cannabis cup I've already been in touch
with Gendo and Mike and they're
hopefully gonna hook up with us a little
later on today I'm waiting for Tony Tony
will be arriving in a couple of hours
and I might just go head on over to
skunk man Sam's house he's hanging out
with Robin canal Clark and I think that
it would be nice for me to go over there
and pop some bowls I highly doubt it
that they're gonna let me pull the
camera out but if they do I will
absolutely get a little quote from each
one of them skunk man sounds very very
non camera friendly so it's very
unlikely but we're all by Betty gives me
a little bit of an interview so kick
space to stay tuned for that on bubble
man's world and for now let's have a
riff
well I am in a non-smoking room so I
probably will blow this outside why
don't I show you guys what's going on
out there so we got a little bit of
construction happen in here they're
working on the canal down in front of
the place you can see they've got a
little bit of a thing set up right up in
front of the bulldog
and just down that way see the building
with the green awning
that is the world-famous greenhouse
where you'll see Franco and Arion and
the rest of the greenhouse crew so
Amsterdam in a nutshell is a really cool
place it's nice to arrive on a day with
a little bit of blue sky no rain and a
really nice warm temperature it's got to
be 10 or 11 degrees Celsius right now
it's unfortunate that there's a little
bit of noise out there but we can close
that off in a hurry and in the morning
for me right now for and just really
stoked to have you guys here the
cannabis cup with me in Amsterdam
probably gonna have one more rip I'm not
sure if I'm gonna wait for Tony I'm not
sure if I'm gonna go hook up with Jen
and Mike I'm probably gonna end up just
jumping in a cab and going and seeing my
good buddies Rob and and skunk man and
so this is it man this is the start of
the cannabis cup you guys are gonna see
a ton of cool [ __ ] this trip I promise
you I'm gonna get some great interviews
and I'm gonna make a point on just
having a lot of fun as we always do so
stay tuned to bubble man's world and
we'll see you soon the tattoo thing hey
guys welcome to bow man's world don't
worry Tony you can keep talking I'm not
interrupting keep talking about Angie
these guys are talking right now and I
thought I would bring you guys in
because it was a great conversation and
if you guys want to go around and
introduce yourselves you guys just got
in the Gold Coast just walked in the in
the door and introduce yourselves go
around and tell us a little bit about
yourself for bubbleman's world
hell yeah and you guys got some entries
this year we do and what's what's going
in into the Cup this year from Gold
Coast we have some flowers are they
mentionable yeah we have a Crockett came
around speaking at EC labs Toni was just
talking about how he tasted all the
different oh geez and the flavors and
the taste
I mean Toni's high on [ __ ] taste right
now and it's really great that he is
because because of it he's got these
incredible pure terpenes and he's
extracted off the plants and instead of
just hitting full you know pure dabs of
dry sifter wet wash we're finding that
sometimes he'll mix the terpenes in with
the hash with a little technique that
he's got and other times he'll just drop
it right on the on the dapper right
after you've hit your your hash kind of
juicer like a chaser interpretations
that seems to be the best way it happens
to be really a great way so let's keep
going around we're at Brandon Brandon
Brandon sorry tripping so you did when
was this this was this is a recent piece
right I have it's brand new Rob's never
about fast pictures of these things
social media I haven't seen a that comes
in three pieces hold on and so what do
we this is a seriously that I would
guess extremely valuable piece of glass
I'm shaking holding it thirty and forty
thousand dollar pieces and he's like
this and it's like then he leaves he's
like a few left repeat they left they
left an ftk at my house one time a real
big one like this Big Lots lime green a
flying saucer all the mothership perks
it's got the bad egg which is just a
straight and then it's got no it's
actually blown out and then it's got the
torus and then the flying as well so
completely ridiculous piece much like
the one you brought I say we do a
session with that yeah are you love the
thing about quartz is this is hot as
[ __ ] like half an inch above my fingers
but you can always pull it out no
problem like the way quartz dissipates
heat this isn't hot this is like
brand-new hot yeah this is not
actually you can't do it with less you
don't this was a glass bowl it would be
hot right there fingers describe your
fingers I can even feel the heat as this
finger climbs I'd say right here is
where it's really quite hot I can touch
here I'm excited bro so so weird oh yeah
James James you were the first you you
two were the first students I met and I
met them via heady heads which is your
brother and I've never actually met
Haddie but I I saw him come across I
think it was through Instagram and
immediately it's interesting how you can
find out the quality for via the quality
it's like if you have this following
generally wizard throws that all into
disarray because he's not really the
highest quality deeply not having ever
met your brother I believe he's a pretty
high quality dude because when I saw
those photos right away I was like sure
hope he does man really like the
palpable in his hash and I'd love to
know I wish he was here the session like
this which is pretty much every session
that we have had since we've been here
quality folks pure Terps and then
because he threw that around the other
day and people like Tony also extracted
pure anthocyanins which is the color
that climbs up the capitate stalks and
the glandular trichomes when you've seen
my macro photographs many of you asked
over the years what is that purple color
that's anthocyanin and it's an
antioxidant and Tony has also extracted
a pure form of that so I'll take a
picture of it with the Mack macro camera
so you guys can see it plus we want to
see this under the macro be interesting
hey we do that in a few minutes once we
start it look like fiber stop filming so
what can you say we should with the
sweet face triceps for sure oh so Kay's
terpene no numbers first
okay just sweet sustainable person you
don't want to stain the bone see that
sometimes strip teams can do that we
were talking about them my body stains
Matt but I never eat Angie
Jilly and Callie oh all very citrusy and
order smelly and that's why if you keep
drying it out of my mother ship right
now it basically tastes like that Julie
I told them I told a hint of coffee I
said I said you know the tansy is kind
of like the in spinal tap where you like
the guys talking about his skin
yeah you're like alright man alright man
I know it goes to 11
alright I know it's loud I know it's
louder than anyone else again but after
after 11:00 after that's the best then
let's talk about 1090 you know because
of the TNT sellout it's like everyone
tries to compared to those like you
can't it's an 11 it's my pain somebody
Cup teams everything barb is around it
Barb's around the ten ten point five
when it's full Malcolm Deborah and I've
only ever made it from seed crops
so it's seeded barb if he's just got so
much of he cures it four weeks to a
month plus before he even does like this
a shake and then he'll collect like a
half pound full bag of barb like just a
big giant bag of yellow pollen it's it
gets incredible and keep that for like a
month or two and then get his means
three little bottles or three big pumps
or maybe one big pile kind of a medium
pile in a really small pile which is
generally the pilot most of us with one
we never hit the big it just never works
like that I wish it did but you're
dealing with things like well terpenes
are so different
Kirra glandular trichomes even the other
side there's such small amounts of this
when you look at this you have to
imagine how this is probably from
several planets or one huge giant planet
just a tiny little like half gram of
that decided small amounts of these
things so who's next up on the shoot
these guys literally just flew in so but
probably in the situation that Tony and
I were in yesterday although it's hard
to say who the server we puffed
yesterday I mean we've had tough but
those guys puff toffee love to star
yesterday
yesterday yesterday so this is basically
what we're going to be doing a ton of I
want to invite you guys into some of
these sessions with some of these heady
folks that we hang out with I mean I'm
not even surprised that Brett when I
first saw Brendan I've seen him for
years but not really like connected with
it but always known him to have some
sick piece of glass I met you we talked
last year at the only show at the marce
Marcel and Deline and we did a damn
crane you had I took photos of Artie
Reese's you had you had a mummy
money shot I got or your money was
literally the whole cup that was the one
shot that I was like that's our
hysterics done I framed it right and the
piece looks so [ __ ] like gangster
yeah capture that trip yeah really for
me - that is my last year Canada stuff
and you might have even had it in the
yellow Pelican case orange hard to
remember these things but that's pretty
good
can't remember the guys name worship all
right you just hit
yeah let's crack the window fishing if
we set off a fire alarm here in
Amsterdam we're looking at about a five
thousand dollar euro 5,000 euro feed so
if the fire department gets dispatched
that happened three minutes of the alarm
going off so to do that and here's the
neat thing about this week's a crisis
although it doesn't mean somewhat of a
Reese's really anxieties for me but for
some that get a little bit of it it's
not really what I would consider strong
resin it's it's like happier resin
sativa it's uplifting it's definitely
pays its sweet taste but when you get a
rocker like what he just took you can't
really almost feel like it racy and it
really is straight-up especially did you
just get off your plate
oh my god you don't even want to puff
much else other than this today
maybe a little coffee jelly bean
all right I'm getting in there
definitely one of those pipes that's
really no need to pick it up you go to
it it's actually it's amazing too
I can actually taste that better than I
could the mothership maybe just because
it's brand new as well it's small that's
why the taste is really
oh good was that taste the full drives
it yeah you get this you get that spicy
and was honest with you no well yeah
thank you Peter in yes for this piece
always shut up to glassblowers worldwide
especially for guys like this that take
it to a level of quality that is equal
to the level of quality that these
hashes are also at or you could call it
a standard if you don't like the word
quality if it implies that you know oh I
don't like the idea of implying that
you're better and that's worse no
problem then just call it a standard we
all deserve the highest standards don't
we that is no and that's like that's a
that's a quality of standard that I can
get behind
yeah that sweet skunk deals with in
cases like that
yeah you can't own a piece like that
without a Pelle I got your actually
carved it out
[Music]
you having dish that goes with it
because when you have a heavy piece you
might as well what did he carve the
titanium - yeah oh my god yes oh wow
that's that's good I love that the
d-mail whip goes with it like the green
coming off of the sneaker is too small I
can probably get a custom all
that was
everything so if a piece like this were
to go on the market not that it would
but there's a where on the market it
would sell for thousands of dollars make
thousands of dollars come on come on
come on
you know because here's the here's the
North American people always I've only
hit two of these sneakers before it was
at the Toronto champs show and then this
dude had both of them he had one for him
and his girl had one actually I think it
was Johnny Blaze money I just mentioned
this too right away and start
percolating you know and he's like good
Evy and I was like just it needs its
recurring on draw a the same way it's
perking out the Swiss perk yeah you keep
you poking down yeah perks like that and
so that's what it's doing that you put
that one is yours so it's literally
parking all the way there and then
clears in Junior I think that's what
it's doing it has to be
oh my goodness pure haze terpenes
and I love that with Tony in the
background then James dude I'm so glad
that of all the people that could come
up here was you guys today this morning
like perfect nice quiet session super
handy pipe and pure terms from Tony V
we'll be back guys peace
[Music]
there you go whenever you look over at
me he's like Cameron Angelucci okay I'm
gonna go do one quick tour of the DNA
shop here let's see if we can get a
better light on there there we go
there's the salt Cola that's an oldie
it's got to be going back close to ten
years alright so we're at the DNA shop
I've known these cats for about 15 years
maybe maybe 13 years I met them at the
first can of his cup about 10 or 11
years ago in the herb industry DNA
clothing
[Music]
hey see you later thank you have a good
one Simon dnase trophies no shortage of
trophies these cats got alright it's
time to go hit some Hells Angels oh gee
thank you sorry have a good one
[Music]
it's nicer be good now
that was tasty really tasty hittin dabs
back back backstage I guess up a DNA
show
[Music]
it tastes like the Arnold Palmer but if
you had strawberry Arnold Palmer
it's a calamity
there we go savvy Tony and orange hooked
up with these guys at DNA and Tony of
course has the tert melt out he just
sort of made a fresh batch and to hold
that up we're gonna mingle and I'll get
under it got a good press test looks
great we've hit it under the macro lens
now it's about to having someone out
with it or Duncan and this is what Tony
made this was the original product I'm
guessing this is from Chibs from the
Meltz yeah
well it kind of looks like a crazy face
this piece of hash right here see that
in the camera with an open mouth hold on
over here we have some cookies Thin Mint
cookies that the Gold Coast extra
extract guys brought by took those to
the shots of those with the macro lens
as well make sure we share those you
ready for a dunk there Tony
yeah get it under the light
[Music]
down okay turn the fan on point about
the window it'll be fine this is art
this is art keep hitting it smoking
still and that's what's going into the
sky right now God there we go beautiful
all right it does look pretty smoky up
there but I guess we'll see you soon
this is possible that was my favorite
part as fast as possible as fast as
possible maybe a smaller dab for the
apartment well I try to go with a little
tiny ball oh really
yeah it looks pretty big when I saw you
drop it in that's a big pile and break
it in half
it looks more sure I just go with what I
read like really need to get re and I
have a pretty high tolerance I can take
you jabs all day long a little bit what
I found was that that yeah exactly can I
feel it that's that's good that's good
right there I'll have to attach it back
onto there now
you're still gonna hit good though and
big so you might as well get this ready
there we go Hotel puffin in Amsterdam
why are we being so freaky because of
5,000 euro fine blown up and kicked out
of the hotel but I think we're gonna be
good
that was a fine sized hit much
reasonable I'll either
in Spanish
you'd be surprised what this looks like
if I pressed it up like that with the
heat and this I will know something I
better move it you'll be gonna look very
much like this not direct see even that
was a little ball I just took and then
what I do is I did this and so now
that's that's really a little bit too
big for me like I just I could take it
all day long but not to take it
perfectly walk over to the window I said
my cup yeah yeah don't need to get
[ __ ] you just need just enough and
that's still a pretty big big head and
that was half a small ball
I wanted you to see what the citrix it's
like it's it rates better pretty orange
banner it's a nice
[Music]
well that boats get ready to go out it's
got a bunch of people there all got
their keys and [ __ ] on candles
[Music]