[Music]
hey guys bubble man here at the noon
coffee shop just down the street from
the LI of plane with Tony V and some
other folks that we just met how'd you
like that turt melt that's some good
[ __ ] right is yeah dude coffee shop noon
come check us out we're here with bird
got jelle and Mike I think giddy's over
there somewhere everyone's in the house
so anyway the Cannabis Cup has not been
cancelled it just has been cancelled so
don't worry about a thing exist in the
hearts of the people man exactly giddy
knows so if you see any one of us in the
streets here in Amsterdam please come on
over and smoke a dab with us coffee shop
noon
peace
he