[Music]
all right guys bubble man and John B we
just cleared we just cleared Customs or
not Customs security it's Customs isn't
it and uh we're about to catch the 420
flight yeah uh to Amsterdam Cannabis Cup
so we'll probably see you guys on the
plane but we will definitely see you in
Amsterdam SO waiting for my cart too all
right we're waiting for John's cart
right now so maybe we'll give a little
bit of footage from the cart they're
coming to give us a ride um apparently
they're bringing us bongs and hash and
uh going to take us all the way to the
end because we're in like gate 53 you
got to go to gate 78 right so all right
well let see how it works we'll catch
you guys
soon all right bubble man and John B we
are now on our flight Flight 682 to
Amsterdam departing at 420 what's the
best time of is we're pretty excited I
know but you know this time at 420 I
can't puff so well but we're all meded
out and we've uh had many many trippy
sticks uh outside at the airport so
we'll be landing in Amsterdam we'll be
going right to the hotel and setting up
the Dil and uh yeah we'll show you a
little bit of of the flight try to show
you a little bit of what's going on
outside and of course when we land at
shiple International we'll show you a
little bit there and uh otherwise have a
good flight John
you have a good fun too all right see
you guys
soon
it's all prophecy everything that's
happening now it's all prophecy
earthquakes acid clouds it's all
prophecy New World ERS in town it's all
prophecy soon be going down prophecy
feel time speeding up it's all prophecy
Warfare bleeding up it's on Prophecy
weapons of mass destruction it's on
Prophecy going back away we come
[Music]
excellent what it is this thing here St
your dream oh I just found something
thank you you I was having
problem yes Taxi's over
here yeah but the the que's up here okay
well we'll go I don't even care
he all
right okay we're both going the same
time no problem yeah that's
fine putting on a jacket real soon I'll
tell you that much I
got come on should be a SPL at
least all right so
John and I have officially landed in
Amsterdam and uh we're going to jump in
a cab head to our hotel and see if we
can't set up a little session here ASAP
talk to you soon what's up bubble man
here we just uh John and I are finally
arrived in Amsterdam and we've been uh
we bumped into Karma
genetics yeah yeah so we're uh we're
going to pull out the denail we've uh
we're going to pop on some we got the
Dil here we got the mother ship in the
house put that right next to the sheld
in Black look at that very nice very
nice nice and let's see what else we
have in the house here somewhere that
bubble that we just we ended up with a
little bit of bubble oh a little bit of
bubble nice St so we're going to set the
Dil up and we're going to do a couple of
a couple of dabs all right so uh we had
to split karmas we got to do one quick
dab and we had to split karmas John got
some birthday weed I think he gave him
some uh Karma OG some uh what else we
got we got headband headband Karma OG
and another one he said is a new one
he's trying anyway we're going to go get
our phones taken care of right now we're
just walking up by uh Central Station
and uh yeah just walking by kiwi gifts
Central Station over there good old
Amsterdam nicely baked we'll have a
session soon hey bubble man here we're
just getting to our apartment and uh
we're about to walk walk right in right
now let's check it out hey John how's it
going pretty damn good all right we just
checking out the surprise should we set
up that Dil well I was actually I jumped
the
gun all right here we go here we go so
we got the mother ship in the
house we got the electric nail in the
house use the tie nail for now cuz my
quartz is on the
way
give him a little view of our Canal
right out backing out into the red light
district you can see the Bulldog right
there and down this way we
have the
greenhouse so we're pretty
stoked all right so we got the denail
set up but it's important when you're
puffing in Amsterdam to not set off any
fire alarms especially in some pretty
fancy hotels so what we're going to do
is we're going to go over to the
bathroom
here and we're going to look
through that's the one that's the one we
want and what do we want it for I'm
about to show you I know someone who got
a $200 fine for leaving that on you
don't want to get a major fine but we're
going to put this up right here
we don't need yeah that guy we don't
need no trouble and look you can still
see the
plastic from the last guy that covered
it
up here all right
so I'm going to open this
[Music]
up shower C
okay WRA
[Music]
tiing a not we've done this before just
tuck it in y cover it up perfect that's
going to ensure that we don't get any
fines while we're puffing tough here in
Amsterdam we got a great room right on
the
canal Bulldog right outside we got
beautiful swans sitting right out in
front of the canal and the greenhouse
just across the way so uh let's get that
Dil going shall we all right so the Dil
is climbing 420 and going
up got the mothership here we want to be
fre little bit of
some
[Music]
OG did you just grab it that's fine oh
God you brought the exact all right so
we got John B here Mr 42 years old right
now got A 42-year-old dab for you well
we're just starting with the mini dab
well yeah we don't we're not you know
we're not trying to prove anything where
hit that D
there so
tasty so
awesome think turn yeah all right I'll
do one
[Music]
I like that thing's working quite
well I think the best thing about the
dino is this I'm just getting right back
in
there
together
and if you're done I'll hit
it all right one more rip for the road
here we're going to go out and I don't
know if we're going to go bump into DNA
or un Rico or who but here I hitting the
mother ship with Noble how's this for
Bubble Man styles yeah just uh just a
screen time to rip
I love Amsterdam stay tuned for more
Cannabis Cup