[Music]
hey what's going on guys bubble man here
at the 27th annual Cannabis Cup and it
looks as though we have lost another
venue it's all good no
reaction think about
this [ __ ] buets BR I
mean from Delta 9 is an
event I'm happy that they left me off
the floor plane I feel really bad for my
friends that put a lot of time and money
in their head stash I almost sh a te to
my colleague s on the phone yesterday
because this is nonsense and it's not
fair and it should be a proper event
should be like the Dao last night eating
together smoking together laughing
together it was an amazing event and
that's what I consider a cannabis event
yeah this is is unbelievable I got
thousand thousand in Flyers myself dude
I'm thinking just sitting in this room
is like €100,000 in booths this is
nonsense I feel sorry for have reimburse
people on this too well you know what
it's going to be okay it's going to be
okay we're going to we're going to
figure it out we have lost another venue
but we'll figure it out we're going to
figure it out we're here on Bubble man's
world who we
we with
Jazelle and Mike Mike and Jazelle are in
the house and over across the way who's
that why that's giddy up getting a
massage and I think I see Tony inside
the noon somewhere uhhuh anyway we're
going to head over there puff some bowls
what's up guys I'm a big fan of you dude
look at this I just met some big fans
right on guys from France
[Music]
ah you know what I'm telling you come
with me and smoke some hash right
now all right we're grabbing these
French guys and they're coming to puff
we got the friends we got friends we
come to the noon the noon is is right
here we you see blue okay okay okay see
you later and we come right on okay cool
guys all right heading up to the noon
here get up what's going on I know
what's going on it's what's going
down birdie birdie the corner are we
allowed in here come on in is this our
spot can I have a dil plug and a
computer and a camera and everything
this home home
home
ielle the flesh it's a
bubble times for people on the street in
fact one lady told me her mom's dying
and we have to get her hat so she can
make I told her I kind of went in about
how upsetting it is that everyone's so
worried about winning a contest and they
all want to enter this contest so they
can win this cup that means nothing and
in the meantime this lady's here from
England and her mom's dying of
pancreatic cancer and she's trying to
find Rick
Simpson's and I'm just like man like my
friends just gave like 60 G of the
nicest [ __ ] cash on the planet to
High Times to smoke do whatever they
please with in the meantime This Woman's
mom is dying of pancreatic cancer I told
her I'd get her some hash and help her
make some I have some of the other stuff
yeah I was just going to grab some from
Buddy and just make a little coconut oil
for she's got to go back to England so
she can't bring the Hat
drops pancreatic cancer stage four
well I think she needs a grand of B
every day
actually all right so I'm going to come
sit with you
[Music]
there so you just did a frosted
FL yeah I thought
so oh three full coughs too that was a
rip dude make sure his secondary coughed
all those hits
out none for
you thumbs up
[Music]
so ready all right this is preash church
Johnny B just walked in the
door Tony V's got got the hit giddy's
got Johnny's back s's in the house in
the
house all right give him a huge one I
got a big one for me he's going to be
like cough I threw my back out he's
lying on the floor for the rest of the
Cannabis Cup I got it all on tap I feel
like the whole this got stormed in do
your PR breathing John prama
breathing y Yama
prama prama breathing John's done yoga
every day hot yoga for 18 days in a row
nice wow beam wow 19 20 21 22 22 days 22
days nice
dude good for John then took my
birthday actually I was doing yoga at
the concert and they were doing I was
doing this go he's doing he's doing
yoga at the mle crew
concert like that's a good way to get
beat
up all right pre- Church dabs done
[Music]