[Music]
hey there's Todd I'm here with Todd
McCormick on the top floor of the I
guess this is sensey seeds Sedum Museum
150 what's the name of this
Street I don't know proun it me neither
but we'll show them anyway so this is
the beautiful street that the Sensei
seed museum is on there's their sign
right there Ben droners and the droners
family have these beautiful museums one
in Barcelona and one in Amsterdam they
used to have the seed shop I'm not sure
they still do that probably Johnny B in
the house DB FL good to see you boys
good to see you to good to see you kitty
hey that chair may be taken all I'll
give it up in just a second after a dab
G G's taking a
dab no I don't want dab he doesn't want
no tur
melt I'll give it to him on that other
pipe what's up Robbie all good and you
excellent excellent in the land of
prohibition yes m w that's weird today
we will watch some Weir the
inductions today we have Mark Emery and
Howard mark Mr Nice getting inducted
into what would you guys say that he
that they're being inducted into here
the Cannabis culture Awards the Cannabis
culture Awards two uh two members that
are welld deserving so we'll be catching
that in a little bit I'll try to film as
much of it as I can hopefully Dane's
going to lend me his tripod otherwise I
got to hold it the whole time we'll see
what he says your camera's smaller hey
guys bubble man here and I am at the uh
sensey seeds Hemp Museum uh here in the
center of Amsterdam and here's green
Pete hey hey hey it's the weed Pete I
like weed Pete weed Pete weed Pete
grower Pete and processor Pete and hash
maker
Pete I only am a customer of the product
ah okay perfect customer Pete anyway
that uh right there was a little thing
called Cent Claus and here in Amsterdam
they have Center Claus they usually have
black Pete which I personally find a
little bit offensive I like weed Pete
much better so we're here at the Sens
seeds weed and Hemp Museum and we're
about to watch Mark Emy and Howard marks
get inducted into the Cannabis culture
Hall of Fame you can see right here
cannabis culture Awards there's Howard
Mr Nice and my good friend Mark emry and
Jody Emery from my hometown in Vancouver
so we're going to see them Mr Rob look
at that come on Mr Robert conell Clark
is in the house today for the one right
isn't this cool we're going to see
Howard and Mark get inducted it I like
it all you Canadian folks out there you
can be proud one of your Pioneers is
here exactly well we'll talk to you a
little bit later when we're inside I'll
let you get to what you want to do I was
following a beautiful woman somewhere oh
my God it happens officer Qui follow her
all
right anyway we're going to head in here
real soon so uh why don't you come with
[Music]
me ladies and gentl Ladies and Gentlemen
let's go to find I would like to invite
everyone which is not going to be on
stage so I'm excluding the winners
obviously I would like you to slowly but
surely make your way towards the gallery
so we can have a the program will then
start so thank you very much
see you
brother I'm going to go yeah I've been
here a while I think we we just got told
now to come here and we were with
everyone Mark
andk yeah so Howard's here too so that
you see Allan now this is it
[Music]
a
we're going to do first part of the
Mommy and then
[Music]
we
Robin Robin
[Music]
feedb use I'll oh maybe I'll when I sit
down yeah hello welcome to the Cannabis
Cup Awards
culture that's because you just told me
about can cup or the high can cup sorry
can culture Awards
2014 uh it is a incredible moment by the
way this ceremony is somehow a bit um
interrupted will be interrupted later on
because one of our guests and nominees
is a bit late because of well problems
with the price this is going to be
recorded right yes so um you may applaud
or not and
um my name is Michael M in dut can you
lower the mic a little bit CU I have
incredible uh kind of
singing around in my head
not um I'm a televis director or program
maker so speak for Dutch Nation public
television uh station called VPR
broadcaster uh I'm not a uh show host uh
and I'm not a presenter it's not
something I do on a regular basis so
please uh pardon me if I make
somehow yeah we'll see um
to my left I don't know if he needs an
introduction Mr drunkers
Mr Mr sens Mr H H marijana Museum Mr
actually also uh maybe the one who came
up with the price or invented it
yes well creative uh no what am I I
thought it was necessary yes uh
necessary why was itary by the way can
you please lower the mic a little bit
because there is really it feels like
I'm in a
bathroom thank
you no no but it's uh you know
can something like she have the museum
nearly 30 years and I see only in my
vision that museum will exist another
couple of hundred years and on that
moment I had a few people that I really
admire and everybody got that right
especially how how thing what we doing
as activists as people who love the pl
and we love cannabis and we see the
source the users of it uh I thought you
know there should be something to
remember in the future and a few
people that I really you know what yeah
we're going to see this very soon
because we have the story actually for
you uh well edited all right coming up
very soon okay uh next to Mr drers is
his daughter Shiva who go actually also
called Dr as well and next she's uh one
of the
um she called herself yesterday Al made
Amer but let's let's do this way she
runs the place sort of kind okay uh next
to her is brother Alan uh who goes by
the name the professor of whatever he
the green the green stuff uh apparently
he has a lot of knowledge on plans uh
work very for a long time here
right yes you don't deny that you grew
up green
[Music]
um yeah yeah he fell in the PO in the he
fell in the PO uh welcome from Tha uh
from Thailand all the way from Thailand
L um and then to my right oh no wait
let's go that Tom mccor who was actually
once winner of
the it's true right that
true how did that to you it's an honor
to be here you know I first came here 20
years ago and was one of the first group
of people that walked into the canvas
Castle when then opened it up to the
public and was inspired forever this was
a castle in the South somewhere in the
South Nas right yeah sort of paradise
for an American coming out from the drug
war it was Paradise it was a dream to
have a basement full of cannabis and a
beautiful farm and yes so and the
education is a huge part of it and to be
part of this Museum and part of what
we're doing which is educating everybody
to the wonders of the plant is very
honorable so it's great to be here
fantastic and then we
have maybe it's sound almost cliche
right like you called prince the prince
and princess of pot is
that the prince and pot and I just kind
of got princess along the
way so you married a prince yes yes I
did and and it's also true maybe all of
you know that you just you're a free man
you just moved out of uh jail yes Rec
right got out of US federal prison on
August
[Music]
12th and I blame Ben Dron
that oh because he got up in this very
spot in this very town on this very day
20 years ago and boasted in his calm
smug way that he had planted millions
and millions of and plants around the
world through his service at sensey
seeds and that this was creating
disturbances and revolutions and changes
of opinion and heart and politics
everywhere in the world and I was so
inspired by that I got up and I said I'm
going to do just like
him I'm going to do just like I'm going
to go home and I'm going to do that for
all of North America and I did do that
and so it's his
fault
heavly we're also very happy uh to could
could could the mic at least uh of Mark
and myself lit well everything a bit low
yeah thank you um uh we are also uh very
uh grateful that Mr sky is here Dan sky
from and now let me put it this way the
High Times Cannabis Cup which is
actually a which has not so much to do
with you at all
amazing
that
first May Restaurant came over $600 to
start the Canabis C and we did it with
case hooker famous uh artist from from
Amsterdam who for
one so these guys they they started the
Cannabis C and okay so you're guilty by
association was yes okay fair enough I
propose by the way so it's a bit the
program is a bit shaky because uh our uh
lost guest Mr Nice I guess everybody
knows any kind of sort of is a bit late
because what what was the reason his
flight got canell flight got cancelled
another flight he was not allowed board
another flight well something like that
he's coming he's in the a he's in here
high
iny right so I propose let's roll a
video
now maybe lower the
light to discover the
world and eased her
pain it gave him the insights
and he fights for worldwide
acceptance this material has been
essential over ages and has enormous
strength it's for Animal
Care and creates conscious
fashion you can even use it for a
durable
future no wonder this influential plant
has its own
award this man won it for his Clear
Vision he won it for his responsive
politics this night won it for his
Global Crusade his research gave the
plant its history a freethinking
politician like all our winners being
brave persistent being
true for the acceptance of cannabis in
all its forms they marked the future
cannabis culture Awards Mark the
future proudly presented by the hash
marijuana and Hemp Museum
yeah now maybe it is time to get a bit
more serious because apparently as far
as I'm aware somehow I have the
impression that around the world we see
more and more places or States at least
the United States where uh U at least
some kind of legalization uh takes
place uh I don't know officially in
Canada it is October 19 2015 is
legalization day in I guarantee ital
election want to support support cation
yes which is the GRE part or the LI
Party of Canada now the Liberal Party of
Canada Liberal Party which has governed
our nation for most of its
history um but let's get more serious
because funny enough or strange enough
or tragically enough in this lovely
little uh country this Delta somehow
things are changing or we feel sort of I
don't know if you can call it clam down
what is what is
cooking you know it's
unexplainable like everybody
most experts you can't explain it it is
so DB or up but what's
happening well it's they they they try
to turn the backwards they say well we
should get rid of the coffee shops get
this and that and they come with a we
you know that everybody sort of card
that you allow
[Music]
problem you
know
so again sound kind of
weird yes you're right kind
[Music]
ofro like
again can you still hear us the you put
the
sound can you hear us
listen guys can you hear us lower you
don't hear us you can hear ler yes it go
down because it's it's good thing I'm
too stoned to
K hey by the way by the way uh please uh
don't by team
profession
um and also by the way maybe I can ask
you I can ask you get you the mic
where's the mic
uh apparently maybe you can inform us Mr
Sky maybe you can inform us maybe you
can inform us of the troubles that you
were facing
oh I to sit down yeah so much better on
my
feet anyway let me just talk for for a
few few minutes here sit down I'll sit
down whatever too tall for the cameras I
guess anyway um listen my name is Dan
sky for the magazine but Ben droner is
here he knows me as Bal McKinnon I came
here in 1996 with hemp Times magazine
and uh we I this is when I the first
time I interviewed uh Ben so that's why
I changed my name because I was working
for both magazines simultaneously so I
my name is Malcolm all the Dutch people
know me as Malcolm and all the Americans
know me by my by my fake name so
congratulations you know who
are anyway this has been a this has been
a wild week um you know the Dutch coffee
shop industry is who we depend on and
they have been incredibly uh sympathetic
and Incredibly supportive and they're
appalled by what has gone down here and
I have to correct some information here
the fact is we have been coming here 26
years we get our permits in order we
don't go anywhere whether it's LA or
whether it's San Francisco or Denver
without dealing with the local
authorities this is what we have done we
have dealt with the authorities all the
all the way along we had Dutch lawyers
dealing dealing with the mayor's office
and in the end he shut us down there's
been some misinformation out there that
we needed a permit that is incorrect the
mayor was threatening the permits of the
venues that we were trying to enter okay
it is simple as that they targeted the
Cannabis Cup after 26 years and shut
down the Expo part which is the industry
the people who are supporting the
Pioneers the real Rebels who are out
there on the front lines every day not
the activists the people who are in
business because their lives are at
stake other people's jobs are at stake
so this is a chance for the Cannabis
Community to network for the public to
meet the merchandisers the people to
meet the companies and it's been shut
down and we're appalled you know the
fact is what Ben said before we're
moving backwards here in Holland and I
say we because my roots are here too
that's where the Cannabis Cup roots are
and SK and in the United States we're
making tremendous progress we have
cannabis cups now six times a year and
every yes go ahead
uh if this if this will be the same next
year could it mean that you will leave
the Netherlands and go I hope not as I
said the roots of the Cannabis Cup are
here in Amsterdam but I don't really
particularly I can't say that we
particularly feel welcome this week the
fact is you know on Sunday I was down
there after the cup you know blew apart
um I was down there in the you know in
the coffee shop district and all the
people are smoking and having a
wonderful time you know cannabis culture
is part of Dutch culture at this point
that's the truth
right and the fact of for for these two
old white men to say no we don't want
amdam to be known for that well the cat
wa wait do two white men two old white
mayor mayor and the Minister of Justice
all right thank you very much let's get
it out the open these guys are get rid
of these get out question question
question question one question just I
just wanted to ask why do you think they
are doing this this year I would like to
know that I would like to know why we've
been targeted this particular is there
anybody here who knows the answer why
the Dutch mayor
or some people say
because I know for a fact they use this
as an excuse many
times thank you very much
folks to your to to answer your question
I got to get going I got to go got
I know the excuse is the European Union
and there has been this
contract sort of that we are not we
cannot but one of our former winners uh
and and former prime minister of the
Netherlands already stated on the
Cannabis culture Awards in
2010 that it's
B but they do use it I have a theory our
movement is making enormous games in
many different places but our enemies
hate us they still hate us the and when
they're losing they'll fight back harder
just like we have to fight back harder
if we're losing so you know even though
we're making progress they're going to
fight back if they really want to and
some people in positions of authority
perhaps want to flex that muscle even if
they feel alone they feel like a warrior
just like many of our activists perhaps
down in South Africa feel alone so they
feel like a warrior for their cause so
I'm just floating that theory that maybe
this is one lone Guy s i ha what they're
doing then again then again though it
may be true and we have somebody here in
the a farmer he's now very famous yeah
you know maybe he wants to be a little
Prof today who is now in how we call
this uh because they and he was a a bona
fight Bona fight uh farmer grower uh so
things are changing then again we are
still kind of Liber liberal this country
I mean still we are sitting here you
know well this could be this could
happen in can to now or it could happen
in Vancouver or Toronto how much can you
have with you there your no legal amount
unless Fally allowed from the government
the tolerance is there could this happen
now in there are many events with a lot
of marijuana yes okay our journalist go
to probably several locations in Canada
where they have regular Canabis
expositions and judging Jo all day
parties but we also have a government
that has cracked down and has stopped
letting people and patients grow their
own PL so no they're not getting
licenses anymore nobody now can get a
license
that very soon I propose that we
although we know although we all know
who Ben is that we still there's a nice
little film short feature made about Ben
maybe we can saw that how do
you guys do you hear me what I'm
saying you
guys roll's cultural wordss are on
initiative with entrepreneur and
philanthropist Ben droners as a young
man in the the 1970s dras gradually
began what was to become a lifelong
quest to unlock the potential of the
cannabis plant and to improve the
quality of human life everywhere over
the years dras has founded and continues
to run various Canabis and hemp related
Enterprises feny seeds has become the
leading international seed bank and has
been setting the standard for decades
this cannabis Gene bank is responsible
for preserving medicinal grade cannabis
strains approved and sold by the Bureau
of medical cannabis an organization run
by the Dutch
government H flag established in the
mid90s is one of Europe's largest
producers and processors of industrial
hem the hash marijuana T Museum in
Amsterdam was opened in 1985 and
presents a permanent exhibition about
the history and uses of the cannabis
plant around the world the museum has
over 100,000 visitors a year last year
saw the grand opening of the hash
marijana canono and T Museum located in
the beautifully renovated moral Palace
in the Historical Center of
Barcelona since 2004 the museum confers
the Cannabis culture Awards upon those
who have distinguished themselves in the
struggle for acceptance of cannabis in
all of its
[Music]
forms as you mentioned earlier You Were
Somehow inspired by Ben right and I
believe that uh besides probably that it
is that was also profitable business you
both also had start a sort of
uh let's say polit not political or
activist uh uh view I believe it was you
I don't remember who it was who came
with the idea like we got to force
legalization by our seeds just by
spreading spreading the seeds all the
world well my phrasee plant the seeds of
Freedom overgrow the government and
overgrow is like a biological way
instead of overthrow which is a violent
way of changing the government against
their will and I thought they're not
going to come around to us
philosophically but we will force them
to bend to us and by doing so by having
my idea for me was that I wanted to be
the person that produc more marijuana in
Canada and the United States than the
police forces of both count could
destroy in the same but to one person
could undo the damage of all those
thousands of that was kind here too
right oh
[Music]
please world yeah
days and people who are in prison and
because they bought seeds in Amsterdam
in in a show and it is it is it is it
the seats or the system that's my
question is it me is it is it the seats
no you know the seats
are it's nature okay but we have to go
back pris because we are we have to go
we will talk about it seriously uh but
actually I'm I'm running out of schedule
already right I'm doing it I'm of
reverse reverse it's okay
well can you please explain us why you
have chosen I mean Trump has been
elected we'll talk to you very soon uh
why you have chosen um Mr so to
speak and uh Mark emry
joh yes what is that importance for the
for let's say the movement or for the
[Music]
like I said this is a a museum and in
the
museum it's about history and it's this
is the new history you know we are part
of a new history and it's not there's so
many people I would like to have in this
Museum it's all around here and there
know so many that they should be because
they find so long but some of them you
know they just come out of the heart and
if you ask me
they ask me who's the who's the
committee who decide who do this it's me
you I have to admit we don't have a
comedi I talk with Shiva and with Alan
but you know it's it's from the heart
and we follow you and you know what Mark
I don't know if you know it but we not
only talking we don't talk and we don't
just put money because we make money
with seeds and we put money there we do
and here my proud da you know she was in
the Canadian
embassy uh
protesting pregnant you know with with
with the belly in the front of the gate
protesting is it there is it there look
at it look at it look at
[Music]
it and it's in the it's an international
thing is the love I have with to the
love I have with fr and H the freze and
all these people and J har uh you know
all these people who win the prize they
like so you guys here my and I I just
feel it it's it's a feeling you know
it's a friendly Affair no no it's it's
it's a the whole uh legalization front
is a family that sense we just Li out
now we go to
otherwise no I find it quite
interesting Mr you he's wired he's wired
maybe lower the
volume pleas because
uh not so much that you are a strange
dck here but originally you you got into
coate with marijuana as a kid because
you were sick right yes so does that
mean that you are more let's say from
the the side of the medical Mar is that
where you originated from or you how you
start it most definitely when I was a
child I had cancer and my mother was
back in 1979 I was only 9 years old and
U my mom gave me some medical cannabis
uh she had read about it in Good
Housekeeping magazine which in America
is pretty pretty square and she was
sitting in a waiting room one day and
said she read about the therapeutic
effects of marijuana and she just
decided to try it because at that point
I had had T much nine times between ages
2 and 10 and my mother was just at at a
loss of things to do and and she decided
to talk to my doctor about it and he was
also at a point of feeling like there
wasn't much to lose because I had a
tumor in my soft in soft tissue between
my left lung and my heart and they
figured why not so we started using it
after I was going to
radi and it
was interesting interesting
interes enough uh quite recently I
believe two years ago something uh there
was a big story in United States um
child the sick child the parents they
tried to get marijuana in their state
was not allowed and they got contact
with these brothers
in Colorado and it became a big affair
because a journalist used to be anti or
swap during this it's true right what
you're speaking of is the CNN journalist
sanj gup he did a episode called lead
which I find mildly
offensive uh he he made a conversion he
actually wrote an editorial against
proposition 19 which was a ballad
initiative which would have legalized
cannabis in California and what they did
was somehow he tuned into what we would
been talking about for many a decade now
and had a real turnaround and he did a
CNN Special that was seen by very many
people and when this family saw it it
caused a lot of people to realize that
some of these children dealing with
intense seizure disorders are benefiting
from CBD now diol CBD everybody knows
who this is
oh and now there's been a refocus on
this because now they're starting to
look at children in these disorders if
you will and uh the children are pure
test subject when I was 9 years old I
had no politics I just wanted to feel
better and it helped how did you
that 20 years ago I walked off the boat
so to speak came on with Jack Jack her
wrote the book The
Emperor the emperor yeah yes and um
after he passed away I released the 12th
edition of his book because I've been an
editor of it since 1994 uh we redesigned
it in 1998 I grew the Lea that's on the
cover it's one
of um well we every time we would
republish the book we would recompile it
with updated information so every
edition of the book was reinvented if
you will So based on the history that we
knew and then trying to bring it current
with what was sh what what is your
current what your current my latest
project was called the culture High we
just released a film uh took 5 years to
work on Ben is featured in it guess
Richard Branson's in it Snoop Dog's in
it whz khif is in it Joe's in it where
can we see well Richard Branson launched
our trailer for us on his virgin blog
October 1st and we are worldwide on
Vimeo we we just hit three on iTunes in
the documentary Section 3 weeks
[Applause]
after and we were just accepted by the
Academy Award for potential
Oscar yeah we're not BBS
yeah no I'm not you can go look it up
you but it's true who's the director um
Brett Harvey is our director we also did
another movie called the culture I was
in prison for five years two oh so yeah
yeah yeah and when I got out of prison I
was just pissed off Mark so I decided to
produce very large educational events
movies and such by the way who has spent
most years in prison of all of you Mr
Mr he got the longest
okay please uh can we can we roll tape
please
for for
who can you please they want to know
what T which one the next one which is
Jo
the his name is Mark Emery and he's
called The Prince of P Mark Emory
founder of the BC marijuana party
publisher of cannabis Culture magazine
and lifelong
activist they say I'm responsible for
1.1 million My Hope Is fre the US versus
Mark
Emy get up and for
godamn let me assure you if you the
Canadian people allow me to be extrated
you will never see me alive again
[Music]
emry was jailed for 5 years for selling
marijuana scenes to American
customers first day of marijuana sales
by state government happen in the state
mer well adios
[Music]
how and how are you actually are you
Mark and I met 19 years ago when he came
to the canas cup was 95 your first cup
uh 9496 94 then yep then our first year
was 20 years together were you then
already also on the F of Med medical
marijuana were you already interested in
that field when I came here in 1994 it's
because in Canada in 199 when I started
there was nothing and I tried to find a
book that Todd later becomes involved
with the EM wears no clothes the 1990
Edition by Jack R who's probably my you
know one of the more profound influences
in my lifelong with Ben and some others
and this book was banned in Canada you
couldn't get and then I it was banned in
Canada and magazine was banned in Canada
everything about marijuana was no longer
allowed pipes bong we only have it home
M which is B
well
actually a up to
$100,000 to distribute a book about
Maryland or or a magazine so it had
scared everybody and no one anymore so
uh when I came here um it was after we
had broken this band and we had
reintroduced to Canada uh the books uh
by Jack rare the magazine High other GRS
by Rosen and then we brought back pipes
and bongs and gave it a political cover
and reintroduced everything and then
when I came here 20 years ago I was
inspired to add seeds because we needed
to raise millions of dollars to give it
away so subsequently for 10 years what
do you mean give it away we gave away
all our profit so we were able to give
$5 million to all these actors groups
and valid initiatives in the US
political parties we did everything we
sued the US federal government we paid
for valid initi signature drives we form
political parties and bro can we gave
money to the Israeli Green Leaf party
the New Zealand cannabis party any place
we could change theal system with our
money I was excited to do it I can't
believe to this day that a Canadian was
able to give money to get medical
Washington DC Colorado few and even
Arizona that same year that I was able
to use that money to get things on the
ball I thought that was just the most
awesome thing Happ
um during uh his imprisonment uh you
more or less well I don't know to go you
already like you kind of uh became the
uh spokesperson such maybe 10 years ago
and moved to Vancouver and got involved
with Mark and then the year following in
2005 is when the US government came into
Canada and had him arrested at facing 30
years mandatory minimum to life in US
prison he accepted the 5-year plea deal
um I hope you understand why I wouldn't
let him take longer one but uh in his
absence yes I had to run our business we
had cannabis Culture magazine which Mark
started as a marijuana newsletter
printed on him and pot TV which is a
video news network which he started as
one of his first video websites ever on
the internet um and in his absence I was
looked to M on marijuana because I run
for office with the marijuana party in
British Columbia I've run with the DC
Green party and now I'm seeking the
candidacy for the Liberal Party of
Canada Are you
seriously by away people in affect lower
your are
youan mean going into follow whatever I
me well okay so here's the deal a lot of
don't trust the government we don't
trust the establishment and it makes
sense that you wouldn't because they've
been the oppressors the drug war and
prohibition have been created by the
people with power that's the police the
politicians the government and they have
oppressed the marijuana people and the
marijuana growers for so many years but
in our activism even before my time
activists have said Legalize It Legalize
It Stop arrest in people for pot and in
order to stop arresting people for pot
you need to get the arresters to stop
doing
that so you have to convince them to see
it our way and it's difficult to trust
the people who have worked against us
the people who have put us in prison the
people who have created the laws that
have destroyed so many lives it's hard
to trust them but you've got to work
with them and I would say that as scummy
and corrupt and unjust and evil as
government and politicians and all of
that can be they do govern Our Lives
whether we like it or not and if they're
going to go with us and Legalize It in
the form they have in Colorado or the
Forum they have in Uruguay or even this
Amsterdam type of legalization they
referred to for years whatever model it
is we have to be the ones to go to the
oppressors to go to the powerful ones
say do it this way do it the right way
do it with the consciousness of medical
marijuana of H of the industrial
purposes of the jobs you can create do
it from these perspectives but if we as
the activists say we don't trust them
and we don't want to work with them they
will go seek others to work with so we
must be the ones
[Applause]
so if they're going to accept me and I
can run for office and get into the
government of Canada and help the
Liberal Party follow through on their
promise to legalized I would do my
utmost to make sure it's the best
legalization in the world so that
America and Obama and everyone else can
say Canada's pretty big they've got it
going on let's do it that way and we can
have hemp and everything else involved
[Applause]
yes yes I'll do the Dirty
Work you
like well run office and I guess to Wi
the hearts and minds of the the large
public get
[Music]
say be for the GRE Lial party the green
party we have the
Lial which again the Liberal Party of
Canada you know the Lial party in
amongst let's say the the biggest uh you
want to talk of
enemy The V day is Strang enough which
is Lial party is against every kind of
legalization but let's make a quick note
about that these titles of liberal
Democrat Left Right conservative we have
to work with them all ending prohibition
is nonpartisan the Republicans and
conservatives can see it from a liberty
and financial perspective and the
Socialists and the left wing can see it
as a freedom and togetherness issue you
know this naturopath yeah there's
everybody has their own approach and
especially remember people who don't
smoke who agree with us like Dr San
they're going to help us win so keep
talking keep networking and never turn
away from anyone I used to want pot to
be illegal by the way I was a pro what
you I didn't like pot and I thought
people who smoke pot should go to prison
I did I did and then I smoked
it
SM
the
elaborate I started out in high school I
didn't like marijuana I didn't think
people use it I didn't I thought people
should go to prison but then I slowly
changed my mind because think of think
of think think of think of this think of
how think of how it is first you think
marijuana should be legal because it's
good but how many of you also thought
that maybe hard drugs should stay
illegal when you first became interested
in pots like some people start with
being proot and then they learn that
prohibition is a problem so never turn
your back on someone who is against you
because if they come around to your side
it's very valuable Mark prosecutor
change s Jo us what he helped legalize
in
Washington May his prut leg time it's
now a person I greet as a friend and
he's become a leg my prosecutor change
side and wrote the legislation for
Washington I
work just saying work with everyone
peace
love where are our great friends I'm not
hearing anything we supposed to see the
the green guys the green
guys where are our but you know what you
know
[Music]
[Applause]
g g
[Music]
maybe you maybe it's clear for everybody
here in the room hello
please hello please please please please
can I have your
attention uh there is some controversy
in this country you must be aware uh we
have tradition uh Santa Claus tradition
and apparently well it's true we have a
blackface tradition but the Dutch didn't
consider it to be like that they are now
uh so slowly Awakening interestingly
enough already in 2008 the green peast
were born uh they were the time they
were far ahead of the time we may say we
even had a black Santa Claus in here uh
a very famous television host uh and
seven years later they are um I don't
know what you are now you
are Trend seters Trend seters yes uh
tonight by the way tonight in tusinski
one a very famous Cinema film World
premiere about this tradition and it's
going to be a bomb at this film and I
told them that I should go to tushi
around 8:30 instead of front because the
whole world press is there and it maybe
uh we'll help your yeah yeah go there uh
May we should all go
there okay and Now ladies and gentlemen
very your may had your
attention Mr mic a former Prize winner
will hand out the first kind of kis
culture award to the prince and
princess Mr M the floor is
yours very nice well you know it's with
great pleasure Mark to to to actually be
the one that actually hand you this I've
admired
your philanthropy and your your passion
and your drive for decades honestly now
and you know there was a few of us I
think in that bus 20 years ago that
realized that our voice meant something
and you were one of those people and you
know the world could like it or not yet
something to say and we all heard it and
that message was great and thank you you
know from us all for for Having the
courage to sell seeds to places where
you weren't allowed to sell seeds to and
for taking the proceeds and not you know
buying yourself a space airplane or a
ticket to Mars but instead trying to use
it as a responsible resource to do good
deeds and I admire that greatly because
in this hippie type movement where a lot
of people looked at wealth as a burden
and not a blessing you looked at it as a
responsibility and you redistributed in
ways that a lot of people might not have
done and then I forever am grateful to
you that for that and I know that maybe
from being behind the scenes and knowing
the people that you've supported and the
initiatives that you've gotten behind
and the change that we have experienced
in America was from generous people like
you and from the bottom of my heart
thank you very
much my pleasure to give you your
2014 Cel
award and a big hug yeah
[Music]
[Applause]
you want
[Music]
say
pleas was locked away as a
prisoner you really did an am amazing
job I've run into you at all these
different rallies Seattle Hempfest and
she was out there all the time pounding
the pavement trying to get people to
listen and and keeping the magazine
going which has been a beacon of
education and and really that's what
we're here for because we believe that
we have a message that everybody else
needs to hear and in all honesty I'm
only hoping that we inspire you to go
carry the message to the people that we
don't know to turn them on like we were
turned on so that we can all take over
and I joke that Timothy Larry had it
only two-thirds right where he used to
say turn on tune in and drop out it's
really turn on tune in and as you were
saying take
over because that's what find the power
James and we're not victims here we're
really in control of Our Own Destiny and
that's what can social R and we need
more strong women like you in this
movement and I admire you so much and
thank you for being so supportive Mark
and thank you for changing your mind I
wouldn't have liked you so much that I
met you in high school obviously but
high school thank you congratul
fantastic I have a question from the
public I have many questions but I can I
hope okay I'll get to that later on but
a message for question for you Jody uh
do you think there's still more s stigma
surrounding woman smoking than
[Music]
men I don't think there's so much of
stigma but women have always been looked
to as the nurturers the caretakers they
give birth they raise children the men
help them you know I it's a group effort
um I just think in general people ask
why are women under representing the
marijuana movement and I would say
there's a fair argument under
represented generally um but they do
make up half of the game I mean it's it
you could say it's a man's world but I
tend to see everyone as an individual I
mean every individual has their merits
and there are men who stay at home and
raise children and there are women who
don't take care of kids so you you you
can't make these generalizations but it
is fair to say that throughout human
history women have taken care of the
home while the men go out and do work
work Gathering and whatever or hunting
you know but even in terms of working
women are only recently recently entered
into the workforce so women have been
there to back the men while they go out
and do so even right now today there are
a lot of men in the movement who go out
and their women help take care at home
but so many women are active these days
so many women are out there I mean if
you want to go on Facebook or any of
these group women are very powerfully
involved so I don't think there's so
much underrepresented as just
it's kind of the way the world is you
know men seem to take more of the
prominent positions but battles shift
can change one question uh from uh Mr
Rolling
Stone um if you could live your life
over again what would you do
something anything yeah I probably
wouldn't have started pot TV if I knew
it was going to cost me a million
dollars over 6 years and make no Revenue
you and but it turns out to be a
historically really amazing thing we
started January 1st 2000 I
mean there are things I would do
differently I would have spent every one
of that $5 million I gave away on
ballting issues instead of like a quar
million uh I valid issues are the way to
go I would have paid used every $5
million if I had have really realized
the good that can come from that prison
I think it's the same for
uh based on the handwriting
uh did prison learn you any valuable
lesson in life I
can yeah is there anything that
you prison brought you
something yeah if you're a good person
you'll be welcome
anyway that's
good meeting in 4 and A2 years I have
nothing bad to say about my experience
fellow inmates they were all they were
great
yeah I got to play with Incredible
musicians who taught me how to play I
knew nothing uh people were very kind to
me I rarely ever heard an unkind word
spoken to me in six prisons did you ever
smoke a reer in prison not didn't even
get near it because the punishment is
too severe and I I actually had no
desire to get high in that four and a
half
years no in prison because I'm in the
present tense I didn't really think much
about anything beyond my own confin so
that was all the books I was reading the
magazines I was reading The
Correspondents I was writing uh I was
very much in the present moment I wasn't
thinking about what I had done or where
I was going or what was coming only in
the present moment Mr alen wait wait
we'll get to Mr alen now uh I by the
[Music]
way also knows do you know something
about prisons
too you can't hear me or
not you know the thing is like I said
you know know uh like you make a joke
about it and I like the joke you know
but we could be all like we convicts we
ex EXs what and but it yeah and you know
what and that the terrible irony of it
is there's so many people in prison
still now I I just met two beautiful
young kids and they're going for 25
years or I don't know what and I I
cannot give you the details but it's
it's it's amazing that people go in
prison and there's so many people in
prison and we got out and I was lucky I
was only busted more than 80 times and I
didn't do more than 6 weeks the longest
but many more than 80 but I was in
Holland and I was lucky to do no more
than 6 weeks and then I do 3 weeks and
two weeks and 5 days and 10 days and
community service and all the [__] you
know but that that but in other
countries you know in the world people
still go to prison for you know you look
in the museum you have a Str of lives
from Mickey and and Chris Conrad a long
time ago and so that's a tragedy so we
we we can and it should be light we we
stoned and ey and it's an event you know
but we should be taking the seriousness
of our activism because there's people
in jail there and they shouldn't be
there for a p and that is the anger or
the the the heart where we come from
that is what we do all
right a little iry irony oh irony yeah
in Colorado and Washington where we've
declared victories no one's been let
off any cannabis offenses in either of
those two states and while it's nice
that we feel like we're not slaves
anymore we can't turn our backs to the
people that still rotten in jail as
slaves and that's really what I walked
away from prison realizing a lot of good
people go to prison in America they got
25% of the world's prison population and
a lot of those people are nonviolent
offenders that were just trying to get
high because their High wasn't alcohol
and tobacco their I was one of the the
other drugs that were not legal so we we
can't really stop trying to to to see
equal rights until we've really released
the people that have already been locked
up for things that shouldn't have been
crime in the first
place before we get to uh Mr update Mr
Howard is marks is on his way he's in
the car he's probably very close now I
think no yes
yes maybe we can have short break but
but I just want to ask you because what
why were you why are you implying that
he knows something about prison you he
know no
just
[Music]
said well the Cannabis culture award is
not about having fun you know it's about
the people who did something or who give
something
who give years of your life in
prison so and now and and we have to
admire the people who are still there
and we should get them out change all
right now we
he will tell you about why we got more
alen will lat uh head out price so to
speak right he will present the price to
Mr Mar
yeah are you
sure oh yeah it's true
true sorry for this confusion
confusion um are you still uh working in
any way in any field are you connected
to to let's say marijuana besides
smoking these
days correspond with everybody
[Music]
here away
are actually all children if six
children are they all involved some way
or
another involved
[Music]
she calls herself Al yeah
[Applause]
[Music]
I I I I truly because uh yes I did this
is all uh my doing so uh uh part of the
museum uh because we reopened we rebuilt
and Alan and my father we we uh
literally spent days in this Museum uh
filling the vitrinas it it was done by
Ben and me and all ay my brothers so
Albert so many people and and we thought
of one question actually for you uh Alan
and um you're forgetting about it but I
really would like to know um what would
be your most interesting finding in in
in Canabis history because I I'm very
curious to the answer okay that's true
I yes
Mr Professor please
answer you know that that was a question
I heard it before and it's very very
hard to answer there's there's so many
beautiful things about this plant and I
think that the true answer is that most
beautiful thing is the plant itself
because that is what inspired Us in all
these years to make this collection here
and make the museum in
Barcelona and inspired us to start a h
Factory and start do all these things
that we are doing today
and um what is the most beautiful about
moment in history or the most beautiful
fight there's many if I mean if you go
through this Museum or in Barcelona
there's so many items that have a story
that you know that you you would love to
tell more and more to all the people
that walk through here but there's so
much only so much you can explain and
show and many things people don't see
but we have we know where it comes from
we know you know the passion behind and
it's uh it's beautiful it's just if if
people are able if you're ever in Spain
in Barcelona please visit the museum
museum over there here we have the hash
Museum on that side and here the hemp
Gallery but there we have yeah my father
has created such a wonderful space that
wonderful Museum should all check it
out I'd like to make a
comment the fact that we are in a newsum
now marijuana is in the news a lot right
now because legalization is happening
politically but we also know that
worldwide or particularly North America
there's a baby boom there's an aging
population and medical marijuana is
becoming more and more popular as well
but once they stop arresting people once
we're really done with that once they
look at it as a massive human rights
violation and they start apologizing for
it in some way people are going to say
tell us more about this plant tell us
more about what it does because
apparently it doesn't just make you feel
better when you're sick it also holds
the cure for cancer and so many elment
it builds buildings that keep you warm
in the winter and cool in the summer and
remove pollution from the air this plant
does so much and when people find out
how much it does when they learn the
history through the preservation of
things like pot TV I'm glad you did pot
TV and through things like the museum
when people come and they find a history
because it's been preserved they'll be
kind of upset that they were lied to
that's what happened to me I was really
upset I was lied to about marijuana
and that's why I changed my mind so
active because they're ruining lives
they say it causes cancer and it cures
caner I mean there's so much ahead
there's so much ahead so places like
this that hold our history our cannabis
culture history are valuable for
hundreds of years to come because
they're going to say they put people in
prison for this they shock them for this
they ruin children's lives for this
plant look what it does so make sure you
do we look at what it does because I'm
continuously blowing away
[Music]
[Applause]
still but I know the weirdest marijuana
fact in existence and I'll tell you um
and this is a real change in tone
actually um it's from Michael pollen's
botney of Desire
very and it's the idea of where we get
the modern idea of the witch flying on a
broom that's so Halloween it originates
from the middle-aged practice of healing
women known as witches sometimes but
healers uh putting a dildo before them
and putting a bunch of cannabis resin on
it and inserting it right up the vagina
which is mucous membrane that is very
absorbent and then they would call it a
flying ointment and then they would have
outof body experiences for several hours
and I bring that up only to point out
that every time you see these children
as witches you don't have to explain
we we proposed a short break no because
he's on his way right and I want to I
want to make because because I have one
more nice uh thing that I would like my
father actually to talk about why why is
the hemp
Gallery not the
museum why is the H gallery gallery is
actually everything in the gallery for
sale and is it is it a
gallery because it it says so much also
about our politics you want to tell this
you want to tell
this we are a gallery we are a gallery
why do you want to share this why do you
want to sh okay because I feel it's
important
yeah it's not it's about what you mean
is about what sometimes we don't have to
follow the LA you can bend the law you
have to you have to
change you know like
uh uh I find five years to open
this guys maybe you you don't have a
clue what we're talking about let me put
it in this way uh he would like to you
know the museum was small you need you
need a larger Museum and in Amsterdam
Now situation is that you don't get per
all kind of re so that's why they open
up a gallery But A G they're not allowed
to make it into official music so it's
called Gallery so you can buy this stuff
but it's very expensive so I wouldn't
try
it
right you can buy you the rules it's
kind of like we have a smoking Lounge
but it's in an office space yeah yes
do
that the
[Music]
rules guys it
maybe make it inter no because we have
to
[Music]
wait can we Dov now
can we get some wine up here as
well or
dabs every can everyone get a wine in
here in seated here as
[Music]