[Music]
all right the melts have just arrived
melts in the house chips and Kevin and
who's this [ __ ] guy over here the
glitter exclu we're gonna call it the
glitter eggs pretty stoked on this entry
this is a 2/2 of our good buddies from
Colorado through this buddy
Dredd smokes weed Dredd yeah Dredd grew
this dread grew the gorilla glue and
then our buddy growing cushion mile-high
Robert grew the Citrix all right
no we just decided that be like a really
great combination of strains and resin I
don't know they represent some Colorado
growers and make a nice collaborative
country doing their growing techniques
and what we're doing with our water ash
techniques same trace was actually
floured outside full Sun Colorado its
weight and then the growth was growing
inside so there's a really nice rounded
profile there fuckin'-a man we're gonna
have to get you guys on hash Church one
of these Sundays yeah definitely they'll
be awesome
yeah man people are really digging it
and there's a lot of people listening
now you're probably even set up the
webcam in the lab one of these
we since what I'm saying we stayed
really busy but we do keep a computer in
there
yeah but make it making hash during hash
Church is definitely commendable oh we
could make it happen that's well we'll
do the firt well do one this Sunday so
I'm gonna invite a whack of people down
for hash church this Sunday we're gonna
get I don't know if we'll do it here in
the room or somewhere else but we'll get
a good venue we'll have maybe two or
three computers open simultaneously with
to two to three people on each computer
it's gonna be killer what do you say
aunty I'm pretty good dab session coming
down soon I will affect your long term
cure and just sound like an individual
graham jar might eventually end up
lighting out those are the things that
really make sure your hash stays
perfectly granular when you're working
with fresh frozen material
there are chunks that might not end up
perfectly drugged but it's your job as a
hash maker to make sure you can identify
those chunks that are not properly
drying so you don't say promis-- the
quality of the rest of your hash there
are will always be the one little piece
that does not fit perfectly through the
sieve or perfectly through the micro
planer that you need to remove from the
rest of the hash
have interesting
you wanna smoke
we're getting close someone to when I
smoke something like that
Juwanna
pretty quiet in here
active but there's some loud happening
here
- is that loud over there it is so loud
over there
jesus H Jackie
over there what's going on out here
Amsterdam
Plus at mr. green tech yeah hi Simone
Peter smokey yeah I didn't say we're
gonna use it we could it's a good way to
look at some stuff I think we should
have a DAB somewhere soon
[Music]
all right so what do you got here Tony
this is well that was really good
actually the way you had it up there
that's straight up like we've time and
time again just washed 20% has turk melt
even to where there wasn't a mouse
factor on this why don't we dab that up
Oh
[Music]
this is going to be close to the legend
century citrus great things
that's so funny turn the world
guy welcome to bubbleman's whoa these
guys just rolled in Ramon and true
cannabliss some friends from online and
some friends that are just killing it
announcer right now from OCD labs and
true canna genetics so dudes you guys
making some headway for legends this
year what trolling through information
trying out a few different things
nice the one thing we've really learned
is material it makes the Welsh
difference you know I having some real
good material around to play with that's
how we use like really experiment is to
keep and time and dedication because
Ramones been doing more investigating
than he has sleep in recently triangle
soon ready for the legends backslide I
like to hear that and so we got all
sorts of treats on the table here what
have you got there chips some jelly
liver now wet wash fresh frozen why
don't you take a dab of this sweet skunk
dry sift
hair on there I'll just blow it up the
window behind you cuz we're in the
non-smoking room at the fire extend you
oh that was not open all open it was
right
Oh wonderful my classic you're like I'll
just hold it until it doesn't exist
anymore cuz I guess alright I have a
wonderful lung capacity also tastes
young in a rush to get out yeah roll
over the tongue absorb good flavor
swish - that smooth as well it's not
rushing to you out
sweet guys are clearly professionals
cool ones that you'll get weight of it
and it gets to the point where the
session just said stuff yeah that's the
turf mouse that's which one is that
that's the Betty Ross no yeah but is
Betty Ross yeah Betty Ross was Bruce
banners girlfriend tap it up you guys
are our guests I want you to catch up
we've been pretty hard
[Music]
to be able to trough Oh
you guys are heading over to Selma's
yeah we talked to him he was like I'm
waiting for for those guys up
that's not about the Windham it's a big
one there you go
we do that every time - let's hope that
one doesn't let it be one of the biggest
one that's for sure we have it on camera
that's when paper shot you so much yeah
yeah we use for watches it's actually
pretty good
I mean be the amount of what would be
about two ounces
you guys gotta open it before you like
trimmed at all but the value on it I
mean the cost on that's a lot less -
because not near as many people have had
a handle it it hasn't had a occupy any
space getting hung dry so they're
sitting pretty a pretty good return as
far as just a few turkeys oh that's nice
it's been the fact that little that
little cherry wait a minute long that
way as far as infusing it back to water
- yeah dude who's up next
[Music]
that one was there was a few different
ones there was like one we put sweet
skunk dry sift and that Terp melt
together
not nice but what smells like this work
across the SFP Kim Jen all the sexy
stuff okay yeah and it's got the same
kind of yeah it's definitely got that
it's just a great assist ateva hazy sick
the smell of exotic
[Music]
so you guys got here cuz they just
pulled out some absolutely fire like
here's the cookies cross you see if I
can get that up a bit
there we go that's the Girl Scout
cookies hit with the SSP Ken Mel pretty
much everything I've got here was the
same mouth I've used and then popped a
whole pack of each one and selected out
the best ones my cup entries and these
are some of the other ones that didn't
quite make the cut for the cup I'm gonna
make a point on shooting these with the
macro lens for sure as well as this one
what was this one that one's the Sagan
star which know that's the purple
cheddar cross sfe gem right granddaddy
chirps really nice crystal on that man
like the resin is visible from a great
distance with the naked eye dry suit
absolutely it's great flowers and then
you guys got your entries over here yeah
this is some of the brand that has had
sentries have a sniff of it is s called
I couldn't
oh yeah beautiful ute OCD representing
with cannabis not riddlin oh my god
which ones that
that's enough of granddaddy terms but a
different long fantastic a couple
different plants which basically it
works out Frieda plants we've had to
divide up for out in four four grams
because it's the strain not cut in or
right Rome once I checked and they said
yep that's cool to do that as long as
it's the same strain cool that's how
we're doing it I figured that's the true
representation of what seed companies
capable so the interesting way to end up
almost upon us but snow that right which
one's it
oh my god that's that tangi Jillybean
Caleo awesomeness and which would
interplay that's took this cool tip life
now what is it turf Zilla hit with the
sfv can melt geez but let's head Jim
small that one the name got me excited
it's very yeah it's very reminiscent of
liked Angie's and marmalade Jilly bean
but it's it's different there's like a
creamy orange sherbert behind like the
orange zest like rotting orange like any
kind of associate Angie would it's
pretty sweet
big shopping bag full of dank weed
that's gonna do it yeah this one here is
the this is more turf life
I love turf I live the turf life oh that
one's lovely come on that is great I
don't have a nice smell I'm as strong as
the orange e1 but very nice profile yeah
that's it she's genuine but complex a
little bit better with the light huh
that one is just it's a little different
the blue cheddar
well that all looks very impressive boys
I think you guys are contenders as
always I'll watch for you guys on the
stage at the at the end of the event did
you check out this blue shoe sale this
is one of my favorite things about cup
time as everyone brings out the heavy
gloss and Europe's just kind of getting
introduced to that whole scene well you
know flags coming in like a day row and
he's bringing like listen no listen
listen
Oh excited this is another stage we'll
be hitting some pieces man I'm telling
you we will be hitting he was over at my
house it was like so yeah I'm gonna
bring this one and this one what do you
think of this one what do you think
these three I'm just like are you
kidding me
like you can't fit in to a photo the
sheer magnitude of something a little
silly oh no wow I've shot that's just
like a little cooler of them it's true
that right there live your dream
collections it's never been photographed
in its entirety as one piece that's
pretty good of the sand fault I'll go to
the damn premiere in gallery and
literally just stand there looking
around silence just if I'm telling you
you guys are contenders
keep an eye on these guys OCD labs
through Canada attics thanks for coming
by guys puffs Wednesday with Tony V
livin it up in Amsterdam and what do you
got there buddy
mmm little pieces some cheese well
cheese Jesus Christ did you hear that
sound do that again oh yeah Lucy it
looks great Jesus
[Music]
well - I watch you watch it's on yeah so
it's just like - off well really just
turn it off right away it's like getting
gains power we have been hitting flavors
like they've been going out of style
like can you even try to name off
someone like all the flavors we've been
hitting everything from yogurt custard
sour fruit purplish heat
sweet buttery haze hazy skunky just
citrus lemons yeah let's see over there
we got the glue we got the gorilla glue
yeah we got the fabuloso blue suede
shoes we got the blue suede shoes over
there
and then there was another one that he
put in there was the baby Ross Betty
Ross Betty Ross do a little googling on
Betty Ross you guys and you'll find out
who she is she may or may not be related
to in some form another to a Bruce
Banner beer no water
just get that last little bit of heat
when you're pressing resin you require
two things you require heat and/or
pressure the more pressure the more heat
is created the more heat you use the
less pressure is required those are the
two things you require to press hash so
I've shown quite a few methods over the
years from the old wine bottle technique
and the steaming of the hash on the on
the stove on low to heat up the resin
indirectly it's never a bad idea so this
is another great way with the oil slick
product there I can't believe you can
heat that up to 500 degrees
doesn't yeah we're way below the of
course yeah I would suspect or the 100
Rangers that's yeah thanks a lot
it feels like Christmas when you go to
open it it should have a nice ringtone
and that's proper so I guess the next
thing to do is for us to dab it
[Music]
oh here's the Joella
Joella is gonna be our news entry what
it is at least movie already is injury
yeah duel of energy all right let's see
you open it up a little off that piece
yeah hold it up in the light like I just
did to the jar Ella and the jar Ella is
the Joella is lemon g13 fish batter this
is lemon G lemon og
well that's insane
oh my god so I suppose we're gonna hit
that ASAP am i right
Don keep an all-right is here alright so
what do we start with
oh you got a huge ball on here for me
what is this this is what we might get
it's as hard as a rock that's impressive
right there hard as a rock
really good whatever is another's I'm
about to try it right now I'm excited so
this is of course Toni's creation of the
tert melts cannabis terpenes added back
to cannabis resin
[Music]
we of course have a non-smoking room
here at the krasnopolskiy delicious
[Music]
there's still quite a bit here
so it's been a lot of pressing up a
little bit to my resin something with
tear up some without terms this one of
course is the jar ella i was holding up
earlier got this one of EG the lemon OG
which is just greasy and ridiculous it's
completely you know hard like glass
shatter really really nice resins it's
all just been great and the little spoon
with the handle sign and I'll have to
get a picture of Pop Wednesday I thought
you guys would want to join us anyway
for a few ribs
[Music]