[Music]
today they have this gentleman here to
my right right here this guy with
sunglasses this is the bubbleman French
antiques
he's got the bubble mouth of up above
except it's a bubble bank it's this guy
is the master of the bowl all right
it's not Bubble Boy this is bubble man
all right
so everybody's have a warm hand to the
legend of cells bubble baths and Tony
Denver Colorado
thanks everybody for showing up it's
been a bit of a chaotic Cup with the
with the government pushing us out here
and there and just trying to mess with
us but I'm happy to see that my time to
pulled it off and we still have a venue
thanks to the milkman I know we've been
coming here for Gee's years like maybe
20 years or more for myself I want to
introduce Tony here who I've got they
mentioned from River Rock he's also from
United cannabis and I guess it was gonna
kind of start this particular talk about
a little bit about what we've been doing
how Tony and I are connected were both
obvious resin aficionados
he's been while you've been making water
gosh and growing her and doing all these
things for the last 15 plus years I
would say Tony oh yeah I'm started in 96
96 okay so you're about 18 years in so
that's great I started a similar amount
of time I was a 92 93 started growing
cannabis got into cannabis activism and
I need three 94-95 and that's what we
got we were applying for HAMP licenses
in Manitoba
that got him growing there legally for
the first time in 73 years it's been
growing ever since I think my little
partner is Alex might be in the room for
Manitoba harvest and fresh mountain
foods and from there I you know got into
the hash game in the late 90s so I guess
where we're coming from is recently we
started a project I'm sure a lot of you
guys have heard there's all sorts of
different things happening in the world
Tony himself is a part of the very big
project called United cannabis and
United cannabis nested licenses all over
North America and in Canada have applied
for in Jamaica which is really what
brought Tony and I together working
together was a project that we started
in Jamaica a company that I started with
my Jamaican partners as well as Johnny B
John her fellow who may also be in the
room here somewhere I'm not sure if he
is right I'm Johnny B so we started this
company in Jamaica and we partnered up
with United cannabis new Tony is
big part of they also have Bernie
Blackmun from the United cannabis and
River Rock Wellness Center in the room
today as well I'm not sure where exactly
he has been he's here as well and what
this project is is I mean I'll let them
tell that you tell a little bit about
your night of cannabis and then we'll
bring in to meet your maker
okay well I'm gonna bring it always back
to the resin because I think it's
important and as Clark explained even up
until a year ago your eyes open when you
start to explore the different varieties
of cannabis and its forms which also
will represent the variety of resident
and the type of profile that you're
gonna get from it so a lot of people I
think look at bubble bags they look at
different streams and different things
and think that's gonna make it that's
the that's the winning ticket that's the
magic of how to make the resin or the
been aesthetics exceptional and really
it's a it's a relationship with the
genetics the resin the cultivation the
extraction process and then ultimately
what are you doing with it
so as far as most societies and cultures
they think of the pot leaf and they
think of cannabis and they think of okay
that's for the stomach community we
can't we can't possibly have those
people in our town so that's kind of
where it always starts in
how that medical cannabis pushing part
of the states and countries there I
think the government's are slowly
starting to realize that while there is
made use of medical benefits here and so
those avenues are now being pushed open
but ultimately at the end of the day
it's free it's free the plan free the
resident so that we can explore it in
its full capacity so social acceptance
and responsibilities of cannabis to be
used probably should be legalized the
medical evidence of cannabis should be
explored to its fullest with all science
and research as well as the industrial
uses of hell that's could be restore
farming back in the United States and
provide limitless jobs and so the idea
of what we were trying to do which is
the simple starting up of River Rock
which is a Medical Center and also a
recreation center at Colorado was
finding a way to synergize the final
therapeutics of the plant and up and the
cannabinoid profiles into standardized
resin and so you have to figure out
where to start when you think about
standardizing resin for medicinal
purposes and what that actually means
it's tony was doing this with river rock
Tony and hurry while they were mastering
the growing aspect and the business
aspect
of dealing with all these different
people it's very difficult particularly
when running a dispensary to deal with
the patients they have difficulty in
their life they're in trials and
tribulations they've got health problems
so just dealing with them alone is a big
deal so while these guys were doing that
work I of course have been spending the
last 15 years learning about isolating
and decontaminating resin glands of a
particular variety of candidates stocked
and sets of stocks are the two that I
prefer all of us being a lower quality
gland that tends to make up a lot of the
extra weight and oil extractions but
doesn't have as much of an important
factor at least in the recreational and
what I would call the extreme medical
where as you know you know a serious
ailment you're in stage three or four
and you need serious saturation of and
of cannabinoids by the cannabinoids into
your endocannabinoids system I'm not to
say that there's no medicinal value in
Balthus trichomes I'm sure once we get
into the know the actual study of
specific types of glands and learning
where these cannabinoids exist in the
different glands that we'll be able to
do specific work breeding and whatnot
but basically I came in ask the sort of
decontaminate you know what the quality
that I've set has really led me into the
team that these guys are building which
is the United cannabis it's really a
beautiful thing to see unity in the
cannabis industry and to see a standard
set so it's not about who you are or
it's basically really all about what you
know and what standard you can set so
here a breeder of exceptional
exceptional town
with exceptional talent or a processor
then you're probably going to find
yourself you know with a position in
United cannabis one day because it
really is this incredibly large growing
company that has a really incredible
route of foundation which is to produce
the utmost quality of medicine to
extract and process to the purest form
to give access to all of the different
people who have a necessity for cannabis
I I get talked to I get spoken to on a
daily basis with people who are sick and
I mean nothing compared to Tony I know
Riverrock sees over a hundred thousand
people annually so the that's a big part
of what River Rock brought to the table
and you know if cannabis is that they
brought this incredible empirical
evidence this sort of data that's coming
right from the patients and I like to
let me talk a little bit about that
because they created a program so that
information would not be lost but so
that information can be accessed in the
new and a new interesting type of way
that allows for more knowledge to be
gained yeah it started you know everyone
starts by saying hey try this drink this
will be really good for your Crohn's so
we're trying this hash this would be
really good for your back and then you
look at the research and you start to
study what's called cannabis
pharmacokinetics and you start to look
at how long this active THC and active
CBD stained your liver stay in your
brain how long does that take to process
and there's one
interesting books and literature that's
come about more publications of coming
out and so there's two there's two
fundamentals that we really focused on
which was Mike reducing its and the
stacking method and some of you know the
static method when you think of rare
exceptions well a lot of people have
been exposed to Gupta in his entourage
effect we like to call the full spectrum
effect so you think of whole planet full
spectrum full terpene restoration type
of medicine that could be delivered in
inactive and active micro dosing as well
as stacking method what makes our system
a little bit different and it's kind of
like the backs we separated cannabis
high ridge CBD strains and high THC with
high terpene profile strains into four
categories those categories are simple 1
2 3 4 breakfast lunch dinner at bedtime
and each one of those categories
represents different types whole plant
medicine in a sense that poppy once all
whole plan THC a with terpene profiles
that match those particular those
particular strengths so if you're
looking to breed high THC with something
that would that you found
creating pain relief anti planetory
energy increased appetite that you would
use those terpenes as Lodge of theirs
and so the extraction process of trying
to get where people were at probably two
years of the floor was simply just
taking water - or taking their hassle
combined with coconut oil and trying to
create a simple delivery system because
most of us don't want to use alcohols or
solvents or chemicals in the medicines
process and so ideally what we're
talking about because it sounds
confusing I'm sure out there is allowed
to take a whole plant and its medicinal
properties and categorizing them so a
category one people would be high THC
with certain profiles a category to be
high CBD a low THC a would sir turkey
profiles a category 3 would be the close
ratios and a clock category 4 would be
fully activated CBD fully activated CBN
creating a wanna watch those four ratio
those four categories allows patients
and physicians to sequence full-spectrum
cannabinoid therapies
Fanny and I so the longer is in a strain
you can dial 8 the type of
accommodations as an example autism
might
active p22 milligrams per mole for
breakfast and for lunch and an active p4
for dinner six milligrams changes a
person's life from a dollar thirty
instead of tried to concentrate 70
milligrams of a flower or it's 250
milligrams and to a piece of hash to
that smoker because it's one-dimensional
canal we didn't what type of delivery
system so between the micro dosing and
the capsules and the categories we've
basically created a way to to allow
physicians and patients to use
cannabinoids similar to music notes
absolutely you guys if Tony's confusing
a few of you guys I'll just give you a
really brief lowdown on waist talk about
keys he's talking pure clap profile he's
talking about the resin off of the plant
that produces the medicines so the
glandular trichomes whether they've been
extracted via water hash via
have the extracts that do a lot of the
work for them in Colorado or whether
it's been dry sifted or even whether
it's been hydrocarbon extracted by the
giddy from with emo tech they tweak
those resins and then they break them
down they know the exact amounts per
milligram per pill and the pill should
really be called capsules because all
they really are capsules filled with
coconut oil and energy be used all while
as well well so coconut oil causes
problems because there's actually
patients out there that are allergic to
coconut oil and so we start to see
thousands of patients and you start
having people come back with burning
sensations down their throat because
they took coconut oil inside at work so
we brought a medical adviser that
discovered stem cells in 1988 and is one
of the leading cancer and tumor research
scientists on the planet he has 200
peer-reviewed articles and developed
what's called patient avatars so he's
actually created what's called cancer no
5 natural plant-based herbs that have
been put together to create a
synergistic effect if by cancer tumors
and children and so as a patient
advocate our work actually removes the
stem cells out of the patient while
being treated with chemo or radiation
and then using natural supplements and
specialized types of foods to bring back
that system get them through the chemo
radiation that reinstall all the stem
cells they have the technology to
recreate that in rodent studies and so
what we're able to do now is extrapolate
cancer patients autoimmune autism
epilepsy that vas fibromyalgia and
recreate those patient avatar simulators
and be able to dial it those particular
categories so instead of chasing the
Holy Grail we're chasing that straight
or chasing that one CBD well now this
has been put into a software that
physicians can understand it's simple
for patients to understand because once
you create the bridge between the two
and allow the two best delivery methods
for this type of medicine and they have
flexibility then you could dial it any
condition you could do it very
effectively and not cost yourself a lot
of money and that's really been a big
big thing with it yeah I guess also go
back to a little bit of an explanation
because I guess we're assuming a lot
here we all have a system in our bodies
called the endocannabinoids system and
this system regulates much of the
biological function that goes on in our
body including when we go to sleep and
when we wake up
get hungry and how well we remember and
so the how it does as it regulates our
immune system and our central nervous
system and it puts them into harmony so
when they are in disharmony with those
two systems it usually means that our
endocannabinoids system is deficient and
to give you an idea of the importance of
cannabinoids breast milk in women
produces essential amino acids which are
basically the building blocks of life
and when you ask your doctor why that is
they don't usually know but those amino
acids actually produce endocannabinoids
inside your body so the endo meaning and
dajin ously inside of you and then
cannabinoids cannabis produces what are
called fico cannabinoids and so we could
use those not necessarily as well as the
smoking and vaporizing aspects that's
great for tremors and it's great for
ocular pressure and it's great for
increasing appetite but what tony is
talking about for a lot of these
different elements the importance is to
eat and consume orally or use creams or
use these drops and get these
cannabinoids into your system so they
can do the work that they do which is
basically fine the cb1 and cb2 receptors
that are found in your brain and in your
peripheral organs and what you know by
basically I use the metaphor that a lot
of us are blown away we think it's
amazing when
we important a gave a young little baby
girl eight months old she had the brain
tumor in her head splitting the
hemispheres of her brain and he started
giving her the cannabis oil of photo
cannabinoids and of course her tumor
shrunk miraculously and toni has
literally dozens and dozens and maybe
hundreds and hundreds of these stories
of people with bone cancer and
metastatic breast cancer of people with
autism that have never led a normal life
and one time after another it's always
the same thing isn't it Tony it's a
miracle
yes so once you start databasing those
results that's what kind of drove us
that's literally with drugs to dni
cannabis and that it was kind of our
fiduciary duty if you will to bring that
information to light and it started with
Rob's that sort of the textures that
started with strains and now it's
literally sublingual drops capsules in
what I call bio nutrient so most people
that are terminal or people that are
having to rely on medicine also allow
their medicine as a food and so bile
nutrient medicinals and so we were
talking about coconut oil before and
coconut oils okay it's pretty good
we used a proprietary
between coconut palms as well as
polarizing that and then utilizing
natural turkey extractions to that be
able to pull whether it's live resin or
the different backs into that plant fat
so that's kind of the newer thing I like
the way you just held up the peer vial
of terpenes like it was nothing
this is pretty cutting edge stuff right
here it's been only in the last year
that we've been reading about K from
trichome technologies you can you could
smell it later too yeah we'll definitely
let you do a smell of this this is
Tony's own creation I was actually
speaking with K months ago and he was
telling me you gotta figure out terpene
extraction this is gonna be the big
thing you got to figure out how to get
it back out of the water you of course I
make a lot of water hash and that water
hash of course is using water soluble
terpenes it's losing terpenes and now I
remember Jim for air singing I have done
show recently and he must be a chemist
he's definitely a very intelligent man
but he was saying that the water can't
reach the wax membrane but I disagreed I
think that once the head breaks off and
it breaks away from the capitate stop
that that thin membrane underneath the
head is allowing terpenes to be released
into the water as well as water being
absorbed into the wax membrane
why we all know made water hash that
really the most difficult thing in
making water hash is actually drying the
final product the water in the ice gets
all the credit I'm sorry it's doing all
the work it's isolating the resin it's d
contaminating everything for you at 99%
so please keep the water in the ice some
credit and after that it's really like
what what I think the extract artist is
is the guy who really knows how to
control his variables and to get that
hash properly dry so what Tony's done
with those water soluble terpenes is
he's figured out a way to extract them
in a pure form so a lot of people that
follow me and try to wonder like what am
i doing the terpene so the fun side of
that as I was a response so we
reintroduced that into a full belt or a
live resin or anything else like that
they act as modulators and we've done
that from people like Robert Clark they
want to be able that talked before us
they act as modulators and so these
things that we see is terpenes and look
at that as flavors and smells they
actually are catalyst for THC as well as
all the other cannabinoids so now
there's The DaVinci Code goes a little
deeper or the root boost code it was a
little deeper when you start looking at
species across the world resin genetics
terpene profiles that then lock and key
with cannabinoids and then those get
delivered to the central nervous system
or the immune system those two
deliveries excellent
I guess leading into the water
extraction and losing of the water
soluble has also led me over the years
of course
mentored by guys like Rob Clark and the
stock man I have been led into the
wonderful world of dry scent as many of
you know I've been sharing techniques
that I'm available to that I'm able to
I've learned a few new tricks over the
years and have been just sharing with
people the simple aspects of having a
quiver as if you're a hash maker and you
think of each arrow that's in your
quiver as one of your techniques or one
of your methods to me the more arrows
the better and so dry sifting is tip
it's the holy grail in my opinion that
before you're making your oil before
you're making your wet wash it's never a
bad idea to look into a little dry
sifting it's different it's not based on
a prohibition based model in this day
and age the same way as cutting your
herb fresh drying and selling it how
much can I get and how fast can I get it
it's really more of an intimate
relationship with the plant that you can
grow the plant yourself you can hang it
you can practice hanging it for
different amounts of times and you'll
learn in this amazing way that oh well
the plant releases resin differently
depending on how I just cure it so dry
sifting is really not a misnomer the
word dry is very important the dry ice
is horses sort of confused that a lot
dry dry set using dry ice which i think
is it's definitely works it's doable but
you run into a couple of variables that
are going to be problematic which is a
cleaning the hash dry rest glands and I
wish I have photos you guys can maybe
you do already but you can check me out
on bc bubbleman on instagram and all the
photos are there on the rest of Latin
photos and you just if you see my resin
glands when they're living on the planet
they're very bulbous and they look like
a water balloon ready to burst as
opposed to when the plants been dried
probably the resin shrinks like a resin
raising sorry resin raising and it
really is much easier to work with
whether you're guarding whether you're
doing the to screen trick that I've been
sharing for the last maybe six months I
learned from a guy online but he he
became such an incredible douchebag I
can't even give him a shout out in my
mind so that's unfortunate
I do like to give credit where it is due
but I won't give him credit so this guy
came up with a really cool idea and I
will share it with you guys it's a dry
set concept and it's a it's two screens
that are much larger than your average
sized rostov screens most of you that do
sift maybe you know 150 160 180 micron
is a pretty big screen I know there's a
company out there called eight-eight
extractors or something
they sell a tumbler with a 200 micron
screen I think that's incredibly large
for Dras 15 but most use it about a 150
so this trip uses a 250 micron and a 180
my friend and I figured while we're up
here talking about all this crazy stuff
I should at least give you a couple of
hash tears so here's one for you
the 250 and the 180 I saw them both you
can buy them both anywhere as a
silkscreen err but you won't be able to
order them at micron silk is measured in
lines per inch or mesh so if you want
those two screens you're gonna ask for a
90 mesh and a 60 mesh and you're going
to be a little confused because the 60
is gonna go on top of the 90 okay these
are counterintuitive numbers micron is
the size of the whole mesh and lines per
inch are just that they are how many
lines of self you can get in one inch
and so it's not based on the diameter of
the hole coming into the numbers that
the bigger the number is four microns
the smaller the number is four lines per
inch so really remember that a 60 micron
or 60 lines per inch screen which is the
250 micron goes on top and it sits like
a dish so the size of the frame are
going up and you put that on top of your
90 LBI which is a 180 but instead of
keeping it the right way you flip it
upside down so now the screen is flush
and there's no there's no edges it's
just the screens that I sell or any
silkscreen you flip that one upside down
on the bottom put four spacers on the
corner and let and set the other 60
lines per inch stream the 250 micron
I'll keep repeating both numbers because
it's totally confusing you put it on top
now the way this process works is
there's a boat
an inch space between the two screens
and what happens is is when you throw
material down whether it be sift or plat
matter it the way the resin falls is the
gland heads fall like stones straight
through because the screens are so big
they don't really get caught up on
anything so they just fall straight
through now the capitate stops the
systole pairs and the stigmas and any
really other smaller components of
contaminant they fall like this and they
do this little thing when they hit the
second screen because they're doing this
they usually stick right into it it's
quite something to lift the first screen
and if you get down on the table and you
look even with it it's just trees of
contaminant it's it's unbelievable when
if you touch it like that you just
dropped 50% of that camp contaminant
through so it is super ultra delicate so
you're not working the material you're
literally throwing material down lifting
both screens very gently and on the
bottom you're basically being left with
what I would call between you know the
first time you do it you'll do it wrong
till you get like 80% heads but if you
start learning that it's totally you
know counterintuitive to how much can I
get and how fast you
so you want to go slow and you don't
want to try to get a lot because the
whole process is to get you know what
we've been talking about that
standardization of medicine and for 50
years as a hash maker in a cannabis
grower I've really been led you know it
offends some people I love the cannabis
plant I just don't look at the bud is
something that I use other than to make
hash that's what I do with it it's a
it's a carrier that brings me the
ability to produce a raw product that is
of extreme medicinal value and I can do
that with cannabis on a multitude of
levels I can extract the heavy amino
acid rich seed oil if I want to acquire
that from the seeds I can acquire the
fiber from the stop if I want to make
clothing or textile products but can
even extract the cellulose from inside
the stalk and if you notice what all
those things have in common is you never
use them all you only take the one from
the hole always with cannabis one from
the hole one from the hole I use my
pizza box analogy when I order a pizza I
generally like to open the box and take
the pizza out and eat it so I do respect
cannabis
I love the plant and we couldn't get the
resident or the fiber or the cellulose
or the essential amino acids without it
but I really do see it as a plant that
is particularly the medicinal components
are things that we can extract and the
more we decontaminate them which is what
this does all about the more we seem to
learn and it's why guys like us are
really at this point in time on the edge
of this information that we've been
learning about for I mean 20
years these guys robbed and stuck math
and the variety of these guys that have
been doing this for 40 plus years keep
in mind like they really didn't know
most of what we know today really the
new information that we should be
sinking your teeth into who's learning
about as much about your endocannabinoid
system as you can learn because once you
learn about that you can then share with
all the people I can't even imagine how
many people all these people in this
room know combined that are dying of
cancer right now just one disease and
you know we all know more people that
are suffering from other things so if we
can learn about this if we can extract
these resins if we can learn about
terpene modulation if we can learn about
endocannabinoids saturation through
programs like the act now and through
these legal models this is we've been
stuck in a prohibition model for so long
and right now we're in a situation where
I see a lot of people I see the app the
activists that I grew up with and came
up in this some of them are sort of
looking into this new I don't know if
I'd call it corporate model but it's
it's a legal model it's a model that is
not based on a profit margin that's
based on you or me going to jail okay
the profit margin that we have been
making off of cannabis for the last
however many decades has been based on
prohibition it's been based on people
going to jail
that's a terrible dollar that's not a
good market so I think if we contain
these products and bring them into a new
model a mall that is not
prohibition law one that doesn't you
know I support dispensaries I support
every single person being able to grow
for themselves on the license being able
to even trade or potentially sell it
within their community I also support
you know company is doing in our large
level with standardizations that are
able to produce medicine for more than
just at one coffee shop or more than
just five dispensaries you know it's a
big world out there there's 7 billion
people then we all have their dope
cannabinoid systems anything you want
ahead today that's ok there's a lot
there so I look at elegant cannabis
spent like bananas and it's like if you
if we took bananas off this planet what
would happen to the human on earth and
we've seen that even growing up as a kid
look I'll get bananas are we take
bananas out of society everybody loses
protein phosphorus the whole world
changes and we just die from bananas
well that's kind of what cannabis is to
me canvas is a food it's of the disorder
it's a medicinal food it's something
that your body has to have it's
preventative in its management and in
the future that the regenerative so when
people are coming up to you and you're
an old person that's saying ok your
insurance program shows that I can
replace your liver we're just gonna
print one out for you we're gonna slap
it in there you're about 75 so we'll
give you about 80 minutes to recover and
if you don't have a properly functioning
endocannabinoids system where the
servers in that working it may not take
there's gonna be all kinds of crazy in
the future things by the time I'm 80
years old
37 in January so I try to look at
in the future and say how can we lay out
about how could we lay out these things
and I think this is a good start like I
said I'm gonna bring it back to the
resident point of your time perfect and
the backs are a good start because it's
the first time we went from taking
granted but and putting it into a glass
of water with ice and watching the
little heads fall saudis Sam and then we
went to a couple screens we went to play
bowls we've had centuries of beating
beating dry-aged but down it res it down
and to Keith rockin all these different
patches of things and then you get hit
to isolator bags and bubble bags and
then you say okay walking out from two
screens three screens for screens five
screens one of those screens really mean
and I think that's really important to
understand that because a lot of haps
makers just get material and then they
go and then they have these results and
they go awesome is really turn me
this one's really greasy this one
happened this one feels really strong I
tested 70% with this one but if you were
growing through your bags or you were
growing your resident for the specific
purpose you pay a little bit more
attention before you even start process
different attention so you would start
from the very beginning you'd use the
little eyepiece and you'd watch the
little resin heads and you watch how
many gathered together and if there's
not a topside party with little resin
heads and they're not huge like you were
talking about there's probably a problem
and we went to Jamaica we looked at tons
of different
times a different but we watched I
watched bags with you and literally
looked at the 90 bag as if it was just
pulled out of a brand-new step I
couldn't believe it actually
I thought I looked at this at the bag
with the scope because I thought who's
gonna serve pretty on it we don't print
the wrong bags on the wrong screens it's
like we've got that down I still just
couldn't believe it I thought this has
to be like a like a 160 bag or something
it was you knows three days of
harvesting ice first of all to get nice
in Jamaica so he was surprised that I
actually even was able to produce ice in
the middle of mouth know where I was
looking out of ice I've been working on
a nice situation
John was hoppin everybody was helping
than Eric had a five-gallon bucket we
had everything right except the resin
except the resin and resin itself wasn't
that good when you looked at it
you know you looked at it under the
scope first thing we said was bug did
you guys have a drama and was this a
sativa that got dry so we look at a
sativa that's supposed to be a long
cycle it's supposed to be outside for a
long time and you watch how the trichome
have develops and you want to go clear
and you're looking at day 70 80 90 those
are really important if you drop halfway
through it and your heads never develop
well now also you got these little tiny
skinny skinny stalks struck it down
heads but never even developed into a
head it's your little stalks well we did
see that absolutely it was surprising
just to give you a little background
upon the history as we mentioned Saudi
Sun it was the first thing that I've
ever seen mentioned about water
traction was in 1988 and High Times
Magazine saw sound took up the ad and it
was stuck Sully Sam's water extraction
in secret and it was basically the jar
method so that was the first time we'd
really heard about water extraction in
1997 a gentleman by the name of
Reinhardt Dell came to Amsterdam and he
brought a machine with him called the
ice-cold extractor the ice ball
extractor was sold to milla milla the
pollinator lady had the ice-cold
extractor and sitting on her couch one
day Eldon r.i.p Eldon we miss you he's
been passed away a few years now old
school - car shishun and my manufacturer
mark Rose were sitting on the couch
looking at this machine and decided to
held in the shouted out two nylon bags
and screen bottoms and a five-gallon
bucket you got the same idea so this is
the birth of the isolator bags about a
year later I came out with the bubble
bags and that was 1999
so from 97 we had
well from 88 we had Saudis sound we had
a long lapse people didn't get it they
just didn't pick up what he was doing
Reinhardt's machine people kind of
lifted their eyebrows a little bit but
the bags were brilliant
you know melody coming up with the bag
idea and Denmark Rose making them right
there and Mila being the pollinator lady
and bringing them to the world and
selling them it was really that team of
people that made the wallet that's how
when I saw that's how I came along to
make bottle bags and you know we came up
with the first three system three screen
system we came up with the first four
screen system the first five the first
six the first seven the first 8 and I
gotta give it up to my boy Jason from
payload bags cuz he has the only 9 bag
system he got the first one and the only
one so he's a part of it too this is the
history you can read about it on the
internet there's all sorts of different
water house companies now I only bring
up the history because recently after 8
years of being litigated by Reinhardt
who does indeed have a patent for water
extraction I finally just you know
started talking doing like a human being
and we ended up making a deal and I've
now just paid for all 15 years that I've
slowed bubble bags
they've been leased under patents and
our company is now selling
it's good to sort of give those you know
who have a position that it's good that
they earn what they should earn himself
bubble banks is now a patented least
product and it's just you know there's
there's a little bit of water hash
history for you so let's uh let's talk
about what we talked about because I
don't think everyone in the room
understands the different back
terminology and so let's say that let's
say somebody grew their their cannabis
plants correctly and they had a OG Kush
or the OG Kush Davi what bags would you
would you say you would see more
collection of the heads and why in those
variations I think it's important well
in a surprise with the oh jeez you're
gonna see resin that melts in the 160
bank if you've grown it properly you'll
have these big fat 160 heads that you
can catch and that's that's the red bag
that's three bags down that's really the
reason I have the 190 bag a lot of
people ask me why do I need 160 if I
have a 190 or vice-versa and I usually
say well because if you breed really
properly and you're growing these indica
dominant strains endure under HBS lights
that you're going to produce these
really really fat hats and then it's
it's nice to have 160 full amount
I wouldn't say by any means it's my
favorite but I certainly would never
throw away my 160 bag because the 120
bag for sure on the OG is gonna be
straight fire and it's gonna be all the
way down through 90 and 73 45 in the 20
we'll melt as well but on the oh jeez it
just won't be the same quality as
between like 120 and 73 and and that's
really based on the size of the head so
when I first released all these bags if
you can imagine many people thought that
I was just trying to sell banks that I
was adding bags because it was adding
money and the more money that people
spent the more sales I made and it
really couldn't be further from the
truth
we tested tomorrow's and I'm my
manufacturer he helped me out an
enormous amount we tested so many of
these bags he lives in Kathmandu Nepal
so he has no shortage of landrace trains
to pull off the back mountain and run
through the bags I'm in BC if you've
ever seen my youtube channel you
definitely know I have no shortage of
strains to run through the bags so
between you know that was really the
work that Mark and I did was finding the
right size bags it's not like we just
picked random numbers although I will
say that the yellow 73 bag could have
easily been a 70 but I was born in 1973
so I thought that I would throw my year
in there forever
a lot of people don't know that and that
was before the 90 bags so imagine if you
understand water hatch the 1973 are
almost always the best regardless of
strain unless you're growing a tropical
exotic grown land race the teams on a
school in Australia somewhere under the
super hot Sun then we do the heads like
I'm telling you the 25 145 and where I
based that on is I used to have a good
friend named the mom didn't be mad mad
he was from overgrow days and he was
living in malm mama been be in Australia
and his father was part of the group
that bred I don't know if you could call
it bred it's a it's a it's a mix mash of
strains exotic sativas landrace Latinas
the diesel guys saw in the 70s and the
80s in Australia and they bred them all
together and I'm telling you I seen
pictures of 15 plus pound plants 18 feet
sorry 15 feet tall and 18 to 20 feet
wide and the crazy bastard used to send
me his bud and his hash so it was in
fact that breeder Steve's wedding
one of the last joints i ever small it's
going to be 14 years of them now I
smoked a joint at the moment gonna be
madness was steep right before I got
married on the beach of the sava beach
but the the water hash that he sent was
completely unique and exotic and just
looking at it right away he knew it was
special it had tinges of red it had the
spiciest most exotic flavors and it was
25 micro now keep in mind 25 micron i
came out without bag well-known hash
smokers laughed at me they said that is
a ridiculous bag that is immature and
broken heads and you are absolutely it
is proof but you do not know what you're
doing about
I got a lot of flack for it and it was
years before those same companies copied
me and put a 25 micron bag in their in
their kids so don't this on the 25
particularly if you live in a tropical
region and even if you don't
I've heard people pulling out fire from
their indoor crops I didn't when I was a
25 at the 45 and if you don't know Jim's
Hill especially like with the banner we
talked about the 120 at 1973 and the
banners just 45 belts just as good and
it has my opinion it has a little bit
more flavor has more flavor from the
plant and then our test is count up if
you ever had a music studio that was my
past career but we used to have this
little Yamahas that would sit up so we
had these badass huge speakers we had
all this really good gear and then we'd
go to master you've got these little
cheap doll house on and so you listen to
the music and if you could hear every
little thing and those flat sheet
speakers then you need the actual match
really
was correct so when you pull the 25 back
if the 25 bag is flowing on that you
know you got some I mean pretty much
that's a guarantee if your 25 micron bag
is lousy you're gonna have nice hash
throughout the throughout the banks for
sure so I don't know I think we're going
to talk about the future on the future
well the future is what's in your hand
right there
the futures the future is it's
interesting because I think every year
that I think it's important that you
guys also look at the Cannabis Cup is
not a competition of who's got the best
situation right now I think it's good
and healthy to have the competitions
about that of all the people that I know
all the friends that I know the industry
every single person in this competition
and high times on the flowers that
concentrates in the full-mouth
everybody's bringing fire these days
yeah everybody who has step their game
up to an ultimate level and now it's
like okay if I was a judge I'd have to
be going off my preferences and I start
nitpicking well the tip of my throat
just a little bit to make it it's like
clearly witzy nitpicking down so steps a
little bit and I think people put so
much emphasis on like who's gonna be the
first second or third place it really
when it comes down
this so this is like a snow so it didn't
happen in Amsterdam there wasn't an expo
but there's still community they're
still they're still gathering they're
still this this is this is the reason
why we come together to be able to
network with everybody to be able to see
those faces that we see on Instagram or
Facebook and say oh I wanted to try the
turtle and I want to try this dry step
and so it's about inspiring each other
and inspiration and that's what's gonna
lead to the future so if somebody puts
something out and they say okay we've
got turkeys now well it's important to
understand with any information that's
out there you have to be responsible
with that information so now it's the
next chapter well just like we had we
had a library helping each other we had
shot who's making it what machine this
process again you know is it closed loop
where did the trim come from everybody's
got those questions now you should have
a safe for the next with the turkeys
where the turkey is coming from are they
coming from canvas Mattoon are they
coming
other fruits and vegetables are they
coming so technically so you have to be
educating yourselves again I think
that's what this is about the future is
inspiring each other coming together
time to time and time again not just in
Amsterdam but across the world and
really see what climate genetics culture
that people can actually do in the forms
of information that inspire the in those
pockets push it up to the new envelope
and I'll tell you you know it was wet
wash for me why I mean I started also 16
17 years ago with oils my first
concentrates got into water - went hard
on that coating - dry sift and now
literally Tony taking terpenes and
adding them back into both the dry sift
and the wet wash the modulating effects
the zestiness that comes with the hit
it's really definitely it's going to be
in the quicker there's no doubt about it
there may be people that dislike it and
fight it but there's I'll tell you when
we walk around right after we're done
here
don't leave because we're gonna walk
around with these terpenes and we're
going to make sure that you smell what a
pure extract the turkeys and hitches we
sums of use - it's such a great great
flavors I wish we could give them all
dabs of it but yeah usually when you see
us we're smoking so this is kind of new
you don't have to read it I have a rake
it's in my suitcase you have a lot
better information out there when we're
not on the regular I think you're right
what does he talk too much I'm just
constantly smoking hash I was I was
going to start this super event by
taking like a half gram dad and just
coughing until I almost threw up for 15
minutes but I thought that might be
awkward
we've been doing it so you really have
been doing it and you don't want we're
going to see you guys around if you do
come up to us and see us and we've got
the rig don't be shy basically here to
share goals and blaze people down and
share information I know that you know
it's it's it's a wide swath that our
community has we've got people you know
wondering if they're gonna win the Cup
or lose the cup we've got companies that
are trying to sell that products we've
got people that are just here to learn
information and you know then we have
people who are literally here to learn
about the endocannabinoid system and how
it can help save either their life or a
person that they that they love dearly
so I'd leave you guys with check out the
endocannabinoid system group on Facebook
if you guys have information to share or
if you want to learn more about your and
ok automatic system you guys can check
out River Rock TV on YouTube you can
check out United
this is at United cannabis don us you
can do Stu you don't kid with suicide
now Rick stone go right back to now you
can check that out and then high CBD to
do it to the whole man's world of
YouTube you guys can check me out and if
you guys see me out there please come up
to me I'd love to talk to any of you
guys if you have any questions and if
you have any questions for either me or
Tony now feel free to ask away open to
you come out you can come up and even
use the mic if you want unless they have
you know sorry if I passed any of us
coming out and I passed out this last
week I'm sorry
it's from the Turks and - at least pass
that four times a day
thanks Tony we're gonna move on we're
gonna start setting up for tonight we
have to do sound check with the fans and
so forth so right now setup time
the coffee shops there a lot right in
this area of good restaurants all around
here in very very unreasonable
restaurants all kinds of different foods
so once again 930 about nine o'clock the
time to get started sure before that
thanks so much we'll see you tomorrow
thanks very much
you
[Music]