[Music]
opening ceremony yeah hey what's up guys
B man here sitting here with Tony and AR
from DNA genetics and this is uh the G
DNA genetics uh Green Green Room
headquarters room so uh Tony and I have
come down to talk to DNA Don and Aaron
they're in the other room just put us in
this TV set put us in this TV set
there'll be in another TV set I like it
we're in this one we both chroma key
into a different set interesting we
could pick a location we're in we're in
in uh ham right now but we could pick be
back behind us or something Paris be in
check be ing Niagara Falls Niagara Falls
all right we might try all of those but
uh yeah you were going to take a fresh
rip out of the RAR brand new tube or at
least cleaned fresh very well is it
brand new or clean no it's just clean
clean a couple of years already going
here we go with a with
a with a fresh green
red nice nice and light
vaporized styles
it's good that's nice Definitely that Co
sure that's um one of our entries
actually is it yeah yeah it look
beautiful I opened the jar when I got
here I still I love her you know what I
mean I love her I just see it as
something it I could extract resin from
yeah it under the better you can
recogniz I think also the better you can
make your your resin can make a better S
I think it's an important relationship
ship on both of them knowing the herb
and knowing the resin knowing the resin
will definitely help you grow better
herb you see that jar
actually who's who's in in under DNA um
DNA DNA genetics it's really good for
sure I think it has a good chance it's
really nice the only thing I'm afraid
about is it's just like
on Old strain that not old but strain
that we've been using quite long already
but it's a strain that you don't get fed
up of something like that you can put
like we really love our Gooser same
thing counts for an LA you know not a
lot of people appreciate that and
they well I think because so many people
try to grow it and don't grow it like
this true so who grew this that was
grown by K if I'm not mistaken he did a
good job looks pretty darn nice I always
want to pull my macro lens out when I
see flavors like that really just got to
go get some batteries this trip so I can
start shooting macro again today we we
actually got a macro lens oh excellent
yeah we got one
for for us to try and make some nice
nutsh shots we're basic like we were we
said earlier we were talking about
setting up our little light set yeah our
room for us to make our uh week our
weekly
DNA video for the YouTube awesome well
if you guys ever uh require heavy duty
high quality macro
shots let the bubble man know I'll come
down anytime and shoot Buds and strains
for DNA is that 14 hour flight for you
uh no but when I'm in town you know I've
always told these guys every year it's a
matter you guys should set that up I
mean seriously you here till when Friday
yeah but I you know I'll be back again
probably before next year you'll see
depending on where uh where things bring
me nice Mr Dawn I just arrived back from
dinner here at the kulski hotel we are
very very with my good friend Don we ate
very good dinner the Don yes very good
now we we must smoke Legends winner
Sarah out in front of the kulski
hotel you smoke Matt the great Gardener
Tony T the
terpinator
run shall we walk through the kulski
let's do it we are at the K nsky
eron really great idea I love this
hotel straight up that's called the uh
the waiting
room you like
[Music]
that all the way through
okay all the way
[Music]
through I thought there was a nice nicer
entrance into your place a nicer
entrance yeah this is the back way Che
this is the back
way it's the
secret see if Dane is in his
room all right back at the kapulsky
great Gardener just opened up oh a
little bit of 90 maybe is that 90 I
smell from over here oh my goodness
this is the backup you guys you guys
went with the 73 I like that M you know
the 73 upon producing like upon making
it was by far the most smelliest bag but
upon aging now the 90 has now become
more smelly than the 73 it really is
holding that sort of shishka sort of
Barb dank smell totally so yeah this one
smells a bit now though I mean it just
keeps changing right what do you to say
about that Aaron from DNA
genetics um I'm waiting for my head okay
perfect it's DNA food DNA approved DNA
approved DNA approved well here let's
hit that actually I don't know this is
the melts but uh you just pulled that
out so why don't we do a little dabble
doodle of
that here we go why don't you heat that
little piece of bar and then dip it into
the MK okay and then dou and then dip it
up oh that was worked out rather
well wow oh now I'm going to St make it
a churro toss it into the into the
aurro you got toss it into the sugar all
right we have to be smart with Hotel
puffing so just give him a
puff take I'm running that way you won't
need to run but you're definitely not
going to take that whole thing no no I'm
just going to it's going to give you a
nice little oh there you go oo nice
good beautiful I think if you just blow
it there you'll be
fine close enough I feel good about that
we haven't set it off yet it's way up
there and we haven't set it off
yet all right I would love a little dab
of that
puffing on some Barb wash
oh keeping it
reels we lost a big chunk of our group
didn't we is gazi still out there
waiting for and where did Dawn go for
someone to come in where did Tony
go just to Tony's room ah yes Joy's got
the same room he's got a room that's on
the main floor when we came in through
that
little you
[Music]
call what happened
Sarah
[Music]
you that back
in had to
[Music]