[Music]
how's it going guys we're here late
night in Amsterdam after a nice dab
session the DNA guys that we just met
I've never actually met either of you
before but you've been around for a
couple years in hardened yeah yeah okay
cool you won last year I think DNA would
choose no less than the top of the pile
for people to represent them so
excellent Tony had a little thing to
share with us so I thought we'd get this
on film
yeah this is the since we're in the
red-light district I figured the red
light iron yeah this is the red light or
hot pressing pressing so there's a this
is a oil slick so it's like a Teflon
paper so this is the new version of what
people have been doing for a long many
decades which is the cellophane packet
you know there's different pressing
techniques from different countries but
this is the this stuff is pretty
high-tech you can heat this stuff up
pretty high up to 500 degrees Wow which
we're never yeah of course not we're
keeping this around 100 and this is
basically a hair straightener this is a
mini hair straightener yeah as a little
on button here so hopefully it'll work
here because we're in color territory
okay so basically the idea here is turn
that on so here's your little packet all
right we're gonna actually fill it up
we're not fill it up by this is all I
have and I just want to press a little
piece but I'm gonna put the sweet skunk
dry sift into the packet okay it's
heating up quickly so you know very
quickly so I just heated up enough to
get it warm just so my finger isn't
burnt yeah it's really hot it's European
heated up laughing well let's go with
that for now just a little pile and so
you use your finger to the gauge how hot
positives and how what is the what is
the gauge of based on your so how so
pretty warm but not hot pretty warm so
you can hold your thumb there you
definitely not see yes cuz you burned
through it cuz if it's hot enough to
burn you
way too hot anyway yeah so I might take
a little second you ever blew on it
still a little hot yes electricity tears
oh wow its weights mission so much dude
close up on this dry sift that's pretty
nice right there you don't even have to
use that I can just put it close usually
yeah let it out
it looks like and pulled back a little
bit of garlic salt tables like sea salt
garlic salt some pepper like some kind
of old-world spice Pig grind spice type
of thing you don't I mean yeah for
keeping me buried I want to close it
yeah keep close that and then see what
the edges are just kind of fold them up
just not like all the way but just keep
them folded I mean this thing is Skookum
it's amazing how fast interesting you
were turn probably about to burn it out
fast that's what it did to the d-mail oh
really
burned out the whip fast that is forever
it's like I'm still attached that's it
we'll just sure not okay we're good all
right so here let me see what you're
doing here you just doing a simple
little zippity-doo-dah dry sift presses
very nice very hard and hardens very
nice back the other way now because it
was bubbling out and I noticed there hey
I like that you got a little dark on the
color there yeah that's what you want
right there you know so that's where
it's actually pressing in mounting hands
it's just enough to get it started
the best way to close up is have it
pulled all the way back and then I'll
not the camera but the if there's an
easy one and then I'll open it up and
show it to that where Tony can open it
up and show it to the camera I didn't
want to overheat it you know what I mean
yeah I'm trying just he's just a gentle
chase it was a lot though yeah more than
you thought hey cuz dry dry heads are
dense like very dense wide have to risk
going to the electricity thing one more
time but no one's if it open and see
what it looks like it needs a little bit
more if we do put it in the electricity
just put it in for two seconds two
seconds and so it means it's almost
working
chew hash you could put this in your
shoe and walk around Amsterdam all day
and you'd have the same piece of hash in
your possession what I used to do years
ago was heat up a marble slab in the
oven boil some water put it in a wine
bottle and before we went over the
packets with the hot boiling water in
the wine bottle these packets were
wrapped in newspaper moistened with
water
made the wet and then put on the stove
on low and it would steam the water
there we go so yeah it needs a little
bit more warmth and that'll go all clear
oh the smell though yeah that's sweet
sweet skunk smell we can do two seconds
and get a washer it's better to go less
than more the first time yep because
then you're just [ __ ]
you don't want to boil it in two seconds
Bob that one one one two three I'll fill
it out no no Robert don't undress it's
better to go laughs wow that was amazing
fast ready to blow up in five seconds
yeah the nation oh wow it burns right
through skin in four seconds who's ready
to curl their hair that fast a 110 into
a t20 bulb that's the problem it's the
size of my hand yes your electricity so
spark plugs
okay gentle oh that's warm
okay okay that's the one that all good
keep going
nice all the way across I may be nice
thing cleared through this time
you could always throw this into like a
freezer mm-hmm and so I was if lock bag
and then inside a freezer yeah to get a
turn really brittle it's dry cept you're
gonna be amazed at how brittle it is
that's what I was just gonna say when we
open this up it's just gonna be crack II
shatter yeah
don't like when I peel it off it'll
probably even break especially because
it's cool in here that nice cool to air
is letting try this is dry sift friendly
temperature probably about eight eight
degrees maybe a little degrees you know
what we're looking for
all right now peel it off while it's
still warm so you can catch it look at
it because it will crack like it's the
one piece it still fits in is beautiful
let's see if we can fit it back in there
somehow though it's hard why don't we
pop that right now yeah and it is
shattered that's right
like if you even pushed that little ball
down a little bit more I think it would
have cracked are the three pieces let's
do it we're gonna go dab it up
make yourself okay that I'm gonna make a
little smaller God make you h2o shot or
not now when you press it then like that
it's just all right let's see if we get
to to date your dunks
[Music]