[Music]
so it's a bubble man's world and I'm the
camera guy right now so uh so here we go
we are outside the dam cring Gallery in
beautiful Amsterdam we're with Greg from
the dam cring Gallery we got flab 421 in
the house who's obviously brought the
glass to town uh we got Ed Borg in the
house and we got douge from Hitman Glass
so we're just standing out here about to
go into the gallery and check out the
show and Greg and flab are going to take
us through it so what do you guys say
it love The
Vibes I'm this SP yeah
I was like pass me that spliff I want
the
spliff
sorry whatever you want you guys want to
take it upstairs yeah I'll take it
upstairs we'll go upstairs take a quick
peek here but then we'll come back and
we'll uh do the rest down here
good nice
top of the stairs smells amazing wel to
the top floor of the D Gallery we have
two shows running in parallel here we
hosted a show a few weeks ago with Team
Japan Snick and Sal we have a few pieces
remaining here in the cabinet from those
guys and
today you guys are at the opening of FL
421 history in the making we invited
Dave who's a personal or private
collector of glass and to exhibit some
really great examples of the history of
glass in the last let's say 10 20 years
some of the best examples that we picked
out from Dave's collection we've got an
epic M&amp;P piece but I'm not the one
really to talk about this Dave can
inform us much better about those pieces
well yeah as he was saying this is a Max
paen piece and it was the uh entry for
smoke volume 1 a book that was done
number of years ago back in 08 8 yeah
yeah it's a lot bigger in person than
the book and the book you actually if
you smoked a recent mmpv you kind of get
used to them at this size and then when
you see this piece you see how epic it
is with all the marbles and all the huge
lightning cane that he's always been so
well known for yeah totally his
trademark but the marbles really do the
piece so much Justice the honeycomb so
lovely the flower like over here
John check out these flowers these two
flowers right here this one and this one
yeah you come into the back of the pipe
and you actually realize it's a double
bubbler for the first time a lot of
people miss miss that they just see the
one single can can see the second can
which is the big bulb this part right
there that is absolutely
stunning yeah it's an epic piece I'm
pretty sure there'll be some epic
pictures you guys will be seeing as
we're doing this and then this one here
is uh Brandon Martin it's from his uh
box set series from a couple years ago I
believe uh 2012
2013 and um it's just you know it's your
beautiful Brandon Martin work it's got
some nice fume work some nice Line work
it's got rocket in line yeah and it's
got this nice little Brandon Martin
creature on the side yeah one another
massive part of his trademark mhm the
fuming and the horns on this one matches
so nicely too yeah this one's a really
nice piece or the uh the line work the
big hands on the on the little dude
holding the marble up is pretty as well
what year is this one Dave um 2011 2012
I believe this one was done in early
2012 okay rather rather recent like cuz
I got the the number zero which actually
doesn't come with a box okay so um how
did you get with the
Box um I bought it off yeah just you
know it was it was when you first did
the creature Series in the mini tubes
and um he hadn't done the Box concept
yet but it was the first one like
there's a identical height set series of
mini tubes with a creature one creature
on it and then some extra stuff and I
got the number
zero before he ever started doing them
with the
box it's like the equivalent of getting
an artist Pro for the wall yeah like a
well I mean like there's a bunch of like
prototype Mothership running around they
got prototypes actually sand blasted
[Music]
in so what do we have here we have two
small but quite epic little pieces this
one here is a mother ship it's the only
double drain Klein hooka it's the only
double drain Klein made by Scott Dey but
it's the only double drain puka seed of
life it's got a seat of Life perk it's
got a maral top nice little ready fumed
expion G marble on top with the marble
on top there is this like uh ready it's
it's deie did the whole piece okay he
assembled it he blew all the pieces he
did the marble um it doesn't have any of
the hose attachments but this is a uh
it's a fumed marbles fumed ready liion
of course red de and then the other one
is a banjo uh Joe Peters collab it's one
of the three from the queen honeybee
series
it's the smallest of the three oh it
hits like a champ it hits like a oh dude
it's one of the best hitting pieces that
that for small ones that you could
really have really really really pull
hard on that and the water doesn't come
up it's just tiniest amount of water
like Dave showed and it's just it's like
a a thimble full of water full I would
say it's one of my favorite ones i' love
to edit that
though so but this one here that's been
on Mark's show a lot but as it deserves
to be cuz this is one of the one of my
favorites I mean other than Marcel being
one of my favorites this piece in
particular it's the uh Phoenix totem
bubbler it's basically like Marcel's own
personal totem pole as um I don't think
he's ever written about it like that but
I've talked to him about it enough to
know that that's how he feels about it
with the octopus and the Phoenix both
are his uh totem symbols so when he when
he was asked to do a piece for uh smoke
2 Volume 2 um the second installation
from the first book that the max pollen
pieces from this was what he felt he had
to
do cool so with the books David was that
common with the with both smoke volume
one and volume 2 that they were pieces
that were asked either to be made or to
submitt it to the book The Artist the
artists were individually asked to to be
a part of it
yes and this is over here is some of the
some of the things we brought that was
just you know ly around not necessarily
the best stuff in the world but the
ghost piece is certainly a nice one it's
uh from
2011 it's um just a really nice uh
example of sculpted uh glass sculpted
borrow with electroforming um all the
little um pieces that are attachments
are little like household items like di
like it's like a AV converter that's
been electroformed and attached to the
back um one really nice piece on it is
on the back um you'll have to go around
but it's got a freak marble on it freak
brain marble and those I've always
personally quite loved quite a lot yeah
that freak brain marble is absolutely
stunning it's brilliant I better go
around and show them cuz we talked about
it yeah this one's amazing out of it
stand too when you hold it in your hand
it feels naturally form and the weight
is just right on the bottom with the
grip it's got a handle it hits amazing
and it's got like a ladder perk here
down on the it seems like just yesterday
I was hitting that tube yeah about a
week ago actually about two weeks ago
and then this is a s blasted Paco fyc
Toro with Ash capture and I mean it's
it's really nice Toro's lost a lot of
its it's so that's a [ __ ] your crew huh
that's
fyc yeah dude when Mar when they came
out with [ __ ] your crew I just laughed
so hard that's so perfectly Slinger
[ __ ]
totally
absolutely oh yeah Slinger was living in
Vancouver when he first started learning
about the sand blasting and the stencil
work that's really where he got into it
okay
and so we get to be there for the birth
of that it's really nice to kind of show
The Ghost with the metal work but then
show the Paco and with the sand blast
sand different so different it literally
looks like it comes from a different
culture well and even like to compare
another another technique over beside it
here this is a Dave Parks tube you know
a little more modern y design a little
more you know modern art style but the
rap and rake uh snake skin that he's
really known for yeah yeah it's a really
nice example of that it's really nice
example too of a a nice small bowl too
that fits really nicely and you
know we got the swing there too that's
actually that's actually what I need
that's the bowl I need that's the bowl
you need that is the bowl you need yeah
and then we don't need to ah right right
and then what do we have down at the
bottom here down at the bottom so on the
left and on the right it's an artist
that's no longer actually on the torch
his name is Steve Gelb and um he runs a
mountain bike store now and he fixes
bikes and it's too bad he's not on the
torch cuz he's a really amazing artist
and they're just more uh older examples
of some ray gun you got some nice
reversals and
some I think I'll pull out my Gelb
Sherlock in the next couple of days cuz
there's a lot of things at the same time
you you should put them in here I want
to smoke with you the one in the the one
in the middle is an ease electroformed
fumed um direct inject Tu really nice
fuming in the in the dome as well you
can see these kind of like bubble marks
through the bottom my favorite is the
fuming through the middle section the
silver and the gold and the way it's
wrapped is just it's just beautiful
amazing and then lastly but certainly
not least certainly not least because
this is a really this is a really
popular piece but this is the Brandon
Martin functional doll number
one um dome's here in the breathing
apparatus where the the breathing tube
mouthpiece would be on the doll that's
actually a percolator so it's an
[Music]
inline right in
there and then the mouth piece is
the part on the side of the head I like
how you got Forks on the back yeah so
he's he's utilized different household
materials again just much the same way
that ghost did you know and and has
formed them into the different aspects
of the doll Dave the blue color in here
is absolutely incredible do you know if
that was or if that was actually a blue
color that BL color yeah but when you if
you wait until it's night time and the
light and you see light shine through it
when it's dark it actually it's all it's
all see-through okay glasses the light
shines right through it you can see
right inside I realiz but um and you can
see on the back here that he's actually
and not easily I'm sure but he's
electroformed his name into the back of
the piece yeah fantastic so you can see
and TI signature just beside it as well
oh yeah so that it's and that's just
pretty [ __ ] cool that's very cool
Brandon but Brandon Martin's a beast you
know the guy's just a beast so we're
going to host a show with Brandon Martin
in May of next year we've already
started the the work and figuring out
which collabos we're going to host with
Brandon and that's a good show to he's a
guy that really deserves a lot of uh
respect for the work he does he's doing
these fantastic pieces where the smoking
piece fits into
the we're okay everything's okay Things
Fall it's
just so yeah Brandon's doing this piece
that he's bringing down to AR basil in
Florida which has these heavy heavy
metal feet that the puppet fits into and
then you the puet that's the most
amazing one of the most amazing pie I've
seen so that's coming in May well that's
he's preparing that for Miami right now
for Art Basel in Miami and he's just he
and I are working through some of the
concepts that he wants to present here
in May and we'll work with a few other
artists and uh get that going excellent
and yeah we've got some big plans but
it's wonderful to kind of finalize on
this one and
just be incredible work because not many
people are doing anything of this
caliber and mixing the different media
trying to make both a functional and an
aesthetic puppet it's true and it's
really it's nice to make it available to
the public I mean I feel fairly blessed
cuz I can just go over to Dave's house
and see this on his uh his hutch in his
living room exact where it sits but uh
it's nice for other people to be able to
come here and actually see the quality
of the piece I mean it's dangling on a
on a on a chain on a chain right you
know what I mean what a concept alone
right there you can hit it actually like
like you can actually just hit it just
like that you don't have to hit it oh I
see what you mean like smoke from it
while I've hit it with you one time you
have you have one time one time so yeah
that's one of the things that we really
wanted to do here Europe is not very big
on the smoking glass culture because as
you seees yeah we hoping it improves and
that's that's why we're here is to
expose this type of work for both people
to understand the workmanship that goes
into it the type of artists that are
working in this these days and also some
of its scale I mean when you see this in
a photograph you would assume that it
might be as big as a cup when I saw the
max pollen piece in Smoke
I assumed also that it was like a
smaller you know lightning bolt type pie
and then I we pulled it out it's huge
like are you kidding me it's the size of
a so max is a big boy he can blow big
pieces oh yeah Max is like honestly like
holding that glass on a py stick and
like flipping it over a flame oh
[ __ ] you're like w w you know this thing
just right right right circulating it's
very cool well right on I guess we'll uh
we'll maybe go downstairs and take a
quick peek yeah okay one sec go ahead
all right so on November 1st which is
Museum night in Amsterdam we hosted what
we believe to be truly a museum level
glass collaboration that we facilitated
between five artists we have Snick and
salt from Texas the same Elmo fire
studio and we have Yoshi condo Rose rhs
and daito who goes by the name dis glass
also known for his slop work and these
are the beasts that were put together by
the guys over the course of 13 months
The Story Behind These are that they're
all mythical beasts of Japan the show
was called Yoku Yokai being the
shape-shifting ghosts and the Kaiju
being more the dragon demon likee
Godzilla characters the guys worked back
and forth um sending stuff by mail but
also flying down two of the guys from
Japan flew down to the DFO and then
stayed in the United States and continue
to work with the guys so what came out
of it was about 17 beasts of this sort
of Epic nature everything from from the
smaller guys that you see up top to the
more epic beasts in the middle and two
monster beasts that we have downstairs
as well as a few slop
cups very
cool love the slop cups with this one
the next one that you're shooting the
sake bottle all the tiny tiny white dots
the ring at the top and just the tiny
dots in that kind of brick type stack
those are all UV reactive there's a
slight layer under the eyelid that's UV
reactive but the guy is hit it in a very
subtle fashion it's also a really
interesting set of teeth from Salt where
it's a fully circular but Hollow set of
teeth underneath so that Chomper
literally like a circular set of teeth
that would just bite into anything very
cool and this is so cool with the
hanging head so epic we got come on
we've got the ogre and we've got these
silver
formed glass with silver over top blades
that have been sharpened by the guys and
this is the capitated head that the ogre
has
captured
man that's really really impressive and
then at the bottom we have an
interpretation of three different sake
bottles so similar to the clear one
we've got sort of smaller drinking
bottles at the bottom we've got a green
one a pink one and a purple guy over
here each of them having their own
Japanese Beast name as well as we move
over to the right
you'll see just like you were filming
the big cab on the RO the rose roads cab
on this one is similar to the one from
up top with the spider where all the
clear dots between the blue dots are all
UV reactive wow so once you pop a black
light onto this everything that's
clear just explodes and sort of like a
bright I just noticed the woman on this
guy's chest you'll also notice the woman
on the guy's chest softens so she
becomes very deeply blasted at the top
and then it softens around leg so that
there's no Integrity lost in the
structure of the leg my God and this
Beast is called iaya which means a woman
whose face reflects as an old man so you
can see the falling slop woman looking
up at the old man a little tough with
the light in here too but behind the
rose roads eye Millies is also a layer
of UV so this one is very taxle and its
UV uses as well just behind the
eyeballs and we've
got got Nick and salt working on the
hands the and the face the feet are very
obviously Snick and then you've got a
Yoshi marble on the back and the rose
roads Cals and disc glass diece skate
did the shaping of the bottle in the
middle
wow it's
incredible so yeah our goal is really to
start exposing this type of work in the
neighborhood we're fortunate enough to
have uh a Glass Gallery that's been
across the street for about 27 years and
they deal contemporary glass work that's
not functional so we have a nice
relation Rel ship with those guys across
the street where the artists come over
here to check it out and our artist when
they visit love to check out the stuff
across the street very cool what's the
name of that place the name of the place
across the street is called the briotti
gallery and it's briotti yes Christian
briotti all right so that's right across
from the dam cring gallery and if you
guys are looking to look and find the
dam cring Gallery it's located at 395
single in the heart of Amsterdam right
behind the Stout line and right near the
FL uh floating flower market beautiful
well thanks for walking us through this
man really appreciate it oh man thank
you so much for rolling
through
yeah did it yep
cool okay welcome to the main floor of
the original doct Gallery where you may
have been here before and seen this
piece by b feine b feine Meer and uh
Martin was not a part of this it was all
this is a collaboration between Martin
between rer and B yes and it is the cup
winning entry for
201 I believe it was it was it was right
on or next to my booth that year that's
right that's right in fact and then
beside your booth last year did you have
a booth last year yes and was R beside
your booth with the backpack last year
Yep they're always either at my booth or
beside my booth most years I've told
Martin uh he can put whatever he needs
to put on my booth and we've just been
doing that for almost 10 years now so
cool so then part of the extension of
the Yoku stuff that you saw upstairs we
have two sloth cups that are in here
well we call them SLO cups but they're
actually five man collaborations really
hard to see under the plastic so we'll
move some of this stuff out but for
example this one is a great thing to
show outside you've got one side which
has a very saltlike face with two
fantastic ey Millies the ey Millies are
insane insane insane right that's insane
and then there's an IM Milly on the Dome
of a different pattern beautiful teeth
too I know and look at from the side so
now you have both faces you have the
Snick and the salt so we're moving over
to the Snick side now we three different
Millies how about that Bindy
Millie right so are you kidding me now
I'm going to also take the diffuser out
and show you from the bottom cuz this
was pretty special seeing how the bottom
looked how Yoshi's section was kind of P
almost made it look like one of his
marbles right incredible and then we'll
turn it around and you see the same kind
of thing from the
top all right let me get in there
without touching that oh oh
yeah so absolutely outstanding work
there are three collaboration cups
remaining is this the artist up here
yeah this is Yoshi condo he's one of the
artists that we had in our show respect
Yoshi the photos that we have on the
wall are by a photographer named Akiko
Akiko good job Akiko These are nice
shots amazing amazing and she visited
Yoshi's studio and made the photographs
and we printed them up on the wall there
are some making up photographs as well
that were shot by Yoshi himself we'll do
the same thing with a marble and there's
one in here I really want to show you
guys it's a new style marble that Yoshi
condo created specifically for the show
most of his stuff is extremely circular
and symmetrical this is circular and
symmetrical but what you've got here now
is you've got he kind of breaks the
circle on the top and you've got this
character inside so I'll turn it this
way and this would you know to most
people would look like a fairly regular
condo marble and then as soon as you
turn it you've all of a sudden got the
breaking of the circle up here incred
and his new style pendants are like this
Beast inside and the Beast usually you
can turn him upside down see multiple
faces I think Mark bubble man like you
were saying earlier you know these
things this is hours and hours of
entertainment and enjoyment this one's
got yeah hold it right there yeah I've
got an opal stack I'm going to turn it
so Yoshi's signature is right and then
you can adjust so you've got but you've
got a diamond opal underneath his
signature opal underneath an octagon
opal you are kidding me right there's a
and the way that Yoshi explained it to
me is he always puts things inside as
marbles for people to enjoy who have had
his marbles for a very long time so even
owning this for a very long time you
will find surprises in it as you sit
there and trip out on his glass really
and that's a very intentional part of
his work is that you know these are epic
pieces they take a long time to make but
he wants people to constantly discover
things we talking about Gates and reos
marbles they're the same you really deep
universes things floating in space that
are only revealed when you turn them
certain ways great name really for the
gates and marbles the universe marbles
exactly exactly now I'm going to take
you over to see three more pieces that
we have here actually four so I'm going
to open the cabinet so we don't get the
glare mhm this is man onti onii sorry
onti onii are uh know onti onti on onii
are the are actually the sushi and onti
right I was going to say why does that
so it's very close and I kept
mispronouncing it my wife who's Japanese
made sure that I got it right so these
this is I mean what you're seeing here
maybe people don't always know but
accidents happen in glass when the guys
are working on the stuff things explode
colors are not always compatible and
here's a great little piece these faces
that have the wonderful Akio inclusion
in the top we got a Ro miniature rose
roads Millie in this one which just
Bonkers how these guys
look so what happened is these little
demons that you're looking at
here amazing so these demons were adhere
to the front of the feet The Story Goes
that this guy captures the demons with
his mouth and with his feet and Stomps
them and the skulls come through when
these were put in the Kil they exploded
on the feet wow so we still deal in an
area that's quite risky you know Fire
Burns glass cuts and not all glasses
compatible and hot glass cuts and burns
[ __ ] yeah so check out the tail that
Yoshi that's a Yoshi marble that's a
Yoshi stack that's been pulled out into
a tail absolutely stunning and the line
work is so fine in there more Bonkers
more Bonkers and you have all the
different sections in the middle plus
the signature Millies on both sides the
tiny skulls by
Aquarius this is the first time these
seven guys have ever come together to
make a piece and from their assumption
this is the first time seven artists
from Japan have ever come together to
make anything wow so it's really
historical isn't it yeah and this is a
dome that they made that's available
separate it's it's again the complexity
in this is incredible you have TK haa
that did the the Cobalt pull and you've
got the AIO inclusion on the top plus uh
opal underne underneath it you got a
Yoshi stack on the bottom of the Dome
and there are photographs throughout the
gallery and some videos behind me of the
making of this piece as well well it's
great that you guys has managed to um
you know record get video get photos and
really sort of all props to team Japan
they did a great job recording
everything so that we could explain to
people who had never seen this or a lot
of times Mark I'm sure you know people
assume that it's paint it's paint inside
some kind of layer and to really explain
how this dot stack worked here how these
tiny dots in the opal just looking at
the opal in the eye it's completely
insane it kind of floats above most of
uh taka miyake's work is like that
they're two separate colored eyes and
the opal just floats gently gently above
I think if you swing around in this
direction you might be able to see oh
yeah you can catch it for
sure it's cool yeah I mean the
Dome the Dome is also incredible look at
the opal on the top there just
wow wow man and you've got a hop a
signature a signature mil inside the eye
so we're going to move down to one two
more epic pieces we have a Sherlock that
was made in preparation for this show um
very you know should we take one of
these pieces outside to show you the
beauty of them in the light yeah I think
that'd be a great idea Okay cool
so we'll take we'll take the Sherlock
and we'll sure but maybe I I quickly
show you the other one as well maybe
bring them both okay bring them both
I'll shut this for you perfect
thank you you're welcome Alison's got
the can I can I ask you to hold this you
know how to handle epic glass so we'll
get we'll get you to hold this she knows
how to handle epic glass hold this
$30,000 slop cut so this is much better
seene here you see the same type of eye
that you were looking at earlier the
color in in the metal fuming is Cobalt
there's a Yoshi section in the middle
and there's a Taka miak a um sort of
Mandela here too that you saw inside now
this one's really special his DOT Stacks
usually are the color dock Stacks which
everybody is starting to know but I'm
going to turn this sideways just gently
so that you can see that there's metal
fuming between the dots that's popped up
absolutely Bonkers work there's a great
example of the fuming coming up about it
Jesus the glst that's pretty incredible
mindblowing right tight it is so now I'm
going to switch hands here God the top
of that bowl is inous too so I get
haa now what we have is the seven Man
team Japan cup here these guys don't
make cups often there are a few examples
of two three and four man cups and this
is the first seven man cup ever created
it's got a excuse my language [ __ ] load
of um Troutman glass in here called
halflife and team Japan were the first
to get a lot of this stuff it's like a
Coca-Cola colored the I think this is
Black Jack the skull so it's actually
not fully black it's kind of like a
Coca-Cola color and then you've got a
uranium eye I just saw that I was going
to ask you is that a uranium marble in
the eye there's a uranium dot in the eye
that glows focused in on that right now
and isn't it perfectly set like when you
look Beyond it it's like looking at a a
Jew right yeah no it's is a perfect orb
now I'm going to turn it around so you
can see the skull on the back actually
let's just turn the
Dome there we
go wow wow I just realized dude that the
oh my
God it's a you didn't notice the goggles
they're goggles I didn't ey goggles
they're eye goggles until we took it
outside I didn't realize that they were
strapped he just put his eyes up that's
right he's just put his eyes up
unbelievable this piece keeps exciting
me so what we've got here is also the
first time that anybody's gone over Yosi
doubled it up yeah so what you have here
is you have an AKO isumi
um line over top of Yoshi's dots so just
crazy again the use of uranium in here
you have the white dots in here and the
white all the white dots in here will
glow but the middle does not so I mean
this this is a fairly special piece what
would a piece like this um this one
we're asking
$21,000 or about €8,000
and this is there were a few there were
a few there were a few pieces that were
made similar to this that were used to
to fund the trip and to fund team
Japan's work for this one of them is the
Sherlock that we're looking at that for
example is
about valued at about 5,000 U us around
that range all of them are kind of great
pieces for collectors to scoop now when
does when does Ed get to take that home
Ed gets to take that home when he puts
his last down payment on it he's very
close and this is truly an unbelievable
scoop I'm going to Puff it I want to
Puff it too so I mean we're we we really
respect the glass and we work closely
with the artist so we
always aome we usually work with our
collectors to make sure that if the
collectors at any point in time do want
to get rid of their piece we will help
them move that piece so the same way
that traditional art galleries and
museums have helped collectors move
their pieces we prefer to move it with
all the authenticity documents all the
things that we have for it move it to
the next customer that's the case but
we're really here to Showcase
spectacular work now the one last thing
about this cup You' got the signatures
all on the back yeah there we go and I
can see them great yeah so you got from
left to right yeah AIO taka slop Yoshi
condo you've got Aquarius on the bottom
as well and you've got Rose Road
signature whose signature is that that's
Yoshi condo nice yeah that's the YK so
I'll turn it around for you ridiculous
dude definitely ridiculous right
definitely so much halflife in this
thing too and
dude the
goggles oh duck boxes are right behind
the door behind those nice chairs yeah
yeah start start unpacking them if you
guys like then hey you want me to bring
where do you like there's a lot there's
a lot of glass bring some of it up
there's a lot of glass there's a lot of
glass bring it
all thanks for taking us through the
show man that's really uh I love the
impr this too we've got Doug from Hitman
Glass here we've got his fine lady
holding some incredible glass and now
we're going to start showing some of the
torch tubes and collabos that these guys
brought that are just going to be I
can't wait I guess that's next yeah
that's next and then tomorrow we're
going to pop up a shop for some of the
smaller stuff downstairs and we'll host
Hitman downstairs beautiful dude I need
to get some I need to get down there
with some Bubble Bags you know fantastic
idea do it we're
onks Greg thank you bubble
man hey yo
B why the timber Rock feel
give me
[Music]
a one man home man
real the purpose after weed that's to
the
Mind purpose after weed gave by this
exper the purpose after the we l i VI
the time
it is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do it purpose of
ding we I've been traveling to Kingston
20 mil hour sing on like the clock fresh
vation with trees and with flowers off
stop
and give me a
B don't give me give
me give me one big and if
[Music]
bigger I make pass pass pass and
now purpose of the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the we to the
mind after we gave by this
the purpose of the weed L I view the
time weed is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying well I imagine down the road there
be some cops setting up them plat and
and all the all traps man man we tell me
and in my bra St that and behind you
scene me and my team have another
25 we smoke it up
[Music]
CLE my
now and Pass and Pass and Pass and
then and make pass pass pass and
then
[Music]
pass
pass I make pass pass pass
bu