hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh you probably noticed I haven't made a
video for a couple of days got Facebook
uh beeps going off in the background I
haven't made a video in a couple of days
because I was blessed with the birth of
my second son I'm very very very uh
happy about this super duper excited it
happened on August 27th at 510 was 710
somewhere my son was born at 710
somewhere anyway 510 West Coast time he
has no name as of yet but I just wanted
to sort of let you guys know why I
haven't been around is because I've had
this incredible experience and I thought
I would do a wake and bake with you guys
here uh celebrating the birth of my son
I hope that you can all twist one up
pack a bowl hit a rig whatever you can
do smoke one in honor of my of my
newborn son he's happy he's healthy and
uh he's here so I'm going to pack up a
little um
Astro Boy that I've actually had curing
for it's got to be since I left on my
first Jamaican trip it was sitting in
the uh in the Box quite beautifully some
Micron and uh this is to you my newest
little
son
so lots of people coming by in the next
few days um the ones that are Bubble Man
friendly I'll definitely uh do little
interviews with and and have little
sessions with um yeah just super excited
I'm super excited for the birth of my
son I don't often share these things I
do have two two other kids I've kept
them quite private out of uh the social
media
Limelight I just thought it would be
nice because I shared one photo on my
Facebook page about him I figured I
would also do a little YouTube video to
let you guys know my YouTube fam that
are out there that uh you know not the
haters or the critics or the negative
commenters but the people that seem to
really enjoy the show the reason I
haven't made an episode is is a very
valid reason and uh jeez I don't know
what's to do now puff more have one more
puff let's have another puff Astro Boy
was absolutely spectacular maybe I'll
hit some of this seven years in the Cure
right there seven years in the Cure just
found this the other day little older
than my 6 and A2 which I have right
here and quite different in how this
one's
stabilized that's the sound of me
smacking up up against the side of my
Keef box and this one here just stayed
pure grease its entire
life really really greasy uh you can
take a little piece of this and
just kind of Squish it up pretty good
it's greasy so it leaves the tiniest
little
film once you get all the hash off your
thumb you get this kind of little clear
film so I think we'll dab up one of
those dab up a little I'm going to
use the Dabber that was a gift from
another father a good friend of mine
Martin Bizzle from rure Mr
B this one's for you and your fairly
newborn child I guess it's been about a
year and a half
now
oh my
gosh now that is a taste
woo the Astro Boy was very fruity and
delicious this one's extreme
Kush and took
it deep down into my throat I could feel
that taste so those are my celebratory
rips with you my YouTube family please
leave a nice comment please puff a bowl
or a joint or a dab or whatever you can
find Cannabis related to help me
celebrate this all right thanks for
watching guys more great shows coming so
keep watching Bubble Man's World
Peace
[Music]