[Music]
hey guys back at the room here and uh
just about to hit a little bit of this
Gorilla Glue which is I have to say very
much like glue trying to get it off of
uh the piece there was
ridiculous so now I'm going to hold the
camera take the dab and film the whole
thing all for you guys here on Bubble
man's world
[Music]
lovely one more happy customer leaving
with bubble bags these though I don't
know I'm trying to get them in Jamaica
but it's not happening yeah
I'm I wanted to keep the drive the the
dry dad
[Music]
s oh
yes
again highest the
highest yes they looking at me eyes so
red because we find up on Sal head
people always ask me say why you so
humble I don't smoke Co that's why
don't s Med yeah
[Music]
herb must be burned like your tee must
be cleaned rather vital for Spiritual
hene a king Salon certify the tree and
he is the
wisest let's see so you're super
inflamed right Jesus dude those are like
about to pop I know [ __ ] that's pretty
gross so Dr Feelgood Tony tpine it's
going to hook Mr Castle a
lot this is a
uh unorthodox methodology however I like
the unorthodox when the healing when the
when the healing needs to
occur sometimes that's how it goes
down and there's our
31° just like that
Holy
moess so what's it feel like in your
mind
first mind so in your mind or something
oh it was no pain just inflammation just
inflammation itchy okay perfect start
with this but so witchy pulling youro
light let's put this underneath your
tongue and so what do we got there five
five drops of
P2 so this is uh an inactive full
spectrum sublingual just keep keep it in
your
mouth move it around M if you want you
can
swallow just a sublingual and
[Music]
then we're going to take an activated
P2 I'm going to open it up the your your
hand rub that all over your uh rub that
all over your
skin yep see go all real nice
[Music]
oh it really does go on nice hey so you
took the inactive on
your you got another half there that you
can
use so this one's activated so that's
activated
[Music]
P2 which obviously just means it's been
heated so it's active THC or CBN or CBD
this is high CBD low
TC um so it's kill it'll start killing
the
inflammation so why the inactive Orly in
the active being active early just gives
it a broader Spectrum so instead of just
like when you smoke a joint you're just
essentially lighting something on fire
at 451° or edible at 350 if you boil it
it's another temperature so um T and cvd
and canids all and tures all have
different temperatures in which they uh
will change or activate and those change
the experience modulates differently
different
receptors change your response so
instead of um arrogantly saying it's one
thing CBD is going to stop it I'm
telling you well this these five CBD
Rich strains like ACDC R4 Harin sour
tsunami
um Swiss gold just combination of
strains put together so you give it like
the full full spectrum effect so that
sublingual will respond with uh it'll
absorb in his glands go into the blood
and it'll respond with a lock and key um
system for the IND avonoid system so
you've got your cv1 CV2 and what THC and
CBD and CBN does for that so if you eat
it it's differently so that's why
there's capsule forms okay and that has
plethora of CV2 receptors if you put it
as a sublingual it's a direct Ping On
cv1
receptor so sublingual is for a central
nervous system so what I'm trying to do
is say hey we put that stuff
on and he's he's you know hitting that
receptor and saying pay attention we
have something wrong in the body so if
the endoc canono system is uh working
properly doesn't have any deficiency to
keep your body in homeostasis
so that's what we're trying to do here
we're using this as a signaling system
to communicate with us to see if we can
help the information go down and
control may or may not work but that's
how I would use
[Music]
candles put that trans dermal gel yeah
what's up some other stuff so this is a
cvda I want to lock it in and CVN now
you can put this on top so take that
take that cream y that's a trans dermal
gel put that directly on there
yep now this is going to lock it in it's
going to be a trans dermal it's going to
push uh full spectrum cbda inactive and
CVN should be really care it sure felt
good when I put it on my burn this
morning it cooled right down and then it
felt like it was like like I couldn't
even feel the wind or any like when my
shirt touched it felt like it was just
like a little thin membrane of
protection it's pretty sweet yeah it
stays on so ideally you're supposed to
use it like this just straight on
straight on right here and then what
that does is it leaves a little gel so
just kind of do it once and it leaves
like a a nice that's what I call it a
gel and then that's transformal so it
absorbs into your
skin is that good or is that that's good
keep doing keep your foot more if you
want should definitely calm it down if I
were to use cannabis you just told me
that's what I would
use that combination of a sublingual
with a topical and then a transal on top
of
that 1:30 in the morning tonight Kelly's
going to be banging on the door dude I'm
trying to get to sleep stuff's
itching got any of that cream that's
crazy though I know that's brutal man
have you gone in the water at all yeah
yeah the salt water make it feel good I
the cool really s yeah I was going to
say I bet so like I I would take my arms
out of the water just above the water in
my shadow and allow the air cool
it yeah maybe like aloe aloe too for
sure she rubbed aloe a lady rubbed aloe
all over me for like is that how you got
that no no this him I showed her this
bur
[Music]
burning you're burning like boiling bro
last one
awesome well time for dabs
[Music]