all right here we are Facebook live been
a while since I did a Facebook live so
kind of feel like I'm in a weird angle
right now I wonder if I can surround
I'll still make it work that's still
working put my phone kind of upside down
there but it's uh well I've got a few
people coming in here I'll be gear up
for a little song rip while we talk
about cannabis hello Dustin bees
provides James Smith
I see DNA I think I just saw them pop in
and say what's up
Devin Simmons Jared skully I hope
everyone's doing well today cheers to
you as well Chris Jones just at home ah
there it is the DNA representative Adam
holes else key I thought I saw a little
DNA in action in there always love my
buddies at DNA Don and Aaron known those
guys for over 10 years and super stoked
to see kind of stoked to see them
expanding into many different projects
you know they've got their LP thing
going with tweed and they took a little
bit of guff for that but it's nice to
see them hey if you've got a complaint
about a big corporate cannabis company
and you see a guys like DNA go in don't
slag on them give them support they're
there to make it better they're there to
actually not sell out but to actually
make the thing that everyone's
complaining about much better so it's
important that we see that perspective
welcome Patrick and Jos Jeffrey Jenn
Bennett's Michael - Tom McCluskey chili
boo in the house
Matt Armstrong I think it's time for a
little six star bubble hash here
freeze-dried to damn near perfection
it's all about the cold these days
everyone wants to make things cold cold
cold cold cold
I love making hash myself because you
know when you make oil what you're
losing and missing out on I'm not saying
you're missing out on or losing
necessarily but what is not there it's
truly not there there is a fibrous mat
inside the trichome head and that is
where the glandular trichomes bio
synthesizes cannabinoids and terpenoids
cackles and organelles called plastids
these plastids are filled with phenols
and terpenes and they push up into the
upper membrane and in that fibrous mat
is where we basically biosynthesize all
of the known terpenes and cannabinoids
and when you squeeze or extract with oil
with solvents you basically leave that
fibrous matte behind and that is why
there is such a difference between oil
and hash and it's why someone like you
know Haley
Cheryl T's daughter suffer from seizures
like you wouldn't believe they took her
off oil they put her on bubble hash
capsules and suddenly she's not having
seizures for 30 or 40 or 50 days now
that's not going to work with everyone
but it's definitely one of the major
differences between oil and between hash
and why they're not the same thing and
why I love the quiver
I'm never gonna be just an oil or just a
hash guy I'm always gonna want to offer
people the majority of both of those
things that are available hey what's up
Mateen - breezy been awhile since I seen
you Mateen is a smart young guy I think
I think if I remember correctly you you
caked up a little bit of coin from an
app that you made or something and I
remember talking to you for sometime
back in the day on different chats
what's up Archie Archie in the house I
always see Archie at the different
events I think the last one I might have
seen him at was in Jamaica and you can
always tell Archie is so gung-ho he
comes and stands at the booth he's
puffing he's sharing vibes and he's not
leaving for hours he's hanging out and I
like that about him hey what's up Andy
our IP to the X my brother feelin for
you thought about you today was going to
tag you on my post and then I realized I
unfollowed you because you I Andy is the
greatest guy Andy Cale such a [ __ ]
great guy but when it comes to the
internet I found you just to be too much
of a dick and I had to unfollow you I'm
sorry it's just your internet
personality in person I think you're a
great [ __ ] guy I just can't handle you
online otherwise I totally would have
tagged you in the Michelle Rainey post -
today
and what's up philip edward pearson i
hope all is well with you in argentina
I'm about to light up the straight fab
here so let's do it we are hitting the
5-star we are hitting the the westcoast
concentrate San Fernando Valley oh gee
and this is some 73 micron yeah
everything degrades democracy and free
thinking will I still be attending the
karmic up the plan is to go to the karma
cup yes hey dude I think about you often
we had some intense moments together
with your parents almost dying and then
my parents actually dying 93 people
online what a straight fab killing it so
nice to be puffing on some to be puffing
on some lovely West Coast concentrates
it's been a while Tommy West James Smith
Dustin this winter is closed thank God I
live close to Whistler so winter is
closer than you can actually imagine for
me yeah me too Andy me too hey I got a
big jar of buds from d4 20 K maybe some
of his his super [ __ ] fire oh gee
cush I'm not sure if you guys can see
that but trust me that this is who I'm
gonna press this whole jar today of
course cuz I don't smoke the cannabis do
a little don't smell flour no I just
extract the resin off of it that's all
I've got my my little unit
here you guys want to come check it out
are you bringing Terps for the Karma cup
should I Ryan would you like me to bring
Terps of the work to the to the cup so I
got this bad boy going on
she's heating up right now she's at 160
I'm gonna bring her up probably not
quite to 250 cuz that's my hash
temperature but yeah very cool that he
made me this these cool customized
plates - oh man's world
Sasquatch for the win you guys one
[ __ ] press some Roz and this is the
gig right here we got this 215 gallon
air compressor so that makes everything
groovy well if this is if this gets
going I will get back on here and we
will we will check it out yes Ryan I
will bring turps for you what Terps
would you like should I just bring a
couple of packs of each flavor and then
you can pick unfortunately they're gonna
be sealed so I can't be opening up each
one and letting everyone smell all 50 or
30 varieties that I have that's my only
sort of problem with the Terps it's a
tough one
yes only the bottom plate heats up
that's why I have them closed because
the bottom plate heats the top plate up
and that is absolutely the Mercedes
rosin presses Evan Haller 100% man that
bubble hit or that bubble hit got me lit
really nice and strong this sfv og happy
to have a little west coast concentrate
back in the back in the stash I also
didn't really mention it but I dabbed
red congolese with that SFO g SF vog
bring me your 3 faves well I'll
definitely have those that'll probably
be like Karma's [ __ ] cush cleaner and
maybe red congolese something like that
you gotta trust them you gotta trust
them
bring some water hash - well actually
the West Coast concentrate guys maybe at
my booth booth 197 although with the
Karma Cup losing you know what it you
can't see it up very close unfortunately
but I can trust that it's six star its
freeze-dried so it has that really light
color and then on the edges where it's
gumming up and
greasing out is where I've been picking
it off so it's definitely super fire
there's no doubt about that Joey cush
cleaner is fire aah yes they do have a
review coming out of that sfv for the
THC see they better get it out soon
because I'm filming mine today
those guys are busy busy as [ __ ] not
that I'm not I'm busier but I am set up
with camera galore hey how about this my
brand new 4k camera that I bought the
other day I dropped it it's all [ __ ]
up it's making funny funny sounds on the
inside kind of bummed out still films
but it's got moving parts inside of it
so might be on a little bit of a break
for videos once I send that in to get it
fixed my old video camera which is here
I don't think it's gonna be doing the
job that it was doing before so I might
have to start filming on my on my 5d on
this big bad boy right here this is what
I might start filming on for a few
videos it's tougher because it doesn't
have that same ability yeah I know I'm
the worst with electronics crashed my
drone too and [ __ ] up the gimbal on
the camera so it's just you know what
just take it in and get it fixed it's
not the end of the world when you do
these things these are toys these are
use and things that you use to to to
play with and to get to get that gravy
footage yeah and Dornan to be honest I'm
getting it fixed right away and I think
it's actually just a piece of plastic on
the inside that broke and then it's
nothing actually major because there's
no nothing in the camera is affected at
all I've already filmed with it I've
already recorded with it and hey right
on Nolan I'm glad you had a DAB maybe
I'll have one more dab before we split
what do I think about the TCC syrup bar
in cannabis culture all right here we go
great question Jeffrey's in OD I don't
[ __ ] like it at all
I don't think it's a very I mean I I see
everyone trying to take different things
and I can sort of see the perspective of
trying to make sipping syrup a better
thing but really my perspective is that
sippin syrup is really like a scourge
and kind of a tear on the social fabric
it's not good it's not something I would
want to promote it's not something that
I can't personally believe cannabis
culture or the karma Cup is supporting
it but when you have these companies
sponsoring things that's what makes
people say good things about their
products because they have a biased and
they're making money with it oh hello
there mom all that Richardson in the
house hello hello so I'm not a big fun
fan of like keep in mind this
promethazine syrup you know where they
mix in with Jolly Ranchers and sprite
and a few other things vice has a
documentary on it and it's definitely
not Pro you can really see how a lot of
these guys are addicted to it like very
badly addicted to it it's basically like
opioids and it's just kind of all-around
bummer I see it as not a positive and
I'm surprised that it's sort of
squeezing into the into the cannabis
world because I just I mean yeah you
want a sip cannabis you want to do that
no problem but why market it as a syrup
why market it as as lean yeah it is
opioids that's what I'm saying dude it's
terrible [ __ ] now the stuff they're
selling at cannabis culture is not
opioids it's a THC version but what I'm
saying is why even promote and teach and
educate about syrup or lean when it's
just I don't know I think it's negative
- yeah and I really do I'm not I'm not
gonna do it I mean I'm not it's my own
personal opinion so I'm not gonna go out
and do anything about it I'm not gonna
be like I did kind of text Jodi at one
point I think I texted one other person
saying is this for real like a syrup bar
like doesn't that does anyone else think
that that's weird but apparently no not
a lot of people do but that's my answer
and I'm sorry if it upsets you know the
caribou company or cannabis culture or
the karma cup I just I wouldn't
personally take that money I personally
wouldn't even if I was trying to pay my
rent I would just choose to figure out
something else
so just me I mean yeah if it can steer
lean heads away from th see that's what
I'm saying there is a potential Pro but
to me it's a strange thing to grab ahold
of and promote a product as in and if
you look at these companies they've made
the bottle look just like the promesa
these methods een bottles the cough
syrup bottles they it's definitely 100
percent promoted as hey you'd like check
this out we got the THC lean so I don't
know well thank you there Matt we're
trying to send out the good vibes
sex sells drug sell its business sadly
well that's it you know and I've also
never really done that someone asked me
the other day hey you've got money man
why don't you just hire some hot chicks
at your booth and I was like oh that's
not really how I like to promote my
product I know a lot about my product
and I'm not saying that there's anything
wrong with hot chicks by any means I
just don't think that personally I want
to use sexuality and girls to attract
people to my booth to then try and you
know lay into them with the knowledge
that we currently have I'm more like hey
if you want to come by and learn about
something I'll gladly spend a half an
hour talking to you but I'm not gonna
try and bring people in with with with
scantily clad girls and whatnot I've
been doing this for almost 20 years and
I've never done that so that's it that's
it squish on what's up Chadwick Bastardo
in the house now that is compassion from
the old overgrow days he is the
originator of the rasen technique at
least in the original first that we all
saw he and it was different from the
squish you know it was the timing wasn't
on but he was taking hash and you know
in a double boiler milking the resin
glands out of non melty hash around a
metal bowl or a glass bowl and he has
some amazing pictures if you punch in
compassion Co mph JSON and full melt
bubble his pictures will come up and you
can see what I'm talking about they're
definitely on point it's good to see you
Chadwick just a name yeah yeah yeah it's
just a name but I mean I still like to
give props where props or duty or the
first person I ever heard talk about
that
and it wasn't until years like a decade
later that that soil groans was
squishing a bud and it's funny because
even all of that happened for a unique
reason the way Tony was actually using a
small hair straightener to press out his
bubble and I used to always laugh at
these guys because they're like yeah
we'd take the full Mel we put it in the
parchment we close it and then we press
it out into dabs and I was just an old
school like really I just squeezed mine
and my fingers but it was from Tony
doing that that nicotine it up and
others and when nicotine was doing it it
was soil grown who saw nicotine doing
that and he just tried it with a bud he
just you know cuz he was squeezing hash
but when he ran out of hash and he
wasn't squeezing it Faraz and he was
just squeezing it to press it into dabs
and I guess one time he squeezed it a
little hard and a little bit of oil came
out then he ran out of hash and he got a
bud and he thought maybe I'll just try
squishing a bud and he squished it and
literally got results and that's really
how it all kind of came around you know
it was it wasn't like he was watching
Chad's post from back in the day it was
really an accident that happened from
you know some things that Tony was doing
Pat and then other people kind of picked
up and started doing and that he saw
that person doing and then did this
accidental thing and these are his words
he told this story on hash Church 25 or
30 or whatever number it was that that
he first came on and we did the whole
rosin episode which if you look back a
lot of the rosin in from all the
companies came after that episode there
was not a single person creating
industrial presses or using presses to
make rosin at that point it was a hair
straightener thing and after that
dialogue in hash Church that's where it
all started that's where people picked
up these ideas to start making presses
and products and the 50 companies were
born overnight and it's been interesting
to see it's definitely been interesting
to see yeah it sure is Chadwick I agree
I'm doing well Ivan I'm not gonna
complain I think I'm gonna take another
dab with you guys and then let you all
go kind of said I was gonna be talking
about cannabis and I don't know if we
really talked about cannabis at all but
well we talked about hash
that's a part of cannabis this is really
nice bubble really nice thing I'm gonna
go back into the red congolese mmm yeah
just remnants in this jar right now but
I'll tell you these terpene jars are
never empty never empty and if you guys
haven't gone on Blue River extract CA
the Canadian site I lowered the price of
the Jamaican terpenes down to like I
don't know like 70 bucks a vial but only
if you buy the 1 ml so I lowered it very
substantially by 1 ml and you get it for
300 bucks and that's 4 packs of 0.25 ml
so people complaining about the price
don't say I never did anything good for
you all three of the Jamaican terpenes
are available in one ml which is 4 of
the 10 drop files 40 drops and it's like
300 bucks so it's substantially cheaper
than anything I've had available hello
Heidi Handford welcome welcome anything
new happening always something new
happening dude Chad you should come over
one of these days I've got like 20
varieties in my Pelican case at any time
I did not see the price of clones from
Whistler 5 clones for 750 that's pretty
ridiculous I'll have to mock them about
that I'm gonna go see them soon and do a
little walkthrough of their facility so
why not the regular Terps I don't know
what you mean by regular turps
I just got some Blue River from Colorado
love the extract well Evan all the
information is on the website so you
look up the strain you had you go into
the SC labs the the testing area he's
got a big spot that says testing and
then you just go look at the variety
that you have and you can print it up
and you'll have all the information that
you want about what's there hello there
Lisa Lorraine's Werner I'm not sure what
you mean by regular turps Raimondo
yeah 750 s ouch I'll be there first
thing on Saturday to pick up that three
pack Nathan's coming for Terps well I'll
try to have them for you there I'm gonna
bring a bunch of Terps I hope to see you
guys in Toronto have a big session it'll
be great and we'll have some West Coast
concentrate bubble hash as well
well Raimondo because they cost more and
I'm not gonna sell them at a loss the
non Jamaican ones are from California
and if you've ever been to those two
places you'll understand that the price
of good cannabis in California is very
different from the price of good
cannabis in Jamaica we've passed that
savings on to you but we certainly can't
offer it to you with our California
flavors unfortunately I wish I could I
really do but you know what I'll say
this much if you like what I've been
doing if you appreciate all the
information that I share if you've used
bubble bags for all of these years and
learned how to dry sift with me and
appreciate hashed Church and all of
these different things that I bring
including these live video Facebook's
it's not a bad idea to support me in my
new ventures I don't say this very often
but if you have a friend that you think
is great and semaine you and you want to
support them for God's sakes don't ask
them for a deal on their product while
they're starting a company if anything
and they're your friend pay extra they
are struggling and remember all of their
friends are asking for the same thing a
deal and what a deal means to someone
who's starting their new company is for
them just to cut out their profit and
when they cut out their profit they're
unable to succeed in their new business
and the thing that you could have said I
supported that company in early days I
used to buy those packs for full price
and I supported him that's amazing
that's how you keep good companies
around do we want to bring the price
down
absolutely is it going to stay the way
it is absolutely not we are going to
non-stop lower and lower and lower and
lower the price but that's all about
manifesting cheaper pounds being able to
buy more pounds being able to take
control of larger greenhouses there's a
whole bunch of [ __ ] that's involved with
this and all I'm saying is don't always
ask for a deal you know sometimes it's
okay to
support and I'm not just talking with me
remove me from the equation remove my
company I'm talking about your friends
that you know in life that are starting
a business can you for God's sakes
support their business by paying the
normal price do not ask for a deal
it's a horrible non friendship thing to
do if anything well the topic right now
Martin is you know friends starting new
companies do we want to ask them for the
deal or do we want to offer them to pay
the price or I mean I've done this paid
a higher price because I want to support
my friends business and I don't need to
do that for five years but maybe in the
first year or two that I support that
business I won't mind paying full price
because I know it's a hell of a thing
starting a new business it's a hell of a
thing and the taxman is gonna come after
you and the brokerage and the shipping
and the your cost the people you buy
your products from will constantly try
to erase that like everything is an
endless price up one of the things that
with bubble bags that I very much not
done over the years is raise the price I
came out with a high price because I
knew I'm gonna offer a a lifetime
warranty and that's part of the price
I'm gonna offer incredible customer
service and I'm gonna be able to be
accessible to all my customers meaning
you'll be able to talk to me personally
you'll be able to call me up or email me
or text me and I will answer your
question that's something that I do
hey welcome Nick tell oh so that's all I
was going off on about that no one even
asked for a price break someone just
asked why the non cali or why the non
jamaican terpenes weren't on sale and it
brought me to remember this that i said
before in here that it was that it's
okay sometimes to support a business
don't always feel like you have to grind
someone down because here's the bottom
line when you go by the coca-cola at the
grocery store from the multi-billion
dollar coca-cola company do you ask for
a deal no you swallow whatever price
they're [ __ ] offering you now I
personally don't even [ __ ] support
well I probably support Coco coca-cola
through one of the thousand companies
they own but I don't drink coca-cola I
generally don't drink pop try not to
anyway but it's funny cuz people in
India will grind the guy on the side of
the
who's selling juice to put food on his
foot on his table for his kids but
they'll go by like a coca-cola or a
Fanta and just pay full price and not
even worry about you know the the cost
difference there I think that we've
gotten stuck in this very strange
experience of not realizing that because
because it's so hard to earn money and
you know when you earn money you realize
well [ __ ] I can save money by just
trying to get a deal trying to use that
coupon trying to try to get the best
possible sometimes people will stack you
know they'll be like I want the medical
prize plus I heard you got a coupon plus
I heard it's a Christmas discount it's
like often I'll just be like you can
have the bags and I've given away
hundreds if not thousands of sets of
bubble bags over the last 20 years happy
to do that you know and that's another
thing that when you're paying full price
you can know that it's like a almost a
form of any type of you know I don't
talk about my philanthropy but I do it I
do philanthropy and when you support my
companies that philanthropy is now part
of you you're you're a part of it and
it's you know doing things like when
chimera got busted sending him some
money so he could get up on his feet
when Mark went to jail
sending Jodie to see him in mrs. hippy
those planes and hotels and car rentals
all cost money so things like that I try
to do on the regular in my community I
won't post about them and I won't
generally talk about them but they get
done and that's another part of just you
know supporting and paying paying the
price yeah drew I see I feel you you
know that's what I feel
yeah Nick I would love to be talking to
your customers I don't even know where
you're at right now but a smoke shop
sounds cool it's always fun to be able
to if you guys share this on your
Facebook the people that watch your
Facebook's are able to see this as well
so that's one thing that you can do and
that's wonderful any new things with the
charitable or get out it too much the
stuff that I'm doing on the charity but
I promise you I do it I find even
mentioning the few little ones here now
it takes I mention those because they're
long
they were mentioned in public by those
two people but I won't mention other
ones because I feel that if you're just
helping someone so people can know about
it then you're kind of a douchebag and
I'm sure that they still got help but I
feel that it takes away you know
absolutely Andrew yeah that sounds like
slinger for sure slinger is a good
friend of mine we've got a long history
together and that sounds very much like
something that would come out of his
mouth for sure where's the shop Nick is
it in Canada or is it in the US when is
the Blue River getting the beaver Terps
we're working on the beaver Terps give
us time we want to you know basically
find the best quality beaver gland anal
glands so give us time yeah i skateboard
my wrist is still sore from crashing and
whistlers slamming so hard beam has no
need to tout himself ya beam is legit I
like being hash beam is a is a good dude
I'm hung out with him on a number of
occasions yeah I've skateboarding for 25
or 30 years maybe thirty now I'm getting
old holy [ __ ]
you know I'm not Thomas I'm going to the
karma Cup in Toronto so if you're gonna
be in Toronto please come by wherever
I'm at I'll have a little booth I'll
have some turps
I hope you guys come by and buff a bowl
absolutely yeah dude beaver as vanilla
strawberry raspberry all sorts of weird
I have a split board I do backcountry
split boarding I do backcountry
snowmobiling I do I do things I'm very
active person if you guys haven't
noticed in this cannabis world I'm not
really inspired to inhale cannabinoids
and then play a video game for four
hours that literally does nothing for me
I like to get outside I like to that's
if you saw the hash Church I did with
Johnny B the other day I went down right
here in my neighborhood down to the
marina hung out on the dock went over to
the beach went on under my buddy's boat
and we filmed it all and it was really
really quite nice oh yeah mom but I'm
still old in the sense that I've I think
I've been skateboarding for 20 25 years
and then I'm like oh yeah I'm 43 I got
my first skateboard when I was 11
actually been skateboarding for 32 years
welcome bird bird is the word
I don't know Todd I haven't heard that
it was shut down yet I heard that they
were [ __ ] with her venues so knowing
Sarah she will pull it off now it's
unfortunate that we're not gonna have
the wonderful venues that we that we had
but I have trust in Sarah and she will
make it happen and I'm still gonna go
support her and regardless of whatever
you know form that is would it have been
great to have been in the venue that she
built worked on and and organized
absolutely but you know sometimes
instead of complaining and bitching and
moaning and whining we can go support
our friends so that's what I'm gonna go
do I'm gonna go support Sarah and try to
support this karma cup getting through
its third annual event so if you're in
Toronto Friday Saturday or Saturday
Sunday Friday Saturday Sunday I'm gonna
be there all of those days I'll be at
Casa Loma at the haunted house in
Toronto with the crew that's bringing us
there I keep forgetting their names but
they're Annie terpene company something
bear so they're putting bringing us all
there and then I'll be at the event
wherever the event may be I don't know I
don't pretend to know but I will be
there Saturday and Sunday I'm gonna have
to figure out Sunday because I do hash
Church for three or four hours and it's
really right in the middle of the day in
Toronto because it's three hours later
space bear that's it Thank You Jeffrey
space bear is hosting an event on Friday
and I'll try to do a little filming
there we'll see how generous my camera
is with the component moving around
inside of it but anyway guys it's been
great I did enjoy this chat I hope all
of you have a wonderful day and maybe
full melt and I'm not talking about the
faux melt I'm talking about the full
melt
bless your bowl sooner than later and
thanks for thanks for yes I'm going
Friday Devin I'll be a Casa Loma at
around seven or eight o'clock with a big
group of you know Remo and Johnny be and
all these people in the industry that
space bear invited so I hope to see you
there if you're around feel free to come
up to me I'm very approachable person
just try to do the timing right if I'm
talking to someone you know kind of just
lets you know even if we can make eye
contact
I'm talking I'll put it in the head I'll
be like okay that person wants to meet
and I'll come over I hate hearing that
people are afraid to approach me or
something because I'm very approachable
and I definitely want to puff bowls with
all of you so yeah have a great day
everybody
we'll talk to you next time