[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here to show you a brand new little
addition to the Apex pen courtesy of
Johnny B from the Prairie uh Cup in
Saskatchewan d420 K is in the house
what's up buddy hey how you doing Jake's
in the house awesome dudes so we are
packing the OG cush full melt dry shift
into the Apex pen Y and we are going to
use this little guy check this little
guy
out beautiful little piece nice little
bubbler it's
basically take it off all right pull the
Dome off yeah right oh what's that you
got stuck on your there's a n that's a
nug of hash oh nuget hash you just a
gram just for quick reload right quick
reload oh my God yeah that's awesome but
if you warm it up it softens
up so you can you can
basically just put her right
on and go for it all right do you want
to do the honors I'd love for you to do
the honors I'll uh get the nice
okay the
that's a real little Ripper isn't
it man what a ripper or what holy [ __ ]
yeah
all right I'm ready to join this party
gotta like that what's up wow it's real
like comfortable and portable in the
hand it really just fits well with the
Apex pen all right here we go
[Music]
that thing is so
cool that Apex too with something else
you can see it's giving some rips give
off a big rip oh yeah greasing right up
once again Apex with the little mini
bong attachment giving it a two thumbs
up thanks Johnny for a great gift thanks
D 420k for helping me uh test it
out anytime peace buddy peace
all right beautiful