[Music]
holy [ __ ] we're
[Applause]
[Music]
cruising
[ __ ]
wild this is
[Music]
[Applause]
insane
[Music]
awesome
drop holy
[Applause]
[ __ ] drops or something
[Music]
else oh careful there's a big giant tree
there
[Music]
[ __ ]
Johnny Johnny
crazy not
[Music]
far
ho [ __ ] that's a big
one a big one okay holy
[Music]
[ __ ] think about those
apples ow I'm
okay holy [ __ ] right what the [ __ ] is
[Music]
that out the demons
demons know
out good times spting out the demons
demons and the good times
[Music]
oh out
[Applause]
[Music]
the out the
demons this is great this is
[ __ ] Nick's just laughing every once
in a while like what the
[Music]
[ __ ]
wow you never had any crazy
drops I notic
[Music]
that right this thing is [ __ ]
narar oh
really
[Music]
okay good ducking Nick I would have
[ __ ] got you in the
[Music]
face
we're going to go to the
[Music]
lake
looks like quite an
[Music]
angle have you been up this bed
yet Jesus Christ it looks pretty [ __ ]
up dude it's getting really different
angles and
stuff
got usess but not long
fure yeah dude make your left
here finally someone let me out of my
casage now time for me is nothing cuz
I'm counting no a now I couldn't be
there now you you shouldn't be scared
I'm good at repairs and I'm undern
intangible you didn't think so I command
you to
panoramic
[Music]
thinki who appears in you to clear your
view when you're too crazy life always
definition for what life is Priceless to
you because
Theo with bub man
[Music]
and fure coming
onad I
got in
a not the fure
[Music]
the essence the basics without that you
nak it allow me to make this child like
nature you have it or you that's a I'm
in them every sprouting tree every child
of peace every cloud and sea you see
what your eyes I see the structure and
the M corruption in the from this
[ __ ]
andise not as musles but provide with me
as a GU y'all can see me now cuz you
don't see with your eye you see with
your mind that's the end so I'mma stick
around with and be a mentor few
[ __ ] remember what the thought
is I brought all this so youvive when La
is Lawless feeling Sensations that
thought was dead
noing I'm feeling got sunsh in a
bag
feel
andess
[Music]
ising it's coming on it's coming on it's
coming on it's coming on my future it's
coming on it's coming on it's coming on
it's coming on it's coming on my future
it's coming on it's coming on it's
coming on my future it's coming it'sing
on it's coming on fure it's coming on
it's coming on is coming
on
[Music]
really you know where you're
going
it's [ __ ] hilarious
dude oh you're doing good Johnny right
[Music]
there
is [ __ ] tree there you might be
better off there you know you do like
I'm going over the tree looks like you
already
have [ __ ] rights dude and everything
else oh yeah you've been through here
this is
awesome wo
last time you went that way hey Johnny
un [ __ ] you're
lean oh we're in mud right
here you're steering the boat you have
to really
pay
[ __ ] maniacs huh
great totally
[Music]
nuts here we are again chilling out
Carol
Lake this how we
do everywhere we now you see why we use
maintainers cuz uh we're always on water
water you know it's good for making
water has not so much for dropping
[Music]
nugget
tomorrow
tomorrow got put my [ __ ] goggles back
on
[Music]
too right out of that we're
good
our yeah let's do that I'm all about
fresh
[Music]
cracks like
yep except the ones that are dead which
need
[Music]
to back on
that yeah yeah yeah what time
holy [ __ ] was that
[Music]
awesome that's just
Aro
[Music]
ohly [ __ ] is that hot I'd pull it over
in the shade if I were you oh there
camper shade or
what
[Music]
that
extreme