[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here in beautiful Kingston Jamaica
although it is a little bit hazy behind
us right now it was much Bluer Sky uh
before we started sessioning and I'm
with my business partner Ashley uh who's
here on the ground one of our guys on
the ground dude welcome to bub man well
appreciate it man and I guess welcome to
Kingston for me yeah welcome to Kingston
awesome so um I want to talk a little
bit about the conference that happened
recently um that actually happened in
this hotel correct no it was only I
think Event Center oh it wasn't the
convention center okay I thought it was
a Pegasus Hotel so there was another uh
ganja conference and I guess this one
involved quite a few ministers uh quite
a few ministers uh a bunch of um
International companies were down here
the C and a bunch of um grass farian
groups are also presenting a bunch of gr
show it's a mixture of
Stu cool very cool and how did that go
it was a two two or three day conference
yeah it was two days um you know it was
a lot of uh presentations and a lot of
uh question and answer period so he
would go out to meet a lot of Growers on
the ground and a lot of different people
and you know and was a lot a lot of
information was being was being derived
so it brought a lot of Growers out of
the Hill yeah I mean it was probably I
would say half or half Growers there
half sh very cool from par there yeah I
would have loved to have made that
conference just travel plans didn't
permit so I'm here this week anyway to
have you all here down here yeah no it's
super exciting obviously uh Tony from
ukan is with us as well and uh we'll be
seeing our our partners uh John sers and
Vivian here on the ground in Kingston as
well and we'll try to keep you guys
informed the best we can with what's
going on and uh uh you know in regards
to the project that we're trying to get
going here and in regards to even the
amendments to the laws and in regards to
updates on what's going on I I just read
the uh Observer myself I guess there
probably kind of rumors out on the
streets as well as the things that are
being said out of the public yeah yeah
and so what's the feeling for you it's
going to be another month or two another
week or two um I think you know I think
it'll get done probably probably by the
next month or so I guess looking
probably at 30 to 60 days isn't too bad
that's a good uh I think that's you know
I'm I'm also in the guessing game of 1
to 6 months because I just you know it
just seems kind of too good to be true
that this is really happening that
they're amending this Drug law and that
Jamaica a country that is so I mean not
the whole country but definitely like a
good chunk of people from this country
have represented cannabis in in in my
opinion in one in a very impressive way
yes you know reggae culture and rasa
culture um just promoting the sort of
love and peace and this Vibe of you know
we use cannabis not alcohol we use
cannabis not cocaine we canis not you
know all these other drugs so I kind of
really I agree with that sort of
philosophy the sort of the ital
philosophy of uh it's a pure rasco bot
down here yeah absolutely it really is
and just you know it's probably 85 90°
right now beautiful day as always it'll
be the same at night right you got to be
loving that and and I guess love it down
here we should probably have a denail
rip let's do it yeah so we're uh I guess
I've got to go get the hash from over
there but uh yeah going to do that so
I'll be right now all right well look at
that we waited 5 minutes and the weather
basically changed and we got the blue
sky that we wanted so you want to hit
this ash absolutely all right brother go
ahead oo man does that look lovely
melting in the
sunshine awesome some of this FL OG
yeah got
sit just showing you the goodness okay
don't want to be putting that plastic
container on the or is that my glass
Blass so mother shipping in Kingston
couldn't be
happier um hoping on introducing you
guys to some new artists that Ashley is
going to turn me on
to we'll give you a little bit of uh
their music and a little interview with
each one and of course uh we're going to
end up seeing some ganja Fields while
we're here or at least a ganja field or
two uh we might meet up with some of our
indoor grower friends we're definitely
going to hear from prophecy and Richie
see how those guys are doing and what's
going on with them in their careers and
music and whatnot and uh jeez I don't
know it's only day one right I've
already had a ton of good fruit a ton of
good seafood mad dabs under the Fab egg
and uh the sun is beating down back in K
Jamaica back in Kingston Jamaica
awesome well we'll catch up with you
guys in a
bitas
easy never give in never give
[Applause]
in don't you
worry man I he SP I love that one you
know yeah man I was feeling that man
speak to the
mind one of my alltime favorite artist
good to have you uh here with us in
Kingston prophecy it's always a joy you
know Bub man you welcome welcome back to
Bubble man's world you never really
leave I never leave you never leave not
since you first came came and came back
and went to we and give back but I'm
always here yeah that's what I'm saying
but even in bubble man's world you're
always there too it's my world Bubble
Man world is my it is it is you know
you're absolutely uh you're kind of uh
that that wonderful sound in the
background that sometimes for me often I
feel that it's almost well for instance
for this for the video we did with your
song yeah puff and the puff and past so
if you guys haven't seen that on Bubble
man's world go give that a check and
share it in your social media cuz it's a
real cool thing we're we're monetizing
it and we're making some money for
prophecy on that video 100% of the
monetization goes to prophecy and uh as
well as it should cuz it's a killer song
yeah you know I did that song when I did
that song sometime you know something s
ah of the time but I think the
intelligent side of we was always scene
where always we is more than the stigma
that surround Jamaica G burners or the
youth on the street side you know I
always see it as education as as as you
know what you can do the beneficial use
from me medically sure so when I yeah
when I came in contact with the item and
find out how the TLC and the canes
can canabo canabo tricky mouthful of a
word yes and stuff like that I really
say yes now I find the set of ones
really yeah understand more about it's
about issue you know totally it's even
an overstanding when you think about the
difference when people are like oh I
like how they say in some songs an
overstanding more so than an
understanding and there's even a great
lyric I'm not sure if it's a szla lyric
or oh who it's I used to over understand
but now I I used to understand but now I
over understand I think it was in a kzi
who has a song called red eyes she birs
to you know yeah sometime what say is
not all the truth you know so we have to
flip
them
M so how have things been going for
prophecy have you been uh in the studio
at all lately have you been working on
new tracks I've been in the studio ever
since um I've completed about like 11
Tracks already for my second album it's
titled a free man and it's coming out
soon but I'm going to be in the studio
now um from the 7th to the 10th of
February as well okay I'm completing
about seven new tracks just to mix and
mingle with the 11 Tracks my album
really get a balance and a feel you know
really like 12 but you know you need to
have like 20 or 18 songs really fluid
from mood that makes sense yes so and so
um um the song body bags we don't want
no body bags how when how old is that
song well that song was always with me
but um when the incursion come about I
saw the need to really push forward and
really strengthen people you understand
me let them know that the voice of the
voices is here I'll tell you for the
title of the song if I told you the name
of a rap song was body bags it would not
be a positive song but his regga song
body bags but my re song is no body bags
no exactly no body bag body so it's like
it changes everything right it's really
a positive song and it's empowering it
like body I want you to name that song
Still Royal resolution okay cuz in
everywhere of the world you know people
dying and people are suffering and it
all come down to body and to people go
to war for the wrong
reason for the wrong reason you know man
driving in car recklessly crash down
somebody for the wrong reason you
understand me I kill a go last K
somebody for fun
again nobodys yeah no IM r in white she
to you know yeah man and we speak to our
own country you know so so we speak to
Kingston because everybody emulate
Kingston you're in America you're in New
York you're in Japan everybody want to
come to Kingston who want to go to TG
want to go to Southside you know want to
go to P want to go to sa you so even and
I B in always myself I'm dri by K you
want to conquer the city when you come
in the city you find there so much
danger as well as there so much
so you
know
[Music]
already
[Applause]
Church to them leaders of the world to
exercise Justice yes he prophecy don't
want to see my innocent people get
caught in the
street man We
R that he'll find a way to inline
my so they make
it
see always great to have you on Bubble
man's world we're going to hear a bunch
more from prophecy on this trip so keep
watching guys
bless after the we that gives
me the purpose after the we that Su
my purpose after weed gave by this
expression and it's a purpose after weed
the we is not here to check the Mind
here it's only here to do it purpose die
remember let's go downb let's go downb
[Music]