[Music]
hey guys how's it going bubble man here
driving down the sea sky highway with
Johnny B yeah man and we're just heading
uh we're actually right in Squamish
right now and I guess today is a
festival uh Bruno Mars and Eminem and
all these other like 30 or 40 bands that
are that I don't know uh are all playing
here in Squamish uh I guess it starts
today there's tons of traffic and
campers hitting the hitting the road so
we're on our way to drop off some
containers some
medtainers and uh who who are we doing
that with again uh Aurora Aurora right
the kind people from Aurora who if you
guys remember now
these guys were the guys that purchased
my camera for me when it got
stolen
in Toronto so I figured I'd hop in here
with John and get to see a face to face
with them give them a thank you and a
hug and uh maybe even puff a bowl with
them we'll see what happens I don't know
if they're big puffers we'll see well
they're great people and um hey they're
going to be uh big part of the festival
this week at 3day event and uh they're
going to be uh giving away met chanders
to all of the lucky people out there
that are going to be wanting them and
going to be using them so if you're at
the festival and uh hey enjoy yeah dude
right on we're going to uh pull up here
in a second now so we're here at the
Aurora Booth with Johnny just he just
gave a bunch of Med tainers away to
these guys over here he gave some Med
tainers to these guys over here we're
just giving away Med tainers and you
know why tell us are these people here
Aurora right Aurora which planting seeds
we know who Aurora is these are the kind
kind people that purchased me a
camera yeah so today we're at the I
guess we at the Squam Music Festival
it's a 3-day event you guys should see
this box in medane as we got out back
check it out let's check this out so
we're just not playing around here guys
is this the box that Hercules just
helped us unload Hercules we actually
had the real Hercules come down here and
um well guys this is what's going on
Aurora is about ready to give away 6,000
medtainers to all the puff guys out here
dude that's going to grind a lot of weed
look at this look underneath we're
talking probably the most mainers you
guys have ever seen and this Festival is
getting all weekend you could get in
that box John huh you could literally
fit in that box oh we could put a couple
people in here we can ship them back
awesome so that's what's going on here
we should go meet leise and all the
girls that have given these things sure
so they're building a stand here as you
can
see they're all in a bit of a meeting
right now all right well we're slowly
setting
up it's going to be
great all
right I guess we should mention here
that we're at this Festival you can see
the stage over
there we're just all preet up the geese
are ready to party the Canada geese are
like let's get this [ __ ] party
started
e it's not a very Canadian
accent all right so we're at the Aurora
tent with Johnny B and Elise and Elise
from Aurora hi yeah awesome what are we
doing here uh we are a sponsor for
Squamish this year we're pretty excited
and basically we're just hanging out and
letting people know about who we are and
what we do and we're going to be handing
out some of your awesome medtainers
that's awesome we have some lighters and
tattoos and I saw stickers back there
stickers and some crazy photos so yeah
if you're at Squamish pop and see us
we're right by the main stage and uh
yeah we'd love to give you your free
medtainer w you guys are giving away how
many free medtainers 5,000 wow that is
pretty awesome and it's amazing how
happy people are each time I see John or
someone give them a medtainer yeah
people just light up yeah no they
absolutely do a lot of people sadly
don't know about them I mean they're so
practical and so we kind of walk them
through and do a quick
demo we have some other things going on
actually too uh you can enter to win a
iPad that we're giving away nice so
we're doing an iPad giveaway and uh yeah
we have people roaming around for
pictures so check out our Facebook later
and see if you're picture when the
picture of the day and picture of the
day picture of the day and you get
that's pretty cool is it like an
Instagram thing or Facebook or uh
they'll be uploaded to our Facebook the
uh Facebook yeah the photographers Weir
are going to do that so what Facebook do
we go to to look at this you go to um
facebook/ Aurora MMJ MMJ Aurora MMJ
Aurora MMJ so that's how find out more
the Facebook we want Twitter is
Aurora mng do you have an in I mean do
you have um he has an Instagram uh yes
we do Aurora cannabis Aurora cannabis so
Aurora cannabis a lot of Aurora we want
to see a lot of these on Instagram you
go M Tander Canada medtainer hashtag
them on there let's see them maybe we
can give surprises maybe I'll give a
free medtainer box of all of them or
something hey you know what that's what
happens when we're sitting here talking
about good stuff so right on check us
out look forward to it awesome
and I just want to say thank you once
again to Aurora for the
unbelievable kind gift of this camera
I'm still going to be taking pictures
for you guys in the near future you know
who's going to be winning the picture of
the day a I love
it bye guys see you soon come check us
out all right so Johnny B what are you
doing there I'm L fli really yeah are
you
curious are you guys wear the gorilla
outfit no gorilla oh and here comes the
RCMP that didn't take very long at all
we from I'm from Edmonton oh we're out
we're I don't know if you're familiar
but kind of the recently changed the
laws for medical marijuana and we're
actually medical
marijuana um so we're just kind of
generating exposure and trying to
educate people on
up and
yeah the St what we're doing today is we
have containers if you see anybody with
them there's no weeding them or anything
they're pretty cool though they're
odorless and waterproof story your we
it's safe it's so it's something you
don't have to worry about it and then
there's also a grinder
comp so it's kind of two
[Applause]
in get our name out there and hopefully
just generate awareness right well with
the new legal system in Canada and with
you know licensed producers and
everything that's happening party me
yeah it's legal just over the Border I
mean we got we happening worldwide it's
it's a it's it's actually good that you
guys don't have to waste your time and
energy on people medican cuz it's really
waste of money I mean we're here to
educate and it's a great thing about
what we're all
about I guess you guys are here to make
sure everybody stays peaceful absolutely
we wanted to sa for you guys
as the best
very nice there's no doubt about that no
doubt about right that we people have to
hide in alleys when they're medicating
and stuff like that should be able to do
in public places and stuff where I can
take certain things so I mean I think
awareness is the biggest thing and like
you said you still look at as an illegal
system but soon to come will be a legal
system worldwide so I mean it's just
that's it paying attention to what's
happening in the news what's happening
all over the world and what's happening
daily with uh well the new gold is
cannabis it's uh what's changing
everything the new gold
[Music]