[Music]
to pretend to cannabis cup burnin enter
hash please welcome the hash queen of
Amsterdam and the inventor of the
pollinator
[Applause]
guns
and we had our own
let's get pushed up cover shop with time
to wax third place winners for never
match the bush doctor puppy shop with
panty wax
taking their way to the stage are they
there
somewhere
[Music]
okay Mila let's move on to second
are they okay here they come third-place
winners once again the witchdoctor
coffee shop with paddywhacks
[Applause]
which does a perfect
[Music]
let's move on to second place winners
[Applause]
second place winners we're never had
there they are once again returning to
the stage from The Devil's harvest once
again second place winners for shoreline
and solvent lists from Green place
and we're holding four photos welcome
everybody from building yo and now all
right called one quick photo we gotta
move on
okay moving on the first place or never
has Lila do the honors
[Applause]
three tops coffee shop of course Harriet
Franklin Lucca representing the
greenhouse coffee shop multiple Cannabis
Cup winner
where is a better hat
[Applause]
[Music]
a little threesome it's a hard work
pedigree from the supernova range we
know they're gonna be stuck suppose in
May 2009 the way is a really nice
abstraction thank you so much for going
it's really a special lemon crystals I
congratulate you
thank you and now moving on to our next
two hash awards the award for import
hash available to all judges in the
coffee cup and the award for outstanding
has produced by a seed company please
welcome to the stage senior editor Bobby
black and the hem foot lands supermodel
Elina Bannerman's
[Applause]
[Music]
you're different right here in Holland
was that guy not a bad job to come out
here with the supermodel I hope my wife
doesn't see all right why don't you was
any work for us
[Music]
please sort of push
[Applause]
don't believe said that much dr. Lewis
dr. coffee shop for maracas lemonade
witch doctor once again we'll be
returning to the stage you'll receive
yet another award
we know they're here because they've
already accepted one award
let's move on here they are they're
coming Perry comes once again our
third-place winner
second place is greenhouse for Kendall
cream
once again returning to the stage the
greenhouse crew makers up strained
hunters
let's hear it for this incredible hack
everybody second-place winners once
again best in poor hat
[Music]
alena don't be afraid to speak into the
microphone loudly for first place okay
breathe wait for twist line
we will just be a mega tweet blog by
three blanks
here they are everybody thanks everybody
all right that's here first place
winners yeah let's hear it for my spot
[Applause]
all right
and now we do the best each company has
a very prestigious award
and the winners are in third place
Kim blends Ovilus wax from elemental
seeds essential extracts and Johnny true
our third-place winners gettin blend
solvent least wax from elemental seeds
and essential extracts by Johnny true I
here
[Applause]
[Music]
our third-place winners well worth the
wait once again
our seed company as winners elemental
seeds and a centum extract form template
sopla swept up to the microphone guys yo
yo answer damn for real give thanks are
coming out this is a collaboration y'all
every time it's a team effort so I got
to get much love and much thanks to
these central soldiers up my attention
soldiers in California ending McGwire
Joni trill who brought me through this
product and pick up two elements each
[Applause]
see that picture when you step outside
touch hope you got a second all right
the Whitewater og from dog walker okey
doke that's right Twitter second place
in EE hat
[Music]
once again waiting for our winners most
likely floating up to the stage okay
folks let's not pose on the stairs let's
let other people up at Cape assist them
I think right now second place winners
receive company hash white Walker okie
from Gold Coast extract let's hear it
winner
[Applause]
James James step up your language
condoms you want to say something to
your your fans
[Applause]
[Music]
would be here without them
Thank You Amsterdam all righty guys
way to go gold codex right
alright guys you're going say the last
person on this bus I just want to say
this is my 18th cannabis cup here in
Amsterdam and this is my home away from
home and High Times loves Amsterdam and
I hope that Amsterdam love side times so
hopefully I'll be back for 18 more the
winner of first place lemon cleaner
oh geez everyone's
[Applause]
you know thanks hi times everyone who
voted for us
got a big shout out to crying love
marijuana cider out of Denver come on
girls 11 G flowers the flowers this is a
[Applause]
recycle retain the future concentrate
this proves that it can't be done with
the unit like this that is run safely
[Music]
[Applause]