[Music]
[Applause]
thank you event and now for our first
award of the night for best food the
prize for the vendor who provided the
most outstanding experience for judges
at the Cannabis Cup Expo
please welcome our cannabis cup judging
hostess Melissa
coffee
hello everybody here thank you for
coming for best booth in third place
since he sees sexy
[Applause]
they are
all right everybody congratulations to
cover the second place in first place
after the picture I'm linking there's a
alright first place everybody first
place for best the best
here he comes let's hear it for my the
master of keys battle of people disease
Thank You winning a first place for best
booth in 2013
and now moving up best front at the
Cannabis Cup Expo
please welcome hi times marijuana maven
the lovely Morgan Rhodes
[Music]
[Applause]
I'm here to present the best
in third place
sublimator bye
winner best rock sublimator which will
sublimate you to an extreme are they out
there supplement winners a third place
if you're on the way to the state let's
scream it out
since we don't see those guys yet moving
on the second place Morgan
second place it's cloudy cloudy for the
house standing sink repents lobby
providing an outstanding experience
throughout the week
those guys have been great with the
Pratt
[Applause]
[Music]
we still get it later everyone
sublimator here is obviously supplement
himself well I'm really excited to give
the freedom fighter of the Year award
because that's what I think this event
is ultimately about it's about freedom
that's what we all share and I think we
all understand freedom in a way because
we know what it feels like to have our
freedom taken away sometimes needlessly
but we're here in Amsterdam and we're
living in a world that's changing really
really rapidly
and it's not going to change itself
we're all gonna have to take part so if
you love freedom and you love cannabis
and you're ready to dedicate yourself to
cannabis freedom let me hear it now
everyone who just take a moment and
picture of the world where every single
person enjoys that freedom and that
cannabis how does that feel
alright well then let's welcome a woman
who has dedicated her life to cannabis
freedom and the freedom of people as a
public defender and as somebody who
helped run the campaign to legalize
marijuana in the state of Washington and
send a message to the entire world that
we're done with this legalized it
legalize that we did it and it's gonna
happen everywhere and we owe a big big
thanks to our freedom fighter of the
year for running that campaign and
inspiring the world
Allison Hongkong
let's hear everybody our freedom fighter
of the year
Ellison Hulka
I really hear from the United States and
so today's Thanksgiving Day writes a new
magazine
clearly appropriate to be receiving this
honor on this day because I am so
grateful that pipelines magazine that
the cannabis cup had been fighting the
battle to keep this treaty together to
keep this community safe and to make
this community free for decades I want
to thank my time at the top for doing it
[Applause]
before I went to work on the initiative
by the to compete in the or I went to
work for the American Civil Liberties
Union watching to the same I was a
criminal defense attorney for over a
decade and so many of our family members
so many of our brothers and sisters have
suffered the battery ran at the door
facing mandatory minimum sentences of
five to ten years literally watching
their children be put down on the floor
with guns to their heads all because
they were growing a plan all because
they were enjoying the grief of enjoying
that plans and that is why I decided to
take on the work that ultimately led to
this day and I'm just filled with joy to
be able to share it with all of you and
thank you all for being here and your
office is learning my tennis Magnus
[Applause]
we really gotta let Allison hear it if
you leave the state
[Applause]