oh man in Chester back we're back in
Amsterdam here again at the dams where
we almost got killed by you do not want
to miss around these trails they will
thank you anyway the last day in the
cannabis cup 26 annual annual cannabis
cups lies here in Amsterdam we're on our
way to the milk bag the Milky Way and
the lights a plane and we're going to
see the awards we're hoping we're not
gonna be too late not so so but we'll go
check it out I don't put too much stock
myself into these awards but I've got
friends that have entered and I love to
congratulate them
you know reports and absolutely so we're
gonna go get some video with the milk
bag of the awards we'll show you some of
the winners and we'll probably go pop
some bowls with some of the people who
placed in the bowl what's up Johnny
there's Johnny Johnny's front of us trap
tuck tuck here hopefully I don't fall
out
yeah hit down the milk today see the
last people in the last day it's always
nice to go to the awards show and see
the people I've seen they're cool no no
we'll check it out we'll see who wanted
for best hash I'm gonna go out on a limb
and say it was water hash oh yeah it
usually is we're waiting for parking
little bit of a delay
I'm with one the last time yeah that was
good I thought he was gonna do it get
that wheel over that curb you take a
ride with the girl in the scooter g'bye
Oh Fabiola
you know Fabiola yeah cool
well you got you've got more days here
the way
alright cannabis cup walking up to the
milk bag going right by the Polly Dee's
there's always a police station always a
police station at the Cannabis Cup ooh
nice KTM Duke 950 adventure
so here's the milk bag and this is a big
lineup a real big lineup
[Music]
I don't know what what's that hey okay
yeah I'm good to see ya oh nice he's
gonna tell if somebody's a Chester and a
hora gay yeah Cannabis Cup he's
beautiful wife in John
[Music]
[Applause]
five days naked has Bobby who will win
the coveted Canada stuff all week long
over 2500 buckets example the finest
cannabis products in the world finally
tonight we award the cannabis cup for
best defense
best sativa fest vibrant and three
categories of happy once we honor the
best product best booth the best glass
of the cannabis cup Expo also High Times
presents the annual freedom fighter of
the Year award and the High Times
Lifetime Achievement Award and we induct
a new member into the counter culture
Hall of Fame
our first Dutch member all tonight at
the 26th annual High Times Cannabis Cup
Awards
now please direct your attention to the
video screens for highlights of this
wonderful week of we