very figure in the world of cannabis and
to present this award please welcome the
senior cultivation editor High Times
Magazine Danny Danko
welcome hello Amsterdam hello canvas
coat welcome to the 26th coat this has
been amazing and this is an amazing
award it's named for dr. Lester briefs
women who planted a seed years ago about
marijuana the forbidden drug medical
marijuana and all of its wonderful forms
of this wonderful flower that we love
the person I'm giving is the war two I
think most of you know if you're if
you're that they love with the cannabis
plant the way I am you certainly know
the name this hand planted a seed with
words of book that he wrote an article
that he wrote in high times for over 30
years oops a road that sold over a
million copies you counted all the
bootleggers well over two million copies
heroes the marijuana Bible that we use
to grow if anybody learned to grow from
the marijuana Bible please no good cheer
you know to call up call for Hayes Rx
and high times for over a decade summer
leaders back he handed that mantle over
to me it was an honor to take that over
for him and it's called dear panco now
it was for case RX then and now he's
published in over 20 different magazines
and over 10 different languages his
books have been translated in seven
different languages and these are scenes
that are planted and have repercussions
long after those plants have grown out
and
that knowledge and that spreading of
information is some of the most
important things that have happened for
marijuana over the last 40 years if you
agree with that give us a chair the
quality of our marijuana the quantity of
our marijuana all of it has been
improved by this incredible man whose
humble and gentle and a wonderful
console and a badge or to me as well as
many of you it's an honor truly a gift
and a better wonderful moment in my life
to be able gingers to stand and give him
this award named name for another
wonderful man and all the lovers and
connoisseurs of this plant should
rejoice in these wonderful heroes that
we have so without further ado I want to
bring am on stage for me Cervantes Jorge
Cervantes everyone winner of the Lester
Grinspoon Lifetime Achievement Award
let's hear it for Jorge
Holly
Wow hey uh wow this is some this is a
bit oh gosh look at thank you thank you
daddy look at this
this is pretty amazing to me
young person is not
which is a CBE hi aunt important phrase
hiding something concentrate on two
hours and real nose up yeah three broken
up in mind these
embodies of the city on the industry
we all know what scandal so for cvd on
culture play the truth place goes to CD
single CD simple winner is a fini
concentrate by the hem company c company
cvd simple are they here are they on
their way
either way to the stage
we are going to hear much more about CBD
in the years to come everyone CBD has so
many miraculous powers to heal illness
heel pain eel skin ailments it's a
miracle ladies and gentlemen winners of
CBD concentrate CBE simple hemp ebony
seed company
we're producing CBD are
congratulations winner of best hi I'm
done with CBD concentrate cv decent
all right I'll gato this move on to the
highest level of CBD and flowers okay
and these are world goes who can athani
gonna mingle seats all right late night
with john b al the alchemist and Rico
the sublimator and his beautiful wife
congratulations guys third prize at the
Cannabis Cup best product thank you
that's awesome shoot a middleman yeah
sure God's what I'm saying yeah awesome
very cool sublimator well deserved well
deserved well design yeah did one better
right on and well-earned will be hanging
out back in Canada soon all together
yeah 2013 cannabis cup peace