[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am freshly back from Jamaica and instead
of uploading all the Jamaican videos as
I would normally do after a trip what
I've noticed is after I've uploaded four
or five or six of them you guys tend to
get a little bored and the views go uh
substantially down and uh I want the
Jamaican videos to get some nice views
so I thought I would intermix the videos
that I
do in between uploading the Jamaican
videos so first off I wanted to start
with
saying a very happy birthday to my good
buddy Johnny B uh it is his birthday
today we usually celebrated in Amsterdam
but today uh you know we're in Canada so
I'm hoping on seeing him later on on for
some birthday Puffs and for now what I'm
planning on doing is I've loaded up my
sled I'm actually sweating like a maniac
I got my Leafa on ready for the winter
out there and my my old crew from up in
Whistler Ryan and Dave some great guys
have called me up and they've said we're
going to go sledding today it is early
the mountain only opened up yesterday
but uh you know if the Mountain's good
to ski on the Mountain's good to sled on
so that's what we're doing today it's
going to be a small Adventure we're just
going to go up I'll I'll record a a
little bit on the GoPro probably won't
be too much fancy riding going on but
definitely some epic views and I want
you guys to join me and puff with us
each time we puff I'm bringing the
denail in the battery sorry the
dabinator in the battery my denail
doesn't work off the battery uh I'm
bringing my mighty volcano I'm bringing
my Atmos pen I'm bringing a bunch of
hash from a variety of cool people like
d420 K and uh the West Coast concentrate
crew uh myself uh Horatio I've got a ton
of great [ __ ] to hit up on the mountain
with my friends so I guess with no
further Ado why don't
we hit a
bowl got some beautiful things that the
West Coast concentrate crew brought me
uh just the day after I landed actually
I'm not sure if you guys can see that
but you see the quality on that there
right so that's some real fun full melt
bubble hash right there and I got to
give it up to those West Coast
concentrate crew you know I always think
of them as a solventless Company the
company does make a lot of BHO and other
things but these particular guys um Adam
and Brett and Phil they're really on the
solventless quiver so they've got the
dry sift they've got the rosin they've
got the wet wash and uh you know really
they've been doing a wonderful job at it
so uh my hats off to all of you guys
let's see if we can't get a nice little
wake and Baker in here the stuff is is
just so perfect it just self- presses
you know you give it a tiny little bit
of a finger
and uh you get
that so very nice very nice little dab a
doodle I'm sure someone's going to
comment on how my finger was dirty
but I'm smoking it so don't worry about
it we're doing this Whistler thing today
and we're going to be in the Whistler
Back Country so we won't be on Whistler
Mountain obviously uh They Don't Really
uh they frown a little bit upon taking
sleds onto the mountain but uh we'll be
across the street actually either on
Brandy or Sprout so who knows maybe
we'll see some of you guys out there and
uh let's have this hit and start making
our way up to Whistler shall
we yummy
all
right wakey wakey now that we bakey
let's get on with the show see you
there well we just went by Furry Creek
with which is actually the golf course
where Adam Sandler and Bob Barker got
into the fight in the movie Happy
Gilmore kind of wanted to film that for
you guys uh hopefully on the way back
it'll still be light out and I'll be
able to just film going by it and add it
into this little spot because uh ah it's
a cool spot when you see the hole and
recognize it right by the ocean there a
lot of you might have thought it was a a
lake so this is the last little spot
right before Squamish so the Pacific
ocean which you could probably barely
see just ends up here and then there's
the glacier in the background up there
and I guess soon we'll come around the
corner and we'll see Diamond Head as
well and then we'll be into the uh
Tantalus mountain range Tantalus
mountain range has been in countless
snowboard and ski videos as well as sled
videos for that matter it's a pretty
epic Mountains they're very European
esque very pointy and sharp uh not quite
like the ones you see up around Whistler
and and blackholm which are a lot more
rounded out even though you you can find
some peaked out mountains up at Brandy
Wine that look uh almost French
Alish line up here I'm not sure you guys
are going to be able to catch it I'll
try to give you a little shot of it yeah
there it is right there so that is the
mine that if any of you uh watched the
go uh the X Files uh there was a lot of
scenes filmed there in there in
particular the one where Moulder sort of
sees the gray aliens in the silhouette
of the hallway that was all filmed up in
uh this little uh mining town britanna
it is called britanna mine good dirt
bike trail dirt biking trails up up on
the mountain up to the right here and uh
great salmon fishing over here on the
left all the salmon that spawn come up
here and then of course you also have uh
cocon e and some uh rainbows that you
can pull up out of the waters up
here all right coming through this
little little mountain range that they
cut open and you kind of enter the
Squamish Valley and uh I you end up with
some pretty pry beautiful Vistas up here
just past the ocean you end up with um
Miran Lake right here so it's a pretty
cool little
Lake Side of the Mountain and there's
also some really beautiful Trails just
up to the right up here all right so
coming around we have the big chief on
the right on the left you have Diamond
Head and uh just up here is Shannon Fall
is a really beautiful uh waterfall the
first signs of winter a little bit of
frost and snow just on the side of the
uh on the road there and uh we're
getting closer all right so here we have
Shannon
Falls give you a little view of the
falls it's quite a beautiful
fall I've gone up to it with d420 K if
you guys want to get a closer look at it
it's about all we're going to get for
now all right just rolling through
Squamish we just entered Squamish this
is uh pretty much the valley of Squamish
houses and you know a bunch of shops on
the left here and we're just going to
keep going straight on
through well we have made it into the
bush [ __ ] just got
real so obviously we got to head up here
quite a ways because the parking lot is
uh there's just too much gravel and [ __ ]
ice this would be brutal to try and
drive up on a sled so we're going to
head up this mountain as high as we can
and then we're going to park and take
our sled off and uh go see if we can't
go have a little fun all right guys so
we just got here to sprout we're about
to uh head up where our last uh member
of our party just got here and uh We've
driven up a fair bit up the mountain and
uh now it's time to get up there and see
uh see what's going on got the GoPro got
the atmos hanging around my neck brought
the mighty pen uh brought the um
dabinator with the Fab egg and the
quartz crystal Bowl so we're not going
up there light by any means uh we'll see
you up there it's my life it's my life
it's my
life and it's your life it's your life
it's your
life but if we come to together for one
[Music]
life we're coming from behind
behind spiritual
Warriors are on a
mission showing the world of a
spiritual Warriors tring from
behind tring forward at this
[Music]
time so let's turn let's turn the
tables yes I and
to turn the
table turn the Paradigm around yes deep
program and
[Music]
reprogram free
mankind Spirit you un
Warriers are on a mission
showing the world
of spirit you un Warriers trotting from
behind trotting forward at this
[Music]
time we the mind set of the people cha
children true true children seeking for
the vi the way
go I and I come to freedom freedom with
a light in the k
[Music]
spiritual
Warriors are on a
mission showing the
world
of spiritual Warriors ding from
behind ding forward at this time
spiritual
Warriors are on a
mission showing the world
of
a spirit you un Warriers tring from
behind ding forward at this time
[Music]
I wouldn't
there nice maneuver this guy's a [ __ ]
Champion
bro well right now I think he's got to
you
think scratchers
[Music]
he
a
[Music]
oh
[Laughter]
they say there will be
salvation I said there
[Music]
be there will be no salvation here and
there until the PO their cries are
[Music]
heard so come now my brothers
all to the call
[Music]
oh
yeah rich man cries are heard my Hiding
man cries are heard then why then why
why can't the poor pay now for the poor
they've been crying out for these many
thousand years their vibrations are
traveling throughout this world oh yeah
so come now Brothers all and to the
call
one one un the word
one but you and I crying out for Unity
that's what God
said that's what marus said m
and now those of you who read the books
of Prophecy that's what the prophet
said that's what they all
say
and got to come
[Music]
now to but it's only going to come
starting with you and you and you and
you yes better got to come now just
better have got to come but it's only
going to come starting with you and you
and you
[Music]
and yeah
yeah we doing it we doing it we doing it
well what what what what you going to do
now with the Judgment so near at hand
what what you going to do tell me now
what you going to do hey hey you see the
blood blood blood of the poor my heart
and soul how far back here Dr and Lena
oh yeah
[Music]
they never showed up there
hey yeah hard to one person
what
[Music]
what always nice to have that Creek
right there when you blow up your beers
yeah and Destroy cream of I like when
you pulled out the like spinach and was
like what the [ __ ] is this I thought it
was spinach too oh that's my
[Laughter]
weed there's Ry guy what's going on we
were just taking a a 5sec break the road
to the easiest it's ever been well then
let's go do it the water to do it I have
cream of everything in this pack it just
[ __ ] destroyed everything look at my
bag of weed yeah let's go look at your
bag of weed cuz it's
hilarious all right so
here's the bag of
weed that is a
serious welcome to sledding [ __ ]
travesty that's a travesty right there
don't all right we got up to the top
time for a beer and a puff yeah bro
woo oh yeah it's such tractiony riding
nice to find some no crust somewhere but
I don't think that's happening and I had
no idea like really well going up there
I saw you got little bus and then you
got on top and hit it again nice that's
what you need to do because if you just
give up every time that happens you'll
be [ __ ] you see I ended up on the
wrong side of the slope down there too I
had to tweak it around yeah know I saw
that you're doing really
well you have to be a little aggressive
for sure are these your first days or
what uh first day of the season but
you've been sledding for some years no
like last year I've been riding my old
500 on Sunny Beach days oh yeah yeah
sort of this is that's a bit bump I
think I'm only three three years in
maybe or four
maximum and he hasn't been riding that's
on her own either so definitely it's a
bit more oomph than the
[Music]
500 oh one man
going purpose after the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the we that to the
Mind purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose after the we l I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of time
ganja is not here to trick the
M it is only here to do its purpose of
that been tring to kingst
hours fres vation with
[Music]
treow give me one Bigg and if
bigger give me me
[Music]
I
make could that up the now before BL
that
[Music]
hey buddy what's up R how's it going
Rave want some food you to give him a
little something yeah break him my piece
of my sandwich off it's right on the gas
cap
yeah sandwich oh he's got some [ __ ]
tuna in
here he's not going to miss that yeah
I'll give him give him one more piece
here
dude are you serious bro he'll come back
he'll come back now we just turn around
let him give him give him a
minute he smells
it you're right you're right Brian the
way he walks is super funny he's just
like I'm just going to Waddle on over
there is it lunch time you freaked him
out with that did I yeah oh well yeah
I'm just I'm moving too much for him I
guess he's he's coming again I I have my
back to him to give him more
it's when you make that noise that he
turns around really yeah now he's coming
back again he's like very close what are
these people
doing apparently they're feeding me fish
little guy M there you go see we're not
so
bad we're not so bad at all hey guys so
we just got up here to the top of sprout
Whistler black home in the background
got some West Coast concentrate I think
we're hitting the purple candy purple
candy rosin here come check that
out very nice so we're going to do that
we're going to have a dab it's uh I
almost have to heat it up in my fingers
before I can pick it up cuz it's so
shaty what was that
for roll that in my fingers you hear the
wings flopping on the Raven what's that
you can hear the wing Wing flap on the
Raven yeah Beauty all right
so I also was crazy enough to
bring the Turpin yeah buddy do some TP
dipping now I already hit the Gorilla
Glue plenty in Jamaica so let's pull out
something that we didn't have in Jamaica
o Girl Scout cookies heard about
that's the one so we're going to do some
purple
candy let's make this nice so it doesn't
break it's it's it gets so hard that it
break that it uh it wants to shatter so
I just have to change the the shape of
it so I can get it in and out of the
bottle we're just going to do a real
quick TP dip there we are up to 461 de
the dabinator and the battery are
working hard for
us all
right and of course
you know when we're sledding here in
beautiful British Columbia in the back
country we uh we love to bring our ships
with us so I thought it was a bit of a
Fab egg sort of a day and uh
535 de in climbing I'm going to go up to
about 600° just because it is pretty
cool up here I'm going to do some TP
dabs little modulation up here in the
just most epically beautiful Back
Country this is day one for me some of
my friends have already been out for day
two but uh here we
go it's
ridiculous smells amazing I know
right oh my
goodness the flavor on that
ridiculous as I spit all over my Dil I'm
going to break one off for the cameraman
cuz I know he's anxious yeah
buddy would you like one as well um I
guess I would try that yeah yeah of
course well sounds
good let's do the turp J Greg's coming
back you can hear that just cracking on
the ice right it's not great conditions
it's beautyy up it's so beautiful for
what it is you know so freaking
beautiful up here so one dab does like
one
toast I mean you could take this in four
or five to you want to hit
this down there man it's [ __ ] awesome
over there all right nice did you want
to hit this
okay ladies first it's nice there's a
couple of intimidating little bits could
she get
down she stays not too
intimidated yeah don't smoke too much of
that you want to hit
that she's like I think she as she be
set it should
be all
right time for the
cameraman this is [ __ ] Steep Hill man
yeah that's crazy that Hill I the same
line not the same but I went with
before 38 throttle delay it's just it's
intim going down if you picked the wrong
line some water she took too big of a
hit hey Elena got some water here back
this and then maybe a little juice after
that it's 100 times better in
there 100 times better you think I did
the calculation I think it was somewhere
around that somewhere around that all
right cameraman should I stop filming or
I'll just take the
camera oh Greg can I steal some of that
there you go dab that in not in the hole
but in the
moat oh
yeah a little hard on your nerves right
this is this is what we're talking about
right
here proper dabbing did you get it a
little bit you want to hit some there
probably some smoke still in there yeah
and then just drop the rest of the dab
in
too and we'll cover it
too now let's get you a fresh one
careful that's hot don't touch your
finger around there
got
a you know what let's decide when we get
there [ __ ] uh put you on a of me
remember you were saying like it's even
like difficult these guys are gone as
long as you put the right line there's a
there's just a bit of a ridge in one
spot but if you going on the WR side of
it you're going
to but you guys punch the line they got
a line in there's no track
you're the first track there's nobody
there just follow someone down and just
stay in the track right and then when
you're down the bottom you can decide if
you want to try it or not and uh one of
us will go behind you and if you can't
do it you'll come up with one of us get
and not like one of us will take your
side off it's not a problem we'll get
her
done it's I like how BR the snow it's
different not the same it does have a
crust but not like this it doesn't get
the sun it doesn't get the late day sun
because of the bowl there day sun now
but it's not it must be not getting the
early or something cuz it's definitely
not as
crusty point is like even me I'm like
destroyed
da serious man yeah serious
business that thing is serious
bro don't let yourself get [ __ ] don't
react as you bounce
arounda
like you know should
try yeah this is really bumpy and um
it's got wind
effective like I went up there to see if
I could jump
down can I do this yeah absolutely yeah
I don't think you'll have any
problem and if somebody struggles we got
or we can just if we do a couple of
loops on the same run you'll have a nice
easy run just my hand that's bugging me
holding my [ __ ] and my finger
together ends up like doing a
little yeah that happens to me sometimes
too you just got to get the blood going
stopping right here was good yeah well
it's going to be a day of like go set up
hang out for a bit go set up hang out
for a
bit Yeah I won't pull this thing out
every time anyway this will be maybe one
other time at the end of the day I'll
pull it out we'll get a nice top of that
Ridge with Whistler black in the
there I just love that my [ __ ] shuts up
tight yeah dude you know what I'm
saying pay attention you'll be okay all
right guys so we are here in the bottom
of the bowl one of our friends ended up
in a hole up there so Dave's going to go
check out see how she's doing
um I think she'll be fine we got enough
of a of a crew here that will yank her
out of that hole no problem but uh give
you an idea what happened here this is
sledding right here
boys
boom all right Dave
[Music]
that
now purp of the weed that keeps me
going the purpose have the weed that's
to the
Mind purpose of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of when I imagine the road there be some
cops setting
up TRS man us we
and tell me your and upon your scene
inter in my brain that and behind your
SC me and my team have another 25 for me
smoke
[Music]
it
uhoh God turn
[Music]
I'm
making and then
[Music]
all
right starting to feel a little more
confident
[Music]
all
right
all right so there it is that's the end
of the day right there put something on
the lens I'm going to have to take that
off that was an incredible incredible
day on the
mountain well thanks guys for coming out
and joining bubble man's world for some
good oldfashioned redneckery and fun we
definitely had a good time say goodbye
to the crew see you later next time
[Music]