[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
and as you can see I'm not in my normal
regular office right now today we are
actually in behind my house up one of
the local trails that splits off and
goes to a few different mountains
locally but yeah I've got the KTM out
here today so we are going to maybe get
up on the mountain head up to the
waterfall have a little session just
show you guys a little bit of GoPro
footage as I've got my chest mounted
GoPro which should give some pretty
decent visuals of the trail it is
freshly wet so we'll try to make sure I
keep wiping it as I rip through trees
and they hit the front of me because
it'll obviously cause water droplets and
whatnot so why don't we head on over to
the old guy of starting starting the
bike styles let's go over here and start
the bike old guy style
[Music]
[Applause]
nothing
baby my name
[Music]
Hibiki
a week
[Music]
well yeah
original indigenous here back
[Music]
give me my
original indigenous dear condom
[Music]
ha
I'm perfect
because
here
in FBI
my
original
here
all right so I just got here to the not
quite beat really the end of the trail
this is really just the beginning of the
trail for people that want to hike some
of you may have heard recently there was
five hikers that passed away right
behind Lions Bay on Mount Harvey
well that is indeed the trail that got
them to where they breathed their last
breaths very sorry for them always a sad
story to hear about people dying in the
mountains especially when you come from
Mountain culture and you love mountain
culture I made it to the waterfall
nonetheless rainin so there's going to
be some rain falling on the lens here we
could potentially get ourselves into the
trees here sometimes I climb up there
and have my staff but just down in here
is good enough we'll see what happens
this is the trail that I came down that
led me right up to this point which is
the waterfall so why don't I go and try
and find something to set up where the
camera won't be getting too wet and
we'll have a quick couple of pups
I think maybe a little bit of
conversation and that'll be it for this
nice quick short video a little bit of
dirt biking a little bit of water
falling and of course a whole lot of
puffins
[Music]
alright guys sorry for the lack of
talking just kind of gearing up getting
things in the go here so I've got a
little bit of that dry sift oh nine
cookies rosin right there for your
demand and I guess we're gonna probably
just do a little dunk this stuff's very
buttery and basically is not very dab
friendly when it comes to the dabber so
I'm gonna heat up the piece sorry about
the loud background noise of course
we're right next to a waterfall so it's
going to be fairly loud sorry about that
but maybe enjoy it I'm gonna get back to
my pipe and we'll see what's going on
here
[Music]
my dunk ready that live down here
sickly might be going for a decent-sized
dunk here
all right back down
twenty-nine seconds still feeling pretty
decent it's gonna go up 45 seconds just
because we're outside and hey when
you're outside it's never a bad idea to
hit it a little bit early so here we go
hit it up everybody
perfect low temp tab just puddled
just because we're on the bush doesn't
mean we have to be savages of course I
still have my DC glass cleaner and my
q-tips
although the glass cleaner is not going
to be very useful at this point in time
because truly that was a perfect perfect
low temp tab that brought my my banger
back to where it needed to be Talia that
was so exciting I think it's due for
another one what do you say one dab to
dab three dabs four let's hit a second
one I'm gonna put the cleaner over here
for now lay down the dabs cue tippers
all right I'm gonna go keep this back up
and be right back
eating it up out in the boonies my
favorite place to be for any of you that
truly know me this is where I love to be
out and out in the forest out amongst
the waterfalls out amongst the trees
keeping fierce
on the on the timer I find that timer
man I'll tell you hitting not that early
- that was at 45 seconds last time it
was definitely what I'd call a pretty
nice low temp tap there's my dad for now
little guy
Rasen rip we're at 23 seconds my FZ
because you need an ofc you when you're
dabbing in the in the backcountry
beautiful okay getting up to 40
yep yep yep all right let's do this
now that's what I call a ripper
so they're perfect low temp dabber
huddling huddling if you will nothing
better than that right there
all right because we hit a couple of
dabs there we're gonna hit the DC glass
cleaner I like to keep it in small vials
to make it portable and easy to use nice
and easy
steams out any dirt and debris that
might be caught down in there any little
burnt sort of nasties they generally
come to the surface with the DC glass
cleaner if done correctly so definitely
stoked on it
DC glass cleaner for the win all right
well I think I'm going to get back on
the bike it's been fun I'll give you
guys one last little shot of the
waterfall and yeah maybe I might ride
you out on the trail and just at one
point in the trail it the ride will end
and the music will come on so I know not
everyone's into dirt biking but for
those of you that do appreciate it thank
you for your time 450 KTM exc is the
model 2007 if you were wondering
I've been the sole owner of this bike
and it has been an absolute pleasure to
ride it all these years let's finish off
with a little waterfall and then I'll
head out on the bike
Shuler kind of real cloud like I say
[Music]
[Applause]