[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am back at high integrity glass art for
an absolute heater of a review we've got
now for the last 10 minutes off camera
I've been trying to remember all of the
names of this pipe so we went online and
we found uh Emerald glass actually who
has a similar piece uh has written
pastel rainbow ready sleeved over Fire
and Ice re Wiggies so this is obviously
ad DOA AKA The Banger hanger which I
really kind of like that nickname piece
is
absolutely beautiful the Chug on it
without the Banger in it
serious I don't know exactly what kind
of perk he's got in here but all I know
is there's nothing blocking the
mouthpiece from the perk and you get no
water even touching your lips in any way
no matter how hard you
pull quite a bit of reduction once you
get the Banger in
there can really see it and hear it you
can almost feel like it's a like a
silencer has been put on the piece I've
got some beautiful um cookies rosin here
that we're going to be hit hitting up
I've already got a little piece on the
Dabber and of course I couldn't help
myself so I dipped into the into the
grape ghost Blue River Tarpin for the
wind so without further Ado this piece
is just beautiful Dosa man you're
killing it bro there's no doubt about it
and I'm really stoked that high
integrity glass art is nearby and I'm
able to always visit because I myself
don't collect pieces on this level
anymore not since the late ' 9s so it's
really quite an honor always to be able
to come and and and hit a piece like
this I mean my God look at this thing it
is
absolutely
beautiful oh yeah just hitting it dry
brings me joy come on that's
ridiculous all right here we
go this part I'll probably edit out cuz
I hate the sound of the torch
you do that right about the tip like
that I read a little article where they
were talking about the hottest part of
the
torch closer no I just go side to side
then up but that's fine you go side to
side in your mouth it's your Banger
that's fine Banger etiquette how about
that nickname that the Banger hanger
good all right let's uh let's do a
little little time
marusi got to have your timer on these
days thank God for the
iPhone and I've been told a good 55
seconds heating this Banger up and
waiting about 55 seconds gives a really
nice not too hot not too low temp uh dab
but something that will be quite
substantial I'm sure got my little dab
on the uh Dabber right there with a nice
selection of Blue River
turpins and I'm pretty sure we're going
to go through this entire group of TP
means right after we finish this quick
little video of this little review of
the Dosa Banger hanger the level of how
many how many layers he's done here is
is really quite incredible I mean I've
always just been impressed with even
single layers of of ready wigwags to see
how tight the lines can get but once you
start overlaying them one two three deep
it it just becomes a whole a whole
different dimension to the art so pretty
stoked on that we're at 55 let's do
[Music]
this bet you guys are peeping this carb
cap this is a special Dosa carb cap
totally joking we don't have the carb
cap right now so we're using this
[Music]
had a little JS technique there moving
the uh moving the dab
around God when you hit that so perfect
and it just cleans to just perfection
that's how you want your Banger looking
after you have a nice dab right there
really
nice well that was so nice I felt like
we can't just do a one dab review we're
probably going to have to hit something
else we've got a little bit of the
Lindsay here we've got some Congo and
we've got some pink I said we go pink
little pink pink hush for the
win oh yeah yeah that's that's looking
right proper right
there you guys can see
that oh
yeah oh my gosh just beautiful
all right well let's get ourselves one
more little dab here for the for the
Dosa review so far I'll say the pipe
feels incredible in the hand really nice
feel to it obviously before you touch
the pipe you can see it and you you're
realizing right away that this is this
is a serious piece of glass it's on
point
artistically um the the work is
ridiculous the the Reed and the wig wags
are completely ridiculous
and I'm also really really impressed
with how well it feels uh when hitting
it with and without the uh The Banger so
let's get another TP dip that was the
grape ghost that we just hit um I've got
ACDC I've got cush cleaner and I think
I'm going to have to go with the cush
cleaner pink cush and the cush cleaner
are going to create a really nice uh
aftertaste that is for sure so let's
just get that in there get that nice
cushy taste in the back of my
throat and I guess we'll do this again
there we
go yeah fits great in the hand I'm
really loving the fact that the pipe
blowers the glass blowers are making
pipes a lot smaller these days when I
first got into this in the mid99s early
'90s pipes were much bigger when I got
into rure of course rers were huge they
had big 188 uh glass on glass
connections that were you know designed
for buds to be shoved into uh into the
bowl and uh and go like
that since then even companies like rure
have been creating more and more
reduction smaller uh carbs uh smaller uh
glass joints and just making everything
a little bit tighter you can see quave
with his Banger and how he's got a
really nice tight tight area that goes
down and opens into a 144 uh I think
there's something to be said for not
only the placement of where he's put
that tube in the top of the banger but
for the size as well you can really feel
it when you take a hit and obviously um
you get used to your your different
bangers and it's uh it's not quite the
same when you hit a pipe without
one at the 32 second Mark we're going to
hit our final rip of the
um the Banger hanger beautiful job Dosa
and uh yeah if you want to uh I don't
even know if it's for sale I guess in a
sense every pipe is kind of for sale it
is a a high Integrity glass art who is
currently uh holding and uh admiring and
loving this piece oh yeah 55 seconds
let's do
[Music]
this wow the tping on that were
incredible
a real take your breath away moment
wasn't almost anticipating the strength
of those cush cleaner Tarpin interacting
with the pink
cush that went deep probably going to
cough for the next five or 10 minutes so
I will bid you all a j thank you so much
for watching Bubble man's world thank
you Dosa for putting out the top quality
glass and of course thank you for being
our gracious host high integrity glass
art you can check them out on Instagram
and on Facebook and on all the social
medias so thanks for watching Bubble
man's
world see you next time
[Music]