[Music]
hey how's it going bubble man here
welcome to Bubble Man's World um got the
the lucky uh I'm the lucky guy today
that gets to hit the Joe Peters uh banjo
collab with the Dosa crushed opal
Mothership honey
bucket and why don't you light that up
CL I have hit the mini queen but this is
uh the first time I've ever actually
gotten to hit
the the goddess and she looks great look
at that detail in the from the base
going all the way up up slowly to the
goddess
herself beautiful thank you
[Music]
Flav for
that is quite a piece the recycler
back that was the
d420 K
sift and uh thanks flab for uh the
amazing
piece talk to you guys soon