[Music]
hey guys how's it going bubble man here
and I am with great Garder great Garder
himself is in the house he's come to
pick up some clean hash and we've
decided we're going to play with the new
ceramic insert that is not ceramic at
all
o but it
is sapphire so the boys at denil have
created a sapphire insert it's different
from ceramic no doubt it almost feels
like a thin composite plastic or
something he so we're about
to give that over to Matt he's going to
put a big old snake of some Barb
99 and we've got a brand new quartz
crystal Bowl here all clean as a whistle
that's never been hit and we're going to
just lay that right down on top of there
so very exciting Matt's going to get the
rip and I'm going to get the film so
here we
go let's see if we can get that out y
there we go beautiful holy smokes that
looks really nice all right
well I
guess get
my light all situated here
have you got
uh something to put it on with oh there
you go look at this guy he's a
thinker he's a
thinker so award-winning Barb 99% grown
to near Perfection by Matt and his
wonderful team at the house of the great
Gardener and decontaminated by the
bubble man
and I have to say it's a beautiful thing
to watch that boil away and bubble like
that that is real real nice looking I'm
guessing the taste on that is just
absurd all right I'm in
[Music]
now I'll tell you something
interesting the end of that
hit tasted like the beginning of a
hit would you say that's two thumbs up
for two tiar
down oh my God God two thumbs up GG
blast GG
blast
heyo why Tim feel good give me
[Music]
a man man
realp the we that keeps me going
the purpose after the weed that's to the
Mind purpose after the weed gave by this
expression the purpose after the we l I
view the
time with is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do it purpose of
D well I've been traveling to kingst
about 20 M hour sing
on FR with
[Music]
trees pass pass pass
make pass pass pass
[Music]