[Music]
you been it's
4:18 I don't think we're going to make
the museum in time hold on but we are uh
I'm here with Todd and Lauren hello
there they are oh hello and uh we're
going to head down to the uh to the hemp
and hash Museum Ben droners Museum
beautiful Museum that he has here and
we're going to do a little hash church
so you guys will probably see hash
Church before you see this but uh you
can come back and watch this our little
journey to the hemp and hash
Museum we need
weed I got weed so you just have that in
your favorites well yeah I do right now
we're set up to roll I like it and
you're getting your 420 spliff ready
yeah yes we are actually quickly as
possible you know NL did a little thing
he was telling me yesterday where he put
everyone in handcuffs and told them they
only had six minutes in the back of the
police car with their weed and if they
could roll a joint and smoke it fast
enough they'd get away with it it was a
little like publicity stunt really and
dude he said after he was done people
were actually coming up to him with
their own weed and asking if they could
be handcuffed to try
it that is quite funny oh dude it made
me laugh I was like you know what nol
you you're a good guy I have an
adversion to him handcuffs cuz of had on
so many times oh my God how about NL do
you know nl's story no how many times
You' been busted when he escaped the
Spanish authorities and jumped off the
50ft wall into the ocean here H uh
that's you don't know his story dude
listen his story is
unbelievable Hey look it's my
name just for the camera guys just for
the camera
L Mansions all the way to the street
end I mean
man Beverly Hills got the idea
definitely y take second right Antonio
Lopez then turn
left well jeez I'm glad I'm going to be
spending a bit time with you barely seen
you guys since I've been here all right
this is not the one I want we're
busy that is not the street I
want this is here turn right then turn
left play car on
play not trying to run over humans you
know no but you did do do the stop
symbol and then say go I like that sorry
no no I like I was like that's go Go I
mean at first I was way big then it was
like they got the message they did the
peace sign was pretty much work it was a
hippie gang sign yeah I would not kill
you gang sign yes whoa little boy you
should look up when you walk I'm just
going to throw that out there
kid he's like walking with a brace and a
cast and I
all right so trip this is see this where
it says museum
museum not yet yeah right there oh yeah
now I do um and my thought is is that I
stop for a minute we unload and then I
figure out what the [ __ ] to do with this
car for a minute dud I have no clue oh
there's at so let's unload hey I know
you let's unload our [ __ ] yeah boys yeah
we're going to unad all right you see
um the
which it's for set up for the the camera
set up for the the
Hat yeah that's what cameras and such
yeah yeahuh
so where do we go where we go yeah where
do we go set up we we're doing a live
Google stream here today um I don't know
I okay no problem
[Music]
your your your event here tonight
because it's room that we've got the the
Wi-Fi beautiful yeah that's perfect one
sure either or this is
great very nice you know which kind of
space you need yeah
just some seats and a little table so
maybe
yeah
sure great the S maybe yeah we'll turn
the music off for
sure excellent wow what a nice so this
is the musical room the musical room
yeah I like it well we can begin for the
first room if you want Black Sabbath
right on the
box beautiful building
so in this Hall we are talking about the
architect and the modernist St we've got
here on the
building and the visit
the what's
that oh yeah all the visitant have a GU
like this one and inside the gallet so
you have all the information inside so
not so so many people know that hen
marijuana is the same plant and this is
what we exp here that's cuz we lied to
them in the '90s when we wanted to grow
hemp we just said no no it's a different
plant it's a cousin and they were like
okay all
right well this is where we explain that
it's the same PL yes exactly we have
some we've got some illustration here
very hard so people know that everybody
know about the Canabis so many many many
times ago it's a classic old photo right
there yeah different
variety hi hi good how are you how are
[Music]
you tired I'm so
tired bag in the watch giving us the oh
we get a
[Music]
tour we're doing a little
tour great this is the bik room the old
Master room with all the painting all
this painting take about the smoking
smoking yes we've
got from unbelievable follower of
Hendrick Martin Sora Farmers drinking
and
smoking look at these guys they got
their pipes and their
[Music]
hat 1650 to 1670 for that
it's
proper it's a proper Museum yeah it's
amazing it's really in the past room was
for the dance you know okay the dinner
everything I think this is a great thing
to do for this
room the pipe room World
seriously man what a collection I mean
look at how we saved our history how
much of this would be lost that's right
has it's incredible
now that's a big
pipe right from
Africa Africa
wow
serious I I suspect that is a
ceremon and then I remember I have
thousand of these what am I
think totally impressed with the quality
of the art and the um collection that
Ben droners has amassed
here amazing job Ben this is really
something special if you're in Barcelona
I urge you to come here and check out
the marijuana and Hemp Museum we're
about to start hash Church in the next
hour here but I'm going to take you guys
on a little bit more of a tour also
game wow the light it's ho also come upo
yeah from the the wick and and they are
smoking Wheats with uh mix of tobacco M
so it would be post Columbus yeah
[Music]
yeah the the
sailing the fiber fiber yeah depiction
of one of the ships of Columbus y
where's the oh here we go I was going to
say where's the 8 foot backstrap Loom
there it
is H importance of the h
incredible
[Music]
h a day back in the day they to break
all day long hey you know what they
called this right
here the hardest job known to man you'll
never see a man doing it it's always a
woman always a
woman big strong arms on those
women you have yeah yeah super strong
strong ladies right there oh that right
there okay I'm telling you listen I'd
spin all day long compared to doing that
work right there that's horrible hor
look at the combing then
afterwards man they got it done though
didn't
they think
[Music]
very impressive Museum
oh right there from spinning your yarn
to looming to your canvas yep that
is love you B at that old break he's
done an amazing job yeah there's the
break right there on the
ground
legit needs to break some hemp there it
is boys
what an amazing
place it's pretty
incredible I thaty going to come back
here well there's the car parts yeah
yeah the doors oh there's the
decorticator the champion 2000 we we
bought or not the decorticator the
Harvester har we bought one of those
from Manitoba and we brought over a
Dutch guy to uh Harvest it that was in
95 when we got our first just made a
decorticator it's inest right now in
Canada oh nice Jack there he isy buddy
there he
is
this wow that's what we like to do way
they come they say Secret Cup
[Music]
it and just you know