[Music]
Hey guys, Bubble Man here. I just got to
the Spanibus Fair. I missed yesterday
unfortunately, but ended up having a
great day spending with friends Ramon
and Ricki. I bumped into Jiga and Flux,
you guys have seen on the last video.
And got myself a nice little table set
up with the Davinator and water hatch.
Wait for people to come up and say hi.
And I guess we'll photograph and video
some dabs and we'll see what people are
doing. Hopefully Jeff Church shows up
later and we do a little bit more rosin.
And uh yeah, just stay tuned. We're
going to have a lot of fun here today.
Heat
up
here. It's the 90.
Which one did you put in the super club?
The
90 figure. Interesting that the 90 cakes
faster than Oh, this one. This one's got
This one was has been open now for 3
days. This one's still on its second
day. Oh, wow.
Interesting. So, she's got the Waro. The
Waro crumbled right away. Really?
Whoa. It's just It's just It's just Holy
[ __ ]
Surprised. Looks like waxies.
Yeah. It smells smells so good, dude. It
looks smells so a lot of email dabs
right there. So, I need some new I need
some new
Yeah.
Booyah. I just want to smoke it. I'm
always happy when the great gardeners
come
by. Do you have a zap tool around? Yes.
There's one right here. No problem.
Sometimes with that, you just heat it up
a little bit first.
Oh, did that smell good?
Wow. Nice work. That was like
professional. Oh yeah.
[Applause]
It takes a gentle hand.
It's cool. They got a sexy guy. Yeah.
Both of us. Those guys are so awesome,
too. Like a local Spanish bag company
both came over. They brought me a little
bit of hash, which to be honest, I've
been smoking. You want to try it?
Yeah. I'm not letting go. Yeah, exactly.
Good call. I don't know
how that's all.
Yeah, it's true. Matt's just doing this
all over. He's probably been at three
booths doing this in the last half
hour. Just roll around and barb people
down. You're getting barbed
up. You got like 100 people, dude.
getting barbed
up. We should learn how to say hold it
in in Spanish.
Barbara.
Barbara
bud. It just sounds so awesome. This is
like Canadian accent. It's like Barbra
by just a barb.
Barb, what are you doing? Barb. Jesus.
That guy's like out. I like how they run
away after they take a
hit. Hell yeah, they
do. These guys are down for the bob.
This was one person standing here when
he started this. It's literally like
one. He's like, "Hey, you want to hit
the barb?"
What is that? It's the barber, bud.
Working on the mother ship. Trying to
get my own mother ship. So all these
guys saying mother ship, dude, the
mothership and the barb, they coalesque.
Just trying to get my own mother ship. I
think we can make it happen.
Oh [ __ ]
[ __ ] Well, it's been 4 minutes, Matt.
You've been going pretty strong.
There's better than sign an autograph.
Way better. Yeah, you can have a picture
or
Yeah. Barb.
Yep. And I'm happy to say that it tastes
like that when I grow it, too. So, it's
like, you know, it's good to know that
you can get the seeds and then actually
get that strain.
Yeah. Cuz I don't think of myself as a
really amazing grower. I hadn't grown
for a long time. I bar both that Afghani
and barber and you you kill the plants
and overwater them and do all these
things and then don't expect to to grow
the fire.
5 minutes 30 seconds.
I think you got some people doubling up.
Oh my god.
Watching the video.
I don't know.
I wasn't watching either.
Maybe. Yeah. I'm not a big oil guy, so
I don't really
know. Take it easy, guys.
[Music]
Too bad this forbat.
We got to stop for a little while only
because this is getting Yeah. Let's take
a break. Break time.
Good. And it took me like 2 weeks to
[ __ ] for a leg to heal. I was
expecting a bruise to come up. Hey, look
who it is. Hey, what's up, dude? Dude, I
just thought we better get a little bit
of footage for Bubble Man's World. Dude,
a man show what his heads have been
saying. Drew's in the house. What do we
got here, buddy? This is a little bit of
Neville's Haze heads. This is like after
the material's been beat up about five
times to get heads off. Uh, and we just
went in again and dug it up real more,
then done a static trick on it. And then
once we had the pile, we put it through
the static trick again and that got out
a lot of the green contaminant. Game
changer on that, eh? Yeah. Yeah. We were
a bit disappointed with Neville's haze
yields. We've been getting crazy like 5
to 10% on things like the Nicole and
24K. And then we had a super frosty
Neville's haze and we got like a
percent. Wow. 2% something like that.
Let's hit that. Let's do it.
All right. So, what do we got right
there? Yeah, that's amazing. All right.
Here. You get to be my cameraman.
Wait, this is I think I think this
is
beautiful. Haze is one of my favorite
suits. My son's middle
really. My wife chose it too. No joke.
My wife chose a
really joke. She said, "Yeah, it always
makes you so happy.
No
posters
that really
old by us in South Spain. Smells
beautiful. It's got
that very Amsterdam coffee shop smell,
doesn't
it? It reminds me of the
SK. Bring
back great gardener in turn for a little
truth. Pretty good time here at lots of
people are coming up showing me hash and
bud coming and asking about the bags
obviously talking about hash church and
man's world. It's really cool how many
uh people were actually able to touch
this audience. It is the YouTube
channel. Very cool.
Awesome. So many people
watching everyone see some
hands always.
[Music]
All right. So this gentleman just walked
up to me and he
is Max from Davinator. He's the
gentleman that sent me the Davinator
from Germany. So, of course, he wants to
give a shout
out. Thank you very much. You know, I
broke my deep dish banger the other day
cuz the element got stuck on it and
you bowl the only bowl I have to smoke.
So, thanks to you, I'm smoking right
now. So, maybe we should take a little
dab. Okay.
Let me load you up with something first.
Max from the Yeah, this is the barb.
All right, here you go. Mothership. And
this is a mother ship. Yeah. First time
for me. Oh,
nice. Woohoo.
Davinator, show us that shirt.
There it is.
Excellent. And did Brian from Dail ever
get in touch with you? Did Brian from
Dail? He's going to. Yeah, I know. He
wants to talk to you and and figure some
things out or whatever. So, yeah, he
liked your unit and that you were using
good components and that you weren't
just copying and, you know, making it
cheap. So, it's cool. We'll hopefully
hook you guys up. Yeah. Right on, man.
videos. What is the word? Uh, just love
bubs. This one's the tri. So, we got
Doug from THC and Hemp Puddlum here in
the booth. He's showing us some fire.
This is the bubble gum. Little bubble
gum. And this is the bubblegum hash that
won third place in the resin category. I
have to say, he just gave me a piece and
it is definitely like I'm pretty darn
happy. Most pieces of hash I'm a little
less than happy. This one I'm very happy
to see. Here's the L. Oh, L.
Did you have something to do with this,
Julian?
L. So, this was
that has a little bit of that. It's
So, what did you do for that? How did we
make Lage? Making Bas country. Basque
country. So, this is also Basque.
There we are. When you want to squeeze
if you want make videos the same you go
in my home. It's far away though, eh?
Yes. We'll think about it. It would be
nice. Be nice.
I have your bag for Yeah. You go in my
home for make.
That'd be awesome. You'll film this for
me? Yes, of course. We're filming this
right now. So, we got Jeff Church in the
booth. He has come by. Doug just offered
me a few buds and we're going to squeeze
rosin out of it. You really want to see
this, dude. I'm telling you. I made some
earlier with this shitty Moroccan hash.
Squeeze oil out onto this in 5 seconds.
Dabs of it. Okay. Yeah. Like Moroccan
hash oil, but it looks like what the
truth is here. Do you want me to Yeah.
Yeah. Which one? This
is what the truth. Oh, church is just
going to be online. It's at uh the Hash
Museum, but it's not open to the public.
Ah, on the line YouTube. Yeah. All
right. So, you got the bud. We got the
bud. And then what is that? That's the
bubble gum. Barcelona bubblegum. Right.
Yeah. Right. Not the bask. That one's
real nice. Almost a little more
fruity. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. There it is.
All right. You want to do it up on the
table so everyone can see?
All
right. Pop the flower in here.
All right. So, flowers in. This is uh
the soil grown rosin technique. Yes.
Soil grown 2015. Thanks, buddy. Thank
you. Soil grown. And then one, two,
three. All right.
Dab. Dab. Sit. Right there. Rosin.
Rosin. Yes. All right. I want a dab of
that. Yeah. Yeah. Here you go, buddy.
Maybe clean that up. Excuse me. I threw
the butt on the hash. No
worries. See that? He melt the oil right
out of the bud. Doug, fresh. Fresh. No
solvent.
Just give that a wipe with your fingers.
Yeah.
I don't, but we could rip a piece off if
you want. So, this is to show that it's
real bubble gum. It sticks to the
bottom. Nice. I like that you got your
med.
Yeah, John. Johnny B. Yeah, man. But
then you know it's bubblegum. You can
stick to the bottom. If you can put
posters up with it, then it's all good.
Maders.
Yeah, brother.
Yeah, Revlon. He gets the good one. Jeff
Church doesn't [ __ ] around. It was
actually the cheap one. Can you imagine
one day where Jeff could be like a
Revlon model like holding one of these
up? When I crimped my
[Applause]
bud for press, the isolator is good.
This Yeah, but we squeezed the hash. We
squeezed oil out of It's sticky. Yeah.
Oh, it's sticky. He's Watch how easy he
picks it up. No salt. No solder. It's
like wax. No salt. Yeah, it's parchment.
But you can also use the Teflon, which
is oil slick. Yeah, they both work. This
one works good, too.
Crazy.
picture of
the second.
Yeah, it just happens
perfectly. Fact that it was a bud in his
jar like 8 minutes ago. Now it's going
to be a dab in my lungs like 10 seconds
later. Man, 25 years we've been doing
that. That's pretty [ __ ] nuts.
Oh my
god. No, I better
not like living
hash. Living
hash something.
Oo, scraping it off the bank and
collecting it as a clear oil.
Yeah, very good. If you learn the
technique, the smaller the bud, the more
return. Okay. Too big of a bud and then
it gets caught.
They still take this and smoke it with
someone that or use it in an edible or
coconut oil. There's still some
medicine, but this is top quality
medicine.
Anyway, you know, you going for another
squish here. I just turned it off cuz
I'm worried that you're going to heat it
up too hot. Careful cuz if it smokes the
thing, it's there's too much power going
through it. That's all.
I just turned it back on, too. So, a
fast bubble might be good.
Yeah, there's some more rosin. Yeah,
probably 50% of what it just gave us.
It's not bad.
It's It's It's like a gas color.
Rossin.
Oh, what's this for? To rosin.
Okay, he'll do it. One second. Uh, he
wants you to try this, bud. Uh, Jeff,
just a little bit. Okay.
Well, a little bit, you know, not too
much. Or you open it and nothing's
there. So, it's just a little bit. Press
this one next. Yeah, he just That's his.
Press it up and give him a dab. Yeah,
for sure. Fresh serve dabs. Fresh dabs.
We're making hash. Careful. You want to
be really solid with this pipe. Never
really hit it from a weird angle. It's
how the pipe will.
The first person that hit it today
dropped this on the table. I was so glad
it didn't break cuz that's all the it's
the only piece I have.
So, what we got? Press it up.
Yeah. Nice.
Yeah.
Give me that thing on the right there.
Yeah. Wait. Oh, here. I'll clean it.
Yes. My fingers are available. I can do
it, too. If you want to keep yours clean
off cuz you're operating the rosin and
stuff. It's fine. Operating the ro.
You're a rosin tech. Terry. Rossin
technician. Yeah. Terry will have a
machine that he's going to be building.
He'll be like, "Wait, I'm building a
machine, mate." I'm like, "Dude, like
your water extraction machine, dude.
Just sell the [ __ ] bags."
That's what I said to Terry. He was
supposed to be the guy to sell the bags
in the beginning and then instead of
selling the bags, he was like, "I'm
going to build a machine."
Okay. Of course, you
never dude. At this point in our life,
we know that the majority of the great
ideas we have is super
I can't exude
narrowing. You got some flavors. Yeah.
Excellent. Excellent.
Always some good good representatives
from Italy, right? Come on.
All right.
Yeah. But Roz, did you see that guy's
bud that we just squeezed? Where did he
get a hit? Awesome. I should have I
should have done that.
Very nice. You make these in Italy?
Where where was this from? From Spain.
Oh, from Spain. Barcelona. Old Rock
Platinum Ice Water.
Very nice. Nice. Nice little res. It's
good, eh? Thank you.
And
so that's someone else. What happens
when you do this? [ __ ] Yeah, the
screen. You want? Yeah, let's do
something. Let me press this really
quick cuz I I promised it would happen.
But then 2
seconds. I got a fresh part for that
stuff. Nice.
I wonder the the mother ship. This is a
Taurus.
Patriot one time.
Yeah. You ready, Bubble Man?
That's enough for me. I don't need to
like take it off cuz I want everyone
else to try it. But I do need to try
lage actually. Here.
That's the basketball. Hell yeah. I'm
going to get it on film when I get
[Music]
la with the bar wrapped around the
outside. Yeah. That
was a
nice makes it so
available car.
Okay. So, go ahead and like whatever you
want. Just like whatever you want me to
put in here. Oh, nice.
Nice.
I had one right here. I got
Doug. Always a pleasure, brother.
Beautiful. Thank you for coming by and
bringing the party. Started the party,
dude.
Doug started the party. Very nice.
Oh, all the great familiar faces. This
is good times right now. I don't mind. I
don't mind.
Careful with that. It's going to be like
nothing we've ever used. You think it'll
be runny? I think you should use this
for that. Oh, it's going to be runny,
bro. This is going to be the stuff that
makes someone pass out unconscious when
they dab it. Trust me.
Second winner. Stab a dude in Barcelona.
We're going to rosen it. Oh wow. Imagine
you take your entry and you rosen it
before you enter it. Jesus. Whose bus
was that one? That one was his. The
sage. Yeah. Let's hit. You take that and
I'll get him.
I'm going to wait until the
video see
how we have different texts. Jeff. Yeah.
I like yours though, man. You know, the
first time I tried to use it, I ripped
the paper like an idiot. That's the best
thing about hashish. Everybody has a
different tech because they did it, you
know, or they saw everybody do it. But
you know, like it's it's all rushing
over time. A lot of time it's just what
you had lying around.
What can I do right now?
Juliet. Oh my god. Look, it's [ __ ]
through without without me even. Look at
this.
That is pre There we go. Pre
pre-pressed. There's already rust and
greasing out. So, this is going to be
epic right here. Barbs and Okay, Barbs.
This is my first time. This is my first
time on the Teflon. We're making Be
careful with the heat on this one. It's
not going to be like bud. Let's Let's
go. Little shots. Let's Yeah. And you
You're welcome to use the smaller one if
you want. No, this is good. Just real
little shots.
Nice. This is going to be nuts. Don't
smoke it too much.
Oh, I can't wait for the money shot when
he opens this. Let's take a peek. Hold
on. One
more. Wow. And there's a lot more to go.
Oh. Oh.
Jesus. Jesus Christ. Set that there.
We'll get a couple dabs. Take a shot.
Smells
awesome. Look at that. It looks like
like a marking a chef would put on a
dessert with like the raspberry [ __ ]
the mango one cake resin, right? And
[ __ ] turn it into just So now Matt
knows why he would take his six-star and
turn it to 10
star. Damn.
Damn. I mean, I haven't hit it yet, but
I have to admit like this could [ __ ]
someone up. This
first [ __ ] someone up. Yeah.
Holy Christ.
That's just like the Shiva snot. Wow.
It's just so dummy. Yeah. Push it down
and and pick it up like snap. You know
what I mean? Like flat the way you were.
Yeah. And just tap it down like push it
down and then lift it up. Here, let me
show you. Yeah, it doesn't seem packed
or something.
There he goes. Now he's got it. Oh, it's
really tiring. Yeah, it's like insane.
Here, I'm just going to go for this
little section here.
That's a nice
one. Someone hold this so I can do the
camera. So, pipe. Thank you, Judia.
[Music]
Ready. Take one. Barbs
in. Barb.
We just made rosin at a bar full melt.
Talk about a good time to roll up,
Joseph. Woo!
Dude, that that's strong as [ __ ] isn't
it?
It's different. Changed it. Changed
totally. You got rid of all the wax
membranes. The carbs that lights up the
face sort of has changed it a little
bit. I got to try this guy. Yeah, of
course, dude.
See this
is still
fantastic. Excuse me. All right. Hook me
up with a little
one still. But it's still tasty.
Dude, that's exactly the one I wanted. I
thought you were going over there and
then you went right to the little ball
that I felt like I should be inhaling.
Did your name on it? It had my name on
it. Is that big enough for you? Oh,
yeah. Pass my
camera and just arms in. Oh,
man. Nice work, sir. Nice work.
Wow, dude. I know what you're saying. It
definitely changes.
Changes.
Wow. Wow.
So, second place avenue right there.
Yes.
Thank you so
much. This is
[Applause]
Okay.
Awesome. He's like, "Okay, that
explains." Oh, thank you.
Well, that was really a nice experience
right there. Look at that.
Yep. I'm going to press uh press it
again. Of course. Press it three more
times. Yeah, I used the pipe. You could
press it in this three more times and
collect all the rest. Yes, the pipe once
in. Uh, yes, please.
I'm just going to leave that one. So,
careful cuz it's on the ground. Oh,
yeah.
You want to do it up on the table so
everyone can see?
All
right. Pop the flower in here.
All right. So, flowers in. This is uh
the soil grown rosin technique. Yes,
soil grown 2015. Thanks, buddy. Thank
you. Soil grown. And then one, two,
three. All right.
Dab. Dab. Right there. Rosin. Yes. All
right. I want a dab of that. Yeah. Yeah.
Here you go, buddy. Maybe clean that up.
Excuse me. I threw the butt on the hash.
No
worries. See that? He melt the oil right
out of the bud. Doug, fresh. Fresh. No
solvent.
Just give that a wipe with your fingers.
Yeah.
I don't, but we could rip a piece off if
you want. So, this is to show that it's
real bubble gum. It sticks to the
bottom. Nice. I like that you got your
medainer.
Yeah, John. Johnny B. Yeah, man. Then
you know it's bubblegum. You can stick
to the bottom. If you can put posters up
with it, then it's all good.
Yeah, brother.
Yeah. Revlon. He gets the good one. Jeff
Church doesn't [ __ ] around. It was
actually the cheap one. Can you imagine
one day where Jeff could be like a
Revlon model like holding one of these
up when I crimp my butt?
For press the isolator is good. This
Yeah, but we squeeze the hash. We
squeezed oil out of the sticky. Oh, it's
sticky. He's Watch how easy he picks it
up. No salt. No. It's like no. Yeah,
it's parchment. But you can also use the
teflon which is oil slick. Yeah, they
both work. This one works good too.
Crazy.
Yeah, you're just half perfect.
the fact that it was a bud in his jar
like 8 minutes ago. Now it's going to be
a dab in my lungs like 10 seconds
later. The 25 years we've been doing
that. That's pretty [ __ ] nuts.
Oh my god.
[Applause]
Like like living
hash. Living hash. Awesome.
Something
said scraping it off the thing and
collecting it as a clear oil.
There's more than that. Yeah. Very good.
If you learn the technique, the smaller
the bud, the more return. Okay. Too big
of a bud and then it gets caught.
You can still take this and smoke it.
Someone that or use it in an edible or
coconut oil. There's still some
medicine, but this is top quality
medicine.
I know.
All right. Now you
got this.
We're going to
press on the screen.
whatever
twist and you
know I'm going to set
up so far
I'm going to give this one more. But
anyway, you know, you going for another
squish here. I just turned it off cuz
I'm worried that you're going to heat it
up too hot. Careful cuz if it smokes the
thing it's there's too much power going
through it. That's all.
I just turned it back on too. a fast
bubble. See how it goes.
Yeah, there's some more rosin. Yeah.
Probably 50% of what it just gave us.
It's not bad.
Yes.
It's It's It's like
a color.
Rosin.
Oh, what's this for? To rosin.
Okay, he'll do it. One second. Uh, he
wants you to try this, bud. Uh Jeff,
just a little bit. Okay.
Well, a little bit. No, not too much. Or
you open it and nothing's there. So,
it's just a little bit. Press this one
next. Yeah. He just That's his press it
up and give him a dab. Yeah, for sure.
Fresh dabs. Fresh dabs.
We're making hash. Oh, careful.
You want to be really solid with this
pipe. Never really hit it from a weird
angle. That's how the pipe will.
The first person that hit it today
dropped this on the table. I was so glad
it didn't break cuz that's all the It's
the only piece I have. Nice. So, what we
got? Press it up. Perfect.
Yeah. Yes.
Give me that thing on the right there.
Yeah. Wait. Oh, here. I'll clean it.
Yes. My fingers are available. I can do
it, too. If you want to give yours cuz
you're operating the rosin and stuff.
It's fine. Operating the You're a rosin
tech.
Rosin technician. Yeah. Terry will have
a machine that he's going to be
building. He'll be like, "Wait, I got
I'm building a machine, mate." I'm like,
"Dude, like your water extraction
machine, dude. sell the [ __ ]
bags. That's what I said to Terry. He
was supposed to be the guy to sell the
bags in the beginning and then instead
of selling the bags, he was like, I'm
going to build a machine.
Okay. Of course you never hire. Dude, at
this point in our life, we know that the
majority of the great ideas we have is
super
I can't exude
narrowing. You got some flavors. Yeah.
Excellent. Excellent. show you the
humble. Always some good good
representatives from Italy, right? Come
on.
All
right. Yeah, we're Did you see that
guy's butt that we just squeezed? Where
did he get a hit? Awesome. I should have
I should have done that.
Very nice. You make these in Italy?
Yeah.
Where where was this from? From Spain.
Oh, from Old Rock Platinum Ice Water.
Very nice. Nice. Nice little res. It's
good, eh? Good. Thank
you. And
so you were
someone else. What happens when you do
this? [ __ ] the screen. Yeah. On the
screen. You want? Yeah. Let's do
something. Let me press this really
quick cuz cuz I I promise it would have
been two seconds.
I got a fresh purchasing.
That that's enough for me. I don't need
to like take it over cuz I want everyone
else to try yet. But I do need to try
lage actually. Here.
That's the basketball. Hell yeah. I'm
going to get it on film when I get the
stage. Last
[Music]
season
last makes it so available.
It's not the car.
Okay. So, go ahead and like whatever you
want. Just whatever you want me to put
in here.
I got to get back to the I had one right
here. I
got dog. Always a pleasure, brother.
Beautiful. Thank you for coming by and
bringing the party. Started the party,
dude.
started the party. Very nice.
All the great familiar faces. This is
good times right now. I don't mind. I
don't mind.
Careful with that. It's going to be like
nothing we've ever used. I think it'll
be runny. I think you should use this
for that. Oh, it's going to be runny,
bro. This is going to be the stuff that
makes someone pass out unconscious when
they dab it. Trust me.
Second winner of a dude in Barcelona.
We're going to rosen it. Oh, wow.
Imagine you take your entry and you
rosen it before you enter it. Jesus.
Whose fun was that one? That one was his
age. Yeah. Let's hit your nail. Yeah,
you take that and I'll get him.
I'm going to wait to do it video though.
So, see
See how we have different text, Jeff?
Yeah. I like yours though.
The first time I tried to use it, I
ripped the paper like an idiot. That's
the best thing about hashish. Everybody
has a different tech because they did
it, you know, or they saw everybody do
it. But you know, like it's it's all
over. A lot of time it's just what you
had lying around.
What can I do right now?
Juliet. Oh my god. Look, it's [ __ ]
through without without me
even. Look at this.
That is pre There we go. Pre
pre-pressed. There's already rust and
greasing out. So, this is going to be
epic right here. Barbing. Okay. Barb,
this is my first time. This is my first
time on the Teflon. We're making Be
careful with the heat on this one. It's
not going to be like bud. Let's Let's
go. Little shots. Let's Yeah. And you
you're welcome to use the smaller one if
you want. No, this is great. Just real
little shots.
Nice. This is going to be
nuts. Don't smoke it too much.
Oh, I can't wait for the money shot when
he opens this. Let's take a peek. Hold
on. One more.
Wow. And there's a lot more to go. Oh,
wow. Oh.
Oh. Jesus.
Jesus Christ. Set that there. We'll
We'll get a couple dabs. Take a shot.
Smells
awesome. Look at that. It looks like
like a marking a chef would put on a
dessert with like the raspberry [ __ ]
the mango one cake resin, right? And
[ __ ] turn it into just So now Matt
knows why he would take his six-star and
turn it to 10
star. Damn.
Damn. I mean, I haven't hit it yet, but
I have to admit like that this could
[ __ ] someone up.
This [ __ ] someone up. Yeah.
Holy Christ.
That's just like the Shiva snot. Wow.
It's just so gummy. Yeah. Push it down
and and pick it up like snap. You know
what I mean? Like flat the way you were.
Yeah. And just tap it down like push it
down and then lift it up.
Ah, here. Let me show you. Yeah, it
doesn't seem as tight though.
There he goes. Now he's got it. Oh, it's
really chirpy. Yeah, it's like insane.
Here, I'm just going to go for this
little section here.
That's a nice
one. Hold this so I can do the camera.
So P. Thank you,
[Music]
Jia.
Ready. Take one. Barbs
in. Barbs.
We just made rosin out of bar full melt.
Talk about a good time to roll up,
Joseph. Woo!
Dude, that that's strong as [ __ ] isn't
it?
It's different. Changed it. It changed.
Totally. You got rid of all the wax
membranes. The carb usually lights up
the face. Sort of has changed it a
little bit. I got to try this guy. Yeah,
of course,
dude. Changed
it.
See this? This is
Yeah. Still fantastic.
Excuse me. All right. Hook me up with a
little one.
Still, but it's still tasty.
Dude, that's exactly the one I wanted. I
thought you were going over there and
then you went right to the little ball
that I felt like I should be inhaling.
You need your name on it. It have my
name on it. Is that big enough for you?
Oh yeah.
Pass my
camera in
arms in. Oh
man. Nice work, sir. Nice work.
Wow, dude. I know what you're saying. It
definitely changes changes time.
Wow.
Wow. So, second place avenue right
there. Yes.
Thank you so
much. This
is
[Applause]
okay. That is awesome.
It's like he's like, "Okay, that
explains."
Well, that was really a nice experience
right there. Look at that.
Yep. I'm going to press uh press it
again. Of course. Press it three more
times. I use the pipe. You can press it
in this three more times and collect all
the rest. Yes, the pipe. Uh yes, please.
I'm just going to leave that one.
Careful cuz it's on the
ground.
Yeah. More
rosin. Barb's not done yet. Second
press. Oh, I can see it. Yeah, there it
is. It's coming out hard there.
Okay. So, that's how I normally do it,
but I do it 230°. That's hotter than
that. So, I did it like half the time. I
did 15 seconds just then. 15 seconds.
Oh, yeah. Drip.
Oh, wow.
Yeah. So, I aim it. So, I I have I have
the part or the uh the screen on the
butterfly and then I do do the crimp
straight on it like this with a slight
angle so that hopefully all of the oil
will drip down off the sides and not be
on the the heating element. You know, it
like comes out it runs out so you can
get as much to say in there, you
know. There's probably Yeah, I'm going
to press it again for sure. It might or
whatever. Yeah. I mean, it's getting
uh I just go like this,
then open it
again. Just push the button twice and
then close
the Did you just get that?
No. Hold it up like this and get a
picture of the one on the left. It's
full of bubbles.
war. Yeah, it is a war
shark. Butterfly. A butterfly. Yeah.
Dab it.
Let me clean it. Yeah. Yes. No
solvent. Yeah. No.
Yeah. Yeah.
Oh, nice. All right. Cool. You want
to videotape people taking my picture?
Nice.
[Music]
Nice. All right. So Javier heard that we
were making rosin. He came over. He's
like, "What's going on?" I got hash.
So he's got the devil fruit. I see you
in with him in YouTube and some videos.
Maybe gardener really uh oiled up the
screen. Beautiful.
It's just awesome. We'll clean that
later. Yeah. Well, you got a whole row
to do his three kinds.
So,
uh, let's start with 45.
I need a spoon or a dab or something
like this. Dabber.
Oh, look.
Oh, it's dirty though. Don't put a dirty
dabber in there.
These are my
people.
Nice. Making rosin.
45. 45. We start with the 45. Okay. I
put more. It's okay. We can do just that
if you want. That's good. Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. Cuz we're going to do three
different kinds. So, just wants to have
a little taste of each one, I'm sure.
So, we should uh get a new piece of
parchment out. Sure. Well, I have
scissors right here. I have the uh the
box with the ripper on it.
Perfect. That's nice looking.
Barbs and Oh my god. Barbs in there.
Like honestly like as nice as Barb was
that's pretty nice.
Yeah. I mean the barb was juicing out of
the screen before we even applied heat.
Barbs in.
in. All right, we got it. Yeah. Yeah. Uh
preparing for Verizon. It's really hot,
though. So, yeah. Well, dude, you're
twice the power. Yeah, twice the power.
Okay, so we got Here we go.
Yeah. Open her right up in front of I
got that for you. I got the top. I'll
keep my fingers on the outside. We
should be okay. Yeah. Huh?
Would you like a dab? Okay.
What the [ __ ] What the [ __ ]
like that. Amazing. Amazing. [ __ ] What
the [ __ ] Pick him up a dab. Like not a
huge one cuz he's working, but give him
a little taste. Sure.
You want to do it when he's done with
it? So you can pick the dab up for him.
Yeah.
He's quality 45.
Dude, it's like up to six star like I'm
interested to see how it it changes for
you. What? It'll how it how it changes
from smoking this from you smoking this.
Yeah. You smoking this. It
changes normally. And I like more press.
It goes broken the tins and mix the oil
and everything.
Okay. But this is different. It's like
uh it's awesomeness
a little bit. I don't know. It's just
down here. I'll grab you. Okay.
Small one.
Like you get
me. Tell
me that. You know, you know,
it's so Yeah, dude. Yeah. Poland snap
shattered. Hey, I know.
maybe
dad. But the taste and cuz he knows the
strain, you know, it's his per he smokes
it a lot. He's
45 micron. Yeah. Amazing. Amazing. Which
one was that? That was That was his uh
devil fruit. Devil fruit. Fresh frozen.
Yeah. Fortified half plant. It's nice
quality, but I must try it out. Yeah.
Yeah. Transform the the getting out of
control. Your [ __ ] parchment, dude.
Jesus.
Wow. It's amazing, dude. He can roll
that up in a second into a little patty
in the middle so it's all clean. I I
could do it as well, but I like the
film. I catch Jeff doing it. It looks
better. It is a butterfly. It's not
beautiful.
It's like a [ __ ] trophy.
Wow. Yeah. And that's just 45. Let's uh
let's try the 73. So much smoother. Like
it cuts out that little bit of harshness
that you get from any contaminant you
might have. That's devil fruit. Yours
yours has very little. So, it's like,
but it's it it's like that waxy
cellulose uh membrane that holds all the
resin in. That's what we're not getting
with the rock. So nice.
So, today Yeah, I killed it with this.
Yeah, man. You're going to win contests
with this. You're so amazing. You'll
take like uh 20 46 90 micron.
People will be like afraid. Yeah, having
heart attacks.
I imagine big pieces. You can make big
pieces. Yeah, big nice. You can make
them just a little bit at a time and
then
the quality is on point.
Where can I go through these two?
Take the flat iron. Yeah.
Wow, that's really
tricky. We're working
on that's why I want to be able
to do
that right now.
We're puffing right now. What a
coincidence.
[Applause]
420 buddy.
Crazy hot heads. This
guy's ridiculous. Yeah, that was uh Oh,
that was the bar. That was Barb. That's
right. Smoking barb. That Yeah, that
doesn't It's different. Hey,
it's nice. Dude, this is fun and
exciting. It's like I feel like I'm at
the edge of the cutting.
Dude, how you I got him on tape going,
"What the fuck?"
Wait, listen. Listen. That dude right
there that you just showed how to make
this, you'll win like a dozen contests
in next year. Rosing his he wrote the
book.
low extraction
every start he'll start going crazy like
he's like yeah let's press out all these
things and we we did one he's like oh my
god oh my god it's dude another level
stepping up I just am thinking of how
many contests Javier will win doing this
in the next one year how many will you
win I don't know Maybe they the same as
strength.
Yeah. Yeah, man. Yeah, it really it
brings the flavor of each strain out so
much more surprise because I made with
this strain is the frost fresh frozen.
It is amazing. But this is like our
next test. I had tests done on the
before the rosin and then the after and
the tarpine content went up from 6.4 mg
per gram to 7.4 mg per gram. It it
gained a more turppen after he made it
because he got rid of the wax membranes
the concentrates. Exactly. So, but it
didn't even the heat did not destroy
everything and it was only slight there
was only
we're back at it. Haze by medical seats
that we can get into. So, this is the
bud.
I love Haze.
So, just a little tiny bit like you
expect with Haze. Yep. Just got those
small resin heads. Let me gather that
dab up for you.
to gather up two dabs cuz I want to
taste them.
Deep Neville deep. That's the deep. I
think I want to try the next one. Yeah,
that's the one. That's the one.
Yeah, he's totally like Yeah, cuz he had
no understanding of what was going on.
Parchment paper. No, I mean I understand
PHO. This is just not You have low grade
hash. Low grade hash you put in here and
you ball it up into it. You know, you
put it in here and you you twist this up
and ball it up and crimp that in the
silicone and it squirts hash oil out.
Yeah. Like little chips.
Little chips. Yeah. It's not a weed
chip. You can actually eat it. No
[ __ ] easy. Enjoy. That's not really
enough for a nice one. No. Yeah. Well,
it it varies. It's a dab, though, right?
There's only one little bite. That's all
that is there. That's all that's there.
Why use this? This is a pizza box. Do
you know what I mean? Like when I order
a pizza, I don't eat the box. I take the
pizza out. Sometimes I dough is not much
better either, right? If you go to a
shitty pizza spot, I would never do
that. I'm all 90 micron pizza.
Just a
second. See if my
game technology.
So, I got barely a little bit more right
there. Yeah. Awesome.
I got this.
Yeah, buddy. Two thumbs up. Two thumbs
up for two tears down.
Yeah, I like the shirt.
Very good. Yeah. What was that? Turn
turn the best [ __ ] into better [ __ ]
That's impossible. Uh, well, we'll see.
Second place. Nons.
The sin of the look on people's faces as
we've been doing this throughout the day
has just been like So, wait a second.
What are you doing?
Oh, it's Look at it coming out.
You get the dripping. Totally.
Thing is, how ridiculous. And Oh, dude.
Look at that.
Hey, Al, you seen this? Squeezing oil at
a hatch. It's beautiful, dude. It's
nuts. And that's barb. We got to hit
that. I can smell crazy a little harder
than I was eating,
but he had his tested and the fact that
that karaopoly was present shows that
the heat can't be destroying too much
raw uh
uh his tested and it was 70% THC non
decarboxilated decarboxilation doesn't
happen in in in 2 seconds with 200°
temperature. You need like the extreme
temperature of a flame or a nail to
decaroxulate immediately.
It's right here. Dude, look at that.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly.
Dude, that's really sick.
[Applause]
It's ridiculous. Now, now Don, Don, go
back to high school for a second and
just think all of these kids with access
to dabs that never had access. They just
had shitty weed they could get.
I know. My sister had a hair
straightener.
Rosin with a great gardener. Trying it
for my first time making rosin. Aaron
from DNA. Don't burn your finger. Don't
burn your finger.
Push down with your fingers. Real look.
Push down with your fingers and then
only for a few seconds and then open it
up and kind of do it again. Make sure it
as you see it's leaking out. That's when
you kind of Yeah, cuz that's hot as
[ __ ] I'd open it again. You don't want
to burn it. Open it. Open it. Open it.
Now open that thing and show us. [ __ ]
put it. Look at that [ __ ]
Oh yeah. Open that up now. Bro, you can
just drop the pressing screen. Oh, look
at that dude
out just starting running down. Jesus
nerid from the Jamaican bud. No, that
was from some rosin that like some of
his nice hat from the bar. You just buy
garbage. You just buy garbage hash and
you squeeze that on camera. Buy garbage
hat and you just squeeze this [ __ ] up
and then you're like good. Just like you
can buy 200 lb of any weed and turn it
into that clear [ __ ] and put some
[ __ ] turans in it and call it 99
different strain names. This [ __ ] This
shit's pretty cool, man. I [ __ ] I got
to give it up, man. It's definitely
cool. That is [ __ ] insane. Barbs in
dripage. So, can you imagine the
barbell? Wherever you go now, you just
bring your [ __ ] little iron now. I
do. And you turn the trash into [ __ ]
stash. Yeah. three star to six-star in 5
seconds. Cuz when you travel, you can't
always have the kind pie. And that's why
we're, you know, struggling sometimes in
different places in the world, but you
can take any of the local flavors and
just get like get 10 buds given to you
and go home and have 10 dabs.
That's nuts, bro. You don't have butane,
which is also it's safer. Like young
kids are pretty stupid. They can blow
up. They can make mistakes. I make
mistakes at 42. I wouldn't [ __ ] around
with it. But at 20, I for sure. I'm
going to tell you the secret machine to
use to make this [ __ ] Okay. Yeah. The
secrets. It's been out for a long time.
The secrets. It's called the George
Foreman. Oh, the George Foreman
rosinator. George Foreman. You put
George Foreman will work because it's on
an angle. It makes it so the fat drips
and roots. You just keep rosining your
[ __ ] and it drip down into the tray. We
just need to get dail to create a George
Foreman a silicon carbide heated tray.
So that is the best heat source. It
really like we have a giant [ __ ]
t-shirt press at the warehouse connected
to a [ __ ] trip. I'm thinking that has
top and bottom work. Yes, that works
100%. Bro, you can giant [ __ ] slabs
with that thing. What you got to do is
you got to put parchment paper on the
bottom and then put buds like 2 or 3 in
apart. Just popcorn buds. You can put
like you don't even need these. You just
put more parchment on top. Give it a two
second press. Open it up. Flick the buds
off. And you've just got you collect the
oil. Bro, I'm going to do that in
[ __ ]
make a video. It's like new [ __ ]
[ __ ] keep I had Yeah, you can rosin
all that, bro. Or static some of it. Or
so much easier than all the other or all
of the above. Who's the one claiming
this? Who's the kid that discovered this
and started? Soil grown really blew it
up by pressing a button and getting oil
out cuz it's simple as [ __ ] but it took
some intelligence to
actually no it's and it's timing. It's
all just social media and the ability to
share room.
Wow. You turned great in super. I think
you can still make more. You can we'll
be able to squeeze that two three more
times. Bro, there's a lot of Yeah, that
would be a regular. You can't leave that
on either or it'll blow. But you can
squeeze it one more time, but squeeze it
way less now cuz it's hotter. So, really
give it like a one or two second or you
might you might burn it. Take two.
And the pressure helps with your
fingers.
Smoking a bit.
Look at it. Look at you. Got to figure
out how to get all that out cuz there is
a ton in there still. It's going to get
refined. The method will get better and
better. You
know, kids alcohol kids that are out
there now going to figure out how to get
all of that out.
Yep. I'll be busy growing. You guys
figure it out. I think it's time for
YouTube. Time to hit some dabs of that
[ __ ] Do
it.
[Applause]
[Music]
These guys brought us some nice
bud.
Alex, Christian, and
Matthew. We're about to
uh soil grown that [ __ ] down.
Jeff just got back, so I figured, well,
we better film more rosin making cuz
we've only filmed like 48 minutes of it
today. See what
happen there. Little bit of distort on
the butt. E, I'm going to repress with
for sure it'll come off.
I've been doing like three presses. I've
seen that a little bit where it's just
the placement of the bud or whatever.
Crazy. So, this one's so fresh it's
spitting out green. That's neat. That's
That's bizarre. I've never seen that
before. I've never seen I've seen
purple. I've never seen like it's like
green cuz of the moisture in the bud
brought some uh chlorophyll
out. You should see that green oil. Pull
that up in the light.
Little bit of fresh bud. Well, let's dab
it up.
It's like blue. Like green blue.
Give me a dab.
Just trying to keep your [ __ ] from
blowing up.
Blue.
Excuse me. I'm very blue. I'm going to
just step out for 5 minutes. Get a
little bit of video from the outside.
What's up, buddy? What's up? What's
up? See you, man. Just doing a little
tour video showing the products. It's a
huge tent.
Good job. Yeah, dude. That's a huge job,
man. The big
books. Wow. Holy [ __ ]
We knew that Spider-Man
Heat up here.
Heat
up here.
Heat up here.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Here's Barney's gigantic, ridiculous,
awesome booth. If you're going to do a
booth, well, looks like Derry knows how
to do it
best.
Wow. Best booth. Hands
down. Hands. Come on. I don't even have
to say it. I'm just saying it. It's
Bubble Man. Good, good to good to meet
you. After all these years, 20 years
I've been involved with Cannabis Cups
since 1995. That's the first time I
introduced myself to you. Right on.
Yeah, man. Keep it up. Keep the good
work up. Keep winning contests.
That's a booth right there,
guys. Then here's the fam right here.
This is where I just feel at home. DNA's
representing. You want to see
contests? Yeah, they've won a few.
Hey, brother. What's up?
How you doing, man?
Good to see you, bro. Good to see you,
man. Hey, this is Renee skateboard team.
We got to get to Miami skateboarding.
Want to see some skateboarding? Maybe
for one year. I broke
my Yeah, dude. My god. I got
night [ __ ]
You know what? He'll fix it. Yeah, it'll
come back. Yeah, it always comes back.
Yeah. Stay tuned, dude. Um, a little bit
rehab one year because I twisted my
knee. Yeah. Nothing. I'll tell you. You
want a secret? Yeah. Be room yoga. Yeah.
Hot yoga. Hot yoga. It's the trick. I'm
telling you. It's like I'm telling you,
man. I I want to try the the the bar,
the big ball, making the exercise. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Trust me. Hot yoga. It's for
the knee. It's for the knee. You know,
you really will be stronger when you
come back. Yeah. You know, because you
make it snowboard. You make it I know.
Exactly. Exactly. It's the boys. Yeah.
Crockett. Crocets. Thank you, man. Yeah.
Crockett's in the house. The whole crew.
Yeah. I can't I just asked them to go
snowboarding.
You were like really nice. It's non-stop
over there, dude. It's
non-stop. So
funny. Awesome. This booth looks good.
[Music]