[Music]
hey guys bubble man here we're at the
Ibis Hotel just uh less than a block
away from the spannabis and we're
setting up here with Tony from River
Rock and we're doing an interview with n
today he's just uh rolling up a spliff
and the sound man's lighting him up and
this will all be part of the uh
documentary that we're filming here in
Spain so n van shyak if you don't know
who he is is a well-known Dutch activist
who runs the wiie wartle coffee shops in
Harlem he's been doing activism with
cannabis for longer than I've been
involved in the scene and he's
definitely what I would consider a
cannabis
Warrior so I'm going to check it out
today
D okay ready to go into isolation
so what kind of hash you got there
n isolator man
nice from UK Exodus cheese grown in
Spain in the garden oh now that's the
right
answer if you don't smoke it don't grow
it
and my personal favorite if you smoke it
smoke it
pure we
[Music]
it
ready I love hash have I told you guys
lately how much I love hash I'm not sure
what this was but it was from jibs and I
love it I love
it yeah
Mark before my uh career in coffee shops
and in the middle of my career of being
a cannabis
grower uh I met a guy uh who had a
restaurant in Italian restaurant and
uh I knew him
from things like that one asked me if I
know AAR carar job so I
said said it's a it's a camp I said well
no problem I know an old guy who does
boat interiors and anything and he's
able the renovat or what we have to take
make St for I said he's not going to do
that know not that that kind of person I
said but I want to do it but up for 25
an hour give 5,000 now the
St and so we made a deal by I was
supposed to get my money one I got back
and I said well okay I wasn't doing much
at the
moment so I took the game and U stes for
400 K kilos according to the
measurements he PED in from
from and um so I I I I did the job and
when when it was finished and I closed
up gamper again went off to Morocco and
that was supposed to be the end of the
job for
me um but in the end they uh called me
over to Morocco because nobody wanted to
take the camp apart and knew how to put
it back together and put fill the stash
so I flew over to
Morocco I I was uh [ __ ] all over the
place and but we had to go back in the
camper and we we uh walked across the
border from SAA the Spanish in on the
Moroccan Coast over the border and uh I
this my has that I had on before and
then we waited on the other side and all
SE us for the for the B that eventually
showed up you know no problems and then
we drove all the way through Spain and I
drove because I I spoke
SP in the south of
FR they parked the camper there and we
were all set they had a garage with Rena
border patrol cars they opened the the
back flaps and we were all sitting down
separately on top of the Customs people
watching them with dog and everything
they couldn't find me and in the night I
went back to the gas station where were
arrested managed to get into the
dust 36 hours sh all right we're at
spannabis and we are about to dab down
the seed Center
representative
B yeah that was the perfect
c yeah
buddy well
done like a
champ
CH spanis with famed hash maker jibs
from the river rock Wellness Center here
we have him taking a large dab of water
hash large dab of water hash
ooo are you there I'm there awesome is
that is that a thing a thing it's a
thing
thing yep hey everybody bubble man here
at spannabis Philip a friend from France
a bubble Ambassador who stopped by the
booth we talked a little bit on Facebook
and uh he's brought some of his treats
to show us for bubble man's world so
yeah what do you got from welcome man
welcome what's uh what do you got going
on here it's uberry cush oh this is the
which one Huckleberry cush Huckleberry
Oregon oh nice Oregon Huckleberry Kush
if you want to get in on
that actually quite nicely uh cured very
marshmallowy and like
crispy check that out there J oh these
are the pills do DEC carboxilate this
all right you have a particular
temperature that you do that at 110 110
f
10 okay great of excellent and then you
also brought a little of the amnesia
amnesia 73 Micron bubble hash and this
is uh quite nice we've photographed it
so we'll have some macro photos to put
in the video we'll probably do a little
dab and a little bit here but uh yeah
this is great it's always nice to meet
uh people from around the world that are
stoked on hash and uh excited to meet
and share techniques and share share
hash
so uh yeah let's are we going to dab up
jip is Philip having a
dab uh
all
right torch time the denail uh Peter out
on us we didn't bring
the inverter we only used a converter
and we thought it was going to be okay
but apparently not so we are using a
something you don't see me do every day
but hey when in Rome or
Barcelona all right so here you go just
don't touch that bow
just can drive you in drive you
home yeah out the nose you get more the
uh the spicy uh yeah the the Turpin are
more pronounced oh absolutely brings
tears to your eyes when you're going up
and nose like that some strains make you
sneeze too
nice just keep the DA
up all right
right on thanks for coming by man peace
guys hey bubble man here and we are
hanging out with the seed
Rippers and Dave and L is here Lorenzo
from gray area is right beside me here
one first place in the solvent category
at the D
yesterday uh yeah we got a ton of people
in the house and we're basically
checking out some of seed rippers resin
so if you want to take a little tour
with us here this here is zombie Cush
excellent quality resin very impressed
with uh the quality of this resin and uh
just the photo it's really
photogenic really beautiful color and
all of it it's got that red
red color to it it's just
awesome he follows he follows your dry
technique plays uh
Facebook group okay tell me that again
um our friend here what's your name
again he follows he followed you Bry
technique so this gentleman over here in
the marijuana safer an alcohol has
brought some really nice dry sift and
he's on the marijuana alcohol yeah he's
got a shirt this is this gentleman
wearing the marijuana is safer than
alcohol t-shirt name what your
name name my name name
all right cool well beautiful hash and
he's on the group he's in the dry sift
group on Facebook so we'll definitely
have to have a rip of that as
well this is David's more of David's
just
Ridiculousness oh
God I think they say Fuego in
so we're here with Tony as well from
River Rock he's got his camera out
shooting a little bit of River Rock TV
and a little bit for the documentary
that we're uh shooting and this has just
been the scene pretty much everywhere we
go Wicked awesome people with great
amazing hash and all around killer
Vibes so keep watching Bubble man's
world and come by spannabis and check us
all
out what is this zombie it's zombie Co
oh my God
go okay well that's just really
nice that is the zombie
cush and I got to say they did a great
job on it you know you're looking at the
resin and you're looking at the bud
bless you Tony Tony
B all right so we're doing macro
photographs right now of the zombie Kush
from seed Ripper and
it's so beautiful and so photogenic even
though it's dried already what he
somehow has managed to understand is
that if you don't touch it and bag it up
and do all this kind of stupid [ __ ] your
bud will forever be perfect and you know
it's the putting it in bags and touching
it and squeezing it back in the bag out
of the bag you just it's a lot of time
and energy to grow resin to give it to a
plastic bag or a glass jar
all right you generate a question I make
it happen and then I translate it back
yeah I guess I'd like to know how it got
turned on the water hash
and he he started by growing and using
all of the all of the ends of his need
everything instruction were the most
accessible to Growers nice excellent and
how did he um get into breeding
so he he actually do quite a joke what
he there go he doesn't really look for
money he goes first gu followed by
Passion yeah his passion got him here
way I I can tell also it seems like the
guy that if he got into herb when he was
younger he possibly had the best herb
out of all his friends it seems like
that you know if you can say that
at 22 he opened his first grow
shop where you get everything to grow
and I just wanted to say that I you know
I met you at the canas cup in Amsterdam
we've met before and I've seen Ripper
seeds but to me I never knew about
Ripper seeds I never heard about Ripper
seeds but I I want to tell you all out
there right now everything that these
guys have shown me is beyond exceptional
super fire hble hash and incredible
quality but I look forward to making
hash with you man yeah absolutely
so it's good to be hanging
out during the beginning of making hash
he just
small kind of pulling himself in the
sense that oh yeah I'm using B but it
wasn't a he started using top H ready
and everything really nice he started
getting this qu
fresh
say he doesn't always make it
fresh he he actually acknowledged that
there's a difference
in for me the the
for him the best thing to do is buy it
for Mon and then put it on
[Applause]
the they also trive by doing four or
five mon free and then pulling it out
but uh it seems it seems to them that
everything was to graded
theice over my opinion my opinion yeah
of course is a strong opinion as it
relates to your experiences no this is
my my
and he brother
Square
friction doesn't
90 oh no
real I
that
[Music]
25 all right anyway um I know one
thing we're definitely going to be um
doing some dry siting together and I'll
show you some techniques so you can also
have full dry
thanks for watching everyone we're here
with David and Seed
Ripper and LU is uh from Canada he's one
of my boys from Vancouver so we're
having a great time and keep watching
peace got
it fan of this
2014 all day team DNA so it's always
cool to meet new people that are like
seeing you on YouTube are friends of
friends are in the community so
connecting with good people is what it's
all about
pleasure right dude time with family oh
yeah DNA winning [ __ ] all
day he's the winner of the
can you tell me I have three levels of
Bubble Bags you know this the original
most expensive what this is original
€300 for 5G eack kit it's the most
expensive I have the next level down are
the standards for a three five gallon
aack kit 30 cheap and then the lights
these ones that are different colors
have the white bag we don't have all the
colors still B okay
they're still eight B still made the
same half but no
warranty so here we have kulo one of my
longtime bubble ambassadors from
Barcelona he's explaining to a shop
owner who recently won the catalonian uh
can of his cup first place he wants to
sell bubble bags and kulo is basically
explaining to him uh about the varieties
and the prices the levels of uh
different
bags down
here new shop owner buying some bag
check
I should go get some more bags from the
back come on guys yeah tell us what you
grew there come on this is the original
G13 cross with the ha haille original
G13 cross with the Neville's Haze look
at the size of that nugget I'll tell you
it is solid it's not like all that's
from the ha that's just the cup of the
col not sanadora cvd aming it's a
76% cvd 11 uh no sorry 6 C uh 6 THC 11
CBD wow great job
man you saw this mat figured you
did
booah great Gardener appreciates all
herb beautiful hey great job
guys
J
aome so yeah more cool people coming by
and talking to us showing us cool herb
showing us cool hash span ofis 2014 is
absolutely off the hook totally [ __ ]
cool event if you're in the Cannabis
scene and you were thinking of a
cannabis event to attend to you might
want to check out Barcelona come check
us out peace
[Music]