[Music]
intern I get to talk a little bit so
it's at the
[Music]
end
hey there he
is hey look who it is hey hi Mark how
you doing very good Todd very good man
what an incredible building what an
incredible Space Place is amazing you
know took 12 years to renovate the
structure after Ben found the place and
then he turned it really turned it back
into its original Beauty brought the
original paint back instead of painting
over it he just brought the originality
back the history back wow some parts of
the building are over 500 years old that
back wall with all of the industrial hem
wow yeah that's why it's exposed awesome
well I'm going to do a little tour Bud
thank you
enjoy don't get the here's one of my
macro
shots that's the famous OG cush oh
beautiful beautiful oh yeah we got all
the books here there's Rob's
book chiac you are in the o to hashish
room if turn around your seat your
favorit this is the evening ah
yes very very
good beautiful Lebanese dry sifting
techniques sifting with the
screens just like temples
Nepali
Afghani
neple
all the African pipes pipes from all
over the world monster
bowls it's like a 5ft 4ft
[Music]
pipe old school Shakespearean style
bowls
hash
brown
Fato little
papers really incredible stuff this is
an incredible Museum I just
can't explain enough how truly
spectacular it is um they have done a
really incredible job I don't think
people can really fathom or understand
the level of collecting that had to
happen before a place like this could
exist so um hats off to Ben for creating
such an incredible collection preserving
such an incredible collection holding it
on onto it for so many years and then of
course being able to display it in a
building such as this that they put so
much time and energy to fix up um here
we have David tinis the younger peasant
smoking in an interior
1660 uh so this uh there's even hemp
oils used in the making of this
particular painting and these are the
farmers uh the peasants the young the
people the workers having a nice night
off you know they've got a couple of
drinks there they've got some herb that
they're burning and it's uh uh post
Columbus they're smoking it with
tobacco show you some of the other
beautiful paintings in here really
ancient paintings some of these things
are are very rare 1600s you know David
tenier again uh Camilo Inon centi
company in a Tavern this one's from the
1900s so it's 300 years after these
other ones
how about these guys over
here Kristoff Von lenski snuffing
tobacco so they're just snuffing
away oh wow I didn't even see
this
holy I had no idea this was here until
right now look at
that
beautiful all right in between the hemp
room and the pipe room you have this
really beautiful
little I mean I don't know if it used to
be a pond room really nice area for
sitting setting up the denail might be a
good idea for
that of course uh they're very
hospitable here at the Museum they're
allowing us to dab they're allowing us
to enjoy ourselves the way of course we
would want to enjoy
ourselves well this one the old classic
giving the dog a hoot
giving a dog a hoot look this random
dude did it 500 years
ago this guy looks pretty bait sitting
in his Palace just chilling out got his
hookah next to him rocking a couple
swords beautiful sliding doors in this
building and look at that we have Todd
McCormick cannabis culture Award winner
of 2012 so nice to see this is a good
dude right here a true cannabis Warrior
a true lover of the plant I uh I always
try to support what Todd's trying to do
because uh well he's been doing it for a
long time and he's uh he's passionate
about it he's intelligent about it he's
articulate about it and uh yeah I think
it's really good for the whole cannabis
scene look at these hemp
chairs pretty
cool cool little hemp
chair all hemp clothing shoes you got
composite hemp for Plastics in car doors
in Mercedes hemp
skateboards uh hemp decorators and
machines for
harvesting got wheels for spinning
backstrap 8ft looms for fiber
producing and then you've got the old
hemp Breakers known as the hardest job
to known to man but yet you'll only ever
see pictures of women doing it really
hard work breaking the hemp
more hand spinning more hand
[Music]
breaking I'm telling you guys uh if
Bubble Man world tours comes to
Barcelona and we end up producing a tour
for Barcelona 100% we are going to make
this Museum a big part of that tour
because the it really is is spectacular
the room is
spectacular so here we are in a
pharmaceutical room so we've got uh
different bottles from different
timelines elixers sedatives cough
specials uh cannabis indic digitalis
to cic and bloat so if baby's call here
bloated I guess you give them that
they've got all sorts of soaps over here
we have some classical jars that were
held you know sativa extracts and
cannabis oil from different companies
Simpson's drugstore here you can see a a
a little a little card uh subscri
prescribing uh cannabis sorry there I'm
a little baked here prescribing cannabis
and uh just all around really neat
things you know headache is no no joke
stop it with Dr anti- pill panes well
those pill panes had cannabis in them uh
over here we get into a bit of a
vaporization we've got uh bedro can's
weed this is the bedro can cannabis
floss bedro can 5 g J uh little jars and
then you can see there's what the bedro
can um license looks like and this is
one of the cans uh from elv Musa in the
US that comes from Mrs hippie one of the
original cans there's only a few people
left that even receive those so and then
other license is on display uh several
forms of vaporizers from The Vapor the
volcano the aromed uh looks like a
verdamper up here they really have
covered the gamut um in each room with
each subject that they're attempting you
know once again look at the beautiful
display of how he's displaying these
bottles cannabis
indicia extract cannabis indicia extract
cannabis Indian cannabis zinc phosphate
with cannabis indicia and
hamus and here we go manner of David
tenier the younger an apothecary
1673 people are coming in and they're
getting their prescriptions for cannabis
and other natural plant compounds and
extracts these are hundreds and hundreds
of years old some of
these particularly the paintings I
suspect this is a GW uh shot of one of
the growers in their mou massive massive
Zone next up we have a little bit of
sort of counterculture you know that
sort of hippie posters the glass blowing
Community hand blown glass from the '
80s 9s down to the 2000s I see her
little rure pocket buddy in the back
there some of the older books and pins
you know stopping the drug war normal
books about marijuana
law another cannabis culture award over
here with Richard Branson Sir Richard
Branson and thoral stoltenberg member of
the global Commission on drug
policy so you can see the place just
keeps going and going and going you can
just continue to walk from room to room
all sorts of different things are
covered in each room and there's really
an enormous enormous amount of
information that can be learned just by
walking through this simple
little just by uh yeah you can see the
amazingness just by watching walking
through this Museum you can catch
unbelievable amounts of
information so here we have a bus of
Williams with one of his style pipes
that he would have smoked back in his
timeline cannabis user perhaps obviously
if he's in here here we go members of
the club the
hashishin Alexander Duma Charles bod
Eugene DEA Geral Nal on Del Balzac theal
goer and Victor
Hugo so there it is the
members I have uh some stories on on the
the
hashishans weary with toil I haste to my
bed the dear repost from limbs with
travel tired but then begins a journey
in my head to work my
mind when body's work expired from then
my thoughts from far where I abide
intend a zealous pilgrimage to there
he's talking about cannabis he is
talking about cannabis here you can see
some people enjoying
cannabis
this looks as though it's cyan or middle
eastern um and
basically an old way to vaporize
cannabis on coals and drying out the
buds really nice windows in this place
as well it's incredible to work uh
Sophia apparently has done a lot of the
um stained glass window window work that
you see throughout the museum and uh
it's very inspirational just to walk
around and see here we go this looks
like the Chris Bennett poster from his
book years ago his name must be in there
somewhere yeah here we go sex drugs
violence in the Bible there's Chris's
book along with uh Neil
McQueen Shiva natala hajra Shiva
and it just keeps going guys it just
keeps
going hey guys bubble man here at the HH
and marijuana Museum in Barcelona uh The
Secret Cup people have just gotten here
they're going to be doing their awards
today so Jeremy's here with his crew
they're setting up their tables bumped
into a few cool guys from Ireland give
Martin and Paul a shout out from Belfast
you guys are doing good work up there
keep doing it and of course I'm here
with Tod cormick and Lauren and we're
came together dabbing it out right now
having a few dabs so I'll try to show
you guys a little bit throughout the day
this is obviously a pretty big oil event
but you know what it's it's a cannabis
event at the same time and it's a bunch
of my friends involved so I'm happy to
uh support Jeremy support the guys at
Secret Cup and uh show what they're
doing and how cool it is that they're
getting these events where people can
get together and uh you know basically
show their wees smoke together and uh in
the end have a little have a little
contest and maybe hand out a few
trophies so Matt the great Garder is
going to be here later today too so
let's see how the Barb does against the
oil I'm looking forward to
[Music]
that hey Mark would you like to
broadcast this broadcasting yeah we have
all the equipment you just have to go to
the car and get whatever gear you want
it is an opportunity if you like okay if
we do broadcast it let's broadcast for
like an hour maximum not the whole thing
whatever you want to do yeah like the
main kind of hour do do the awards if
you want I like it I'm
down all right so so then these got to
go yeah get rid of these and maybe even
like I just don't want to have it to
where there's a bottleneck yeah you know
like well these are definitely gone
let's get rid of these all right to make
these to another sorry all
right right oh here we go Secret Cup
[Music]
Barcelona nice all right it's 420 here
at the uh marijuana hampen hash Museum
secret cup Gathering and I figur I was
going to hit some full melt dry sift
[Music]
katonic happy 420 happy0 happy
4 nice Ed do I don't have to go to HQ HQ
comes to me yes
swanie time Swan glass is the guy from
Oregon I like it it's really cool
looking it's one of
five looks
beautiful very nice Wicked Man dab that
up his name is killer skunk killer skunk
that's a good
name oh nice here we'll check them out
thank
you
got everyone representing
here representing Secret
Cup come on yeah Javier's in the house
yeah boys wicked
wicked finland's in the house
yeah
I
hey everyone this is true from True Cog
genetics from OCD Labs at the head
museum for the secret cup Awards
spannabis it's been tiring it's been a
lot of fun all right guys what's going
on with the secret cup having a [ __ ]
blast out in
Barcelona hi there no distraction see
you there maybe on the stage we see
check it out right here Hing at the
secet cup Barcelona waiting to see who
gets the first place second place third
place
noning dabing Secret Cup let's get ITR
cup bab secr cup the best Cupa back now
right guys so we just had the uh pure
turps brought
over nice turine content right there
real nice color on those turps real nice
smell on them we'll probably do a little
dipping and I'll let you know how it
turns
out phone from OCD Labs where we at
buddy P museum museum for oh Secret Cup
Secret Cup you've been puffing your own
dry sift haven't you oh yes hell
yeah all right we
[Music]
got Jeff what are we doing here we're
going to make some rosin more rosin more
Rin and who are we making rosin with
with Mark Emy and Jo Emory with the
emories taking pictures of each other
this is
awesome
all right well as you can see the secret
cup here is just blown up there's tons
of great people in the room totally cool
cre of people and uh we just bumped into
the emories good friends of mine from
British Columbia and uh we're going to
do some
rosin for Mark and jod so I've never
heard of this I've never seen it I'm
totally bewildered so yeah so
essentially think about it like you're
you're turning the resin heads right
uh into a liquid and they will be pushed
out from the side of the bug so yeah
let's uh that looks like a good size
butt clean off a little bit of the leaf
and the stock Yeah clean off a little
stem
here Sarah
uh we'll put that in there in the
photograph somewhere oh yeah the part on
the table
sure
yeah
excuse me excuse me unug the phone right
what's that yeah you can unplug the
phone
totally all right all right we're about
to get
power you can go upside down
too nice she got
it nice job thank you Sarah sck it into
the Dil huh sck it into the Dil no no no
no just into the plug into the plug in
the wall okay that would have been
something looking at at at the display
people are doing that no way yeah no way
yeah the original paint I know you know
he didn't paint over it he had it
revealed yeah that's original he didn't
that's why it's not like popping popping
he didn't have it repainted he had it
unveiled it's unbelievable man you know
how much more money it is to uncover
and just paint it over holy smokes true
restoration so we got this Bud
here and then we got this
thing pretty riing hot getting it up to
temperature this is a true Testament to
how much resin is on the bud too cuz and
then you come over here and you go like
this so this way you can see also how
much oily it is
right and there's a little little tiny
dab on it we'll try it again wow I
wouldn't say much no no no but it
depends it varies from Bud to Bud if
there's a lot of RA we were gifted this
so I can't speak to what it is yeah like
the other day someone gave us a
beautiful Bud we squeezed the dab out of
it but then someone else gave us a bud
and we got like three Dabs out of it I
see what's happening you can see the oil
now little bits squeeze it first time
really
hard
yeah now it's wa
for now the but should be wa for
I yeah that's
one yeah which is what you'd expect out
of a bud a small little bud I think
that's one it will be when he collects
it
up here collect it up well I see why
it's $100 a gr I see why it's $100 a
they have to show it to him with
hash it's good bu than you
do you want to try dabbing it Mark we'll
we yeah collect it
for the parchment paper is great yeah
parchment and the the slick sheet oil
just picks the resin up
beautiful you see how the dabs Gathering
now on the on the edge of
the
all right that's kind of
fun
right get you to hold this
pipe beautiful oh the Dil or electric H
this is a dabinator from Germany all
right so that was on a bud like 10
seconds ago and now Mark's dabbing it
wow it surprised me it is that's the
part that really is surprising you know
that you just dabed that bud yeah well
that was an interesting
process well think of how many years
that was definitely one good hit low
side of it from that same amount of bud
I've seen three times three times same
as me and that would be too much so you
know but it's no I mean that
it's good way to determine potency like
take one gr and see what you can get out
of that one G see how far it will take
you it's a great way to test butt if
you're buying pounds as a dispensary to
a great way as a breeder to test tpine
and oil
content exactly you're but you're a
Compassion Club buying pounds we want to
see the resin content squeeze a bud you
can weigh the bud before you squeeze it
Mark and then you weigh the bud after
you squeeze it and you find out
the weight of resin on the
plant yeah all right we're going to try
with the moist but that's moist and
given to us by someone else moist butt
okay a little different sure all right
more pressing
I we saw him yesterday together the blue
the blue
blue was there it was from a purle fresh
ptuh yeah from a fresh Bud it was it was
fresh blue yeah it went blue it was
amazing never saw blue right all right
here we go
again
this squeezing buds squeezing
buds giving you anything yeah little bit
here and
there I better drink that
water what do we call this Pro rosin r o
s i
n and if you want to follow the kid on
Instagram who really came up with the
idea of squishing buds his name is soil
grown would it be fair say that if you
took the bud apart into little pieces
and then likees it's better the smaller
the pieces the more you get out he uses
a t-shirt press and and puts like 12
buds in at a time with big sheets of
parchment we have to make it with hash
smell S I don't know but this is the
travel method
you this is like anybody can steal their
sister's hair iron instead of like
stealing a in
PC crazy chemicals are
freak this is natural and let's it's
like exactly and we can do it with nice
hash
too what happens in the we're going to
do hash after this it turns low grade
hash into high grade oil well this is
nice grade hash yeah yeah we'll turn it
into higher grade highest grade oil yes
highest grade
oil see that I can see that on there it
seems small but
I up yeah
yeah you're killed me before that's the
fresh never comes off as nice
eh the water keep makes it stick a
little eh yeah
yeah everybody's unique like a snowflake
yeah true I like the way you said that
everybody is unique like a snowflake but
I heard it as everybody's unique yeah me
too
but she said every Budd yes true every
bud is
unique I did hear that they found
snowflakes that are the same actually
so it's a nice case you got there buddy
yeah have you have you guys met Javier I
don't know Javier is from medical seet
this is Jody and Mark yes I know I know
I meet with your day and the last time
you stay here and listen next
time next time you come here if you want
to find good
bud I'm not
joking she couldn't find any good bud
when she comes to Barcelona she can't
find nice pot everybody dabs in oil
these days too right it was
like's
the she's dabbing it out
Javy oh yeah
you making Instagram post over there
mark yeah awesome um is this a
ER uh it's a woman's hair straightener
or a hair
straightener that's what do they call
them a flat iron a flat iron right of
course Jeff knows right that was just in
a butt on your pocket that you might not
have even
poed so maybe up in Canada they call a
hair straightener but like girls laugh
at me they said that's a that's not air
Canadian girls wouldn't laugh at you the
hair oh all of a sudden every girl is
calling here let's rosin up a piece in
the
screen strain that butt
out nice that's what we're
doing we got to do it with a screen
though after this next piece of
hash there we go what was the name of
that nail I got hijack what was the name
of that nail that in a second we're in
the middle of using
that we're in the middle of using
it I know but we're in the middle of
using it that's what I mean I'm filming
a video of us making it we'll make that
too but right after he does this piece
what that nail the brand what is it uh
this one's called well the electric nail
is called dabinator and it's in a
Mothership pipe and what is
this I don't know but something
something pretty nice that someone gave
me so and then do the hash the
dry man we need two of these
[Music]
revons so watch the hash mark you don't
want to miss this what happened to your
little one the other day I have it it's
like in one of my bags you get it out
well looking for I think it's actually
in my suitcase that's either in that
room or in Todd's car so I got the hash
a little ball here I baled it up in one
of mar 25
my yeah you know maybe qu or something
there and
then you press
it 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 wow you can already see that
hello
dabs oh man should we taste that you see
what I'm saying Mark now you see the
smell so cool it is so cool higher
quity Todd wants a dab Todd wants a dab
how much and weight would you say that I
bet you got 50% out of
the and he probably d% of it I was like
to try that we doing it we're doing it
at the house fresh press fresh press has
off the bed hot it's unbelievable the
first time you see it open I
hope i' have to let the world see this
screen technique so that they can get
right to a great product with it and
make them want to experiment on
flowers how was that can you experiment
it was excellent but we have to clean
the bowl
oh another squeeze or no yeah I'll give
another
School of
isolator gave it this school of isolator
is what they make every
week nice they teach
everybody oh good well thanks that's
awesome I like the school of
isolator all right we got this
going second squee see what we get this
is so fresh and so new Mark is literally
sharing it with the world right now okay
honestly how much did it blow your mind
to get out of prison and have a
smartphone put into your hand yeah
that's right holy [ __ ] so that's it's
worse for me because the judge banned me
from having a phone in my I know you
didn't have one for
like digal anology from The Brick or
from the little flip
razor to oh my god wow that's amazing
this what's interesting is that right
now this technology whatever you want to
call it is still in its primitive stages
that it's using
hair and when it turns into using
different temperatures and finding
different activation levels I mean so
much potential at that leftover gummy
gooy and now it's like power and and
from my perspective I can tell you for a
fact this is definitely less than half
of what I gave you yeah so we got more
than 50% return out of
that an
ashay oh yeah right
there thank you so much all right now we
have the dry sift to rosin up oh nice so
we'll go right from Bud water hash to
dry sift I would like a DA that one
excellent well we're that's he's up next
the re whatever you would like Ros who
wants that no just put put in that rock
or something yeah like if you put in too
much it's not efficient what you want
right here and I will do I want to share
with the it's not
just we're just turning it into dabs
yeah yeah how many dabs would you like
as many as we can get all right then
they're all there how much did you put
in twist it
[Music]
up that's a SE Cup represent yeah
you're doing this with a how do you feel
high smoking decar weed well it's not so
decarbed everything you smoke is
decarbed cuz when you burn it you decarb
oxalate it this temperature is not
enough to decar that's why when Jeff had
his tested a
of%
sure we'll get it so that
that the test means that the heat
obviously it would be the first one to
be gone for sure the Turin are being
affected but activated and destroyed not
necessarily at this
point from the scientific perspective
when you test the material after you do
it de decarbox silation doesn't
generally Take 2 minutes unless you use
like 5 or 600° plus of heat which is
like when you burn a joint or take a
dab but this is 5 10 seconds it's not
just not
enough yeah and and you know if you put
a little bit more in there like looks
nice you should dab that too much you
got line heat you know so there's a fine
balance with this technique but when you
upscale it what about doing it without
the screen I just want the PIP um your
contaminant runs with the oil I'm going
to give it back to you in a
second no problem he just wants to take
a picture you want a picture of this
pipe this does to be a big dab I'll just
give you a little dunk okay there you go
a little dunk I'll do you mark and then
we'll give you the uh the carb cap as
well cuz it's
[Music]
funny enjoy
wasn't that
was boom oh
boy oh
boy
boy a little dle do you what's up
boss Manitoba in the house so I I see my
Facebook feed today and in it there's
this giant [ __ ] dude like bench
pressing a guy and I'm like look at
these [ __ ] maniacs and then I look
again and it's my friends really I'm
like what the [ __ ] who were you Ben
pressing or you know you were you were
powerlifting or I was
squatting they said I couldn't squat 100
lb I was like that I that made
IED that guy had to
100 that's what I'm saying he was a 200
lb put on
his dry Manitoba representing
don't [ __ ]
around yeah yeah hting the
[Music]
[Applause]
boss yeah
buddy you guys just went through the
full rosin experience like Bud I I'm
telling
you I was I wanted to
wait so much look it's true it's true
it's
true strawberry
B we can make we can make out of it btom
I can squeeze a dab out of that you see
the bottom of the trim bag it's like all
this out nice should we squeeze a little
bit Bobby nugs you know him yes
he actually got to try the dry sift from
this oh Bobby nugs got the good stuff so
you offered Bobby nugs the dry sift he
was around me he's my hood Bobby's
awesome dude shout out to Bobby he is a
good guy I hope you feeling better
brother yeah me too we're going to get
him uh it's one of the worries that I
have with him that I keep that I've been
telling him because he doesn't know
what's wrong with his lungs that I want
him to just smoke the safest possible
product as possible cuz he has lung
problems this asthma thing knocking him
out and putting him in the hospital
that's serious [ __ ] that's like my girl
was extremely scared she's friend with
everything my he supposed to come on
hash church that day he got basically
sent to the hospital instead yeah we
supposed to have a party that night CU
you never showed up to it down Rhode
Island
brutal can I take tiny little butt of
that and squeeze it CU then I'll have a
dab so that that's how you do it can you
make me a dab of the strawberry banana
yeah let me let me just give a little
squish on this oh yeah squish that no
I'm just lining things up yeah perfect
getting things into the queue yeah yeah
yeah you know how I do yeah well you
know how I
do I'm the Q Man Ro making rosch with
Reverend cannabis Reverend Jeff Church
team Manitoba Team Canada and team and
team Seattle no voice team Seattle and
team Ontario and team
Colona that's why I said team we're
representing all right how we doing
dry sift again yeah looks pretty decent
it's all
right I mean I'll tell you what uh way
more way more coming out of this than
came out of Ramon's but Ramon had
already robbed all the nice 99 once you
squeeze it open it so the camera can see
it each time and then that's the money
shot yeah bet it wasn't smell Vision
right so many
people
nice like that's what I'm talking
about zero parts per million no V oven
no purging and no butane so here's a
little bit of a lighter uh hashes that
other stuff was black this is go to the
bottom of the grinder is that what I saw
you
guys your Instagram
should it out I'm from Scotland watch it
too from
scoty yeah this is now dry sift rosin
look at it dude get rest if you take a
picture of it I would suggest I would
suggest doing this you know holding it
up into the light
that's nice should be making dry SI
bro show me how to do it my that's all
IED to nice congratulations thank you so
much I just had my third really it's my
first ni nervous you'll be happy dude
hey much love to cat too man I love you
girl yeah representing on Bubble Man's
World God I thought you lost your bag
there for a second no it's I had a water
and it's gone
now I had it right
here man that was really
really yeah but I don't know which
one faces and a lot of new faces but the
family is still the same it's great to
see the movement so strong all the way
overseas thank you guys for uh the
passion that you have for Canabis and
and for being a part of the event so
thank everybody for being here
[Applause]
yeah move right into the awards um I do
want to say a couple things that uh it
takes a special thing to make a secret
cup happen and a lot of people that put
in their effort here um you might not
realize how many people have have really
given of themselves I want to thank
Lorenzo he he really made it possible
[Applause]
W thank you very much to him uh our
first award is going to be for best
solving you guys have a really strong
solventless scene out here seems like
it's uh maybe even better than what we
have in the States it's it's an amazing
thing I got to try many many good
solventless uh hashes out here and some
traditional ones really really
great the winner of the best solving
list is medical Hunter medical seeds
number
[Applause]
yeah thank you very much say something
about your p and tell everybody what you
enter my enter is I can speak
Spanish
[Applause]
the the name of the St is no name the
gross is chees you cake with g
the bag I use
is and micr 73 micros and the process is
water and
[Applause]
ice the next prize is for that's butter
W I thought we would have more butter
out here but the shadow scene is strong
but uh some very very good Butters were
entered the highest scoring butter
Lorenzo
[Applause]
yeah
yeah okay I after amnia from lalada it
was really nice weed
nice it was just really nice
[Music]
[Applause]
body stacking medals stacking medals
over there with
Nerds okay the next award is the
connoisseur's choice so everyone here
got to vote on what they think the best
has is regardless of the score
regardless of
anything the hash you guys chose as the
best from the whole event is uh Qi
[Music]
[Applause]
concentrate
thank you very
much
to do the top three prizes overall now
these are the ones that move on to the
finals at the end of the
year third place is going to get a rig
and also an email but unfortunately our
trophy torches and pendants are stuck in
customs
the winner will also receive those
things as
well third
place BJ extracts number
[Applause]
number 13 was a Skywalker OG
nugrun wax dry scroll back oven or dry
scroll back and cross
international thank
[Applause]
you okay so second
place I think it's called deor
tree
[Applause]
tell us about
[Music]
[Applause]
your now for number
one okay so we had a lot of really good
stuff entered I really want to thank
everybody for putting forward their best
effort I felt like we got a a really
good bat of different kinds of hashes
and uh this is also the uh best shatter
as well it usually happens so for number
one best shatter and the number one
overall the winner of the whole Seeker
Cup team 10 extracts number 14
[Music]
[Applause]
he's not here but uh in his
placee you want to say something about
what he entered you know a Karma
genetics headbanger as a ecsd cross uh
push my favorite of the trip as
[Applause]
well thank you guys for coming we're
open
[Applause]
till there you have it guys that's the
secret cup Barcelona done for
now keep watching Bubble Man
[Applause]
[Music]
world