hello uh how are you al man good uh this
is my city and I show you yeah this is
Barcelona City yes this is the first
time we're going to get shown Barcelona
by someone who really lives here and
knows where to go where the good smoking
spots are okay and where the good
inspiration is okay so all right all
right let's do
it so fast yeah they never no doubt most
people that are heads people that are
really into it have never seen that many
different kinds of hash I was impressed
when you showed me those all those boxes
with the different sure it was great
okay so was the YouTube uh bubble man's
world audience they loved it yeah I love
M car I love I love maybe make more than
a smoke yeah well
maybe it's
but I like love yourh I I'm like a
searching goal you know the the the the
guys uh cleaning yeah the alist the soil
exactly exactly this is my goal I like
that yes right so we just pulled into
this little parking lot and uh it's got
these two poles like in the middle the
new drivers is there holy [ __ ] is this
where he wants you to park yes no
backing into there or are you going to
back into there there in the back
nice I'm ja
mcai it's your City
yes I think uh that's very tight I've
never
uh Jesus Audi X6 is a really nice car
which
[Music]
one
boom that's how you do it right
there all right I'm here with atcha from
medical seeds we're just waiting for
Javy he's uh gone to do a few chores
we're going to have uh well a beer for
atcha and a cheers a little Peach drink
for me so that's what we're up to
Barcelona all right so uh we nbed out a
little bit the uh restaurant was closed
that we went to that was kind of fun
right second chance man second time
second chance we going to the typical
Restaurant Seafood Spanish all right and
another parking
lot perfect
mea all right second chance this
restaurant this is this is the the the
brother the one we're going to or this
one no no uh there there okay there but
the pulia yes it's like a aoo sh nice oh
looks really you said it hey there it is
wow that looks nice Seafood
shrimp every Ty got see food and Pap ho
smokes that looks so good from Spain
awesome in we
[Music]
go
now 3 years ago like that it's not legal
too no they stopped it so that's the
that's is just telling me over here is
the bull fighting
arena right here so several years ago
they stopped it no more bull fighting
yes but still
dabbing all right
finally back for pops when I smell I
feel the high yeah
206 no I feel but I I I think this this
is not K me sure dude this is so nice uh
for those of you that aren't here this
is it's about a year and a bit old uh he
grew it last year before I left I think
or maybe before I got here and this is
2046 which is a Cali Mist I believe a
pre98 c Mist cross to NE is pre98 though
correct yeah of course of course I I I
have one pre98 and one pre 96 and for
your Neville's Haze did you plant many
and find the best one or was it a gift
or how did you find your Neville's Haze
W it's is the queen I think of my seat
bank is the the the more older plant I
got it in my my Ru mothers you know what
I mean did you plant it from seed did
you get it seeds from Greenhouse
surprised me because I can't find I try
to find the same genetics but but I know
some years ago greenhous is Los genetic
sure because but Greenhouse definitely
worked with Neville back in the day
Neville was hanging out there so it
would make sense that they would have
access to the original Neville T yeah
yeah yeah yeah and I guess after Neville
left I think they got Shanty Baba on
board Scott he made maybe the super Sil
when Santia work in the in Greenhouse
exactly
exactly in the mean time somewhere in
Spain there it is there it is look at
that guys um I just it was funny cuz
when he handed it over to me it was just
utterly beautiful but there were like
four little pieces of contaminant so he
was like a it's dirty it's dirty but we
cleaned it what I cleaned all the pieces
perfect thank you thank you very much
looks better now maybe one one or two
more but it looks a little nicer right
mhm okay all right so I guess it's time
for a dab I of course don't have my
right
power I don't have my right power right
now so we're being very careful with the
whip I don't want to blow the fuse in it
or however you know put too much power
through the whip that is only able to
put a certain amount of power it's crazy
step down power here from 220 down to
110 that we require but once that heats
up I'm definitely going to hit this and
what was the name of this one again a no
name no name yes variety of strains like
a a cross to cheese a cheese cross s yes
with something else from you sensy star
across to cheese cheese UK beautiful I
we hit a Sensei star across with a
cheese UK to start it out there's so
many lovely things that you have in your
yeah this is train this in this case
this is
no name
is the Taste is not too much sweet but
for extraction what the [ __ ] it looks
just beautiful the bubbles everything
when you put in the Nile everything is
disappeared you know right yeah one
thing I noticed when I smelt it it
didn't have as strong of a smell as I
thought it look so nice I thought it
would be very strong smelling yeah like
like
now
everybody like the the strong test like
a cou like Amnesia you feel the test in
the moment you
know well that was really
nice it did damn
near boil away to
nothing almost no residue in the nail at
all hitting that deep dish Banger oh
there's the carb that I couldn't find
what do you say you want to hit one of
these anyone are you guys going to do
work for a bit these guys are actually
working right now they're kind enough to
be letting me film but what they're
doing is they're preparing everything
for spannabis if you can remember last
year when I did an interview with h
Javier he had that incredible he had two
of them actually had uh one box it was
all uh ice water hash bubble hash
isolator whatever you want to call it
and then he had another one that was all
of his oil extractions which he's done
an incredible book that's really
covering the the gamut for extractions
what is your book called again M yeah
your book your yes the book I give to
the editorial yeah but the him correct
the the mistakes autographics you know
my my work is finish what what is the
title of the book though the name of the
book I think manual extraction manual
extraction yes oh perfect I mean it
covers I've never seen a book that
covers more because it's not only for V
or or mechanic extraction is for
therapeutical for every
extraction for the marijuana oh my
goodness now what is that this is the
fresh frozen look I know don't do it
this is don't do it I'm going to show it
to the camera still oh no don't do it
okay okay you got to see this cuz I got
to turn it at a bit of an angle and I
don't want wanted to fall out but how
about that for some quality guys this is
73 micros fresh frozen deil fruit
amazing this is Devil's fruit yeah and
the the oh you try the thir watching
yesterday 45 microns and everybody say
it's amazing it was beautiful it had
really really wonderful flavor but this
is clearly the first
wash oh yeah I can't wait to hit that
that's going in right now yeah this is
amazing amazing
amazing
wow like a snow Yeah like a you know how
say the name one one is snow one one
flake FL that's that's it
flake W this is nice no flake flake
flakes little little Dabble do you all
right yeah The Taste on that is really
good grow with me and him don't know the
the weat
H so bad between is dry you
know and see one month later I say hey
what the [ __ ] what is this I think what
the [ __ ] him grow but don't remember
this is deep Neville this is deep
Neville deep Neville number H 16 oh my
God
16 it's crazy man
who now it's yeah last time I I I saw it
was wet you know was just good okay I
got to show this to them because this is
really really nice see it under the
light here
guys really got to do it justice by
getting
close I mean that is
fire yes for Destruction this plant what
the
[ __ ] really eh yeah
well I'm not surprised the real
crystal there we
go so you can see clearly that the guys
at Medical
seeds have a strong clue as to what's
going on it's great to travel to a place
like here knowing you guys and just be
able to show up and see you know what I
would consider definitely
probably the top some of the top 5% of
the herb the best that's in this
country I don't think that's going out
on a limb too much that is so
nice well definitely going to get the U
macro lens out at one point in time and
give you guys a little show to see
really the
quality I wish you guys could smell this
it is so musky and
so just hard to explain the smell is
very subtle yet dank extremely dank so
well know we have a few more bowls with
these guys record a little bit of this
session for you guys and then uh I think
we're going to bump into Flav and are we
still going to go see some spots here in
uh your City to smoke what what do you
say SP well like a nice smoking spot
later or something or do you want to
just go to
HQ you know your city your spot oh yeah
yeah ah our C our SP yeah you know
like don't get me wrong this spot is
great I love the power I love the herb I
love the
hash man that's
nice and I brought my lens so I can
literally use this time to photograph
all of these get nice photos you've got
more under here don't
you perfect I love it let's put these
back in
there three number three
yes moist left in this
one I like have different phenotypes
yeah oh is that all crooked kind of
looks crooked I tripping yeah it's
totally
crooked we
go does anyone want to D yes I want it
all right which one would you like why
not would you like Barb maybe these know
yeah did you want to try something new
like I brought a little bit of no no no
no I don't I don't have any new products
no no do you want to
try of course for me to offer you of
course my okay I figured sorry sorry no
no never be sorry Matt just gave me
today thank you Matt House of the great
Gardener very kind of you my brother so
this is some of his
Barbara okay bubble hash
oh it's extremely tasty extremely strong
and just really you'll love it you'll
love everything about it it melts away
to nothing it's you press uh no he put
it just in this little parchment and
gave it to me I he must have pressed it
oh yeah look at that quality
yeah yeah
amazing when you get it close right
you're like what yeah when it's go just
you know not to touch it too much just
touch it a little like push your finger
on it a bit because you'll be surprised
at how it
feels okay it's very very soft you know
what I'm saying yeah it's sticky he
wasn't even able to touch it he said
that he had to freeze it before he could
break it into pieces so let's have a dab
of that it goes with a temperature oops
got
it it is much oh perfect nice nice if
it's going to fall somewhere it's nice
when it falls somewhere clean fell in
there we would have been like a
tragedy a
tragedy all right so let's see what we
got here everybody's going to beet you
know oh
yeah all right so we're getting nice
small medium size
dad have
uh deep Neville
right deep Neville I love that one of
the strains that Javier has chosen to
work with two of them actually is the C
mist and the Neville's Haze both of
which I think have very special
properties that have been lost to those
who grow only kush or only these strong
strong indicas that exotic flavor yeah I
I I think something different I think
the people
[Music]
grow more plants for the time like for
the efforts yeah because the the people
think more in money than the the it's
true the love in plant you know what I
mean it's true yeah he's basically
talking about what I call the
prohibition based mentality the
mentality that's to grow how much can I
get how much yes and how fast yes
exactly when I the people Quanto you're
asking the Quanto question exactly you
got it wrong the people love my genetics
cuz you asked the calate question yeah
yeah the hze but when ask ask me for the
weeks okay my friend
I for from yourself what the [ __ ] all
right here we go here's a dab for you
you ready okay yeah deep dish Banger
time just let that drip right down there
it goes look at that
boom Matt and Sarah killing it so happy
that you guys are just my friends cuz
you do a great job at what you do the
great Gardener is very good at uh well
he's like you guys in the sense that he
recognizes quality I've always been um I
find myself attracted to characters like
Javier who are very like just
passionate you know because those are
the people that take this first further
they further it so I mean look what you
guys are doing right here right now this
is this is on par with anywhere I've
been in the world for Quality those are
beautiful buds this is beautiful hash
yeah you know for me is the the gold you
know so what I say to you out there is
that don't think that it it's once and
here's something to be said from Spain
as well how long ago could you find
quality like
this still today you can't really find
it unless you're you or or you're
someone that knows you you understand
like this I can't go buy this at the
association across the street no you
know what I mean maybe a friend I mean I
have to admit at HQ they have some
pretty great stuff but this is It's on
another level no always I make heart
yeah I make for myself of course I can
tell this the first people I want to
like because it's me of course you know
what I mean and I try to to make the the
best hustle always yep than ready for a
d ready for the body one of the things I
love about the Dil is sort of the ease
of just passing the pipe around even
still with so take a few seconds let it
heat up and when you see it melt to the
bottom then you're there you
go got to thank denil for always hooking
me up with the goods and I got to thank
dabinator as well cuz today I'm actually
uh using a combination of the dabinator
and the denail tools so dabinator got
the European power source which is key
so I've been really loving
that nice
hey
Barbra
awesome little
Barbara it's nice oh dude it's so nice
you know what it is you know what's nice
about it I don't know shisha Berry O you
know shisha Berry yeah sure this is this
is the Shish cross the pure aghan look
this is you said look look it smell like
this Yep this is shisher of course it is
now I wonder what line of shisher is I
us say shisher where did you get your
shisher it's a deil fruit devil fruit
yes he gross
to where did this you when you got your
shishka Berry yeah 12 years ago from
spice of life Ste of course dude how
about that he pulls out now listen this
is also made from the spice of life I
got it more genetics from the spice of
life like Su and and Blockhead Blockhead
yes nice I love because my BL head when
it's dry smell like a banana dry is
amazing amazing I mean wow just to give
you guys an idea when he pulled it out
it still obviously covered it Leaf you
can't really tell just how dank it is
but just pulling off a few leaves
there you can see that that's some
pretty quality nug right there breeder
Steve yes I always respected Steve
because he was also like us in the sense
that he was obsessed with the best
making the and generally for himself he
was happy to pass it on but he was
always like it was his desire to have
the best and grow the best that you know
that produced still to this day so many
of the best resins that I that we're
finding Devil's fruit which I hit today
uh deut from Ripper seeds gave me a
little Devil's fruit bubble hash uhhuh
yeah and then you as well definitely the
two uh nicest hashes i've smoked since
I've been here as well as Matt from the
great Gardener well that's always a
standard uh that the Barb is going to be
right up there in the top to every
time so let's see I hit your Devil's
fruit I guess I better hit your
proac yeah o that's also not much motion
on you see how Javier does it looks so
nice when you style it out starting to
fall down to the bottom I can just show
you right through the glass window which
is
wonderful you know I like to show you
guys up close so you can see that it's
I'm not just talking out my ass I'm not
blowing smoke up these guys' asses this
is really really great quality so it's
nice to see of course it's nice to dip
my Pala into the the Pala one so they
call this theala it's the shovel it's
the it's the bubble man's
choice this what
they
wow Prozac
is very unique now what did you use to
make Prozac proac is lavander gross to
Goose lavender okay but it's much close
to Lavender listen when I first blew it
out it tasted like soap then it tasted
like like lavender gum that weird
lavender gum that tasted a bit like soap
yeah I can't remember what they used to
call it Thrills I think that is a really
unique tpine so you use lavender and
cross it with Kush Kush which was the
cush purple cush from
Canon
officialish wow I'm going to have to
spend at least 2 hours photographing
this stuff so you guys can see it on the
macro lens and I'm definitely going to
do that um we got Flav on on his way
here I think he's bringing a sick
Mothership that we probably be hitting
in the near future but uh for now I
think I'm just going to keep puffing
enjoy some of my time with these guys
cuz I don't get to ever spend enough
time uh with the medical seeds crew and
uh yeah we'll be back in a little
bit
hey why Timber Ro feel good me
[Music]
a oh man home man real purpose the we
that keeps
me the purpose after the weed to the
Mind purpose after the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
VI the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of time
gja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do it purpose of
D we have been traving to King 20 mil
hours sing on like the clock FR with
trees
[Music]
flowers
me give me one big and if
biger
me pass pass
[Music]
pass I make pass pass pass
and