[Music]
hey everyone welcome to Bubble man's
world just uh kind of gearing up for
spannabis today's the day John Burell
did his interview with um I guess the
national CBC National is uh going to be
on March 31st and April 1st you can
check that out all across Canada and
today we're leaving for spannabis so we
are off to Spain we're flying out of
here in a couple hours and I thought I
would start the video of the journey to
Spain with a beine rep cuz you know that
D nail is packed oh maybe you should put
some hash in the bowl there bubble man
going to hit a little watermelon that we
made up with Ron up in Proctor there
some months back really nice punch to
this hash great spicy flavor extremely
dried here we
go bowl didn't want to come out there
which does happen
sometimes not so much when you're
hitting the denail cuz you don't really
need to pull the bowl out but
uh I guess that's locked in there a
little bit from the last time I had the
denail in this
BN have to deal with that
later anyway super excited to get to
Spain Barcelona uh we're flying to
Amsterdam today as well so that'll be
nice just to kick down in Amsterdam for
a few hours and uh yeah we're going to
bring you along with for a little bit of
the journey uh next up I'll be at the
airport bumping into John I'm going to
go finish packing and uh enjoy the show
everybody I hope to see some of you in
spannabis peace all right we have
arrived at Vancouver International
Airport and who's that
dude Jo John B I just got out of the car
are we going to Spain going to Spain
dude good to see you yeah all right so
yeah just
uh my ride's just pulling out look at
how how low that is my ride just pulled
out they just dropped me off so uh I
guess we're going to go drop our bags
off yeah and maybe go and have some
Trippy Stick session and then we need to
all right cool we'll see you in a bit
just remembered something J what it's
puff Wednesday I know it's puff
Wednesday we got to get in there get our
bags put away so we can go enjoy some
puff Wednesday here at the Vancouver
International Airport here we go
the
KLM
hey guys John and I here at the
Vancouver International Airport
departures just had a little bit of
lunch little peanut butter sandwich and
an orange
and kind of feeling that it's that time
to show me where you
trippy John uh John forgot his trip so
let's rephrase that we'll be sharing
we're going to be sharing an as now and
then I also have chamber and an extra
glass chamber
spam but my battery is still charging it
thought this is like a high five
this yeah more like a [ __ ] yeah but you
what it's it's it's a sweet thing going
be able to sit down and
the
world yes
indeed you have
uh yes I've been to Barcelona uh
beautiful city beautiful people really
great event ESP spanis is is amazing
it's very
busy kind of Cutting Edge there's going
to be you know the Spanish have a lot of
leeway with the with the plant they're
able to do a lot of things uh pretty
much since 2002 or 3 when Switzerland
kind of closed it down a lot of people
moved to mag uh where was
it yeah in Madrid I guess I don't know
it would be nice to be there it would be
nice to check it
out
a little trippy rip we are at the
international airport so there's a lot
of buses and TR going by constant we got
ourselves a nice little spot here in the
sun though literally our bags are
checked all we've got is the carry-on
bags and by carryon bags I do mean we
have the
Dil with multiple whips Mothership
quartz bowls tie bowls ceramic inserts
the whole N9
yards it's all we right
there if you hold if you hold the the
thing on yeah it's not really H I think
we need to push that down a little bit
give you a really good
rip what don't you
maybe beautiful dessert yes we're going
to be eating some caramels some uh High
CBD canonic caramels from the great
Gardener got a couple each to Wolf down
on the on the plane we can take the
element
[Applause]
up it's quite nice to be able to sit
here and puff before we jump on plane go
Asam yeah I guess puff Wednesday today
is going to be in Vancouver it's going
to be in Amsterdam and it's going to be
in Barcelona and of course it's going to
leak into Thursday because uh of the 9h
hour uh time change and the 9 plus hour
flight but for us puff Wednesday is
going to be a an
international yeah yeah we land in Spain
and we kind of
getting
so you know what maybe hour or two c on
flight see how things work out maybe not
I sit beside him we like to chat yeah
we'll be chatting it out for sure chat
that's for sure it's so nice to feel
that it's just legal for us to enjoy our
medicine our caramels which I think I'm
going to eat one yeah
you yeah not sure what I even did with
mine but I know there's somewhere
there's one so these once again are from
the great Gardener nice hi CBD catonic
uh not overpowering by any means very
tasty just go us some nice relaxed Vibe
on our
flight definitely really oily mhm so
when we get our
swamp we did this pretty much at this
very spot this very spot it's going to
be this spot we're going to come here
and this is our spot if you're ever in
Vancouver and you're at the
International Airport come by and hit
mine and John's bench
if you look around you might find a
treat think some
slide it's always best to leave
something behind fly safe anyway we're
going to continue to puff and we will
see you I guess maybe on the plane more
likely we'll see you in Amsterdam at
shiple sound good John
[Music]
a
we never stopped puffing well why would
you we're still here puffing at the uh
at the spot the trippy stick's hitting
Like A Champion so uh yeah just push
that resing down and she gives good
rips yeah so def couple of CBD canonic
uh caramels down the throat how
beautiful the
days know it's so perfect just like wow
what what a great time to leave
beautiful sky and that view as we're
leaving Vancouver and just flying over
your house and think the direction we go
yeah yeah fly over Mar's place it's very
cool this going to be awesome pretty
much an exciting day go see some buddies
in Amsterdam then split out of there
probably we'll be on the plane with some
friends so we'll take wages as to who
we're going to be on the plane with is
it going to be S is it going to be Ed
who's going to be on our
plane see you later guys all right so
John and I have arrived at the uh I
guess it's kind of the food court
there's like swaggy food in the
background actually Milestones over
there which is probably where we're
going to go no that's where we are going
to go but the cool part here is check
out this this aquarium in the Vancouver
airport just you know some
10,000g salt
water a little
boring size of it absolutely that's like
that's all
alive whole amazing they're pretty cool
too the way the fish are like swimming
around backwards and Starfish stuck
thing there yeah you can see them all
down there all the starfishes and the
the Ling Cod down there looking like
he's going to
die might be a c but well there's one in
there under the rock yeah hang looks
like a sucker of some
sort anyway let's go hang out and get
some food let's do it
[Music]
about to take off of John B on puff
Wednesdays here we
go
w
hey JB yo Dude Looks like we found a
nice little rooftop Terrace here in uh
shle airport it's wicked out here dude
should we set up the camera and do a
couple rips I think we're set ceras all
right okay I like
it well welcome to Shole International
Airport in Amsterdam everyone we're uh
sitting here me and John just enjoying
this beautiful Amsterdam day like we
can't kind of believe it you left
Vancouver it's blue sky we land it's
blue sky we flew here in under 9 hours
it was great the caramels lasted nice on
the plane the Trippy Stick session
before we just kind of had a little
little Trippy Stick session before we
got the camera on I got the Trippy Stick
right here uh the problem is is we are
pretty much on camera all over the place
and there is no n roen rokun in the
terminal last pet Park Cafe no smoking
outside we didn't really want to attract
any attention so we had a little mini
Trippy Stick session off cam we're
sitting here well baked and uh we're
going to head down to Barcelona in about
2 hours so 4 hours from right now we
will be in Barcelona coming out of the
airport and we will definitely be
setting up the camera and having a PP
Wednesday Trippy Stick session in
Barcelona Barcelona or Barcelona as they
like to say here in so stay tuned pull
up a chair pull up a bong and we'll see
you in
[Music]
Barcelona put on the
Unis we got Simon we got Jason we got
Don Ed
somewhere over
here Johnny's in the house I wonder if
he's going to spit on his per wizard
outfit o the purple wizard outfit are
you going to put any outf time no not
this year dabs though we'll be dabbing
with you guys soon in Spain see
[Music]
you piece of
in
all something show
way and then one day you
find a behind you
one can
[Music]
run
he hey he he he he he
he he he hey
[Music]
he
and
[Music]
welcome to Barcelona please remain
seated until the fer seat Bel sign has
been switched off this is the end of our
flight we like to say goodbye to you now
I don't want
toal we're here we thank you for Flying
K and we hope to see you soon on board
for one of
flight enjoy your stay thank you and
goodbye all right freshly landed in
Barcelona go to jump in a cab guess head
over to DNA's hotel and maybe get a dil
session happening [ __ ] we're going to
get high bro in this [ __ ] they
got dabs they got Tangi we got
watermelon watermelon we're good hey I
think your bag just fell oh there goes
original dab cre on a three wheel motion
oh there he goes there he goes how's
that puffing it's great barcelon in nice
that's what I'm talking about love it
I'm going to pull my Trippy Stick out
that's is on and the dnails getting fued
up we're here at Dawn's room yes Aaron's
coming up John is here I am here the
denail is in the
house and by Dil you're not talking
about Don no I'm talking about the
actual D the actual nail of D I know you
don't smoke flowers but I know you
appreciate them so
absolutely 100%
appreciate can't get the resin without
him there you go you just can't get the
res
without I love it legal
Dutch um yeah look at the Year Don
Morris 126 2011 I still carry the same
containers I ain't paying that I think
it's a grand the idea of what people in
Canada are going to do too you know
we're just not going to be all right
that's a new one that's called 24 karat
gold it's kosher
Tangi yeah oh you're right it totally
looks like it looks like kosha but then
SMS like that's nuts crazy it's [ __ ]
crazy bro dude it's fire bro dude 24
karat gold and the T and the U kosher is
Jew gold right originally so then that's
why we call kosher gold kosher is Du
gold okay that's all it is it's is that
so so that's the crew the crew that grew
it that we got it from called it gold
that was what they called it see a
little it looks great we didn't want to
call it gold because it's not really a
can market
so but all we did wasend so it is J gold
it's the same strain you see what I'm
saying so when we made a j gold the pink
cush is all that and I got all different
beans for all this kind of crap so the
the kosher times the Tangi since kosher
is really duw gold we call it 24 karat
gold
cuz there go you heard it
here right you heard it we spend it so
when we do make regular seeds we could
we'll use either yeah we'll use the
Tangi
exactly and this is 12 our Skywalker and
it's
[ __ ] also flame bro yeah right there
yeah could be the dankest weed we see
while we're
here that's a Skywalker that's just a
Skywalker cut it's an OG cut doesn't
really have a lineage right it's like a
cut and so yeah that's people have
different versions of their Skywalker or
whatever but I mean that's C we've been
running for years
and here yeah the and then Aaron has
some Tangi on him I brought Tangi and um
tast that smells killer yeah you smoke
flowers or you
just I smoke
flowers but I know it's going to happen
we're going to get this denail on and
it's going to be
like and oh I have Tang actually I'm
glad that one plug worked cuz the other
one
didn't I'm so glad it's always a little
bit
nerve-wracking that's just
straight oh God it's so rank stupid I
don't I don't let's say I'll smoke a
joint of it because it's nice and I like
it it doesn't really get me so [ __ ] up
so then I'm always like feeling that I
just smoked and I still need to smoke
yeah I got the camera on oh nice yeah
just chat TV we're just chilling hang it
out [ __ ] and we have gifts SAR
too always nice when you show up to the
hotel and the the woman hands you a box
and says oh yeah by the way this is a
package that was delivered for you and
when you said this is called bubble
hash he's like what
that call on the phone John oh it is
called Bubble B
yeah oh yeah open it up buddy let's see
what we
have gifts oh gifts are so great thanks
for putting that water in
John that's awesome that definitely gets
you the first rip the color on that yeah
he does good water hats the weed will be
one way or the other it's it's good it's
grown good and it's organic but you know
it's aged and it's spish style it's
going to be killer
but it not going to compare to
this maybe know what he's doing yeah 73
to 160
mix he doesn't do any
VH that is looks like oil look at that
stuck to my stuck to your nose
dude yeah that's uh definitely a nice
black little shiny tur
oh but this is the one yeah I can see it
right away all right
well nice call him up right now John
you're up
buddy look at me I'm just like right
dude well you well we're all using it
medically but let's just say you're
using it a little more medically yeah
you heard what happened to John No he
fell 30 ft broke his neck in like two
spots and his back shattered his leg and
his head smoked the the wall on the way
down and it got all cracked his jaw and
broke his where did you
fall he was onal drugs living underwater
like my neck in four places so a C6
burst my neck BR like bur pesus from
Impact shattered in 15 I see completely
rebuilt icated my wrist is hyp sensitive
A3 a shadow my ankle I broke my head
broke on my teeth my where did you [ __ ]
cannabis is his pain I don't use any I
I'm doing interviews with CBC National
CTV News and I'm published all okay
where did you fall from bro a scor a SC
yeah J 2000 I'm talk by trade I'm a
laser by trade and I'm [ __ ] my which
one did you hit water well you hit the
watermelon I'm going to try this one
okay um is what it is you know what I
mean p myself under the wheelchair and
[ __ ] [ __ ] yourself up bro dude he
himself up so
bad I want to show you guys the quality
that we're dealing with here this is a
what Don just opened
up yeah but I mean that's not that's not
enough is that the quality or
what that's a gift from the south of
Spain further south than we are now
beautiful gift I've hit pumping this
like da that there there's the other one
too that was the 73 through 160 you can
see it's just shiny as
[ __ ] very nice and he's got a couple of
strains as well Girl Scout cookies what
PK purple cush PK yep in candy cush C or
kosher but when I smell it it's hard to
see because it's hard to tell cuz I
think it's been age usually ages sh they
look like they age all those buds yeah
this was might have been last year's
outfit this is my first Spanish bubble
since I've been here and it looks
absolutely full melt and delicious we
just showed it to you on the camera so
let's give it a
rip and I'm looking at it to see how
well I mean the stuff is just like it's
just it's turned completely to oil
completely the oil it's just my that's a
70 a 90 or a 73 it's 73 to 160 so it's a
a
blend
what up Cal how are
you well I got your package I wanted to
tell you thank you I'm here with bubble
man and Aaron and we just sampled your
goods and uh that's the first Spanish
love we've we've
encountered it's beautiful beautiful
hash hold on I'll put you on speaker
phone there beautiful hash man we just
smoked it out of the denail with the
mother ship it melted into a liquid
dissipated with little to any residue
and a beautiful high after a 10hour 14
hour flight let me tell
you yeah we appreciate it as
well yeah man absolutely that would be
really cool John and I are here in this
elevator with a ton of crap F we barely
fit in the elevator and we're going to
go see Tony and jibs so uh let's make
our way here we
go very
careful I find
out aigu
fabri
[Applause]
the all right so we just got to Tony's
apartment linked up with gidy up jibs uh
John's still in the house and we're just
about to rip up uh some bubble has in
the Dil so I guess we're going to
rearrange the apartment first cuz it's
just not quite it's just not quite the
way we want it so can put it in the
corner
now I love how giddy's exhausted so you
have a moving furniture and
lugage we days and all a sudden we're
moving
furnit
here rearrange based on the wall outet
for the Dil all right we'll be back
soon is loading up a hit see you later
man what do we got there some Mendo
cross
some a 90
Micon oh I see you're discing it up yeah
we'll give him a
nice donut what you have a hotel with
Jason yeah I know I'm saying we going
over to no later oh yeah just to see
everybody Tony you ready yeah I'm to
sleep you better get ready man you
better get ready see see lat yeah you
too man for sure I'll do
it look at me I'm just like you know
what
like are they bringing over all the
camera equipment put it on that'll
Inspire watch it's on Tony Tony it's on
oh it's on who nice and slow and steady
is this
ceramic steady
Meo
oh
T that's beautiful it just goes to
nothing thanks thanks apprciate
wow that was awesome that was so good
for the camera and he didn't even do
that on purpose he's just a loving guy
he's loving
guy
booya I like it m's on the computer
chatting in the background the
mothership beautiful Viv
espol little trans dermal THC pure
CBD pure CBN uh is a CBD is a
CBD
CBD there's
CBN CBN canab demonstrated results sh
muscle spasms inflamation and insomnia
so if anyone has seizures and there's
five types but if you feel that you want
to test that
out instead of Chasing The Strain
chasing the rainbow if you will and axis
these are available on both sides now on
adult Sid adult use that's where people
really had the misunderstanding you know
they thought we were like all wrecked
it's really about trying to get more
access to cover all the bases so it's
like why wouldn't a parent want to come
in and try this see if it help
absolutely
All Pure CBD helps okay there's your
solution perfect there you go yeah at
least add it to the quiver yeah so it's
not oh it's very
cool Afghanistan we stayed there and it
comes in lotion now too trans dermal
Afghanistan
just