[Music]
I started record started okay hey
welcome to Batman's World we're at
Medical seeds here at the spannabis 2014
we're with a bubble Ambassador here hav
he's going to show us his herbs he's got
his bubble hashes here his uh Earls he's
got it all here he's going to take us a
little bit through this so good see you
man okay really definitely to see you so
what we got here you showing me the
Canadian cush yes Canadian cush is a
genetic I create for European market I
bring the genetics from Canada carpel C
anal c el Clon because I know the
professional growers in Canada
two years ago I win the second place in
sativ yourself and I changed my [ __ ]
El CL for with the different CL the
different grower to acquire the yeah so
did you breed it or did you just acquire
it and then self it in the seed did you
just make seeds or did you use something
different your own exactly you did that
exactly what else came what what did you
process a for GR
to C CR yeah excellent very nice yes
because in Spain well in Spain in Europe
the CR is the new theme think it's like
uh it's definitely like BC Bud La bud
this is Kush like it's just straight up
it's a nice Kush beautiful Kush so
that's Co the
SM and this is a parp Bo this this
genetic I present in this SP I in many
cups it's amazing bu amazing Crystal I
this see a straight for
for
me exactly I win three or four cups now
I don't know maybe I I win the the this
year
inanis
yeah very nice yeah congratulations dude
you're killing it yeah thank you thank
you thank you I knew right away when I
met you in uh Toronto yes when I met you
I was like man I only meet maybe a few
guys like this if I'm lucky
event like over 4 days or whatever and
the minute I met him I was like dude
this guy's brother I know he's doing
good things in Spain so cool what what
do we got here this is my new creation
my my new
creation regular seeds this is regular
not feminine this is the the first Trin
I I create regular is one one because I
want the people select the more
different genotypes
uh and yeah exactly and I have the real
na case I have this clone 20 years ago
yes when it's the real case in ameran
it's a really difficult plant for grow
this 16 weeks going to say 18 16 16 16
but when you make six maybe it's a
little two weeks more sure but I cross
to deep chunk for cutting the the weeks
for cring CH yeah I I Tom Hill CH yeah
Tom Tom Tom Tom Hill he took Tom Hill
deep Chun yeah and he you selected
exactly I selected one man deep CH 10
years ago my is 6 years AG I deep chunk
Lev yeah and this is what this is yeah
and this is Jesus Christ open [ __ ] up
I three or four different genotypes uh
for example this is a nille this is the
name is a number three short in Spain
Corto Corto okay yes and deep nville
strain three
large oh this is kind of fruity and
unique dang nerdy holy jeez that's uh
reminiscent of almost what I saw years
and years and years ago when they
claimed that there was the UBC chemo or
the BC Cho like the from like the
scientist or whatever very dark and like
when it when it when it dried it was
almost just like hash it's more you
couldn't really break it up you know
exactly so that's very nice to see so
that's deep devil
three yeah I'm my fa you have because
because I I like more of the cases too
when it's more longer it's more
sativa more you cut out that time you
cut out that time you lose that tpine
profile those flavors you know the tpin
it's the English word for the the
smells so if we go long with the hazes
we get those spice yeah yeah spice
perfume or
something acid a little bit
acid absolutely and this is number 16 I
select because half so much crystal is
so fast and this was your Haze one
one yeah but this is a the same deep NY
the different genotype
163 he's got them Jarred up in some
really nice jars and well like
professional like come on the guy is a
professional there's no doubt about
it oh yeah that's beautiful
too very nice resin you know it's just
uh in the game it's so nice to see
there's how you just it's always awkward
if someone shows you something that's
not like just that you you don't you
don't want to lie and tell people like
that's super awesome when it really
isn't this is really superb like [ __ ]
Primo herb like I know for a fact if I
made hash out of this it would
absolutely be
fire smell too smell that camera
man that's
a everything my man
Mak this number well all this product is
for I love this this ch now we're
getting into more hazy more hazy the the
structure is is like a sativa structure
yes
exactly it is much more
CA and it has that that spices in there
yeah it's almost like
campfire know what I mean if you've ever
had like smoke gamage on your
clothes that smell oh camping
last minute on the battery that's really
nice that's okay we got another
battery so that's the Neville deep
Neville number three L which I'm
guessing is long large large awesome
that right away and this is the queen of
sativas the medical seats is 2046 is
close to nille close to K oh before
97 oh okay
with with the older
uned that was I got it that was the
more like from 973 yeah 398
97 but for me the more casy plant I got
it is everything oh this is
awesome this is a
oneq
beautiful last seconds on the battery
all right well you can you can stop it
and we'll
back
put so
much that's the actual purple this is
more genotype meno genotype nice serious
meno I like the perf you're right
doesn't have a strong smell at
all doesn't have a strong smell at all
but definitely like decent purple herb
I'm not usually a huge fan of purple as
a photographer I love the aspect of fall
colors in cannabis
definitely that's beautiful it looks
like we're getting to my favorite
personal part which
is the water hash water has no the first
I think the the best part for the final
oh there you go okay sure yeah he's
going to show us his oil he's going to
show us his extracts uh Javier does it
all he does seeds he does water hash he
does uh extracts and I'm hoping to get
him a little bit on the dry set show him
a few tips on how to clean dryp to uh
99% pure gland heads yeah cuz that's the
next year I'm going to come you're going
to have a whole one of these full of Dy
and all these pure heads yes I'm telling
you so these are your go through these
you want to show us these yes I make the
different styles for the people know
know if I try the different strengths
the how is the
best different process for the strain
you know I make for example the IGA is a
a really good for S and because when I
make a Bo it's more wax that I prefer
coconut bu the coconut Bo in Span in
Spain say when it's too dry yeah the
sample okay this is in Spain no it's wax
it's migita de Pan migita the pan is
white bread the part of the the bread is
inside fresh exactly that's fresh plant
that's what I I don't make oil but I I
know resin straight pan baby and this is
a I prefer make a Bo H for you can smell
the turp noise and how smell the the
strange right right you know but 100% I
like more a smoke bubble H mechanic
exraction I love mechanical myself I
prefer finger finger C sure yeah your
own
fingers sometime is mode but it's really
a strong for
me after I learn every different process
I know uh the gas is inside the sample
right yeah of course sure not it's I say
it's the laboratory The Specialist say
right yeah yeah exactly you going to
test yeah exactly so there you go yeah
tested by the lab okay I'm sorry uh this
is so fast that's okay okay your show
you showed your textures I prer it's
more my PR this is what I'm excited
about this is definitely what I'm
excited about these are his varieties of
bubble you can see how Javier is very
much the perfectionist he likes to like
categorize and just nice clear I I'm
just impressed I like all the the
packaging the Dual and triple packaging
some pressed some powderized yeah yeah
exactly double high five from the bubble
yeah but some people like more press and
some people and you have all the people
covered right here that's what I'm
saying everyone is happy exactly
exactly yeah for example I don't know
you want to try a song theme yeah I mean
I did bring a denail but I also brought
a bong I could just easily pull the bong
out if we have a screen of any sort
might have to drop a screen in there but
we can do
that oh excellent let's do dabs
right
now uh this is quz nail we just need to
heat it up with the torch okay okay oh I
hope I brought a
dab right there sorted just like that so
maybe a little bit of aqua and the Bon I
don't think I have enough but some
better than
none get it about the p
E I like to put up there
b then we'll if this torch is in working
order a few H it's quartz bowl and a
quartz uh carb
C this
I know maybe in Canada a perfect yeah
chance they
they I want to inside yes yes I like
that yeah yeah you should absolutely
he's talking about the new uh I guess
the treating yourself Dash Champs um
taking over from Mar orenda and the John
from skunk and I believe the guys from
Champs are co-working the event and
that'll be in May in Toronto and so yeah
it'd be great to see you there with
entering some some strains so I guess
we're going to take a dab or or two we
got the uh if you want to pull something
out I don't know like I don't know for
example I
recommend
like when dve the first time
really I
mean don't want to sleep team want to
walk around yeah yeah it's way with the
uh powder bubble what I like to do is I
usually take uh the little Dabber and I
just I usually have an electric nail so
I'll heat it up on the quartz and then
literally just like stick it in there
hot and the powder just sticks to it you
don't have to like press it up touch it
with your fingers yeah
so I guess we're going to take some
out oh guys already in
there I got
it that's ridiculous that bowl is like
250 bucks or
something that bowl like a couple bus
you want to try is hard to
blow just need no video okay cuz problem
p no no after after problem
man yeah exactly I do okay there yeah I
did I butcher your
language H we make two linguage in
Spanish and English at the same time
very cool I prefer make a i isimportant
information is a great photo essay sty
Technical and too much photo because the
the people you need it you must have too
many photos yes for example the this is
the inide oh beautiful so there's
intruction there risk
therapeutic mechanic instuction and
that's where I and chemical extraction
solvents yes introduction um for
example the first warning signs warning
warning warning knowled because in in
Spain
have so much accident yeah if you're
going to teach people this sort of
information it's important that you yeah
you teach them the safety first really
that's information about the Heats
information about the risks the risk the
the solvents
uh prot different system for safety the
quality of the herb par exactly I can
tell from the picture yeah exactly that
and I'm obsessed with that is up this
more attraction like tours so you made
all most of this is all you and your
photos yeah yeah yeah exactly exactly
this my world the last 10
here looks it's pretty Dam good yeah the
olive oil I saw that it look for salads
for my sacks for everything super good I
love the bottle too yeah exactly Bott
for that's good yeah I'm cream super
professional I'm impressed Rick Rick
Simpson uh oil yeah and for example
after the next capit is do you do some
explaining in this book on the Endo
canab system yes exactly I explain a
little bit about absolutely inav system
this is the next step on showing all
these and the safety and why are people
using it and what is it doing I I show
the different meth methods of
construction and the different meals
meths you can use say the Maran
yeah yeah creams and everything the
different meths I studying about
everything it's crazy I study more there
than when I'm young it's
crazy but for example the
H
but and a mechanic stren you like uh you
put the wheat in the bag like dry
sifting we call it dry sifting yeah
exactly and uh after with the
in the pollinator in the fer and bubble
quality great quity beautiful yeah yeah
you got the whole process to start to
finish with the strainers yeah yeah I'll
make the different techniques with my
team
with picture yeah thank love that love
this this looks like scotman Sam's
almost yeah where did you get that from
this is a mosino parus nice and this is
the
the when I make for insight in the cup
this is the
sample yeah I like that I've seen this
one recently one like it that you did I
really like it nice to see you're
playing with your resin that's beautiful
red thank you thank you
absolutely I better take a hit while
he's talking cuz I still haven't taken
one I fed a couple out
we go walk around a little bit okay
don't worry we come back of course back
soon right on guys we come back I pound
you out but I'm kind of full and no
worries man nice to meet you see we'll
see you guys again soon I'm sure we'll
see you soon thank
you all right want to sit over there we
can both sit over there I want to both
be well okay I'll sit here for now and
then I'll take few spot
go yeah dude yeah man yeah man the
aftertaste on that is ridiculous
it's like uh fruity candy right like
some crazy fruity
candy absolutely wonderful that was the
the Y GRE or E
GRE 73
micr very nice very nice thank you thank
you thank you very much you let me know
if I
can I say you want to smoke the mother
chip a little head I'm come sit over by
here
the hash will pick the hash up now guys
ready all
right great
this a great book you put together here
man this is no small feat you've really
put a lot of information I can honestly
say I'm not sure that I've ever
personally seen this much extraction
information in one
place about the V yeah the who different
styles and Hony Mon and uh we make a
so and
so yeah I love it I love I love to see
this representing in this book this is
definitely uh a book to be in this is
great man it's nice to see you working
so hard it's nice to
see Hill or
res thank you we're going to film more
with you you are myen bro oh dude insire
me right back I I don't know who are you
I make H with you B long time ago I win
so many cups I don't know who are you
when I see you in Canal it's like I see
a is there more ex excited personality I
know in the [ __ ] marijuana Market I
don't care nothing you know what I mean
of course of course I love when you me
I'm creative I
happy to share the information with
people like yourself who I always have
called Bubble ambassadors because they
go out in the world and they just share
the information and that is enough to
inspire people I mean who walks around
with like a thing like this this is an
inspiration to any hash smoker I know
many of you will be watching this on
Bubble man's world you have to agree
please comment if you do you want a hash
collection like this and I think we all
need one you know and that's why guys
like you and me where we do this and we
inspire people you know more people are
going to have it when people see this
video of they going to go do this when
people your
book when they watched you win all your
cups every year people are like C it I'm
going to do it I'm going to buy some
seeds from ja no no no the people told
me how you make but I explain everything
you but is say I say I explain
everything in the book but the people
say no maybe you're little I know no
promise you people always think that
we're back I I present every my secret
pick up because I don't want inside in
the [ __ ] cups anymore I want teach
the people for the people make really
good [ __ ] there's a lot more substance
behind that that's more important than
just you know winning a
cop exactly exactly exactly this is
beautiful Ash I'm excited I don't want
to leave here I want to like attach
myself to this thing the whole time I'm
here
here spanis 2014 P for medical seeds
thanks for watching guys see you again
soon peace bye
[Music]