[Music]
very I got
some [ __ ] yeah orange lighting welcome
to Bowman's world we are in Barcelona
with jibs and John and me and Sublime on
the uh bows so I guess it's waking bake
huh boys indeed we've been waking baking
it for a while kind of just sitting here
for about an hour puffing and chatting
and then uh I realized why haven't we
been filming
this uh Tony's still asleep he went
pretty hard I think for like 48 Plus
hours or something yeah what you guys
went it was about like 36 hours to 2
days of
took us a while to get over here neither
of us really slept much the night before
but nice too exciting eh yeah that's
awesome but we're here now in Barcelona
it's morning time getting the flow see I
had the patch on last night that Tony
gave me ah yes which one CBD CBN I did a
CBD patch last night great sleep these
are these are really cool man yeah I
just looked down I talking I was like
look at her I did the patch last night
patch I might have to put on patch Today
Show be effective in treating
inflammation diabet great I so relaxed
last night I feel really good after 12
hours of being on a plan yeah they're
great if you're around traveling all day
of Colorado Mountain you guys got it
down there let me tell
you so we've been puffing nothing but
the full melt since we got here we've
hit watermelon we hit that crazy Spanish
bubble yesterday I don't even know what
was that that wasn't girls coat cookies
red stuff not red stuff I don't know
what that was that was we'll have to
find out Don and have it it was
definitely topnotch Ridiculousness then
we bumed seeing them yeah they dude
they're looking forward to seeing
you they're definitely looking
forward yeah last night we went through
the cham dog uh
cross yeah the kog meno cross I think I
might hit some of this Grand Star Killer
wow this is this this is soapy I like
that well this there's no more of this
so you can tell was last night yeah went
through quickly yeah this was uh
definitely um well it was enjoyable
absolutely just amazing good work man so
day one of the spanis today yeah look
forward to seeing what the event is like
oh seeing all the people too seeing all
the people seeing all the friends great
folks in the house it's going to be a
lot of fun playing ride in was full of a
lot of people yeah oh gosh our plane was
just we had uh we had Simon from Sira
seeds uh Ed Rosenthal wow Don and Aaron
were literally sitting right across the
aisle next to us it's a serious lineup
yeah we had Jason was there from damp
cring there was even a couple other
people that I I recognized but didn't
know their names but they're definitely
in the scene and work in the scene yeah
if that plane would went down we were
laughing and would have came know yeah
take out like a big chunk of the cvas
can just like one
plane well well you know it's that last
that 2:00 flight into Barcelona the day
before the event right yeah you figure
most of the people from Holland we flew
in from Amsterdam obviously you guys
might have seen this uh puffing on the
rooftop uh rooftop patio
there and and as we were talking about
uh leaving Vancouver like he's like we
should make a b and we're going to see
on the plane from Amsterdam to Barcelona
cuz you know we're going to see some
people and of course turn like gy hey
what's up and we first walk down into
the into the into the place there's like
no one there were the first one was like
there's got to be something he's running
back and forth goes don't they haven't
changeed they always change it at the
end and we're like people started
talking one slowly people started
acquiring and sure enough that was
awesome buty good 90 Micron some of my
favorite always probably forever very
clean so yeah we got a good day ahead of
us we're going to do some filming with
um with this documentary thing that
we're doing with Tony go do some
interviews down at span and check out
what what's going on tonight there's a
party at
La
yeah yeah Club ver there's a party
tonight so we'll be down there doing a
bit of filming and
puffing and just uh I guess we got our
friend Amir is on the way right now he
just came in from Turkey he's on his way
here Louise from Canabis culture is on
his way here he's not with Canabis
culture anymore no
no he's down in that he is the can
that's culture actually we're all part
of the culture true enough so we're
going to continue on puffing bows and uh
maybe Tony will wake up a little later
on and we'll uh we'll hear what he has
to say for our
first morning waking up in Spain we
going wake up we do a huge session he's
going to wake up
like talking 2 hours we filmed it you
can watch it we got I'll be like check
this out look at the light I want you to
look at the light he was so excited
yesterday I was excited for him like I
love the way he Geeks out on the quality
and like settings the shot up and the qu
the sound quality and the video quality
and the it's just uh he takes things
serious he's got extreme attention to
detail and um I'm sure he will be
recharged tast on that watermel is
it yeah fantastic I don't know what he
used to do that string Astro Boy but
I've looked it up a million times and
it's funny that I just um forget it each
time love that it's a TGA string okay
and I guess it was a bad
boy was uh doing a breeding doing some
breeding for
sub and finish that up the watermelon
was an accident the AST boy was an
accident okay accidents accidents
happening sometimes are fantastic
absolutely that's why I tell people all
the time to uh play around and make
mistakes it's like don't be like cuz
they'll be like what's the best way to
do this what's the best way to do that
I'm like look I'm just here to give you
generalizations I'm not like the guy
telling you how to set up your lab and
that you have to do it this way or that
way I'm more like trying to show
everyone in general how to do it and
from there which is something I just
recently posted in that drawing hash
group which was like you know get the
basic foundation and then if you have
people that you are inspired by their
hash or how it looks and they live in
your geographic region ask them some
questions exactly you know it's no point
drying techniques will definitely vary
from where you are well that's it you
know this this this someone like Britney
telling someone oh you know there's
moisture in that hash or there's no
moisture in that hash or telling people
to jar it up after 16 hours of being
microplaned fine for the desert maybe
not so fine
forou where it's humid dude come on like
it's ridiculous that [ __ ] [ __ ] a
thick desicant and I mean a thick
desicant our moisture levels are so high
in the air that parchment paper is not
thick enough in fact the first time I
used cardboard and it was thin it wasn't
thick enough not even close cardboard
get what's your relative humidity out
there oh my God like I was going to save
higher oh really see that's the issue is
like I'm in Colorado
60 60 60 is a nice day and it's
everywhere in Colorado in a room and
it's 20 to 30% humidity get sometimes it
will get down to eight you know if I can
get room down to
20 it's a little too it's not it tries
really quick and then I'm like okay two
of us just got excited when you said
like really all right you guys ready for
this this strain was an unplanned
pregnancy the AST boy watermelon well
while making more Danny Boy seeds bad
boy was working with live pollen for the
first time he got major drift and a few
Apollo 13 females seated while we know
the taco male and what he did to females
we had already grown our Danny Boy and
simply loved what he added to the Killer
Queen the shock was when grow started
coming in with Growers tossing out
collected strains and replacing with
this little bit of dankness what you
look at is a cherry tart Apollo 13 and a
damn serious sativa hybrid some decent
heart racing visuals I was about to say
definitely a nice SAA yeah so it's
Apollo 13 crossed with Ortega crossed
with c99 okay and then he's got below
that he's got Ortega crossed with
c99 Ortega us californ and Inda c99
princess crossed with Cinderella 88 he's
got the it just goes right down the
Apollo 13 is genius cross with the p75
the genius is with Jack herrer which is
the haze times Northern Lights five
times Shiva skunk it's it just and it
goes for a whole like dude that to me is
impressive the family tree of genetics
and the explanation well they're trying
to yeah they're trying to take it all
the way to Afghani original
Mexico land race drains which is
impressive
yeah right on good job sub job I like
that very cool right down to the bottom
princess that's the p75 I've never uh
p75 that sounds like some uh didn't Ed
rosenell used to have strains back in
the day like 20 years ago that were all
like J12 and I should ask him I should
yeah you don't see edit all the
events I was surprised to see him in the
airport yesterday
yeah look forward to meeting
them also in Vancouver Puffs he'll love
your hash he puff he'll he's he Puffs
tough oh he was one we we laugh and then
uh the health Expo in Vancouver he like
came back he's like yeah I like that
need
to then he just kind of took it he's
like oh yeah I opened it up he's like
really oh thank you cuz everybody just
offers some weat so it opened up the
jars to hear have a smell he's just like
oh thanks and grabbed a handful and I'm
just like I guess I guess that's how it
go yeah there you go help yourself came
back signed a book had a little chat
that you know all my friends were coming
up to me dude look at Rosenthal signed
my book look at this I got a book signed
by Ed Rosenthal I'm like check out page
four I go to page for acknowledgements
thank you and there's like a whole page
of people but I'm like right in there
and like the ninth name or something
bman I'm like dude I'm in your book I'm
in the
acknowledgements basically because I
have paid for ads with Ed that's why I
got acknowledged I I've always uh
advertised in Big B book of buds and
we've always done well with with Ed's
projects he he has good distribution
people like his stuff like it's Quality
quality you know and is that the room
yeah it could be our
door could be a mirror see who it is it
could be Louise I bet you it is
translator uh-oh we might actually be
equipped is that at the at the door door
I don't know do we Buzz him in yeah that
that that that phone
hello okay here I'm buzz
in was that it was Amir air yeah amir's
on it amir's turkey and Amir Amir owned
um a restaurant across from my gallery
the melting point the melting point yeah
I had a gallery back in 2002 3 and four
3 four and five it's where marble
Slinger and I did the degenerate art
show okay the original one before the
documentary which was just a huge glass
show it was a beautiful Gallery had a
raw food
Cafe super high integrity had a Vapor
Bar like 10 12 13 years before before it
ended up happening it was it's just it
was too bad that it was ahead of its
time and basically I ended up closing it
down after my um father passed away it
was kind of a quick
shocking experience like when he passed
away it was shocking it wasn't like he
was sick or anything so yeah what up
once that happened it was kind of like
ah I don't know if I have the
energy buy dude I love the stash that's
fcking awesome dude my God how are you
in here good oh dude good to see you you
know John how you doing you met in
Amsterdam how you doing and this is Jims
hey here nice meeting
you uh we have some beautiful P we're
doing a little filming right yeah yeah I
did an that
one the seat
bu what's happening we're just uh
filming bubble man's world okay yeah
would you like a rip a bubble as you're
joining the table I'd love one I'd love
one how have you been good excellent
right on good to good to hear how's
turkey treating you it's kind of chaotic
at the moment really
yeah that's weird when [ __ ] gets
chaotic o
45 fuy
the 45's got TPS like champ they're
always very tppy yeah always I can pick
the 45 out with my nose I don't even
care how many hatches I on the
table if I can't pick it out with my
nose cuz it all I don't care about the
strength all has a
45 smell there's a certain tping profile
that always get it's like I don't even
know how to explain it it's like a
concentrate of oils it's why always
always lights on fire I've never seen
the 45 knot light just the way it be it
just lavas out and
just yeah lava yeah
fuel I'm a
fan how was that great so how long you
here
for until Monday okay cool I think the
majority of people are here till about
Monday we're going to uh be here till
well after that that's one we'll be able
to think once we go to that spanis it's
going to
long it's not going to be it's going to
be so busy dude and so big and grandiose
that it won't I don't know how big
events get here and I was really
surprised to hear that they have a whole
like operating two to 300 Social Clubs
here like that's oh yeah a really
impressive statistic even from Colorado
where oh yeah cannabis is legal
Barcelona definitely has a huge club
scene here 300 cannabis clubs 300 and
what's the population city what I'm not
sure let's find that
out you can buy just we open how is that
well it's like go on
PFF puff you can be a
member some members can only invite
other members was the scenario but it's
not 1.6 million as of 2012 what no just
the Barcelona yeah Barcelona yeah it's
Bist we get SP second largest city in
the country with of 1.6
million I'm probably getting like 10
million tourists a year or something
Madrid's got
3.2 Paris is in the Middle with
2.2 I thought just a little 1.6 million
people yeah that's a fair chunk of
people for sure yeah it's a fair chunk
of people all right well I think we
filmed enough we're going to continue to
puff and uh catch you guys later camera
I'm
joking hey we're filming
we're live we're live in direct here at
the spanis Pinsky we're looking for
Pinsky Pinsky is's right there Pinsky we
found him finally made it here all right
tough to
travel it is got to get motorcycle yeah
we got got get on all right so here we
are at banabas coming in hot I got
there's giddy okay 10s extra all right
it's easier
I think we're
here it's a serious line right
there all right well I guess we're
walking in the door here it's
[Music]
banabas pretty nice building to host
today yeah it's not too shabby this uh
beautiful entrance made of a pyramid you
know you got to admit that entrance back
there what we would call the lobby was
as big as cannabis Festival yeah I would
say this is humous I'm really cool the
way it's laid
out a lot of booths a lot of people
people we almost want to look at a map
because we going to be
walking oh yeah Greenhouse has got the
monitors do they
have DNA Paradise there's Luke there's
sweet SE oh yeah we should go see Don
dar
back there who's that h
I
you what's up can we get
some we hit it it's gone dude I'm so
[Music]
sorry what's up bubble b tv dook to be
here or river rock TV but all and all of
the above DNA TV and DNA TV that's
exactly it bro look at the [ __ ]
cops well represented boys
standing to my left two guys who really
need no introduction but uh you know if
you live under a rock or somewhere in
the desert you might not know
him DNA how you guys
doing keeping it fun you know it's
barcela what about you ER you eating any
good seafood while you've been here man
yeah you know uh my good friends over at
R Dan s out too uh one of my favorite
Seafood restrooms last night had a great
Lobster shellfish we always have know
but yeah man uh how long have you guys
been coming this SP think start you were
just talking yeah I don't know I want to
say like
yeah we set up our n or 10 our first we
set up is way over there with one table
we set up our C pack team we have four
Str sold three packs all right sweet and
we're doing better than you guys
I think 12 PS in your first year yeah so
there you go it's going to be like four
times awesome yeah I mean uh it's good
it's good to be out here you know in
Spanish uh call our friends so we don't
get time who all have we seen today we
seing Milo saw noan
Shake
AR all right guys here at spannabis and
we just bumped into on Rico from
sublimator Bubble Man bubble man what's
up man see you dud see it it's Canabis
dude this is your first as well my first
and I'm I'm I'm a little overwhelmed by
the size of this place it's just wow wow
wow it's like give me goosebumps yeah
there's an enormous amount of people
here it's awesome tons of boots good
quality boots as well let's check out uh
let's check out your
boots did you get a good that smells
nice in the air yeah that's a lavender
oil that I
uh it's not lavender it's an OG per but
it smells like lavender check this out
you don't do that stuff I know but no
but it's nice to see for you you know
thanks for sharing
absolutely you give a
h are you
out gentlemen here for
Tony I'll have some I'll try it let me
let me in try it I'll try anything it's
pretty true it's pretty true
I'll tell you what's in the house how's
it
going
Cante hot kante is both ways Cante
Cante all
right monster dab for
Tony oh my goodness Tony are you going
to do that it's just a half gr you'll be
fine it's just it's just okay it's just
a half GR
oh she's just dabbing from the slab slab
dabing D all right well what's up Al
what's going on brother dude good to see
you man you as well having fun in Spain
oh dude absolutely stoked day one of
this banabas and just kind of walking
around bumping into familiars it's a
pretty epic first day yeah you know it's
good there's so many people I'm diing it
it's actually quite
ridiculous jibs is in the house
yeah
dude all right well we're going to
continue on here thanks for uh checking
us out en Roo thanks uh bubble men see
you bub Bubble men's world peace out you
got to take that again dude take two you
know Tony can't wait longer than like a
second take wait wait a second
here I like that that was nice
bubble at the bottom yeah that's killer
you got to try them kill
it wow that's bubbling crazy yeah jibs
made that jib made
that jibs made
it I didn't even realize the
camera finger on the whole Mark if you
don't mind do on that one you can tilt
it if you want mine
1 2 3 there you
go holy [ __ ] mobile it's going it's
going it's going keep going I'm just
going to we
mobble that's
prober sublimating Little River Rock
bubble hash made by jibs Rico brought us
the sublimator we're here in Spain I
just ripped it that was [ __ ]
delicious super delicious give thanks
thank you thank you sir thank you thank
you Alex Alex all right Alex just
stopped me here in the spannabis and
he's he's local Barcelona and he's
showing us uh his dry some dry sift from
uh from Morocco Moro quality all right
let's check it out double
zero well it's the z00 that it's can you
focus it it should focus on its own hi I
got
it this one it's really nice it's really
well if you want to take it out yeah but
it's really you know there we go wow
beautiful it's beautiful and the smell
if you could smell it with
the excellent I'll take a little smell
yes ah yes yes it's hard to to to let me
let me so it's always nice in hash
culture when we can recognize someone
that you that you appreciate their work
in one capacity or the other know if you
appreciate the photos I really
appreciate the photos I'm glad you love
it all and uh here check this one out
this is what I got this is from Canada
this is the watermelon with my friend
Ron oh nice it
out check it
out I actually see saw you
OB yeah so this is part of the hash
culture in Spain he recognized me came
up said he liked the videos recognized
scal appreciated our videos and and then
showed us some nice uh uh Astro I sifted
from Morocco what did this make uh this
was with Astro Boy the watermelon feno
so TGA strain Astro Boy but it's a
bubble has this is bubble has 90 Micron
yeah 90 Micron great spice to it though
almost a reminiscent of an old school
hash with the new school full m want
SM yeah kind a watermelon you know yeah
we have lot of lot of you know really
it's like the best it's like the best T
I ever tried who's got the lid me or you
do I have the lid or you have the
lid so yeah it's just nice to get
together with people just you know even
if we can't maybe you know be puffing
it's at least nice to share the smell of
your hash with someone that you know
appreciate
really okay keep in touch sure take care
brother peace got to love Spain just uh
uh setting up with Scott and Tony here
for River Rock TV they're about to do a
little clip right out in front of the
entrance we're just sort of in the lobby
outdoor entrance area of spannabis and
it really is quite a large event i' I've
heard 50 60,000 people attend this event
and I've heard more than one person uh
who works in the industry lives in
Europe and goes to all the shows say
this is the Premier cannabis show
basically in Europe right now we'll uh
keep giving you little Clips here and
there
peace hey what up bubble man here with
with Remo the urban grower pretty hey
folk how you doing pretty stoked I had
no idea you were going to be here I just
came in at the last moment last moment
and you're going to make it back on time
for the uh court case in Canada yeah I'm
only here four ex a hit it quitt deal
nice and of course here is spanis 2014
in Barcelona or as most people here
pronounce it Barcelona you can Google
that and find out why um so you see uh
well there was a king many years ago who
apparently had a list and no one wanted
to make feel uncomfortable cuz you might
cut your head off and so everyone just
said Barcelona so you'll see many people
say Barcelona it's uh I'm not making fun
of it don't get my head off uh have you
seen any nice nuggets since you've been
here done yeah you seen some nice things
oh yeah excellent real amazing stuff
seen some crazy extract really
yeah I have I'm in the same boat I've
seen some beautiful herb DNA had some
really nice uh Kosher Kush Tangi cross
that looks just like Kosher Kush but
stunk like oranges and then they had
some uh gifted strains from the sou of
Spain right when we met up with them
they got the box right there we open it
this really beautiful red bubble friend
down just that bubble it just turned
intoed
disappeared yeah it was really nice so
what's your plan for the urban grower
here at the 4 days you going to cruise
around film your show yeah we're making
videos we're taking pictures we're
beating people
and I was going to say are you
introducing the gel so that's good you
want tell a little bit about your
gel just been in Canada is for roting
it's a
rooting
[Music]
gel people gel we have two kind of well
I'll tell you one thing I've never heard
or uh met a basically a rooting gel
company owner who grows as dang of a
herb as you so using your own project
product I think you're okay
yeah I tried experiment we
actually we worked at thicker thinner we
Chang different amounts we got
work awesome cool it was really good F
in India Remo and definitely uh we'll
film again for your show probably
tomorrow and uh we'll make a video we'll
make a video and we'll see you guys
later at spanis 2014 yeah man
[Music]
it it
well there's medical
seats he's huge we can go left or
right left yeah this is
fine EAS
yeah
yeah all right here's an interesting uh
little point of uh view we're at we're
with the CBD crew here and uh Matt the
great Gardener is just in the background
talking to a good friend of mine Robbie
who's been at many of the legends of
hash parties and we are about to be
shown the canonic dryp that the great
Gardener uh grew and I
clean man did that [ __ ] re up I mean
my God I like it with your smile in the
background too that's very nice wow we
like it as
well that is absolutely beautiful thank
you for
sharing awesome
[Music]