[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
just a real quick uh shout out to the
guys at method 7 Paul and Jeff and the
whole team I just received my new green
coupe PS pluses I got to tell you I'm
really impressed with the quality of
these glasses boys with the Carl ice
lens with the um it's actual glass not a
plastic uh it's absolutely unbelievable
what it turns the day to I haven't even
gotten it under my HPS yet but I wanted
to let you guys know that I really
appreciate the gift I'm sitting on my
sled right now 800 cc's of pure insanity
and power and I'll be making sure that I
got my method sevens when I'm up on that
mountain
so thanks a lot guys check out method
7.com for these glasses and many many
more for your growroom needs remember
guys don't grow
blind