[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am up here in Whistler British Columbia
staying at the Weston Hotel one of my
favorite digs to stay at while I'm up
here and uh we've got a little bit of a
fun day today my buddy Brad's birthday I
think he's 31 we're going to go up to
the Whistler black home park on black
home mountains sorry there's two parks
one on either mountain and uh just get
some footage you know get some pictures
of some dudes busting some serious [ __ ]
it's the XL Park so there's always
something fun going on there's usually a
variety of Pros in there and because the
snow's been uh you know non-existent
this year we have not much else to go
with other than the park so going to go
pick up my good good buddy Devon who of
course is the place where we host hash
Church from each Sunday we got to give
mad shout out to Devon for allowing me
to roll up at 8:30 every morning on
Sunday and just do a nice loud hash
Church got a big bag of hash here we're
going to go for a little
morning toot oh let's go for some uh
some d420
K always such a pleasure to smoke my
Good Buddy's dryy sift such kindness to
sh share I really uh I'm always shouting
those guys out obviously because
they're very worth shouting out okay
here we go little couple more pieces
stuff's just stuck all over to to the
top of this I love it got the Mother
Ship Fab egging
it and uh yeah let's get this wake and
bake going so we can go back down to the
valet get in the car and go pick up
Devon
all
right let's go grab Devon
for
[Music]
small
f
[Music]
that's hey Mark yeah I'm Ben you're Ben
how's it going D
in the middle of how about you guys yeah
not bad you know I had my car brought up
and then I ran away yeah yeah it's all
good gentlemen here have the keys I'm
filming you guys on Bubble man's world
oh bubble man filming us yeah I'm
promoting the Weston and how awesome it
is to stay here nice thank you guys I
hope we're the ones who make it a well
dude you guys I just told Ben literally
he like well it's not the nicest hotel
I'm like yeah but it's got the best
people working here you know what enjo
thanks guys they can't they haven't
picked it up yet I can't find it all
right sorry for the interruption guys
but we'll see you soon right
on
[Music]
back to let you don't shine shine till
the break of day
all right so this
is the house of hash Church hello hash
Church what's going
on ah you making some vaccins on your
snowboarding yeah I was just doing a
quick wax but I got my ready to go oh no
rush dude I'm just uh filming a bubble
man's
episode what up what up good morning
Bubble World so this is uh This is how
we do in Whistler right going to the
rocking in the house coat wax and Boards
rocking in the house Coat House coat wax
and Boards got my robone right home you
look like [ __ ] Dumbledore from
uh that's smart though dude doing it
into the box like that that [ __ ] gets
everywhere would be better if I had a
nice station set up here but no but you
have all this useless [ __ ] you have all
this useless [ __ ] that needs to be on
the Shelf exactly [ __ ] like six
batteries for
[ __ ] never
awesome well um no rush we're good to go
oh yeah dude I'll be done here and I'll
get my GE on all right sounds
good so this is the hash church house
this is where we I sit for hash church
right here first few I sat over
here but then they had this nasty bong
and I didn't want to sit too close to it
I was like yesh I have got to get out of
here so we set up over
here of course it's Whistler so every
house has a
view so I don't know if that's W no
there's wedge the top of wedge is over
there not quite
lake is right over here in behind the
trees basically it's um ridiculously
warm for Whistler right now it's never
this warm it's um not in February anyway
so uh most of the snow has melted off
the ground you don't see really any on
the trees uh even going up quite high up
the mountain the trees are still bare so
we're still going to have fun today
though I think uh I'm going to grab Deon
and we're going to head to the West End
Buffet they have this killer buffet at
the Ober Grill so why don't you guys
join us for that am I supposed to close
this door is that my position
yeah oh it's just the uh weather
stripping on there thick so you got to
pull the door ah yes sometimes it props
back
open one
sec I got it here got imagine
but AIC
Buton the
West are we
uh should we go right to
breakfast sure now all right I'm not
sure what we could do with our boards
I'm sure we just leave them somewhere
yeah that's what I'm
thinking
some that hurt but at least that stopped
it
from that that hurt that wasent I'm not
going to lie that was not
[Music]
pleasant most awkward board
carrying yeah let's do
that of
course dude come on that sounds like the
way we roll it's like the smartest idea
ever unless you want to go up and have a
puff
first yes I do believe I do good sushi
here
Kaz oh yeah still got
yep oh
man so Deon had the uh brilliant idea of
coming up in having a few dabs before we
uh head down to the buffet so dab it up
brother f fire in the hole fire in the
hole hash in the
[Music]
bowl love that mother
ship the denail rips just keep giving
they're like oh you thought you were
done you're not there's
more very good professional as you can
see Devon has his hotel uh puffing down
pat simply put exhale out the window now
of course if we do have an inhale out
the inside we've got the fire alarm
cover that every Hotel comes with in the
bathroom they call it a what do they
call it they call it a shower cap but
it's really um a cover for the to the
creat bu mine that's it that's a smoke
protector protector I'm going to dab one
up dab it up I'm going to dab one up
brother as
well some delicious
too too many different kinds of
delicious hash to even
mention
powered through that
[ __ ] super stoked for Buffet super
stoked for black home park today it's
going to be good and bad's birthday to
top it off and be's birthday to top it
off
sweet all right there's record button
all right dev's going in for a
second
can you see the Mother Ship man staring
you
down
bombastic ready for a
buffet two fingers in the air I'm ready
to M down bro yeah let's go hit
it yes two towers at the West End East
and
West to the north and
South what's
that oo I'm looking forward to this
food wow I was going to say isn't it the
what wasn't it the oine grill is it been
that long since I've been to to the
Western wow I can't keep
up the grill and
Vine please wait to be seated all right
so
this want to
uh look at the blue light got to work
the white
balance there we go we're waiting to be
seated
wow they changed it in here quite a bit
how's it going has it really been so
long that I've been here that you are no
longer the oine grill but you're now the
yeah wow okay cool excellent well we're
excited fast is goes fast it looks good
all right well welcome back yeah is it
the breakfast buffet yes it is would you
like that or do you prepare a the car no
well we'll do the buffet okay that's
great
in
yeah this is
great oh yeah this looks
delicious oh my God great job
guys
salmon
eggs
[Music]
he how you feeling about this stoked a
bit wed me too dude all right fruit
plate
with granola and
berries beautiful
omelette yep I'm going to enjoy this
here we go
butit all right so that was a delicious
breakfast yes that it was that it was
bro brunch felt like I had a couple
breakfasts there uh we're gearing up to
go have a quick hot tub and maybe a
steam sauna here at the Weston but
before I've been meaning to do a couple
reviews on these units uh originally
jonthan from Wizard puff sent me the V5
o vaporizer from uh flower mate I guess
or it's called The Flower mate yeah it's
from flower mate vaporizer
technology and uh he sent me this um a
while ago now probably close to a month
ago told him I was going to do a review
never got around to it volcano since
sent me their Mighty another vaporizer
and the reason I feel okay about doing
this together is because Jonathan sells
both of them at wizard puff.com so we're
going to do a little review on these and
actually how we're going to review them
is we're going to take them up the
mountain today into the black home park
make sure we have them there with us so
we have uh an ability to
medicate so which one should we try
first straight to the flower mate the
flower mate open her
up open her up got my medtainer with a
little bit of herb that uh that I grew
back about a year
ago prepare
that sneeze
excuse me spicy weed so that's pretty
sweet did you just uh screw it on yeah
exactly it just screws on PO the bottom
this little guy has a ceramic I had a
really good little little book in here
that we
could so give you a little idea on this
V vaporizer it's portable design fits in
the pocket real easy Advanced
temperature control system ensures per
perfect function and perfect or purest
vaporization we're going to see um innov
a vapeway with three-way temperature
setting this I liked so it's got a nice
design to hold in your hand easy it does
feel pretty solid doesn't it m um now
level one which if you push this button
five times one two three four five yeah
blue light turned on and then inside
there it should yeah this little blue
light on the outside says that we're at
level one which is 385 de fhe so we'll
leave it at that we'll let it heat up
we'll pack it in a second um we can also
move it up to 400° F by um clicking it
some more times I I'm not sure how many
that that's on the next page to level
two and then finally a red color which
is
415° pretty cool option for a portable
vaporizer to be able to do that I like
that built-in lithium ion battery you
can tell the whole thing is basically a
battery no plugs uh to take with you
huge heating chamber huge ceramic
chamber helps you get best experience
okay it's got a Bora silicate glass
mouthpiece little slider on top cooling
holes there with the green button or the
green lights
super simple I guess uh here why don't
we Medan her a little
herb I think it's as simple as just
unscrewing the
top and then loading the
chamber
okay always interesting vaporizers are
always interesting in the sense that um
if you get them wrong
if you if you don't know how to do it
pack it incorrectly if you pack it
incorrectly or you do just the smallest
thing wrong you don't get the rip so
give it a rip let me and I'll find out
what you need to do to uh move that into
different
levels that looks like it's coming out
real
nice milked up the little mouthpiece
pretty nice
showing them that's of
quality showing them up
close well this would be fun to have the
mighty and the uh the flower mate with
us the
V5 how's that tasting on the lips you
getting some nice pulls on that yeah
nice excellent I'm going to pack a
little bit more
for the next unit we'll try in a bit
here
oh yeah little rip let me give it a
shot nice that was two in a row you blew
that yeah three even yeah no it's not
bad
that's
doable now they also sent me a unit
along with this when you come back Dev
it's right beside the computer there
that little metal piece
yep
I thought he said it was an herb
chamber let's
see so yeah he said this was another
unit I guess that you could attach on
here
somehow not sure exactly oh I guess this
just comes out
maybe oh
yeah
that comes off much the way that comes
off
interesting I'll have to figure out how
to use this additional
piece uh seems pretty simple I guess you
just go like that put that in there I'll
figure out what this additional piece is
uh later on for you guys and make a
point on showing that to
you um yeah not a bad little unit you
know pretty small chamber in the sense
but if this is an additional chamber
like an XL chamber for larger amounts of
herb which I think it must be well then
that's pretty cool going to try and hold
the button down for 3 seconds moved into
the next color it's kind of a purple and
so that tells me now that I'm going to
move up uh above 375 deg or 380°
whatever it was uh and get myself into
yeah 385 so now we're going to go up to
400 so 15° temperature
raise not
bad not bad at all for the flower mate I
can push it one two three four five more
times and it shuts off it is quite nice
and small um this would have been a
bummer had it not been unscrewable cuz
you just snap that thing off in a hurry
and then you can uh you can close the
unit which is also pretty
cool you can close that unit right up
boom and then on the bottom the
mouthpiece just goes right back in and
closes not a bad little unit probably
good for warming the hand too feel it I
have hey out on the mountain yeah
that'll heat you up all right so that's
pretty cool flower mate we're going to
have that with us today and uh we'll let
you guys know how how many hits we get
out of that and how well the battery
operates and etc
etc all right and we'll figure out this
giant herb chamber as well I think it's
an an added herb chamber I'm pretty sure
so now from stor and Bickle from the
good people uh who brought you the
volcano geez that must be going back to
1999 or
2000 so this is called the mighty it's
uh I guess their Premier um portable
unit I never expect anything but sort of
exceptional quality from volcano uh say
what you want about the unit but it is
quality built it's got an incredible
warranty and they last a long time I
know people that have had them for well
over 10 years uh so this is a nice
little uh design here the
mighty it's got a nice little design got
a digital screen I'll peel that plastic
off uh comes with as volcano used to
sell back back in the
day this little guy here which is a
screen
pad and I guess you can put that in
there and that way you can use
concentrates here's the unit itself when
you push the power button on it vibrates
much like a cell phone and then you've
got your bottom temperature which is the
temperature that it's going to go to and
then you have your top temperature which
is the temperature that it is at right
now and this unit's pretty simple uh
it's got a cool little mouthpiece right
on the top here uh you can twist the
entire thing to open it up to reveal the
chamber and now if you were going to use
uh concentrates you'd put this little
fat screen right inside there and then
drop your um concentrate full melt dry
sift whatever on top uh the unit
obviously has a screen on the top here
as well and that just screws right back
into place super easy peasy also very
handheld and portable and we're going to
Devon and I are going to load it up
right now and let you know how it
tastes have to say the taste on the um
flower mate was pretty darn good yeah
man that one's brilant ceramic through
glass I mean uh that thing's awesome not
too shabby at all the size of not
everyone's like daily iPhone yeah well I
guess some of those new ones are massive
like yours but yeah that's like your
average one it's
true oh that smells
nice no that it does all right so here
we go into our chamber I like that they
made this very wide big open chamber so
that as you fill the herb uh you can uh
you know try not to miss and get herb
everywhere even though I still generally
do give it a little blast
out a little blast out all right so
we've got
195° celius which is geez it must be
about
42 or 400 something degrees I guess I'll
give this shot at first they did give us
also a grinder two little Grinders not
really my style they're kind of plastic
Grinders I guess probably people would
be pretty stoked still I guess oh yeah
you know knowing them it's I don't even
know what that is actually I don't think
that's grinder dude high performance
vaporizer that's like a component or
something to
it oh that is
tricky a component that one looks like a
grinder oh yeah filling the ground
herbs this is just tripping yeah the
other one's a grinder I'll have to
figure out exactly what this one is see
this is what this is remember when it
was saying filling and filled with
ground herbs that's what this
is ah so it's the it's the helper that's
what he was using to fill the units
somehow come on how does that go on
there wow okay this is a cool thing that
I'm just sort of discovering now it
looks as though
they have a way to fit this on top of
here and so your ground herbs just
naturally go right into the chamber
without you having to do what I just did
like an idiot that's awesome so yeah
we'll check that out in a bit I'm going
to hit this for now cuz it's heating up
something different for
sure
that was a nice tasting
rip
interesting M very flavorful it had the
unit had just turned off but I still got
my my
hit I guess it's got battery saver I
believe you got two large lithium ion
batteries uh in either side and then
just the middle is the actual Vapor
vaporizer unit then you have the screen
it's pretty cool little
unit
the screen uh the opening the the the
the straw is quite big it's not like
restricted at all you really get a full
flow of
vapor yeah that's
incredible wow that last rip I took I
was hauling on it kind of breaking my
intuitive knowledge of vaporizers and
that if you suck too hard you create
cold air that cools the unit and gives
you less of a hit that just did the
opposite I was pulling on it quite hard
for my whole hit I wasn't doing the slow
and steady I was just doing the vacuum
and that was a really exceptional Vapor
rip um obviously these units are in
different price ranges uh I'm not sure
exactly the price range um unfortunately
I didn't do that research I think this
one for some reason might be around the
$300 area and this one might be around
the to $150 maybe 200 not sure they're
both quality units in that sense but so
far for rip for rip this thing has given
me the most insane
rip the mighy speaks for
itself yeah that's quite something well
we'll bring both of these up on the
mountain uh actually we'll bring them
out to the hot tub right now and let you
know how they do around a hot tub and if
one gets wet see if it gets destroyed or
see if they're you know we'll just test
them out we straight to the test
straight to the test so see if they're
waterproof see if they're waterproof
exactly there's all sorts of things I
don't even know about this unit look at
this thing I just found the little
cleaner right up the bottom all right
there you go for cleaning out
the wow
I can't believe this thing Mighty is a
good one the mighty is
[Laughter]
mighty
awesome can't go wrong with the
mighty should we hit that hot tub yeah
I'm down stay
tuned
[Music]
hot
Ching got a fever of
103 hot
[Music]
Tu super
cooked we could have come up here and
have
Buffet what's
that
yep it's the
CCPA annual
meeting hope we're not
late here's the mighty look how just
fits into the surrounding atmosphere not
standing out at all but just really a
real nice little
unit flower M's no SLO
either exceptional little unit nice and
small in the hand not
worried all right put that key in
the yep
open sesame yes open
[Music]
sesame's the old
western o
pool
nice and empty in
here which is ideal which is ideal when
you're walking into a bathroom with your
camera
on hey what the [ __ ] what the [ __ ] what
the hell are those two doing turn that
thing off man all right so we're going
to have our first uh bubble session uh
I'm was just joking so all right steam
room is equipped with the steam Ste
let's push that button and get that
steamer on let's turn the light on I
guess they're working on one of the
showers pretty sweet rooftop showers too
though all right they got these new
lockers that you just push the the code
in and you can get a free
Locker eucalyptus steam then we'll come
out take you out to the hot tub and have
a session all right all right that was
an exceptional steam eucalyptus let's uh
let's head out to the pool of hot tub
area the Western uh let me change the
light for you guys here that's no
good there we go so they also have a
really nice sauna room not huge just a
tiny little guy but it's quite nice get
your dry heat
on got a nice indoor hot tub next to a
nice seating
area and and then they have um an
outdoor pool an indoor pool that goes to
the outdoor pool and then a nice little
hot tub over there so what I was
thinking is that I would hang my
actually I'll put it over by the hot
tub
[Music]
on
all
right this pool is about as warm as a
hot tub right
now I don't think it'll go so deep that
I can't walk all the way
over
yeah with your lifestyle right here guys
dabbing it up actually we're going to
end up using those vaporizers that we
have over here sitting by the hot
tub oh yeah that's
warm that is
warm access right
away
all right
so let's see we got the the mighty
vaporizer turned on here 45° C we're
just in time for a mighty session bro
Mighty I got the mighty all packed up
and ready to go and uh yeah beautiful
day I like how this thing gives you a
nice big full battery read six battery
bars on that not sure if you guys can
see that but there's six of them and
we're at 100° C already and I can start
to smell the herb in the unit I think
it's a good idea to go s bubbles while
we film our sesh hey you should show
everyone your crazy [ __ ] Whistler
collar
bone oh yeah I'm right on camera oh yeah
look at that [ __ ] thing that that is
some [ __ ] up there it is there it
is yeah if you come shred hard enough
you too can have a collar bone like that
you got to earn
it 160° CI that something you really
want to earn no it's not it's not
something you want to
earn dude how sweet is this so nice that
they closed the whole place for us to
film bubble man's world oh yeah shout
out to the Weston for uh shutting down
the pool area and the hot tub area so
that uh we could film our little episode
and tell you how awesome they are here
at the Weston from all the people the
staff that work here through the kitchen
um and the hotel the valet they're all
really super good people a lot of them
Shred the mountain and uh I see them
outside of work so yeah shout out to all
you guys we have reached temperature did
you hear it vibrate yeah launched up
ready to go
mhm
this thing gives incredible rip
that
Sprout looking
good off in the
dis jeez I guess you could easily have a
rubber sort of piece on the outside of
this thing like a membrane and you could
easily hold it with a wet hand I'm sure
you could potentially even hold it with
a wet hand although there is an opening
right here to the uh power unit so keep
it out of water folks they don't claim
waterproof oh that's just darn good
tasty too that's the Astro Boy it was
really tasty yeah even old herb that's
over a year old and it still just has
that Wicked taste doesn't it nice little
high from it too I was just gazing
hookers I know you keep looking behind
me like there's someone there oh no
there was a dude standing there but it
was all good I wasn't just going to blow
it
out I would
have one of the beautiful things about
having a federal license here in Canada
is as long as you're not uh obviously
breaking anyone's personal rules
business rules or um offending people uh
with children and such that it seems to
be a pretty safe bet that um doing a
small amount of vaporizing in an area
that's not affecting anyone and not CH
and not affecting even the place I think
it's a good thing to allow people to do
such things rather than make them feel
like they have to go hide to Simply
medicate particularly for some people
that you know it really just requires a
quick one or two rip before they can
sort of self-regulate themselves back
from either an anxiety attack or a
potential seizure uh you know Tremors
from with people from with uh
Ms man that cool wind is nice isn't it
yeah all right shutting shutting down
the mighty going to go put that one away
talking to my
wife well we do have the flower
mate I guess we might as well just get
her done
son nice steam right into a hot tub I
like this I have to
admit that little sort of uh little
cubby hole to keep it put away in and uh
yeah I'm impressed with that oh we got
this
resin all right so that closes back up
this simply opens
up all the herbs still in there
nicely I'm still always want
to give it a little blowby blow so we'll
go 1 two 3 four five we get our blue
temperature it takes a few seconds to
heat up now this one's a little more
simple in the sense that it doesn't show
us any temperatures um we know that
there are three temperatures uh the blue
the the pink and then the finally the
are purple and and then finally red are
the three options I thought the second
one was supposed to be orange but I
could be mistaken now that I'm all uh
Vaped up at the hot tub here in the
Weston and that cool wind is feeling
proper
mhm nice day yep AB going be fun on the
mountain it is going to be fun on the
mountain isn't
it oh that's ready to go oh I bet
doesn't take much for it
that taste is
exceptional you really can taste a a
difference in the ceramic to The Boro
silicate as opposed to the um I guess I
guess it must be ceramic into more of a
plastic composite that uh uh the
vaporizer guys are using they also have
a bigger straw and a feel like I get a
bigger Rip but I'll tell you herb vaping
the same herb There is almost a sweeter
taste in the first you you took the the
first few rips the last time so I didn't
get that sweet taste but this time I I
got it all right let's hold this for 3
seconds I'll turn that to the next
color yep there we go wow It beeped like
a cell phone as well I guess they're all
doing it so yeah you can see the little
but the little uh flashers got a little
sort of pink side to it as well and we
could even go
three more seconds and then she goes red
and now red is a
450° um temperature that it's going to
go up to we'll see if we can taste the
difference in that
rip just beeped again I'm guessing that
means it got up to temperature so this
unit is quite fast in regards to how
fast it gets up to
temperature um nice and portable I'm not
sure that it would survive a drop in the
hot tub nor would the other unit so if
you're going to be jumping in the hot
tub this uh winter uh and using these
units please be careful and don't expect
them to cover any warranty damage if you
get water into them that's why we don't
have the bubbles on here so so far so
good pretty impressed with both the
flower mate and the mighty love the
taste on both of them love the
portability and uh yeah it'll be
interesting to see how long the
batteries last once we have the session
that we had the session that we're
having we're probably going to have
another one in the gondola and then
eventually we'll get up to the bike or
the bike park the the the the park and
we'll see if the batteries are still
going and allowing us to take rips up
there laring and charging larg and and
charging see you guys on the
mountain all right so we're finally
heading
out for the
day
clothing
this is pretty much just beautiful
weather
hey looking forward to some Park
lops really look what new job we get on
the car look it's actually way different
well they sure did that looks completely
different at least on the outside I
wonder if they did any interior
[Music]
work you heading up black
home
yeah no I don't think
so think I got
[Music]
everything
think I found the right
[Music]
spot
theall how's it going you
well I wouldn't say no to
help
cheers W this old rickety old Tin Can
hey yeah holy smokes compared to the new
Whistler ones change your face I like
the old RI G yeah me too is very
different oh yeah there we go put my
tripod through the
window
well it's
official it's hot as [ __ ] so that's the
Whistler Gondola over there big glass
roof what the mountain come coming
down we are heading up black home so the
blackholm gondola does not make it all
the way to the top it's going to take us
to
Excalibur yeah
Excalibur which will be nice cuz we'll
be out of this hot box Excalibur
accelerator I think it is I think the
G's called Excalibur right top is
accelerator speaking of hot box we could
pull the mother ship out and do a
dab or just use the vape pens or just
use the vape pens God we got
opportunities here vaporiz it's the
Gula oh
yes so there goes Whistler
Village bye-bye Whistler
Village Cougar Mountain
there's a mountain biker that's
insane it's still February I know 24th
for that matter dude whatever I'm going
up right now without gloves in a hoodie
yeah I
know want to thank my boys at triome
heavy extracts for the hoodie today that
will be uh keeping me warm up on the top
of black home Mountain while we're uh
enjoying a little Park
session
all right so we're coming into mid
station
here and I guess we're getting off huh
no we're staying on oh yeah we're
staying
on wow it's been a
[Music]
while all right we go up to
Xcalibur oh no is this what is this
called This is Excalibur that's what I'm
saying so what do it go up to
accelerator hey
guys
on Bubble man's
world well for this time of year to be
this high up the mountain there's the
ski pool jumps for the summer that's the
wizard chair over there all the streets
like uh spearhead drive and painted
Cliffs there's some nice condos that you
can rent over there if you want an on
Mountain experience this doesn't look
very good though look at this dude how
barely it is oh I know
man wow looks like it's the end of the
season does look like the end of the
season at the end of February sure hope
it's not uh it is one of the cooler
things to look at all of this and just
think this is what we ride down we ride
down here we go through these trees we
go everywhere there's Boulders and big
gnarly
features Fallen trees and such and the
snow just covers them all up I mean I
can't imagine coming down these Cliffs
on our boards without that snow tell you
that
much I'm finally getting into the into
the snow line up here this seems like
naturally a snow line that they didn't
have to push
down pretty
unbelievable God would this mountain be
fun on a dirt bike imagine in the summer
if they just did it for one week they
invited everyone with dirt bikes and
they set up monster courses and they
just did a huge dirt bike event that
would be awesome wouldn't
it I would so support that event in any
way shape or form that I could possibly
do oh there we go let's give them the
view so there we go what is that Ulta
[Music]
Lake yeah that's
Ulta there's the Whistler Village say
good bye-bye as we head up up up and
away
[Music]
be Nick's up there the crew yeah
exactly exact
the all right
well huge lines up at
accelerator massive [ __ ] dude going to
be there for hours
bro
thanks
dude holy Christ is it
warm I should thank Nico right now Nico
shout out to Nico here on the uh top of
black well not quite the top of black
hole mount maybe about a third of the
way up or halfway up but ni had this
board made and given to me at the
Solomon Factory in France one of the
last boards to be pressed there and uh
if you check it out he actually got my
name on there etched in that's on the
inside so can't remember what it was
called a gstick or something but
absolutely beautiful board
uh I remember km charged me an arm and a
leg to bring it home as extra baggage
but man what a nice gift Nico so thanks
a lot bro I hope you enjoy this video uh
we're thinking about you here in British
[Music]
Columbia all right M
Devo
ah just in time to answer
it there's Whistler looking Majestic
over on the other
side damn
Majestic all right well let's head
over wow nice tune job on the board
thank you
brother
very
[Music]
nice I feel like I barely fit through
that
thing how's it going dude pretty good
excellent it's a rough life you're
having right
now
here why don't you hold
this and I'll uh I'll get a vaporizer
ready for us I mean why not
right the gondola just felt a little
forced so we'll go this style reach down
see what we find
first see there's a big
speaker there's a [ __ ] ton of d except
wow I really have this bag packed pretty
good A little
deeper little deeper you find the mighty
hey Mighty how you doing buddy all right
let's turn the mighty on right off the
bat see what we got in the medtainer
shout out to Johnny Be fellow with his
medtainers not very often that I use
them I'm not really able to shout them
out cuz I really don't use herb that
much as most of you would
know
nice and clean in the
chamber pretty easy going in the sense
of how to how uh cleaning it and then
reloading it even the wind is a little
bit windy up here it's not
completely windless up here and it's
still pretty easy to load up not feeling
overwhelmed the one finger
clean sure the outside is all nice and
clean before you screw the top up
on this way so we don't lose
it
and we' got
133° so far if you can see that not sure
but uh yep we're
good about another minute of enjoying
this View and then we're going to have a
nice little session with the uh mighty
here on the Gonda so or this chairlift
sorry uh I'd have to say how easy it was
to find in my bag unload and reload turn
it on get it up to temperature and then
here soon to take a rip I'm pretty
impressed with that it also feels like a
durable unit like if I dropped it maybe
on a day like today where it's hard pack
it would probably break but on a regular
day where the snow it is just reg you
know normal nice and soft snow it
doesn't feel like dropping this would be
saying goodbye to it it feels like you
could come back down and get it and you
know it could potentially still be on so
but let's have a
rip
a solid size rip I'm impressed because
um it's a cold wind out here the chamber
really has to be sealed well and
containing its own own heat well cuz
it's a nice cold wind in my face right
now
oh
yeah brother man
yep pretty good easy use for a chairlift
unit great taste on it
too can start to feel the temperature
different uh difference up here now I
wouldn't by any means say that it's cold
but you can definitely feel the coolness
in the air from all the snow that's
present now bad in the fact that the
chair lift seems to be rocking at a good
clip not bad on the mighty hey no not
bad at all
dude not bad at all near the end of it
though what's that near the end of that
hit give it a shot you might be
surprised well how do we turn it up in
the temperature like you said just oh
yeah just with the this this one's
really easy yeah just like the up button
click yeah get it up to 200 if you
like chairlift rips
sweet hey maybe we could uh get them to
stop the chairlift so we could just
enjoy ourselves for a few minutes
without the
wind hey would you look at that we
stopped
good fun up here on Whistler Mountain
just beautiful can't wait to get you
guys into the park and show you what
some of these uh what some of these guys
are capable of doing off of uh off of
some of the features in
there you've been having quite a bit of
fun in there the last couple of weeks
yeah it's been good nothing well since
the sun came out but it's still been
bulletproof but it's still nice so it's
good I guess from 12 or 1 till 3: it's
uh it softens up a little bit in the sun
yeah there soft spots and there's still
their icy patches in the shade it's
still solid here still cold up here at
night and nice you just got this to spe
to a temperature I Heard It Go like a
text coming in it's h we're already
designed
to um react to to that very sound of
that particular vibration of what many
iPhones sound like when they uh are
vibrating what a freaking beautiful day
now we're getting near the top here a
little bit closer
and where do we head from here down to
let's go down to Jersey down to Jersey
and then up to the top of cat Skinner is
that what it's called Uh Jersey and then
we'll be a top cat skner and solar yeah
yep all right just in this top shelf you
yeah just fold the little piece in and
get it in there and then I turn it off
if you can just get this manage to close
it all around that would be awesome
I like just giving a real honest review
having it with us pulling it out
throughout the day using it and letting
people know uh you know what they uh
we'll get a few other people that have
never tried it before to hit it as well
and see what they
think that'll be of course Mountain
device before the Mother Ship gets
pulled out because you know I got my
mother ship in
here hell yeah I brought the mother ship
on the mountain are you kidding me
people are like why do you bring your
Mothership with you I'm like so I have
it with me doesn't that make good
sense I had my bag grab the other day on
the peak chair I had my helmet and my
goggles hanging off of it my goggles
kind of went down and snagged so I was I
was pulling for a bit but I managed to
get them off off before uh before it
fell
up
ho I just got so much [ __ ] it's
[Music]
awesome probably not
creepy
all right
G
heading up a little
[Music]
higher
actually pretty
good tell there's a run that's just
fantastic the bowling alley
[Music]
here
yeah
wh there was like an
ankle bit hectic getting on but I think
it managed he uh all right so this will
be that that one cold
chair where you kind of feel it the rest
will be in the sunshine yep and Sun's on
you sure is sunshine sunshine Bry yeah
so we're getting into a little bit more
of the
gnarly part of black home getting up up
up up on the left there's a black home
Glacier up in behind there can't see it
but it's
there up on y
super stoked all right so the last
little section here we're heading over
there on the other side of that Ridge is
where the uh black home park is and then
over here is where the black home
Glacier is it's pretty gnarly cornice up
there the whole Mountain Top is a
cornice God it's not many people on the
mountain hey no it's
incredible it's surreal
actually wouldn't want to be dropping
those Cliffs
today even on the power days I don't
care to really drop
those I've done those on a pal day it's
kind of fun oh I've done them
but they're just not your
style they're
steeper
[Music]
you
see how
that see
[Music]
more
oh I guess I should tag
in well I'm doing everything but T like
tying
my never mind I'm I'll be
fine all right man there go well I got
this lens but I'll take it did you want
to just take this bag yeah well when we
get there yeah I'll take it right now
dude okay [ __ ] dude come
on got that miss the towel right okay
well I'll try to just you know at least
have the towels in there so it's keep it
safe that's all it's in there just
your no
[Music]
problem
always
surprised gentlemen's how you do man
very good yeah very very
good you guys R guy ufp in the train
garden I didn't even recognize you did
you knock out your teeth or you got a
mouth guard in no I wear a mouth guard
so I don't knock out my teeth good good
job good job I appreciate that all right
well this should be
fun yes here yeah I have talk to you
talk I talk to
him um not really interested coming
[Music]
up
what are you going to hit the jump on
the right yeah the jump on the I'll
probably go sit on the knuckle
there you want probably be the better
spot
[Music]
I
don't worry about me I'm not going to
hit you
[Music]
yeah what's
next
yeah I was going to check out
the all
right do it the one the left over here
yeah right side okay I'll Follow You
Down
[Music]
start doing in charge
a day in the park the black hole
[Music]
Park yeah
buddy
[Music]
cins right see
there want go
back
guy he Edgar Casey
[Music]
nice run dude yeah not a bad first La
yeah with a huge board bro that's what's
getting me what is that like a 168 or
something well this is the 52 the 5'2
that they have really two priz they have
wow why does it look so huge just the
shape the nose is just big on it but
yeah yeah
okay well I'm sure like in the Sol and
yeah sure fun but then again I'm not uh
I'm just trying to keep it together with
all this equipment in my uh hands two
backpacks and two
[Music]
cameras
yeah nice
[Music]
bro yeah ni fun
day jumps are fast right now I bet she's
solid Landing but fast it's good for
them get back there Jesus that was
pretty serious rotations he was doing
yeah ran away nice to see just a a full
lineup of people hitting it eh non-stop
now we got the
[Music]
skier all right good old Whistler lot of
talented Riders endless amounts dude
it's kind of
ridiculous slays in all the Arts
here we
go this is the one where we're going to
get the baller
[Music]
[Applause]
angle it's going
backwards
he was who the cameraman was waiting for
you can tell it he jumping
yeah pretty big jump right there you say
20 ft yeah Budd he was double 20 ft
that's bigger than 20 the table the
table Toops like yeah 40 pushing Jesus
it's not super steep Landing
too people are just standing there
waiting for someone to hit it
Budd Bud double back flipping in the
last few days there's been tons of
people on it it's probably this group
well I'd love to get some footage of
that for sure it is it's like my f and
them they all got their Red Bull helmets
and all that ja on oh yeah rep
representing oh yeah they do so they're
hardcore it's a good day for it
fastest awesome par
there
[Music]
he's not hitting it is he no
way what's
that oh is that what
happened that's why everything's held
up brutal this is the dangers of the the
bike or the Whistler uh Snowboard Park
here guys it's
uh
he's damn I hope he's doing okay I hope
he gets better hate to see that young
kids all crumpled out on
the on the bottom of a big jump like
that it's definitely no games up here
you know you come into this section of
the park and you better know what you're
doing and even though that do know what
they're doing sometimes you can uh you
can get rocked up he's
up head good to see good to see he was
knocked out for a while there I
[Music]
think outdoor sports are very dangerous
that doesn't stop us from doing
them HCK it in the
park he yeah just going sand in the park
on some days like this that are solid
man how did this dude get crushed
here I don't know what
happened it's
brutal I mean Dam it's a flat area solid
day there it is a solid day I'm maybe he
came up the lift and he had to go take
I'm going to try and put that backpack
on the back of my backpack we're going
to hook it up a different
way
[Music]
okay I'm
thinking you want to do another full run
or do you want to go sit on that knuckle
and get some
shots
I wouldn't mind getting a little bit of
footy yeah he got knocked out when I
going up he was back out
that you down
F uh I want to film that clear Rail and
then the quad
[Music]
down
all right hopefully I got that on video
in
[Music]
camer
you lead the way cuz you you can get us
to a good spot I'm sure well we can I
just stand right in front of that snow
gun there we can just sit there all
right let's do
it
even over by the snow
gun right this is probably as good a
spot as I need out mother and get some
shs oh those are heavy bags not going to
lie
I'll say the one thing that's a bummer
is I did
forget
my water oh really
yeah maybe someone will pull up with
water well if we need to we could do a
lap and then go into the Rond and get
water in
there
hey yeah I guess we could hey we'll just
finish the we'll do a cozie run and then
come back do another
run never like to see it but at least
he's on his way to get
[Music]
help
it's like motorcycle gangs or something
he the shredders yeah the different
groups they just come in hot it's like
oh those guys aren't [ __ ] around man
it's the Whistler Park crew no
joke I've always had fun coming in here
and getting pictures there's some
exceptional riders that come in here and
if you set up your shot properly and you
get the right mountains in the
background oo Man red Riders you get
some pretty amazing stuff
this is a spot right here that right
here is where I'd like to sit right near
that chair and snap some some good shots
my
200 all right
so we have
stopped due to our forgetfulness of not
bringing
water some whis
Jacks it's that right there oh
yeah all
right yeah you sit in
[Music]
town
what are they serious
this
how's it going Tim dude good to see you
playing picture wow yeah we're doing
video pictures we going to grab some
food but I guess they're closed pretty
much yeah that hurts uhhuh oh well got a
little cheese and
crackers I wouldn't say no to a little
cheese and crackers I'm sitting over by
the window all right well we're coming
to join
you with our
Waters hang out with
Timbo
surprised you're not
outside I said I'm surprised you're not
outside was I
just talk about crazy
timing how have you been oh real good
how about you I see in the postings
there you're doing a lot of stuff a lot
of traveling yeah I go to Jamaica a lot
lately oh cool cool got to go there
actually next week how's that for a nice
little dessert in between that's just
like epic right there I'll take
it I'm a good bumping India
[Music]
Tim
back
they seem get buggered
off see any what's that said I do not
see any
inight oh well we can uh go down and do
the Dil session quick yeah maybe quickly
go down to that big Kong even and get a
a video or a few pictures before the DL
session big Kong what well not the big
Kong but the second the big jump oh
jump
so
they usually over in those trees over
there guess or those trees over
there it's funny cuz we rolled up here
they were here I saw them flying oh
yeah I guess they're going to catch the
last little opening bit of the mountain
I'm cool let's go check it let's uh go
hit the Park yeah I'm thinking of what
did you want yeah you want
[Music]
sweet should we get the mother going I
think we should get the mother
going so we got the dry
sift get the wet
wash get the
water got the
Dabber I got more [ __ ] up here then I
know what to do I think I might be the
only person ever to have brought a
mother ship exactly up on a stei up oh
my
excellente Beam Me Down scottt
yeah exactly man I'm as high as I can
get at 6,000
ft or whatever we're at 50 probably
50 okay so we got the water we're not
rookies we were rookies we're not going
to lie we didn't have the water
initially we went up to the rendevu
where we bumped into Tim thanks for the
cheese and crackers M got love whisper
Whistler hospitality
all right almost
done so obviously we can't have the
denail up here without bringing very
heavy batteries and my 40 plus pound
backpack is is already heav enough heavy
enough so going to hold that for a
minute y gear up some hits the hard part
about this always is warming the hash up
to the point where it softens up so you
can kind of uh get a little dab
maybe here check this
so show you what we're
here look at that oh it's flake yeah and
that's dry sift too it's not bubble
hash how is it process uh just
mechanical mechanical separations via
screens you know just bouncing uh
bouncing resin over screens and then of
course uh you know some more techniques
in regards to further refining and
cleaning or decontaminating the resin
right pretty stoked about this
dude got to say I like that did there
too that was good that was the proper
way to
transfer we got
helicopters we got mother ships we got
one person after another behind us
hitting these different
features not bad
I always find the torch is a little bit
difficult to deal with outside cuz you
can't really see what it's doing but
I'll operate it by the
sound once we get that quartz heated up
nice and
hot get a great
rip or a dab as the kids are calling it
these days Tim oh yeah a dab A little
dab will do you yeah this is what they
say This brilliant team commercial
totally I remember
oh that's hilarious that's like some 50s
and 60s [ __ ] right there even before
that I was going to say maybe even 40s
eh yeah Brillo or BRX or
Brillo um brilliantine brillian
te all right I'm going give us a
shot for a
da doing a fine job fine
job
Wally G that's tasty
stuff I'm
fine hold that
dab we'll get you a piece a little
flake
such a sweet place to to spend your days
yeah I mean my goodness it's so epic
like truly people throw that word around
like it's nothing like my new stereo
system is Epic no it's not you stereo
system is not epic like it was amazing
no no no was not amazing it's cool it
can be cool but epic it could be L let's
leave epic for such things as mountains
as far as the eyes can see yeah a slice
of Humble Pie is so big yeah it'll kill
you in an instant if you floor the whole
day
yeah
awesome there we
go that will torch you
up
even if you want to after this dab going
rip down and get it well if if we got
enough time I'll stop him do that
quarter pipe again next time oh yeah get
that shot get right on top of
it
know you're taking as much as fast as
you can cuz I think quick quick I'm not
even sure how H we got it but oh yeah
he's getting hit God you got to love the
quartz my torch just
died that was
scary torch died uh
uhoh not a big torch trouble in hille
tonight I got the electric down at the
the
car the electric
nail wor too much definitely
not well I got the
[Music]
well do you still have that charger
cable I haven't used that uh little mini
hit I have to bring it it's a USB one
right it's the one that screws up you
have a Trippy Stick yeah yes I know
exactly
[Music]
right boys it's holid day for the jums
we good
[Music]
I was sporting my
Hitman hat to today under the old
goggles but I wasn't jumping Devin was
woo
Airborne good to have the bucket when
you're
airborne
freestyle terrain look at that Free Ride
session smart and enjoy well I think I
think we session pretty smart up here
wouldn't you say of course we had the
mothership and as you can see feeding
your endoc canabo system shouldn't just
be looked at as the negative stereotype
of like oh they're getting stoned it's
called feeding your endocannabinoid
system tuning in you know it's helpful
with meditation it's helpful obviously
with a guy like Devon who who wouldn't
uh put himself in any unnecessary Danger
he still feels that he's safe to have a
rip or two and go and do some of these
jumps feel that it helps you a little
bit it well a collar bone like mine it
definitely helps yeah just to some
tension and pain for my injuries sure
play a big impact a little bit more CDD
give a little bit more on the uh
flexibility too I'm sure
mhm it does helps with a lot of
injuries
here oh yeah well we're looking at the
North Face of it we are we're not going
to be going down that face the South
face will be lit up actually that's
right I think so too man I think we'll
be
fine I'm easy I like the idea of taking
them across the peak to Peak and showing
them a little bit of the uh
that
yeah I got it it's a
[Music]
beast
how's it going man talk about how you
doing today pretty good that's
good pretty darn good stoked we caught
this oh yeah this has to be one of the
last cabins ehy yeah I got five more
minutes too 415 we good good to know all
right
yeah very good peek to
peek the big peak to
peek we just missed the sightseeing one
with the glass bottom but I'm over
it okay I think we've been in it enough
times all not what the Height's all
about snake to me oh looks like we're
going to have our own cabin how fun is
that maybe I'm a little to right on
thanks
dude
[Music]
all right how's this for fun
all right I think this is pretty going
to be pretty freaking awesome do
yeah possibly just a two
of and our
dabs oh all right guys woo tight you
feel the power of that first little
dip
so I say we pull out the
vaporizers we unfortunately didn't get
to rip with Tim felt kind of
bad
wow really feel the motion of that I've
never felt that so strong
before awesome Peak to Peak Gondola dude
longest one in the world 50 million
bucks
unbelievable so
[Music]
awesome open some windows in here it's
so
hot
super
under
want to fill yours
sure it's that one
yeah sort it out it's pretty
sweet turn that bad boy
on oh it's so warm in
here I got to open the back that's the
problem you got to open these back
windows got a little a little bit of
a so I just drop it into this one H
what's that
yeah drop it
in I'm going to close this guy up
now we
go so beautiful out
there you could have a nap up
here oh
yeah hold the
C I'm at 165 I'm going to start giving
her oh
yeah
so you got about 11 minutes on this
Gondola from one side to the other
taking us from the top of blackholm over
to the not quite top of Whistler but uh
damn near
close top of the gondola Roundhouse
and we're getting right above the uh the
river down below which is where uh Shane
makoni when this first opened uh I
believe he did like a backflip race jump
him and Eric Rona yeah Eric roner was
here too for that yeah they both jumped
off it they B jumped off it very cool
Maniacs rip Shan Cony Legends yep never
a day goes by on this mountain and many
other mountains where people aren't
thinking of those
guys P
way the might is just delivering great
rips got to
say although I think that one might have
it on Flavor that was a real almost a
connoisseur model isn't
it
that's tasting this for well we're
definitely hitting tasty by it too
what's the turn up on how you turn this
you hold up for 3 seconds oh you hold
and then it'll turn it'll glow yeah
there you go and then you'll see two
colors glowing in it purple on one side
and a blue on the other and then you
hold it for three more seconds to get it
up 415 which it will go all
red my unit just got up to temperature
I felt it
vibrate and that sun is be
right can't even really enjoy the view
that way almost have to look
back I look over there I mean that's
really the most epic right
there very nice flavorful all the way
through well it's been a good bubble
Man's World episode today riding and
Whistler hanging out with Devin showing
you guys a little bit of a Local's life
it's pretty good living up here even
when the snow was sparse which I can't
believe it right now I just kind of came
to grips with the
view like I just kind of realized oh my
God there's no snow at all
except over there there's plenty you can
show them those
mountains
spearhead what's
that spearhead jverse it's all the
spearhead and that's overlords at
12:00 beautiful mountain that's right
I'm
sure
want to go into the back country can
head all over
there this the back of the singing pass
and I guess back here you have OBO
and cowboy
Ridge that's on wer side it's over to
the right right yeah that's all on wer
side yeah and so but this all just must
tie into it like Decker and all that to
the left coming from black
home
okay we
go people have been doing that for a
while haven't they going into that back
country
Zone how's the Vapes man all good I
might hit mine
still
CH well that's a really nice feature
right there where it's kind of Vape on
demand for a while I mean mine did just
turn off
now still giving pretty nice
[Music]
rips
all
right
beautiful come down on the mountain no
doubt about
it up in triome heavy extracts up on
Whistler that's hot which one I had this
I had touched the uh the base look at
the the base of glass well that's all
part of the learning oh yeah but I like
the fact that it's got a case in it so
you can unscrew it from the top and
still put it away inside and even if
it's hot I'm sure that it doesn't really
out yeah it's awesome CA much
problem all right put it away top
still just unscrew it from the
top
shut that open that that in sh that it's
not a bad little I
got that's interesting how now it
doesn't seem to yeah I was
tripping all
right so carry the triod in the that
[Music]
camera that was
great what's
that everyone's up here who's that like
Patty and all that oh you want to go say
hi might as well stop by and say hi
sure what's
[Music]
that time make it up
yeah we're just going to we're just
going to grab them you know they Ser
anymore
thanks they'll spend the next 20 minutes
trying to kick Patty
out
[Music]
I'm
[Applause]
[Music]
buddy what's up boys good filming it
how's it going everybody yeah nice
getting some cool shots right now hell
yeah bubble man's world so these are
Whistler locals they hang out and they
drink beer and sometimes smoke
marijuana often using terms like shred
and Nar sometimes in the same sentence
like shred
[Music]
thear what's up doing good man oh dude
we missed that we didn't get it on
camera chair yeah he fell off the
chair do you require first aid lot more
than first aid yeah you psychological uh
do you give
mental okay on a scale of 1 to 10 how
drunk is Bri uh Ryan right now I'm going
say2 ooh a solid
7.2 it's a big
one
sound hey are we too early for groomers
are we going to get some
groomers oh pulling the birthday card
over there hey isn't it your birthday
Patty next yeah next Monday oh [ __ ] it
really is yeah it really
is a lot of daily though
daily this is the time of day when the
drunkers songs hey I know who ain't got
the
money you get three grand we for
whoa hey hey now ho
there a week come on 12 Grand a week a
mon I don't know what he gets that'd be
unbelievable oh yeah that'd be some EI
I'd be signing up for yeah maybe him and
Deon
combin 12 G this is slow rail today yeah
you're really not making it fast are
you
it's open up here end of the day
[Music]
open you want me take anything you
so you can take it no don't worry about
it bro one's just going down one just
came up I guess we could go hit some
groomers if you guys want to get some
Freshies you know I think we'll be able
to do the 7 yeah I think we'll be able
to fly in the sixth stay the sixth and
the seventh and then we'd have to leave
the eth because we well we fly out we
fly out listen it would be pretty cool
dude I've never been to a to see you in
the grill at a at the cup that I'm
speaking at and
judging will you be judging on that day
or the last day I don't know but we'll
hang out well [ __ ] sure we will
regardless I will get eyed to the
pie [ __ ] eyed yep I agree with
that let go damn it's a Danka I
[Music]
know
ah fresh
groomers this is
nice
oh
[Music]
yeah
we're all
together H what we just got cameras
hanging off the
back no bucket no dude I was bombing
there yeah [ __ ] it no bucket [ __ ] it
Buck
[Music]
it
yeah try holding a bunch of cameras
everyone going straight down I'm you
guys yeah dusties I'll meet you I'm
going to go to red chair I'm going to go
down red chair and go to the the Weston
real quick see that old dusty dirt
though yes we will
[Music]
gentleman's