[Music]
hey how's it going everyone welcome to
Bubble man's world I am back in my
office in beautiful British Columbia uh
freshly back from the Cannabis Cup in
Amsterdam the 6 annual had an amazing
time this year I got to say I you hear a
lot of people say bad things about the
Cup every year and I have to say I just
have mostly everything is good that I
have to say I met some great people I
saw some nice products um these
generally the whole
cup is like two parts for me I get this
visiting friends that I haven't seen in
a long time and then I also each year
feel like I make not a huge amount put a
couple of really key friends key people
in the industry that I meet and this
year I would have to say that those
people were from the river uh River Rock
Wellness Center in
Colorado Tony and Scott's crew down
there Dane and um their amazing grower
who I didn't get to meet but I did get
to sample his wees and of course jibs
who is their hash maker who makes some
just wonderful water extraction all
around it was a really great experience
and I I really enjoyed hanging out with
those guys um it was it was great to see
the DNA boys great to see um just
everyone horta lab um medtainer John was
right across the way from me that was
always uh nice generally I have to say
the cup was a good experience for me and
I just wanted to share some of my
positive outcomes from it a few stories
with you guys um I I really should start
right off the bat with before I went to
The Cup this year I ended up hooking up
with um Brian and Stevie from denail and
these guys are great guys they've got a
really great product um I know they're
not the originator but what they have
done is they've taken a product they've
maken it that much better um they're
extremely knowledgeable when it comes to
the engineering of their product and
even the thermodynamics of titanium
versus uh quartz uh and of course what
I'm talking about is the
denail I've got one right here uh on my
desk beautiful uh zebra wood model uh
it's plugged into a titanium nail right
now uh in the mothership and it's up to
about 800 810 de and I've got a
beautiful variety of hashes out here
thanks to the guys at oil slick uh
thanks to Lars who really kicked me down
these products via the guys from oil
slicks and you know it might be funny to
think that a bubble guy might be using a
product like this but I got to say for
for my for my full melt bubble shatter
uh stuff like this that is absolutely
just you can't touch it you can't deal
with it this stuff is a real solution I
have to say um I'll be taking a couple
of dabs of this on the denail while we
talk and whatnot as well as some of the
other varieties um this is um I guess
it's about 5 years old right now this is
Master Kush I've had it for at least 5
years it's it's like a red oil it's it's
shatter um at the warmest touch though
it it's hard and then the minute you
touch it warm it does that you see what
I'm saying the warmth of your fingers is
enough to get this stuff to make a real
mess so what I'll do is I'll use the
skillet tool to get it off and then
we'll just leave that like that for when
we take it down that's how sticky that
stuff is right there I'll be able to use
a a lighter to get the skillet tool off
later but with a finger it just becomes
a real mess but I can smell that
wonderful Mash cush smell coming through
loud and clear so we've got these on the
oil pads uh we want to thank the people
at Skillet tool for hooking us up with
the tools to to get our hash off our oil
slicks and then of course I also want to
help thank those guys for these little
cool balls and the little containers
that they kicked me down uh the oil
slick guys kicked me down at the
Cannabis Cup um right now I've got some
OG bubble cush full melt in this one
here and I've been cruising around town
with it it's been quite convenient more
so than I thought and then the little
guy here I've got some full melt dry
sift that I just made from some of John
B's medic cush a bag of shm that he left
here a while ago I ran it through my
tumble now and I cleaned it up on a
secondary screen with my carding
technique and I made some real nice full
melt dry sift so I think I've mentioned
most of the companies I wanted to
mention I guess I'll give a little shout
out to uh K9 tubes with their little
mini uh rig uh pendant rigs not really a
pendant but it's definitely like a
necklace rig it's got the little hole
for wearing around your neck and it's
got the little educated nail in there
with the uh yeah nice little Dome that's
a cool little product right there but
when you want to get a nice little rip
and you don't have uh uh room for a big
rig also want to give a shout out to
Trippy sticks amelo you're a pleasure to
hang out with at the Cannabis cupo
always a pleasure loving the glass Vapor
Chambers uh the titanium element with
the Deep ceramic dish a little bit more
battery power than the rest of the units
it's why I stand behind trippy sticks
it's why I sell these things because
they work for me on the regular basis
um couple of piles of hash out here we
got Bubba and OG um one's 120 one's 90
Micron we've got about a quar pound of
beautiful John B nuggets here can't
remember the strain might be medy Kush
I'll open that up a little later but why
don't we start with hitting the denail
through the mother ship using the
skillet tool so let's see if I can just
oh yeah oh yeah so we'll just take a
little dab off off that it's transparent
I can see the gold coloring in it um I
do have a quartz bowl with this as well
um however I ended up leaving my 14 mm
quartz Bowl in Europe cuz I couldn't get
it clean more on that
later um but I have an 18 quartz Bowl
here but only a sheld in black and right
now I want to hit out of the Mother Ship
so let's dab the master Cush
probably could have used a carb cap
there I do find that when I use the
skillet tool and I cover the little hole
I can do a little carbing that way but
it's really mostly carbing the amount of
air that I suck in and not really
keeping the uh smoke from Raising off
the dish
really nice flavor on that you probably
noticed I didn't even cough it's h and I
have a sore throat and a little bit of
the Cannabis Cup
cough the 5-year cure there's something
to be said for it um it did stay out of
the fridge for about 3 years in a wood
box in a cold dark place and now I have
it in the fridge not the freezer and I
allow it to breathe about once every
month but this stuff's going on 6 years
old it's five plus years old
and just an
absolute I can't even describe the
subtleties of the flavor that just came
into my throat just
now um yeah just really nice it's
satiating my whole throat it's up on my
lips it's in my
throat and it's it's why you sometimes
want to cure your hash I don't have you
don't have to become religious and cure
all your hash all the time but it's sure
nice to take half the hash that you make
and you know use it the way you love it
and then try a little of experimenting
so many people are experimenting with
changing the texture with leaving
moisture behind with all these other
things try curing your hash for 6 months
to a year to 2 years to 5 years I'm
telling you there's something to be said
for it particularly water hash it
removes this scratchy harsh feeling um
we were talking to a diti today uh from
New Deli in in the chat room and I urge
some of you to come check out my
tinychat.com back SL bubbleman fresh
headies we have different people at
different times today it was at DTF from
India talking about um Milana cream uh
the Kulu valy the Himel pesh area of
these valleys um Parvati Valley and
where uh some of the best hash is
produced in India in these in these
areas and they have been for 800 plus
years and he was just giving some great
Knowledge from a from a first person
who's been there done that kind of thing
lives in the culture knows the people
talking about the differences between I
mean smoking out on the street to get
high as opposed to the
spiritual uh prayer of a Chillum with
the sadu sh you know praying to Shiva
and it was all just really great
information so if you get a chance come
check out that chat room I know I'm
taking left rights and and full 180
turns here but uh I'm just excited to
talk to you guys from my office and of
course that Master Kush didn't hurt
things uh either so why don't we get
back to hitting some full melt dry sift
just made this today been curing in the
uh in the bag for some time left it open
for o probably almost a full month got
it really dry you just you want dry
material when you're doing dry sifting
especially if you're not using this dry
ice method but you're using old archaic
screening methods it's great to have dry
material so we'll scoop out a nice
little rip of the full Mel dry sip the
Holy Grail of hash right here as you can
see I have piles of full melt bubble
piles of even the shatter bubble here
that I have out on the oil slicks but
you'll never really see huge piles of
this hopefully in the future right now
not so here we
[Music]
go I'll do a macro video of you guys so
you can see this particular dry sift
melting I'd say it's a good 90 to 95%
pure heads it melts fairly nicely but
the quality of the resin wasn't the
highest that it could be so it's got a
little bit of a slower volcanic eruption
to its melt and I'll also show The
Master Kush 5year cured shatter
bubble as well as a bowl of the OG and
the Bubba because it's just so enjoyable
to
smoke ah so let's tell a funny story
from from the Cannabis Cup this
year trying to come up with one I guess
I was the first Booth searched uh by the
police this year at the Canvas Cup they
came right to my booth they told me
there were rumors that we had more than
we were
allowed which I think is laughable
because we definitely didn't we were
comfortable in talking with the Dutch
police they were polite they weren't
rude uh they just wanted us to follow
the simple rules as the police often do
I saw a lot of people bashing on it and
and it isn't something really you want
at the C cup but at the same time when
the Vibes aren't completely terrible
it's a bit of a unique position for us
maybe an American who's you know never
been harassed by the police in a way
that you're not really
harassed you they're just literally do
you have five grams or more no just have
five Gams okay have a nice day I know
some people are complaining about it and
it's a bummer for seed companies that
want to display their cannabis's but you
know I think over the years many many
people sold a lot of cannabis at the
Cannabis Cup and that in part was
probably why now there's stricter rules
and they're watching things like that it
does ruin it for the seed companies that
just wanted to show strains of what they
have in a nice big Cola bud but it is
what it is and as things are opening up
in some places they may close up in
others we still have Amsterdam we still
have this ability to go there and it's
it's pretty unique I know that it's not
comparable to what's happening in
Washington and Colorado and California
right now but it's still a good time and
I hope that can preserve it and allow it
to continue to happen I've been to the
Cannabis Cup since 1995 that was my
first cup at the P's party house and I
just feel that it's a unique event it's
a 5-day event not a two-day event it's
something that uh many people want to
complain about but yet if you make the
best time about it there's you can
really go hit an incredible group of
people and talk to them and ask them
questions in regards to you know things
that they may not have the time to
answer you on social media sites they do
have the time to answer you in person at
the Cannabis
Cup so let's see um I was honored to
speak at a panel this year at the
Cannabis Cup with um Mike Carrol uh from
California um Scott from rare dankness
from
Colorado and uh the DNA boys from
california- Amsterdam uh Danny Dano
hosted us and that was a really nice uh
time I've usually only spoke by myself
on a few occasions I'm not sure how many
panels I've ever spoken on but it was
nice to speak with those guys it was
nice to hear what they had to say all
knowledgeable in their fields and uh it
was nice to be able to fit in with a
group of of Growers and breeders as as
whatever my part was talking about the
resin and talking about I guess the end
result of which um we would be seeking
the desired traits for breeding in the
first place the resin production
cannaboid profile and that sort of
thing so that was really nice and then I
also got to speak uh on my own for just
about an hour I did my own talk on water
extraction and dry sifting and uh the
endoc canabo system and the best way on
feeding the endoc canabo system and
little bits of quotes from Dr William
Courtney and Dr David Allen to the
doctors that have turned me on to a lot
of the information that I know about
those such things so that was really
nice as well um I didn't have any drama
like Ben drunker was able to create uh
Power to Ben he spoke uh I guess on the
last day at the Cannabis Cup and he had
his sensey seed girls uh three or four
girls go throughout the audience and
give away free cannabis and so I'm I
guess there was an undercover police uh
in the audience and so he tried to stop
it from happening and I believe if I'm
not correct me if I'm wrong Ben removed
him by the collar of his jacket from the
room in which case a lot of police tried
to to get in and some people in the room
sort of kept that from happening for a
while but uh a little bit of drama when
you're trying to give away good cannabis
uh it was always something you were able
to do with the Cannabis Cup so that's
that's a little bit disappointing
but what can you say you know it's still
a good event you know you get to see
this unique group of people there's
always fun concerts um this year uh it
was nice to meet James from loud seeds
it was nice to meet bezel from beesel
extracts always good to see Nic from the
essential soldiers crew the essential
extract
soldiers um headyy heads his brother
James and the Gold Coast extract guys um
really cool to meet those guys I maybe
repeating myself I'm not sure the last
dab of dry sift was very wonderful
probably follow it up with an OG Kush
hit of the 120 right now and uh yeah who
else to thank you know so many cool
people that we met it was great I hope
that you guys all come by the fresh
headies booth next year Legends of hash
dinner don't want to talk about it too
much because it's really a private sort
of closed door thing but you guys know
the gig the way to get a ticket to the
legend is to bring your nicest piece and
show it to me at the Cannabis Cup at my
booth we love dry sift we love wet wash
um we don't accept oil entries uh
unfortunately as of now we're
celebrating Legends of hash uh we did
celebrate um Legend this year his name
was L shabaz
kalandar uh he's been sung in many songs
as the Breath of Life uh you can read
about him I've also posted about him and
the famous uh mum that he's buried at in
and where they keep these Hubble bubble
pipes burning these twoot tall Hubble
bubble Afghan pipes Burning uh day and
night while people dance in ecstasy uh
at his gravite so check out L shabaz
kalandar on my Facebook page Bubble Man
fresh
headies and you can read a little bit
about him and maybe we'll see you next
year for a piece at the booth we' love
to see some really exceptionally
well-made dry sift we love to see some
exceptionally well-made water hash we're
looking for water hash that hasn't
buttered out you need to dry that [ __ ]
proper and if you think you can do it on
parchment paper great if not I urge you
to use a food grade cardboard or even
the other day I was talking to Matt rise
I know a lot of you guys bash on Matt
and I know he said some things in the
community that he shouldn't have uh he
does definitely ow owe out some
apologies but I like to keep everyone
together rather than separate and I I
you know he I was asking him the other
day what he uses as opposed to cardboard
and he for the first time said something
that to me not he for the first time but
someone for the first time replied with
something that made us equal of a sense
which was uh thick paper towel I believe
under screen that he's drawing U the
bubble out on St stretched a big nice
stretched screen so if he's doing that
that's great that's still a desicant
that will still Wick the moisture out of
the hash so of course if you're doing
something like that to me that's the
equivalent of cardboard it's the
equivalent of getting something done
which parchment paper absolutely does
not maybe in a low humidity area but for
sure not anywhere else so I wanted to
say that and uh yeah I guess I'll have
another dab I've rolled myself some of
this uh oh [ __ ] was that the Bubba
thought it was the OG but I guess we're
going Bubba here we
go really great taste on the denail
bringing me back full circle to the
dmail cuz I brought them up earlier
wanting to shout them out Stevie and
Brian you've done an exceptional job on
this product um I really messed up I
took the first one to Amsterdam I
plugged it in with a converter not an
inverter and we cranked it up all hot
and we put it in front of a window with
cold air rushing in so
we we really put that unit to the test
and of course we pooched it I'm going to
be sending it back to him and he's going
to open open it up and check out you
know what was done but you have to
understand like no product could expect
to survive that so when we got the
second one from them this one with the
zebra wood I was a little worried I
wasn't sure how it was going to stand up
being set up to a step down converter
and running for 10 plus hours a day at
the Cannabis Cup in a room that's not
heated the room was cold well I'm happy
to
say this is the unit I brought to the
Cannabis Cup both whips from the other
unit the one that was plugged in and the
one that wasn't plugged in the one that
I pooched both work so that was really
cool and this unit worked flawlessly for
10 hours plus a day at the Cannabis Cup
for 5 days straight um that's pretty
incredible okay to keep a consistent
temperature for from within uh you know
the one degree or the two to 3° it would
move I always knew when they had the
door open cuz it would move almost 3°
which which was a vast you know it was
vast compared to what we were used to
inside at our hotel room which was
1° so I can't say enough about the unit
um I love the lightweight cable cord
that they use um it's it doesn't
constantly knock over my bubble uh you
know pull things off the table uh not
pull over the bong cuz it's so heavy so
that's a a real topnotch product I love
the quartz Bowl The Taste was really
nice for me but I also like the titanium
Bowl we were hitting around 750 to 810
you know I don't have enough uh
experience with it to say I know which
one I like the best I do like that Smoky
Rip but I do like that tasty rip and I
like to meet somewhere in the middle and
I it seems to be around 800° 780° for me
uh for the bubble in the water uh water
hash that I'm
smoking so I guess I won't keep you guys
any longer I've talked a little bit
about the Cannabis Cup I've talked about
some of the products that I was having
happy to receive and happy to use happy
to put through the
test um took a couple of dabs with you
guys maybe I'll finish it off with a
nice full melt dry sift rip out of the D
nail can't say enough about these
Mothership pipes either I know a lot of
people are can't wrap their heads around
how expensive they are and it seems
absurd for a clear glass pipe to pay
,000 or
$2,000 but we had the Fab egg there and
we had the straight Fab there and they
were pretty much two of the most unique
pipes in Amsterdam the way they hit the
consistent uh saving of flavor through
the filtration I'm not sure I understand
it but I really got to give Mothership
uh two thumbs up and so yeah if you're
in Vancouver if you're even online I
believe it's high priority or high
integrity high integrity they're both
two companies high integrity is owned by
a friend of mine here in Vancouver high
integrity glass and he specializes in
Mothership and you should go check him
out and check out his motherships this
one came from him and many of the pipes
you see flab 421 on Instagram has also
came from him and his company and you
should go support them because they
really have a line on some killer glass
uh please check out uh us at fresh.com
and bubble bag.com come check out the
chat room at tinychat.com back/
bubbleman freshes I'm in there usually
once or twice a day if you have any
questions if you want to talk chat puff
come on down and I'm ready to do it and
uh otherwise I guess we will see you all
next time um where we're going to be
hooking up with flab 421 and hitting his
new Joel Peters I don't even know the
name of this pipe it's some crazy you
know honey dripping it has a cool name
it is a cool pipe he's super excited
which means it's over the top so we'll
be bringing you that video soon and in
the meantime I'm going to leave you with
a nice rip of a full melt dry
sift peace out
for