[Music]
Hey guys, Bubbleman here. Just just
hopping in the boat for the first time
of the season and heading out onto the
Pacific Ocean here. We call this little
section the house sound and it is my
home. Beautiful. Got my little dog with
me. Oris, how's it going, buddy? You
good? You good? Yeah. Yeah, you're good.
You love on the boat.
Okay. So, I was hoping on getting a few
friends out on the boat today, but uh
for now, I think we're just going to
head out to the back side of Gambia or
sorry, uh Ber, which is that island
right in front of me there, that little
guy that's the closest. And uh well, I
think we'll uh we'll go have a little
dab session over there.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Now you're living in this
life. So this boat goes about 45 miles
an hour.
Not the fastest boat on the sound, but
uh not definitely fast enough when you
want to go shred the the ocean. I go a
little
faster. They won't see the next ride.
They won't. They won't. They
won't. So many I recycle
garbage. They won't see the next life.
They won't. They won't. They
[Music]
won't. Don't react before you know. Now
you may act on an impulse. That's wrong.
That's wrong. That's
wrong. Now your next door
neighbor has a wrong impression on
you. That's wrong. That's wrong. That's
wrong. filling up folly against
someone who is
innocent. That's wrong. That's wrong.
That's
wrong. Living in our
limitations with false
impressions. That's wrong. That's wrong.
That's
wrong.
Wouldn't you be
sorry? You acted on a false
impression. So be
sure before you react. Be
sure before you react. Wouldn't you be
sorry? Reacted on a false
impression. So be
sure before you react.
[Music]
All
right. Well, that was a nice little rip
across the How sound. Just a few
minutes. And uh I'm at my office. So,
this is my office. This is where I I
usually come and spend a lot of the
summers. Um if I got to work, if I got
to do editing, I come out here, sit out
on the boat, and uh just sit right in
the back of this island. It's always
calm here. Even on the windiest of days,
it's uh 90% of the time it's going to be
calm unless the water's coming up from a
particular angle from up north from
Squamish. Um just checking it out to see
if there's any seals on the rocks
because
um well, the moms, they they come here
and they lay their their babies out on
the rocks just to hang tough and then
they go feed for them, go hunt for food.
So, it's uh it's nature. You're going to
see uh potentially out here we'll see
bald eagles, gold eagles, um sea lions,
seals, uh killer whales, humpback
whales, blue whales, and Pacific
white-sided dolphins. Those are all all
little bits of nature that you can see
out in here. And it's uh it's pretty
damn sweet when you see it, I got to
say. The seals, they blend right in with
the rocks, though. So, they're literally
the hardest thing to see on the coast
here.
I'm sure there's got to be some here,
though. They're always here. Pretty
early, but
uh we'll tag along the side of the
island here for a little bit and see if
we can't catch a little wildlife to uh
to have a session with. My dog will keep
an eye out on
things. What do you say,
horse? Out on the out on the water.
co-pilot. Dog is my
co-pilot. Look at how beautiful the
mountains are that I that I that you
don't see very often because they are
where I live. It's not in my view, but
uh yeah, those are the mountains that I
live
on. Pretty
sweet. Really surprised we haven't seen
any seals out here yet. Usually would
have seen like 20 or 30. It must be too
early. Or they're all out somewhere else
hanging out. Man, what a beautiful day
it is today. Let's hope D420K and Johnny
B can get out later today to come for a
little spin. Come for a little puff
down. Um jeez, I guess you could call
this uh ocean dabs. The ocean dab
session. Hooking up my buddies out
here. Show them the
beautiful, beautiful, beautiful
place. It's
uh yeah, you can live out here for a
long time, you know, and not be and if
you don't have a boat, it's really quite
a different experience from having a
boat. Probably going to truck around
this whole island once I've had a few
few puffs. I was kind of hoping on
showing you guys some seals, but we
might have to wait uh might have to wait
for that cuz it seems like it's a little
bit early. It's about 8:00 in the
morning right now. So, I uh I really
jumped the gun today and and got out
nice and
early. So
sweet. You guys a little view what I'm
checking
out. See the water's down. Not not as
low low low low as it goes, but it's
definitely a a little bit low from the
tide marks that you can see across
across the mountain
careful around this side because you
have uh you have more
rocks. There's a
seal poking his head out over there on
the
water. Probably some out of the water,
but I don't know. There's another one
over there.
This could be the
moms
hunting while the babies relax on the
rocks, but I haven't seen any
babies. Usually don't go too close into
this little area cuz uh you can smoke
rocks. Although right now we are 53 ft
57 ft. So not too bad.
tell you those rock towers can come up
pretty damn fast though when you're
cruising along in a
[Music]
boat. All
right, this looks as good as any spot.
What do you guys say?
All
right, let's get this
untied. And
this
actually Yeah.
Oops. Look at this. The
biminy boat essential for the house
sound. getting a hot summer this year
and uh it is really really essential to
have this thing down when you're a pasty
white guy like
me. Must hide from
sun. Must hide from
[Music]
sun. All right, guys. Well, we made it.
We made it to my office. We're sitting
on the back side. I guess we're sitting
on
the east uh side, the east coast
of Ber Boyer Island. If you want to
Google that, it's in the House Sound.
And uh it's a habitable island. There's
a few people that live on it, but not a
ton. I got seals, three or four of them,
floating right in front of the boat now.
Maybe they'll uh they'll come up to the
side and to the back and we'll see them.
So, today I'm just going to have a quick
little session out here with you guys.
don't have a ton to talk about, but I
really figured more than anything this
would be an eye candy video. The boats
on a slow 360° turn. So, we're going to
get the mountains uh in behind. Then
we'll eventually be posting up towards
the north where you can see um the
Diamond Head and the Gabaldi Mountains
as well as um Anvil Island, one of the
islands here in the House Sound. So,
I've got my mother ship Taurus filled up
with ocean water, rocking the DC glass
banger. Thank you very much for that DC
glass. And uh I brought out a little bit
of
rosin. We got that right there, too. I
know you can't really see it, especially
cuz it's not in the sun, but just trust
that it's amazing and beautiful. You
know, it
is. Oh. So, yeah. I'm going to invite
Johnny B and D420K out on the boat later
on. Hopefully, they come out for a
little session. Be kind of fun to have
them out on the boat. Um, you know, for
me, having a boat is really mostly about
just uh a a good 50% of it is doing this
right here, getting to where you're
going,
stopping, having an awesome session.
That
is boat fun like to the tea for me. Um,
the other part of this boat that I
really love, which we're going to do
this summer, is wake skating, wake
surfing, and wake boarding. Uh, in that
order, wake skating is by far my
favorite. Wake surfing is my second
favorite because you don't need the rope
and it's kind of cool to get in behind
and jam behind the boat. And then wake
boarding is kind of on my third of the
list. It's uh I got hurt a couple years
ago trying to jump a wave and tweaked my
neck and have to admit I've been a
little bit afraid of the wake board ever
since the wake skate and the wake surf.
I'm able to easily jump off and it it is
removed from my feet. But I'll tell you,
when you whip when you when you bail at
20 m plus an hour uh on that wake board
and it grabs the wrong way, and I'll
tell you, that is some serious ankle
pain that you do not want. I'm sure that
many of you out there can
attest. So, I guess it's time to
uh light this puppy
up. Loving the DC bangers. Real thick
glass. Um, kind of a little bit of a
nerve-wracker in the sense that you
really do need a decent torch. You need
to uh have a decent flame to get this
thing hot. Just burning off a little bit
of my last hit that I took here before I
went on cam. You know, you got to take
that hit just to make sure it's going to
work out. The prehit hit, I like to call
it. Sometimes I take a pre prehit hit.
I'm sure most of you know there out
there what I'm talking about.
Love the portability of the Mothership
Taurus as well. You know, I don't feel
it with my straight fab. Obviously, the
thing is huge and I definitely don't
feel it with my egg either, but the
Taurus just really feels like a piece
that you can bring with you anywhere.
And uh well, I damn near have, haven't
I? All
right. Dabs on the
ocean. H surprisingly not as warm as you
might think. Never got to
orange. Very nice. Very tasty.
Loving the mother ship, loving the
rosin, and loving the house sound today
on the
[Laughter]
boat. Getting a little bit close. I'll
back her up a little
bit. Another thing that you boat people
will recognize, the
endless the endless backing up. You
don't want to be too close to that uh to
that coastline.
Luckily for me, this boat has a great
reverse. Always remember when you're
backing up in a boat, too, to look. I'll
tell you, if there was anything floating
or, you know, god forbid, like a rope or
something from someone's buoy, you're
pretty much uh going to say goodbye to
your
prop, goodbye to boating for that
day. I've learned all the lessons the
hard way, that is for sure.
Oops. Bang. Boom.
Bam. Oh, yeah. This is
the incredible amazing
spot. Might head up to Horseshoe Bay or
Bowen Island later. You start getting uh
you stop at this spot and then you head
to the next spot and you you can travel
a fair distance throughout the house
sound. I mean, it's pretty big. I'm
hoping on getting Rob Clark uh up here
this summer. He was thinking of heading
up to California and if he did, he was
going to try and make it uh make it up
north to see us for a little bit. And
Rob is an avid fisherman. I would love
to do a salmon fishing with Rob Clark
video here in the house sound. And the
pinks are running this year, so it's
totally realistic that we could uh that
we could get such a thing
done. What's up, Orus? What's up, little
bud? My dog gets slightly nervous on the
boat. Not too nervous, but just nervous
enough to give a little a little kind of
Was that a tick? What do you got on you?
Oh, no. You w you went through Oh, I see
what you got on you. Jeez, you got a
gazillion of these on you. These are
probably what's pulling your
hair. Dogs. Hey, aren't they funny?
Funny little creatures. Love
them. Well, I don't really have too too
much left to say. Um, I've already
mentioned a few times Periscope, new
app, doing some live video footage.
Quality is not that great, but it's kind
of cool how fast you can just go live.
So, I am going to be using that a little
bit. And for those of you that enjoy
Bubbleman's World and might feel that
you're missing out, you can just check
me out. Join uh add me on Twitter, BC
Bubbleman. The app works through
Twitter, so you can't really avoid that.
And, uh, the app is called Periscope.
And uh I may just go live right now on
Periscope at BC Bubbleman. Thanks for
watching, guys. And
uh this video is not over. We've got a
little bit more boating to do. So you
guys are coming with me. I hope you
don't mind. All right. So just as I
started to pull away, I saw a gold
eagle.
[Music]
Don't react before you know now. You may
act on an impulse. That's wrong. That's
wrong. That's wrong.
Now your next door
neighbor has a wrong impression of
you. That's wrong. That's wrong. That's
wrong. Feeling up against
someone who is in the That's wrong.
That's wrong.
Sorry for the short shitty footage
there, guys. But
uh yeah, that bird was flying at about
35 m an
hour. Beautiful. They seem to hang out
off the coast of this
island almost all the time. Where the
most place the place I've seen golden
eagles the most uh is right here on uh
off the coast of
Buer. All right.
[Music]
Living off
limitations with false
impressions. That's wrong. That's wrong.
That's
wrong. Wouldn't you be
sorry? You're acting on a false
impression. So be
sure before you react. Be
sure before you react, wouldn't you be
sorry? We're acting on a force
impression. So be
sure before you be
sure.
Well, that was a little bit of uh the
house sound for you. Wish I could have
showed you a little bit more wildlife.
I'll be trucking around out here for the
rest of the summer, though, so I'll try
and catch some whales and some uh
dolphins at least to share with you
guys. Always nice to share dabs with the
dolphins and the whales. And uh I guess
I'll call it a call it a day on this
particular video. I may still get
together with uh D420K and Johnny B or
one or the other, if not both, I hope.
And uh that'll probably be another video
to ensue as well. So stay tuned and keep
watching Bubble Man's World. Thanks for
your support.
Peace.
Impressions costing judgment on your
brother. True. I finally
meditation. Yes, you heing to
[Music]
temptation. How many times you've been
on the other side? Someone's making
judgment of you. That's wrong.