[Music]
everything behind us that's
moving hey guys welcome to Bubble man's
world it is Sunday afternoon and I'm out
on the boat with my my good friend
Lincoln AKA marlar Mar marlar and I go
way back we've known each other for God
it's got to be 17 years H 15 to 17 years
for certain definitely uh both involved
in the Cannabis uh community and
Industry back in the day and in fact one
of the original churches right here when
we used to do Church before it was
called hash church and we used to go
across the street to my friend amir's
Place Sunday at Ryme restaurant on
Sunday that 12 man table that we used to
sit around beautiful 12an table we made
hash in his bathroom yes many different
wearers all the different Growers that
came it was it was pretty cool and it
was really the the it was how hash
church was started because it was that
concept years later up you know just
this last year is when I started it 53
weeks ago and it was the the church that
we used to go to that was the B involved
the evolving of it it's absolutely so we
are out on the beautiful house sound we
got boat is cruising by us in the
background we got a a variety of
mansions here just on the side we had to
kind of pull in a little bit close to
the houses because uh the water's a
little bit rougher out in the middle and
I wanted to be able to do a video where
I could have my mother ship sitting out
without being worried that it was going
to tip over and uh potentially burn burn
the the boat all up so it's nice to be
out on the water after church it is
freaking a beautiful day man was a great
sermon today too yeah it was good you
know it was hard to it was hard to come
out of the gate after hash Church 52 I
have to admit that you knocked it out of
the park it was an unbelievable
experience and you could tell everyone
was excited about it and they wanted to
be a part of it and it's those people
wanting to be a part of it and getting
excited that makes hash Church what it
is when when certain people just decide
not to come or enough people decide not
to come and be a part of it it it'll get
boring very fast so we got to keep it uh
topics changing yeah keep the topics
changing keep it on point and keep it up
to date with everything that everyone's
going going on whether you're in the US
whether you're in Canada whether you're
in somewhere in Europe we try to stay up
to date on all the information so the
weed stories are great oh yeah man we're
really rocking right now hey woohoo hope
you ain't getting seasick out there oh
[ __ ] Hey listen I think it's time to hit
some rosin we got this turp rosin here
thanks to Tony tpine my man Tony tpine I
got some sour d rosin gently added to
the Lindsay OG 90 Micron bubble hat
rosin so we took the bubble we squeezed
the rosin out of it we added the Tarpin
and uh well we were hitting it earlier
it's beautiful it is I think it's over
there tongue twister I was wondering if
we were sitting on it that's awesome
like no cuz we were on the other side of
this big house we're getting actually
brought up in a very nice way I'll move
the boat if I have to at one point but I
think for now we're good man I think
it's time to have a little bit of a dab
finally got the denail actually sorry
the dabinator today we have out on the
boat uh hooked up into the boat so the
power source is solid we're good to go
we're not worried about that it's just
uh maybe we'll just smoke all the rosin
that I have here marlar yeah I'm totally
down of course marlar is a South Park
reference for those that you don't know
it I think it was like was it the
Ethiopian guy isn't that jumping the
jumping the border is that the ones that
try and take the job God damn it they're
taking our J no I thought it was yeah
maybe those were the marlars the mar
I'm pretty sure that's God we can't even
remember someone's going to fix it
because this they'll know these people
watching are like up to date on this sh
you stupid Stoners you forgot what it
was about man come on it's super easy to
remember it was about that Ethiopian
dude I'm certain and I think all he used
to say he had a spaceship no that was
the one that went derpa derpa no that
was der that was der derka der the is
the is the Arabs this this was the
Ethiopian dude but yeah nonetheless
we're trying to figure out all of our uh
IST South Park stereotypes that they
Mock and rip
on you know it feels like when you rip
on everyone evenly that it's just right
and as long as you don't like one rip
more than the other it seems like you're
okay you know it's a it's a Dave
Chappelle sort of way of going out about
racism and prejudism so I have an
appreciation for the humor freedom of
speech freedom of
speech
that would be wow rang me the first
round let see what this is going to do
bell ringer every time
he see the fairy coming in how about
earlier when we were like literally like
200 ft behind the ferry that was kind of
cool have the camera
there yes we went out earlier for a
little Adventure but we didn't bring the
camera so we kind of felt like man these
guys kind of missed out on a little bit
of an adventure we'll uh we went back to
the house grabbed the camera and decided
to do this short little just a little
video you know a little after church
video there's a rocker for you dude take
as much of it as you want or as little
of it as you want I'm going to do the
whole damn thing do it as you please my
friend okay I may cough all over the
camera but that's all right as well we
don't
mind so yeah good conversations in
church
today possibly going to get a couple of
more at least one more version of church
might be coming down the pipeline it
might be a little branch of the of the
church and it really once we get more
into the R&amp;D of these tpin we're hoping
that we learn enough about them nice
hit that we can actually produce uh you
know an entire show on TP talk just the
full uh explanation of tpin and more
chemistry uh other than from just Mark
scalone we'd like to get in a a tpine
expert that I've been uh going back and
forth with trying to get into church and
uh yeah I just like the idea just smoke
it we'll find out put it to the test
it's the bio assay right yeah this how
you test it burn it and test it or
smolder it and test it whatever God it's
so nice bro it is actually CU may I take
a look and smell you sure
may I like the discussion that you guys
were talking about the parchment paper
and about trying to find your next thing
cuz I found that that was really
interesting today yeah you know I mean
that piece right there solvent and that
taking away that little and you guys
getting paper well that's just it right
it's like the better I have a new
material I haven't cut it up into
sections that's why I grabbed this
little bit of uh rosin today and put it
on a fresh piece of parchment that had
never been squeezed or used but I also
love the idea I think that uh you know
maybe at the end of it maybe we will
come to the conclusion that parchment
was the best that we could do but I
highly doubt it I think that the
discussion will be to bettering the
whole
process well glass would be your next
one correct well a lot of people are
talking about glass but I'm you know
first glass won't do well under pressure
it would have to be some sort of special
glass not to crack and and smash also it
it potentially holds heat in a different
way I mean that'll be interesting you
know I think it'll be a lot of different
Minds coming together to figure it out
but when you get enough people trying St
leave something behind or you just can't
get it off of that well stainless is
once again it's like yeah this is this
is easy to remove and put on and collect
from it's a transition
transitionary uh process of the process
where you go from the but or the hash
squeeze out the rosin you've got to
squeeze it somewhere to get it off so
right now oil slick pad parchment paper
PTFE all of these things have been used
and of course you know everyone argues
this is better than that I I suggest
that I really don't know which is better
but because I'm smoking a lot of the
product I would like to for sure know
which one is better and that's that's
really why we bring up the uh not the
argument but the discussion yeah
discussion for sure I would think like
something like a template or a small
little like piece but then you're
getting into metals
and yeah I mean that's those are the
presses right like obviously metal and
glass and all the things that presses
would be made of would not be what we
would be collecting rosin from it's just
not going to happen like that we need to
have
some sort of little interface like this
like when a seed cracks and it comes out
of the hall there's a little membrane
that allows it to slide out of the um
out of the the seed Hall without being
damaged I can't remember the name of it
uh Skunk Man Sam mentioned itos or some
sort no there's an actual name for it
this little piece and it and I believe
most seeds contain it and it just allows
the embryo to slip nicely out without
the root or the caladon which are those
first two round leaves of most plants uh
keeps it from getting
damaged man we're we're drifting in nice
I I see you keeping your eye on the big
log there yes it's only a 2 three ft
away from us but you know got to look
out for that man this is nice we're
probably in about 8 to 10 ft of water
right now maybe about 30 to 50 ft off of
the uh the shore got to be probably
about what 16 17° out here say even a
little warmer it almost feels like maybe
18 feels like it's up there man like
close to beautiful day out here today
burning on the back of my head we just
wanted to share a couple of dabs with
you guys share a little bit of the view
out there with us uh and uh yeah I don't
know if I have really much else to
say we dabbed we boated we chilled out
yes I think that's a successful little
video right there thank you for having
me oh [ __ ] dude thanks for I called
right after hash church I announced on
hash church that I was going to put my
boat on the in the water after 3 and
half hours of us talking and this guy
literally called me a minute or two
after hash church and was like went
offline I was like hey marklar you know
co-pilot like absolutely man and
co-pilot UF here go one second oh where
the what's that our paddle go oh I put
it away I literally just put it away
it's under the seat you have to pull it
out at a weird angle kind of push it in
and then pull it out there you go it's a
weird little thing how it kind of fits
one way but not the other
way how big is that log she's a biggie
she's she's a oh yeah she's a day Ender
that one right there you hit that in
your boat going to full speed so many
different worries out there today I
haven't had my boat in the water for
several months if you guys watched on
Periscope that day when I cut in front
of the big yacht and I and the Periscope
went dead and nothing else was said well
at that point I had problems with my
engine so I shut the Periscope off I
eventually got towed in and and uh the
motor needed a ton of work so for 2
months the motor's been rebuilt replaced
overhauled the whole nine yards it is
pimped out and so now the boat is I've
got motor confidence which is important
tight very very tight but how many logs
are out in the ocean right now oh it's
busy out there it was like three we
could go logging out here yeah you
literally could go pull out a thousand
logs out of this ocean little chunk of
the ocean be honest with you you could
pull logs out of here that would would
be probably very beautiful to clean up
and do some wood work with you just be
like yeah score well a lot of them come
from uh you know log booms believe it or
not like some of these logs that are
perfectly cut like that one and that one
and that you can see the cut on them
right those are from log booms other
ones that have been Fallen trees that
contain the roots obviously down the
river yeah so it's a mixture of the two
a couple telephone poles right there I
like the vision they're the view they're
getting in the background of anvil
Island that's pretty sweet this is sort
of Whistler area behind us it is nice if
you drove up that's North right there
and you would event excuse me you would
eventually uh end up in Whistler can you
see the seal behind us yeah there's a
seal right there up right behind us
swimming in
the I've been desperately trying to see
the whales and the Dolphins this year
I've been they've been eluding me I got
to see them from my deck and it's just
like I want to go and have a little dab
session with the whales and share it
with the bubble man crew cuz I know that
uh it would be something that they would
really en enjoy yeah
exactly well I think uh we're just going
to continue dabbing on here but uh we
won't blab on there's not much else to
say but thanks for watching Bubble man's
world guys thanks for uh sharing your
time with us and if you haven't already
please give the Subscribe button a click
and if you have already subscribed maybe
give us a thumbs up if you like the
video yes I say cheers stick to the
course now
let's stick to Life's course now and
don't away
now you got the ship I got the ship yeah
buddy hit and
steady steady
[Applause]
shipping I want you to stop
start
over there's so much so much to be
done I'll stick through the course
now won't stray away
now