[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world I'm here
with John B just got together for the
first time in what seems like 14 days or
something it seems like when did we make
the Little Pony bubble um it been a
Wednesday ago a week in 78 not 10 it's
been 10 days 10 days ago we did a trip
to Whistler and we made some uh bubble
hash next to chimus Creek with Phil you
might remember it while the bubble has
been sitting out on cardboard and drying
in my Gorilla Grow Tent completely
sealed from the environment in a nice
low 30% humidity 60%
temperature and we're now kind of ready
to get it off the cardboard and get it
into the little
containers and 90 this is yeah this is
the 90 this is the My Little Pony so
while I'm scraping and collecting John's
going to tell you a little bit about My
Little Pony we've told you about it
before but he's going to tell you again
and then all sitting here exactly so if
you want to talk I'll be the guy
scraping resin in the background
scraping resin My Little Pony as you can
see this is what we have R so this is
actually the tops was all the bottom so
this about half of what you
see and fresh frozen there about half of
was sitting out there so you roughly
about 24 that's about 10 oz there so um
roughly what SE here in the bubble hat
and the the Mind Little Pony nice strain
bubble
Kem cross with a stunk Haze
NL and and we talk a lot about this
right now because um it was from 1992 is
written on my bag it was just a
handwritten had skml something it was a
northern skunkies or you know there's a
lot of we're talking about it cuz I
called it medy My Little Pony and uh it
was also cross with another strange that
I've worked with so yeah that's kind of
the story behind it and it's just so
tasty it is I call it dessert it is it
really is dessert I had another buddy
over today and the first thing he said
is oh I remember that smell it was that
Northern L it's definitely got an old
school smell to it it's got a definitely
old school smell to it and they old
school beans and it's something I've
collected over the years and um I I
can't even really recall where they
actually came from but um that's the
story and I got a little video that I
said in the past that I actually have a
twee on there and I was running the
other strings you had some use that my
someone had we got it I was just
actually going to give a quick tip here
while doing this which is quite helpful
to know uh when you're getting nice
sticky bubble off like this it's you
know you've gotten it down to a nice
powder form but it's still bit sticky
rather than just go straight what I do
is I go at an angle and I kind of go
real slow to avoid um the shooting
bubble you know the flicking shooting
bubble that just releases and and shoots
off off the cardboard and into the great
unknown so just a quick little tip not
to cut John off on his My Little Pony
story
cuz me I uh use when I'm cleaning used
to be Glazer by trade that was after my
accident that's what I used to do and we
used to clean the glass with a razor
Blaze and you clean it on an angle so it
doesn't shatter same thing excellent
yeah it's something that I do exactly
the same thing and it's uh it's it's a
great thing to actually uh just point
out the color on this is absolutely
spectacular we should hit that it's
completely
white yeah and definitely we will be
just get it into its container so we can
get this cardboard off
here and get the next one up there we
go that's
45 why you written all these containers
you know dollar stores they work for now
soon to come yeah that'll get us to the
next maybe these little slick pads yeah
once we get them into the oil
slick let's see what we got here well
that's what uh this is the dry sift that
I got from my DK 420 from PG exactly yes
that is the treat that I brought you
from the man himself very generous very
generous thank you thank you
definitely
uh puffing with fresh clothes in here to
my friends but yeah um Just sh to him
he's he's keing it up there like I said
on my other channel oh yeah great guys
up there it they're doing great they're
doing good things and it's nice to it
was great to spend time with them they
just all of them were
just really good dudes I have to
say so one thing about My Little Pony
when I always run and I think we
discussed this before I was on the for
is really everybody always wants to get
this gr hash but it really comes down to
the growing and growing in your
environment of course and and for me
organic growing is what I've always when
I changed over Mark made some suggest he
goes you know you did stuff in the past
he says it wasn't really melting well
back in the days I wasn't always using
well Nutri I use Med one right now um I
I wasn't using an all organic base and I
don't know what it is but um for me it's
uh it's what's working for me and uh
yeah it's definitely working for you man
the resin is beautiful long flush I
always flush for at least 35 days so
this key just lost water um letting the
plant go to turn letting it finish off
so not cutting it to a day actually the
plant go all the way until it stops
actually drinking so there's little
things that I do that actually help me
achieve this actually beautiful bubble
hush that I get mhm well well as you've
seen over quity happens in the grow room
and and and I I'm also getting very good
quality and that I can down I'm a bit of
a snob really comes down to what you're
doing in that room and uh for me it's uh
controlling my temperatures um and U
paying very here let me grab the other
one real quick here we've got these
sitting on the 4x2 screens and they've
been completely protected for the last
12 days that one's clean so you can turn
it sideways if you need be you can get
it back in there
we'll get back
to the 160 that some pretty nice 160 I
got to
admit look at that I got a little piece
of my own pressed hash on there
accidentally nice
[Music]
yeah nice sound
anyway wow well this 120 is um what I've
seen actually and I've ran the same kind
of batch now three times same amount you
res and I'm seeing this definitely a
bigger yield and I
really what we may mention it come down
to the temperatures it was actually 0
deges God did we use cold water the
water was ice cold the ice wasn't
melting nothing I think the temperatures
with everything everything just being so
cold actually you discussed about being
in a freezer in the past and stuff like
that it was a nice cold environment when
we made this house you know it didn't
stick it came off the screens perfectly
water was just glacial
cold you know what didn't need to rinse
it out like rinsing the top of the resin
or nothing because the water was just so
cold it was so so cold we still used a
ton of ice which was you know great oh
no we did
yeah all right so 120 wow this is a nice
here let me just make sure we got the
cleanest possible screen even though
your 160 was beautiful why bother
contaminating any of the 120 if one
doesn't have look at the color look at
the color look at the color of oh my you
know what like that is
ridiculous I mean ridiculous that's come
on that's a h that's that's I'm looking
at the
amount well the amount is ridiculous I
haven't even done half the cardboard
ridiculous it's completely covered the
entire piece of cardboard uh and you
know what U we're going up for the river
next next one no problem
I or if you want rent a sled and come
with us to the back country and we'll do
it in the ice cave man your resin
deserves to be made in an ice
cave oh I can see it popping when you're
doing that there a little yeah but not
so bad just little little minis we're
coming at an angle I'm excited cuz you
just I guess you would really have to
lot you do understand but uh when you
spend 4 months working on growing some
beautiful medicine and when it comes
into a pile that
big like really it's
beautiful it is beautiful that's like a
beautiful
thing wow nice pile tell you I know just
fu yeah real beautiful oh excuse that
language personal I mean we didn't run a
ton that's the thing right I mean I've
obviously seen giant pil I keep running
all the time great um for what I've seen
from what I've been cutting roughly into
that rubber made bin which you've seen
in some of the other videos it's roughly
about 400 to 430 G of of fresh and this
is what I'm getting consistently about
90 maybe just under 100 G of dry of dry
and and and by that's a nice little pile
man that's a beautiful pile that that
that you want to spin it around a little
excited spin her around like you said
even that 160 looks marvelous what do we
got here 73 73
my one of my fa hard not to be I I was
actually discussing this with a friend
today and I was showing him the
different the different grades and he's
talking about yeah I got a two bag
system I'm like two bags what's a two
bag system I've never about
1998 oh yeah we do that for years old
boy old school guys and I was like well
see this is the problem it doesn't it's
cool to do things for years but what's
even cooler is to accept that you can
learn and constantly better
yourself like I've I've been doing this
for years too and trust me I'm you know
we're learning every day like I don't
ignore I know a lot of you people right
now are cringing that this is on
cardboard you know hey John put some on
uh parchment paper we're doing things
we're trying them out but and you know
what it it wasn't sticky I left it on I
I think I yeah I just did a little
picture of that and stuff like that it
was on put it on the water extraction M
but hey this is coming off beautiful oh
beautiful look I'm not working you I'm
too busy looking at this resin well
right away I think we have to hit each
one y and just talk about uh this is
really the final part to our Whistler
video right now you know so I'd say
let's just put that back inside forget
about that 190 for
now it's not really the one that you
want to keep you can use it for several
different things I was talking to oil
slick today I'm hoping on becoming their
Northwest distributor up here in the
Pacific Northwest in Canada anyway for
these oil slick products I've absolutely
been stoked on these little
stacks you know the little uh these are
full of dry sift that I made while I was
up uh in my last video with d420 K these
are also very cool these little glass uh
lightproof jars that you can't see
through so there's your 25 Sir John what
would you like to start with oh 90 90 so
yeah I really stoked to start working
with oil select none nonetheless it's
something I've been keeping my product
in it's not just a product for oil works
great for bubble hash works great for
dry sift and uh yeah you know what yeah
I like you're going right for 90 did you
say I love it yeah of course dude come
on it's likeing back he like going right
for 90 yeah going right for the
90 great to uh get back and hang out
with you have all your beautiful herb
here surrounding us your resin is
absolutely [ __ ]
delightful put on here Beau in put chain
down push this in a little for
you a little dabble do you I think uh
with this particular bubble what I'm
going to do I'm not sure what I've done
now with my oh my dab
kit I think I might go more along the
lines of the Dabber traditional it all
it did was melt instantly and stick to
this thing it's not you're not having
good success with that no this this was
what I'm thinking is heat the Dabber up
and then dip it in to this 90 oh yeah
that's crunchy and then pull it out wow
yeah my
turn let me get the I love holding the
pipe from the bottom and really show the
here we
go this
is yeah it's it's like the smell and the
flavor is definitely very unique that's
uh that smells like My Little
Pony but we're talking about does it
have really that hay smell to
it and really um really trying to
determine oh it's nice it's Unique it's
different it's not Haze to me but
there's a unique taste in there it's
fruity there's undertones that are
almost
unrecognizable just remind me of old
things school well that's why they had a
date on at ' 92 and I know that's pretty
clear
so and who knows where are they came
from
but oh that was a great hit I'll tell
you it's eye closing hash literally
makes you want to close your
eyes very nice
material
it's great that we could wait for two
full weeks and just leave it be and
that's really in my opinion the uh the
kicker in in in properly drawing bubble
hashes well you know what
like feeling very it's just very it's
just I don't eat anymore right now I'm
just I'm happy defin strong one thing
I'll say about um properly drawing
bubble and how you can tell the
differences and I've learned this uh
really just in playing with full melt
dry sift pure 99% head dry sift when I
squeeze dry sift together it's hard
right away and it's almost sometimes
hard to make it flat and thin it's just
you push a dab together and it's almost
hard instantly bubble very rarely does
that because most people's bubble is
still moist it still has wet in it you
know it's
not just grease all the time a lot of
the times that bubble has moisture in it
it's the wax membrane and it might
appear to look nicer but it's degreg and
to a hash smoker who's a recogniz not
recognized but um an experienced hash
smoker will feel the difference in their
throats that's that little bit of
harshness you you must have as being a
judge this year at Legends and sitting
with the the the Heavies you you know
what I mean like those guys are serious
has smokers Oh serious they're not it's
not and they're not doing it for any
recognition they're not doing it for any
like to be in a magazine or they're just
like that's who they are and they take
it very seriously so I think that's what
was so great about being able to judge
there and stuff was was talking with
them and and asking and then and then
it's just the passion you see in people
that's it for for no reason re and and
and and then looking over at you going
you're just like us yeah that's it I'm
just so passionate about the same John's
definitely passionate some of you have
made comments in the YouTube videos like
man I love how the grower is so proud
that's his passion that's why John and I
click cuz I'm in the same boat I don't
grow but what people do grow I want them
to know how great it is and how you
offer them that is you teach them about
purity you know before we had bubble
bags and water extraction you know pre
99 you know a lot of people most people
had never seen this and it just didn't
exist in a lot of people's stash most
people haven't been you know exposed to
full melt dry sift or full melt bubble
pre pre 1990 99 sorry so here we are 15
years later oh my mine was um black hash
and you let it stand on fire put it on
it smell awesome and it was killer was
the best I still hear people to this day
it had the gold seal on it it's like
oh
yeah and then you you go to amam they
have little stuff please help yourself
could you imagine how they would never
be
this and then John I
know
oh it's like yellow and then there's
tiny little flakes little pieces that
didn't quite get microplan that got you
know we'll have to separate those out
because they are uh they're just a
different color and they look totally
wild mix that's what I just took a piece
over that and hit it yeah well those are
the best pieces to get rid of right away
cuz they're the most likely to have
trapped moisture and that's why I did
that and even a piece that's small the
size of the tip of a match head is
enough it's enough to have M
moisture so I guess uh it was a success
the fresh frozen batch and whiske always
a success actually I would say yeah out
of what I see sitting in front of me I'm
cold cold cold and you've been saying
that to me ever since I
keep it cold keep it cold keep it cold
absolutely well doing it at 0°
temperatures while it's snowing out yeah
that was nice hey come on we'll be doing
it again we'll be getting up there
sooner than later hopefully into the
pton back country maybe the ice cave to
do a nice batch I really want to get
that done this winter I think that it
would be valid to show some epic
snowboarding epic skiing ski flying and
sledding all mixed in with a video where
we go to the ice cave and make a fat
batch of fresh frozen I know maybe some
dry sift some dry sift so yeah just want
to thank everyone for watching we're uh
going to continue puffing bowls here but
we won't take up all your time and uh
yeah right on dude good to see you again
John we'll be back uh for puff
Wednesdays puff Wednesdays we'll see you
in a few days peace
peace
[Music]
oh