[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
it is what is it a Sunday today Sunday
the 14th and it's my son's birthday
tomorrow so I'm actually just taking the
boat out of the water
and I figured I would take us for maybe
a little How Sound rip I know a lot of
you guys enjoyed it when I tripped out
on the boat with uh Flav
421 with all the Epic glass now today I
don't have epic glass I just have my
little uh Hitman as well as I have a
pure hash joint just in case I feel the
urge to smoke one with you guys out here
but
uh yeah go for a little boat
[Music]
Crews you like that horse
hey you stoked you on the boat you want
to hit that has joint or what he's like
yeah pure hash joint
buddy all right well let's give her some
Gusco here
I guess we could get a
sunrise here comes our
Sunrise yeah
buddy Sunrise what do you think of that
Sunrise
orus who out there loves their dog I
mean how [ __ ] awesome is it to have a
little dog or a big dog or a
medium-sized dog that just hangs out
with you and just loves you how great is
that love your dogs everyone treat them
well they deserve
it hey guys welcome back I'm uh just
sitting out here on the boat and my God
is it beautiful there's not a single
soul on the house sound right now uh a
little bit of waves coming in on the
side here you can see how the boats
moving fairly substantially as these
waves come in nice rocking feeling I got
my little dog oreo with me out here
today and uh I got the Hitman and I
guess I just wanted to have a short
little conversation with you guys today
about a few different projects I've been
working on they're a little bit I'm
terrible in regards to things that I do
and then never mentioning them um I know
I mentioned these guys quite a while ago
Frank 51 um did the cover as well as a
spread and the back cover on this book
it's a really great little book it's
their 420 Edition and uh oh look at that
a little bit of hash stuck right in the
inside that's awesome so yeah it's a
good little book it's got a lot of
different you know pretty much most
people that you associate heavy duty
with uh cannabis uh will be in here
we've got chich and Chong obviously and
be real from Cypress Hill and Snoop dogs
in here and we got Dazz is in here we
got some Jamaican dudes some Reggae
artists we got myself and
Slinger um whole whole bunch of people
uh Dr Dena is in there gpen has a page
basically a bunch of people I know a
bunch of people I don't know there's
Slinger page Slinger's got a great
little write up in here definitely worth
checking checking slings little article
out he he does a little interview JP
bomb does an interview really great
grower oh and full flavor extract water
hash little water has article so all in
all it's definitely a book worth
checking out you can check it out at
frank1 151.2093
cannabis uh side of things um secondly I
recently did um a spread and a cover for
cannabis Now Magazine if you guys are
familiar with cannabis Now Magazine uh
you can check it out at cannabis now
magazine.com and you can also check out
cannabis now on Facebook they've got
about I don't know 2.5 or 2.7 million uh
likes which is uh pretty substantial
traction for Facebook they're definitely
doing well and then I also have a a
fairly substantial
uh right up in here as well I got the
bee on the medy Kush which Johnny B
really loved and then a couple of more
just nice bud
shots that uh nice big
centerfold and last but certainly not
least that same picture you saw on the
cover of the book it's a popular one
everyone wants that shot and that shot
was Remo the urban grower so check out
Urban Remo on Facebook and on YouTube
because if you want if you enjoy photos
like that you'll definitely enjoy the
content that Remo the urban grower
provides so I suspect now it's time for
us to do a little
puffing got my
Hitman got my fresh frozen Astro Boy my
Skillet
tool and uh my
torch so I should be able to get the job
done here I always find the skillet tool
is a little little bit big for this
particular piece but uh ah we should be
okay we should be able to get her
done it's quite something even even
heating up the nail is a little bit of a
challenge
I definitely love my denail for this
very reason I find the nail is uh a
little
bit little bit you never know especially
outside if it's actually
working there we go I got a better view
on it
now getting it hot hot
hot yeah I wanted to take the Dil out
today I've been uh doing a little bit of
work with uh denail with Brian and Nick
Stevie um not sure how much I'm allowed
to say but we're kind of working on a
little project together kind of trying
to well those guys are pioneers there's
no doubt about it and I think that they
recognized um some of my value in the
fact that I I really use these things a
lot that their products I take them all
over the world I use them in different
scenarios and I really sort of put the
product to the test in a way that a
group of guys like that who are
constantly pioneering you just know
they're going to have an appreciation
for someone like that and uh indeed they
do all right well let's see if we can
get a little hit on this
thing well there's no doubt about it
that worked I definitely got a rip uh I
got my new method 7 shades on there's
something I wanted to talk to you guys
about these new coupe the coups really
like this style kind of that Rayband old
school style Ferris bu or whatever you
would have um I've been using my sun
resistance uh these ones I guess this is
the the regular um uh pair and I've been
absolutely loving these and then I met
James from method 7 at Pacific Garden
Northwest uh Pacific Northwest gardening
supplies vendor day and what a great guy
really knowledgeable super information
if you if you guys are looking locally
in BC for method 7s you can get him from
IG green planet.com or Pacific Garden uh
Pacific Northwest garden supplies and if
you're looking for them anywhere else
you can check out method
7.com I'm telling you these coups are
really great they had they had sent me a
pair of the new Coupe HPS with the
mirrored glass lenses and I went and
shot at tilray a couple of days ago and
I'm not sure if he was one of the owners
or if he was was one of the head Growers
but I let him put on the coups and he
wouldn't take them off he basically told
me that he needed to buy them he's he's
getting more for all of his gardeners at
tillay and uh so I was real happy to set
that up and and and Link those guys up
together because obviously Till's got uh
you know a couple thousand lights
burning and a lot of people in those
rooms uh their eyes are being affected
by by that strong powerful light so
always a good thing to have your method
sevens these aren't particularly a pair
you'd wear in the girl room they're a
pair for the Sun but uh yeah I sure love
them give you a serious Testament of how
much I like these I'm quite a shade snob
I've been using Maui gyms for the last
10 years and I've gone through many many
many many pairs and they're 350 bucks
they're not cheap anyway I've Got a
Brand New Pair of Maui gyms at home
right now they're in the case and I've
been wearing my method 7 so I got to
tell James that and I think he was
definitely like wow that's that's a true
story well I'm going to take another rip
here and then I think we're going to
boot around just do a little circle of
the house sound and see if I can't maybe
locate uh some Dolphins and the whales
uh yesterday I heard were up in the
sound up in Squamish so maybe we could
head over to the back side of anvil or
something and I want to show you guys
the whales I want to show you guys the
Dolphins cuz it's definitely a level of
excitement that we have not yet achieved
here on Bubble man's world when uh when
you get out on the boat and you see the
whales or the Dolphins I just I really
get giddy I turn into like a little kid
I'm very uh big animal lover not sure if
you guys know that about bubble man but
uh it's part of the reason I'm a
vegetarian I'm not really big on killing
and eating animals I just love them I
love animals I think they're great and
uh I can't imagine just you know having
the love that you would have for your
dog but then you know just eating a
cow cows are pretty cool too
anyway that's the end of my hippie
rant time for another
bow got to love the hitbad
that's some glass that I would carry at
Fresh headies I have to say Hitman has
nice glass maybe that's something I
should do get in touch with Hitman and
see if we can't get some of this glass
on full melg
glass.com what's wrong ores what's wrong
buddy
hey what's wrong he gets a little boat
shy sometimes maybe he wants to go for a
ride catch up with you guys in a
bit all right so we're on the back side
side of Boer Island you can see the
lions in the background those two big
mountain
peaks and uh this is the only part of
this particular Island that is
inhabitated that is inhabited sorry
inhabitated CLE dabs too many there
b uh so yeah West Vancouver right across
the way on the other side of that uh
mountain is
Vancouver and then you have Horseshoe
Bay up here where I catch the ferry when
I go see Matt the great Gardener and
when I go to tillay any of those sort of
[Music]
Adventures
yeah
yes the habitated side of Bo
West Vancouver across the way a
beautiful cloudless
sky and
uh all in all a good Zone
[Music]
I'm just going with the flow thinking
you guys might appreciate um just
floating by this island so I think this
might be a good time to load yourself up
a fat dab twist up a fatty gear up cuz
we're going to do a couple of minutes of
uh just enjoying this island look for
seals
Eagles um
Dolphins
maybe back side of this island is often
where the mama seals will leave their
seal pups while they go hunt for the
day so you see baby seals quite quite
often just laying on these rocks um they
blend in quite well but if I see one
I'll uh I'll stop the boat and zoom the
camera in the best that I can pretty
cute little little
guys that almost looks like one but it's
a rock
wow about 400 ft deep here on the side
of this
island what do we got flying by
seagull yeah a little seagull
a really beautiful island to kayak
[Music]
around surprised there's no Pops in the
sun it's the right part of day for it
[Music]
w
oh there's a baby
pup there's a little baby
pup couple actually four or five all in
one little
zone I'll try to get closer
without aggravating
them and see if I can get in here and
show you
guys so the one on the left is the one I
saw first the far left you can see
they're just kind of littering the Rocks
there sorry it's so
shaky hate that sort of
shoddy camera work oh there's a bunch of
seals here actually I didn't even notice
like 10 or
20 not necessarily babies some of them
are anyway there they are
I don't have my
telephoto I guess I could take some
pictures for you guys and add them into
this video why don't I do that all right
I got a little closer for you guys and I
snagged some pictures for you guys I
think my dog's just now realizing that
they're there on the side of the Rocks
quite a few over in this corner
too going to back up don't like being
too close to the islands and I don't
want to encroach on them too much
we haven't bugged them out they haven't
moved so have a good day bacon
seals just one of the really beautiful
and cool things about living in British
Columbia is things like that being able
to
uh float by on your boat and see 20
SEALS or 10 SEALS or five
seals just chilling on the side of the
Rocks like that
very
cool let's go see if we can't catch some
Eagles now looking up in the trees bald
eagles mate on the back side of this
island so there's often always you know
generally one or two of them uh couples
I mean so two to four bald eagles we
should catch at least one of them it is
a pretty vast Forest up there it's just
a matter of looking for the white head
there goes our
neighbor to ding that boat
[Music]
so we're heading into the house sound
now that island in the background that
um appears to have no
top is called Anvil Anvil Island
there's not much going on over there
other than I believe a Christian Camp
[Music]
I guess while we're floating around this
island we could learn a little something
about our endoc canabo systems not sure
how many of you guys are familiar with
your endocannabinoid system but uh it is
a system that helps uh regulate most of
the biological functions that occur in
your body uh how well you remember and
how well you forget how well you sleep
and how well you you wake up when you
get hungry and when you're full how well
you go to the bathroom all these certain
uh all these different biological
functions are uh tuned and put into
homeostasis via um uh your endoc canabo
system and the proper feeding of that
endoc canabo system which of course
doctors tell us to uh consume amino
acids Omega-3s and Omega 6s there's
actually eight uh essential amino acids
that humans require to survive and a
couple of more three more I believe uh
for children so they need 11 and we need
eight anyway those uh amino acids are
building blocks and they help produce uh
endoc canabo uh inside your body that's
what Endo means endogenously uh those
cannabinoids are produced via the
building blocks of amino acids but you
can also get more help and saturate your
endoc canabo system uh by
consuming uh phyto cannabinoids which
are exclusive to cannabis now phyto
canabo um CB D CBN CBC CBG THC all these
different uh you know them all I'm sure
um these these function in our bodies to
help regulate and uh our endoc canabo
systems and put us into a state where um
we don't get as sick we are less
susceptible to disease we are able to
prevent things like heart disease stroke
diabetes um these are all very important
factors in life and uh if you look them
up they're very high uh disease rates uh
the highest disease rates in the world
heart disease and stroke diabetes and
the cost of them on the healthcare is
astronomical so just simply allowing us
to consume phyto canabo and when I say
consume I uh please don't think that I
mean just
smoke um the smoking uh please when I
say consume please don't think I mean
just smoke because truly what I'm what
I'm talking about is I'm talking about
the creams uh the transdermal patches
the lingual drops um Edibles and then of
course uh vaporization as well smoking
has its place don't get me wrong it can
stimulate appetite quickly it can
relieve ocular pressure quickly uh it
can produce wonderful euphoric feelings
which I believe are uh medicinal and
preventative in their own way and uh
yeah all around uh saturate that endoc
canabo system when you can and I'm going
to leave you with that cuz I feel like
I'm kind of going on and on now but uh
thanks for coming out on the boat with
me it was real fun sorry I didn't uh
really have much more to talk about in
regards to uh J herbs and I didn't
really show you many hashes or herbs but
uh we saw the beautiful house sound on
really like a 9 out of 10
day and I think that's uh that's pretty
good I'm heading up to Whistler for the
next couple of days so you may catch a
bubble man's world from up there I'll
see what I can do thanks for watching
guys
peace
[Music]