[Music]
all right day two in the cies sitting
here with Ron we just woke up a little
while ago we were up quite late what do
you work every night till about 3:00 in
the morning in your gr yeah yeah yeah
nice one room comes on at 10:00 so you
got you need 3 or 4 hours in there yeah
exactly so I decided to do a little
filming this morning we were talking in
the chat tinychat.com slbc bubbleman
freshes and that is um yeah we were
talking about just Stories We were
talking about how Ron used to own a a
hydroponics shop in Manitoba that's how
we actually
met I needed um I needed help with my
grow I was quite young probably about 18
years old and I was just starting my
first grow and I guess the plants got a
little sick and I had heard rumors about
this guy who was apparently you know
pretty cool this was you know 25 years
ago in Manitoba which kind of is still
not really very cool of a province
wouldn't you say no still not cool no
it's still not a cool Province it's why
we're here in British Columbia both Ron
and I probably should have lived here um
most of our
Lives yes yes but uh we're here now so
we're just is probably going to chill
out tell a few stories puff a few
bowls and yeah yeah Ron was talking
about having
uh th000 watt light bulbs in the window
of his hydroponic store back in the day
and I remember driving by before I knew
him before I went and asked for his help
and seeing these light bulbs just
shining out of the street right onto a
major major Street in in Winnipeg pretty
much the ma not Highway number one it is
exactly Portage Portage Avenue is
Highway number one so right on Highway
number one the Trans Canada you had
5,000 Watts burning beautifully yeah and
what uh and a three arm Sun Circle turn
in three of them to show people Sun
circles oh yeah yeah what did the police
think about all that uh they didn't like
it they they came and told me to they
didn't tell me they said listen we know
we can't stop you from doing it but uh
if you continue to do it say you get a
Breakin in your place we won't be able
to respond because we'll be blind
so uh maybe you could just do something
about it and uh or else we could uh or
we could park a police car in front of
your store your H your power store and
see how many customers you get in a
daytime with a police car up front all
day didn't they do that no they yeah
they did once just I'm pretty sure I
went there before and saw they did for
an hour or two once but they told me
they were going to bring a bus down one
from the from the from the shop and just
they didn't need that was not running
there was in a park in front of my place
and leave it there and really like not
that you were like a really bad dude but
you just didn't have a good relationship
with those guys well no no no pot didn't
have a good relationship I didn't have
it either but I think I was had not a
bad relationship well they hated that
you loved pot if I could put it any more
simply than that do you know what I mean
they hated that you loved pot yes and it
was Winnipeg and not only did you love
it you see you seem to like educate and
execute pot better than most by what I
mean by that is like how well you grew
it how much you grew it and how many
people you T poot to grow it you know
this is why Mark emry is sitting in
prison right now in Mississippi he loves
it we both love it because he loves it
to a point where he not only wants to
share the information it got to the
point where Mark stepped to the next
level and was selling the beans you know
so many people have harshed on Mark
saying that um you know they've
criticized him oh he sold seeds and it
was a huge ripoff and he was um uh you
know making millions of dollars it's
like yes he sold seeds that were
extremely expensive and he did make
millions of dollars but here's the
different part with Mark that you don't
hear with many others and that is that
Mark gave all his money away Mark never
bought himself anything fancy he never
you know bought himself a a house or a
car or anything he's just basically
lived in his modest
apartment and gave all that money to
often American Growers that had been
busted and needed money for bail to get
out needed help with lawyer fees um it's
kind of like when you go to an auction
and a silent auction and you pay more
for the item than you're supposed to you
don't leave and complain that the silent
auction ripped you off you know that you
supported something that the money went
to a good cause MH and that's kind of
with Mark that you have to really give
it up to him I mean he just gave and he
did it in the times of uh when when I
was doing it I'm I'm an old dude sure
and Mark was doing with what didn't mark
used to have a bookstore he did and then
his bookstore went to his interest went
to pot and then and but he was in our he
he did it in a rough time he was the
Pioneer oh yeah he's always been also
much like you in the sense like
just he's always gone a little Against
the Grain right when there was when
there was a garbage um uh strike in
Toronto uh back in the 80s Mark was the
one that organized hiring like scabs and
basically oh I found that hash awesome I
found the hash he fired scabs and I
can't remember the tonnage but he moved
tonnage of garbage to the dumps from the
city on those hot summer days where the
garbage was just going to cause sickness
and stench and all these you know like
we don't need that in our city he did
the same thing when he was told he
couldn't sell certain types of magazines
you know that got him into bongs and not
being allowed to sell bongs and cannabis
so hey it's definitely um it's all about
the love that's what it is my passion
comes from the love absolutely his
passion comes from the love you guys are
both cannabis Warriors I know I know you
both both well I've known you for 25
years I've known Mark for 20 years and
uh I definitely know that uh I would
defend you both in in your love and
passion for the plant and I'll say one
thing right now too because we're being
videotaped Mark is teaching somebody
right now in a prison system somewhere
in wherever it's Idaho Ori Mississippi
Mississippi yazu City yeah yazu you can
guarantee that he's entertaining and
making all their lives much much better
he's passing the word around all down
there you know what Adam Bowen wrote a
song and I I think it's called something
about the Tricom inside the Tricom or in
the song he writes about Mark Emory and
how he collected the fists or sorry the
fingers of activism and made them into a
fist sort of a metaphor that we were all
sort of apart and away and and he
congealed Us and got everyone to sort of
do stuff and in the song he sings Uncle
Sam has ingested marijuana in the form
of mar emry and he basically sayings
that that's going to affect it was
amazing cuz he basically wrote that if
if the United States inhaled Mark Emery
into their system that he was literally
marijuana and that they would
change that he would change their system
from within and you can honestly say the
prosecuting attorney who prosecuted Mark
Emery is the same man who a year and a
half later or 2 and 1 half years later
was the promoter of legalization in
Washington
if you can wrap your head around
that so maybe they did ingest marijuana
now we've seen Colorado bring legal
cannabis to market we've seen California
there's a variety of other Vermont and
so they were sort of validating that
Mark did get all this rock and rolling I
mean it's hard to say right but it is
pretty unique they're saying they're
saying it he was he wrote it in a song a
few years before it happened any anyways
right on from Mark we'll see him soon I
guess this
summer you know one thing we all say
about Mark though too I just want to
throw this in because I don't know who
will hear this but um jod does pretty
good behind him you know it's
a fighting pretty amazing yeah she's
done a really amazing job she stepped up
at a very uh young age and just a person
that wasn't in the scene at all and came
into the scene and absolutely just has
become one of my favorite spokes people
for for our our scene and she's taking
really good care of his business while
he's gone to you know we can see we
talked to employees we talked we see how
is going and more importantly she's
visited Mark yeah lots yeah like you
know at least once a month maybe twice a
month so let's just give Joey something
for this all to right on absolutely yeah
big uh big Kudos big big kudos to them
yeah we're in our chat right now and one
of our members is saying that uh yeah
people say bad things about Mark and jod
and I just want to say that people
people will always want to attach
themselves to any type of fame or any
type of subject that is being spoken
about any type of news and jod and Mark
they're kind of famous they're like a
news they're newsworthy story they're
our Representatives they represent us in
the news and in the media our activism
and all the work that we've done over
the years they're kind of our
Representatives you only get a few to do
that in the media and jod uh you know
jod and Mark Mark is a strong
personality so sometimes he rubs people
the wrong way it's great that he
manifested jod into his life because
it's hard to see jod rubbing anyone the
wrong way you know she's just sweet nice
person wholesome honest like just a
really nice person so I'm glad to call
them both my friends yeah D when you
think of the girl the strong girls of of
the pot World me being an old guy I say
we got to add Hillary in there too yeah
well you know what Hillary was
definitely like the
original powerful you know like just
incredible spokesperson always came out
smelling like a rose every time you saw
Hillary on the news it was like woohoo
yeah you know and then she stepped away
and that is Hillary that is yeah that's
that's who who Hillary always was so but
when she stepped away jod really kind of
stepped into that position and I never
thought anyone would be able to sort of
step into that position cuz Hillary
would just you know she would pull it
off every time well Hillary was born to
be it yeah yeah jod I don't know I don't
didn't know for those of you that don't
know Hillary Hillary black started the
BC Compassion Club um we met her years
before that when she worked with Mark
emry at the original hemp BC and she was
probably 17 years old when we first met
Hillary so yeah very cool she sat in
your on your in your living room that
one day I said I want to start something
that have for compassion for people yeah
well I remember her saying she didn't
like the word medical and she didn't
like the word marijuana so she wanted to
call it uh Cannabis Compassion yeah and
so she was kind of thinking about moving
to San Francisco to live with Todd
McCormick another well-known cannabis
activist who she was um dating at the
time but she was having some
difficulties I had just moved to British
Columbia this was
1996 yeah it was 1996 and so she decided
it was either move down with Todd which
I'm very glad she didn't Todd ended up
getting arrested in that Fiasco they
were growing in a mansion in Bair a
couple of properties over from the
Reagans that was the the Peter
McWilliams um grow as well where Peter
McWilliams uh ended up passing away and
all of that due to not being able to
take cannabis for anti- edic he he
choked on his own vomit uh they had
taken his mom's home away and told him
that they were going to keep you know if
he smoked cannabis that that they
weren't going to be releasing his home
just a terrible story Todd did 5 years
on Terminal Island for that Renee B was
wanted for a 10-year sentence she had to
escape up to Canada that's that's when
Chris Bennett met her and so all these
things were happening it was uh it was
just a real crazy time and Hillary
literally I had just moved to British
Columbia from Manitoba Hillary was my
one friend and I was just like I was
right behind her to start her Compassion
Club idea and of course the BC
compassion club's been around for 18
years now um I was one of their first
Growers I was happy to support them with
cannabis often at a lower cost than I
could find cannabis for myself but it
was definitely something that uh it was
a good thing when the Cannabis
Compassion Club got started oh for sure
I'm so proud of it's unbelievable when I
go when I go to my local town here and
and go to the compass Club just know
that it's there I see people coming in
that need a place to um to just go it's
that where there's some friendly people
that can you know give them the best
service they can absolutely it grew into
such a beautiful thing with the health
center on the other side with the
massage and raiki and all these things
they offer for free from the profits of
the Cannabis they send that over to the
next side and then there's people that
can go talk with counselors and just
it's really a POS herbalists it's an
amazing Place yeah information sharing
yeah so that's the BC Compassion Club
you can check that out uh I think
they're on 13th in Commercial Drive and
I mean it's not even just BC compassion
don't you think like even just our
little Nelson Compass absolutely it's
they're all over that they're it's
they're they're popping up everywhere
and they Hillary really set the bar with
what um it's not about making money it's
not entrepreneurship it's about uh
friendship it's about healing you know
it's it's about I I see people sick
people go in they get a smile on their
face when they all they see buy some Mr
Nice you know whatever what to the
watermelon whatever it is totally uh and
you see a smile in their face they walk
out you know they're going to have a
better day you want another rip sure
love them all
right yeah so we're not exactly sure
what we're going to do today we'll
probably do a few clips from Ron's uh
grow he did just cut down um the
majority of his crop but he's got a new
one flowering so we go in there and get
some tips from him and then maybe we'll
be making some uh some bubble has today
as well we should yeah yeah yeah Ron's
got a whole whole bunch of uh nice
material put aside for for
bubbling as well as dry sifting there's
a several pounds sitting out on the
screens show you that a little later on
too and hopefully we bump into some
local Nelson friends' be nice to see
some some cotney friends that I haven't
seen in a
while and later tonight I think we're
going to go by the answorth hot springs
so
stay tuned see you guys later
[Music]