hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and
welcome to Epic nature I have jumped on
my I guess anti-nature machine dirt
bikes a lot of people find them
obnoxious I grew up on them since I was
7 years old so I have a different
affinity for them as most but I try to
be as polite as I can when I'm driving
on trails and whatnot maintaining the
nature of the environment without going
off the trail that being said I am up
here in the garabaldi brome ridge
absolutely surrounded by nature and
nothing but you can see there's still
quite a bit of snow up here I've
actually gotten about as far as I can
get I usually go up to the peak of that
mountain up there um I'm trying to see
if I can get up on the left side here my
buddies are just up on the other side of
the mountain about to shoot some guns
and I figured I would do a little Vapor
session with you guys I got my uptech
here so I got to give a shout out to uh
Gary and Sam from uptech and just give
those guys monster props for uh hooking
me up with some uh wonderful quality
vaporizers
beautiful uh to give you an idea where I
am this is north in the background if
you see that little peak of mountain
that's called um why am I brain farting
on that that's the Black Tusk and the
Black Tusk can be seen of course very
well from here in brome but it can also
be seen uh quite well from Whistler
Mountain if you've ever been on the peak
of Whistler Mountain you can absolutely
see uh the Black Tusk Peak pretty
beautifully from there sorry about all
the moving around and stuff I I I know
it's not
ideal with the camera moving like that
I'll try to get it
steady I think my friend is coming up
here right now actually maybe he'll be
on the video with me my buddy
Ryan well here he
comes I'm not even sure if that's him oh
yeah that's him anyway I hope everyone
is doing well out in YouTube land I hope
you guys have been appreciating your
summer and of course enjoying nature as
often as you can one of my favorite
things to do with ganja cannabis resin
whatever you want to call it it's to get
out in nature it's not to just sit on my
couch and play video games although if
that's what you want to do power to you
I'm definitely not against you doing
that but uh if you get the chance try to
get out into nature man you'll see it's
pretty damn
fun woo yeah buddy yeah
bit oh yeah dude that was awesome seeing
you coming in the background just doing
a little bit video for bubble man's
world oh cool I was in the wrong gear on
that last Hill but finished it yeah you
did it great I think we'll be able to
get up on the left side here if we
really really wanted to you for sure
we'll get all the way to the point with
uh this bike I don't know by yours I
think I'll get there I think you can
you've been killing it man first day out
and you're shredding it yeah
well 25 30 no 30 35 years of dirt biking
yeah yeah had a
boy all right well we're gonna continue
on thanks for watching guys just a
little taste of the Beauty and the
epicness up here in the
bro