[Music]
bubble man's world we're smoking hash
we're driving Harley's we're floating in
boats and we're visiting epic nature
[Music]
sits give me a
one man home ground man
[Music]
real the purpose after we that to the
Mind purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose after we l I view
the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
ding we have been traveling to Kingston
about 20 M hour sing on like fres vation
with trees and with flowers
off me a
big me give
me give me oneg and if it's
bigger me pass
[Music]
pass make pass
pass
could up
that now before
BL
and pause that
now purpose after we that keeps me
going the purpose after weed that's to
the
Mind purpose after weed gave by
this the purpose of the we l I view the
time
we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do with purpose
of
dying well I imagine the road there be
some cops setting up PL all traps man us
man we tell me off and on your scene to
intervene in my bra St that K and behind
your scene me and my team have another
25 we smoke it
[Music]
clean man ass
now pass pass pass and
then I make pass po pass po Pass
and Pass pass
[Music]
pass pass pass pass