[Music]
All right. So, we're going to do another
little garden update here. I'm in about
week
four. The watermelon's producing very
nice nugs.
Nice resin content on the
leaves. Uh over here we have the Medi
Medic
Kush. And then we also have Oh, that's
nice. That mighty Kush. We also have
uh the Chem4
reunion. Under that Chem4 reunion, you
got a nice big fat watermelon nugget.
Look at that little guy.
Watermelon being the astro boy. You can
see some
nice nice nuggets stacking
here. Where's that other head? That this
guy here, this branch had a really
nice unique fat head. Got
to stake that one. Um, oh yeah, we got
the My Little Pony as well here in the
background. She hasn't really pushed out
her resin content yet. She's not covered
covered covered in resin, but
uh she sure has a real nice smell. So,
these are now being flushed. Um I'll
probably flush them for 5 weeks, if not
longer. I'm not exactly sure the
flowering times. I'm not really paying
attention, so it'll really be about what
I prefer. I'll uh probably snap off a
bud here and there, you know, cure it
out, dry it, and um dry sift it just to
see if the resin's melty and ready how I
like it. That's kind of a neat way to do
it. And uh otherwise, yeah, I'll just
keep you guys updated on my little crop
here. I'll keep you updated on my
mother's. All right, so here we have the
Afghany and the Sweet Skunk. Just just
enjoying a little bit of
sun, you know. Little bit of beautiful
British Columbombian sun, ocean, and
mountains in the
background. This is going to be some
very happy moms. Both of these will be
moms. Uh Matt Safer soaped them before
he brought them. I see no signs of any
bugs or any mildews or any problems
whatsoever. Just real nice healthy
little plants. Sweet skunk and
Afghani. Next up we have the barb barra
bud update. Barbber's doing great. Um
really happy. Also bug free, mold free.
Really nice plant.
Uh, it's got a great tight interoting on
these arms. Matt's uh done a nice job. I
mean, this would be a great little plant
to uh to flower with just a single top.
It's growing four or five nice big
arms. Yeah. Well, it's not getting
flowered. Just going to be a mom for a
long
time. Mommy
styles. Thanks for watching. Peace.
[Music]
Mando
old the planter of the
trees and marsh of the ganja farm the
ganja
farmer alongside me on that blazing
Yo yo
I love to more and more each and every
day. I love to get you more and more
each and every day. Come
on. I rise this
morning. I've got to have me
some. I see the new day dawning dawning.
Polite
as everyone got their own thing
[Music]
doing. But me, I've got to have some
sense of each and every day.