hey bubble man here with uh John Bell
from Med taner Canada we are uh out on
the beautiful house sound and we're
going to today going to make some bubble
we're going to make some bubble it's the
first time for me I've made a lot of
bubble over the years and I've done it
all over the world but I've never made
bubble on a boat I've made it on a bus
with DJ Short and Mark Emory driving
around the city of Vancouver that was
fun at the 2004 tokers Bowl uh I've made
it on the side of mountains I've made it
in jungles I've made it really all over
the place but we've never done it on the
water we've been talking about this for
a while we got the beautiful Sunshine
Coast behind us where uh pot TV was
based out of in its earlier days um we
got Whistler up north Anvil Island
behind us along with Gambier and the
Elfin Stone Mountain behind that really
just a beautiful day we figured let's
make a little YouTube video and maybe
get some tips out there to the people
that uh haven't really learned the
proper methods I I don't want to say
techniques because everyone wants to
make it their own technique but really
it's a simple instruction for doing this
process and if you follow those simple
instructions and you use exceptional
material like uh what John has brought
us here today woo jeez what do we got
here John that's a medy Kush medy Kush
you know my Str tell us a little bit
about the medic Kush medic Kush medic
Kush is a strain that works very well
for me at uh came to me back in 2006
after I had an accident and it worked
very well for medicine for me and it was
uh from seed and uh over the years uh
named it medic Kush it works so well for
a medicine then I uh entered into a
Cannabis Cup in 2011 at Ty treating
yourself and I won first place for ex um
growing medical cannabis for the medical
cannabis cup so that was kind of cool
really good for pain and spasms I'm
going to guess huge High TC high CBD
very low CBN and as you know the
triclone development which we've done
with dry in the past is amazing right
we've been talking about making bubble
for how long it's been too long too long
and here we are it's probably November
since the Cannabis C oh so of course I
brought the finest and this is not uh
this isn't this is so you know just to
go back a little bit when John says he's
growing his own medicine John had a
pretty terrible accident back in 2005
2005 right so John I mean I I'll let him
tell you in a quick three four minute
clip of what happened to him so you
understand that when he says he's
growing his medicine he's not talking
about like uh the odd headache here and
there this is a serious accident that
this man went through so yeah tell them
a little bit about your accident H well
back in 2005 went to work one morning uh
bright and early sunny out like it is
today and uh really excited to get to
work cuz that's what I am a hard worker
and I uh loaded up a scissor lift and
made a wrong step and fell 28 ft on the
concrete and um broke my neck in four
places shatter my armor 50 and it's all
rebuilt I got plates in my neck I got
metal in my back I shattered my ankle
and got some pretty major injuries and
um using recreational Cannabis uh
started using beautiful brownies
actually BC Compassion Club Society
excellent uh I was going WC was paying
for cabs for me to go there three times
a week to buy beautiful brownies nice
it's made by DR Hornby and Paul and
there's some all about decarbo oating
and that's where I started finding out
how Canabis works so well for a medicine
it helped with my spasms tremendously
and over the years uh me published on it
uh W award words on growing for cannabis
and being published on standardized
medical grows about educating about
medicine and and one more step was
actually uh tricomes which you've showed
me over the last little bit yes triome
extraction properly uh use uh well this
is definitely beautiful herb like I'm
not no joke this is uh this is really
nice herb like any thank you man that's
like respect man that's awesome you know
anyone that uh well it just looks
perfect popcorn nuggets dened covered in
resin
we're going to turn this into hash we're
going to make some we're going to Bubble
this oh man I'm stoked oh look at the BC
faer behind us yeah there we go used to
take that over when we were filming
these videos back in the early days in
Mark emy's basement at the pot TV
headquarters that was uh I guess Lo
located in Robert's Creek at the time I
have no idea where yeah that was fun so
all right to take you back to where
we're at right now is we're basically
going
to um we've got an8 bag 5 gallon kit
here you can see these are the bags for
those of you that have never used this
process these are 5 gallon bags they fit
inside a 5 gallon bucket uh the outside
one the purple one here has a 25 micron
screen and then within that I've got a
white bag with a 45 screen I've got a
yellow bag with a 73 Micron into the
black which is 90 one of my favorites uh
the orange 120 and then we're going to
continue to stack the bags for you guys
on camera while we just sort
of chat away I'm sure John's going to
have a tri stick here soon I'm probably
going to have one as well it's uh you
know one of those days out on the boat
the sublimator or the the uh the big
bong with the lighter in the beine it
just becomes more of a pain in the butt
than it's really worth and the triy
stick just makes it so easy for us
medicine on the go we got to uh give
props to amelo for really really you
know getting that cartridge out of the
Trippy Stick was for me what finally
made me like these pens when it was
cartridge only pens I wasn't really a
fan so yeah just overpack m oh it
happens that's okay takes a second yeah
a little fix up I brought a couple too
so just in case we i' be popping on mine
all day I know you were getting some
like I was saying bong siiz rips out of
your Trippy Stick was awesome I'm going
to use the 220 bag even though if you
want to grab the bubble now bag um we're
going to use the bubble now or at least
try the inverter on the boat isn't
really as strong enough to run the 130 W
motor as we thought it would be so there
you go um this is the 220 Micron bag all
of our uh cannabis uh and ice is going
to go inside here then we're going to
fill this up with water top it up fill
this up with like packet full of ice and
then we'll we'll mix it for about well
maybe 5 10
minutes by no means will we throw the
herb away afterwards there'll still be
resin left on it but I'm pretty
efficient in my extraction ratio so most
likely he'll be able to just soak it in
a uh a coconut oil and make some nice
metaal with uh what's left over right so
that'll be perfect we'll make that
happen with the 220 in
here beautiful evening for doing making
bubble I got to say oh you know what
it's we've been kind of trying to get it
done all day and the whole day just not
happened as days happen push back push
back push back but now perfect look at
this yeah I'm pretty excited about this
this timeline that we've got going on so
I guess what I'll do
is get John to put his medic Cush
there and that's about I don't know 150
g or so I think a beautiful popcorn nug
I don't know if they want to show them
if maybe I'll get a little closer here
I'm we'll just show you guys you know
what kind of material we're working with
I don't I know the camera's not going to
sort of fix itself but uh I can throw
that in there yeah let's see if we can't
get that in there we'll get
that I don't like to you know be too
rough with it because uh you want to
make sure yeah I what you're saying I
want to make sure that uh it doesn't
start falling the resin doesn't start
falling out of the 220 M screen really
so we're going to close this we're going
to move actually there you go hit it
right
there all right
so I would usually make my own ice but
today it was kind of a do what you can
sort of day and uh we ended up buying
ice just from the local uh one of the
local
marinas that we were nearby
[Music]
so H that's interesting stereo just
started making sounds let's turn that
off all right there we go oh man like
all of a sudden I heard like weird news
and then I heard some bringing me down
we haven't I'd still put more ice in
this many would kind of think I'm insane
but po ice can the more ice that you can
yeah it's you know not the best ice so
apparently I'd like to crack this on
something that's not the boat oh there's
a
perfect
whoa
excellent still a good chunk right here
so you fill it right up to the top with
ice is what you're saying I like to fill
it up to the top of I oh you know what
you are uh you're guy so I think uh what
are you saying is fill it up to the top
yeah I mean you might as well fill it
right up you can't get enough of that
ice in there really we want as much ice
in there as possible so that's good
we'll get this zipped up there we go and
then uh we have ties that go through the
zipper well that's a smart thing well
you know the zipper has been known to
open up in the uh mixing motion so we
just close it up I designed this bag as
a barrel-shaped bag so it would kind of
fit nice into the uh machine once we get
the water in here you'll see the ice
will melt it'll make a bunch of room for
that herb to start moving
around
nice yeah good fun good
fun walking down to the dog coming in
with a cooler everybody's you can smell
it was funny oh my God you could smell
it you can smell it on the other side of
this island right now what are you
talking
about open up the back of the truck and
everybody looked yeah so here we go
we're going to get this kind of mixed up
mixed in we got beautiful clear water in
here now we did test this a little bit
earlier and we're not going to get the
full power that we're expecting so
basically I'll I would turn this on
generally for maybe 3 to 6 minutes um
you can always run it for as long as you
want afterwards if you want to do it
another mix if you want to beat it
harder whatever but but I'll do like a
6-minute
mix we'll turn that up to 6 minutes and
we'll see if it's going to have the
power to actually spin it I don't think
it is which is no problem cuz we're
going to spin it we're going to help it
we've got a little hey so bubble man
here we uh we had a little bit of a of a
problem the inverter wasn't working for
us so here come some waves crashing
around here what we're doing is we're
we're doing the old school redneck
method we got the uh the
ore and uh we're mixing the medicine up
here we
go if you can see how what color is that
water right now oh God it's like golden
beige golden or is that like a dark kind
of it's nice man I kind want to drink
all right well we've done our mixing
we've got a beautiful color water here
in the bubble now we've got the 8ag 5
gallon bubble bag kit sitting in this uh
nice little uh cubed uh container
usually use a bucket but this is kind of
cool I'm digging it so I like cuz we can
see the C and everything you want to
drain that in there Johnny bubble now
has a nice gravity feed drain you just
lift it up off the top dump it into the
bags and uh look at the color that yeah
I wish you could see the color of this
boy that's nice that's cool all right so
common misconception is that you have to
have the water all the way to the top of
the bags not true uh the water's not
even a third in here right now it's
because there was so much ice and
material in here which we're just going
to leave in there and bring up to the
house uh later for another run cuz uh
well I didn't get it I didn't have the
bubble now I like it to turn on and and
actually work and because we didn't have
the inverter and it wasn't able to work
I had to hand mix it I'm sure we're
going to get top quality but I bet you
there's a little bit of resin left in
those in those nuggets so we'll be
running that again later those nuggets
are full of resin so um at this point um
one thing I I I suggest to people is to
leave the water and the resin combined
for longer than you need to it's easy to
um just kind of get rid of the things
you don't
need and get those bags out of the water
so I'm going to lift up this is a 220
bag so it's not really something that I
would normally collect what I would call
a smokable product out of but uh it's a
big enough bag that it's going to catch
something for certain and uh especially
when you're using uh you know nuggets
like that
we can slide this over right to here
then I don't have to I can actually put
it up here for if you want oh this is
perfect yeah this is great so there's a
little I don't know maybe a half a gram
of some type of what I would call mostly
contaminant but what I would never tell
a customer to throw away you can use it
for baking it's all usable there's
always medicine available there's going
to be some little headies in there not
not many but
some all right so there's
that
um at this
point I do I have to bring this forward
a little bit
more this is just a nice clean water
that I can flip the bags inside out
on and get them clean of all the resin
that's on them immediately this is a
pretty important thing to do with your
bags if you want them to last if you
don't care that if they don't last for
10 years then you don't have to do this
and they'll just work less and less
properly for you and uh yeah I usually
just do that and then hang the bag we'll
get that up here for now to be on a boat
so we can just hang that right there so
that was the 220 bag next up we have the
green bag which is the 190 also really a
bag that I
use to separate out contaminant from the
rest of the bubble but uh lo and behold
not surprised this looks pretty darn
blonde and
delicious not a huge amount there but
definitely a nice little
ball drop that right on
there oh yeah that's
sugary I'm getting excited if now well
look at that wow not a ton but look at
the color yeah look at the color and the
Purity will be what I would say is 99%
hits so normally I don't take the 190
and wash the dirty spoon into the 160
however this is exceptional looking
resin so I'll clean that in there
and I will do the same thing with the
bottom screen from one screen to the
next so we don't have to lose that resin
now because this is resin soaked water
I'll still make my way over to my fresh
water and rinse that bag really
nicely and that's uh I think those we'll
actually take this uh bucket of water
and run it later through the
um through the bags so no resin is
lost all right 220 190 next up the red
bag the
160 it's a little
bumpy a little bit bigger maybe twice
the size of the last one maybe not quite
twice the size I'm never overly uh
excited to see large amounts in these
bags so this you know a yield like that
doesn't disappoint
me for too man look at that getting BL
and bler of course it will look exactly
what look at the three different colors
they're like that's there's going to be
seven all right so we washed our spoon
in our 120 and then we're going to do
the same with our 160 bag flip it inside
out the best you can without getting
resin all over the actual material do a
quick shaky
rinse just real quick
and then back over to our freshh water
that we can really clean off these bags
will last you 10 plus years if you just
take care of them and it's it's really
sad to see how many people don't take
care of their
bags all right here we go inside out and
ready to
hang next upop now we're getting into
the good bags John I know now we got a
120 a 90 73 a 40 and a 25 left so I like
the 73 you like the 73 I do for some
reason it's Wally I think I'm partial
from the 120 all the way down to the 73
so this is much slower yes of course it
is we're going to get a much nicer uh
little blonde color on this one I don't
know what it'll be like for a mount but
this the Purity on this is going to be
beautiful and we'll uh make a point on
taking some uh some nice
photos so we can
uh that's like look at that I I know
it's I got to take wow it's darn near
Perfection that is a um it's just and
that's 120 so camera's probably not
autofocusing for you people at home
which is fine I'll be able to take this
home and get a few
pictures that's exciting that's twice as
much as last time now maybe three times
color that's yeah bubble's real
deceiving you know sometimes you think
oh I got so little but uh but when we
did the the dry SI thing on it we know
that
was I suspect we'll get a
nice return cuz it was such nice
material so continuing to wash each bag
very
important rinse them turn them inside
out stop every once in a while for a
Trippy Stick
H that that ttin we were floating around
in there yeah well now that the seal is
dry see the bone dryness of it yeah that
is some bone dry herb oh look at the
slow water on that one slow water is
always a good
sign means there's something blocking
the
screen oh my goodness that is this is uh
this is your favorite actually on your
face you just see you had a nice
little it's uh not quite as much as the
one 20 but how about that for a
color look how trying to get there go
look at how suy that is yeah it's like
Silk it's going to be really
exceptionally I wasn't expecting to get
a big one out of that anyways I
was go there's more falling off the
leg there we go there we
[Music]
[ __ ] push them back a little bit might
need another SC so they're not touching
well I like to have them all together
to show everyone oh that's and then
we'll go right back into this
one yeah we're going to wash it and the
into the 73 we'll just get that washed
washed away
clean I like that I've never done that
before we're saving monster Hits
just res is just too valuable not to be
saving it on all
levels I think this plant's way too
valuable be sitting well exactly right
all right Johnny's favorite coming
out flowing down flowing down lots of
water in this oh I can
nice yeah yeah it's in there I
don't I'm I'm watching it from this
side just creamy oh it's going to be
cream
creamy
it's getting blunder and blunder and
blunder yeah oh yeah very good very good
very
good back into the
45 what's your take on the 45 you like
the 45 well you know what a lot of
people have a lot of different things to
say about the 45 the 45 is a funny thing
yeah if you let hash snobs know I'll
tell you they don't like it okay when I
tell them the 45 is the 73 or the 90
they love it there's no doubt about it
that it's potent it's not just immature
head there's something going on in in
the 45 it's extremely
oily so there's a high tpine content in
the 45 okay almost always it's really
almost the most accurate generalization
about bubble bags and water extraction
that you can
make and uh yeah I mean it's it's always
a good pull it'll probably be the
biggest pull right now when we pull this
45 yeah look at it it's just covered the
whole look at that oh yeah it's actually
on the side there too oh yeah now this
will be nice little
pull oh my God is it creamy and really
really nice
looking I love how it's all foamy in
there and stuff oh yeah fo
yeah but I've actually never made bubble
from many Crush before so I I've
never how bad that's
um now I'm just going to make sure that
we have all the proper room that we
need bubbles such high quality that
there's absolutely no problem in just
this like's already drying we sure don't
want to let it sit here for much longer
I'll tell you that
much
WoW that's a beautiful 45 that's even
Gander yep going to the 25
and5 I was I it was nice that you
explained the 45 bony I never really
thought about it that way
you I just gave some to a friend as a as
a gift a small amount and he at first
just thought oh he's just giving me
stuff he doesn't like and he went home
and he had a little little smoke on it
and basically couldn't believe it he was
just like wo what was that that you gave
me thought it was 45
yeah there's nothing wrong with 45 it's
not like you're giving you know the 190
away or the 220 there that looks like
just absolute pure now here's a bag that
causes a lot of people problems because
of the screen is so tight it holds the
majority of the water a real easy
process for draining this bag is the
quick lift and then release lift and
release lift and release that's lifting
the resin up off of the bottom of the
screen that's allowing the water to wash
through the screen so a lot of people if
you let this bag just drip it'll
eventually almost
stop I've had people leave it on their
you know the bathroom door knob and 32
hours later it's still dripping into the
uh into the bucket so definitely a good
idea to help this one along take a wh of
that Wow Fresh I've never really stuck
my head in there before Oh man it's
awesome cuz it's cold and fresh and nice
yeah M really nice ni be careful so now
I'll put this down in the towel this
towel is going to uh absorb a lot of
that water it's in it's still in there
want to WRA that towel around
me yeah it drips absorbs right I mean
it's going toor through my skin
so M look at that very nice very
nice all just really really nice looking
resin no complaints on that and you know
what wow that's um that's
impressive 1 2 3 4 5 6 2 four six eight
different colors yep blly you can see
such the difference too love the like
the bubbles in it that's like the it
looks like the moon huh yeah exactly
when people see that that don't really
know they often mistake that for the
honeycomb oil that you know basically
has been purged out and then creates
those Honeycombs this is uh just
water purging out and uh turning into a
nice honey combed bubble of course we're
not going to leave this this is
extremely wet bubble and we're uh we're
still going to break this bubble up
we're not going to be doing it on the
boat we decided we'll uh when we get
back to the house we'll show you how we
uh process the final bit of resin into a
powder and how we get it dry after that
cuz that is a specific process it's very
important process and it's once again
something that a lot of people get
wrong all right and a little bit of
bubble as you can see goes a long long
way Che my
brother well we just made a batch of uh
bubble I don't know how much is there
maybe 10 grams or something hard to say
I think there was easily 10% that was
able to return we should have probably
gotten 15 G so if there is only 10 G
there or eight or whatever it just means
that there's eight more sitting in the
bag for us nice so uh
yeah cheers from British Columbia
hopefully we'll see you at the Kush cup
in the health Expo in Vancouver on uh
what is that the 26th 27th and 28th or
28 299th 30th 28th 29th and 30th we got
kush cup happening as well as uh the
health Expo in Vancouver so you can
check out
kush.com Vancouver 2013 into Google and
find out a little bit of information
about that I'm going to have a booth of
both places so please come see me if you
have any questions John will probably be
happening there as well definitely be
having a meter cada boo yeah for
sure so yeah you know what I've I've uh
actually finally R out
what does that taste it tastes
Divine I was just going to stick my head
in there wow is that nice really nice
it's
cany wow
that's that's really
tasty just wait till we smoke the hash
John just wait until we smoke the
hash this before I end all right so
we're done with that water we've had a
couple of sips and we're just going to
give it back to Mother Nature there's no
more resin in it we've run it all
through the screen so yeah let's get rid
of
it look the fish coming on up those fish
look ripped well we hope to uh see you
all again real soon and uh please leave
some comments or questions if you have
any uh at the bottom of the video here
and uh go check out uh bubble .c
fresh.com and full melt bubble.com for a
community of bubbleheads and dry sifters
sharing our techniques and photos and
there's a chat there as well if you want
to come in sometimes you can catch me in
there and ask me live questions sh I'm
there too you got anything in left to
say Johnny thanks check out meder meter
canada.com medtainer canada.com we're on
Instagram just like uh you are yes my
Instagram as well if you don't know it
is instagram.com slbc bubbleman if
you're checking it on Google otherwise
just BC bubbleman on your
smartphone talk to you soon peace peace
out hey bubble man here we're just uh we
finished making that batch out on the
boat it was a little bit too windy to
think of breaking the bubble up so what
we did was we uh very lightly dabbed it
in the uh pressing screens which come in
the bubble bag kit you get three in a 5
gallon uh in a 5 gallon kit and this is
basically um to gently uh when we take
the the bubble out of the out of the
bags we place it inside the pressing
screen I usually like to do it in a nice
row so I can see all my conss and then I
merely have towel underneath and towel
over top and I I gently dab the water
out now depending on the quality of the
bubble you'll want to leave more water
present for um a quality of resin that
is extremely hot
that resin will self press and bond and
trap moisture in the resin and I think
it's why a lot of the uh people are
using this microplaning technique I find
that um if you've over pressed or over
dabbed or allowed the resin to self
press in any way which we obviously did
because we were out on the boat we had
to leave it in uh in the moist Patty and
then we brought it up and I just froze
it um that resin is at this point not
going to work through the strainer I
usually use a little bit larger of a
strainer than this with even larger
holes and with a spoon I place the Patty
in there and I gently uh push it through
and it basically falls out as a perfect
powder as long as I let it fall very
thinly spread on the
cardboard cuz let's keep in mind this
there's a lot of moisture in this resin
it's completely soak and wet and the
real plan is to get it out in the best
way possible without affecting the resin
so there's a variety of uh schools of
thought on this process uh I'm one of
the old schoolers that just break it up
into powder through the strainer uh
there's no grinding involved so the
heads are completely intact not that I
can't say that the heads aren't intact
when you grind Frozen resin but uh um
well we'll photograph this resin once
we've uh once we've dried it out I'll
photograph it with my macro lens and
I'll see if there's any difference than
the resin I look at that's through here
nonetheless they both work they both do
the job what they're doing is they're
breaking up the bubble into a really
nice spread thin surface area which then
allow
the bubble to properly dry now maybe
down in California and Arizona you can
dry bubble properly like that on on wax
paper or on parchment paper that they're
using but I prefer for the rest of the
world uh especially places where the
moisture content is high in the air uh
that you use a desicant and I just use a
cardboard this is no special cardboard
it's just a double thick corrugated
cardboard um food grade so that it's not
you know soaked in chemicals and
basically
this is the cardboard I use and the
cardboard acts as a desicant uh it pulls
the moisture out of the wet bubble
rather than thinking that it can air dry
I just for years uh dried my bubble
improperly and and couldn't believe how
actually difficult it was to get bubble
to properly dry so I'm not saying one's
better than the other if you use the
micr planer and and you're getting your
bubble dry and it's you know you're a
connoisseur and you know the quality
then that's great and uh otherwise the
strainer works really good as well and
in fact I have the fresh Bubble from uh
yesterday that we ran on the
boat
and so let's see for instance here's the
uh here's the 190 quality just run that
real quick through the through the
microplane and
it'll fall on the cardboard as a nice
powder definitely working good but it
definitely feels like it's grinding up
I'm used to just pushing it through so
this bubbles nice and Frozen I've got it
in cooler here and uh it's amazing that
this 190 actually
looks uh to be a decent quality because
um it well it just never is and by
decent I say absolute crap for a
connoisseur but still something that's
actually smokable by by most
people so that broke it up into a nice
powder I would say that normally because
I'm just doing filming here alone I
would normally use much more cardboard
uh even for a small amount of bubble
like this I would usually probably
spread it throughout this whole section
but I'm going to want to show you uh the
grinding of all the different
grades the microplaning and so I figured
uh that's a real nice White Rock that's
the
160 we'll just run that through there
really nice color pretty much
white there we
go
micr pler cleans quite nice I think the
fact that the resin is Frozen is
key because um yeah it cleans off real
nice even for a high quality resin you
give it one good whack and it's almost
90% clear of of any uh of any resin left
on there so we'll just make sure this
190 is far away from our
120 so what we got
190 160 that's actually a mistake that
first one was from the 220 bag that's
what happened
190 and then we'll put the 160 right
here the 160 looks even better than the
190 did really nice White Rock of bubble
and that of course is due to the fact
that we froze it almost immediately and
when you freeze it
uh well you're not getting any more
degradation you're not getting any
oxidization you're not getting any light
put it in there in a nice dark
container and this is
absolutely
blonde bubble is very
Frozen very
Frozen all right so that's a real nice
color can't wait to get that under the
lens because there's moisture content in
the bubble and it's so sticky that even
with a little bit of wind that I'm
getting back here right now I'm not
overly worried about it we've had a
couple of good wind gusts and uh once
the resin hits the cardboard it's
basically uh it's not going to come off
until it's dry now and because we broken
it up into a nice powder um it will come
off the cardboard nicely I'll show you
when it's dried as long as I don't put
it in some heated space uh it should
come off the cardboard just beautifully
so now we've got the 120 with not a lot
of room to dry it we're probably going
to end up taking some of the 90 space up
cuz this 120 is really
nice just white in
color now I might uh make be making some
of you laugh out there I don't know I'm
not micr planer I've never really uh I
mean I've done this a handful of times
obviously but not to the point where
I've gotten comfortable and come up with
my own techniques with it I'm pretty
comfortable with the
strainer that's how I like to do
it all right so that one 120
literally took up the
rest
of the cardboard so we'll just scratch
out the rest of
those and we'll move on to the next next
one I've got uh obviously the 90 the 73
the 45 and the 25 and I'll basically be
doing the same process over the
cardboard and uh I'll get photos of the
whole uh microscopic process of what's
going on the resin um definitely looks
as though it's been shredded to
me but uh we'll see with the macro lens
in just a little while here thanks for
joining
us give you a quick show of uh this
resin you you see the one in the bottom
corner there that's the actual 220 we
used a 220 bag in the bubble now but a
little bit of contaminant got through
and the tiniest little bit of resin is
actually in there and then the rest of
it is basically almost so blonde that
you can't even see it on the cardboard
but I assure you there's a a fair bit
there all right so this is the
last one the 25 this one's the
45 grab that out of
there and a quick little microp plane
later this bubble is really nice
color
blonde definitely not on my microplane
game here a little bit of little bit of
bumps always running out of cardboard as
almost every Bubblehead does when you're
using this method
all right that's some beautiful 25
micron
wow B on my
fingers it's just starting to get
sticky great looking bubble