[Music]
all right hey welcome to Bubble man's
world I'm here with flab 421 hey
everyone and
today we're kind of celebrating Marcel
braa now other glass blowers were were
involved with these incredible pieces
and and Flav's going to go through them
and explain uh you know some of the
technicalities some of the glass blowers
that were involved and whatnot but uh
generally it's really a Marcel Vibe it
is very much a Marcel there is a lot of
ready lines going on a lot of air trap L
air traps yeah absolutely well why don't
we start by taking a dab of some
beautiful foam out bubble you've got the
Marcel Carlson collab yes this is one of
the crate sets that him and uh Chris did
couple years ago yeah it's beautiful I
got to hit this one in um in Toronto at
treating yourself and it's a beautiful
pipe
yeah real nice little piece yeah the
chip sections that Chris did are lovely
the shaping is really good and honestly
the
hit awesome yeah I was really happy with
this one the the thing about this crate
though that maybe I should even go get
is the Sherlock that it came with
beautiful and very very rare to see a
Carlson Marcel Sherlock I think it's the
only one yeah we'll have I don't know I
can't claim to know but I do believe
it's the only one we'll definitely have
to show that so you got the Dil with the
quartz Bowl on the 14 quartz Bowl set to
840 some nice full melt Hash D
exciting excellent so yeah always a
pleasure to come over and sesh with flab
literally this is right before I kind of
said to him hey how should we set this
up what are we what are we going to say
and he he just says we're just having a
session man this is how we do it
so good quote from the The Humble man
that is flab
421 thank you I I'm always honored of
course to smoke out of any type of
pieces I mean as most of you know
already that are looking at these pieces
some of you may recognize and know these
pieces and for those that don't I can
assure you they're definitely some of uh
some of the most
you know
incredible uh
artistically created and unique glass on
the planet great so very as he's taken a
dab I'll talk about this one this is the
smoke volume two piece that Marcel did
for the book
compilation um when I was talking to him
he sort of described it as as a totem
piece for him because the Phoenix and
the octopus are both very uh close
Animal Spirits for him it's very large
chugs very hard not
necessarily the best for anything but
hash really cuz as you can
hear chug nice chugs crazy excellent so
we love this guy up yeah yeah I'll take
some of this you want this hash oh yes
that was a really nice beautiful full
melt that that bubble man has provided
as you can see it's uh
out it's plenty 150 gram I believe melts
into a lovely
liquid yeah so this is absolutely a
stunner I don't think a lot of people
even realize that the Phoenix is coming
out of the top there it's almost so
subtle the way the wings are holding the
top disc yeah actually I'm give a shot
of the disc cuz it's a giant I'll
photograph it as well and we'll make
sure that we insert pictures as we're
talking about the different parts to the
pipes I'll show some nice close-ups for
you cuz uh that's just always a nice
treat all right torched
up woo she fills up nice that Phoenix
almost right up to the head right up to
the neck that smoke went
beautiful now this one I haven't smoked
I haven't smoked out of this one uh out
of Singularity or out out of uh this is
the buck Marcel yeah Buck Marcel and is
there a name for this one uh just it's
an anger fish oh okay um it was done as
part of the project 33 right at Living
glass works that's beautiful yeah it's
they're all so different these are all
so different you really couldn't have
had like a greater selection of pipes
man this is a beef cake piece I'll tell
you this is quite something to have
someone go and pass this over to you no
it's a heavy it's a heavy chunk of glass
this is generally not pass over at like
concerts when you're just like at a fish
show and you turn around and someone's
like hey did you want to take a hit of
it even though fish 2000 was yeah well
of course that's Marcel right all right
let me
out whoa chugger
yeah and he's a beast
wow love that old school can and how
perfect down
foot well the ready lines are kind of
off the off the chart yeah they're
completely over the top it's like a
ratachello that just continues
on very very nice yeah and I agree with
you the old school can stop the
down like you can see it's grommeted in
like there
is very a lot of difficulty taking the
down stem out You' have to take it all
out out blah blah blah yeah and the down
stem
is about that long I wouldn't want to be
the one charged with that job no no
certainly not excellent and so that's
Marcel's totem piece yeah that's sort of
the way he described it I wouldn't like
claim it as that I wouldn't say it's
like his totem piece just in
conversation with him I like the idea
though cuz it's I mean I've bought of
course Marcel's first two pieces of his
first three from 1999 Marcel 1 and three
and though he only did three pieces that
year and they were all octopus and fish
oriented MH and he kind of kept up and
played along with that octopus theme for
a few more years he did the fish 2000
pipes with the
dolphins and he ended up I think it was
around 01 or
02 hard to remember May when he did the
first goddess piece that was one of I
remember him bringing it over and it was
this beautiful orange and
yellow incredible piece and then yeah
from there on we found him found himself
doing the Phoenix I remember he actually
brought the Phoenix the first Phoenix
piece it was a sculpture a huge
sculpture he brought it to the
degenerate art show that Slinger and I
threw at the M the one that he did on
his own not the one that him and yeah
this was a sculpture a giant huge
sculpture and it had a bowl and it had a
bubbler uh in in the uh in a in sand so
there was a dish yeah this was from
degener R1 this was from degenerate R1
and it was a giant clear Phoenix that
was 5T tall coming up out of the sand it
was completely over the top he drove it
up in his little truck and the crate was
like literally filled the back of his
truck and when he showed up with that
piece I'm telling you when he showed up
with that piece first it was Jason Lee
and hops they sent the motorcycle in
when that piece showed up we all said
okay nothing else has to show up we have
an art show right here oh [ __ ] yeah do
you know what I mean for the time that
it happened and whatnot and hops being
unknown and Jason Lee just being at a
level of you know I mean he's always
been killing it but he was just really
killing it so good and that motorcycle
showed up and we were like okay we're
good to go and then Marcel showed up
with the
crate he blew my mind yeah we're really
good to [ __ ] go how can this not blow
your mind totally yeah well I think we
should move to the buck fish piece yeah
cuz Singularity it's it's very fragile
very difficult we got to have a lot of
open space um as you can see it's a nail
with a
dome and the pipe comes out so we'll
leave this this guy to last this buck
and Marcel piece is absolutely
incredible the first time I saw a photo
of it I want to say it was maybe magido
who had it in his hand but maybe it was
a different one that he had it was a
buck one of these fish yeah no buck is
known for doing doing the fish designs
yeah completely over the top the SK yeah
I mean Buck is is a a just a how
everybody knows absolutely love this
really thin stem that comes into the
mouthpiece and the way you can hold it
with this giant ball is just it's really
quite a comfortable uh comfortable piece
you want to uh yeah load it up and take
the first hit
fantastic um I've been smoking he pieces
for a long time so I have to say I'm
fairly comfortable holding them and
passing them around but there really is
an unsaid etiquette in puffing with
people's headpieces of this level you
really have to be smart you can't be
moving all quick you don't want to be I
mean for instance when I rolled up here
I had my keys I still have them yeah I
wear my keys around my neck well the
first thing I did when I got around this
glass was I took them off my neck and I
put them away any type of a necklace
with a medallion or even those glass
beads sometimes or metal discs like
leaning into a headpiece like this could
really put you in an uncomfortable
situation I've stopped wearing a lot of
last pendants just for that exactly even
what you just did you know just the way
FL put his arm he just put his arm in
between these two pieces to grab a piece
of hash that's fine he owns these pieces
he can do that but to be someone else
and to just think that you can do that
to clip something it's just so the glass
deserves a certain amount of respect it
doesn't mean you have to be like walking
uh you know all super scared and and not
confident you want to have confident
when you hold glass like this but at the
same time you really want to move a
little bit slower than you normally do
such as that's for me this for you all
right good thanks woohoo hitting my
first buck Marcel
collab you know if I could quickly just
go off camera for two seconds I'll go
get the attachment that makes it the
anger fish oh yeah no problem did I see
that next to the uh Maxes yeah yeah it
was next to the max you might as well
bring that little dry Max piece out
too just for fun really beautiful dry
Max piece um held it up to the light and
it was just all amber colored took a few
photos I'll insert it into the video and
then
uh so that's the Ang angler piece oh now
that's awesome this is what Ma this is
one of fish exactly right with the light
that hangs off the front of
it my
God I was looking to see if it was a
dome no yeah wouldn't that be [ __ ]
sick though with a little sliding uh
sliding yeah that would be [ __ ] sick
that is a real special piece of glass
you know you got to give it up to these
guys that are just taking this
constantly to the next level y they've
got Opals and joint spots here and I
noticed that in between the um the two
fins back here the eyes
are ridiculous rello discs
yeah yeah that's uh the color other than
then the the white ready is uh a depe
dark is depe Darkness yeah but um really
nice yeah here I'll take that for you
sure all right nice to actually put it
upside down like that and see the bowl
from that perspective no yeah yeah no
it's cool Max pollen break there's the
little Max yeah let's like a little Max
smoked volume two you know and I mean a
little max if most of you know Max he
doesn't generally make pieces really
small he likes to make some nice big
ones um this one is absolute Beauty U I
held it up to the light I took some
pictures I'll show you guys in the video
it just came out yellowy gold really
nice looking looking piece and it's a
dry pie
pretty large Sherlock like Reef thing
but and which volume smoke is this pce
smoke volume two smoke volume two I have
smoke volume one but it's a it would
take up a large chunk of yeah it's a
much bigger piece heavy
too I I I bet much heavier than any of
the pieces on this table more likely the
weight of that piece and that piece
combined we really should got some beine
yeah I don't hit uh straight hits very
AC like that I have to admit since I got
the
denail and you have the denail you can
pretty much put it in most of these
pieces which is a nice thing to just be
able to like hold out that bowl and
throw it into another 14 piece no it is
yeah it's fantastic actually in uh fit
in pretty much any of these although I
tried it does not fit into Singularity
well Singularity is you know you hit
Singularity how you don't start
modifying a piece like Singularity you
don't we should actually we should we
should hit Singularity sure sure you
want me to roll a couple of dabs so this
section
here is filled with I believe it's a on
gas or but argon Argon gas yes
and when placed
onto the the base it blows up you can
touch it you can move your finger around
it it's like Elric exactly it's like the
ball we'll set it up later on and do a
little video for you yeah but it's
beautiful but the pipe itself is just
this little guy here
it's very beautiful the uh Deo
rainbow yeah that's incredible yes super
beautiful when uh Marcel was talking
about it was something like
35 of these were needed just to get
these three to match um the piece is a
collaboration obviously by delene
Peralta Aon serson Marcel braa and
Robert
Mickelson so all yeah gods of the of the
glass game that's doubled so there's one
on the bottom as well as the
top of the
Dabber
oh I missed that fabulous so you can
take the one on the end and then when
you pass it back to me I'll just pull
that one off and yeah put it on the top
so for sure all right you got it
all really hard just great to hit all
these pieces this is just such a
beautiful piece of glass and I love the
way they created I one of the things
that Flav was didn't really talk about
that all these little pieces all these
little pieces
around each one of them comes off the
piece so I guess if you the piece is
very poetic in my opinion if I can just
give my quick opinion here is to have
every single piece a single a singular
entity to be able to come off and then
come together to create the larger art
form much like any of us has small
individual aspects that come together to
create the single
self I just feel this pipe on such a
different level it is such a true work
of art um it's definitely not your
everyday pipe and even these little all
these little guys yeah that I believe
that was Robert I would say it is it
reminds me of his art for sure uh he
does a lot of that and he does it well
and these are impeccable all these
little guys that go around the base
they're all joining hands and feet and
knees and they're making the pattern of
uh yeah it's just really quite quite an
interesting piece of
glass
oo hit and
Singularity out of all the pieces that I
hit I hit them all dry before I tried
them and this one it it really it grabs
you it's it's a deep oh yeah chubble you
know I was very uh Marcel's doing a has
for
me but he just got back from Europe so
it's going to take some yeah well I'm
definely down with uh you want just heat
it up there and then I'll just that's
pretty
neat what yeah no it's awesome you put
the Dome on there for me too or what did
you get a d l no no
put I do have a dome list that would
work on it but it
just there's something about having
these beautiful rainbow di R ready Ts
that are on it that just make that much
better woohoo well bless
up uh pretty stoked to be hitting
this
sorry
party
wow that's something else yeah it really
is oh look at the little opal right in
the drip at the bottom yeah no there's I
couldn't have even noticed it if my
fingers weren't there it
disappears it's really this is really
truly a beautiful piece of art I mean
they all are truly beautiful pieces of
art
but yeah this one's speci well there you
have it an absolute stunning collection
by anyone's
standard um this one more some of the
nicest
Marcels on the Block
with impeccable artist
collaboration um
yeah I'm almost speechless yeah that
glass truly does speak for
itself it really does there's very
little that we can do to enhance its
quity it's truly deserving of the melty
hash you know you can honestly say like
pieces like this you want people smoking
the absolute nicest possible resins that
they can and very much so it's good to
know that you
are well thank you you know thanks for
having me over FL no dude it's always a
pleasure yeah dude this is great it's so
we're going to definitely have to bring
you're going to have to bring something
along this lines next year for the
legends of hash party uh I think so
we'll literally have a corner I was
going to bring I was actually going to
bring this one like I really was but the
Fab eggs they're just so popular it
would be nice to have line up to the
Hubble bubble and a line up to one of
these epic pieces totally well your your
friend who the owner of of the Hubbly
bubblies is um when he saw the the
mothership piece that I brought he was
very impressed and being a collector of
pipes that are hundreds of years old let
alone he was very impressed with the Fab
bag um I would love to take some of this
out there to show him cuz he's a true oh
yeah historical collect
of he would love to in fact you know
what we'll be sending him the link to
this show so he can watch this he he
likes to be uh unnamed yeah um but he
knows who he is and uh we're thinking
about you and we're uh we're dedicating
this show to you because your Hubbly
bubblies those those pipes and those uh
bowls they're they're special and I feel
honored every year when he when he
brings them to Legends to allow us to to
smoke out of them no it's truly I mean
for me being a a pipe collector it's one
of the highlights of my year um being
able to smoke out of uh we're talking
about the Hubbly Bubbly pipes now of
course yeah Afghani water pipes that are
a few hundred years old they're um made
by the The Afghani man who supposedly
invented the water pipe um to all
historical documented
knowledge so um yeah so to for for
people like me and and other collectors
out there that have collection like
stuff like this to be able to to to Puff
out of Afghani water pipes that are
hundreds of years old it's like pouring
light Bas to the Greek gods with with
high-end 2013 resin oh exactly oh man
totally stuff they were not smoking 400
years ago necessarily yeah no definitely
not definitely
not right are man I'm uh I'm stoked to
have come here we've hit all the pipes
we've shared it with you we're not going
to keep you guys any longer but uh until
next time I'm Bubble Man PL 421 and uh
yeah we'll see you next time oh good
night
all