[Music]
all right
so we're making bubble today here in the
snowy Winter Wonderland of the cotney
we're going to oo that smells really
good we're just going to whip off a
quick batch Ron's setting everything up
with the 20 gon into the bucket to drain
into the tub uh it should be good we're
running watermelon today so we're going
to go get some
snow and we'll be right back all right
so we got to get some snow clean area a
nice clean area snow is generally not
the cleanest stuff even though it might
come across as maybe that it is it's
not you
uh you want to get the cleanest
oh I'm just coming and checking it
out here's Ron's Greenhouse that he
built last year
beautiful you got some big plants going
in there eh yeah right to the roof right
to the roof 18t that's the way to do it
so there's all the little roof balls oh
yeah so where are we thinking go up here
look
yeah head up into the
back the back 40 the back
40 into the snow we go into the sow
there nothing swimming pool you know sow
there you got to be clean looks darn
clean yeah in the
middle I'll take the top layer off you
just take the top layer off exactly
throw that away and the
bottom this is Ron's private snow
collection I didn't know you had a pool
oh I just put it up for the kids last
year oh good
fun
okay go like this
here like that oh that's great
snow say you can't go wrong with that
top
layer take
it buddy what's up buddy what's I can
barely see you in there of a piece of
like a tree a
Lim you know like from the trees and
something fall down the first B catches
all that right yes but we do want to
make sure that this is clean so yeah we
don't want any dirt no dirt at all no
there might be some pine needles that's
okay pine needles aren't as big of a
problem cuz we can separate them out but
tiny little Flex of stone tiny little
bits of dust and sand and stuff it could
potentially sink
so all
right so what we're doing right now is
we're collecting snow to chill our water
it's probably unnecessary because it's
so cold out right now but it's a cool
thing to show you guys that you can use
snow to chill your water you can also
actually make little tiny snow balls and
if you soak these little guys in water
for the short amount of time they turn
into ice
balls so you can get many many many of
these little ice balls in and you can
actually run a batch without ice cubes
we're not going to do that today cuz we
have Cubes but it's something you can
do all right so we're going to take this
snow back and make some Bubble Run you
bet all right be
careful oh Ron yeah what what are all
these here that's just all the stocks
left over for
my oh that's just the last crop he says
eh that's
great did you see how I made this dark
room in the end I saw the dark room's
great yeah great access that's kind of
looks cool with the snow all over
the the
pots grower
supremus beautiful little zone for
making bubble today
rock and roll so I'm going to come over
here and just turn you real quick so
mark C you're the bubble man so I'm
going to ask you things even though I
made bubble half many times I still
think that there's always something to
learn cuz whenever you come here AB I
always catch on to something makes my
life easier absolutely so for this y
cooling up the water we've got a couple
of options what I would normally do I
would put that snow into the water and
then I would filter that water as we
poured into oh nice good idea yeah so if
you want so let's take these bags put
them here for a second put this here
with the water and pour from here sure
and this is store bought ice I would not
normally use this but because we have so
much snow and because the water is going
to be so cold and because it's what we
had access to we're going to make it
work today so if I'm in the way here I
hope I don't walk so we're going to put
the snow into there sure we've left the
water outside for an hour just to get
cold in the temperature of the our cold
is outside yeah so there's the water the
snow going together nice cuz like cuz
like you say Mark the colder the water
the better right
exactly oh I love to get my hands dirty
we just D no I think that's good right
now like look it so what snow what ice
does you can really see it bubbling you
see the bubbles coming out yeah what ice
does in water is it's a thermal reaction
that it actually pulls warmth out of the
water and that's how the ice melts ice
doesn't act add cold to the water it
pulls warmth out of the water and makes
it cold well makes sense when you think
about it's trippy though right so we'll
let this sit just for a few minutes
trippy let's have a Trippy Stick exactly
we'll go Trippy Stick we can we can see
now that the snow is um hey isn't it
always time for a Trippy Stick it's
always time for a triy stick I'll go
grab one one away I just want to pull a
little bit of these you can see that
snow was actually very very clean
compared to most yeah there's a little
bit of pine needles just like you said
there would be Y and because of that
we're going to filter this water
probably through a 25 micron B what a
good idea yeah and let me tell you this
is
cold holy Jesus that's well God was nice
to us though he gave us a cold day but
not a ridiculously cold day we're happy
poror Frost everywhere it's it's really
nice it's very nice okay so um I think
we're going to be okay we're not going
to need much more of that what we are
going to do is we're going to we're
going to use the 5 gon clean bucket okay
and we're going to filter right into the
bubble now okay so I'm going to go get
the bags real quick yes I'm going to go
War my hands we'll be back in a second
everybody
it's awesome it is always trippy time
all right
so just in snow so these this is our
bucket y we're going to be using fits
the bags like a
glove do you want some uh some uh
Sometimes some people they put too much
water in I know it's CU they're big
bubble don't have down much they put the
the the straps for motorcycles you tie
your motorcycles down on here St the
slide that's a hassle though yeah I
don't find that my bags slide too much
when I put them all inside one another
there's really no where for them to go
yeah you know especially if you've done
this process of you know fitting them in
nice now are you going to screen first
and then pardon me are you going to
screen that water first yeah yeah yeah
you're right I want to uh we'll use the
45 it'll be it'll be small enough the 25
will be maybe a little too slow so let
do
that you want to come uh with some
buckets pour it through with ice in it
if yeah yeah it's
yeah sure as we're pouring through I
don't know where you're going bud Oh Oh
I thought this I thought this way stra
no you got to pay attention Okay we're
going into the bucket that bucket is not
going to help us that bucket's going to
help us when we filter everything out
yeah okay
I we are moving quick I actually noticed
when you poured it I was like wow he
poured that really fast I'm surprised it
didn't pull the bag
out all right so is all that going in
yeah you know we're just getting it
filtered that'll probably be good for
now okay let me just get this
out which is basically going to be a
ball of ice yeah now we pour water
through that again it'll make it a
colder one yep leave the bag down there
I'll pour more through it all right here
we
go ready Rock ready to
rock
perfect I
let putting your St into down something
dir so that that is some cold chilled
water
Ron that's the way to go yeah this back
in
here
yeah see it's got a little bit really
not too much negativity in this bag a
little bit of
uh little bit of pine needles but they
came
out it'll just add to the fruity Taste
of the watermelon
exactly exactly
hey is that thing still going
okay okay
so we didn't leave ourselves a ton of
time today so we're going to make sure
out a couple hours I'm going to make
sure yeah I got to fly out
so I spot a
t all right
okay usually I would have these all
organized and in when I'm filming but
sometimes it's nice to watch uh watch
them get placed into the bag the
bucket these are all still inside out
from the last time I was here using them
done our bags 25
4573 next is the
90 they're all color coordinated so
if you don't like the
numbers you can deal with just the
colors all right
so our
okay 20 then we're going to do
one 60 and 190 you know the crazy thing
Mark I want to say is this I you know
I've been an oil maker for years yes and
what a nice proc this this process is
just so much well it's you know we're
not knocking squirrels out yeah exactly
yeah exactly if you want to tell that
story well he's tell the story of
squirrels is whoops I use chlorophyll
chloroform yes uh hard to get we used it
I wanted the very best solv it once I
was a real oil maker and uh and then I
made a stainless steel tub that uh that
the the Chlor the Chlor form and and
produ s in together I put it into the
stainless steel tub had a little uh
heater electric heater underneath the
tub on on blocks the stainless tub had a
2in hose going in this end with blowing
air into it 2 in going out this and
blowing out to get the the chloroform
gone instead of reclaiming it yeah
evaporating it out evaporate out I put
it out in my back driveway Longs had the
hose the exhaust h s can way out and we
came a couple hours later and here's
this little squirrel little chipmunk he
was out he was down and out and gone we
thought we killed him we felt terrible
awful thing for our process so I went
and got the old shovel put him on the
shovel got him on the shovel was bar and
we sat him beside us for a while we had
a hoot and all of a sudden he starts
moving he starts moving he shakes his
head oh he gets how he looks at us he
goes I'm out of here yeah he was freaked
out he's gone he was like where
am I so I think we chloroformed him
unfortunately we did we did all right so
if you want to grab that bag of
watermelon trim I'm very excited today
we're running watermelon that is a Astro
Boy pheno from the TGA genetics crew
subcool in the and gang Jill awesome uh
breeders say what you want about subcool
and TGA but the bottom line is they are
full melt genetics certified every
strain I've ever run from them has been
full melt what's up buddy you coming to
see me you coming to be on camera coming
to make some bubble this is my buddy
Ron's dog buddy you guys have probably
met him already he's a purebred Bouvier
totally cool
dog um so yeah we'll fill this up with
ice throw a little ice in
there it's good to get the ice broken up
it's not going to serve you well to have
the ice all uh you know in one lump now
like I said I'm not usually a fan of
using this this ice but I tell people
look when you can get R perfect rice ice
no problem when you can't you know deal
with it deal with what you can
get don't don't cry about uh that you
don't have the heady ice if you can't
make it it's not going to be the end of
the
world all right buddy we got three big
bags of ice in there we're going to get
the the herb in there soon this is going
to be
good yeah nice and easy have everything
set up for you the bubble now is going
to do the mixing it's going to filter
into the bags and all Ron and I are
really going to have to do is pull the
bags scoop out the hash place it on the
cardboard and clean the bag so I bet you
we get this done in about a half an hour
which be cool I just want the one bag of
watermelon okay that's the okay and
here's the little one water now okay
this is the one I believe I saw I got W
inside that yeah and that's the same
stuff yeah the different that's the
that's the that's the different this is
already the spin Pro and that's the
stuff that's off of trimmer Trace fine
that's fine we can do them both you know
that's the hand trimming yeah that's a
small enough amount we can throw that in
there as well yes yes and then uh here
actually we'll throw this nice and fresh
and nice and Frozen and the smell I
can't even describe to you how good it
is it's like you can't believe believe a
bunch of greenery could smell that good
yes yes you
know
that so you put two bags ice in first I
put three bags of ice in okay three
that's good right all right so throw
this guy in there now another a large
bag of the watermelon going
in now often I would
also that's okay I'll wait for you to
stop so they can hear me yes uh often I
would do a mix when I put this in I
would uh you know put a little ice put a
little leaf put a little ice put a
little leaf I don't have time today this
is a quick rushed batch I'm leaving for
the airport in probably an hour and so
we're going to show you what can be done
on the quick we had too much fun we
didn't get TI time to do work we did so
we can move this around a little bit and
get that fresh frozen trim I wouldn't
suggest doing this with with dry
material because uh well the crystals
will just fall right off the bag all
right let's get this big boy in here on
okay move these other bags oh yeah look
at
that okay
so perfect amount of water we've got in
there um really just a matter of turning
our washing machine on let's give it
about oh I don't know a couple of
minutes
on
all right the water's already changed
color doesn't take long to get that
color
changing you
know nice soft mix on this
batch we're only going to mix for about
minutes and then we'll come back and
we'll filter it through the bubble
bags and we'll make a little bubble what
do you say buddy
want to make some
bubble P up puppy hey buddy is your tail
wagon you're a happy dog are you a happy
dog you're a good
boy good
boy so it's a bit snowy it's always nice
when you get a
little little
snow yeah little bit of snow beautiful
day whipping up some
bubble you got to love it water and ice
doing all the work for us extracting the
glandular Tricom head off of the plant
body prison and isolating them into
seven different Micron sizes I got to
say bubble hash is a good
thing all right so we're
back we're back guys we're uh going to
filter the bags through the bucket we
don't have a ton of time to waste so
this is a real quick simple move click
the button to drain and it drains you
can see the color of the water is gold I
have no no
um no doubts of the quality that this is
going to be now I'm already seeing a
pool of
contaminants we'll make sure we
definitely you know pull that bag up and
really get that screen as flat as we
can there we go that creates a lot more
screen surface area one of the things I
like to talk about is you know a lot of
guys want to know why they can't buy a 5
gallon set of bags with a
220 20 gallon set
now the bags were designed for a certain
amount of herb to release a certain
amount of resin for the screen diameter
for that size of screen when you put too
much resin or too much herb in uh for
such a small screen what happens is the
160 bag starts catching more than it
would normally catch and in doing so it
creates a catch and the 90 and the 73
and some of those better grades they get
caught up in the higher grades we don't
want that to
happen so we use the right size bag for
the right amount I think today we ran
probably less than a kilo really maybe a
kilo and a half wet yeah you know 1,500
G wet so this is about a 200 g 250 to
300 G run and so yeah whenever I'm in
the cies making my bubble hash or dry
sift Buddy's right there next to
me hey
bud what's
this is that the bubble water you got
like bubble oh yeah look at that yah
look he's like oh that bubble water is
making me itchy making me itchy
man good amount of water here I guess we
could start filtering this
too so it's always a nice idea to put a
a tap in on your bucket especially for a
20-gallon bucket although this bucket is
a little shrunk down I'd say it's a
little smaller than your average full
size garbage can still got the same size
of screens we still use the proper
amount of water so
I'm pretty sure we're good to go that's
a nice looking process I bet you film
will look nice the water falling down
there and the water falling down there
yeah you know it is really nice actually
the hose right here let's just give the
old hose you can see a lot of resin on
the bag I used to pull the bags first
well yeah but I want
to I want to shoot all that resin down
yeah
yeah me lift that upway spr
go
perfect little
more like lift it up a little out of the
we can yeah got to squish it like this
when it's tight you always put your
hands in and flatten it out a little
yep right
in all right there we go that's the way
to get it out that out there go I like
to hold it up to
drip
that's an average run for people right
here okay excuse me right you agree M
this would be an average amount for
people to run
yeah all right the water's still very
golden there you want to hold that want
to show the folks at home what we're
dealing with up close
here so we still got a very gold water
we've got the pump
on
[Music]
uh on yet no might be a little clog here
all right so we had a little kink in our
hose she's draining nicely
[Music]
now I get a little Shake around not yet
please okay that's okay it's just
looking real nice it's it it went from
yellow to White I really like that
shot that is
nice all right so let's give it a little
more hose water you got it clean up that
last little bit of resin the stuff is a
nice little spray so it's not crazy mhm
for sure it's more likely to clean it
properly
too the hair down
there got the hair
[Music]
out
okay all right so we're good there you
can turn the drain off I don't know if
you're on but I like sometimes go like
this here yeah I'm on like that yeah
give it a little lift and get that last
little bit out sure it's nice and clear
water too that's a good sign okay I like
that water to be coming out clear
towards the end once you filtered okay
and our tap is still
uh still
running okay so we got everything
drained it's in the bucket we've got our
water and our res sitting here Mo you
know we we got rid of at least a couple
of gallons oh yeah easily like uh five
full gallons of water in there which
means we only have about 10 plus left in
here what we can start doing now is we
can start pulling these
bags
so um we're going to do I want to show
people the process
Ron that's not no it's fine if you want
to grab your spray bottle you
can
you just got to get back in the camera
view yeah I'm going to move the camera
off the tripod while you do this okay
okay
so this is a simple process that you can
do with a little spray bottle and you
can clean the bag by literally going all
around the top edges spraying everything
down into the
bucket that spray is here can I just do
this real fast all right so we're using
the hose to clean the top of the bag
we were going to use a sprayer but his
sprayer was just next to useless so
we'll just use all you need is a little
tiny bit of forced water and
uh you can do this real fast let's just
say there we
[Music]
go so there's the hose cleaning
everything into the middle just gives us
a nice Easy Pile to clean out if you
want to pull that out with a spoon R
Yep this is just a two 20 bag so really
this is just pretty much
mulch yeah just throw that on the old
screen
[Applause]
there okay so right off the bat I would
I here's a great thing to show you guys
CU what Ron did here is what you don't
ever want to do you want to keep your
resin organized and in place so what
happens when we come and grab the next
resin where are we going to put it are
we going to throw it over here and then
one over here and one over here and one
over there there's going to be no order
and people aren't going to know what
they have so what I have always done is
I've always started first of all it's a
sandwich it's cut right down the middle
and it folds so this is the half we're
going to use and we're going to start by
putting our 220 right up at the top and
we're going to put our 190 here and our
160 here and at the end we'll have a
nice row of our different hashes and
we'll be able to close the pressing
screen over top of it and remove some of
that moisture so let's get on with that
real quick all right so Ron's now going
to rinse out the 220 bag that we just um
cleaned um because it's the 220 bag we
didn't have to clean it a huge
amount um it's a contaminant bag and we
already used the 220 bag inside the
bubble now so it's okay to just flip it
inside out as Ron's doing here and rinse
it off into a bucket somewhere with a
nice uh Cold Water Rinse make sure you
clean the screen well with cold water
and then hang that screen or bag he's
got a nice line right here we're just
going to hang the bags right away cuz
it's very important not to put your bags
away wet very very
important you never want a buildup of
the of the of the car another little tip
here as I'm pulling this 160 bag out
there was a lot of resin on the tops of
the screens and I could have pulled the
bag out but what I did was I dropped it
back in and I let that resin cool
towards the center it'll just give us
less amount of time that we have to work
with the hose or the spray bottle we
have a spray bottle it's just not a very
good one you do want a spray bottle with
a bit of of pressure something that
actually you know will give you a good
amount of of pressure so you can move
the resin around and get it get it where
you want it that's a good amount of
pressure yeah pulling the resin right
into the center perfect Ron and then
also sometimes if there's contaminant in
the resin I don't see this as often but
I've heard a few different people talk
about it as a tip so I'll share it with
you guys that you can use this to sort
of of wash the resin over the screen
some people are doing that I personally
don't like to expose the resin to more
water than it needs to be because
especially forced water will leech out
water soluble Tes but um definitely this
is a great idea just to pull the resin
into the middle of the screen you can
see how easy that made it for him
perfect Ron right under that 220 as
close as you can get it without touching
and uh we'll pull the next bag for it
bud so this one is the 160 this is
generally when you're using nice
material like the
watermelon um that you'll start seeing
an actual smokable product that's not to
say you're going to see that with every
strain it's just not the case but you
definitely will see it with
waterm now you could also have this
little bucket here that I'm using you
could have it on a stand it could easily
be on upside down on a bucket and be
higher for me so I don't have to do all
this bending down but uh
we're just setting this up makeshift
today it's not super super
duper important to get everything set up
exactly perfect cuz it's nice to know
with bubble that you can actually whip
off a batch and still literally make an
amazing quality
product with uh you know a little corner
cut here and there like oh we used
floridated ice oops well we had to um
but we did use the snow um this bucket
is actually full of snow right now and
it's kind of neat because it's making a
really cold area for me to collect the
bubble out of perfect oh that's great a
little bit of a little bit of water
that's
good that's very
good ready to clean yeah you can put
that inside now Mark you taught me a
long time ago about now when we I get to
the B bags yes rinsing those into the
back into the uh through through the
system you know I wouldn't I wouldn't
put this personally into the the 90 but
I would definitely put it into the 120
so yeah rinse it inside out in here yeah
this is why why throw it away right yeah
you can even do this you don't even need
to do that you just
dip now the resin's gone and now you
rinse the bag with the cold water
perfect and I'll pull the
120 oh man this bag does not want to
work
off oh the heada cop does it would have
been a time in the past where we would
have run away but not
today nice release of the water in an
instant by just lifting the bag allowing
the resin to lift and allowing the water
to rush through nice and quick nice
which nice return on that I love that
put this snow down a bit more I love the
snow in here do you yeah it's making a
nice cold atmosphere and you know of
course bubble loves the cold you don't
need to have a warm warm environment
when you're making bubble hash that is
for
sure how's that for a yield run nice
that's good yeah but we've got a little
problem what well we've got air in the
bag because it's so tight okay and the
air won't come out so you see how it
won't let the bag you see what it's
doing that's air okay so got the air
yeah we got to lift it up unfold
it oh that what a yield that a little
bit of run let's show him with the
camera
wow cuz that's a nice
pull there we go that is a nice pull a
nice color oh yeah it's going to be
beautiful excellent you want to spray
that up a bit you you
bet great way to clean the bag
efficiently
excellent all right that's perfect we'll
let that settle the water a tiny bit
yeah as you do that you'll actually pull
water out yeah you can use the air yeah
there we go to pull the water out look
at the little bit of green on the edge
there yeah almost like a little bit of
leftover chlorophyll or
something very nice all right scoop it
out
okay oh that's thick yeah it's thick
that's you know that's like 10
G easily and we didn't put much in
that's funny thing full bag I get big
bigger yields out of my 20 gallons when
I put like a kilo of dry
in tiny Ting of green I know we'll see
go away this is going to be golden well
I know the material too though so all
right that's perfect you can flip that
and put that last little bit of resin
get it exactly and your spoon as well
okay you have my spoon as well yeah you
don't want to leave that just to dry
okay yeah cuz that's hard it's raw hard
just a little rinse like that yeah just
a quick little rinse like that is all
you need that's a nice touch to tell
tell people I'll tell you absolutely
awesome you want some help lifting that
oh no we don't need to hose it right cuz
we're rinsing it right we're rinsing it
exactly okay I got it perfect you want
to get it inside out though not right
side out I usually put my hand on the
bottom yeah and push and just sort of I
close it so when I push P it up I'm not
pushing the resin onto the side walls of
the bag okay so when I grab it I kind of
close it up perfect yeah nice
rinse excellent Ron is a great helper
he's very eager to do things the way you
ask him to do them good job Ron well
people have to learn the right way right
well it's important right all right so
we'll rinse that off I was by J and I'll
get to the next
bag all right here we go
okay so Ron's cleaning the 120 bag I'm
going to pull the 90 bag this is going
to be old this is going to be a good bag
I can feel it it's also very heavy it's
got about two two full gallons of water
in it and you see how slow it's draining
watch how fast I can make it
drain does that knock any of the glasss
through the screens that you might no
the glands aren't going to be pushed
through a screen that's too small for
them to go through I mean even the
pressure of lifting the bag out of the
water and that 20 gallons of water
pushing through the bottom of the screen
has to be way more pressure than these
little shakes okay perfect yeah all I
know is there's always great resin on my
90u bag shake it you w't break it shake
it you shake it
990u all right this is exciting I love
pulling the 90 when it looks
lovely
beautiful perfect let it pull right into
the middle there okay got get a little
slower for a second we'll just let it
kind of
drain little
tight just for the
picture
my fingers
there looks
good all right you want to scoop it out
with the spoon you
bet so there's another 6 to 8 gr
there can't wait for the yellow bag I
love the yellow bag I don't know why but
maybe a little less maybe four it's hard
to say it's thick isn't it yeah it is
very thick very thick oh yeah it is a
thicky
nice maneuver well done and with the
hand I'll go up to the other side now up
there yep if you're all filled up we can
use the other pressing screen as a
sandwich to put right over top of it oh
perfect
beautiful get a little shot here of
water yeah we can rinse that out there's
a lot of 90 there but it's just going
into the
73 if you want to pick that up though
you can put it with the 90 I'll just
last enough that's for
sure I just had a really good idea that
I want to share with you guys what if we
were to have a tiny little compressor
that sucks air in the bottom of a
special bucket designed to place the
bags into you put the bags in you
tighten the screen and then you turn the
little air pressure on and it sucks
water it sucks air out of the bucket run
can you see what I'm saying you know
when we put the the bucket down the bag
over the bucket how it creates these air
pockets what if you had a little hole in
here with an air pump not pumping air
but sucking one it's the valve like a
sealer I don't it needs to suck air Ron
you understand it needs to suck the air
out of the hash you see that movement
there uh I think this might be a good
idea stay tuned for potential new new
bubble invention I like the
idea do you see what I'm saying though
you know when we put the bag over top of
the bucket and we push it down you know
how it sucks the air and the hash gets
like perfect for pulling off the screen
I would like to create a little product
like
that
awesome done deal not done till the bags
are clean yeah you want to make your
bags last forever hey it looks so good
the way you've hung the bags too the
black one's going to go there yeah and
then the 90 oh this is real
nice in case you guys haven't noticed
yet Ron is a quality
guy and a hard worker I'm very happy to
be spending time with him here and
getting to play with his resin and
getting to wash and dry sift the the
buds and just hanging out with all the
great people here in the cies it's been
a great trip I'm really uh can't wait to
get back that's for
sure
little bit of a green tinge but I know
it's going to come out these two pieces
here especially are going to be very
golden sometimes when you w wash fresh
material um you'll release a little bit
of chlorophyll I'm not going to say that
it's water soluble but it it does come
out somehow into the water and it some
I've seen it in the hash and then the
hash dries and it seems to disappear
with the moisture that's in the hash so
it's the color is actually in the water
not the hash and we'll show you that
later with uh photographic
evidence want to pull that 73 U bag yeah
should we do it this is your bag Ron why
why shouldn't you be the one to pull it
I love this
bag
beautiful yeah check it out check it out
if you just
go yeah nice e well that sure makes me
feel better it's gentler
boom all right we can take that over to
the
bucket yeah i' shave these handles off
for future reference for a bubble bucket
yeah be perfect okay
bag would go over it's that's what the
bag's getting tight on actually okay
yeah you're right here we go there we go
like that idea now imagine I had a
little pump that sucked air from the
bottom of this bag and and you just saw
these bubbles disappear in an
instant
he knows how good our hoodies are our
hoodlums are working for how warm we are
oh I know I'm actually really warm right
now for me and the cies all winter long
this one jacket it's definitely below
zero yeah and this is this jacket is I
just love it that's want to say that I'm
sorry I just got my new one too and I
got to say I am digging it yeah they
rock all right so give that a scoop
there
on scoopity
dupies M fudy you know what I've noticed
about every single of the last three
bags what they are thick
yeah this is really what you want to see
when you make bubs you know like I said
this isn't a gigantic batch by anyone
means but we put probably less than
1,500 G of dry of wet material in so you
got to think that that's about 300 G of
dry so yeah we should get a
good you know
20 15 to 20
G you know as the guy that makes this
prod though I I don't usually look at
the volume I get I look at I like the
quality of course it's the only interest
I have as well this but this thing I
hate when you're a good grower you don't
mind but the bags really show the
quality of the grower cuz how if I did a
terrible job on my on my on my product
it comes out right here this that's
that's exactly grower this is our test
that's the truest truest thing you could
say you know I say it a lot but because
I'm not a a big grower I don't think
people hear it as much but when you just
set it there that's a very accurate
statement the bags are the of God when
it comes to the quality of your resin
tell you how how good a job you did and
how good your strain is how how good
your choice is on what you're growing
yeah
perfect okay to rinse the spoon over
here yeah rinse it out in the bucket
nice no nothing's going to dry up like
that there there's a non-rinse
spoon oh yeah exactly right so uh keep
your spoons R great idea thanks for that
pit Mar get that 45 bag full this is one
of the bags people tend to have a bit of
a hard time with it tends to hold a
little bit more of the water but as you
just saw me drain it in about 5
Seconds it can be done without side
walls of mesh and without um you know
big
Loops I don't think people are draining
their bags with a bucket you know this
is just a couple of gallons of water
that you have to deal with with not 20
full gallons of water if you do it right
so we've always found
it oh here we
go
okay you want to give a little spray on
that one or
yeah
little snowflakes coming out in the sky
com going in there
beautiful so this is our 45 Micron bag
often a decent
yielder um always creamy resin uh very
oily usually the first one to catch
flame when you're smoking
it and uh you know for whatever reason
it's never really a favorite yet it is a
sellable product it is a product that
you see dispensaries and such but
generally in the world of the head stash
the 45 is not the one you'd pull out to
brag to about with your friends still a
beautiful looking product that'll take a
few seconds for the water to drain out
just because it is the tighter bag you
can kind of give it a little bit of a
shake yeah a little shake shake shake
shake shake shake little shimmy you know
just to move that water to a new area
because it's making a dam where the
house is so thick in there the water
can't get through it the 25 and the 45
always do that so you got to help the
water move around away from the down yep
so if you want to give that a
shot if you want to pull that out with
the spoon there
yeah I think it's good now you ready to
go there
yeah look at that that's
thick yeah that looks very thick all
bubbles thick
but now you mentioned the different
screens is it not have I not heard you
in the past say that different types of
pot give different yields and different
screens absolutely but you know what it
is an extreme thing for the majority of
the part if you're growing
indoor you're going to see most things
in between the 120 and the
45 what I've noticed is tropical grown
outdoor sativas that are pure
sativas their heads are extremely small
and you'll usually get the nicest ones
and the most out of the 25 and the 45
okay but that's a tropical grown like
Australian 20 weeks sativa
I haven't seen that as much with
hybridized sativas that are grown
indoors oh beautiful piles here that
we've pulled out for our little day of
bubble making before I jump on a
plane good job good
job I guess we'll just pull this one out
and rinse it in the uh 25 y spoon first
very tight the spoon in the bag can be
done simultaneously I find when I'm
doing the process it's just quick I
usually do my bag and my spoon literally
at the same time and then we can just
pull this out yeah there we
go this is a very important process of
saving your resin glands and you want to
be careful when you do it yeah don't hit
sides you don't want to hit the sides
what I would have done is I would have
squeezed the whole screen in my hand
from the bottom and when I lifted It Up
Inside Out the whole entire screen all
the resin would be crumpled in my hand
and then I would you know push it into
the water that way and that way it uh
just ensures that you're not going to
push those resin glands onto the sides
of the bags and that you're going to
clean them off now that is tarpine Rich
water with 25 micron heads floating
around so you do still want to take it
the bag and rinse it with uh your your
your clean water out of the
H and we're pretty blessed to be doing
this today in a really nice snowy
environment it's actually snowing right
now it is a beautiful snowflake very
light
perfect hey you want me to hang the
yellow one yeah right over here yeah you
got it yeah you a lot of times in the
summertime when I'm doing this these
bags will all be on the on the on the
line yes I love when they're on the line
and when the planes come over I think
they must see all these different colors
think I'm some kind of quite a
show good video this going to be a great
video okay finally the 25 micron bag the
bag that gives people the most problem
the bag that people say I don't even use
that bag it's so difficult and hard this
bag can pay for all your bags if you've
got a four bag kit this bag can pay for
them and buy you four more bags this is
a worthwhile bag to keep even if you're
using it for medibles whatever the
purpose is it's always worth keeping so
I'll show you I can do it I want to show
them the quick quick
release and you make these bags good
enough they won't bust oh exactly and
this isn't like hundreds of pounds of
water I'm not uh Superman by any means
you know and if you're if you're in a
situation where you can't lift this bag
I always suggest get someone to help you
it's worth
having it's a worth worthwhile bag
having and now you see the water is
released we could have built a little
cage a small little cage around the
bottom inside of this and that would
have kept the bag from sealing around it
and it's it would have released more
water but this is this is makes shifting
quick and good so we're not
complaining 25 micron is about the only
bag I do that to I'll give it a little
bit of a squeeze get some of that excess
water
out
um yeah you hear a lot of funny things
that people say online about damaging
the glands and this that and the other
but let's not use the water right away
let's use a spoon the 25 micron is so so
slow to drain and it's so easy to clean
for whatever reason these small heads
you see how they clean off the bag yeah
like nicer than you see how clean that
is almost like the hose did it oh yeah
yeah yeah and so if we put too much
water into here what'll happen is it'll
just never drain and we'll need a
pressing screen the size of this bag to
um to to fit the hash on to even right
now it's bubbled up and I'd say most of
what is there right
now
is is uh bubbles here we'll show
you so there's a pile of 25
micron and you can see the bubbles
popping um probably not even a bad idea
to leave this for a few
minutes um what we're going to do now is
we're going to take this we'll place
this over top of
this we'll get some paper towel or a a a
cloth we'll put it under and on top of
this and we'll gently press some of the
water out we're going to be doing a
strainer process today um Ron's got the
strainer stainless steel strainer little
guy and I'll push this through and put
it out on cardboard as quick and
efficiently as I can um because we're
doing that we don't want to leave this
bubble to sit too long because we're
outside we have an advantage um it is
kind of like being in the fridge or
whatever but um at the the same time you
don't want to you know let it sit for
too long before you strain in particular
it's you can leave it sit as long as you
want if you're going to microplane but
straining is a different story this
stuff will self press and you won't be
able to push it through a strainer so
we'll get to that
[Applause]
next all right so we've got our resin
here our 25 micron is still sitting out
in the bag which is fine it's uh out in
the cold weather we've got the towel
underneath and we've got the towel over
top we've got our strainers a little one
and a big one and a variety of spoons
that we'll be able to use inside the
strainer to allow it to to fall properly
so I've also got um this is helpful
cardboard with all the numbers written
on it already 160 120 90 73 and 45 and I
have uh some other cardboards here as
well with more numbers on them so
it's pretty important even though you
might think you know what's going on to
mark down the resins like I was saying
to Ron earlier when he had put the the
220 right in the middle if we had all of
these you know sure an expert hash maker
should pretty much be able I could tell
you which one the 45 is the 73 and the
90 would be pretty easy to hone in it
wouldn't be impossible but let's just be
organized and and do this the proper way
so we're going to do straining today
we're not going to do microplaning
microplaning is a process where I freeze
these after removing a lot of the moist
moisture either letting it Wick just
like this freeze them and then microplan
them over the cardboard we're going to
do stainless uh strainer today and I'm
going to just clean this out a tiny bit
cuz it's still dirty from the last time
I used it giving it a little whack like
that will literally clean 95% of the
resin out of it that's why I like the
strainers it's nice like that so this is
pretty high quality resin you kind of
have to know with straining how what
quality the resin you're working with if
you're working with an extremely high
quality res and you press down really
hard it's bonded you're never going to
push it through a strainer you might as
well throw that stuff in the uh in the
freezer and microplan it so I'm going to
be um pretty gentle you can see there
these patties here have now dried out a
tiny bit pretty much for straining I
don't want them to be much drier than
that I know the quality of this
watermelon I know the quality of subcool
and his strains the TGA crew they don't
mess around um those guys produce full
melt genetics you know know certified by
me the bubble man um yeah so let's let's
do this we've got our strains here I can
kind of lift it up a little bit for you
220 190 160 120 90 73 and 45 so we're
going to take these for starters now the
220 it's it's nothing it's not even a
product so I mean literally I'll just
put it up here in the corner of the 160
I I won't push that through the strainer
I don't want that on the strainer
contaminating my uh my final product and
nor do I want uh the 190 uh they'll both
be cooked into metaal most likely so
those can just sit right there on top of
the screen or on top of the cardboard
this is the first one I'll actually do
and I suggest when you do this that you
use a separate strainer for your lower
grades as opposed to your higher
grade so clean that out we're going to
take our 160 now place it in our
stainless strain strainer and literally
just grind it through you know not
grinding it harsh but just nice and
gently and you can can see it just Falls
as
powder and uh I'll get Ron to do a few
of these later and I'll actually film it
closer so you can see what I'm talking
about of allowing it to spread thin and
so as you get to the end when you think
that you just have all this hash stuck
in your strainer you just come over to
the other side and kind of give it a
little shave and give it a little
[Music]
whack and everything comes off of your
strainer so there's our 160 done our 220
and our 190 are sitting there undone I'm
going to take this strainer and this
spoon and put it over here because it
has a lower quality resin and because we
want to be obsessive about this let's
think about it we grew this cannabis for
3 months we made variables of choosing
phenotypes growing it under extreme
conditions from controlling everything
in doors to trying to control bugs and
powdery Milos maybe you're in a
greenhouse and you need to add extra
light because it's not sunny enough and
you need to there's so many variables
that happen along the lines and then you
get to the point where you trim it and
that's a variable and how you maintain
the trim and what you do with the trim
and taking the trim and finally washing
it not leaving it in the water too long
doing all the steps properly getting to
this point this to me in my opinion is
the only thing the water hash maker is
doing right the ice mixing is popcorn
and anyone can do it it's it's it's
water and ice is doing the whole job for
you so please don't take credit for that
the grower has grown great resin for you
so please don't take credit for that
what you can take credit for is doing
this properly doing this process
properly is extremely important and uh
you'll be rewarded when you do so this
120 that we have is huge so I think I'm
going to put it on the 120 and the 45
it's a very big piece piece of of uh of
120 so we'll get that right into the
into the
strainer you can just put it all at once
nice little pile there and then
we'll want to move this out of the way a
little bit cuz actually I think yeah I'm
going to go 120 I might even do 120 45
and 73 this is so big I might do the
whole and you can see how it comes out
you want it to spread thin you don't
want it to be get and all thick and
that's why you need a lot of space for
the cardboard a lot of people do this
wrong they Clump it all up this hash
needs surface area once it has the
proper surface
area the cardboard is going to do its
job which is to Wick the moisture out of
the
hash very important process it's why so
many people that are that turned off a
water hash because a it was never dried
properly or B it was you know made
incorrectly little things little
variables like um not leaving it in the
water for an hour so the card filled up
there I'm not sure where I got caught up
I was tapping the 120 Micron we've now
moved into the um 90 Micron beautiful
beautiful nice fatty little Patty of
just absolute blonde goodness we're
going to get that out on the 90 here the
strainer just works so good I got to say
like I prefer this over uh the
microplaning every every time it's just
so easy you've watched the videos of the
microplaning and the grinding of it it's
just I mean I don't do it a ton so I'm
not pretending to be the the you know
the expert micr planer but I definitely
definitely prefer
this that's just clean and easy I don't
have a drop of resin on my fingers I get
all the resin off of the
um off the
strainer even though you can see the
there is a little bit of a buildup there
from someone not cleaning it you can get
it all off if you require it okay so get
over to this 70 Micron
here 70 can go right into that same one
and we'll see what we got for
70 all right I managed to save some room
on
that so we'll be able to do our
45 and still make room for it because
I'm not sure if you guys remember at the
video there I actually put the
120 on the 45 and that's important that
I Mark that down that these two are 120s
now and as well that I mark this
down that uh I don't know if there's a
pen around but I'll make sure that I do
that because I don't want my resins all
mixed up once again 45 I could guarantee
tell I can always tell when it's the 45
it has a very particular taste almost
regardless of the strain
it's always very
oily all right so there we have
it you can see that it's really not as
difficult as some people might make it
out to be you've got
your cardboard resin 160 120 90 73 and
45 all beautifully spread all right just
wanted to show you guys we didn't forget
about the 25 micron although we did put
it at the 90 we'll have to change that
here's the 25 Micron out on the screen
getting ready to drve this is um easy to
move in my opinion cardboards light I
can go now and put it in the room where
it's going to be drying and it's just
going to stay away from dust debris hair
everything um we'll probably take one of
the one uh 100 Micron screens the four
the framed 2x4 ft frames I have and
we'll flip it over top of this so
nothing can fall on top all right so
here we have some of our dry sift
cleaning that's just that I cleaned
out now under here we have our bubble
just sitting out on cardboard it's you
know sometimes I would have it more
enclosed in um like I like to put it in
pizza boxes and have them closed this is
fine no one comes in this room um I'll
probably even seal this up like that
just a little bit more cover so the hash
isn't exposed this dry sift I don't care
about it's talcum powder it's stuff I've
already cleaned out the heads from and
uh so yeah I'd say we got a good 15 to
20 G here and I'll be back to show you
that when it dries I got to go get on a
plane right now so hopefully Ron comes
and sees me soon otherwise we'll have to
photograph this when I come back CIA for
now so um I think that's pretty much it
we'll catch up with you guys later when
this is all dried I'll end up getting
macro photographs of it and melt shots
but for now I just want to give a huge
thanks to Ron for having us out here I
want to get the picture just to say this
you guys if Mark was seems at all fast
what he's doing he's on a plane in the
next 10 minutes we got to get him on icy
roads into the airport and on a plane so
he did that rock and
roll cool we'll see you guys later on
Bubble man's
world literally minutes away from
leaving to the airport I can't believe
you did a bubble ride we what are you
talking about you almost everything hey
to let everybody know might want to know
how long did it take you to do the whole
run we'll answer that
question 3 days no no no no the
R 3
days 3 days of party and had
Dr oh that pbell dri is the right on let
me hit you with
that well it was a great visit Mar it
was a great visit Ron really a great
visit cheers dude Merry
Christmas oh yeah one thing I love about
great dry is you can have the most
valuable puree headed dry sip just
sitting in your hand and coughing like a
mofo and it's not going to move you know
the dry sift it's when it's pure heads
it's a clump even in powder form really
have to break it through how does that
taste have a seat cuz you're out of the
out of the you stick your head right out
of the
camera all right so here we go very very
nice hit i c do two I can okay here you
go I'm bring it closer to you yes here
we'll just that in there I'm then to get
this in
here the
Dil that's on the
[Music]
Mothership
s Francisco
B that was the one the one the one
that's trying to cross my eyes here
let's give you another special one okay
look at how easy it t twisted my Rubber
Arm go ahead what's
going watch how we can melt that out by
just putting the carb cap on
yeah look at that
boom can't say enough about the carb cap
although I have to say that I think
glass blowers should probably start
designing little things like this
because I know this is a k9 tube and
it's you know $100 plus dollars but I'll
tell you it makes a great carb cap
really increases the hit saves saves a
the day for the guy that hasn't got the
big lungs too slow it slows everything
right down nice thing exactly man I've
had such a great tra trip it's just been
great Ron like once again so good to see
you brother it's been uh you know we've
been dry sifting we've been wet washing
we've gone to Hot Springs I've seen
friends that I haven't seen in years um
got to make some bubble with snow you
got to love the cies if you guys have
never been to the cies I suggest making
a trip out coming and checking out
Nelson all the surrounding areas like
winlaw and caslo and Proctor these are
all cool little places where you can
meet unreal people like Ron
so thanks for watching and uh stay tuned
for more Adventures from bubble man I
don't know where we're going to be next
but it'll be cool peace out everybody
peace
byebye