hey bubbleman here today to talk to you
about fresh headies brand new product
called the bubble bags light the bubble
bags light is a reply to the marketplace
being created around the high end
original bubble bags which all speak to
you a little bit about later which are
pretty much one of the highest grade
levels of extractors that you can
purchase warranty lifetime and parachute
throughout the whole nine yards we
created a fairly expensive product that
not everyone was able to afford into so
it created a marketplace where a lot of
companies were selling cheaper inferior
bags and unfortunately in the corners
that they cut to get those cheaper
prices the effects were felt by the end
user in the lack of quality in the lack
of potential workability or usage
sometimes the bag straight-up didn't
work sometimes the screens were the
wrong in the wrong order sometimes the
materials used were extremely cheap and
threads came up apart and other things
came apart so you basically ended up
with a product that you are not inspired
about and so bubble bags light is a
reply to that or reply to the
marketplace that's been created around
the higher-end bubble bags original in
order to release a product that the end
user can afford first of all and be able
to get into the world of water
extraction get into trying in and
experimenting with it without breaking
the bank so today I want to talk to you
first of all about the five gallon eight
bag kits if you're familiar with bubble
bags we sell generally eight bag kits in
all our sizes which are one gallon five
gallon and twenty gallon they all come
with eight bags but we also do for bag
kits we've discontinued our threes but
we sell individual bags so you can make
any kit that you want so back to these
bubble bag lights five gallon one of the
first things I did right off the bat I
can show you have an original set of
bubble bags here this is a little bit of
a more expensive fabric material it's
softer and thicker this is quite a bit
thinner so right off the bat I thought
what a great way to cut costs
I'm still making a carry case still
allowed to hold the bags and so you can
carry it but cut the costs it won't
affect the quality of the end product
that is being used to make the with
these bags so that was step one step two
which was a fairly big step if you're
familiar with the original bubble bags
there's eight colors we got them right
here the originals blue the two 20
micron bag the green 190 bag the red 160
micron bag the orange one 20 micron bag
the black 90 micron bag the yellow 73
the white 45 and the purple 25 micron
fairly expensive to buy cloth for all
those colors to the fairly exhaustive
investment and I was able to cut some
corners and save a little bit of money
by with the bubble bag lights I also the
main reason I did this I was able to cut
the colors down and only release three
colors so these particular the lights
are always going to be red white and
blue and those three colors in eight
bags will still represent these original
colors and how I did that was if you
notice the work bag is a 220 and you can
open it up this one's actually inside
out right now I was using it there's a
band on the bottom of each bag and the
threat as well you probably can't see it
but I have photos of this the thread is
blue and the band on the bottom of the
bag is also glue so this blue band
signifies the original work bag which I
just showed you in the original bubble
bags which is a 2 20 micron so that's
our 2 20 bag we move into
the next bag is a white bag the next
four bags are going to be white that's
going to be the 190 through to the 90
micron and each one is going to have
that same original piping of the
original color so the 190 original bag
is green green piping green threading or
red for the 160 orange for the 120 black
for the 90 and so on into the last three
bags which are blue they're the 73 the
45 and the 25 so they're going to be
yellow white and purple which is
according you know it correlates I
always like the bubble bags that it had
both the micron sizes but it also had
the color coordinated thing it was
always a nice bonus and it was it's for
sure you know people are still going to
always want to you know that are serious
about the game always go with the
original bubble bags but for those that
really want to experiment and get into
this game without affecting your end
product you're still going to make it as
nice of a product as you would with the
bubble bag originals you just won't be
getting a lifetime warranty so there's
those in a nutshell you're also going to
be receiving three pressing screens they
come in these little books pads whatever
envelopes you want to call them and you
open that up and you'll have a 25 micron
pressing screen with a band all the way
around and that folds in half and that's
how we dab the moisture out of the final
product so I didn't want to cut corners
so bad that I gave you a lesser product
and that's why I'm still giving you
three pressing screens because it's a
very important part of the process to
dry it and to get it properly opened up
so I definitely was going to make sure
that three of those went into every kit
alright