okay so moving on to the bubble bags
originals eight colors we got them right
here the originals blue the to 20 micron
bag the green 190 bag the red 160 micron
bag the orange one 20 micron bag the
black 90 micron bag the yellow 73 the
white 45 and the purple 25 micron the
bubble bags original are still untouched
in the marketplace for quality really
it's since day one I always went with
the nicest highest gsm thread count I
could go with the highest grade
pharmaceutical screen whether night XR
polyethylene parachute thread to sew the
two together just really never cut any
corners in the manufacturing and in the
materials that were purchased these
materials are all purchased in different
countries and then flown to another
country because the that's where the
best sewing job gets done so all these
things correlate to a higher-end product
that's why we put the lifetime warranty
on it we know that these bags will last
for you know between 10 and 20 years no
problem and I wouldn't be surprised one
day when the company is older than 15
years if we hear there's bags that made
it 30 40 years on my Facebook page just
yesterday a gentlemen posted a set of
his 12 year old bags from 2001 all
stacked inside a bucket and showing all
the labels nicely and just saying you
know still in great use so it's great to
see that the bubble bags they still
demand a high price but they are
respected in the industry they're the
tool of many of the top quality extract
artists out there and people respect
bubble bags people like bubble bags
along with the quality along with the
material we also offer top
top-of-the-line customer service like I
said when you offer something like a
lifetime warranty it's best to make it
easier for your customers to
actually get that lifetime warranty
rather than make it difficult for them
so we usually just ask a few little
questions here in there but if the bags
have been defective in any way shape or
form we urge you to get in touch with us
and we'll replace them so thanks for
tuning in here today with me a beautiful
beautiful day here in British Columbia
and I'll finish off with showing you a
little bit of the sunset