hey guys bubble man here at the house of
the great Gardener having a great day uh
they're just taking the canonic now off
of the stem uh this is the high CBD
strain
absolutely really nice uh smell to it
looks ex completely covered in resin
really good job they've done here um
this herb is in like a perfect state
right now for um I guess to the next
stage of either going to cure
if I was a hash maker for dry sifting I
would probably leave it a little bit
longer and then I would sift it and if I
was a wet washer only I would uh pretty
much wash this right away so nice big
tub of of
Bud you know big
uh and a bunch more hanging
here on the
line so please check out House of the
great Garder on Facebook and Instagram
they
are great Garder so talk to you guys
soon