[Music]
welcome back guys Johnny B and me in the
house and we're about to fresh frozen
dude I'm so excited that you came by
with the fresh frozen watermelon today
yeah no that's a birthday treat for real
what kind of friend brings this problem
now of course I'm not keeping the resins
but just to be able to make it and smoke
it with John to me is a perfect most
beautiful of birthday gift so I've
actually got a rarity here that you
haven't seen yet I've got all three of
the bunk bed kits
that we're selling right now from the
original the top grade warrantied for
life durable as a mofo except that I
have yeah exactly that's the
professional house makers kit that's the
most expensive fog gallon aid bag kit
that comes in at 320 plus dollars number
two which still has all the colors right
just a slightly lower GSM thread count
the bags are still quality right and I
use an outside bag to change the color
to show people that this is not an
original kit so that they shouldn't be
paying the original price this bag is
about $50 cheaper this kit I basically
passed the savings on of the slightly
cheaper material for the bags and the
cheaper out outer material and basically
patch that right on to the customer so
that bag comes in at about 270 thanks
Canadians hey are you much sorry and
then the final ones which unfortunately
these look a little smaller than those
other two kits because I only had a 1
gallon kit and these were fives but
pretend this is a 5 gallon kit now these
are the lights and these are the ones
where I really went out hard on the
savings I changed everything there's no
eight colors like I took away the eight
colors and put only three colors which
was a pretty massive savings for me
being able to not have to buy eight
rolls of full color which is you know
it's everything everything adds up it's
very expensive to buy eight separate
roll
I was able to pass on a huge savings on
the eight bag five-gallon kit of the
lights at just a hundred fifty bucks
that's like half price it's less than a
half price for the original so you know
what just lots of people always asking
for deals and always asking for cheaper
set so I like to accommodate we give
deals and we have three different sets
that can accommodate you for whatever
your priced price it's not to sound too
much like an infomercial cuz I like the
fact that John and ionize videos are
more chill and more real but I I never
talked about the bags that much and this
is a good time to do it and we use these
ones already we use the lights and one
of our other video exactly and we've
used the originals I did the originals
with Remo I believe and it's just a
matter of one day running but it's your
birthday today so what bags you use well
for my birthday I'm using the
top-of-the-line 100% full lifetime
warranty bubble bag originals course you
know and man that's soft like if you're
going to travel with this bad boy as a
hash maker across the [ __ ] plains of
Afghanistan sleeping in the mountains
you know and I open I think we might
actually try and do that I think we will
do that after Jamaica which we're gonna
do in a couple of weeks we're gonna be
in Jamaica in a couple weeks with Tony
potentially Chibs Scott from rare
dankness and a few other people I've
invited down for kind of just a real
cool hey let's get together and have an
amazing time in Jamaica go hang out with
some cool artists and Kingston go to a
couple of cool parties meet the Rasmus
go into the hills make hash isn't that
what it's all about
oh that's just like sweet alright so
Johnny Cash John is brought over the
watermelon today we've got the fret I
won't pull it up just yet because we
should fill when we fill this we will
need the herb better go so we're gonna
use the bubble now for our mixing and
we're gonna use the barrel shaped bags I
know a lot of people love their
triangle-shaped bags which I will be
bringing to market soon spoke with a few
different people recently nicotine being
one of them offered him pyramid shaped
bags cuz we can of course manufacture
any style of bag that people request if
there's any professional Hashmi
out there that want their own specialty
kind of bag you know get in touch with
us we'll make you anything you want and
one thing you know about bubble bags and
fresh Shetty's is that we make quality
products that's it's a good offer anyway
so we're gonna do the fresh frozen how
much did you bring weight out of or
hunter grams of wet for 400 grams and
that's the watermelon that's the what a
memo you showed me at the front door oh
god dude you know it smells down here
they just go up to the camera and show
them this glisten the negative
perfection whoa isn't solid it's pretty
frozen dude look at that
that resin was so sticky I did do a
video of it alright layer of ice this is
my birthday treat Johnny
happy birthday oh it feels like little
icy trichome rocks okay more ice now
yeah now we're gonna put the chosen make
nice little layer of ice and then a
layer of or so yeah you can put more ice
in
excellent you basically want to make it
so the ice is covering that layer of
herb pretty much completely which it is
they're perfectly yep we're going up for
the camera
okay just barely touch this herb a
little bit God is that nice now you can
put a bunch of more ice I'm just I just
put that back in the ice right there
[Music]
I've done this before with me and
without with in with them this is a
perfectly that father was the 400 grams
it knocks this bag perfectly yeah I was
getting used to it I like my little
Rubbermaid bin so once that's all the
fresh I know I'm ready good to go and
this the 2.5 gallon nine point five
liter bin that I'm using good sign John
we have five nice pieces of ice here
perfect there we go back Sean so today
we're gonna use ice in the bubble now
machine as well nice just because our
water is not necessarily gonna be the
coldest coldest coldest you could start
turning that water on now actually I
will let that water run because it is an
outdoor hose in a black hose sitting out
in the Sun when it first comes out it
can be pretty warm and we're pretty
blessed with our water that just fits
Oh perfect uh no real it's gonna be nice
I can't even tell you how good that TGA
strain smells
I call it watermelon all the time it is
the Astro Boy from TGA and it is a
really nice strength there you go but I
was gonna put some ice in here to pour
in there so we're using the bubble bag
originals I'll get rid of the lights and
the standards and there's one more
little bud I found would you like to put
some ice in there so you keep that for
photography reasons later nice it's on
the gun no stuck to my fingers so good
boy one away we will but what we're
gonna have to do first to get a little
of this mounted because it's such a
perfect amount we basically filled this
that's the cool thing about the the
barrel shaped bag is that it fills the
Machine perfectly and just allows you to
mix as though the Machine the bag isn't
even there you know what I mean that's
what I love about this bag that's why
I'm so surprised when I hear people say
that they prefer the triangle bag and
that they're getting a bigger yield and
they get it I get my yield I get what is
there I never get less you know what I
mean if there's 10% that's what I'm
gonna get and having a barrel shaped bag
certainly isn't going to be it isn't
going to make it that I get any less
let's get some water on that yeah we'll
bring over the hose over here I'm just
gonna pass if I'm the camera here I
think it'll just reach if we're lucky
we're lucky I think we just happen to
perfect there we go so we've had the
pressure turned down there so we could
do this
we got lucky there I got it awesome you
know I know this is good come you know
what I want you to do come around and
dab me out a bowl with the D nail I'm
gonna be amazed you know that's great
about that sliminess
I can reach in here with a nice little
ball yeah it's awesome
all right
oh yeah there you go dabbing and filling
up the bucketful ice here getting the
bubble now going it's just very nice
asking beautiful oh that's nice what did
we dab up there number two and three
[ __ ] oh gee I like that pack indeed
it is a very nice play I'm sure I like
it a lot it isn't yeah this is filling
up beautifully perfect yeah you're just
hearing now what's getting up to the top
which is great oh not even close
it's actually about halfway perfect yeah
and luckily it's got quite a bit of
distance about an inch and a half all
the way around the whole thing that can
fill with water
excellent yeah you know you don't want
to take away all your water the water is
definitely a very important component of
making water hash water and ice always
what you say keep it cold
mmm-hmm keep it and I'll have you all
know that this hose nozzle was cleaned
by myself before I stuck it in here I
made sure to get all the particulates or
any little pieces that were on it off
and I cleaned it up real nice
I've been getting a lot of sort of flak
lately because I show people how to make
a bubble and of course I like to show
them how to make it properly but I also
like to show people how to do it easily
with whatever they have available for
where they are not everyone can afford
an expensive hash lab with machines and
ice makers and AH rows and so for those
people it's nice to be able to show them
a way to to be able to hand mix and you
know how to get your house dry properly
and all those things all right now we're
getting close to the top
okay I'm gonna turn that off so I'm
about maybe two inches from the top and
the reason I'm leaving that distance
this is nice too now the bag will go
sideways and upside down so I got it
nice and upside-down all tied up we're
gonna do about a ten-minute mix today
and then we're gonna come back and we're
gonna pull some bags for you nice and
quickly the bubble now has been filled
with water ice and herb john told us we
put 400 grams of fresh frozen in there
which is probably around 100 grams so if
we can pull out anywhere from 10 to 12
grams of hash and return we've done
exceptional so let's get her mix in it's
my birthday batch it's your birthday so
we're gonna continue to smoke hash while
this bad boy continues to make cash yeah
I hid yourself some Hoss oh you're nuts
oh me oh well alrighty then stoked kind
of let's make a hash in her birthday
it's your birthday
and always hitting it nice and all
someone was saying though we take big
bong rips I think no I think it's the
quality of house that we're smoking you
think we're taking a big one but it's so
smooth it was pretty big okay let's
bigger than normal
what is your how can you not do a big
birthday trip who's delicious that sauce
that's nice too
the more water and the more ice more ice
[Applause]
more ice merrier yeah
you're gonna get a great extraction
ratio
[Applause]
John's got the parchment paper here
we've got pizza boxes four of them
spread out which will be more than
enough for 10 to 12 grams it's always
great to use less hash for large area
the more surface area the better and
we've got the parchment paper unbleached
for putting overtop of the cardboard I
get so much flak for people a harsh and
on me for cardboard I show you the
cardboard because it's available to most
people of course if you can have
parchment paper and you've gone to your
store and got some that's great just
make sure in high humid areas that it's
not stopping the wicking I do worry
about the wax paper
esque miss of the material but here we
got John he's just gonna fold up the
edges and we're folding up the edges on
the parchment paper to just make like a
little protected area so the bubble
doesn't you know fall or get knocked off
the parchment and we're gonna continue
we're gonna tape the parchment as well
onto cardboard thank you sir you're very
welcome always nice to give a friend
hand especially when it's you know about
birthday hash patches there you go
all right so that's pretty quick just
picking the four together like huh
yeah once it stays up nice nice little
box that's perfect for keeping the
bubble hash safe all right well let's go
see if if it's time for us to pull the
bank's tape down the corners a little
bit looks yellow and smell it
[Applause]
it's almost like a beige yellow
I'm totally excited to go how cool that
is I can feel it when I opened it it
nice and
we're gonna get these bad boys working
real soon
[Applause]
all right we're back and our bubble now
has just stopped mixing we did about a
ten-minute err sample 10 minutes and
water is pretty trippy it's almost like
now that is funky I don't even know how
to describe it it's got this light light
green but the green is like a good it's
golden oh I want to say smell my fingers
but I'm not smelling a finger it's so
yeah feel free to have a sip I always
like to taste my rather a problem
there's definitely resin you can see it
floating right on the top in that right
yeah it's nice hey yes I like it
so we are gonna put the bags in the
bucket real quick this doesn't have to
take a long time and I'll just go
through the colors and the micron sizes
you start with the purple the 25 micron
it's the smallest screen make sure our
bag is nice our bucket is nice and clean
because I do remember we got a little
few nuggets that fell in there otherwise
the only thing that's ever gone in this
bucket is hash so not bad
alright so 25 micron going into a clean
bubble bubble bucket yeah we don't even
have to turn it over but you can it's
definitely not as necessary
takes a lot longer if you want to do all
the bags but it does help keep the
screen nice open 45 micron the white
this is our second bag and it's
definitely a bag that produces no
shortage of resin that comes out of the
45 micron bag really regardless ADA
stream it's what I be pumping lately I
mean that smoke is I'm 45 my little pony
73 micron that means he's out of 90 73
120 but it still goes to show you that
it's worth puffing I'm actually doing a
little bit of
watermelon on top of that excellent so
this was 73 yellow I'm not sure if I
mentioned that I might have I might not
have we've been dabbing bowls
so there's 73 yellow used to be the gold
bag until the black bag came along and
stole its thunder yes the black bag is
my favorite bag and it is the 90 micron
today on this day of 90 micron I wear
all black and honor of my friend Xavier
from medical seats rocking the medical
seat shirt that's job is there awesome
oh great time with those guys just good
dudes they can't wait til they come here
we can show them you know our style we
got beeping and bangin and beacon and
dancer number 120 micron orange so that
night it was a pretty a pretty good ad
in from the 122 the 73 everything
between the 120 and the 73 is delicious
and awesome and you loved it but there
were still thoughts that if we separated
it it might even be more different and
of course it was very glad to have my
1970 separated red 160 micron this is
the contaminant bag but can also be a
quality bag you know there has been
resin that comes out of this bag that is
melty I'm huffing on some also 160 no
right now really yeah my little pony no
I'm also 190 Green sorry to interrupt go
ahead oh I'm just saying how tasty that
160 is because I have some good wow this
is nice so um you can always try you 169
your 45 you have to be quite pleased if
you're a good organic grower you'd be
amazed at what you can get but they'll
definitely know it's when it's special
you'll see right away if you like
waiting so this is the 220 now and we're
still gonna use it even though that the
bag in here the bubble now barrel shaped
bag is at 220 I still like to use my 220
bag
and just in case filter out any other
contaminants that are a large
particulate separate out from those
smaller screens passion this looks like
this bags been mixed once they pulled
what was good to keep your bags clean
it's good to check the bottoms of your
screen sometimes before you shove them
into a bucket it's a good idea you can
have debris and dirt on the bottom of
your screen and now there's some dirt
that's right into your good hash and now
you don't know how it got there but I'm
sitting on the bottom of the 73 or the
bottom of the 120 and you pushed it down
and when the water and everything went
through that little particulate fell
right into your hash and it's just one
thing to pay attention to so we've got
all these now we're going to do the
draining a quick little drain just over
slightly all right and we'll just do the
green on this boom that's exciting
yeah that's fun I love this part make it
hash they don't what boom you know what
it's it's the most exciting part yeah so
because this is fresh frozen watermelon
and it's a fairly warm day thank God the
Sun went a little bit behind the tree
there we are in for some quick pulling
of bags because when we pull in fact
what I would suggest John is the 190 and
the 160 no problem but when we get to
the 120 I think we should I need to dab
you up wick right away
all right that there pass me your
Tupperware container always make the key
for a second one oh absolutely
that was that nut so we can whip up a
second run so fast to yourself when
using fresh frozen of such quality
nugget you got to do a second run I just
touched it my fingers are sticky
well that water was coming out nice and
clear adding that extra gallon or two
was worked out in our favor you're just
gonna unplug this get the bubble now out
of the way we go right and we almost
killed me actually this will be a table
there we go
excellent all right so we've got our
little area set up here with our bags
I'm using a small bucket to flip the
bags over and then we've got a spray
bucket over here so that we're gonna be
able to utilize it spin it in the ice
for the whole time so it's excellent
all right so even right off the bat
there's spring to be done on this bag
they do this is great so happy can't
wait to see the night on that one bad
boy there we go I'm gonna flip it up and
you can do some spraying if you like
yeah so this is mostly pistol at Harris
stigmas big large contaminant if it was
bubble it'd be moving a lot faster so
this this part will be a little bit slow
when you're spraying John's got it about
half way cleans now yeah it's definitely
I'm sticking really as you can see right
now he can you can but it's it's just
all right so let's just give it a quick
little scoop what we can find we've got
the screen nice and wet just give that a
little scoop and drop that right there
to 20 micron flip this take this here
John we'll give it the clean-out over
there just like right here it's really
convenient that's nice to have that hose
you're off camera but what John's doing
is he's leaning over the deck right now
and he's just cleaning the bag with the
hose here I'll give you a little a
little visual cleaning the bags with a
beautiful ocean view in the background
good Johnny no this is nice
this is darn nice all right well let's
get back to pulling our bags we
definitely don't need to spend any
wasted time leaving the water in the
resin in the water so quick 10-minute
rip on the bubble mouth and then pull
those bags that was very little in that
bag almost nothing see that every day
although there is stuff it's kind of
spread out on the screen it's invisible
because of the orange screen in the
sunlight I almost couldn't see it
this is more resonance now it's already
moving much easier than that other stuff
was just pile it into a little spot very
small little 190 keep that on and just
clean it like that with the easier to
clean when it's stretched
I often clean my buckets my bag
stretched over a bucket like that it's
it's held in place it's easier there's
no mob eases there's no creases that
hold the bag shot in in weird ways and
it's just like super quick alright a
real small amount of 160 probably
because it's just so damn good there's
very little contaminants this herb
that's something to come
very small little piles but also not
important piles alright now we're
getting more into an important a bag
that you want to see some resin in
generally is your 120 it's a nice bag to
see a little piling never a bad thing
yeah a little pile of some some niceness
show the camera here little pile of
someone 20 goodness this teamwork there
you go
we're making bubble boom melt on our
Gmail what snails by puking be skillet
tools for me bubble hash galore alright
looks good
pick that up oopah so this is the bag
that we put in the next bag to come yeah
exactly you don't want to lose this
resin that's a good point to be
remembered by even this little bit of
hash that stuck to the spoon right into
the 90 quality is there no problem
you're definitely not contaminating that
bag by any means putting a tiny little
bit of 120 in and white and then you'll
still make sure we give it a good rinse
alright 90 bike bum bag one of my
favorites always good when it lifts up
with a lot of water there's about a
gallon and a half gallon and a half of
water in there right now which tells me
something's covering the screen at least
a little pile
this is always nice to get your yield in
your 90 bag if you can a bad thing give
that 90 you tiny little particulates but
if I rinse the bubble around we should
be able to pick them out which is like
too much use the bottle in a second once
I get these new guys Irish three or four
just tiny little things that we don't
want in there and let me tell you this
thing does not want to pick up whatever
it is all right you got a bug spray this
up in just push the bag up put the lip
up on the bag and it makes for easy even
easier spring and I can just turn it boy
there so you can just stay in one spot
whatever works best for you looks like a
nice pile there's definitely probably
threw three grams there I would say
where is that last one 20 was maybe half
a gram 73 45 still two more good bags
that we're gonna pull oh we're gonna how
creamy that is oh it's delicious
Rick's on the screen remember these ones
need to go through the sieve almost
immediately we can't leave this out for
too long we can't waste all our time
filling all these bags anyway we're
gonna have to see some I think yeah that
is like trim to the Krampus sound so
there's that I'm thinking what I'm gonna
do now though is potentially strain that
1/2 hour all right so we've got our
parchment paper made into a big square
here with the edges done up layer down
here and I suggest we do that 90 micron
and almost immediately let's get that
done right now all right well let these
guys see what's going on a little closer
so I'm just gonna put the screen right
here sure I'm gonna go grab that
Oh sounds good man just gonna quickly um
oh it looks perfect it looks perfect for
micro plane itch for receive it for sea
Vitch I should say sorry it was mixed
the names huh all right so there's the
ninety we're gonna gently rub it through
the screen and you can see it's got that
perfect right now that it's crumbling
perfect so what I would suggest John is
use the end okay and you you rather than
make it awkward on yourself come back
around here I'll show you here I can't
show you without showing it there you go
basically use the bottom of the spoon on
the edge of the screen
so I'm gonna try and he's gonna come
back I'm gonna show this right here
there you go now a lot of it right now
is stuck on the outside but I give it a
couple of whacks and it's quickly coming
off oh that's beautiful look at exactly
and see how we put the lip on there
because as he's tapping away the lip is
actually protecting it from jumping off
of the lip is working for us very well
yeah it does doesn't it Danis quite
happy with that oh but you know what
he's getting a little bit excited oh you
got to get a little excited we're
cleaning this hash off we don't want it
stand in our seat we want it on that
parchment getting dried all right that
was 90 perfection right there well
that's all you stuff coming off Wow
worried about bouncing everywhere was it
we just let this dry a tiny little bit
this left little remnants that are in
here we'll give it a good whack in about
two or three minutes and it'll just fall
and cover this look at what beautiful
coverage we got with that sieve and in
the Sun it looks so nice doesn't it job
oh yeah it does some nice close-ups here
I'll give it back to you there my friend
oh dude beautiful right there cuz you
already there beautiful beautiful job
today is the birthday boy I know it's my
birthday I should answer the phone it's
birthday everybody's calling him he's
making hash if that's what he alright
that's awesome
all right we'll be back in a second all
right that didn't that 90 look
unbelievable aren't you glad we received
that right away I'm telling you right
now if that 73 was still sitting there
it'd be a done deal the 120 we could do
any time as well but we'll pull these
three bags and we'll do them all
together we'll be quick though because
the 73 is gonna be just much like that
it's gonna be creamy deliciousness that
90 bag just made it all yeah right there
and the 73 is doing it too just so you
know just so you know it's also doing it
yeah
all right yeah the 73 is looking creamy
too a very creamy I can I could smell it
all right let's get that in there Oh
thought I was gonna pull the Ricky ledee
I thought you're almost gonna pull a
rookie moves you know we do that even
being we do we do we do I mean that's
the that's one of the main reasons I
don't mess around with chemical solvents
but the fact that they're just come on
look at this in the Sun look at the
color of that that's just amazing you
know what that's you know I can see it I
wish you guys will bring it to them
we're gonna be like this is one from
here directly in this I'll let you pull
that little chunk out in a second once I
get it right there that guy
and I think he didn't have a bit of an
animal in that there we go a couple more
perfect so stinky
yeah this is gonna have to go all right
want to get the spoon spoons right here
oh yeah this is just like that night he
was just like that it even wants this
just stay on this that last little bit
dang keep it the you know what it's
almost the same amount with 73 is there
it looks beautiful it's even like
hardening on the spoon here screen the
next screen is coming up the next screen
the next screen I should not be the next
parchment the next cardboard and
parchment we're hitting gabs it's easy
for us too
alright so take that guy right here we
can rinse this guy off ASAP because he's
already starting to dry and that's one
thing we talked about is don't let your
screen one of the things they were doing
in Spain that I couldn't wrap my head
around that I really was thinking that
it's just something they shouldn't be
doing and I saw more than one person do
it they pulled all their bags out and
then they hung them and lean them up
against one another put them in a bag
and high-quality resin is gonna wick
moisture just sitting on top of that
screen so much then it'll be very
difficult to see if micro planing will
be one of your only options at that
point and you'll have to of course
freeze the resin before you do that
because it's a warm environment in Spain
especially in Barcelona even
it's hard to get to a cool temperature
that you can actually you know even just
playing some some hash without having it
just start melting your fingers all
right it's richer bags very very devil
there the better yeah no it's good so
we're just given the resin and ice the
resin is so clean Beth Lee Mort I see
you yeah it's like four grams at least
I'd say we've got our 10 to 12 grams
anyway Joseph just from the like two and
a half to the two to three two three
four five six
yeah we've got about ten anyway we still
haven't pulled 225 either though just
give this a couple of good squirts to
show if there's any contaminants in
there no it's beautiful then we'll scoop
it all up how's that for not a drop
drive would you like that
that's cute dude that's a nice pile
that's a huge problem
that's not even done yet that's thanks
thank five times of everything I'd say
it's at least five times of everything
yeah I think there's about six grams
just there that's definitely close to
five maybe 456 you know I'm just
guesstimating just like you and I'm like
you know no no more accurate and my
guess we're gonna weigh it and we'll
find out what its gonna be like yeah
we're definitely let you know
I'd say we're gonna get that through the
plane real soon if you want to start
sieving yeah why don't you come over
here and see why like
bags all do the cleaning on this bag I'm
gonna grab this 73 right off the hop
sure man yeah get that going right away
it's good looks good hey you blow that
off nice and fast tech I can just do
that nice work though well easy going
easy going so yeah this is a nice easy
way to clean bags isn't it yeah isn't
that nice haha totally digging it all
right excellent
excellent so remember the cleaner you
you get your bags the better it's you
get that resin stuck on there and you're
the one that's gonna be dealing with it
that is the truth of that never a bad
idea to just use a little extra couple
extra minutes and make sure you get it
real dry well that's looking great John
that's the 73 73 all right you could
probably afford to card just a small
section of this over there real quick
you might even be able to do it just
with the lightness I wouldn't touch it
with your hands but and then we can put
the 120 right here I will draw a line
and then we've got two more in there
that we'll have to make i'd say we're
gonna need at least a whole one
easy-easy for that 45 right now yeah
then I'll pull the 25 bag this is a bag
that everyone has a real problem with a
simple technique you can see that it's
holding at least 3 gallons of water but
a simple technique is to lift it very
quickly and the water just releases so a
bag like this generally when I start
doing this little jerk upwards method I
can drain it in about 10 seconds
fresh frozen John but I still have more
that's sitting to be run again like
we'll put it in the bubble now again and
run another batch so I'm going to grab
that we're not going to film our second
batch but we will let you know what came
of it
that will do many push maybe a little
couple days down the road notice how I
filled the bag with air and slid my hand
down the bag to actually get some of
that excess water out do not physically
grab the hash in the screen and squeeze
it that is not a good idea it's just
something that definitely is not a good
idea and then finally here we've got our
25 oh yeah looking good John the 120
looked beautiful the 25 is one of the
unique resins that you can actually
gather with a spoon almost as well as
you gather with the spray bottle but why
that is if it's the size of the heads
obviously it is it's the only thing
that's really different about it just
clean it so well 25 micron the grade
that will pay for your bags whether you
want to use it in a metal bowl or an ax
joint or smoke it in a bone
I saw Franco from strain hunters
recently going off on you about USF's 25
micron bubble so you know that there's
something to it there's some actives in
there depending on where it was growing
on the strain this color of this 25 is
absolutely beautiful
yeah awesome I got water spraying in my
face this is awesome it's beautiful look
at the Sun just just goodness this is
totally beautiful
totally awesome birthday thanks for
coming over John oh you know what I mean
you always come over but put a nice guy
to bring the fresh frozen and hey plan
this like this is a day it was something
that I you know it's I'm gonna I'm gonna
give me this cut I've rushed this home
now about Christmas I brought him here
from my friend Ron's yeah we were
laughing about it today it came home in
my pocket in a plastic bag and I'm gonna
go get the second parchment paper so we
can get on seething that 25 and that 45
I'll be right back
and what I'm gonna do here as we know
this side here is the ones one and this
side here is the 73 so instead of
drawing a line on the paper here I'm
just gonna write it on the cardboard
gives me an idea
I put the 73
and the 9v fills up that whole tray and
this 45 is definitely looking so sweet
so I'm gonna wait for mark to come out
here right now move this whole dollar
bags we've seen the 90 the 120 the 73
and what we have left is the 45 and the
25 we're not bothering with the 222
190th 160 it's just schwag Isles I'm
gonna pour this water into my garden
down below that's terpene rich hey here
we go that right there is what we call
koala tay 445 I'm gonna smile on your
face look at me dude you're 45 below is
that Johnny
already five is this your 45 over that's
the 45 Oh John do you think that III
think it's just a beautiful thing
what are you my friend it's for you I'll
look at that for you I think I think I
think listen maybe just a little bit
tiny little bit if it's no good you let
me know if we need to we'll add a tiny
little bit of moisture it could be
perfect it could be perfect
oh yeah it's coming through nice it's
sticking so gently give it a gentle
little smack on the edge as you move it
as you yeah oh yeah that's perfect John
oh this smells amazing it looks unreal
II hear ya believe how the smell this is
the colour is written this is probably
the nicest 45 I've ever seen it's
definitely very nice for me that what
I've grown so I mean
here and there you can also do a light
scraping on the outside make sure you
move it when you do that or you'll get
clumps though move the whole unit around
even towards some of the empty spots so
this is a real important process the
sieving or the micro planing we're doing
the sieving technique it's good to keep
your tools cool we're doing this in the
sunlight so you guys can see it really
well obviously it's a better idea to do
this in a colder environment
not that it's SuperDuper warm right now
but it's definitely probably ten degrees
well we are so filler up nice little
pile right off another piece and just
kind of working yeah gently sieve it
through the screens you know there did
this did have a little bit more moisture
removed even though it's sieving
perfectly if I left a little bit more
moisture in it it would have probably
sieve even a little bit more perfect
both the to the 90 and the 73 were like
that as well
but this looks great you're gonna get it
all the way through and you'll be able
to to cover this parchment paper nice
and evenly so wherever you see it to be
the least amount is where you kind of
want to spend some attention whoo nice
yeah I like that I moved the paper open
just as you did it all right I was like
team I was like team work you're like
very receptive to the motions John hi
you know what we work well together we
do get the job because we're just having
a good time but now it's cuz we love
what we do we do love what we do and we
seem to be very much alike in our in our
just in our histories and the vision
involved with and we just seem so damn
happy to share with the people out there
you know what what's what's the best
thing you can do is show people this
yeah baby it's my birthday hash look
look at the bottom of this I'm so
excited
oh yeah let's look at the bottom of that
in the sunlight alright give it a gentle
smack rather than brush it with the
spoon you can smack all most of that off
sometimes I go high like on this on the
top part that's good and then of course
some more loosening of it up as it dries
as we're taking time that bubble will
dry out a little bit more and it'll even
break off easier sometimes the little
bits that get stuck on the outside you
can gently brush it off with a spoon or
you could use a brush you could also use
one of the anti-static brushes to get
this bubble off and that's just a nice
even amount we'll give that a few more
good whacks on the edge of the stainless
steel strainer with the spoon real good
ones give it a top whack like a nice
hard one yeah that's where you see it
really start see how I see it bouncing
and releasing them yeah excellent
beautiful alright well we've got our 45
we're gonna move on to the 25
so we ran out of space on our parchment
paper we don't really want to rip out
another batch and the 25 micron of all
the hashes if you get it into a thin
enough patty it seems to be the one that
can actually dry in a patty so we're
gonna do a little experiment just with
the 25 we're gonna leave this little
patty as is and we're still gonna get it
on to the wicking table here we've got a
nice little spot in the corner of our 45
we'll put it on the parchment there and
we'll get back to you and let you know
how that kind of turned out it's been an
unbelievable birthday batch with my
amigo Johnny I mean such a good friend
comes over with the beautiful mess whips
off a batch with me and this in this
beautiful area that we live and yeah I
mean basically the only thing really
left to share which I'll end with is the
macro photographs of the resin that we
just made you know starting with that
120 micron beautiful heady heads all
stuck together in little clumps
beautiful color dropping down into the
90 and suddenly it's like whoa that
stuff is surreal Dimond like glistening
amazingness with the 73 looking almost
exactly like the 90 to the naked eye I
expect that it'll look pretty beautiful
under the macro lens and then down into
the 45 and I'll shoot the patty 25 and
we'll share all this greatness with you
guys so once again Jon thanks for coming
out such a [ __ ] pleasure dude always
a pleasure hanging with you bro I'm
excited you know what dude I'm excited
too this was this was a great day and a
great birthday so thanks everyone for
watching we'll talk to you soon on
bubble man's world peace
those are my bird friends they're saying
John bubble man share that 90 90 90 90
90 90 90 90 90 micron we will peace
[Music]
you