[Music]
all right so we're just pulling the 25
micron here you can see it right here
it's taking its time it's pretty soupy
if he moves it around with a spoon there
you see there's still quite a bit of
water so we're gonna try the vacuum here
Matt brought over the vacuum back
Rhoni and we're gonna stick it into the
bottom of the bucket here through this
little hole and we're going to see if we
can't suck the air bubbles in the extra
water out of this out of this house
but we have success people that was very
successful
it sucked show them that that is like I
mean it was almost too much almost
pulled it through we yeah okay so when
doing this you don't want to do it quite
that that hard right it's a little thing
we can use water and clean that so just
wipe off the initial amount with the
spoon and then we'll use a little bit of
water to pull it back into the middle
and Wow
so I guess we're gonna have to use a
little bit of horsepower there's not
quite efficient though at work right
there see you later all right
all right so we bought it we poured a
tiny little bit of water just to show
you that we didn't mock it up the
yeah we're gonna bring the vacuum back
over and we gonna suck this water out
for you don't seal it quite as well this
time we'll let you know
that's enough all right now to try to
get that out how that works pretty darn
well I mean if we used a sharper tool
that's almost perfect
[Music]