hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
just saying hello to my beautiful little
ladies they are producing some real nice
heady heady resin I'm just so excited
about having a little crop and of course
as some of you know who have been
following my social media I am so
[ __ ]
stoked that Matt the great Gardener
passed along the sweet skunk thank you
so much Matt I really don't think you
realize how happy I am and I appreciate
the ARB and I appreciate the Afghani
those are huge gifts as well and I'm
going to go on about those I'm sure but
the sweet skunk I have a history with
and I just wanted to say thank you man
the great Gardener House of the great
Gardener go check those guys out they
are good folks can pick up their seeds
uh their High CBD marker seeds are going
to be coming out soon with warlock and
Renee multiple fenos they've got uh Barb
I believe theyve got hom Afghani they
they are literally going through the
whole gamut of their strains and adding
the CBD marker from the the canonic so
check them out if you need some high CBD
strains or if you just really want full
melt certified genetics that I can
assure that you will love the taste the
flavor and the potency of go check those
guys out I am going to say goodbye to
these little ladies because I'm heading
up to Whistler for the weekend going to
go see Phil from True genetics and a
couple other good folks and hopefully
we'll do some wet washing while we're up
there so this is just a little video to
show you my little measly crop that I
got going on here just six plants and a
little tiny um you know two foot by 4
foot uh tents couldn't be happier anyway
thanks for watching Bubble man's world
got a ton of good videos coming up for
you puff Wednesday with John a couple of
days ago where we did some really fun
things and that video is really fun and
then literally the next day I went over
to the great gardeners and we filmed
again so some good videos coming up stay
tuned peace