hey bubble man here just wanted to do a
new little series of Clips called water
hash tips with bubble man so our first
tip is going to be today in regards to
Preparing the trim why don't we start
right at the beginning
when you've got nice trim it's a good
idea to go through it and make sure that
there's no types of contaminant in there
you don't want any fan leaves in there
or any types of stock separate your fine
trim and your popcorn bud out
themselves if you can do this at the
start while you're trimming off the
plant if you're using fresh material
freeze it right away if you're not using
fresh material no problem but make sure
you trim over a tight screen that will
help save some of the dry sifted resin
that will fall off in the due to the
brittleness of the dry nature of the
herb
so you can use cannabis buds you can use
trim you can use stock you can use all
these different things but really make
sure your trim is clean have it
separated out and you'll find that the
quality of your final product will
sometimes go up uh quite a few notches
just from doing this simple tip okay
hope it helps