hey Michigan we're bringing my hash hits
and more BC Bubble Man products to a
dispensary near you thanks for staying
tuned you can do
like hey how's it going my name is
Marcus Richardson aka the bubble man you
know I've been into the Cannabis
industry since I was about 15 or 16
years old I was deeply involved with the
hemp growing legally for the first time
in my province of Manitoba back in the
mid90s I moved to British Columbia in 96
and became an integral part of the BC
Compassion Club through growing and
providing and procuring cannabis for
them uh and it was around 1998 that I
ended up getting into a little bit of
trouble uh and that trouble funny enough
led me into the wonderful world of
[Music]
bubblehash and then really most
excitingly are these Bubble Man brand
deals that I've been doing recently the
key factor for me is finding an
incredible hash maker and with Michigan
it was no different I was reached out to
by a gentleman by the name of Papa sift
uh AKA Ryan wall and he just checked all
the boxes a true bubble Ambassador a
true lover of the art form of hash
making and uh he reached out to me and
he connected me uh with this amazing
group of gentlemen of Growers from
Michigan called
ranic uh and really it just everything
fit like a beautiful
glove hey everyone it's Papa here
Welcome to our lab come check out where
we make all the BC Bubble Man products
here in
Michigan I've been doing solvent list
for like since 2009 I'd say and I've
been doing it at scale for since like
2017 so I think I just had a strong
grasp of running a lab I also had
experience running a BH Lab at a
different facility in Jackson Michigan
so it's kind of all translated and was
able to pull together and run a small
crew over
here we decided to go to Jamaica
Cannabis Cup in 2015 I think it was the
first International Cannabis Cup down
there and uh a mutual friend linked us
up and it was cool to go meet him and
pick his brain but I wanted to just go
there to meet people like Marcus and you
know people that I wanted to just
network with and see if I could uh
figure out how to get into the industry
it's been fun kind of managing that and
uh trying to break
through Papa sift is really second to
none and for the bubble man brand to
survive and to succeed that is a major
important factor in in moving forward
and so I got to give a huge shout out to
Papa sift uh following the bubble man
Sops incorporating his own Sops that he
learned over the years from me we've
done many many many FaceTime um hash
making sessions with our Osprey with our
hashte with our Ros and presses uh from
decarboxylating materials using the
sample automation rosin reactor all of
it we've done uh closely together and so
I just got to give a huge shout out and
a thank you to papa for sort of putting
all of this together with the bubble man
brand and
oranic BC bubbleman has been the brains
of the operation and I'm the hands
carrying it
out he he does have very precise Sops to
follow so um when we're trying to do
certain higher end SKS it has to be
pretty specific on how he wants things
followed so depending on the skew um
we'll do three to six washes and we'll
start off with very gentle agitation and
uh slowly ramp up agitation just to make
sure that we're getting everything off
and not leaving any meat on the
bones I would be remiss as well if I
didn't mention the live hash Vapes that
we're going to be releasing with the
Kung Fu Vapes in the Michigan Market
really excited about these I've been
testing a whole variety of Vape Hardware
really like the Kung Fu disposable units
that's going to be live hash rosin these
products always of course take you got
to grow exceptional Canabis you got to
do it with Consciousness you got to do
it hopefully regeneratively and
sustainably so you can keep doing it and
then of course a really important factor
as well is making sure that you have the
right hash maker for the
brand we just got the Kung Fu Vapes has
a nice airflow it preheats every time
you turn it on and off so it never gets
like stuck it's a pretty smooth
experience I'd
say so we did the 7390 and 120u of the
strawberry lemonade that I'm washing
right now so you'll get uh different
flavor profiles from each bag I noticed
uh more of a creamier one for the higher
Micron bags and more of a fruity flavor
for the
73 the BC Bubble Man products are going
to be something new to the market and
we're really excited to bring them
here so these hash hits are dryft from
BC Bubble Man techniques they're
disposable five come in a pack they're
02 each so each pack has a gram of hash
technically by like volume for white one
of these is equivalent to a joint these
are our first batch here in Michigan so
I'm pretty excited to get these on the
market we just got the test results back
this is our first drop and the strain is
soap
the ranic crew is incredible and amazing
they've been the perfect Partners
growing 17 Acres of incredibly organic
beautiful sustainable cannabis flowers
really paying attention to the Sops in
regards to how they harvest how they
maintain fresh frozen from literally the
time that the plant is cut down right up
until the time that we're processing uh
the material so they've been incredible
in that sense I couldn't imagine a
better partnership and we're really
looking for the same thing in regards to
dispensaries we're looking for conscious
owners people that want to get their um
customers you know sort of the best that
they can depending on where they fit
into the SKS because when I say the best
you know the best could be a hash hit
for one guy it could be full melt dry
sift for another guy so it's not really
speaking about the quality as much as
what is the best fit for the customer in
regards to price point uh THC percentage
and atile organic um compound so if you
feel that that might be you guys and
that's one of you know what what's sort
of the mission behind your group in
Michigan we would love to hear from you
you can reach out to uh BC bubbleman
icloud.com you can reach out to BC
bubbleman on Instagram Papa on Instagram
ranic on Instagram uh and if you reach
out to any one of us uh we will get the
message and we'll make sure to reach out
and see if we can't create some nice
synergies uh with local groups in
Michigan