hey how's it going there from fresh
penny is limited and the creators of
bubble bags we're here today to show you
what we do with rolling papers a lot of
you out there know that I smoke only
hash I haven't smoked herb cannabis for
over ten years close to 12 but because
I'm the distributor for the hoodlum
jackets they come with a rolling paper
insert I've got a pack right here if the
Raw's that i pulled out in one of my
jackets it's a nice raw organic the
natural way to roll
I personally don't smoke paper or glue
but what I do do with rolling papers is
I have a little little trick that I sort
of learned many many years ago you just
take a normal sized rolling paper this
is a king size but it should work as
well and you fold up the bottom edge
just above the amount that would be glue
on the top edge so that's folded up and
then we bend it down just to put a
crease in it we're gonna do the same
thing with the top of the glue we're
gonna bend that down and put a crease in
it and then we're gonna do the same
thing to the edges about the same amount
you know the amount of glue that's on
there or whatever that is a quarter of
an inch or something so we make that
nice and good use your nails to really
make the crease stick all right do the
other last corner here okay this one
looks pretty good I usually like to just
twist up the two corners kind of just
triangulate them there all right so this
one looks pretty good
what we do is we hold the middle of it
on our finger and we spin the rolling
paper spin for me spin for me it's a
little bit too creased there okay there
we go now we're spinning
now our spinning
see if I can get it on camera for you
because it really does look pretty cool
when you make it work
and you can easily do this at home all
right here we go spin coming back around
spin so that's the rolling paper trick
and well I've got you here I've got some
really nice bubble shatter this has been
curing for about five years in my bubble
box here and it is absolutely shattered
right up let me just pull out a tiny
little bit of three screens set to throw
on top I've already got some nice
shattered loaded on there it's just
obsidian block I wish you guys can see
it from where you're at I'm smoking with
b-line today as I do every day
thanks to hash beam who turned me on to
beeline a few years ago now I've been
using it pretty much endlessly and
thanks to Nate dizzle for this beautiful
Swiss perk that he gave me a couple
years ago when I went to Germany with
him and Steve hops all right
bubbly bubbly
[Music]
until next time