[Music]
hey bubble man here uh just heard John B
pulling up the driveway thought we'd
catch him before he got up here
oh backing
up guys he's backing
up are we good yeah we're good man
welcome
welcome how's it going dude always hi
you know yeah buddy John be in the house
bringing me some goods and he's brought
goods he's getting used to this now
right yeah I could get used to this for
sure
[Music]
so cocu fiber
Pro mix perfect C all right well let's
start pulling this stuff
out drop that right there pots
pots stuff sunflowers perfect
compliments of course
Dan thanks Dan Dan from KW this
off you seeing that
always a good idea to lay the tarp down
dude coming up here huge accident on the
freeway was back up all the way to west
from the bridge so for dinner man oh
excellent sorry about the accident but
still like it was looked like it was
anybody was hurt like 10 cars are all
fil up something all
righty
musty knife didn't we bring the blade
down yeah yeah got down here excellent
and for me okay I'll show what I do man
this is cool I always just do this sure
Slicer in
half almost in half little less than a
third just break her off
yeah there we
go yeah use that as the lid see next
time Che this out I've always had fun
doing I do this all the time perfect for
small Growers we always have this little
uh technique put their hat back on put
the hat back on put the hat back on we
going full full bag of Coco No we do
half I was going to say pass me that
ra Che out the tart
m
there we go look at that you got a baby
baby bag oh it's nice and it's nice the
old stuff we have to break apart so much
this already comes free little bit of
new train 300 parts I think it
was someone will correct me on that of
course oh yes excellent the internet at
the Internet tour we certainly don't
claim to know everything not even close
just learning ourselves so we'll get
this all mixed
now oh yeah reminds me back of the day
getting soil ready for outdoor you get
all the castings and build up the soil
so nice huge mountains of it on
tarps that's cool that'd be totally cool
me I've been doing it in bins for years
no mountains no tarps oh this was in the
cies 20 20 years ago that's sweet so you
know it just shows that uh the
dedication dude that's awesome that's
just how they do it they were showing
really how you know I was really on
there sort of like just happy to be
there
learning so yeah this is nice you like
that eh yeah it's my favorite mix it's
what I always do it's what I've been
doing the whole time and I just want to
show you what I was doing well you know
earlier today I asked John I said did
John um you know maybe you could get me
a bag of castings it's just the old
school organic farmer in me and he he
said you know I I use there's tons of it
in the med1 so I don't really put them
in so I said don't even bother grabbing
the castings we'll check it out med1 has
so so far produced Immaculate resin from
from the pictures to the smell to the
visual just with the naked eye no one
has said I'm doing anything wrong well e
kill weed is quite easy that's what I
mean it really takes the part of my
French the [ __ ] out of gr it's just easy
you know what I mean but you know what
it's it's uh this little things mixing
the soils like I always say I use promix
and some cocoa and and that's great you
know I'm not trying to well why don't we
why don't don't we go and get those
plants from upstairs trans and bring
them down here for transplant sweet
sound like a plan sounds like a perfect
plant that's what we doing here we'll be
right
back so we're just uh adding a little
bit of
moisture to this
soiless about 3 4 lers of water it's a
big tub it's already pretty much you
know heavy I wouldn't want to make it
any more heavy for me to be moving
around by
myself yeah we just been adding a little
bit of a H2O yeah just a littleit little
bit out of time yeah you don't need to
be adding a whole bunch you'll just make
your thing so heavy and I mean you can
always water the soil when the plants
are in it this is just to give it a bit
of
moisture so bab right here you look how
the thums just making them hit look at
that guys and this is an Afghani look at
that The Afghani The
Afghani I'm going to give you a little
picture there guys well H that's not not
working too well for me oh no it looks
nice no it was about I like this I like
this PRX chair I have got going on
that's beautiful I'm rocking the uh the
cocoa fiber chair you got the oh the
Coco you d low I'm a do low rider thing
yeah reach over grab some pots my friend
all right then oh look at that got some
sunglasses cuz that thought is perfect
you got a couple of pots here now you
got your what do you got on that side
well we got these sweet sweet skunks
that we should probably start with nice
they are the sweet skunk
definitely um the ones I'm I'm most
anxious beautiful uh to get going these
are going to be mothers of course can't
wait look at this perfect clone right
here and right here and there these are
going to be
beautiful yeah dude I'm excited we're
both excited this is uh you know got
some exciting times basically John and I
don't keep strains from one another we
we don't John doesn't tell me about his
awesome strains and then tell me I can't
have them and of course you know because
of how helpful John was since since the
beginning of helping me get my license
and helping me on every level with
planting and and cloning and the whole
nine yards of course John always has
access to everything I have there's no
uh there's no other way about it buddy
how about that hey dude same goes on my
you got all no problem you know it's not
even props it's expected ah you know
what it's just uh we love this plant
this plant this plant this plant here
actually I'll give I'll pass this well
you know what you you you do that one
okay and I'll do this one here perfect
I'm going to do
this for me when I open these up I just
kind of give it a little
squish that works out nice pull off
gently
yeah with this one here we do have a few
with but we can actually pull those
right through nicely and there we
go looking beautiful
awesome just trying to get this little
hole opened up so
these these roots can make their way
through want to there we
go that's what I'm looking for right
there now for me I just do this move
some dirt off to the
side Lo
in beautiful nice and easy I'm just
having the nightmare from hell with this
root mask but I got it oh but that's why
you have him in you did an awesome job
of it going to go the other way though I
like this flipping right down the other
way yeah well you know I don't want
that all right hi hello there look got
some nice trays look at these just came
in handy but did these come from the
airport by any chance sir uh yes those
were the two extra little ones there I
was looking for something today and I
was think well we didn't have any so I'm
just happy that's here it's beautiful
yeah very cool very cool
cool
so put that one aside c b so I'm going
to get him a little
straighter get him a little
straighter you know sometimes just how
you put a plant in a pot really will
affect the beginning of its growth and
of course it's very simple to train that
plant back to where you want it to go
but just personal choice I like to have
my plants uh you know
straight
all right so I guess next up PO me I'm
going to go Barbara and you're going to
go Afghani woohoo we're not going up too
big on size from here about a gallon so
for me I'm going to put that much dirt
in yeah it's not going to be too much
we're going to mostly it'll be a base we
can put that right down on top that'll
be about perfect right
there okay so we're back after the dog
experience um going to do the trans
transplanting of the Barb and The
Afghani so I guess we'll both we've
already put a tiny little bit of uh soil
in the bottom of the pot I'd say I have
maybe four or five in tops there you go
mainly because 2 in of this pot is um
actually
not let me see if I can reuse the
sticker that would sure be great I think
it's going to have some yeah prob going
to pop her there we go just like that
look at that look at that nice nice to
see The Roots going on upside down in we
go beautiful I'm with you on that one
here we
go and just fill up the
sides lightly just throw the dirt in
there of water will do the rest for me
yep and the plants are definitely a
little moist which is nice yeah exactly
the soil so it won't need water right
away probably wait a you wouldn't really
want to transplant super dry plants the
dirt could start falling apart and it's
just I I find it a little bit easier to
have a bit of moisture in there for
sure not super wet that's for sure no
not super wet they got watered uh a
couple days
ago and I see how you water you water
very lightly you do quite a I water
lightly and great job of doing it and
often like not super often but you know
I like to let them I find if you just
water them too much they um they have a
hard time drying out
properly we G so there we go
with the bar now you notice when I did
that I put the sticker on the bucket
before I transplanted and before I put
the plant down I put the peg in the
strain one thing you'll never hear from
me is not knowing what strain I'm
growing or what strain I have because
I'm obsessive with the name and the
labeling of the strain I I just I know
that it's it would be easy for me to put
this down and even mix these two plants
up in an instant which I do all the time
yeah it's so
easy so we got those you got your
sticker on that one and did you also put
the peg in there or did that get lost no
I think I think it actually um got lost
and I apologize I I took mine out and
put it put it somewhere here probably in
the
dirt I bet you when you dump the plant
it might have gone in the dirt but I uh
possibly no I don't think so we'll find
it or we'll use a new one we know it's
Afghani from the sticker on the side I
can't tell you enough label your plants
multiple times label your plants put a
little stick in the St in the in the mud
put a a um a sticker on the pot it's
it's everyone thinks they recognize
their plants and knows their plant so
well I say nothing better than having a
label on your plant so that when you
share it or someone else get gets it
it's just easy um I mean Matt gave me
both of these uh all three of these
strains with labels uh double labels
sticker on the pot and a little piece
stuck into the into the into the dirt so
that's
definitely thing for yeah great idea
well just cuz these darn genetics right
they it's so easy to get them all mixed
up and people don't know what they have
and they don't know what this was and
that was keep mine down to a m minimal
so at least I got an idea and well you
have idea you cuz right now my two my
denas and my number four I know they're
one of the
three oh oh no but the for someone like
myself um I I just I guess for me I just
love I know what I have and I got an
idea and once I'm like hm well this is
something uh it's going to be a new
surprise cuz I can't remember what it
was well that's what John and I are all
about sh sharing with you too is that
we're different people and we have
different ways and so we're just telling
our ways for the people that would um
have things in common with us and
there's many other different way ways to
do this these are just a couple of
different ways that that we're doing it
the most important thing I always say to
myself I damn I should have labeled it
and hence you know what I mean yeah I'm
obsessive with I'm okay I need label my
next one so I have already I want to get
that Afghani label I really want to find
it oh we're going to get it and get it
in the in the yeah because it definitely
didn't go in the soil because it no I I
didn't put it in this soil either but uh
it is a small little label that could be
I'll find it one day and laugh it's
right around me I'll be like got it John
I found it oh wait a second see this is
how it
happens anyway we're going to uh
probably end up I guess we'll water
these plants and then a little later on
we're going to take a couple of clones
off The Afghani and the Barb and uh nice
send John home with those once our sweet
skunks get a little bit older I'd say
maybe two or 3 weeks nice once they're
growing nice and we've got them up to
sort of this style you can come take a
bunch of cuts of those too and that's
going to be beautiful for my summertime
one because of the sweet in the skunk
and they're get more of an outdoor look
at the little tiny leaves how it almost
looks like a Bonsai I love how it's like
the I mean you just see how M worked on
the perfect clones here right just like
right from the start you see how he's
branched them out so they be main moms I
like it how he's done here you know it's
beautiful I see it with your name on it
right over there that's beautiful I see
it right from here John he's going to
give it to me yeah well I'm going to
pass it on I you know it's just I don't
even feel oh I want say you know what
yeah that's it's it's a nice thing to be
able to uh actually enjoy um what we
love so much absolutely man so we can't
send them in the mail and we were not
you know if uh no these ones are are
here at a legal grow and they are going
to stay here at a legal grow so yeah a
lot of people going to be say hey can
you send me that
andem I I offer the strains to my
friends with
licenses and that's and that's who I
offer it to and I hope that eventually I
get these
strains you know I know Matt's got his
strains so you can buy them in seed form
that's great that's awesome I'm into
getting strains to breeders I'm into to
people working with these strains I
can't wait to pass the sweet skunk
around to a couple breeder friends of
mine I might send it to Javier at
Medical seeds in Barcelona um Phil from
True genetics up in Whistler wants to
play around with it it's a nice thing to
let them play around with it and it's
it's an ideal thing I know some people
think that the Jean Pool will be
destroyed but you know as long as we
keep the originals they'll be fine the
difference in the Lea P see it's just
structure and that's like like you know
for me that I I really pay attention to
the serration and Lea patterns and stuff
like that because it gives me how to
identify a lot of the strains and how
they grow so I am able to see the
different genetics and see how things
actually I mean beautiful five we' just
yeah you know what I'm excited why don't
we go mix up a batch of Med One show
them how simple that is and then we'll
give these guys a little water we should
do that and then flush out we'll give
some water uh clean water non food to
the uh Blooming Garden as well we'll
show you a little bit of that took a few
of the shots macro shots of that medy
kush
today that was nice just looked so clean
and untouched yeah cuz you never touched
it yeah they just looked like Perfection
just I I'm I can't wait to share with
you guys the string definitely produces
some nice resin as I've seen from John's
grow I just I've never been able to
shoot it whenever I want yeah you know
what the live and and seeing that live
plant resin is actually like I've seen
the shot you done with Remo and stuff
like that
just beautiful seeing that development
and how it is on when the plan is
untouched you can actually take a good
close look like I mean your picture is
phenomenal but I mean being able to
really take a look at it and then
understand what we're actually really
trying to get into that's a huge part of
our education John it's it's the
medicine you know but but the
photography the the detailed macro
photography is a huge part of our
education um it's it's well for me it's
being the next step yeah absolutely me
too and I've you know been playing
around with it since 2008 and it's been
growing and and each year becoming a
little bit more and more the teacher
right there uh the student right here oh
I'm I'm I'm the thing I am but a student
I am but a humble servant of J get this
guy a little bit
higher well there we go awesome well
we'll uh go mix up the medicine and
we'll show you guys that
next welcome back guys we are now here
on the deck in one of my favorite zones
around this house I I would say this
this Zone here second to The Hammocks oh
The Hammocks The Hammocks take it but I
mean it is very nice relaxing we always
get it when the sun's cominging down
because we're always like the evenings
or the midaf afternoons cuz well because
we're doing all this all day getting
ready that's it it's endless and you
know there's a little bit of behindthe
scenes stuff that we have to do to get
this stuff ready for you guys believe it
or not um so what we're going to do now
is we're going to show you a real simple
feeding using medy one one part system
John can tell you a little bit about it
and uh yeah it's it's what I use it's uh
everybody aome it's what I use and and
and as you can as Mark was saying it's
just it's just easy you know what and a
lot of you guys out there are your small
Growers and and really it's just like
give your bottle of shake right uh it's
a one part growing Bloom it's got all
everything you need um if you want to
learn more about it of course I'm sure
you can Google it but I'm not going to
get too much into it but I mean this is
this is yours and this is uh 15
milliliters one
one
tablespoon nice looks so killer coming
in last time I grew I was growing with
Earth Juice probably 15 16 even 17 years
ago it's been a while so uh the same
smell that guano wish kelpy just
awesomeness and of course I um brought
you some uh ph up and this is probably
enough to last in for about probably 3
years to give you a little bit of an
idea the water comes out of the tap here
at an 8ph oh really we just put the med
one in okay and that well maybe even
seven seven 7 point something um we just
put the med one in to that 7 to8 pH
water and that brought us down I'd say
it's going to be about 3.2 um right now
it's at 3.5 it's holding around 3.4 3.3
yeah for me I get 3.7 at my house 3.3
and and already Mark is now dialing in
his 32 that's awesome he knows exactly
what it is so I mean for me at this
point I'm going to step back because
he's already dialed then what you do you
know what I mean yeah and it took you
know it didn't take very long like it's
a very simple system John showed me how
to do it just basically dial the put it
the tinest little bit of pH up I've got
uh a half teaspoon here which is 2.5
milliliters and I won't even use that
much I'll actually see how much you're
using there you can see how he's uh I
can already see the the indent side he's
already got like a small measurement
that he keeps using and it looks like
youve got it dialed in my friend well
you know what I often will I'd rather go
slow because I don't have any pH down
yeah so there's we don't want to go over
PH down and then water down I've had to
do it so many times yeah but happen it
can happen but it's such a pain in the
butt oh huge I'd rather have uh so this
will probably take me up to about five
maybe 5.2 no it's still 4.5 so it's slow
I'm going to put probably the same
amount in there and of course we're
looking for a 6.2 to a 6.8 that's the
pretty much IDE pretty much what
everybody kind of aims for it's the
ideal neut
uptake
pH so we'll KCK a little bit more of
that out a little more more I probably
still haven't put a full one of these in
you can put a full one in and nail it
but if you go over the tiniest little
bit I'll tell you it takes forever to
get up to the right time amount
sometimes but one drop brings it up like
four points or something how did that
happen I don't know you know what so for
me the fun on my water I I my water
comes out of the top at 63 uh I
shouldn't say out of the top my
rainwater sometimes and out of the de um
sometimes I get 5'6 sometimes I get 62
oh yeah but I get I get an average of 50
Ms of Med One to 1 mil of pH take that
6.1 6.2 you've nailed it and he roughly
about a me in a bit there yeah yeah so
we've got our food it's mixed it's
simple um we went 15 MLS which um for
medy 1 week one you can go as low as 2.5
Mills per liter which is basically we
put in about double that but these
plants
here as well as these ones they've been
growing for over a week so we can start
in at the two week point for oh this is
what I I've been doing for um for years
I've been using med1 since 2010 I
started doing the testing on it and a
buddy you know what this is how I do
things this what works for the strands
that I know that work here sure
everybody really needs to pay attention
to how how you know some people burn
their plants um you know what I always
just take my time um I I don't feed too
heavy I uh I take my time just like
Mark's doing here he's got his whole
little watering techniques and how he
wants to do things and everybody's got
everybody's got their little techniqu do
it the way you want to do it that's the
coolest thing because it's your little
thing and it's your it's your it's it's
it's your medicine it's your growth you
got like these four five plants oh man
how are you going to let anyone tell you
anything you can listen to ideas and
Concepts and here you go buddy you want
to give those guys a couple of shots
these are bigger plants they could
probably even use another feeding but uh
these ons are quite small with a small
root mass so I think the amount of water
I gave them will be more than enough
probably about 600 milliliters little
bit under a
liter and uh John's just doing up the
Barb or no The Afghani sorry these were
the sweet
skunks and last but certain enough not
least if you want to slide that over
going to slide this over here pull this
one towards me and as I turn I was cuz
the all the dirt was on the side and the
moisture was already there so I was just
kind of feeding the do it your way do it
the way you like it yeah this is I'm
very into uh feeding right down on top
of the stock but at the same time you
don't want to do that all the time or
you can end up with a bit of uh stock
rot Remo was really uh showing me about
that with his big plants yeah it's it's
not as big of a Devastator on the small
plants but a big plant basically you get
a little bit of that and uh it ends up
locking up the root system and he can
lose an entire plant so what I did there
is cuz the P the plant went right in the
center and it had that little one in
wide there I think we got for me did
that the roots are all right there so it
just dri down to the outside yeah just
touching those roots and taking up the
uptake and these are going to so many
different ways the funny thing about
watering cannabis is you'll see like we
didn't even plan this did you notice he
watered it exactly the opposite way or I
watered it exactly the opposite way of
him if we were working together and
trying to grow together that would
basically divide our friendship and
because Growers have to do it their way
you all know you do you're all the same
way you have to do it so why we're going
to do it our way so I'm going to water
in the center John's going to water on
the outside and geez I bet you there's
100 other guys watering a hundred other
different ways I I would definitely
water in Cent when I'm going the smaller
plant I was looking at the bigger plant
so there's reasons for why I did this of
course we have different plants we have
different
that's the wonderful thing about growing
Canabis you can grow any way you want
and in the end resin talks so if you're
producing full melt resin and people are
telling you that you need to change the
way you're doing things but they
themselves are not producing full melt
resin you should avoid listening to
anything that they have to
say I listen to John and I listen to his
tips because he's producing full melt
resin you know and I haven't grown in 20
years although I have to admit I'm
feeling like I know what what I'm doing
that you should take we should take take
them inside and take a look at you
haven't grown into oh this looks amazing
in here dude well a small garden easy to
take care of all right all right so come
check this
out all right so here's my little guys
my little gals I should say all brought
over by you how long ago would you say
you brought these over John I don't know
it's been there for a month and a half
two months you think it's been that long
I don't even know we don't P more about
five and a half weeks I I don't even
know you know I think they've been
flowering for maybe four four and a bit
well they're looking amazing my friend
look at that so as you were saying like
look look at how well you're doing
you're doing amazing well we're
definitely you know avoiding new burns
on the tips I guess there's a little
yellow right there I know that would be
the you're starting to not feed the well
that's that's exactly it so now they're
starting to Autumn off and we're going
to start getting some uh you
know definitely uh the watermelon is
looking amazing yeah that looks
great really nice resin production here
uh underneath here we have the medic
Kush wow which is looking absolutely
spectacular as well just greasing right
up real nice living resin behind there
yeah Bubba cam right in behind there
kind of uh growing up
almost almost leafing out again kind of
stretching those buds out yeah I guess
it's the style of the Nugget cuz I've
definitely been avoiding all light in
this tunnel or in this uh tunnel in this
uh T little tent We Got My Little Pony
in the background now she's way behind
the rest of these guys because she's
going to flower for weeks more so her
resin production is not really on point
just yet compared to the rest of the
plants but she has a long way to go you
can see that satty Le just climbing up
there is that nice looking great all
right so dude you know what dude I think
we should uh
I think it's time for us to have a
puff and uh we'll get back to you guys
in a little bit
peace well another puff Wednesday is
complete John I figured we might as well
just finish it off with a sash like
always yeah the plants look and I was
just like look at how beautiful that is
and look at just like yeah you know what
they're looking happy they're looking
happy to see the new the new the new
structure and ah no complaints got
temperature wise here 749 perfect what
do we got over there in the balls today
well I think we got some watermelon
watermelon yeah a little bit of
watermelon from Mr
Ron this is some nice 90 Micron this is
well cured now it's been curing up since
uh December that's what I mean puffing
on my friend that's that little bit that
you gave me little bit seven G actually
a little bit he's like here just take a
little bit home he pour His bunch in
there I've be puffing on this for a
couple weeks weeks but it's almost done
load it
up so this is going to be nice today
we're going to hit the 90 mic run that
Ron has all nicely cured up for a couple
months and then we're going to hit the
90 Micron that that we made on your
birthday at both watermelon woo
I'll tell you this
one is so spicy and hashy because of the
long cure and he almost even over dried
it by leaving it out for so so long
that's a killer head that is a killer
head that's way too big I want you to
have it oh no here we go see wait a
second there we go what are friends for
mhm I'm going to give that a Little Help
by pushing it up against the wall
smudging it
out
yeah that's what friends are for right
there how's
that tasty I hope I love this
watermelon that's a nice little way to
clean the dab up right off the edge of
the table like
that well you know what like always um
we got something always new happening
here yeah there's always something new
happening on puff Wednesdays we uh
you know what El it's you guys are the
big inspiration your comments and uh
your views people just paying attention
to what we're doing it makes us feel
like holy [ __ ] people like this stuff
they they keep asking so we make more
videos and we come up with more ideas
and we're definitely down with your
comment ideas if you have ideas of
things you want to see me and John doing
that are within reason you know we're
not really kind of uh the crazy uh types
to just do a video about anything what
we'd like to learn if it's cannabis
related if it's something you want to
learn about if it's something that you
think we might know about or might want
to learn about throw a comment in and uh
you know let us know what your ideas are
we're down that's going to be um you
know we're going to need someone to
actually know structure that there's
going to be like all these comments
coming in that's okay it's going to be
fun here um oh what do we got what's
yours next Jack bear oh dry SI fo oh
boom boom
Shaboom yeah Jack rare this came
from well as he's hitting the tooke it's
a bong rip of course clean by only but
the master
here always beautiful been a really long
day as
always well I'm glad you made it byy
again man well you know what these
ladies um needed some bigger pots and uh
exactly grabbed a few supplies
from I work Mission Mondays so that's
what I do hooked me up there and it is
it is Monday today tomorrow's Tuesday
and we're going to be filming the second
part of puff Wednesday I got to start
filming these puff Wednesdays early
because I'm not putting them up till
Saturday or Sunday yeah so we're going
to actually do the starting of puff
Wednesday Tuesday and finish off on puff
Wednesday yeah well I mean this will be
the first part oh is it yeah this is the
first part of you coming by and doing
the plants and then tomorrow we're going
to go out to Siri to my buddy's
Warehouse um he's a wholesale or a
distribution distribution hydroponic
company and so we'll be looking at
picking up an 8x4 tent with some lights
and bulbs and all the little bells and
whistles that we'll need for the unit
and um yeah from there we're basically
going to boot back here to the garage
and set that tent up get these plants
into the top tent and get my blooming
plants that are currently in a very
small four uh 2 by 4 four so small I
know and get them into that 8x4 how
happy are they going to be under six
well I mean I could put three 600s in
there 3 600 yeah no it's um I'm excited
I'm excited I'm turning the whole thing
into hash like I am yeah in uh four
weeks or so um I'll be turning the four
watermelons the medic Kush and the uh
chem4 reunion into hash and I'm not sure
how I'm going to do it yet I might keep
one watermelon for sift and three for
bubble see it's hard because what I did
I I did half I went four I still have
one in the freezer at home I have My
Little Pony in the freezer at home and
we have medy Kush in your freezer from
yes that's still there yeah second run
we're getting backed up see what's
happening we're just so backed up but um
we're just not running out of resin it's
not needed right now but I'm sure when
the time gets close we'll definitely be
washing that yeah for sure there you go
[Music]
budos
oh
yeah one thing about the Dil is it
really sort of trains you to hit a bong
differently if you hit it like a beine
RI and you'll there's a lot of the hit
that's still there I find it's taking me
a while to train myself to do this long
slow sort of
haul so as you saw I was trying to do
small ones but Mark always here likes
that hit me hard let's go big let's go
big so now it's my turn let's go big now
you're going for the 90 fresh frozen
okay well kill me John my little Bon oh
you got your own thing there oh yours is
cleaner mine's a little warm though I
just cool it down right on the on the
stone just for a second the sift is not
a friend nor is the full melt bubble to
um a warm metal Skillet tool here we go
and see some clones on here with your
name on them John
and you'll be seeing those grow in my
garden too yeah you will there you go
ready kind started bubbling on top of
the that was amazing the way it
dissipated
yeah oh that is the 90th boom isn't it
yeah that's so nice and uh that's why it
hits almost sift like
there's no one on God's green earth that
could deny it looks like Sif the TP
Factor on that
resin but it doesn't it's different I
guarantee if we had the same well let's
do it let's make sift from my watermelon
in there I'll dry it I'll hang it for
like 14 to 21 days break it up gently
over the screens and then the other two
plants I'll break up two over the large
screens and I'll do two into the Bubble
Bags there we go I'm so
excited I'm yeah actually what's funny
is I I just cut down my last four
watermelon and my three medic kushers
last night oh yeah and they're hanging
because the ones I did previously two
weeks prior I just took them extra long
like day
105 um having fun now I'm going to dry
sift those hey do you want to cut a
couple of clones right now do you want
to take a couple of these barbs in
Afghan home today yeah yeah okay well
let's do that let's gra one of each for
now perfect yeah
go
here okay so we're back um I managed to
grab the two that John gave me the other
day with I guess he gave me three
actually but I gave one away that's a
nice thing who did I give that to see
that's what we're talking about is
Sharon I don't even remember who I gave
it to it'll come back wow cool someone
got it they're stoked um I only had
three but I gave one away cuz of course
that's what you do you you give one away
or two if you have three as long as you
got one for you and so now these two
that John gave me just the other day
that were full of watermelons I guess
now are going to become an Afghan and a
Barb so we're going to put an A on this
one a a and coincidentally we're going
to put a B on the other one A and B who
would have thought it that's hilarious
yeah maybe the next one we should cut is
the
anatonic c
c and then D digweed digweed yeah that's
one of that those are olds that's that's
awesome so you know what the best thing
about this is is once I get these old
nights and healthy is I'm going to cut
an A and A B and I'm going to give it
some well I hope you do I think it's a
beautiful thing isn't this what we're
doing so you want to get you want to go
pretty small here you think it's
something like this that's be you know
very easy it's a nice little clone hey
yeah it's on the major uh just go at an
angle it'll still leave a growth
sight all right want just pull this guy
off
yep oh yeah give me a tiny little bit
more
Perfecto one little one little unit one
little unit there you go that is one
afgh poros
and now a Barb find yourself a nice Barb
you can take anyone you want anyone I
want you said you found one said no no I
I had seen one on The Afghani truly like
it just was standing there saying I'm
take me yeah I'm looking at this one
right inside of here see this inside cuz
it would actually wouldn't work too well
see this one here I'm going to show the
which one here so on the inside here
this one on the inside here you see this
one's coming in so these that's the one
I was looking at this one here is going
to cause a problem in a sense in the
future but we'll make an amazing big
clone beautiful clone and what I was
doing before what I showed you on my
channels my it would be okay if I peel
would you like me to just cut right
below that you do whatever you like it's
a pretty big Branch so you definitely
don't want to leave too big of an
exposure there so what I'm looking here
yeah leave maybe one growth sight is I
can leave these two growth sites and I'm
going to cut nice big long stem nice big
long stem straight
across and then I'm going to cut it on a
five and there's your B and there's my
V Barbara and Afghan I'm super stoked
dude dude yeah it's awesome thanks Matt
thanks Matt we couldn't have done this
without you buddy you were the beginning
of this circle and we're going to follow
this around and we're going to see how
far it goes I want to give him a number
four yeah well you will give them a
number four we're all this is exciting
once you start sharing strains that's
the energy that you start falling into
into this energy oh the cat's chasing
the dog interesting so you know what
they're having some fun today but they
are you having fun buddy he's like come
right here you chasing the
cat that's the best thing about life
okay leave the cat alone yes leave the
cat alone all right so we took a couple
of clones the cycle put the mosquito on
man is he a big mosquit look at that wow
I I that would be a shot right there
that would be a wish I had my macro lens
cuz Al you move too close to that guy oh
no he's not moving he's happy I should
run and get my macro lens it's a huge
monster mosquito just I think he's going
to sit there I think he's going to sit
there very cool let's hit up yeah I
think we should we've taking a clone and
uh each oh you got Barb don't you I have
Barb somewhere I put Barb in my pocket
look at that so we're going to hit some
Barb and some Afghani now you know what
I think we have
that might
be yes yes that's Barb right there well
Afghani we have to go hunt down well
we're going to hit the Barb CU we just
cut her yes I think it's it's a must
that we I think it is yeah it's a
wonderful thing is it you up or me I
think it's you I saw the size of that so
I'm going to go it's his
turn all right then I'll take it never
pull a dab you wouldn't take for
yourself
beautiful meltt and that's the best part
about the bar I'm really looking forward
to Growing it and of course I'm going to
use my feeding program I'm going to use
Med one that's it and
um yeah massive actually no I use
massive sometimes depending how I feel
but I'm definitely going to grow her my
way and uh we're going to be smoking her
and uh I'm going to say about four
months cuz I like to uh do my little way
and I like to hang
and I think it's a 60-day strain I don't
even know I have to I'd like to know
exactly well I'll take it how long that
I feel it's ready where uh I like to
stretch things and take things to their
LM you know what's interesting since I
started growing again after 20
years um is that I'm not really I I like
the idea of a generalization but so far
like Matt gave me these strains I didn't
even ask how long you would flower them
for I'll flower them for as long as I
want to flower them for I'll grow them
I'll watch them I'll photograph them and
I'll decide when they're ready to be cut
down everyone's different and I think
that's a great way to go you don't have
to let anyone tell you when the best day
uh to cut a strain down is cuz it's
really giving up a lot you've you know
you've already maybe potentially uh
given up the person choosing a selection
or a
phenotype we've already given up so much
I'm happy to grow people's the the work
that people have
done but I'm definitely not given that
last uh well I do think things different
like I mean like we did in the last we I
cut all my bottoms we made made some
beautiful beautiful [ __ ] fresh frosen
with it I've let it go for another
couple more weeks and I'm going to take
those tops that's what I'm going to do
too yeah that's what you know what and
when you said this and I was like you
know what I'm doing this I think I think
you said it and I just just went and did
it I like that makes sense or I've been
doing it or I just I just you know what
well all of a sudden those resin glands
have access to the light they're already
there they've just H they haven't
fruited out oh you we don't care how
much bigger the buds get that's not what
we're trying to attempt to do TR we're
trying to get resin we want to Sugar out
the resin we want to mature the resin
and we want that resin to be just melty
yeah melty and awesome so definitely has
to melt you know what
um that's the key yeah
absolutely I'm going to go find the afan
all yeah
yep and of course the Afghani we've hit
the Barb let's hit the Afghani
the two we just cut oh look at how that
is in there that's it's cream this is so
good here you go sir you had the Barb
mhm you didn't have the Barb no oh my
God okay you hit the Afghani first this
is so funny and I'm slightly baked oh
that also just melts away to nothingness
lovely so I've hit the Barb he's hit the
fan next up Afghani for me and then Barb
for
John trying to keep this our game on
point here sometimes it's not too easy I
think I might have done one actually
really yeah I think I think I think I
help myself we'll have to watch I think
I help myself it'll be on
video I might get two out of
this definitely tasty you know what I
know I had
one we're just being
stonners but you know what it's always
great you know looking at the strings
and uh how affect us and this one here
is definitely what we need for
nighttime it's just hit me right away
nicely so that's
Barb and
Afghani tomorrow we're going to set up
the 4X 8 tent and go to sir and check
out the shop we'll see you tomorrow guys
thanks again John you there yeah dude we
will see you in Siri s peace
out he let's do that one more time
our end all right so where will we start
we'll start at
like that's Barb yeah that's
Afghani and uh I guess uh we'll leave it
at that and we'll see you guys tomorrow
in sui I'll see you there John awesome
dude sweet
peace yeah I like that
one the
people n own
[Music]
designer
people today
tomorrow today
tomorrow man not real worri today
tomorrow same
way real worri today
tomorrow no
black the direction the truth we
we hold the the see the youth and Al the
truth and capure the spirit and then
Rapture recruits when act you determine
the action the move definition
message we carry use history of the
brothers take a step in them Sho so you
man be Rebellion before the stor with
the
yourday
[Music]
tomorrow
today today tomorrow same
way man wor today tomorrow
not in these last days with babon me off
Pathways in the valleys and
the me like like
aing when start up boots no fear there
aold Ste no scissons no comb here no sh
no sleep at
times weak at times some people can have
peace of mind but this peace of mind is
very relative them want to take a pece
of mind and s relatives when we come
them see how dread it is cutting off the
enemies
energies man real today tomorrow same
way today tomorrow we
[Music]
not