[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh haven't filmed a video for a few days
I released macro photographs from 2008
and I have 09 10 11 12 and 13 all sort
of cute but I didn't want to just shoot
a bunch of macro photographs all at once
so I figured today I would do some hits
um out of the sublimator which we have
right here the 2.0
XTR as well as the denail which we have
right here um plugged into the quartz
PUK and be bowl and it's in a bubble man
Edition rure kind of neat hav't hit one
of those I also pulled out my little uh
I guess they call this the was it a
peashooter they had a name for it I
can't remember uh Martin gave me this
pipe a couple of years ago at the
Cannabis Cup um had a little boo boo
broke the bistable but the way the down
stem fits on this one still works
perfectly so going to hit that one um
very nice gift got this gift from Nate
Dizzle when I brought him and Steve hops
to amster uh sorry met in Amsterdam we
brought them to Germany uh to link up
with Martin from rwer where they did
some collaborations uh that was very
nice of Nate to give me that pipe Steve
also gave me a little pipe that I would
love to have here doing this little
Gauntlet but unfortunately uh I smashed
that one just a few weeks ago uh also
last but finally not least uh the
Sheldon black which Richard gave me um
several years ago now uh from Amsterdam
and what is it the six arm pretty
straightforward little unit um thanks to
hippo for fixing this bistable cuz I
broke that about a year and a half ago
and of course I've got the Mother Ship
here ready to go uh with the XTR uh
actually what we should do is we'll show
you turning on all the units so um for
the denail which is right here this is
my custom bubble man version we've got
the remote control so simple as pushing
that little button is going to turn that
unit on that'll be up to temperature in
about 3 minutes um the XTR also has a
nice
little little guy we just just push that
little button the light goes
on and then we dial it in I'm going to
go for herb which is about a seven not
sure if you guys can see that right
there
but all right so very important once you
do turn the sublimator on never to uh as
well as the Dil for that matter these
are both hot units be very careful as
you're leaning over in any way dealing
with this units you just have to
remember that they're they're very hot
and that uh you can burn yourself if
you're not careful so I think while we
are waiting for the denil and
the sublimator to turn on I'm going to
turn on the Ember which is a wireless um
ceramic heater much like the herb iron
and that was gifted to me oh 3 or 4
years ago in Amsterdam as well so for
that I think we're going to hit some
seedsman hay bubble I've got a custom
stainless steel screen inserted into to
the um Lux Bowl which was also a gift
from Richard man lots of kind people out
there so I suspect for this we are going
to need a little
beine which I have many of right
here and a little lighter couple of
things I haven't needed for a
while but it just goes to show I got a
lot of people asking me what you prefer
this what you prefer I love it all I
love a quiver I get into things you know
when I first got my sublimator I used it
endlessly when I first my Dil I used it
endlessly when I first got the beine I
used it endlessly and now I'm using you
know right now I'm using basically the
last few days the sublimator in the
denail the sublimator is allowing me to
hit herb again which is great um I do
have a solo from ritzer which is another
cordless little vaporizer which is great
for hitting herb on the go but it
doesn't really give you that punch that
the sublimator will give you pretty much
every time
so light the old beine with the
greenhouse lighter let's get this
Gauntlet started shall
we all
right always nice to start a gauntlet
with some mind melding sativa seedsman
Hayes um bubble hash often is the
best in around the 45 to 73 Micron this
particular batch that I just hit uh is a
45 Micron one of my favorites so let's
see um the denail will be hitting now I
think we're going to go with the
denail let's keep it
sativa and let's go
rip some great Gardener sweet skunk this
is dry sift that I cleaned up a few
weeks back it was extremely beautiful
dry sift even through a single screen I
managed to clean it up a little bit and
make it a little bit more beautiful so
this will also be my first denail rip
out of pretty much anything other than a
Mothership so looking forward to hitting
my custom rure
all right using the quartz carb cap as
well oh man The Taste on that quite
nice all right so we did the beine we
did the um D now let's hit an ember rip
real
quick we'll do an ember rip of some
Bubba cush bubble and we're going to go
for the end rip let me see what we got
here we have bowls and bowls and
[Music]
bowls let's do the Ember rip out of the
little guy
here don't actually have my three push
uh Bowl so I'll have to throw those
stainless steel onto this as well get
some of that Bubba Cush
super
nice all right love the feel of this
bong just having the bman rure in my
hand which funny enough this is a bman
rure as well it it has my logo etched
into the back which you can kind of see
there this one's got it in the front
it's my color sequence red gold and
green all right let's see what we got
here just turned on the
Ember as I was going to hit the first
bowl with it and I I realized I wanted
to do the be line first first so beine
denail and now we're going to Ember up
once that gets nice and red hot for us
so it's got a blue light that's half red
and once it goes full red uh that's
generally where you see the tip of the
ceramic turn orange I can see it
happening
now oh this is great still got a few
more pipes to rip looking forward to the
sublimator herb hit I'm going to do both
a sublimator herb and a full melt bubble
rip here we
go for
ooho that was pretty special really
grabbed me by the back of the
throat it's quite amazing how different
each one of those hips were from the
combustion with the flame to the denail
rip with the quartz Bowl to the Ember
rip and then the sublimator
oh yes I think that sublimator will be
up to
[Music]
Temp oh yeah so generally with the
sublimator to actually get it to work
this is
important when you put it in the bowl
heating the bowl is part of the process
you can't really get sublimator rips
with a cold Bowl heating up the bowl to
the temperature that the nail or the
wand or whatever you want to call the
unit is very important and this is
something that you learn pretty quickly
so I've got two types of herb here I've
got if you can imagine some UBC chemo
and some rock star from Remo from it's
got to be a month and a half ago when I
went there the first time and shared
with you a video and then I've also got
some really beautiful it's one of John's
kushes this one's just
purple and both of these because I get
given herb all the time and I don't
really um
I don't smoke it um I basically often
give it away when I came across the
sublimator I started saving it my
sublimator uh I sent it back for the new
version and I've been waiting so I had I
wasn't using cannabis so basically this
cannabis became very dry which in my
opinion is generally pretty good for
vaporization you don't really want moist
herb I find even when the sublimator
isn't giving me that first real RightWay
rip it's generally because there's too
much moisture left in the herb
so we will grind it up with one of
John's
medtainers don't see me do that very
often I feel bad I've never really been
able to promote this little product of
John's and uh it's not because I dislike
it it's just that I've never used it for
anything other than to carry like stacks
of hash in so now that's all changing so
why don't we start with
John it's quite
simple sure won't need to do much to
powder that herb
all
right I use the tool that unrio
supplies to stuff the herb down a little
bit if you it's very fluffy so if you
leave it sit this goes into the bowl a
fair distance and I've seen people do
this as well where they push the top of
the sublimator down onto the herb and it
can potentially cause a little bit of
burning so here we
go oh my
goodness can't even really describe the
subtle differences and nuances that
you'll feel when you hit a sublimator
for the first time
um there's just something different
there there's something a little bit
more than what the the other
vaporization companies have come up
with it's just a really nice
taste packed with a really great hit
this is how much I put in this little
bud
[Music]
I mean come on that's the real [ __ ]
right
there a little tiny nugget has me
hacking more than all those beautiful
bowls
P you
all right well thanks for watching we'll
see you soon on B
[Music]