hey guys bubble man here just about toh
take a rip here on the sublimator from
enrio um this is an amazing incredible
new device that I just recently got
turned on to and um aside from the fact
that it's a gasification process
sublimation turning the the solid into a
gas without going through a
liquid I can't say enough about how it
affects the hit how wonderful it tastes
even though this is a plastic tube and I
never smoke out of plastic tubes
although I suspect I'll get myself the
wand working with just uh glass bong in
the near future but for now I'll show
it's as simple as loading up a little
bowl or big one for that matter some
watermelon full
melt putting that in the old mouth and
dropping this into the
[Music]
chamber
pretty incredible size Vapor hit it
dissipates very fast in the air The
Taste is unparalleled particularly once
you start playing around with the heat
and getting it to that perfect heat
temperature that was a dry hit through a
plastic tube I'm not even coughing um
the size of the vapor molecules the way
it breaks them down allows it to get so
deep into your lungs everyone has said
it once they've exhaled it it's this
incredible permeation and the tpin in
your mouth and in your throat really
quite a good little unit I'm sure
there's a little bit left
[Music]
here anyway that's the
sublimator hope uh hope you enjoy we're
going to have more videos of it coming
up soon and uh myself the bubble bag
booth and sublimator will be at the
treating yourself expo from May 24th to
26th so hopefully we'll see you
there