[Music]
hey guys John B and Bubble Man back in
the house actually just outside of the
house outside of the House John just
rolled up for puff Wednesdays might have
uh seen on his uh Facebook post that he
was going to set up a medical marijuana
Garden Tent today and lo and behold it's
house dude so what you got here what you
bring us let's check this stuff out you
bring us we got a little bit of
everything here that's the best part all
right so first we're going to take these
off the top because we wanted these to
put the pots on because you got such a
cold oh yeah these are great these are
great these are 4x4 grow Tech uh tubs so
basically they're going to they're going
to fit the plants just perfect this is
exciting so this is what I picked up
from your
buddy and he's got these new bulbs all
right we got the Dig digilux uh high
output digital bulbs these are sweet dig
metal highi lamps it's got the Spectrum
analysis on the side 75,000
lumens I'm really curious about these I
I've never seen these before Oh the Nano
yeah these look so cool revolutionary
ballast yeah it's like check that I
opened up the top and I was like okay I
got to stop right there because the next
step is you sh me these look really
Stell they're small they're ttin dude
this is ridiculous 600 WT B I know I
just like what the hell like and four
bulbs four bulbs we got two mides and
two HS HPS is Perfect Two 600 W Bast
these look ridiculous I know it's pretty
cool what else did you bring here John
to set this down right here for now all
right here I can do that as well um well
you know what one thing we have to have
is of course venting you you need air
air movement I say is the key with
everything it's definitely really you
you lack air and one of the things I've
noticed in a lot of gardens that I've
shot over the years that one thing they
have in common with a lack of air is
they usually either have a high amount
of mildew or they have a high amount of
bugs bugs don't seem to like the big air
Mo movement you know when you you keep
your plants happy the the temperatur is
down so four Honeywell uh power
circulator Force Power
25% and I didn't go like to like
Canadian car anything there I went to my
buddy he own a company called uh H&amp;M and
he hooked us up dude yeah I got that bud
totally hooked up so we got four of
those awesome we got this duck I've
never seen this before so I'm sorry I I
did this Che the out for 6 in and I was
like wow the camera it comes it comes
with two brackets and it's a this this
stff feel this I was like really
surprised aluminum three layer how many
feet is this 25 yeah I was going to say
20 or 30 ft so you know we're going to
need L up because we have 6 in and 8 in
going on so you know this is the start
of it excellent then we got these mobile
sockets but what we're done with this is
a little bit different cuz these don't
come with shad so we're going to use
those probably somewhere else right cuz
we talked about that so that
we got the adjusted Wing Shades ah
excellent all right everyone loves the
adjusta wings these are I believe what
the great Gardener grows with there you
go yeah yeah the adjust the wings and uh
of course uh those up to Green Planet
all those on that Green Planet linked us
up really nicely check those guys out if
you guys uh have some Hydroponics needs
and I'll also be linking up a website in
the title of this video for all this
other stuff I got through these guys uh
they're a Distribution Company but I'll
be linking you through to stores that
also sell these products so more ducting
over there more ducting well this is
going to be the 8 in for that that
Wicked fan right there oh you got an 8
in hyper of fan you remember we told
anything man I just he just brought me a
6 in about maybe two months ago and man
I've never fallen in love with a fan but
I got to say out of all the little toys
I've gotten in this new Growing
Experience I got to give it up to hyper
fan it's it's like buying one of my own
products in a sense that when I got it I
felt right away that it was quality and
that it was good and of course it ended
up being even more and better than what
I thought it was I'm super stoked on
that that's a 8 in fan 75t 75 Watts with
uh 126 CM an hour dude 75 WT my other
one's 35 your other no your vortex my 6
in hyper fan is 35 watt crazy tiny
little thing can clear my air uh in my T
instantly yeah when I saw 710 CFM 75 WTS
I was like hello wellc how do you
awesome so we got that we got the honey
Wells we got the hyper fan and of
course so we got the ultra hangers these
are great for the adjust the wings yeah
these are great they are so killing
these are definitely key with the little
carabiners in there and that nylon on
it's strong uh up to 150 lb perfect and
I of course got some Zippy strips to
attach those Z straps are essential size
so we had to that things we don't even
know that we want is
thatan in there oh got number right here
I'm used to this so of course it's all
about safety so I got you this flame
Defender so automatic self-contained
fire extinguisher now John is a smart
guy uh he just doesn't talk the talk he
does walk the walk and this is an
important thing if you're going to build
yourself a little
garden understand that you're not a
professional sometimes in all the
different aspects and if you're not a
professional maybe the best thing to do
is cover your ass in any and every way
that you can this being a great way
protect yourself your growing
environment your
home is your most important thing and so
this will be uh basically in the tent
and it stays like a sprinkler it'll stay
over top of your your timer here that I
for for the L Foams out uh it lets off
it's not a foam if if it goes above 95
that will let off well basically your
plants are dead anyways so these are
it's power okay dry M dry
chemical excellent well I mean hey
better than burning the house down
that's for sure there you go of course
controller this is key this master light
controller this the big thing right here
four lights 15 amps 120 and 240 volts
relay hello why not do it the right way
if you're going to do it all these
products are an imperative part on
growing properly the little things you
think you don't need like the simple
timer becomes the biggest nightmare you
could ever possibly imagine trying to
wake up twice a day to turn your lights
on and turn them off and all that it's
ridiculous and then one extension cord
per each timer and like dude please no
that that's what they talk about people
are causing fires and stuff cuz they're
being unsafe they do the key things yeah
it's just little things temp so you hook
your fan up to this so if it actually
gets a little too hot therat thermostat
turns on so your room is never above 80°
cuz this will always vent out off of
that another great idea uh to make up
for potential human error and to make up
for things that we can't foresee like
those random days where it's supposed to
be 15 or 20° which I guess would be
about 65 or 70 Fahrenheit for the
Americans and all of a sudden it's uh
you know 30 or 40° that day Celsius
which would be about
110 f so therat perfect buddy I got you
that and then of course I got you the
human thermostat that's key you know so
that way you know and with this one here
you get set so you know your minimum and
maximum so when the lights go off you're
going to know your humidity I can't
actually imagine not having this simple
piece of information uh John brought one
by with the first tent that we set up uh
in my office and uh every day I look at
my humidity and my temperature every day
I used to write it down I knew
everything I wrote everything down for
years the how everything fluctuates so
in fact the hyper fan because before you
brought the hyper fan really is a
testament
to the the temperature that it keeps my
tent at on 35% I never have to turn it
up full just on 35% which is as low as
you can go with a hyper fan it's got a
variable re uh little uh dial and you
can only turn it down to 35% power and
it it it's pretty quiet at that point
but it's still working um it keeps my
tent at 7 75° it never goes warmer even
the other day when it peaked at about
20° my tent was like 76° oh that's sweet
yeah so these are definitely also I
would really say this is an important
part of of your grow
tent excellent so maybe we'll get the
table out we get the table out we'll set
up the camera at a different angle and
we'll show you guys all this stuff sort
of uh oh well we also have the tent we
got to get the tent out we haven't even
shown you the tent is these hard hard
trays you were talking about oh those
are key as well little key things here
get rid of some of this stuff the idea
is we're going to pull this table out
we're going to set everything on the
table so we can work off of it and uh
this is all you need you can set
everything up here that's it rough cost
here is you know going to give you the
cost of everything here which is roughly
about about 15 16 I think retail yeah
perfect work off a table all right so
this is it is a 4x8 secret jarden it's
the dr24 w same one I got at home the
secret jardan yeah I love it dark
room Dr what does it say that oh it's a
dark room it's a dr40 w the dr40 W I
started off with one of those and then
moved over to uh a good friend of mine
and he has it all going right now you're
a good guy John and then I gave another
one away you know what these things are
key for people growing their medicine
and this what we talk about is being
able to grow your own medicine at home
and we're going to show you how we all
grow our own medicine at home you know
for the for the cost of maybe under
$22,000 you can have a setup where you
start producing resin and one of the
great things about these videos that
John and I are showing you right now and
you can check out John H Bell's Channel
at John H Perell on YouTube as well for
his own separate grow videos is that I'm
going to show you how much resin you can
grow in one of these tents I'm not going
to tell you well I mean I am going to
tell you how much bud I get as well but
it's not going to be weighed dried
trimmed it'll be uh look I got this much
wet I ran it I got this much dry resin
it's going to be about resin production
so I'll be able to tell you how much
square foot you need to produce how much
resin per month to set yourself up for
your I love that you know what like
everybody's asking with me how much how
much do I need to grow to grow myself
one gram a day that would resin that's
the question that's the question we're
going to answer in the upcoming months
so this is what this is all about right
now this is awesome yeah dude let's get
the table out let get it going you know
what all right so we got the tent ready
to
basically pull
out open the box up
anyway all right okay this is all in a
nice bag it comes in a bag are you
serious that's really
nice get
up just have it in the uh have it in the
bag look at that so
these are the corners so this why nice
to have the table R besid you hear
absolutely there's the
instructions yes inst stret this tells
us how to put this bad boy together that
will be
required we have many different bags of
post actually going to show you how this
go together I would suggest that these
bags of posts are not to be all mixed up
immediately oh no no you keep defitely
St
and
[Music]
uh here's the liner that goes on the
inside here excellent so this will be
the inside
liner and uh that will be for the hooks
this is going to be your little Windows
a yes
little and the bag will come useful for
when we uh move it to uh someone else's
place yeah exactly it will and we'll
have that on film as well so there's
those hooks
the first thing we're going to do is
we're going to actually put this
together I always do first yes
absolutely so every one of these are
numed we have a e
b
b these are going to be our rails we can
take just right across the thing I done
so many of these I've actually probably
set up like 30 of these okay so um this
will be our top so we can just move
these right out of the way for now don't
have to be in our area excellent put
them over here on the snowmobile there's
going to be our four main Corners so let
going to start our bottom base excellent
so we'll open those
up the
direction the directions are never a bad
idea so now we're going to get all the
A's fairly simplistic directions too
it's pretty easy so we have all our A's
I do this so I can get my bottom base
and then you know how big your tent's
going to be see like this yep and then
the other one goes there these are the
two metals it just shows that these four
corners see these Corners are those not
these yes I said so perfect that's all I
was trying to make sure we have that
right it's always good to have a friend
to go over this with make sure yeah a
couple sets of eyes are better than
one said3 still going to read the
instructions I'll show you the
instructions too real quick it's a nice
little sheet
here dark
room and then it's also got a step by
step so we're basically in this step
right here we're going to set up the
base and once we get that done we'll
move on to the next point of business
what just getting the we just basically
set this Frame Up ever so
simply so that was real
easy we SC we got that put together our
frame pull those bees out pass me three
bees one two two three and three and
these are tapered one end so you can
actually put the top together and make
the height perfect so that's a good idea
if you uh heard what John said the
tapered end goes up because you're going
to be adding the extra metal piece to
get the
height okay so that's oh you want me to
plug that in but that doesn't plug in
Stand It Up Stand what up stand up oh it
stands
up and then we're going to put the top
one pieces at a time yeah I think all at
once would be sweet okay
if it's you know cuz it's so not heavy
it's not it's we can do it we can do it
and we're grabbing just a plastic and it
seems like all the parts that could fall
out have already fallen
out have already fallen out so I'm just
going to
grab I'll just come over and plug them
all in yeah I figured if I don't move
oh that's beautiful oh that's a
beautiful okay so inside and now we're
at the point where we just have to
basically zip it together zip it
together so let's pull this pop over and
then we can zip it down is there a top
oh yeah there here but I was trying to
do in the beginning what I was
oh that's a
tent Johnny all right
tent
accomplished
excellent
so you should open up the front door and
take a look inside
yeah how's that people we just got
ourselves so this is how I mount my fans
in my tent and because there isn't that
much room I like to get them up high so
what I do is I've just started taking
this out of the
box get this out of the box and I drill
holes in the bottoms and you know what I
always like to go right through the
bottom like this cuz you kind of want to
keep it close because of course it's
just a pull on each side right
yeah
so know the light is in here here's our
switch that's going to blow down and as
you can see and now the Fan's perfectly
mounted in the corner you can adjust it
and it blows the wind on the plants
we're going to put these in all four
corners beautiful and that's just the
way I mount my fans excellent man yeah
all right so we've got all four of our
fans mounted two on the left side two on
the right
side a quick zap strap tip from John B
now we're going to take this little
piece of grate and this is how I'm going
to mount the little timer cuz the way
they have it is they make it difficult
but I came up with this ingenious little
way of I cut this down and we're going
to tape this on there and zap strap it
to the side and then we're going to
mount the timer next and that way we can
start plugging things in and then we're
going to take the piece of board to
mount the fans well I'm just going of
come in here like this and pretty much
cuz our power and everything is running
off of this corner right okay okay
that's where you want the power so we're
going to mount this little thing like
this and I got this uh handy little tape
cuz it's you know tin foil tape looks
nice too
[Music]
just like
that just like that just little handy
tips make like easy you know yeah and
then we're going to put some zap strap
so I'm going to make sure it's really
good and tight and we're going to zap it
again all right and then we're going to
mount the fire extinguisher up here okay
and then the lights will be right here
perfect yeah all right just little
stages all right the master lighting
control see what what we
got to verify the ballasts you plan to
run with the mlc or properly internally
connected to 12240 volt operation all
right so what do we got here we got
ourselves a mlc 4X Master lighting
control so check this out so just me
being
jie
this turn into it perfect yeah yeah that
makes perfect sense
let's get that done all right so John
be's mounted that really quite nicely
it's in place and ready for ready for
the next adjust a wing so we're at that
point yeah my my favorite I love these
things medium size for a tent it's all
you need those big ones are great but
they're definitely not going to come
inside of there right so I got that nice
little package and how these come apart
here is really quite how they I love how
they do this they put a little
protection on it
open it
up and boom and on the other side is
this little blue conone we're going to
peel this off and we're going to put
this thing
together look at that you do this as you
can see putting together these little
grow tents are very very easy it's
really a a no brainer in a sense like
anybody can really do it you have the
hooks on each side
here as you can see we put these
together and you slide it that's it
that's it then the next step as it shows
here you put the little folds on the top
which you've got right
there yeah it's a nice little
uh
product I I really enjoy this part cuz
they're just so easy and then simply use
the wires to loosen or tighten them
angle the lights at different angles
going to mount look at how easy this
comes beautiful local socks completely
attached it mounts on the underneath all
we have to do is wire that into the
ballast just plug that in yeah to the
ballast right into the ballast beautiful
I know so simple they make it and this
is all the CSA you know it's all great
to
go and it'll plug into the Ballance just
like that just like that beautiful El
approved right there very important here
in Canada and that's Plug and Play the
majority of ballasts will oh that will
all balles yeah all the older ball you
know what most balles are all the
same so so now you're going to mount
that in
there right so we just screw that little
guy right in
there and I got the other on the other
hand need a hand holding that or there
you go thank you sir let me get that for
you there we go
and is it
grabbing pretty easy here we're just
going to like unwind them and as you can
see each end's got two this one here is
got the different holes yeah and this
one here has got the single so I'm just
going to
proceed with putting this one right in
this side
here all right and I'm going to set this
one off to the
side and the best part about these
is they just bend they just bend they
just bend we can stick this in here like
this wrap this around here like this and
then pick your your length that you want
it at well you can actually pick your
your different sizes there exactly right
which decides the length of the cord
which decides how
angled there we go the reflector
becomes beautiful so that one's open but
if we got the tent there we can kind of
give her another full yeah no problem
and go into this one simple simple
simple
simple they're nice little almost not
very metallic are they that's a
plasticky like yeah they work pretty
well you
know I have
simple yeah I've definitely seen them at
the great gardeners Matt's got them now
you got
them and the easiest part about it is
there's just no no screws no nothing
it's just there perfect and now check
this out now now we're going to grab
these hooks I'd love to check it out but
you put you turned your back to me all
right so here is
the
nanolux the inlet cord right here
sweet and there's our
ballast o I'm going to have to get you a
110 plug
yeah that is awesome that is nice
nice looking little unit you got a
little dial there too huh yeah dimming
different percentages looks like that's
going to plug perfectly right into this
isn't it yeah absolutely I saw the plug
it fits perfect perfect just a matter of
uh figuring this out that's the 240
we'll have to get it's just your basic
computer so 300 oh I've got one y
perfect perfect perfect now check this
out we have our hangers ready okay we
got our hangers
we're going to clip these on into here
beautiful like
that and undo
this have the little button here so we
can kind of do
this and all we do is you lip this
around and then we hang it and then just
put one on each side and one on each
side excellent excellent just like my
light in my tent right now just like the
lights in your tent right now right now
and then we're going to mount those
balles right on that little board
underneath of that other one we have
over there and you know
what let's go rock this
in really quite easy
[Music]
and there's a light or a or a reflector
with ready for a
light and now we're just showing you how
we get this we adjusted properly and how
Mark wants to have them in here if he
wants to have them sideways and stuff so
pretty
much how easy it can be look at this I I
I love this cuz normally I have one Bast
in here and a 600 I had a 400 on the
track is what I have before but this
here is just so convenient would you
like me to give you a hand there at all
or um you know what if just hold that
there and then you've got both your
hands yeah I like that I'm going to move
it down about that much be able to put
the zap strap through the back
here and we're going right around around
how we did the last one coming in like
this strap in strapping it
in we like zap straps they seem to work
quite well boom yeah zap straps are
great zap zaps are
great so I want to go kind of through
the back like that I just did that other
one okay I went through here like this
oh that's a great idea yeah was just
kind of you know what make sure make
sure it ain't going to go side to side
or anything like that yeah I mean that's
something you'd want to have nicely uh
secured
other things you got to look at safety
but uh once again we're going to cut
this one off here how we just did the
other ones make it look all nice and
clean absolutely hyper fan time hyper
fan this is my favorite part John I'm
not going to lie this love the [ __ ]
hyper of course here's a little remote
control there oh yes yes and it's like
really it's so light see
like so light dude that's ridiculous I
know 75 WTS light I mean I mean what do
you think that weighs 12 lb I'm just
going to do this guys you want me to
hold it up there for
you all
right
whoopsie up and I got that there want to
move your hand for a second I here yeah
all right now we just got to get our
last two in there I felt on the outside
of the tent you want to put that fourth
screw in yes I'm going to get her done
right now I mean this fan I'll tell you
one thing people you do not want to
leave this even when the screws that he
put in all at Angles I have to say I was
a bit nervous because this this thing
has to be tight on the
board excellent when I oh she's tight
she's very tight
excellent you know what then we go to
there that's the hyper fanc me Hyper fan
loaded this tent is getting full Johnny
oh yeah you know
what this tent is getting full now we're
going to put the ducking right through
here for the 10
in perfect we got it all ready yeah peek
in there
hey all right so we've gotten to
installing the most important part
security security and our security here
happens to be a fire extinguisher
because really that's only the security
we really need sure we've already
mounted it up in the top Corner yeah
pointing down right above our
Electronics everything's right there so
if anything goes wrong this is where our
fire is going to start is going to be
here not at the mobile socket or the
bulb but this is if anything's going to
happen maybe something will show it out
here well if that happens boom automatic
fire extinguisher this is extell we have
no problems house is safe awesome there
we go this a sell a little tent dude
this is a Stellar tent okay buddy I love
it wow I like that I can't I'll watch
you open yours that was like St see
they've got this almost like a little
piece that would fit into your shoe it
feels like foam cut to the bulb that's
look at these bulbs so we'll get these
bulbs out without touching them with our
fingerprints we'll see if we can do that
they they come in a little it's like a
velvet little thing and you know what
I'm just holding on to it like that
that's pretty cool
so um I'm just going to get in here and
screw this sucker
in I'm with John I've never been into
touching my light bulbs it's just
something that I feel more comfortable
um you know not touching the light bulb
direct it shouldn't be done you get
those oils on the bulb and
quite awesome all right B again that
Ball's plugged
in all we really have to do is plug in
our
ballasts as
currently let's see what we're missing
here what are we missing Johnny oh the
other plug the other plug the other plug
for the
ballast
well oh very nice
I have the plug right here well you have
the plug for the ball that's that's what
I'm looking for oh oh for the B no it's
in there I'm sorry no problem I didn't
think I didn't think you did but you
said you did so I thought I was thinking
of the re question
you these are some
heavy hey guys so it is now the next day
and the tent has been finally set up
with the lights we've got our exhaust
with the hyper fan through an 8 in tube
that's going out the window and we're
just going to start putting plants in
here really stoked on the ease of use of
this tent how easy it is and uh just
yeah I can't can't say enough obviously
John's helped out we did have to change
our controller we put the Sentinel MD T1
in um the other one actually wasn't
working we thought we thought the
nanolux B weren't working but they're
actually working beautifully and I'll
take you just through the tent here for
a quick little
tour let's get
our white balance
organized here we
go so
HP HPS lights time 2 600s with the
adjusta wing fans we've got our nanolux
ballasts which you can hear these guys
have little fans it's pretty awesome
intake and outtake one on either side
we've got our Sentinel so we can have
all of our fans plugged in on this side
we've got our light here and then we've
got a light off which I'll also be
plugging in some of these little fans
which aren't turned on just yet I've got
my one little watermelon in here so far
she's looking happy she's got more room
than she's ever had so you can really
see this thing is a resin
producer this thing is going to kick out
the
goods all
right so all in all I'm uh pretty much
stoked on my little garden I guess I'm
going to go up and get John to help me
and we're going to bring all these
plants down and then we'll show you one
final shot of the garden with the plants
in it and uh yeah we'll just go from
there we'll let you know how much uh dry
vegetative weight sorry not dry because
I'm not going to dry it it's going to be
um well some some will be dried I'm
going to dry a couple of plants to hang
for dry sift and the rest I'm going to
do uh wet washing one plant runs per so
uh it's going to be a unique way for me
to collect my resin and I hope you guys
stay tuned and watch cuz uh there's
going to be things to learn all right
peace well we're we're back again John I
know you have come back and done John is
beyond a good friend let me tell you uh
a few things didn't work yesterday are
bored for whatever reason we haven't
figured out if it was a fuse or whatnot
so we replaced the fuse with the
Sentinel and d uh
T1 uh we've got both the lights lit up
now and we brought our plants down and
we've staked them John um put the hyper
fan ducting in inside the tent as well
as to the window so we have our exhaust
set up would you like to turn that up
Sir oh yeah let's Crank that up great
suction beautiful suction and and look
how quiet it is that's full that's 100%
yeah I mean when you turn it down to 35%
it's still pumping good air and you can
honestly barely hear it so yeah we've
staked up these plants they were all
being held up by themselves in the
little tents I've got the one mother uh
or not the mother but the one big uh
Astro Boy sitting in there already and I
guess uh it's just a matter of throwing
some of these guys down I put them
already in there I know you're a man
I've done this before okay then there's
there's something else we need to do
John where would you like to put the
plants sir well before we put any plants
anywhere here I'm going to take my shoes
off see I too and I'm going to go into
this
tent with John and uh we're going to
have a little ball we're in the tent
we've got the Hitman baby cake you can
pull it forward a little bit you're kind
of hiding behind that I'm hiding tip
that back I'm not in here hey you get
right in then get right in we got room
for it we got the Hitman for you man I
got some water in the hit
Hitman we have been sketching out on
quite a few of our videos where we just
get all excited and we don't even put
anything waterwise into the pipe we
really don't need to it's that clean and
not good it truly is there's Swiss perk
the Mother Ship certain pipes do hit
unbelievably you got to move over you're
literally hiding behind that wall there
you go now you're in the
can you go sir I'm going to heat up this
side for you nice and cooking for me
side that your hand is on thank you yeah
you know
looking good we like to help out the
ones that like to help I'll get you to
variable click that fan and we'll show
them how fast it's going to clear this
smoke out of this tent a good idea thank
you
brother got to crank her up
[Music]
oh yeah just gone getting sucked right
out I'm watching it right
now you just
watching
it yeah I really can't say enough about
these Hyperlite fans they're [ __ ]
awesome really
are I guess it's it would be neat to own
have a grow where every single product
you love as much as you love that
product you want me to hold the torch
and I'll give you that here we
go I like this little baby cakes it's um
it's a nice P really happy that you pick
her up oh yeah me too I got to actually
get in touch with the guys from the
plant to make sure I paid for this thing
oh you did did I I let wait
there PA with bubble bags I think yeah
they're carrying your product now see
that's a great thing but they've
actually carryed my product since day
one they're like the original Spanish uh
the original Spanish guys in Barcelona
that really started using the bags
first they knew what was
up great guys actually really nice guys
well I can't say enough about uh these
plants they're really starting to look
beautiful and someone wrote it on the
um on one of our videos or even it was
on a photo resin Growers and that's
truly what we are we're resin
Farmers you know not just Tricom Farmers
but resin Farmers we not really
interested even in the entire glandula
tricomb we're really only interested in
its head we Chase resin we're the resin
Chasers you'll see us we Chase resin all
over the world maybe we might be chasing
resin in Jamaica next week we're just in
Barcelona right now we're in my garage
chasing it so my house last week chasing
it it happens all over the place and you
should be chasing Ching your resin too
you should be chasing your resin too hey
why don't we put these plants in here
real quick and we'll leave them with
that final shot of the the plants you
take that down I'm just sitting right
here since I'm down while you pass them
into me bro sounds perfect let's throw
the old shoes
on watermelon bent watermelon I put the
Watermelons on this side a few of them
yeah here I'll give the other watermelon
here we
go watermel across the back which would
be your front yeah perfect love the
Watermelons um we can throw this guy
literally right here to have tall sativa
My Little
Pony we've got our Kem for reunion and
our
medy and she goes here we go and here's
and then here's me getting out here's
John getting out and medy you got to put
the medy in
dude medy
cush there she is guys
always
beautiful yeah
dude I think you're going to have to
show them what you got going on in here
yeah
absolutely going to step
out all right so our little action
corner with our exhaust uh fire
extinguisher our timer with our fans and
our exhaust our lights our two digital
nanolux ballasts loving the fans on
those nanolux to cool themselves down
that's a great idea intake and outtake
on either side of the fan and then we
have medy Hayes Med cush Med Kush yes
sry starring and we have starring the
medic Kush
next up we
have chem 4 Reunion Bubba cam Bubba
cam Bubba cam Bubba cam Bubba cam Bubba
cam
liy yes was very Ling carrying it
down in the back beautiful we have Astro
Boy
and another Astro
[Music]
Boy I love how it's just starting to
blow like that just start popping there
certainly not
least my little
p if you
could there you go yeah
nice little wispy sativa packing her in
mine's still going little twin nuggets
right there week
15 My Little
Pony Astro Boy
so all in
all we have a happy bubble man I've got
my 8x4 tent John helped me beyond help
the plants are in here blooming I don't
have any more that are blooming for now
but I've got some inedge and I've got
some clones that I'm taking so in the
next 4 weeks the majority of these will
be turned into hash and hung and then we
will uh refill this tent up real proper
with uh probably about six or seven
strains in which we'll also
finally begin to tell you exactly the
weights that we're going to get from
resin out of this 8x4 to 600 W T um BS
thanks for watching
guys peace
[Music]