all right so here we are guys we just
bumped into each other at the airport
Toronto day Toronto day Champs day 4 in
the morning yes bump into each other at
the front of the airport we walk through
the front door I see this medtainer on
the ground I think has John tossed that
but John hasn't come in yet so I pointed
out to John John there's a medtainer on
the ground that one does not smell very
airtight though does
it I'm telling you I think that the guy
touched the outside of it anyway open
that up and show us what we got in there
because it's hilar
we found this at the airport you
guys so yeah five big Gaggers about a gr
gr and a half a piece and and a roach
someone ruined the roach and threw the
roach in the fresh weed which guess
they're like popping quickly threw the
roach in there to jump on the plane went
put it in their pocket they th they're
getting L they going be like [ __ ] I got
no weed maybe they maybe they'll be
flying to Toronto and we'll bump into
them and we'll say we found if you lost
a purple medtainer we found it let us
know anyway see you guys soon we're
going to go board this flight peace guys
peace