[Music]
all right we're here in Barcelona at the
spannabis 2019 we're actually in the
city right now at the W Hotel
we're here with Kelly Blackwell who has
practiced sadi Pleven of civil
disobedience in order to I guess maybe
originally give her son a higher quality
of life but also to actually extend his
life and and bring him out of out of a
near-death experience so Callie I'll
leave it up to you two to tell the
viewers here on bubbleman's world what
how this all transpired okay thank you
very much I'm Katie back well and I got
into cannabis because in 2010 my son was
diagnosed with acute lymphoblastic
leukemia and then two years later he was
diagnosed with a much rarer form of
cancer called even cell sarcoma this
left him to be the only person in the
world to have the two colors together
and because there was no protocol for
him doctors this idea to give him a bone
marrow transplant
now unfortunately Darren had four bone
marrow transplants in ten months because
each one subsequently failed - from the
donut one from himself and then the last
and final moment transplant was his own
cells Darren had been through
radiotherapy five years or four years of
radiotherapy chemotherapy say because
there's no protocol there words where we
will give him everything the kind
without killing him so you had adult
doses of everything and then three days
after he had his final transplanting
Travis fingers down the side of his
hospital bed and picked on put to
catastrophic infections in his hands now
with the brand-new bone marrow
trying to kick in and it usually happens
within 21 23 days but it was just
struggling far too much with these
catastrophic infections you also have
one in his mouth as well which was a
kind of portion of his tongue so he was
in a really bad way
told us that nobody has ever engrafted
with a bone-marrow transplant after 50
days hasn't happened by 50 days it's not
happening there's nothing there there's
no chance so day 46 came we'd always
have many many conversations running up
to there saying you know we've only got
one chance left this so we knew it was
coming but on December the 8th 2013 they
said to us ok there is nothing else left
now you need to go to a hospice when do
you want to go and I said well how long
are we talking I saw his antibiotics and
the only things that were keeping him
alive apparently I saw them as a
conscious life-support machine because
Darren was very aware and and he was
part of the conversation I was always
very open with him about every part of
his journey because I it's his body's
his his life right so they told us that
once they unhooked him from hounds of
politics we were looking at 3 days a
week at most these infections ravaged
him and when did we want to go sorry
December the 11th question yeah three
days when would you like to go your
child yeah they say he was in a bad way
but what about mum I mean you were with
him the entire time you were basically
experiencing this horror yeah the other
side of the coin it was a roller coaster
board I never bought ticket to you and I
couldn't get off and I couldn't get up
from that from July the census 2010 I
was on that roller coaster and from that
day that very first day that they told
me have leukemia I knew there was a
chance we could lose him so fast forward
four years and the roller coaster I've
been on I had already grieved him we'd
already accepted it was it was very
matter-of-fact everything that happened
at the time and I think for me
especially it was a guarded way if I'd
have allowed my emotions to take over
nothing would have got done you know
it'd have been four years of hell I
think you know we don't have a choice of
what happens to us but how we react to
it that's everything we have that yeah
that's everything I mean as a parent I
just picture yeah fetal position corner
it's how you are in your head
like when you're on your own and crying
but I found writing very cathartic and
so because therein was so bad when he
was the only one in the world to have
these two cancers the only one in the
world why my book is called 2.7 billion
because he was the only one and I
started a journal I started writing and
blogging about him in hope to find other
people with the same cancer in it and
and because of that by the time we got
to the hospice he had twelve thirteen
thousand followers on social media so I
was finding every day I was writing what
was happening and I was getting feedback
from people saying I'm she was scared to
check on Facebook in case he's dead you
know and it's like but by far the way
cathartic at the end of David that was
my therapy um so we went to the hospice
and Darren didn't go was in the first
three days this was December the 11th he
just turned 14 on December the first so
we went and I say he didn't go anywhere
we had Christmas on December the 14th
then we had another Christmas on
December the 25th then we have New
Year's and Darren was still here but his
organs were slowly shutting down his
stomach was producing a pint of bile
every couple of hours I was having to
draw out of a nasal gastric tube because
if I didn't eat vomit and the tube would
come up he'd have to have another one
put down and ask for a tramatic so um
you know who having to do all this and
it was just the case of waiting and
Darren started to get very anxious
because he just wanted to go now he
plans we sat down and we planned his
funeral he plans the venue the hearse
the music the costumes because it was
fancy dress don't have an idea be fancy
dress and he picked some very
tongue-in-cheek uniform was full for
many of his family members he can have
the last laugh that this was one of the
things that really grabbed me about this
story
watching the interview about with both
of you sitting there and talking about
planning his funeral and just the
positivity you know in his in his eyes
while he was explaining it in the smiles
and it was just like wow like this is
this is the thing that most of us on the
planet er are the most afraid of you
know people are terrified
death and here have a child you know
facing it yeah he couldn't wait he was
he he was looking forward to and the
planning of every hero will I mean
hearing have a Playstation a couple of
watches to give away but you know he did
it and he also wrote letters to family
members picking them up on their
behavior and literally giving them
advice the saying look if you carry on
in this way this you know life is too
short for this you know he really did it
was incredible quite something to have a
child who's on his way out use that term
you know life is too short
yeah it's like well okay no denying man
exactly exactly
listen yeah um so yeah days 69 came
around and Darren was still alive and
kicking although bit he was you know I
say things are slowly shutting down and
the doctors were saying to me this is
the beginning now it's this is this is
what we see and Darren starts get very
anxious now sort of two-three months
previously because Darren had the
catastrophic infections in his hands
basically his fingers here down were
black them an aquatic they were
literally dying on the end of his hand i
I've been crying about this this morning
an immediate life or how did he feel I'm
crying over one day of this and he was
like this for couple of months no
literally feeling his hand died so they
wanted to amputate I stopped them from
amputate and I said look I don't him
means he's dying just I wanted to die
pain-free that's all I don't want to die
on morphine because he didn't want to
die on morphine you know he'd written a
death plan saying that they'd taken
everything they're not taking his death
and he wanted to die conda's mentis he
wanted to experience it so I talked them
into giving them here and you reacted me
here when they took out the nerves they
actually cauterized the nerves so that
he never feed his hands again and they
said look you'll never feed his hand
he'll never use it and I said I don't
care his diet doesn't matter you know um
but previously to that I'd ask them for
he was on the fence and oh he was on
morphine nothing was touching his pain
so I have a look up alternative
treatments for pain
Petric hand came up which is a cannabis
based product available in Holland and
I've read an article about a guy who got
it on prescription he gone over and so I
I said look we can do this I'm willing
to go toilet no it's not licensed for
children you can't have it okay but it
could work it works very well on your
Pathak painting it works yeah but you
know so I thought okay well I'll do it
myself
main ingredient cannabis I can get some
of that so I've got some from friends
who had met I'm a just a vegetable
glycerine teacher with the with the
plant plant out left with this honey
kind of stuff and I put it in a vape pen
theme because he was in hospital and I
thought if he can have a vape pen it
might work on his but it didn't but he
liked it he felt quite cool sitting in
the hospital room like this plume of
smoke
no it felt naughty but in his how old at
this time and 13 for not attending 14 so
to me was like what I tried or failed
I didn't think any more of it so fast
forward now a nice business day 69 and
he's very anxious so they start upping
the morphine and I'll ask for bone
marrow aspirate to be done when they go
into the main ball joint and they take
out a piece of bone marrow and then they
can look at it and tell you exactly
what's going on it's it's much more
accurate than a blood test now when we
gone there his neutrophil count which is
the white blood cells that fight
infection were naught point naught
naught naught v which is nothing there's
nothing there so obviously still alive
so I said look please do another test
tell me that it's tough definitely
nothing there because he's still here
you know you should be dead so they did
a test they 69 it came back nothing
nothing there I remember the nerves
coming to me with a piece of paper and I
opened it and I'm so sorry there's
there's nothing but both me and Darren
had talked about this and we both hoped
that there was nothing because as sad as
it was I didn't want to I didn't want to
see him suffer anymore and I mean it
gets to the point you know when you when
your dog is poorly and you have to make
that decision right this is exactly the
same thing but it's it's a child and so
I was we both look at each other when
good it's just a matter of time now you
know it's the end of the podding and the
poke
and of the hospital visits and of all
that um I say they starts giving
morphine he started to be in and out of
consciousness and this wasn't what he
want ends so they took the morphine away
he still very anxious about when am I
gonna die thinking he's gonna you know
die in this he just didn't know when it
was coming
so the sleeping tablets obviously made
him very in and out again so I just
thought well as a mother I have to give
him what he wants in his end of life I
can't do anything else for him other
than ensure that he gets his very last
dying wish
that's my only duty now right so I just
thought I saw this tincture and I
thought I just got I'm just gonna give
him a load in his mouth and just get
chills people out right kind of his
chills people out so I gave him five mil
under his tongue sublingually and within
half an hour his whole demeanor I
literally saw the relaxation could
literally see it in him now about half
an hour after that a nurse came to the
door with a drug called cyclers in now
Darrin had become incredibly addicted to
this drug so much so that he would
scream at the nurses if you couldn't
have it every few hours and the way they
had administered to him had had caused
it was almost like care of him and he
was before it was incredibly addicted to
this drug and I saw the nurse come to
the door and I thought what if I've now
caused some contraindication and I can't
tell them what I've given him an arm God
and I didn't need to worry because he
turned to her and he said I don't want
it she's left her one dose and countless
other things I made a vegetable crisp it
wasn't even feet I you know it's just a
whole instruction and so I look and she
said well and I said go go before he
changes his mind and she took it and he
and I said you sure you don't you don't
want that and he said no this is enough
he said cannabis has given me everything
about drug gave me but without the he
was off his face when he was on that you
know
he said I don't want it sleeping tablets
stop the morphine stopped everything it
was an exit drug straight away and for
me it was already a miracle because this
was going to give him the death that he
wanted right so for me this was already
a miracle so he continued to give it to
him and over the following few days he
was really chill was really had a really
kind of he became very introspective as
well
he became very quiet in himself and
really started to think about things and
he really accepted death then and he was
really ready to go there was no more
panicking Oh five days later we sat in
the in the lounge and Darren had a
heavily bandaged Terrence I mean he's
like Mickey Mouse he was and they said
don't take those bandages off because
underneath it's down to the bone and
it's surgically just you know so he's
there with his hands like this me asleep
when he woke up he pulled his hand out
and the bandage in the middle was off
and Martin won't look at my hands
what's wrong with your hand I didn't
even register that there was a third
bandage missing he said my finger look
at my finger so I went oh my god and it
looked like mine but much much thinner
that's not care but was no nail but it
was pink it was healed I was I was no
hang on this is wrong because you can't
even create skin cells without
functioning bone marrow you can't so I
said to the doctors we need we need
another test and they were running
around you know we need to do a blood
test massively he literally five days
ago there's nothing there and they said
we need to do a test and they did a
blood test an hour later it came back
and his neutrophil count was naught
point two five well so he had almost I
don't know how many hundred higher it
was a lot it was there anyway and so the
nurse the doctor was like well so what
you want us to do as I don't know what
you mean what do what I want you to do
and she said to Derek well you know
usual protocol is now if you get a
temperature we will give you antibiotics
you know what you wants to do nice it's
I want you to leave me the [ __ ] alone
and the doctor said well I swear we
flippin and I said
10 seconds ago he was dying and now
you're telling him he's not when you ask
him what he wants to do as far as
medical procedure come on please you
know so it was there so I continue to
give and his account just got more
higher and higher and higher and he
officially engrafted on day 104
holy smokes 55 days after the length of
the maximum yeah has anyone ever grafted
at that time no nobody after 50 days it
really is the the one in seven billion
boy yeah yeah but unfortunately got
worse after that his mental health
deteriorated oh just chronically because
now he didn't die and the hospital was
because I couldn't tell anybody why done
the hospital we're now saying well we
don't know if he's gonna live we don't
know where and they actually said in
front of him where he could drop down
dead next week we don't know
so this limbo he was now in limbo and he
explained it to me he said mom it's like
there's a door open and everything if
everyone adds is behind that door and
you get to the threshold and someone
slams it in your face and says not today
and you have to turn around to hospitals
and needles and drop and he just went I
don't want this anymore so for a period
of six months he tried to kill himself
mmm I took shoelaces away from him right
up outside all of these things we were
evicted from the hospice I I also took
the cannabis away because I wanted to
make damn sure that it wasn't a
coincidence and when I took the cannabis
away his blood count halfed
when I gave it back it doubled and I did
that over a six blood test period so I
knew I knew that it was that we always
loved to tell you it wasn't well done
clinical trials well the same to me we
can't say that it works
they called him a miracle they'd rather
say it was a miracle done anything else
you know even now but so for the next
six months trying to sleep and the the
room he chose to kill himself with
through starvation so he would literally
refuse to eat anything for six months
and he got down to about 24 25 kilos
which i think is about four stones and
pounds I think that's not a lot he was I
so showed you picture means he was
skeletal I've never seen anything like
it except for on documentaries of
Auschwitz and things like man it was
skeletal and it was the most horrendous
six months because cancers one thing and
treatment is one thing almost the
passenger to that but this was now
Darren and I was trying to encourage
Darren to eat and he was no because I
couldn't I couldn't give him a future to
look forward to
so that was devastating so they wanted
to section him sedate him and force-feed
him I asked for some mental health care
and was told he didn't qualify so he
never saw anybody for that so his left
to me in my pop psychology trying the
game to E and and then I got involved
with some local communist cops cuz also
had seen what countless have done so I
started to branch out and look and I
found a very local characters club some
lovely people who kept telling me you
need to meet this guy projected fields
you need to meet Jeff ditch fields and
Ron Stovall who's Japanese I google him
okay Wow so a friend of mine said look I
have a villa in Spain taken to Spain
taken on holiday you haven't been away
for years and years
get away I managed to talk the hospital
and to let me take him and I said look
if I take him on holiday and I come back
and he's still refusing to eat I'll sign
him over to you I haven't actually cycle
whatever you need to do so you took him
to Spain and that was in July 2014 and
met Jeff the following day only wanted
to say hello to me thank him for his
work really but he then looked at Darren
and said my god he looks like he's dying
I said yeah it kind of is you know and
he said I think I can help with this and
I was like well you know he's because I
again didn't think about the eating
sorry I didn't even curse me about the
munchies you know yeah and he said look
he's a syringe of oil it was
Nevin Hayes I believe it was Graham and
took him back to the apartment and the
following day I gave him a tiny tiny
little bit on a on a crisp and I said
don't eat this and he did yeah it's it
because drugs he'll try anything
you know he's I've seen him on cats and
I've seen them on everything so kind of
it I had no qualms and giving him this
and so half now an hour later I was
prepping lunch and he was down by the
pool with his brother and I I shouted
down here do you want anything to eat
expecting the same gun to come back and
Darren shall we don't make me loads I'm
starving so straightaway food gave him
food he ate for 12 hours yeah for 12
hours the next day and the next day
other next day and he just his life came
back into his eyes he was very very thin
people in Spain were looking at him like
he was dying but to me he looks
incredible because I'd seen him with you
at home so far yeah I see this the scene
a piece in my book the light in his eyes
kept just switched back on and he was
back in the room you know so we came
back after 12 days in Spain we came back
to the UK and the doctor took me to one
side and said my god he's his mental
health is improved by 300% I said I know
it happens when you eat food yeah you
know and she said he doesn't want to die
I said I know and she said he's put on
four kilos I said I know she said the
holiday demon worlds are good I mean yes
it's not today yes we'll leave it
they'll accept that they'll accept that
yes anciens you know they'll accept that
and again I had to stay quiet because I
was terrified of social services coming
in taking my children not only with
Darren you know be taken in scabby who's
one thing that now clearly was working
for him again cannabis now this is the
second time cannabis is brought him back
from the brink and so he's been on oil
every single day since July 2014
every day without fail 150 micrograms
milligrams say micrograms a milligram
milligrams 122 milligrams every day and
the things I have seen since that so it
was a miracle the first incidence the
second time was a miracle in my eyes
what's happened since is miraculous his
hand he can feel only the tips of his
fingers he can't feel about two weeks
after he came back from Spain he starts
seeing mom my hands hurting this is your
hand can't hurt me
you have no nerves your hand corner
we're telling you mommy said it's like
electric shocks coming down my fingers
it's a pain for me wiring the nerves
Regenesis neurogenesis was rebuilding
neural pathways in his hands from around
the damage and I say now he he has he
has problems he has to pick things up
like this mhm but he has full range of
movement he wants to be a chef he oh
it's incredible you know and I literally
slapped his hand on his oncologist s and
go-to thing that I can't economist but I
can own a better one here he has a
basket necrosis in his right femur which
was basically an inch of bone at the end
of his femur which was dead necrotic and
that was due to steroid use while he was
climbing and the blood couldn't get to
the bone so it died and they told me
that within five years he would need a
knee replacement if he were to survive
because this is irreparable you can't
repair dead bone right so I think it was
about six or nine months ago now he had
an MRI scan because his left leg is very
twisted the bones are physically
deformed so so he had an MRI scan and I
started the oncologist office and he
said I believe you are under the
impression that Darren had a vascular
crisis I said no I wasn't under the
impression I had the scan would you like
to see them well um you know because I
believe you must have been under the
impression I saw you're gonna tell me
it's gone and he said well yes but
that's impossible and I said well kill
it's not because it's happened and he
said well I don't see any if I don't see
this in any of my other patients and I
said none either
from cannabis and he said I knew you'd
say that word and I said I'm going to
keep saying it because you're the reason
why my son's still alive and you've got
60 people out there that could benefit
from it and you'd rather put your
fingers in your ears I said this is
happening the a Baskin coasters is gone
the near ectomy it's been fixed he's now
six years post his last trial in almost
six years process last transplant so
they are saying that he should have
cataracts by now
he should have a heart murmur at least
he should have issues with his internal
organs because the amount of
radiotherapy and chemotherapy they blast
in it he should be having now it's
called long term side effects if you
live longer than five years if because
that's all they go for is five years if
you get past the five-year mark they
don't start looking for these long-term
side effects so Darren's going in
regularly and there's nothing there's
not even a sign of any long-term side
effects and they are bamboozled they're
they can't understand and he sits and
goes kind of this kind of pest cannabis
you know and then and he's had it
written on all of his medical records he
stood over his oncologist and said I
want me to write what I did and what I
was taking on what I'm taking now
because I'm still taking it I want on my
notes but I don't take any of the full
pharmaceutical drugs that I'm supposed
to take the knife I don't take any of
them he's had maybe two colds in the
last five years he's been honestly he's
one of the most healthiest people I know
and he's he's supposed to the infertile
so I think next month he's going for
fertility because he's 20 this year it's
gonna be 20 in December so he's gone for
a fertility test because he wants to
know him and I said yeah don't rest on
your laurels with that I can guarantee
anyway you know he's gonna end up having
means of children you know it's like
it's just been it's nice night and day
from thee I mean it doesn't help from my
perspective when you have the word harm
in the first five letters of the word
pharmaceutical you know that's a strange
thing to have that word harm of all the
words you could have in the word that's
supposed to represent medicine and to
think of all of the things that just
kept going wrong as they continue to go
down that road I mean just the story
that you told that is so incredible and
then you just you know cannabis
truly is just unbelievable yeah and the
fact that there are people in this world
that would rather like you said put
their fingers in their ears and not hear
it it's it's it's criminal yeah it is
it's crazy it's actually beyond
negligence it's is sickening to allow
parents and and the loved ones of these
sick people and the sick people
themselves to go through that and and
just when it's it's how can we not use
the plant-based medicines as the first
line of defense why do we always have to
wait till three days before death yeah
and I know in the UK you know like I see
what's going on there in the UK is it's
it's not good not with cannabis you know
what they're doing and the way I mean
the southern little guy who they were
took his medicine away at the border
like this is this is like what you would
expect a demon to do if you ever came
across a dinos you know okay so that's
yeah it's completely just really evil
yeah evil oh it must be a miracle no
you're under the impression yes I mean
yeah this is exactly why I feel that I
do what I do now is that obviously since
since all those followers that Darren
had they all saw this miracle and then I
started to get inundated with people who
wanted the same miracle and so I'd tell
them I would what I did and many of them
would say oh no I can't do that it's
illegal and which is sad but I respected
that and so for the last five years
because I wrote a book and I've been in
television and I've been very open and
out about this and I've been in
Parliament I've told the chief of police
what I do
I told specific MPs what I do I was
arrested outside Parliament not long ago
probably test their nice dresses our
suffragettes as well so it's kind of it
was the public I didn't intend to get
arrested but it just happens we've make
very good photos mien kampf stress as a
suffragette hundred years later fighting
for the right to give my child cannabis
now and 100 years
I couldn't vote but I could give my
child Cadmus and their tables have
turned right so so now I'm inundated
with people who come to me again
at the end of their life such a shame
that it's usually at the ends of their
life but so now I've seen I've seen this
plan for perform miracles hundreds and
hundreds of times since then hundreds of
people have come off pharmaceutical
drugs and onto cannabis because they've
come to me and so now I will now
introduce today say the JJ is she's my
right-hand lady she's we've known each
other for a few years
we've both been working in cannabis but
it was came a very natural organic join
with we're having a pairing yeah really
between us that the people come to me I
do a lot of consulting I talked them
through cannabis and because many of the
people who've never touched cannabis and
their life when they come to me to you
right so I have to I'm giving them their
first hire on helping them I'm talking
them through and and then JD mixes up
the oils to the preparations to the may
shows that we need
she sources the oils we make sure that
we know where it's coming from so JD has
very good content absolutely our
standards are so high because this is
medicine this is not a joke if there's
alcohol in there that's not supposed to
be in there or if there's all this
contamination or we don't know what the
will the profile is every single piece
that everything to the ghost trust is
tested so we know exactly the profile
and because it's the only way that you
can administer medicine properly when
you know what's in it so we have this we
have this little relationship going
where we work very very well together
and it's yeah it's beautiful and I
couldn't do what I do without JJ you
know it she's been a godsend to me we
can now help far more people than just
me on my own you know so we've got other
people he's starting to get other people
on board but it's very difficult because
I guess our standards are so high but
not many people can meet those standards
unfortunately I have a lot of people
saying I haven't no Deval here do you
want me to do
you get rid of it through me I'll help
you and I say what is it tested Oh No
well I'll get some tested oh yeah but by
the time the test goes back it'll be
sold so you know you either have it now
or not Isilon I'm having not all then
thank you very much yeah of course I'm
not doing that I'm not peddling you all
you know so that makes it difficult if
we often have people sitting waiting for
test results to come back we will not
release the oil until test results come
back so we are very stringent like that
um but yeah it's incredible and actually
I in the UK all those things aren't good
on the public side of things public
opinion is very good excellent the
public half I before I wrote my book
while I was writing my book before I
decided to publish it I used to look at
public opinion and whether one eye would
be safe coming out as a mother giving my
child an illicit drug because I was
watching people be very very angry about
mothers over in America who were giving
their children cannabis illegally no I
was just for pot heads and why are you
giving that to a child and you know
doctors know what they're doing it was
very much that kind of rhetoric and it
scared me too much to come out so I
wrote my book and I left it a few years
then I look to public opinion again and
I have changed dramatically - well
obviously we know that cannabis works
you know there was more of those
comments so I felt safe so I came out
when on a television I was one other
fact well I was the first person to ever
go on television and admit to breaking
the law and actually give yeah yeah
there are a lot of other mothers in the
UK who really do their children needs
our Congress right now and they're
begging the government's given what they
need but um I wasn't going to beg to be
a lawful customer I my son's helps was
there paramount you know so I I was the
first one to come out on the television
and say that actually breaking the law
yeah oh my god there's absolutely Leah
yeah there was a lot of stigma and a lot
of fear and even now there's a lot of
stigma and or fear that are stopping
these parents from embarking on this
I'd since then since going on the
television I watched public opinion
again now sway and we are now at a point
where 99% of people on comments
especially are or yes campus works my
nine uses it all my even if they are
ready resources oil you know there's the
mass confusion at the moment with CBD or
in the UK and of course because there's
snake oil salesmen and it's there's all
sorts of sort of yes information about
the media push out CBD all has cannabis
all cure the media use the word cure in
the same sentence to see video so we
fighting against the misinformation the
propaganda the reefer madness everything
that's going on but most people now you
know if you to tell them all I gave my
son cannabis they go wow that's amazing
that's great that's good good for you
good for you you know so things have
really changed we just need the
government but the government are doing
what they're doing they're lining their
duct I've been a rotor that they can be
personally profiting from this it's not
about you know many people in the in the
UK we say we look at America like how
much money they've made that they've
paid Colorado paper schools health care
this they don't be great if I'm
fortunate in your care government don't
care about how much money they can put
in the public purse only care about what
can go in their pockets and when you've
got a prime minister whose husband is
the biggest investor in 2gw pharmacy
it's cool and our drugs minister who's
husband owns the land that 220 tons of
skunk is growing on every year in the UK
and yet has no medicinal benefit and
we're not allowed to have access to mass
hypocrisy' well it makes you psychotic
that's that that's the UK's media for
the last 15 years and we're actually but
we'll be able to sell it as a medicine
and are three good benefits back so your
son must be absolutely blown away and
inspired by how his experience has led
you guys down this journey now of
helping all of these other people what
does he think of that like he must see
that he sees it but I think he's quite
much
he's very Darrin lives in the moment and
he bet he does he always has he's he was
diagnosed with autism eight years old
and he's also has Tourette syndrome so
he's also seen that be treated very well
with with cannabis you can tell that he
has not ended the world for a little
while because you autistic trade start
coming out and you see it again with him
but so he is although he's very proud of
me I'm sure I'm sure I say that because
he's never told me so I have to presume
that he is but this is Darrin I know I
know there and I don't expect any
anything like that from him but I know
that I know that he must be proud in
what I'm doing that I'm going on in
helping other people he knows now that
he comes second to cannabis he knows
that and so does my other son because
this is far bigger done their day Darrin
has put me on a journey and now his
journey is to carry on whatever he wants
to do with his life this is now my
journey and he has firmly put me and he
knows that so he he's you know he's
quite happy to come second Congress cuz
he knows how porn is to me and to him is
new you know the only reason why he's
still breathing
well I mean I'm very glad to be able to
to share your story to my audience and
to you know to try and like I said
earlier I would love to get you on to
hash Church we can try to raise some
money for your for your group you know
generally in the story in the time when
we're online and we're talking that's
when really people are the most
susceptible to be able to just hit that
donation they want people want to be
able to help especially with Nathan
especially when they hear a story that's
so incredibly inspirational like this
one it's just like what a journey this
was how many years from 2010 to
[Music]
place with your with your child where
you actually want them to die and where
a child has been through so much the 14
years that they want to die you know and
then cannabis turns it all around
completely isn't why isn't this
available to everybody that's what
drives us to carry on really I mean
Kenny's experienced she knows exactly
how it is for mom to be in that
situation when you actually want to
release your charge you've been
effective seems to be the only release
yeah well so so for people who are
watching right now how can they find you
guys what are the social media addresses
websites the book titles where can they
find all this information about guys so
on Instagram I'm the underscore cannabis
underscore activist JJ is at Gangan Anja
and then I'm on Facebook because Callie
Blackwell and you can finally I have a
public page which I answer many emails
today I have a public page twos my
normal one just cut back well I have a
website
Callie Blackwell count at UK I don't get
to update that very often unfortunate
it's more like a holding page but you
can be directed to all of my social
media pages I have a donate page on
there as well it's very straight for you
to my PayPal which I don't expect people
to donate but if they want to then it it
will directly go to help because this is
a completely not-for-profit thing you
know we don't make any money on top of
what we do we know because you have a
sore yes I can't formally I can't
morally take I think you gotta make the
money from the sick P we can't morally
make money from someone that I know how
I feel like from the journey that you
just took financial burden
I mean not to say that hey we do need
companies that are going to come out and
make it accessible in a mass scale and
those companies will require to profit
to make profits so they can continue on
but it doesn't have to be this this
pharmaceutical model where it's ten
thousand ten thousand times the price
and it's only our product because it's
patented and it's some yeah like I say
that I was saying someone epidural X
which is the GW pharmaceutical CBD oil
that they bought out in November of the
for children who have been lucky enough
I say lucky enough to be prescribed in
the UK three of them now are I've gotten
completely backwards in fact have gone
worse than they were ever and he
literally like zombies and it seems to
be there's in the I think it's in the
insert of the epital X he says about the
strawberry flavoring causes severe
degeneration one of the main nerves so
the delivery system that they manage to
pager because they can't actually patron
cannabis so it's done reaching the
junior you know because of greed they
want to yeah control it well they're
nice to be side effects right there has
to be repeat customer otherwise John's
company goes our business if there's no
repeat customer then the drugs company
will come out its its business sense if
you look at it on a business sense its
it makes no sense to make something
actually works otherwise he's got to the
end of their business it reminds me of
this young girl from Sweden who's been
standing up for the environment grip
Greta
I believe he slapped the UN the the who
in the UN she just was like you guys
aren't mature enough to take care of the
planet yeah give it to us yeah yeah
exactly but she she had a quote and I'm
trying to remember what it was
I'll have to I'll have to remember it
was it was a very powerful quote and it
was it was in regards to what we were
just talking about Rain Man but I've
lost it no come to you yeah shout out
and I listen I wish I could sit here
with you guys all day I've totally I
love the vibes I love what you guys are
doing I think it's extremely important
it's it's some of the most important
civil disobedience that's going on on
this planet right now
so really like you know I can't say
enough good about what you're both doing
and continue to do this journey and no
matter how hard they come at and we
never never stop never stop well listen
thank you so much for coming in and
talking with us and this is we're gonna
be staying in touch for sir yeah it's uh
yeah absolutely amazing work amazing
women you guys are doing the the really
serious good work out there thank you
very much I know I'm very honored to
even be invited to talk to you it's ya
know this will be this will be the first
of many conversations that we have so
thanks a lot guys
[Music]