these are designed to push the amount of
the industry TVJ is Anthony love reports
ganja sensor me male lead the plant
often described as the healing of the
nation but for small farmers the
regulate of the legal ganja industry the
cannabis Licensing Authority CLA is
causing headaches
one such headache they point to is the
fee they're apt to pay it just to start
up this clear this is far beyond us look
at the before planting a seed of ganja
leaves a million are to realize before
being considered eligible for a license
a ganja farm should be properly fenced
and surveillance cameras must be
installed for many small farmers the
cost to do so is exorbitant Delano Steve
Wright is a director at the cannabis
licensing authority it's expensive not
deliberately it's expensive because the
process here cost money and it has to be
very stringent what laws would have to
be in compliance with international law
have to be in compliance with the UN
conventions what we're working a
solution right now we have the ability
to the farmers to defer their payments
but the fee isn't the only thing the
farmers are taking issue with some are
of the view that the industry is
designed to favor big investors but at
least one of those moneyed investors has
fired back arguing that some local
farmers have trust issues when I get
into some heated discussions sometimes
with my rice friends they'll say things
like well you know you can't come and
steal the market it's like well no we're
all the market we it's the world we're
all brothers and sisters and if you grow
so much herb in Jamaica that all of a
sudden your Jamaican friends can't smoke
at all say some over to Canada since so
long to America or send some over to
Europe that's that happened for decades
and so now that's what we want to happen
again I wanted to happen legally which
then takes us to banking local banks
have shied away from doing business with
players in the ganja industry because
they fear they will be seen as engaging
in money laundering and lose valuable
business ties with the US banks but
the farmers are questioning why banks
refused to do business with them when
they are the ones collecting on behalf
of the cannabis licensing authority if
something that I can understand what it
is dear / - it is a very complicated
situation because there are computer
makers that are involved in the
candidates case bank accounts and there
are so many companies involved the legal
cannabis space that do not have bank
accounts it's a very sloppy situation
and we wanted to the result so forth
whatever happens in the United States of
America in fact what happened in Jamaica
and also make about the world and the
CDJ news the standards and regulation
division of the