[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am here at the kapulsky apartments and I
am in Amsterdam just uh behind Dam
Square on the main
Canal uh can't even remember the name of
this particular Canal but I've been
staying on it for over 10 years you'd
think I'd know it it's the same street
that uh uh the greenhouse is on and
we've actually been here for a few days
I'm having a bit of problems with slow
uploading still trying to get my
Jamaican videos up so I thought I would
just touch base with everyone and let
you know that all is well and the videos
will be coming soon oh that's a real
nice piece this is the uh
jarella Tony's tur melts I've been
hitting them like mad if you don't know
what those are check out the Facebook
tur melts is Tony's able to extract uh
pure Turpin from the cannabis plant not
from any other plant not using any
chemical solvents he extracts it and
then he Recon constitutes it small
amounts of it there's some pure Turpin
right there moonshine this is like a
ridiculous amount um there's another one
that's a Jil Bean that he's let cure a
little bit and so it's gotten a little
bit of a different color and this one
also has a little bit of a different
color so I'm going to hit a little rip
of
[Music]
that
got to love staying on the canal So
today we're going to maybe go see s we
might end up seeing uh Rob Clark and
skunkman Sam and we'll probably end up
seeing Ramone and true cannabis from
True can of gentics and OCD
Labs everyone's just been great so far
super excited to show you guys a ton of
this Amsterdam trip and right now I'm
going to start by showing you a little
[Applause]
Amsterdam
all right guys more Amsterdam coming
soon bubble
on