for 99% of everybody else I people who
have Alzheimer's people have cancer
people who have Apple are say right of
course a whole plant extract is is gonna
be a superior cannabis medicine should
people have the right to get isolates of
course people should have the right to
choose whatever cannabinoid formed they
want I mean that's we were all given
endocannabinoids systems like there for
a reason we've learned I think a lot of
people or endocannabinoid deficient and
I love the idea of cannabinoids being
fortified into foods and put into drinks
and just like for people to have more
access to them as well yeah of course
right it's the largest neurotransmitter
system in the human body and in most of
the world for most of you know at least
the last 50 years people have been
deprived of the nutrient that engages
with that neurotransmitter system so
it's crazy you know when this period is
looked back upon it might be a hundred
years before it's looked on from this
perspective but prohibition of cannabis
will be recognized as this like bizarre
thing where you in beings willingly
divorce themselves from the most
valuable plant on the planet yeah and
people will look at it just
incredulously mm-hmm but there it is
right maybe this is the human race
learning a valuable lesson you know like
we were talking about earlier
we're just making a big - very valuable
though the regulation and the changes
are happening today are that they're
actually making you test dose exhibit
show strain value like whether to C or
CBD so you can make educated decisions
on what you're consuming because
consumer protection container protectors
that is the best part of the new
regulation - there's a lotta really
really really personally who's eaten a
really hardcore edible yeah thousand
milligrams that they're sitting you know
probably face apart for most people like
to go walking on Queens day well look
you know everybody's system is different
but I think CBD CBD is gonna be a bubble
and that bubbles gonna break you know
what we know from a fully legal mature
cannabis market where people have access
to the full spectrum of cannabinoids
yeah very few people choose the CBD
isolate any worse and
and most most people prefer I'd say of
all of our CBD rich formulations whether
it's a flower or a tincture or a capsule
one to one is really the the most
preferred animations and TFC in there
Bruce founded weed md in canada and so
he worked in before that he worked in
like old folks homes so he came from a
highly regulated business already
something everyone was a cannabis
industry so regulated Bruce was just
like well it wasn't just bad regulation
knowledge variance it was more around
the polypharmacy issues with seniors and
looking at seniors suffering over
prescribing of opioids and antipsychotic
drugs and looking at the value of
cannabis that could actually treat some
of these indications and that's really
what like made it for me valuable to get
involved and I'm like you know this
could be a really interesting safe way
of my career path and you know what I
still teach and provide value for
seniors and do it differently and when I
maybe my first business card and a
canvas sleep on the back people that
didn't like it was an alien like like
the pharmacies and the corporate world
and like they're like are you insane
Mike boy maybe I am but you know it's
evolving and it's developing and I'm
super glad that I took chose this path
to go on with you guys on this adventure
for the pioneers and really have blazed
the trails and like really unloaded
didn't figure out the science for what
we're doing here and I'm learning every
day I'm no idea what's going on from
2012 today
that's like six or seven years of
hardcore intensive sort of training I
mean it's a lifetime and every day is a
new day and every day you learn
something totally new and it's a very
complex world and just like everything
that's happening in THCA and this and
that and terpene thought of using what
are the effects and it started with
sativa as a make you feel awake and you
know indicator narrow leaf so it's like
all these things that we're learning
about this industry that's some nice
medicine and this herb in this
incredible plan but makes the soul
unique and valuable just lemon the
journey and that's why you caught that
in insanity right which I call a divine
madness right I mean we are we are we
have all been called by something right
which is I don't I don't think we've
fully wrapped our minds around hearts
around or certainly our brains around
what this thing is but we're all being
being called by the same force at the
same just like a really great feeling at
the end of the hall and you know what
the end of every day when I was in the
long-term care world I'd come home and
I'd actually have this feeling of like I
actually just actually provided for the
world today I'd like people died and we
took care of them we let them live their
lives with integrity we celebrated their
life for as long as they lived in these
homes and like all this stuff you know
and when I in transition of this career
and I was thinking how can I compare to
this value my life and feel the same way
about and interested in something but
this has actually done that for me and
so I'm you know this experience has
actually provided that value for me with
all the patients and all the lives that
are changed and all the incredible
stories that are shared with me over the
last seven years that I've been involved
in
I feel very fortunate to be included
cannabis in any senior facilities in
Canada than that many I have act
I had actually like corporate contracts
and seniors facilities to provide
prescriptions with the doctors to treat
medical indications like for real with
cannabis like that's what's going on
right now there's an animal patient he's
long to look there to all of it and
people are interested and they're you
know it's not the 90 year olds that are
like looking at this so intensely it's
the children of the seniors that are
looking at their poor parents like being
all doped up on opioids and drooling on
themselves and are non functioning well
let's just try this room and see if they
respond awesome they're walking around
holy [ __ ]
Greg hasn't walked in two years sitting
there drooling on herself we thought she
was done
well she's dancing having fun yes it's
freaky it's hard to feel bad when you
feel good like it is that's the truth
though then this happens well so I'm
nervous
one of the things we're going to do on
this trip is visit a elder community
down well for ten hours okay the one
that you went to know I'm getting ready
to go to right it's an elder community
the features of vegetarian diet that
incorporates nutritional cannabis into
that diet
cannabis medicines and and topical
treatments awesome and so I'm getting
ready to go down there and see it but
you know the organizers are just
reporting amazing amazing how those I'll
tell you try to leave
night we will see all the lights on the
mountains that yeah that made me so
happy
me too thank you really looks like it
looks like stars way it's certain points
you can see like you know these are
little family communities that's so
crazy I sure wouldn't be hard to find I
think we should go see you grow there's
100 of them remember that all of those
firms are growing vibrates oh yeah
they're growing but try this actually do
you want to go that they discovered yeah
he's like saw the Sun emerge so there's
these key figures and so L got to was
think one of the guys that went up into
the hills new Maren barrows and he
showed them how to extend their life
cycles all those lights a lot of them
are there because of him I told him I'm
like dude that's like epic like you're
like Mustapha the Nigerian that brought
slipping these screaming techniques to
[ __ ] Morocco in 1965 and started this
huge thing like imagine being the one
dude that went to Morocco I was just
like did you guys know about this have
you ever seen this before like 150 miles
of cannabis just kept planted so anyone
that says one person can't make a
difference I don't buy it yeah you know
it takes a lot it takes all of us but
there are certain key people at certain
times that just crack it out of the park
without even trying you know yeah but
then you you know you always wonder
right boys at the time or was it the
person then yeah or not it's like it's
taken an army of thousands of us tens of
them I mean it's very the point of all
this is this doesn't go back to the to
the 20s and the 30s like that's [ __ ]
you know it's strange years maybe
thousands so in the European tradition
I would I would put the date at around
teachers like the Roman Empire adopted
Christianity as its official religion
and then bishops were sent out all
across Europe to cut down the sacred
groves of trees to poison the sacred
Springs to burn the sacred books and
knowledge the Muslims redeem innocent
women not just the Christians I don't
know if it was 14 their 16th century in
Cairo but the Sufis the Muslim Sufis who
were hash eaters they were having their
teeth wrenched out in the squares they
would put their fingers down their
throats if they threw up green and it
was cannabis they can pull their teeth
and guess what yeah no it's a that's one
of my one of the stories that I tell
about this too if you actually if you go
back in history what you find is that
cannabis has always been an object of
suspicion by elites financial elites
racial elites religious elites any kind
of a leak and I think the reason for
that is that the authority of the direct
spiritual experience that we have with
an abyss is stronger than any other
intervening mediating authority they
can't send it back it's so true it's
always been that like seemingly forever
where people have just and it's people
who don't use it that have this massive
problem with it you know I think it was
dr. David Allen that talks about the
enemy
hijacking the little switch that's fight
or flight and he talks about the
endocannabinoid system and how this
little switch gets like rusted in to
flight mode and so a lot of people that
are like really severely severely
endocannabinoid efficient are like they
want to be prison guards they want be in
the army they want to work for the
police they want to like have control
and rule over people and it's like those
are the people that have the most
problem with people using cannabis it's
like like Steve said and 100 years from
now what we have never had before right
is with the reforms that have happened
and the sciences happened
we now have an ability to absolutely
document everything that we say so now
modern talking about is coming along
like for years yeah it would be like oh
yeah you can go look at the old oh now
take a look no we have the human
clinical trial analysis in computers
yeah with people that you see and
holding everything in the palm of their
hand like access to all you know say
what you want about those things but
they're definitely like a part of the
revolution you know like people
revolting because of what they learn on
these on these phones totally a part of
it okay two different the difference
between before internet and afternoon
today right when I first started doing
activist work if I wanted to catch the
government and a lie I had to sneak into
the university library which was like
you know at the two-hour bus ride away
it was too young to go into the
university right I'd have to go through
these card catalogs and I'd have to find
these old dusty values of like original
material then I have to copy them right
then I have to like get this stuff if I
wanted to share it with anybody I'd have
to like run it off on this old
technology called a mimeograph machine
and fold it on put it on some wood
stamps on it and take it to the post off
right it took forever to find how the
government lying debunk it now right
it's like I see so the piece of [ __ ]
that comes along ago debunk and I put in
the name of the study and usually like
I've got six or eight people around the
world who have already analyzed the
thing proving it to be false right my
forty thousand followers know about it
and they're spreading it on the Internet
oh yeah oh yeah did you see the RCMP
what they announced in Canada recently
they said this Lego gummy was such a
high milligram dosage it was enough to
kill a toddler oh my god they have since
retracted their track it's amazing
they're like we took a 25 pound dog and
injected it with three ounces of extract
intravenously and we surely thought it
would die and a day and a half later to
our surprise it was fully recovered then
we took another dog and injected seven
grams of pure extract into it you know
and they're just like it to our surprise
once again there's no dose we can give
these dogs to induce yeah like yeah they
could have just like gone back to the
East India Report which the English
Parliament commissioned it was published
in 1894 and they already tortured dozens
of dogs to prove this way back then they
did not need to do any more dog work
I don't know if you've ever been to the
ICRS the so I was there in Leiden in
March and the first day was great I went
with Dave Watson and some other friend
from Sager a tissue culture company and
you know the first day was all junket
partland
it was in you know a John Portland spoke
and he was great he's a character he was
doing the pollen study where the pollen
was found and it's tracing the history
of cannabis through these pollen tests
that they've done and it was great all
plant-based but the next day it turned
into like we tortured these mice for 14
hours at a time and they're like they
have to give them so much smoke because
and I asked the guy said why do you have
to give them like that much smoke that's
the equivalent of what the person
smoking 10 pounds and he's like well
when we give them a small amount we
can't tell I'm like yeah walk them
across an aboard of nails to see how
fast they react I'm just like listen
there's got to be better ways for us to
figure out mechanisms in the brain like
maybe maybe we could take psychedelics
and learn about some of this stuff like
why do we need to torture animals I
couldn't sit through it
these are monkeys and dogs and rats and
mice I was just like man this is like a
part of being the science that I'm not a
big fan of there's got to be another way
we can create a system that can still
produce results we can learn these
mechanisms we can learn how they work
without
creating that karmic debt one oh let's
see here in all of recorded human
history there is not one death that's
been introduced by cannabis they know
this so we can't have human trials we
instead need to torture animals who
don't have the ability to give informed
consent there's plenty of human beings
happy to give anything or consent to
participate cannabis [ __ ] with a
nelson research that guy he's been
smoking pot for 50 or 60 years like it's
unbelievable how they
look at it like still to this day I
think that until they acknowledge that
it's not dangerous that we don't need to
protect children from it that maybe we
should protect children from
pharmaceutical drugs like fentanyl and
alcohol like that those could those
things have very low ld50 numbers the
amount which is also a sick if you know
what ld50 means right back to testing in
animals and it's the amount of the dose
that they give the animals when a 50% of
the subjects and that's of course
there's an open story I mean but then
it's not such a worry the way they treat
cannabis like plutonium you have to have
a biometric three-foot fixed safe with
rebar in force and it's like treating it
like it's plutonium is a part of yeah to
me it's just part of an ongoing the way
their homes and their bars are sitting
out on their owners yeah of course you
know you're totally right you know that
they they still regard cannabis as a bad
plan and as a dangerous plan and that
informs everything so in California
right now we have basically a California
right now the since legalization for
adult use on one 118 we lost about 50%
of the previous legal consumer base
because the tax rate went from around
10% to in some places above 40,000 and
everybody who is in the market before
January 1st 2018 was somebody who had a
recommendation from their doctor a lot
of them were veterans a lot of them were
seniors a lot of them were families with
children and they were the parents
generation for the for the medicine for
the medicinal part didn't get
consideration in the tax there is there
was a split right there is a very small
enormous count which can be given okay
but in order to receive that discount
you have to have a doctor's
recommendation and you have to have a
state-issued canvas cart when you start
adding up the cost what everything
doctor requirements visit right the time
that you take off of work going down to
fill out the application picking your
card back up again you have to be you
know quite a heavy consumer to be able
to justify spending what amounts for
most people to four or five hundred
bucks to get a discount that's about
seven and a half percent yeah so I it
the the treatment of cannabis as a sin
product instead of a wellness product
has as sent you know the people who need
a legal regulated market than most
people who are vulnerable who have
compromised immune systems back into the
illicit market where the cannabis is is
untested right so you you see it
everywhere we I mean the tax rate a tax
rate of cannabis and California is
magnitudes higher than the tax rate for
alcohol so the state is incentivizing
people to consume a substance which we
know makes them reckless and violent
right and disincentivize people from
consuming a product that makes them gin
you know you raise a good point because
like I still talk to the people you know
in Canada and we're we're like you know
there's heavy taxes on this product and
they can go still visit their buddy
bill and grab their bag and don't pay
taxes on that but I'm like how crazy is
it that we've evolved to the point where
you can actually go in and out have an
educated decision but the product you're
gonna buy it
I mean to get to that point but the
testing and all everything that's
required to ensure that the grow and
everything is clean and tested and
profiled there's saqqaq there's a
there's a serious cost of that and i
think there's value to that I agree
absolutely first definitely no
definitely look I'm late and I'm talking
I'm talking to guys that are like well
often like can actually
for this and they're like saying oh I
still buy it off Bob because I get it
for 40 bucks for a half an ounce what am
i do what are you smoking
I wouldn't like we've evolved like this
is something that you know to the
dispensary you know this is this this is
that you can see the profiles like get
involved when see learn about what works
for you it's something that cannabis
consumers have a right to okay every
other product for human consumption to
make sure 8 it's safe so the idea that
that that the only way that you can get
a cannabis product that has been tested
and is safe is to pay 50% or 75% more
than you would need to on the
unregulated market it's just another one
of these examples of where the stigma
that attaches to cannabis
just continues to create all kinds of
social harm to get that to accuracy you
know it's not the cost of the testing
that's raising the price of cannabis at
least in California yeah there's yeah
look there's some cost that's tested
okay but what's really driven the price
high is the fact that the taxes are so
high and the reason the taxes are so
high is because there's a whole
constituency of the state of California
that would prefer to keep cannabis as
inaccessible as they can for as long as
they possibly can in the misguided
belief that they are protecting society
by doing that and many of them actually
think that they're doing the right thing
I mean you you're a hundred percent
right and I agree with you wholly that
the cost of the testing isn't raising
those prices but it's a cost of the
production to meet the criteria for the
testing for release for distribution
that's where the money is
I know but what above life what we get
in return for having to bear those costs
is the ability to scale and if you can
scale efficiently yeah then you think
our videos cost I and that's why I'm you
know
much as I love small right no man I mean
nice I did this here place where
cannabis consumers deserve what every
other consumer haves okay and yes we
should always be able to get good craft
cannabis I agree we should also be able
to get cannabis that's grown an
efficient scale that maybe a lower price
and we should always be cannabis in our
own homes right
a guru so but there should be a
multitude of ways for us to get cannabis
because there's a multitude of cannabis
consumers with different types of Altru
and there's a there's a huge new
infusion of into the cannabis culture of
all these young people that were never a
part of it before so we have to be open
with our arms and we were at a meeting
one time ago the gap it involves it's
since the beginning you know around
2012-2013 well I got my 25 years in you
know for us we started very young Jack's
book we were in our teens we've got
Jack's book we started reading it real
like kidding me this is crazy and we
were living in Manitoba and so we were
like how are we gonna do my dad pulled
me aside
thing better do it right didn't want to
get in trouble so me and my friends were
like let's become a head back to this we
learned all this [ __ ] from Jax club we
live in the prairies let's create a
document get some minused meetings with
our Minister of Finance and our Minister
of Agriculture and let's propose that we
grow hemp in the prairies and we went in
and our deck set on the front pages of
the trillion-dollar crop and the guy is
just like what you know world ready
dough
students Terrance and they're just he's
just like you know what is this guys and
we're like to make sure mate
it says the billion dollar crop and he's
like what's this I'm like well that's a
a magazine cover from Popular Mechanics
in 1932 and I'm pretty sure it was the
first time Billy and a dollar had ever
been used in an economic statement and
all his ears perked up I think he saw
what it was a real you know it was a Oh
cousin pages out of Jack's book he's
gonna believe an 80 year old man anyway
it took nine months
and we got a license to grow him we
planted our first 5 acre experimental
field in Manitoba in 1995 by 1998 all
the groups across Canada had organised
and changed the law from experimental to
commercial that was when the hemp seed
company started being coming into play
that year we started a fight or
remediation program in the Ukraine to
remove radioactive nucleotides out of
the soil using hemp we didn't know that
that could happen but the people who
grew in Ontario were tobacco farmers Joe
Strobel and Jeff came in 1994 think
about SARS licence oh well they spray
radium-226 on their tobacco fields it's
a radioactive nucleotide that raises the
levels of nicotine not allowed to do it
in a lab but you can do it under the guy
an herbicide and a pesticide that they
have to wear like hazmat level seven
suits or whatever super poisonous [ __ ]
so they have to test their field and so
after the hemp crop they tested it and
they were like this is here like where
did it all go happened then they tested
they happen they realized all hemp is
pulling out radioactive nucleotides so
that turned into a trinova project and
it turned into this pretty cool thing
that kind of all it was this it was a
the company was called consolidated
growers and processors and it didn't go
anywhere I mean the woman that was in
charge of it maybe was a con woman
I don't know she ended up in prison the
company kind of folded but my partner's
started Manitoba harvest and so that
company recently sold Oh about three
years ago it sold to the Compass Group
433 million and then the Compass Group
just sold it to tilray for 419 million
so a hemp seed company you know like
that was just kind of started by a bunch
of dredges that were like English and I
was in the has finished read when that
would all that man anything you know I
started my company evolution
I remember a pollution we were
supporters we sold it out our hemp store
the hemp exchange yeah we used to buy
evolution that was one of very few I
mean what was a 2-star dog came down
later on down to show dog there was a
little after up there's a couple other
companies I mean Danny always had access
to good stuff and Rob was you know
another good source but Rob's doing hemp
again now I don't know if you know about
Rob Clark's project Anarchy he's got
this beauty he's doing beautiful rugs
and all sorts of you know it's called
hemp boutique I believe meant he's
working with a good friend of mine from
Turkey Amir and they've got beautiful
stuff they got like drumsticks that are
stops like the fibers okay
we got to remember to talk to rob about
it yeah get rumble call he'll be stoked
so do you I do it did is well let me
tell you all story because I'm not gonna
ask if you know it because probably one
or two of you might write but if you
take a look at the Indian flag of India
you'll see that there's a circle
and that circle is a spinning wheel and
the reason that it's there is because of
the role that textiles played in the
indian movement for independence so back
in the days of the English Empire when
it was ruling India they would buy
cotton from Indian farmers at very very
low prices they would ship it all the
way to Manchester they would mill it
into textiles and then they would bring
it back to India and I ridiculously huge
profit
so Mahatma Gandhi started a movement for
Indians who supported independence to
spin their own cotton and weave their
own I'm like an 8 foot backstrap loom or
whatever mm-hmm exactly right that's the
same and and the fabric that was
produced is called Cuddy and Cuddy has
this very distinctive rough texture it
looks just like yeah and it became the
symbol that supporters of the
independence movement always were fewer
supported the independence movement then
you work haughty you wouldn't think of
buying fabric that was produced in the
English factory an amazing be English
empire arete right so I think the time
has come now for us to embrace that
vision for the cannabis right for a long
long time it was difficult to find him
products that were reasonably stylish
enough that they could catch traction
but I think that's changed now and as
soon as as soon as I start finding some
more really very kind of stuff I'm just
I'm going to start wearing it all the
time
about it right here bezel that is
another thing that we can do to to break
down stigma and educate people about
cannabis that's very easy Oh take a look
at my jacket did you know yeah
well surely is something that he'll
probably find interesting and appreciate
what we have I mean I was so involved in
the hemp projects from the beginning I
moved out to BC very early on 96
we got hemp going I was like okay my
furnace I'll go to BC be our pioneer
well he just stayed in Manitoba and did
this hemp thing I ended up hooking up
with Hilary black becoming the first
grower for the BC compassion club she
was like kind of in love with Todd
McCormick she was like should I go back
down to California and live in a mansion
next to the Reagan's a real weed and I
was like or should I stay in Canada and
start a compassionate Club that's like
she became a servant to the people this
girl who grew up like fairly like you
know in West Vancouver when a well-off
family gave up everything and just went
and her integrity was so high she just
like didn't make any profit for like 20
years
and so I felt you know that experience
of getting to grow for those people
they're all terminally ill this was 97
98 so it was a lot of AIDS patients
suffering from wasting syndrome it was a
lot of junkies out on the street that
had acquired all sorts of heinous
diseases like some of them were stacked
like five or six and they had mental
health problems and it was it was the
beginning of civil disobedience where we
were kind of like you know we can't do
this for headaches it's gotta be
something serious
you know where it got you know
California of a sudden some years later
it's like all they're just the one for
headaches like as if it works for
headaches little did they know healthy
for the rabbit hole where people are
just always trying to you know downplay
the the effects but yeah just moving out
to BC was it was
you know meeting Hillary doing that for
the club getting busted at a roadblock
was 16 pounds and a bunch of cash
because people were breaking into her
club they were driving cars right
through the front windows and then
trying to steal the safe so I took home
some herb one day and got popped at a
roadblock with it and became one of the
first compassion club cases in Canada
Richardson versus Regina was my case
John Conroy was my lawyer and it was I
had no idea that had anything over three
kilos in Canada at the time was a
maximum fine of anyone guess 25 years
for just over and I'm like whoa like
just a second like this is just flowers
like what you guys talking about I don't
think anyone's ever been given it unless
you know there was other circumstances
going on but it still freaked me out to
face that and in that moment I was it
was a cop who busted me in a roadblock
and I remember thinking like is this a
is this a costly mistake or a valuable
lesson now I lost all this stuff for the
club and I felt like I had to pay it
back and then I had to pay a lawyer and
I had to do all this stuff and I didn't
know what to do and I started the bubble
Bank company that was and I thanked that
cop years later at a roadblock even
Constable John Lowe I pulled up to a
roadblock I was like John he's like he's
the clues man I'm like Mike Richardson
you don't remember you busted me at the
roadblock end of the bridge I said
listen I want to thank you because I'm
not being sarcastic it or not like I
really want to thank you like you helped
me in a way that I can't even begin to
thank how much like it's like because of
you like thousands of people around the
world are making their own clean hash
and that would have never happened I'm
serious I'm not being negative I'm not
trying to be like give you a [ __ ] you
I'm like I'm serious man like you you
were you're a big part of this you're a
big part of my history man and I'm gonna
mention you every chance that I get is
you're a part of my history you know I
said earlier I think we're all being
called by a force that's too big for us
to comprehend right and that force works
and
really mysterious ways and sometimes
brings us pain so that we can be
motivated to make the changes to this
world
exactly I'm a fleece throw that right
there well the pleasure sitting and
hanging out with your guy you're
definitely a person I've wanted to meet
for a long time being in the industry
for so long I've admired the things that
you've done the moves that you've made
I've seen I've watched I paid attention
today when I'm late when I was just like
I got a text them I'm just gonna be like
no he loves that
it's beautiful hash let's link up I
figured you'd be super busy not too busy
for this look
when I first I got I got busted and then
I smiling on a cloudy day I got busted a
1991 Saturday I got busted in 1999 with
exactly a hundred and ninety a glass of
memory
I never forgot any case the important
part of the stories that I got posted in
1999 couple hundred pounds of weed
fairly serious I charged in the United
States at that time and [ __ ] MERIS ago
so I get busted I [ __ ] lose
everything that I've worked for I all
the cash the house everything
everything's gone like 45 years old and
and I'd already been in the process of
moving to California got out to
California and I got like nothing so I
go into the dispensaries and I see these
ugly little balls of black goo that are
supposed to be water hatch and and I was
like I tried it it was just it didn't
work for me but I had read Rob Clark's
book right so I understood the process
right and he's one yeah as I said where
where he had instructions for making
water - right my first I started that
was the Mafia's own right I start off
with the coffee cone so I was like
familiar with the technology in fact
when I used to go down to Mexico I would
bring coffee cones with me so that I
would be
you know have some good hash to smoke
well while I was while I was down there
but but I took a look at this situation
I was like alright there's an
opportunity here so I got your bubble
bags size of those bubble bags up to
Mendocino calico and I started
collecting everybody's trim which at
that point they were like oh you want to
take it away from here hello yeah I'm
getting ready to compost it he changed
all the way right and and so what I did
differently was drying and sipping the
product and and then branded Shiva
Crystal's was the brand and and we hit
the market probably like 2003 is my is
my guess so man you you know your bags
helped me because the business that
allowed me to get back on my feet
time to start Harborside I tell you it
wasn't too like 2003 2004 I get calls
from guys from Eureka Trinity County all
in that area Mendocino maybe like
[Laughter]
touches my heart man like I mean I'm
just selling bags you guys are the ones
putting them to use you know I'm just
putting the information out there and
teach them people and it's been it's
been one of the biggest blessings of my
life being able to do that you know
going to Jamaica in 2000 bringing bubble
bags turning all the farmers and orange
hill onto it giving bubble bags away you
know to the tune of a couple grand each
trip that I did it because I knew no
one's gonna be able to buy $250
you know bags but just teaching people
that was so rewarding and being in the
grill
when they had the one hi Times Cannabis
Cup can't remember 2014 maybe they're
announcing the winners for the hash it's
like you know third place is this guy
Winfred he's he's he's one of the guys
that gave back to second place is junior
he's like one of my Bros that I taught
personally first place is Ziggy he's the
guy that I gave him the first banks to
in Jamaica like it was unbelievable it
just makes me feel so good of course and
to see the pride in their face you know
like I took this skill I've kept it over
the course of 19 or 15 years and I I
worked it and I if you listen to the
bags they can direct you to finding the
cannabis that you're looking for you
know or growing better cannabis or
figuring out how to get a plant to
express those profiles to the maximum
you know effectiveness of its abilities
and so people a lot of people didn't get
that and the people who had great weed
they may bubble hash with like this is
genius but 80% of everyone else were
like they made that black goo balls and
we're just like nah this is what let's
just make butane there's no matter how
shitty your weed was Beauty always kind
of came out as a gold oil so tool to a
lower level kind of connoisseur or
someone that's just getting into it
that's good quality that's like look at
the quality it's like nothing like and
the same resin would be like sand
you couldn't press together if we made
bubble out of it and the number one
question for bubble hash makers is how
do I get my hash to melt like yours
and I always have to say well I don't
want to be a dick but you have to grow
better herb like you have to and if you
listen to the bags they're there they're
your word of God they'll direct you you
just just keep trying new things making
mistakes learning and and you know
putting puttin your yourself out there
to take in get this knowledge that's out
there because there are incredible
people putting this out non-stop
Instagram you know Twitter or Facebook
like all the different cannabis sites
all the different social medias like
it's amazing how willing people are in
particular with cannabis to share the
like it's like where else like you said
there's this calling that it's like not
only am i super passionate about this
and making it my life but I have to
scream it from the mountaintops to about
like scream it from the mountaintops you
absolutely have to scream it from the
mountaintops right because I mean my
belief is that the that the existence of
our species and possibly the existence
of this planet is right on that you take
a look at all of the ugly things that
are happening in the world today in
people's hearts and minds and in the way
that we're treating the planet a wake-up
call is clearly needed and you just
start thinking a different way of acting
in different way I don't know of
anything well I know some other
visionary plants but yeah in terms of
what's realistic in today's world I
don't know anything else is capable of
making that change in the time that we
have less what is it twelve years that
we supposedly have left to dial down
global warming before yep
so scream it right I mean that's what
we've been doing all these years and we
just got to keep doing but here's the
good thing oh yeah like what I've seen
here in these two conferences in
Colombia is that you know how how under
prohibition it kept us all isolated into
these really really small communities
and we couldn't be open so we had our
own small circles of tight people that
we trusted and and and that operated on
a local level and operated on National
Lab all right and now with reform
actually reaching multiple different
countries around the world right we are
able to come out of our hiding places
we're able to like say oh hey you look
kinda like me yeah kind of talk like me
you even kind of dress like me oh maybe
maybe are you in my tribe today right
you know so we're seeing this like
coming together of this cannabis tribe
that has been existing all around the
world for all of these years but we've
been forced and dispersed into this like
hidden diaspora right yeah and now we're
coming out of those hiding places and we
are meeting each other linking like it
is all these little learning linking
teaching right that's a teaching
function that we've been doing I think
if you teach correctly you're always
learning we have another meeting all
right guys what a pleasure I'd love to
grab a picture with you and Bruce let's
Greta it was possible that would be
amazing
[Music]
you