[Music]
Hey guys, welcome to Bowman's World. Um
today we're heading downtown and we're
going to go meet up with um well
hopefully we'll see Dana Larson from
Sensible BC and Original Cannabis
Culturer. Um we will see maybe Jody and
Jeremiah down at Pot TV along with
Marijuana Man. I'm definitely going to
be seeing Matt the Great Gardener and
John Burfellow. Uh we were supposed to
maybe do a little bit of a show on Paw
TV with Jeremiah there, but today I
wanted to actually talk to you guys a
little bit about, you know, we show you
a lot of this uh the main stuff with how
the the cannabis is grown, how it's
processed, how the hash is made, how the
hash is cleaned, but I've never really
shown you a simple thing like how do I
get the hash back to the great gardener
without it turning into a giant puck of
grease. So, this is how ridiculous you
got to roll when you're rolling with
full melt dry sift, particularly of the
caliber of the great gardener um full
melt dry sift, which
is it's insane. It's just so greasy. You
literally have to do this. So, I have
multiple ice
packs. I have the three containers. Um
the seconds's on top, the first on the
bottom, and this is I guess what you
call thirds. couple of different grades
and then a a cooking grade. I've got
another giant thing of ice here and I've
got an ice pack that it's all sitting on
and it's inside a cooler. So, this is
what you have to do if you want to hope
to have a chance on on getting I want to
be able to give this to Matt and I want
it to be powder, perfect powder. I don't
want it to be all clumped up and greasy
and I just prefer it like that. So, this
is what you got to do. Get yourself a
cooler. Get yourself some ice packs.
Make sure you get that sift into a
container that's sealed in every way.
You don't want any moisture getting into
your dry sift. One of the great things
about dry sift is you don't have to dry
it. So, it would be a shame to get
moisture uh in your dry sift and then be
forced to dry it.
So, on that note, I think we're going to
have a dail rib. Got a tiny bit of the
barb dry sift here.
Just rolled it into kind of a little
puck. Should be able to dab that quite
nicely. Little mini hit
there. Hitting it through the D- nail.
Very nice. So, we'll clean that dabber
up and we'll hit a little of the Astro
Boy fresh frozen that John and I made
the other day. I think that's always in
order. Nice little Astro Boy Chaser to
my 99% barb dry sift
rip. I was able to go out into town the
other day and just give a few key
friends um a taste of this. My my friend
Frank Coover, uh my buddy Marijuana Man,
the original Marijuana Man, Greg from
Pot TV, and uh as well as John B. Always
got to share with John B.
Oh, yeah.
Anyway, I'm going to head downtown and
we'll catch up with you guys down there.
Peace. All right. I've just arrived down
on the pot lock and I'm going to head on
over to the uh vapor
[Music]
lounge.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
How's it going? How are you? Good. Are
they setting up over there yet?
Hey. Hey. How's it going, dude? Good.
How you doing, buddy? Nice to see
you. All right, I think I'm going to set
up over here. How's it going,
Marius? Time to filming some hot TV.
Hey, what's up? What's up, Mark? How's
it going, dude?
Good. Oh, time for a session.
Go see upstairs. I'll be right
[Music]
back. Yeah, actually.
How's it going? Yo, I showed up. You
did, Jeremiah. We got quite the [ __ ]
show today, too. Are you working hard? I
am working hard. You're [ __ ] right,
dude. I'm working damn hard. It's good
to see. I see the on the phone with Mr.
Enrico Buchard. How's Enrico doing? He's
going to call in the show live from jail
today. Yeah, he's doing okay. Um they're
not the bail's high. Uh well, he hasn't
had that hearing yet, but um they have
uh put the charges on him for seeds.
Now, they're saying basically that he
sold a couple packs of seeds to an
undercover officer and he also sold a
couple packs to see of seeds to these
people who started this grow operation
apparently. Jeez. And that's how they
got him. And now he Enrio isn't a seed
seller. He's the inventor of the
sublimator. He has a restaurant. Um the
seed thing was just that a friend called
him and was wondering if he could get
some seeds for these people and he just
did a favor. Got the friend was a narc.
The friend I guess somebody narked and
there was an undercover officer involved
somehow and uh and somehow Enrico got it
all pinned on him, dude. That he was
selling seeds to this big grow
operation. And but Enrico beforehand had
had verified that they were medical
patients that they were using this for
their sickness. They were going to
supposedly to take it home and grow it
in their own garden. It wasn't meant to
be some big grow operation where people
were selling it. So he's going to call
in while we're on the show. Call during
the show. Now the crazy thing is that uh
they've been using our video that we
shot on Paw TV of Enrico in the Strain
Hunters vehicle and stuff like playing
it on the TV. Yeah. And so this seems
like kind of one of those things, you
know, why do people when do the cops
ever go after seed dealers? There's sea
companies on every [ __ ] block. We I
have there's like several sea companies
out here on the street right in front of
us here. Yeah. I always think that it's
a specific thing, right? It probably
fell right into their lap and then they
decided, well, let's just uh let's get
80 different cops to work on this for
the next 6 months. We'll spend like, you
know, like 400k. Exactly. And uh we'll
make a big news story. And that's really
what it is. And Enrico happens to be a
guy who's gaining some notoriety in the
pop movement. He's probably becoming
more popular out there in Quebec. His
name's making it around. You know, they
know where to go to find footage of him
on TV. Enough, you know. You going to do
a bong wrap? I'm going to hit this bong
right now. I have some. Now, I believe
this is I was told this is uh what is
it? Uh seaw's haze cross with nepoese
the bud. And I have a little bit of
butter that was given to me as a gift
sprinkled on top. Rip it up. Boom.
Falazi. Boom.
Falazi.
[Music]
Booyah. All right. So, I just got to the
BCMP, the vapor lounge here, and bumped
into Melwin, who uh was at the booth at
420, and he's got his buddy Johnny here,
and uh Sarah, who's hiding kind of
behind him there. There we all are.
We're about to do some D nail rips,
guys. It's got a nice
clean tattoo. Yeah. Straight
fab that you may have thought was
remove. Let's clean this. You get lazy
with the Gmail on the cleaning of the
piece. Yeah.
Today I just thought that's nasty. You
can't take that out. It's always nice to
have clean piece.
That's what I'm saying. So, first up,
fresh frozen Astro Boy that I grew
myself in wash a couple days ago with
John B. This is [ __ ] awesome. The
water.
[Music]
[Applause]
Yeah. Car too. It's always nice to use
it when you have
[Music]
it.
Yeah, is cranking the tunes for
[Music]
us. How's
that noise?
[Music]
pop
[Applause]
[Music]
res almost 20
years really high profile as bubble man
not really able to do
something but Now the
[Music]
[Applause]
license, right? Yeah. Just like dessert.
Dessert. I didn't know that.
[Music]
Well, once again, just like John B, he
uses cannabis exclusively for his pain
medication
[Applause]
[Music]
for
Heat.
[Music]
[Applause]
Heat.
[Music]
Awesome. That was
nice. We'll catch up with you guys in a
bit. Peace. So, look who just got here.
Mr. Matt is in the house. The great
gardener. What's up, everybody? How's it
going? And my responsibility is almost
complete. Uh-huh. I'll tell you, people
have no idea about this aspect, how
ridiculous this is. It is ridiculous. I
showed them earlier on the the start
part of this video of how many ice packs
I had to put into
here to keep this
hash from greasing up. I only have two
ice packs. I'm going have to borrow one.
Yeah, these are the ice packs that I
brought knowing that the grease up
factor within 5 minutes happened. It's
really that one that you're that you're
going to want to be. Uh Although I'd be
surprised if it was
nice. I did things a little bit
differently this time. So I got less
seconds and it's nicer.
And then
surprisingly lost gets to get lost.
Yeah, it's pretty nice. I couldn't
believe it personally.
So yeah, while while the one is out,
just put it in into the ice. It's just
that easy because it really is just a
moment of getting nice and stone. Oh,
let's do a rib sitting out there. The
sun shifts, comes through, the shade
goes away, the sun beats on it for like
18 seconds. It's a brick block. It's
never you're never going to be There's
something nice about the way he's
shaking it right now. It's just moving
around. This is the way this is the way
I wish all the people in Spain and all
over the place when I when I have it. I
always talk I wish you guys could come
here and experience it when it's in
powder form. This
is right and we're doing everything we
can to invent ways of getting that
getting it powder form out to the world.
Um the numbers um it was about 135 g
when this tub was full and I cleaned it
and I cleaned uh 23 g of seconds. I
cleaned 40 g of thirds and I cleaned 66
g or 66.7 g of first you know 99% head.
So that ratio is 50%. So, that was some
pretty clean sit that was already 50%
heads before I got a hold of it. So, I
cleaned out 50% of that material. And
now, uh now Barbara is truly able to
show her quality when she's combined
with with the proper purity. Oh, the
flavors. It's the fl It's the flavor.
Even the smell. My whole house reeks
like bar 99% right now. And I was being
religious about like keeping it cool and
going into the freezer right away. And
in fact, my whole freezer also smells
like 99%.
It's pretty awesome. I would get It's
going to be great. A colder freezer for
that. Oh, no. It lives like in Yeah, it
literally But I mean, at certain
temperatures like 3 or whatever, I swear
to God, you can still smell it. You can
still smell the tarpen evaporating at
minus4. Can I roll a couple? Those are
some volatile oils. Of course.
You want the ice?
My backpack.
Yeah, makes sense. You want that, too?
Pack it up for travel.
[Music]
Awesome. Well, that's an important thing
done. I
uh come check us out at our booths at
Champs 222. Actually, I'm uh
519. Yeah, James. 519. And I've been
shouting out 222 to everyone for the
last like 4 days. 519. I'm uh 506 and
John's 407. Our booths are combined, so
we're all we'll all be in a fairly uh
close area. Definitely come check us out
at Champs. And uh Champs, it's going to
be a great time. I think I'm on a panel
on Friday with Simon
uh from Sirius Seeds and the Joint
Doctor. Excellent. So that's I think
Friday at 2:30. I'll make sure I film
that so you guys can uh you guys can
check it out on Bubble Man as well. I
know you got a plane to catch. I got a
plane to catch. Thanks for uh Well, here
let me give you one quick. See everybody
in Toronto.
Actually, let me give you my This is
right here. My fresh frozen uh one you
just made. Yeah.
Not all every day I get to give uh you
know, Matt the great gardener some resin
that I personally grew and washed. So,
have a
treat. Certainly don't mind cleaning up
after that hit.
Awesome. See you guys later. All right,
dude. Safe travels.
Peace. Later.
I'm going to wait for John B to show up
and we're going to go film with Jeremiah
from 420 News. Catch you in a bit. All
right, Johnny's in the house.
I actually don't know. Yeah, I was going
to wear my le and a half shirt and his
last minute.
Right, these guys are setting up for
Jeremiah's uh Pot TV 420 news. There's
Mario over there. John's about to take a
rip of his of what? My Little Pony made
He's one of those bronies.
He's a brony.
[Music]
Sorry, don't be.
And it is also super quality. Just gave
uh Matt the great gardener his dry
[Music]
samp. Then I bumped into John and he's
got some My Little Pony fresh pros and
I'm not sure 73 or 90.
I appreciate it.
It is very
fresh. I think I might have to
[Music]
double
power. I want to switch these two
nice here.
[Music]
I'm going to turn my camera off now and
we're going to go on Jeremiah's show
here in a few minutes. So, we'll see you
over there, guys. Peace. Peace. Well,
how about that for a deja vu, John? I
know. We're back again. We just had a
delicious meal. Herb crush salmon for
myself. I had the the salmon rice bowl.
The barbecue salmon rice bowl. Yeah, I
like the rice bowl. wasn't too happy
with How about those appetizer with the
AI tuna tacos and the sushi cones
becoming a regular dude I'm telling you
like what would you guys like they don't
even right now I think it's just more of
a why aren't you getting lobster grilled
cheese I haven't gotten it for a while
now and I'm okay with that you know what
it's good it's nice to try different
things we've been hitting it up for
dinner lately actually so John and I
just uh yeah finished the pot TV episode
there with Jeremiah on his news 420
news, cannabis culture news. Yeah. You
know what? It was a quick in and out and
say hello, talk about the chance coming
up event and discussing u discussing
doctor's prescriptions and how they're
educating doctors across Canada to
prescribe cannabis for different
conditions and stuff like that, which
was a good show. Talked about champs,
talked about Enrico.
Yeah, poor guy getting messed up with a
bunch of [ __ ] Yeah, we've all been
there.
Maybe not. Maybe not in that
level. Yeah,
but what are we hitting there? Um,
whatever it is, he left me none. He took
it all. It was a tiny little rip. Wow.
But I have a whole other jar of hash for
John. See, he left me the
best. I never mess around when it comes
to John. In fact, how is the hash that I
uh gave you last time? Is it still I
actually after you know he's like here
I'll give you a little bit of hash and I
had a good story. He filled up the
container like really it was nice. It
lasted me like a month and everybody
knows how much I puffed. So there's
actually hash left in here. Totally.
What are you talking about? It was just
like you're
silly. You
know. So I'm going to heat up this side.
Yes. And I
will help dab a friend up. Oh, that's a
very nice thing. We drove around the
block here for about a couple of rounds
before we realized there's some huge
movie or TV show filming and they've
literally got every parking spot blocked
off as not a parking spot right now. For
the last 6 minutes, we've been parked
illegally. So, we thought, what better
thing to do while you're parked
illegally in Vancouver but to smoke some
hash.
Well, people walk by and look in the
vehicle and think, "What the [ __ ] are
those guys doing in there?" Take a look.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Was that bad looking?
No. No. It was kind of just like I think
those guys are dabbing.
I see us smoking um full milk. Oh, that
smells nice. So tasty, too. Oh my
goodness. See, see where the difference
is? Nice to have a dessert hit after.
It's that beautiful dessert hash like
that is so tasty. No coughing, no
nothing. There's no moisture in there.
It's very tasty. Just beautiful. Yeah,
we did it. We did it. Job well done.
Well, I'm going to head my way. John's
got some rush hour. No, worse than rush
hour. Um rush hour long weekend traffic.
Traffic and rush hour, though. Yeah. Oh,
no. I guess that's over. You never know.
I might it might take me a while. I I
might pop in, but uh I got to try and uh
get my uh upload done. I was doing an
upload today. Do nice. Yeah. Go check
out John on his uh channel at John H.
Perfellow YouTube channel. He's been
uploading uh some bubble hash making
videos and dry sift videos and growing
videos and just what I do. Just all the
things that uh that you want to see John
doing. What we do. Exactly. You know.
Indeed. Awesome. Well, once again,
buddy, it was a pleasure hanging out
with you and bumping into you. I'm going
to head off my way, you head off yours,
and we will see you guys later.
[Music]