[Music]
uh
heom dry sift cleaned the [ __ ] up on the
ceramic dish and uh ready when you are
Matt ready all
[Music]
right Ru
and
again lion with li with the lion with
the LI with the LI
the
the the
[Music]
andus napole Bel Julius Octavian and
Augustus in the August and in the July
try still you are not of the
lion still you are not of the lion child
bring my daughters bring my
son I know that the day will
come I know that the day will
come I know that the day will come
napon
the obsessed with
being
man
and Egyptian culture conquer the
conquerer bring my daughters bring my
son I know that
the I know that the come
I know that
the
[Music]
every Washington DC