[Music]
hey welcome to Bubble man's world I'm
here with my good buddy Mike who I've
known for over 15 years a bubble
Ambassador and we're sitting here at the
Shannon Archer Memorial bench it's just
over to the side here I've decided now
that I'll just have my sessions next to
the bench not to offend anyone and uh
it's just a beautiful day here in
British Columbia heading up to the to uh
Squamish on the way up to Whistler on
our
motorcycles and uh we thought we would
stop and I would tell you a little bit
about this Apex electronic cigarette
that I recently got turned on to in uh
Jamaica so I realize the camera angle is
pretty dark but uh I wanted to show you
this we're going to have a little
session it'll be my first time hitting
this unit
my buddy bird who I met in Jamaica
Kingston Jamaica awesome dude this guy
is fun he's going to come up he'll like
bird okay really really character of a
guy and so he uh gifted me this and said
check it out see what you think I was
hitting one in Jamaica and I was quite
impressed with it so we've got this uh
really big uh strong metal he always
bangs it to show how strong it is and uh
you know you've got your dome right here
he's got the ceramic dish fish with the
um Titanium element it's a little bit
bigger and deeper than most that I've
seen it gives a real serious rip um it
also comes with a charger a little
silicone case for your hash uh a steam
version a vaporizer version for herb
that screws on and then the oil version
as well although any pen will fit on the
um Apex battery because it's the same I
don't know if it's 10 mil or what the
size is exactly but it's the same as the
majority 99% % of all the pens out there
so I figured how long does the battery
last 4 days wow dude that's what I'm
saying now that's what he says I told
him dude I bet you I kill it in a day
and he says I bet you don't
so let's put it to the test I'll give
you two days watch us kill it right now
in three
hits the bugs is it brand new with a
factory charge or did you give it a
charge yeah it's basically brand new
with a factory
charge what was that for a will fill out
that's a Topper look that ants all over
me right now must be sitting on the
nest there that's a good amount yeah
it's
full clean the
edges rip that
Dome like to do the honors brother oh
thank you front button kind of sits in
your hand so you can do kind of this or
this I was kind of doing this way and
had it in my hand or you could do it
this way you can do it any way you want
I wouldn't turn it at too much of an
angle Le with the powder for the
beginning but once you here we go once
you flame on oh yeah that definitely
globed right out right away and turn to
a nice Smoky nice little chamber here
you can look at your Vapor yeah how's
that taste really good little 99% dry
sift really good nice the aftertaste is
amazing yeah
dude M thank you for that honor hell
yeah
wow I like
it and they call it an electronic
cigarette but I think I swear he should
call it something
different it's kind of some Next Level
[ __ ] it comes with a little tool yeah a
little Dabber tool for getting your [ __ ]
in there nice you could tell the parts
are high
quality what's that the charger in
here yeah and then the
battery I get that it's like a little
smaller than a
c but bigger than yeah your standard
vape pen 3.7 volt 18 800 milliamps so
yeah that's got quite a charge man you
could probably go four days I could see
that yeah real deal for sure and it
complement the whole size of the thing
yep big enough to house that battery
that's what I'm saying and the way it
fits in the hand is quite nice as
well I do like this sort of thing right
here mhm does it have an on and off auto
kind of thing so when you pack it away
does it like you know lot of vaporizers
have a five button on off it doesn't do
that oh but he said he's never had the
problem it's such a heavy button but it
doesn't like feel how heavy that button
is you really got true you know compared
to that little plastic button that all
you have to do is lean it up against
something it's a springloaded button
it's a spring loaded button exactly
pretty cool little product I got to say
I'm definitely hats off to the Apex pen
uh we'll be carrying them on Fresh
headies here in the near future and uh
we still carry trippy sticks so check us
out for uh our variety of vapor pens
that we promote remember I only use the
two the ones that work the best for
me and props to the dry sift too yeah
killer beautiful was that a AST no that
was um oh it was an OG Kush cross a
fruity OG Kush
cross remember the name of it all right
cleaned it for a
friend so we're going to continue our
ride here we're here by on motorcycles
we're going to continue up on the
Highway 99 towards
Squamish catch you guys in a bit all
right peace all right guys so we just
arrived here in Squamish you can see uh
the chief over in the distance that big
giant chunk of granite behind the Tim
Hortons and uh this is the Shady Tree
they got some really nice food here
we're going to go in and have a salmon
burger or something along that line so
uh in the shade why don't you guys come
with
us any little bit
helps
it's all fun and games until someone
closes the bar M mine would be it's all
fun and games until the denail
breaks no Vape back up
exactly all right here we
go please seat yourselves all right we
can do that no kids cuz it's all right
so there's the salmon burger from the
Shady Tree that I was talking about what
do you got buddy it's a full pork ooh
with onion rings onion rings nice and
Bob looking up like he's looking above
up above the
Rings
yeah time to
eat all right guys welcome back Mike and
I are now at I guess we're at brtan
beach yeah brania mines are right there
yeah so if you've ever driven uh home
from Whistler this is the Sea to Sky
Highway Pacific Ocean on the right we're
right in front of a giant mine they used
to film X Files and such things in there
yeah yeah it's an old copper mine yeah
exactly kids have gone and done the tour
with their school yeah Scooby-Doo was
shot down all right that as well so
we're sitting next to the ocean we
thought we haven't dabbed yet so I got
the Hitman out put a little water in it
and yes uh Mike said is it okay that
it's salt water it's going to have to be
for
now sea water sea water oh I actually
got to get one more piece of the puzzle
which is a very important factor it is
the
nail I thought thought I should bring
this Seaside Nails Seaside Nails get the
nail out see what's going on Torch to
bring our temperatures up to
nail yes yes
yesing what temperatures do you need for
the nails work uh we just heat it up
orange and then wait for a few minutes
and then dab it or wait for a few
seconds usually just heat up the right
side which you can get on doing just
like
this you want to kind of hear that sound
to make sure you know the T there that
sound this is great for portability it's
my first torch
nail you got the sound that sound right
there so we're hitting some full melt
dry sift that I made about a month back
I think it was uh an OG cush cross from
uh a friend up in Prince George A friend
of d420 K shout out to Jay for uh for
this dry
sift man it's got to be like 95° right
now yeah and a little even more with
this torch next here yeah right
all right let's see we'll give that a
little bit more of a
hit all right I think she's a
girl I think she's a girl
Mike that was a real nice
rip real nice
look at that quality
too clean ends very
pure it's definitely good funny thing uh
to tell you guys we climbed a gnarly
fence to get in
here thinking it's just you know it was
tough we got to climb in we got to get
in here there's this huge fence right
here we're not supposed to be in here
and uh there's not a fence like 30 ft
back so we won't be jumping the fence
necessarily this heat up the other end
the other side the opposite side
yeah
perfect
sound oh yeah I see your oranging
out tempted to go for a
swim ready
yep
Pitman rips by the Pacific Ocean I wish
you guys could see exactly how much that
was bubbling in here almost overflowing
like magma melted up quite nice didn't
it well done so I guess we're about 15
to 20 minutes away from uh the home
station so it shouldn't be too far for
us to get back the highway is quite busy
it being Sunday on I guess some sort of
holiday it's uh yeah BC day tomorrow's
the stat holiday so today's the Sunday
long weekend ah so lots of cars coming
down from whar tons of cars coming down
I couldn't believe
it and uh maybe we're going to go for a
dip in this ocean right now it's so hot
I'm telling you man the right thing to
do pretty
much in the
O I got I got trunks in the bike nice
thanks for that rip of them man yeah
most uh welcome Mike good
stop so our next adventure takes us to
Lions Bay lb yeah we're off to lb if we
have a swim we'll share a little bit of
it if not see you guys in lb see
[Music]
you