[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am here with Chris Bennett you guys may
have seen him on hash Church the other
day thanks for coming by what's pleasure
man to Hash church and thanks for having
me by here at your Abode I'm super
excited to talk to you about a few
different things and we've got a couple
of ships on the table so we can get uh
sublimating and denailing while we yeah
while we discuss uh some things so it
was pretty cool having you on hash
Church the other day it was uh I mean
I've always known you've had a a deep
knowledge of sort of different
historical contexts where cannabis has
found itself and one of the things I
appreciate about that historical context
is that you look from it you look for it
from other sources other than like
cannabis authors yeah yeah well I don't
want to be quoting you know cannabis
Advocates so I'm looking more at like
archaeologist work Anthropologist work
history of religions religious texts and
things like that and digging around in
those and then trying to accumulate them
and put them in one place where people
can access that information very cool I
think I heard your bird coughing while
you were yeah yeah my bird he mimics the
cough and uh uh inhale so he'll be
making a bit of noise in the background
his bird takes hits and then coughs
after uh the exhale and it's pretty
funny and I just heard it right before
he explained that so uh Chris has a
bunch of cool little things to sort of
show us and I figured we'd probably get
the party started by having a dab I'm
always down for a dab what about
yourself ah sounds good yeah yeah I'm
not too big a Dabber mostly I vaporize
you know raw cannabis and stuff like
that or I like I like rolling up an oil
snake with a dab and putting that and a
joint and it makes a nice really yes
smooth smooth burning joint I always
picture you with a joint myself
yeah what do you say there Kitty you got
a beautiful cat yeah it's a bangal it's
uh yeah part wild jungle
cat yeah you can kind of tell definitely
doesn't look like your average uh he'll
be over here at some point I'm sure
he'll come check us out when he's damn
when he feels damn good and ready so is
this some hash you made or uh this is
hash from a friend a local friend up
north of whist and it's some pretty
melty stuff you can see it's of a cush
variety with a tiny little bit of nebula
mixed in and it uh it presses up real
nice into a goopy sort of sticky melty
product and uh I'll give us an give us
each a nice little dab we could probably
just do a dunk don't even need a
Dabber see you know one of the things
when I interviewed Lawrence chernak uh
told me that when he was like
documenting has hashish making in the'
70s and stuff like that generally the
hash wasn't off of buds like the type of
buds we see it was more like almost
plants in vegetative state or very very
spindly Buds and the hash they're very
Rous though for some reason but they
weren't producing the big dense flowers
that uh that we traditionally associate
our hashes plants with here you know
right well I just took a hit out of the
mother ship and it was a dry hit it was
okay though I have to say like really
smooth didn't cough at all and I tasted
beautiful flavor on um on the
exhale but I'm going to go put a little
bit of water
go all right
so I got a nice lovely dry hit out of
that but I have since put some water in
it for
Chris I was surprised at how nice the um
pipe hit without water I have hit uh
that one without water and I've hit my
Taurus without water both mother shits
not sure if you're big on the mothership
scenario here but these are particular
pipes that are made by this company
Mothership and uh well they just really
hit if you smoke a lot of bongs you
really recognize it quickly as um an
incredible flavor sorry about that I put
your phone right on the hat no I'll put
my phone off so it doesn't rain too I
got a dunk for you here
cool grab that
guy and then we'll just get that in
there
really uh quite jealous of your smoking
Blazer that you've got on there that
thing looks pretty
legit I uh
1920s yeah for real I love the idea of
having a Legends of hash party
nice very
tasty I love the idea of having a
Legends of hash party and at the door
you get one of these like smoking
jackets you know with a little like
maybe some wipes in the pocket and some
whatever you require in the other
pocket hopefully some selection of
hashish in your pocket or something like
there we go even if it was just one
little you know your first dab you just
pull it out of your
pocket wow we're utopian dreamers there
we go it's been uh you've been involved
in cannabis for 25 plus years yeah yeah
yeah for sure in 19899 found out about
industrial hemp and Jack hair and all
that stuff and uh started kind of
promoting it from then on yeah that
would have been very similar to me I was
definitely into uh the smoking of it in
1989 by 991 I started to grow it and
become more of an activist and then got
into the whole hemp thing out out east
before I came out here and it was
definitely um it's been a good
foundation to have that sort of Jack
really brought more of us together than
we'll ever know yeah Jack yeah he's the
father of the move modern movement you
know what I mean it had well you know
I've been smoking herbs since I was 12
years old and grew up here in Vancouver
and I actually went to smokins at the
art gallery in the 70s um yeah I don't
know I can't remember too much about it
I just kind of can vaguely remember
being there and smoking weed that's
pretty a big crowd of people you know
and uh uh um so that but it kind of died
off and through the 80s and stuff like
that through the efforts of a of a
mother of some child all the head shops
got shut down and so all pipes bongs and
High Times grow magazines any literature
promoting legalization was completely
banned you know what I mean and so uh um
there was not really much of a scene
here in in in BC at all you know in 1990
when I started promoting it I didn't
know anybody else I think maybe Paul D
police out in Nelson the Holy Smokes
guys the Holy Smokes guys out in Nelson
uh um was doing a bit of promotion out
there but I had to you know kind of
search that out to even he definitely
they were for sure because we were
connected to them in Manitoba and how
that connection happened was one of
their uh good old time friends and
partners Alan middl Miss y he came to
Manitoba and moved there for a while
with his family and that's when he got
involved with the we were all involved
in the Manitoba hemp movement together
yeah and so of course when we went to
the cies for Manitoba who would we go
see we'd go see the Holy Smokes guys
we'd go see Dustin sunflower and yeah
those are those are good uh Good Times
indeed memory
of yeah I met Dana Larson as well you
know the other well-known BC activist
too he was like at SFU and he had a
group leag for ethical action and drugs
and I had this thing called patriotic
Canadians for hemp and I had like one
little piece of hemp paper you know
cardboard and a little swath of hemp
cloth and a bag of hemp seeds and i' go
to these universities and colleges and
I'd say okay this is hemp paper and we
can make all our paper out of hemp and
hemp seeds around and you know and uh
that was kind of how it you know really
got going you know so what year would
have been the hemp times that that
brother Leroy guy was always hand that
was like 92 3 4 okay 92 9394 cuz that's
when I started coming here was right
around 92 I guess and we hooked up with
them and we had you know it was like we
were we were able to get hemp paper in
large amounts and some hemp cloth that
we later found out was did not really
hemp cloth the tie sure the tie well I
had a business moment hemp seed treats
through the a lot of the that's how I
first and uh that was the first
commercial Venture of wholesaling hemp
seed Foods as far as I know and I sold
those all over North America through the
US even in other we bought them and sold
them at our hemp store and that was like
one of the things we were the most
stoked of we often had the mama Inda
hemp seed treats opened up broken into
pieces on on a table so people could try
them yeah then they didn't have the hemp
nut which really revolutionized uh the
hemp industry the hemp seed itself is is
kind of husky to eat and it's raw form
in the M indc treat it was kind of a
sesame seed snap type thing so it kind
of worked for it but it was it was
holding it back and then once they
figured a method of properly dehaul the
seed well that was whole industry blew
that was even more everything than you
can imagine because the seed that was
being used prior was actually sterilized
seed you you were unable to sell live
seed which one of their tricks and it
was hell you know like I was importing
all the seed I got from China and
sometimes the seed would show up and be
rancid and I'd be out my money or it
would get hel at Customs forever you
know you know I'm renting a bakery to
make my product that and I can't get it
or there was a lot of uh uh um road to
to to break through to kind of uh get
things going but now the hemp industry
you know it's it's a real money industry
and I'm sure it's already a
multi-million dollar industry here in
British col in Canada I mean you know
already absolutely and uh you know and
the hemp nuts great I throw like four
tablespoons in my morning smoothie every
day and it's a definitely a big part of
my diet and uh the healthier things that
I eat you know yeah as it should be you
know essential amino acids have that
word essential in front of it and I'm
sure one day we'll see that word get put
in front of phyto canabo they'll be
they'll be essential phyto for sure man
you know probably one day there'll be
juice and whole buds with seeds in it
you know and getting all the Cannabis
goodness out of all that now that's a
juing there you go yeah yeah juice your
oil from your seed and your phyto canabo
from the leaf and the bud simultaneously
damn yeah yeah well you know in 1990 I I
guess like where I differentiate from a
lot of other actives I pursued this uh
uh study of cannabis and its different
religious roles in all throughout
cultures and religions you know and uh
that happened I had this really powerful
religious experience in 1990 that left
me uh believing that cannabis was the
Tree of Life this you know holy tree of
life that had leaves for the healing of
the Nations and all manners of fruit and
stuff and I really felt that after this
experience that uh all these industrial
applications of cannabis were related to
this you know how we could get rid of
our prochemical uh uh um needs and all
fossil fuels and all that with hemp
fuels and hemp Plastics how we can feed
the world with a hemp seed I was on it
replacing soil depleting cotton with
hemp you know what I mean and so it's
always uh uh um uh um been kind of a
what I guess is my specialty in the
Cannabis scene over the last 25 years so
I spent 25 years research on the role of
cannabis in in history and religion
particularly its role in Magic and
religion and I have to say you know 25
years later uh that original religious
experience at a time when I had never
written anything um High School Dropout
I hadn't been particularly uh a pursuer
of intellectual type of things and when
I you know at that time I was a surfer
living out on the west coast to
Vancouver Island and incl and as much as
I'm a pot activist now I was a surfer
then my whole trip was like a gr grew a
bit of weed and uh had a job as a night
Watchman a few nights a week and it was
like chasing waves man and it was a a
really good time in Canada for Surf and
there was like maybe like a dozen
Surfers between ulet and toino and now
there's probably a dozen surf shots
between ulet and toino you know and so
it was like a pioneering time for cold
water surfing and a really great scene
you know uh um but yeah you know I'd say
that as fun as that was you know the the
the work I've had the opportunity to do
in regards to cannabis history's been
just as fulfilling for sure oh
absolutely well that's what a great
thing to get you all inspired for the
Cannabis historian
role chasing waves chasing waves man
it's a very Zen experience you know
surfing is like one of the most Zen
things out there you know and it's up
there when you're out on a a good day of
like say a place like Jordan River a
really good point break over on
Vancouver Island and you get like a
quarter mile ride on like a you know 6
to 8T wave uh um and uh uh that's right
up there with the hottest Sex You Ever
Had You know what I mean uh um it's like
a pretty you know and if you like you
know get slotted in a barrel or
something like that that's just like
this Timeless Timeless moment of
everything's kind of stand still and
you're in this perfect cylinder of water
you know it's just like uh uh um
something that sticks with you you know
beautiful sounds so good yeah man it
would be so good if we could experience
something like that today after a nice
session like this it would be like just
be surfing yeah absolutely man
well maybe make it happen yeah who knows
man maybe we'll make it happen so this
is the sublimator now um this is his
newer unit uh the V oh I always get the
name wrong it's pretty cool it dabs up
on top here and then herb inside it's a
vaporizer so if you want to hit it you
can haul ass on it right now yeah and
you can you can haul ass on it it's
different from most vaporizers in the
sense where you will uh I know you said
sometimes it's a little bit too much so
I'll just pull back you don't have to
pull like what you got there is what i'
call kind of King hit a real nice flavor
all the yeah plus it's a sweet skunk so
it's not really a head what's the
difference between the sublimator and
other VAP why is it hit so much harder
okay I can only use the word the
metaphorical words to to pass this on to
you but I will say that what he's doing
with this unit the way and this is the
key right here these two touching
because it's not about the wand it's
about the atomizer this piece here what
this does is it it creates an entire
space that is a particular temperature
and you put your Herb in and then you
pull it through this tiny little hole a
ventury right what it does is it
basically accesses magic I have no idea
how to say it any other way than that
but if you are a smoker and you just
test this thing against any other unit
no other
vaporizer it's hitting like this thing
then it's all about if you want the full
rip the half rip you know it depends
on how hard you pull and how long you
leave the um wand inside the atomizer
for definitely um love the idea of a
sublimator bar where you have dab
attendant taking care of the the the
unit for you and just serving you hits
cuz that's that's definitely where I'm
at with
it but The Taste and the smell of that
is absolutely Sublime nice little narrow
Leaf cultivar nice yeah what do you
think of the uh the new Theory the wide
leaf and the narrow Leaf drug cultivars
um I yeah I don't know man it it's like
I think it's still like sativa sativas
are thin leaf and indos are wide Leaf
you know and I'd say that uh you know
the indicas you know they they kind of
came out the where the du Kush kind of
meet up with the aan Chan mountains
there in China and you know I think that
uh the Marana that they found in central
China the really well preserved stuff I
think that's like it's still got the
sativa like leaves but then it's got
some indicia like qualities as well and
it's probably right when they're
starting to like hybridize it enough for
the indicas to produce or something like
that I wonder if we'll ever be able to
tell for sure regardless of anyone's
Theory through gening and through the
mapping of the actual genetic I don't
know you know like I like I I think that
things like acal gold and Colombian and
Mexican red hair I believe that those
are just you know European hemp
varieties that got brought over and got
adapted to the warmer climate and
started producing more resin and became
those types of plants you know what I
mean uh you know the whole idea that
hemp doesn't you know have to contain
any THC or these that's like a modern
hybridization these industrial Str with
a little bit of like resin and th it
works as a bug repellent and stuff like
that and grows healthier you seems to be
a pretty important component at least
for the plant that's followed us around
for the majority of our history yeah
yeah for sure it seems that uh THC seems
to be a pretty important you know I'm
I'm sure the earliest users they were
like probably just growing one big
cultivated crop and like a buffalo
utilizing everything off of the plant
the seeds and the stock and
the um you know that was like the
earliest uh but you know as a cultivated
crop Carl seon uh um believed that that
was likely Humanity's first cultivated
crop and and the word cannabis you know
the root word for cannabis Kaa that's
like Proto indoeuropean language and so
that's like the oldest type of words
that we can trace back so it's like
right at the very beginnings of language
and stuff like that as far as we can
trace it back there's references to to
cannabis you know what I mean um so it's
very very old and current archaeological
evidence for like say uh uh um
production of hemp fibers tools that are
used for uh breaking the fibers off the
stock of cannabis that were tools like
these were still in use just a few
hundred years ago uh um but they found
ones dating back to about 28,000 BC you
know what I mean and U I think uh it's
uh you know even older you know like
there's some some evidence of of stuff
even older you know so the
archaeological evidence is just as far
back as we can date it through that but
it could have been tens of thousands of
years before that you know and people
like Dr Jeffrey guy and John mcpartland
Dr Jeff guy's the head of GW
Pharmaceuticals they're speculating that
you know cannabis itself you know the
resids and the the drug effects of
cannabis may have facil played a
facilitory role in the very important
period known as the greatly forward when
we really start moving away from being
animals living in the jungle to more
civilized being and Tool making and uh
uh um all that type of stuff right so
that's somehow uh the Canabis High and
the novel way of thinking that it
produced facilitated that step forward
you know what I mean and then you know
you got to think about those just with
those dates you know the history of us
growing this plant beside where we live
you know and in our Villages and growing
in our human waste because night soil
you know before we weren't like pumping
all of our uh uh human waste out into uh
the oceans and uh uh polluting our Earth
you know there was a time where it was
like part of the cycle of life and that
we were like bear [ __ ] in the woods
going back into nature and we utilized
it into our own fields and our crops but
that energy of that going through us
that puts some of us back in that dirt
man and that's that's our relationship
with this planet you know is it's like
we have a a
co-evolutionary relationship with
cannabis and that's why we have this
really incredible endoc cannaboid system
that matches up with the cannaboids in
cannabis and other aspects of cannabis
as well like Gamlin leic acid which is
in the human mother's milk and uh along
with endocannabinoids uh uh but is you
know in just a couple of other rare seed
oils and stuff like that right you know
what I mean it's like we have this
inherent relationship connection with
this plant and that's why it's curing a
you know a lot of these diseases that
people are treating with cannabis
they're now being referred to as endoc
canab anoid deficiencies you know what I
mean and so that's like uh that's like
how how close we are with it maybe those
these are all starting to result from
our separation from this herb that's
been part of our our life on earth going
back thousands and thousands of years
you know and what a fascinating history
it is too man it's completely
fascinating and it's pretty heavy when
you get down to thinking about each one
of those components and how they line up
the co-evolutionary aspect of us with
cannabis you know the Dr Jeffrey guy's
theories of the Great Leap Forward being
sparked by
cannabis um it's no big secret that the
more we learn about cannabis and its its
role in our lives in our lives that you
can just see that a lot of this agenda
that seems to be behind making cannabis
illegal is
simultaneously creating different
industries that could only exist with
cannabis being illegal you know like
there's no need to replace um uh the
endocannabinoid
systems food if you will the phyto
canabo and the essential amino acids
there's no real need to replace those if
you let people have them in the first
place you know once you remove phyto
canabo from the person's diet then they
become deficient then they have all
these different problems and then they
give you pills which are signalers for
your cells to tell your cell oh you're
having a problem but it's there version
and it's never as good as it's never
natural it's never natural well because
natural is unpatentable you know they
want to be able to patent a specific use
and they I can't
believe have any of a deeper
understanding or at least a deep enough
understanding what's truly at work here
because I don't believe we even have an
understand well you know it's like by
prohibiting it they've made it also into
this super powerful force of cultural
change right you know and it's almost
like the classic you know Garden of Eden
myth and God says don't eat of that tree
of life or on that day you'll surely die
you know and then they eat of it their
eyes become open and they start to see
all the uh uh um uh crazy [ __ ] uh um
going on out there you know yeah no it's
pretty heavy indeed it's uh well we're
both proponents of cannabis as you guys
can see and after a nice cannabis
session and a tea and sitting around and
discussing uh cannabis and the history
of
cannabis I like to unwind and go for a
longboard absolutely man let's do that
yeah uh um let's Skate okay all
right boosted hey
electrified so you got your little
remote control remote control
Bluetooth
here chargeable little remote control
rechargeable board gets about a 7 m
radius with about 22 M hour four
different settings from beginner to
expert you know and uh great brakes and
that's your remote that's the remote
there just pull on here UPS
forward this ways
reversed crazy dude well show us let's
roll take it
off there'll be something that area d
yeah yeah
exactly I'll give you a warning of
anything on sounds
good electric skateboards for the wind
[Music]
all right yeah the these are super cool
man really loving this
thing see I can see L one of
these this is super cool right now we're
charging the battery yeah that's how you
charge the batteries they just bring
that brake down a
bit super easy to control guys backwards
and I'm breaking down a steep
hill if I even just take the Brak off a
little bit we will go
cranky well I got to say this is pretty
cool Chris
yeah we head all the way down Ontario
yeah wall and then seaw wall the way
along the seaw wall yeah come
on this is
great okay bike LS in
Vancouver look I'm getting up next to
you all right but I'll let you lead the
way damn fine way to get around the city
I'll sure say that I'm probably going
about about 20 25 clicks right now
apparently maximum this thing goes is
about 22
mph which is definitely like over 30 km
an hour it's pretty
cool yeah buddy that guy was laughing
how could you not laugh I would laugh
myself so that's cool you stop at every
stop sign just like any vehicle would
rolls yeah then you roll through with
cars or you just go through your own sp
oh yeah this is real
nice real
[Music]
nice we're
good that was really nice heading down
that one no brakes needed there a
well I got to say this is pretty damn
cool these skateboards are definitely a
keeper Matt was smart to grab
one are you kidding me right now bro
these are
awesome people are smiling I'll tell you
when they see these things are always
asking where'd you get that what is it
you know [ __ ] I get asked all the
time I think there's like a total
business in vancou for these things man
so kill you get to rip this
back
wow here we go guys seaw wall of
Vancouver favorite right
here hell yeah it is woo
electric skateboard for the wind
following Chris Bennett through the city
of Vancouver I likes it I likes it a
lot this thing is too cool
[Music]
definitely unbelievable way
to got it got it good call so Chris just
showed us the water and uh the Water
means we pick up our boards it's not
worth the trouble keep your feet out of
them and boom
back on the
horse BC Stadium right up in front of us
here little tour of Vancouver
I'm following your
lead this is definitely new to me not
the kind of skape oh it's wonderful
feels really good
carve
away yeah it's pretty cool man
man it's fun it's really really
fun nice layback
Chris after this brick I'll film you if
you want oh yeah no worries
come
[Music]
so this is my morning to you are you
kidding me this is so good
Chris you're living a good life
bud we're going to walk past this eh
easy enough to pick up stay out of the
water okay cool yeah yeah for sure okay
cool
big bump coming
up so this is bubble man on his very
first day on this thing which he's
really
rocking anybody that surfed or skated or
snowboarded
they're awesome on these things you know
they just pick it up right away I hadn't
even skated or surfed in like 15
[Music]
years straight through straight through
oh want to make sure there's no
water budy
[Music]
very cool man very cool
holding my own doing
well loving this [ __ ]
Bro Electric
[Music]
some of those bumps really throw you for
a little
spin I love your commute bro
yeah I mean you got a good commute right
there we going left yeah we're going
left
[Music]
dude people would be renting the [ __ ]
out of these things are you kidding
me well you'd ensure it by getting them
to sign a waiver saying that you're not
insuring it and that they have to pay a
deposit how much is the board
worth
L9 sing
oh these are great
dude this
guy what a character
Electric
people really trip out on these things
I'll tell you that much rubber necking
and
everything much easier than a bike all
you do is stand on
it and use this little controller to
just forward motion can't believe how
great this thing is
Chris is getting going good
now shredding up hills now still going
probably a solid
20K which is 5K faster than we're
supposed to be
going I'll have you
know coming up to English Bay
[Music]
dude this is
killer it just keeps getting better yeah
like you're killing me bro this is so
good this is ridiculous yeah I just
think it's great yeah for sure you
should get one man obviously everyone
should and now we're going into Stanley
Park or what's this back into oh killer
and then we'll go recharge dude I could
do this all day long bro then we'll have
that full ride back very
cool yeah buddy get it get at it
you Bo
dud that was so [ __ ] awesome Chris
found it out dude coming to work
amazing you know so we are in the new
cannabis
culture spot
all right and this is Chris's shop the
urban Shaman location number
two looks good bro Clark Clark how's it
going man bubble man you're on Bubble
man's world are you on a longboard do
you ride a longboard no no I don't
unbelievably fun I cannot believe how
[ __ ] awesome that was ripping through
the city seaw wall every single person
looking at Chris one time after another
rubber chicken in their necks to look
back and be like what the [ __ ] was that
it makes the smallest amount of noise
but it carves uphills I'm very impressed
Chris you got me sold yeah are awesome
hell yeah
[Music]