[Music]
Hey guys, welcome to Bubble Man's World.
I am back on the electric skateboard
following the great gardener and Mr.
Chris Bennett and we're out for another
adventure. This is the third adventure.
Our first time out with Matt and uh
yeah, we're going to take you guys for a
little cruise along the seaw wall. Maybe
some dabs of some GG1 and some LHO
later. And uh yeah, keep you posted for
the
fun. Didn't see that coming. Eh, almost
went off the
[Music]
edge. I love this thing. This thing's
awesome. It's ridiculous, dude. Chris
has got the styles.
Yeah, it's really flexible. Chris was
telling me that it's like a snowboard.
He hit a bump and it almost Did it shoot
you off or almost? I did. It was I did
this afternoon. I hit a speed bump and I
landed and it sprung down so much that
it actually flung me off the board. It
was like a new sensation in
skateboarding along with that one right
there. Oh, that's another one. Isn't it
weird? Holy [ __ ] dude. You really got
to plant that back foot when you give a
guess. I could I'm taking this thing to
like Spain and stuff. Oh, yeah. Oh, it's
going to be ridiculous. You got to have
a crew though. That's the key. That's my
DNA skate army. Yep. DNA skate team. I
told D nail about them and how they need
to put a whip hole in the battery.
Now, let's stick to life's course now
and don't stray away
now to days that come. Yes. And seasons
pass. Man and man give thanks. I sing.
Hey to be here on this journey that I
and I are
on. I want you to stop the way your
living can change your
ways. Let's start
over. There's so much so much to be
done.
I'll stick to the course
now. Won't stray away
now. Stick to the course
now. And don't stray away
now. So on your mark, get set, and get
ready
now. Starting from
ABC. Come on, let's make it
rain. Starting from 1 2 3.
Mathematics it no
lie your children
[Music]
I now the voice of fruit remains the
same today
today as
yesterday it never
changed never changed
[Music]
As the message in the
word you've never
heard, it remains the same unless time
change.
Harsh reality of life come home to
you. You're not hearing the message in
the words.
Now you see the rest of my words coming
to
pass. Stick to the course
now. Don't stray away
now. Stick to the course
now. So on your mark, get set, and get
ready
now. Starting from
ABC. Come on, let's make it
right. You're starting from 1 2
3. Mathematics, it don't
lie. So judge your sons and daughters.
Let's
unite. Play your part and don't let them
sell you a six for a
nine. And don't let them sell you no
nine for a six.
You see them
so so
blame that they will force it off on
you. You
you they will give you water to carry in
a basket. Oh.
So on your mark, get set and get ready.
Now we're starting from
ABC. Come on, let's make it
right. Starting from one, two,
three. Mathematics, it don't
lie. Stick to the course
now and don't stray away
now. Come on, play our part now. Let's
play our parts now.
Don't stray away
now. Stick to the course
now. Children I night
now. Follow the truth now.
[Applause]
That's so sweet, dude.
[Music]
Is this like sesh spot number one? Yeah.
What's that? Oh, we still got a fair bit
of juice, though.
Sesh spot number one.
I'm always down for that. Turn it on.
Sesh spot. Good spot. What's up? I said
is that a good spot?
For whatever, dude. For
[Music]
anything. All right, got that shut down.
What do
you tiny things you threw in
here? Yes, we threw a few tiny things in
there. Some big effing
boats. That was a real nice little ride.
Yeah. Every time I feel like I get a
little better. Sure. I'm sure you are.
It's playing with the bounce. Yeah.
Getting used to the bounce. There'll be
some cool things you can do in the half
bounce. Have you seen any of these guys
where they're like walking the
longboards and they're like they're like
turning like this and then stepping on
this foot, turning right and then
stepping and then I've been trying that
but every time it's just like Oh, this
stuff. Yeah. Yeah. And then you kind of
like the board's turning too. It's not
just like going in a straight line.
Exactly. When you do this it puts the
board over there. You really got to I
try, but then it's like I'm going to
break my ankles. It's good to try that
stuff without the uh motor.
Yeah. Well, that was about 7 minutes of
non-stop break for sure. Yeah. In case
you ever run out of juice. Absolutely.
Well, I'm down for having a quick little
dab, I suppose.
I suppose. I suppose. One up in you. The
classic one uppery. I'm gonna give away
a h 100,000. It's like a sweet. That's
how much? That's just gonna be sweet for
the grower.
That would be sweet for the grower. What
grower doesn't want? So, I don't have a
dabber, but I do have a Dodge key that I
put my dab onto. Oh, there you go. So,
I'll just
uh go with that, I
suppose. A little spot here. Oh, is this
like a regular uh pup spot of Chris
Bennett? H well my mom used to live
right around here so I've been down here
quite a bit but I guess it's like a
regular puff spot but I've cruise down
here on the board before I like
stretches with the nice curves and
stuff. Oh it was nice. I'm looking
forward getting a little bit further and
then I guess we'll have to turn
around charge a little back hill so that
should be pretty accurate. So much fun
dude. Oh, just like practical now. I
come over to Vancouver on the float
plane. You must love it. And I got that
thing. I'm getting like I don't use any
taxis. I got out of using taxis. I
started sort of using the whole day and
sort of walking around Vancouver and
really no really get to know. Now I got
the board and it's like sort of cruise
around around the block. I get to work
in the morning. I'm like totally pumped
because I've been carving all the
[ __ ] way off the sea wall to work and
by the time I get there I'm just like
and then zooming by guys on bicycles. I
pulled up to a stop sign today and I and
I and I hit the brake too much so the
board went backwards and it flew me off
like two steps and and the guy's like,
"That board's as big as a snowboard."
And I'm like, "Yeah, yeah." I go, "It's
really bouncy, too." And the light turns
green and I'm like, "And it's electric."
And I just took off and all I hear the
guy was like, "That's [ __ ] awesome,
man. Holy [ __ ] That's [ __ ] cool."
Yeah. Yeah. No, for sure. I get that
from all the time. There's so many
different ones, too. like it's uh you've
done it good by having like two or three
different ones to sort of kind of now
you can kind of see what's out there and
uh
yeah. Well, I'm looking forward to
trying one of those motor wheels. Yeah,
that's kind of the the next one I'm
looking forward to as well. There's a
couple that I saw that had uh just no no
big batteries and stuff. The motors were
much smaller, interchangeable inside.
That's another key. Even if these ones,
which are pretty big batteries, I I
would probably put up with two or three
of them in my backpack and and roll
around the city, if I could just, you
know, quick change them for for a city
dweller. For sure. Yeah, absolutely. I
wonder if any of these portable
vaporizer batteries have anything to add
to these, like how powerful they are.
Dail D nail should build the talk to
them today about it. Electric skate dail
with an attachable sort of dail on the
side. No, we literally talked to them
about it. Uh, well, I've talked to them
a little bit about it in the last week,
but today I'll buy one. That's what I'm
saying. I want I want on the list with a
hemp fiber deck. Hemp fiber deck. I
don't know if they got the hemp urethane
yet. There, dude. Definitely doable.
Game changers. What about the Aquabus?
What about like some like crazy hemp
battery out nowadays, too? There. I saw
some things about these hemp batteries
that they're making. I think they're
bigger type of uh a bigger type of
battery, though. That's cool. Should be
uh something that should be available
for sure. Carefully you don't step in
the bag of [ __ ] At least they put you
bag your [ __ ] up and then you leave the
bag.
That kind of defeats the purpose of
double or you got pollution on your
pollution. Exact. If you're going to
leave it in a bag, then you're supposed
to put it on someone's doorstep and set
it on fire. So when they come to the
door and they stomp it out, you get [ __ ]
all over their feet. That's like the old
school like that's how you know that's
what a a hooligan was in the 70s. Nicki
Nikki Nine Dorse. Yep, there it is.
Nicki Knight. Knockk Knockock Ginger or
what was another name for that? I don't
know. We used to call people up and give
them boulder dash questions over the
phone. They were ahead of them. They'd
be like, I like it, man. It is a
beautiful day in Vancouver. And uh I
hope that you guys can come to Vancouver
one day and pick up a skateboard like
this, even for a rental. Maybe um
someone like Mark or, you know, someone
in the industry will will do 420 tours
of these skateboards because I'm telling
you, man, a quick little electric rip,
you know, a little uh restaurant action
or a vapor lounge, another rip. That's a
good idea. No, it's a great idea.
Certainly wouldn't go good with a bar
cruise, that's for sure. No, that's
that's what I difference between pot and
booze. You know what I mean? you go to
any like surf break, any snowboard hill,
you're going to find the hardcores are
all puffing down really heavy before
they go on the run or the ride and uh
it's good for these types of board
sports where you kind of like focus in
on on the ride and it just everything
else just kind of gets gets away from
you except it's the scene that's pouring
through your face as you cruise through.
It's the groove, man. Y the big fatty
and go on a ride on the groove.
Absolutely. It's uh I mean it was great
even before the Big Fatty, but it's
obviously going to be that much more
enjoyable after the the Big Fatty. It
reminds me of uh who was it? John
Stewart in the movie Halfbaked. You ever
gone longboarding on weed?
No,
no. Today you have You're on camera like
about to do it. Longboarding on weed.
Oh, the rights, dude. I don't think I
have gone long boarding not on weed.
That's what I'm saying. You know, like
it's like I do everything I do is on
weed. So, you know, I might wake waking
up I I don't often wake up on weed, but
not long after waking up I am on.
Sometimes I do wake up. I wake up, I
smoke weed, I go back to sleep.
Sometimes wake up and got the joint in
your hand. It's in your mouth already
lit and everything like, whoa, that's
weird. How long have I been asleep?
Oh, yeah. Nice to see the boats out in
the water. Oh, it's killer, man. right
out on the water. Yeah, it's got to be
like 25 plus degrees right now. My uh
brother-in-law, he's got this boat. He
throws off a big wave that you can surf.
It's not the water
ski a wake surf. My uh my boat does that
as well. Have you been doing it? Uh
yeah, we do it. Yeah, it's quite fun.
You do it mostly in the lake. It's
easier. I was I was going to say that
way. Well, you got to go behind Gambir
or you got to go like where it's classy,
but it's only certain times that it's
like that. So, no, not very often. More
ocean. It's wake boarding and wake
skating. I love wake skating. Wake
skating is just a board you stand on and
get pulled behind the boat. It's
unbelievably fun once you start learning
how to do
[ __ ] and stuff. It's like, man, it's
freaky. That's a ridiculous
boat from the San Island. That's kind of
got I sell cocaine written all over it.
track runner from towns over Washington
State. Big bulky two big bulky guys
riding their cigarette through town.
[Applause]
Yeah, I like Joe Rogan.
Ever since Joe Rogan's been around, I
always have uh hustle dudes coming into
my shop. Why? I'm the most hostile.
Yeah, he turned people on. You know
what? You can almost thank Todd
McCormack for that cuz Todd McCormack
turned Joe Rogan on to DMT. Huh. And
then Joe has like a big long the one
where he gives Todd all the credit like
man my friend Todd had this [ __ ] and oh
my god it's really if you follow Joe and
you see where Joe went deep like where
he was like became a much deeper person
it was after that DMT trip and Todd's
got Todd's got John Lily's uh
deprivation tank at his place as well.
Todd's no joke. So pretty serious
hashurch attendee. Of course, we're
talking about Todd McCormack, good
friend of ours here at Bubble Man's
World. I think I'm ready to get back on
the board. Let's do this [ __ ]
The red light starts flashing.
They say there will be
salvation. I said there won't be
[Music]
children cuz there will be no salvation
here on earth until the
poor cries are heard heard.
So come now my brothers
all rally to the
call for
one unit.
[Music]
One word.
A rich man cries are
heard. My cries are heard. Then why then
why why can't the poor pay now for the
poor? They've been crying out for these
many thousand years. Live vibrations are
traveling throughout this world. Oh
yeah.
So come now
brothers and rally to the
call for
one unit of the world. One word for you
and I crying out for unity. That's what
God
said. That's what Mar says.
[Music]
And now those of you
who read the books of prophecy, that's
what the prophet said. Hey, that's what
they all say.
[Music]
And better going to come
now. But it's only going to come.
Starting with you and you and you and
you. Yes. better going to come now. Yes,
better has got to come. But it's only
going to come starting with you and you
and you and
you. Oh
yeah.
[Music]
Now I
Yeah, it doing it
well. And I know what what what what you
going to do now with a judgment so near
that hand. What what you going to do?
Tell me now what you going to do? Hey.
Hey. You see the blood blood of the poor
my heart and souls it's crying out. Oh
yes it's crying
out pretty soon every lightning and
thunder earthquake world wind and fire
be crashing in
kissing on you. You, you, you, you, you,
you. The wicked ones, the unjust ones,
all those who use people's rights. Oh,
yes. For their own
gain. What? What going to do now? With a
judgment so near at hand. What? What you
going to do? Tell me now what you going
to do.
She's a
[Music]
blood.
Hey. Whoa.
[Music]
The rapid change is happening
everywhere.
Everywhere. Rapid changing happening all
over the world every
day. Some people feel secure
in where they're
living. Those people didn't know.
For there yesterday they were living in
peace in
peace. But now
today bombs and
missiles are falling on their face.
Their face.
All the people
[Applause]
get get get
this first and scattered
astray. They lose their own land and
they become refugees.
[Music]
Don't let Babylon school
you. School you no school
you. Don't follow their
instructions spoken
from them crooked tongue. Yeah, them
fork tongues.
But I'm only want to fool
[Music]
you. And then you know damn I'll go use
you you use
you. So all you people you are
seeing see that there's no light in them
ahead.
[Music]
No. Whoa. So turn
around. Turn around. I say find better
ground cuz you are seeking for
better have no
[Music]
But no, I'm no light in the tunnel
ahead. No, there's only
darkness
ahead for you and you and you and you.
Yes. For them. No hand.
Oh,
[Music]
here. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Woah woah woah woah woah
woah. You see me here, you see me there.
You see me almost
everywhere. I'm a
r dread man. You can't stop me now. Got
children on a high. Oh yes. And we can't
be stopped now. In between now and here
and there, we walk the
street. You can't stop me now. Got me
now. You can't stop me. No. No. You
can't stop me. No. No. You can't stop me
now. You see me
everywhere here and there. You can't
stop us now.
Rest the children on the move. The
children on
[Music]
our you can't stop us. I say we walk. We
walk. Yes, we walk the straight and
[Music]
narrow. You
can't stop us.
We are here to stay. We are here. We are
here. We are here. We are here and are
here to stay. And there's nothing you
can do. No, nothing you can do. Cuz you
can't stop us now. We want the rights.
We want the
rights. Children
are the rights. We want the rights here.
Children and there's nothing you can
do. No, nothing you can
do. The toughs that you
set they can't catch. I know here and
there. I'm everywhere.
[Music]
on the rise here and there
every
[Music]
now right
In we're almost everywhere.
[Music]
[Applause]
Boom. Man,
I don't know what my shit's saying. I
don't even have anybody. Should I turn
it off and then turn it on again? Okay.
Then it'll show you what you got. And we
got We want to head back. We're on the
last leg. Yeah, I'm on the left. Yeah,
I've got two dots. I got one dot. You
got a little more juice, but not a
little more than us. All right. Well,
that was hell of fun, guys.
I guess uh that was a great rip, man.
That was wicked fun. I'm uh Oh, that's
fantastic.
I might uh It's my new It's my new
Vancouver commute, that's for sure. Seaw
walls connect a lot. You know what I
mean? If you got to go places and if you
go um bike routes Vancouver, there's a
PDF that comes up that has all the best
bike routes. There's some that go like
along the roads, but they're separate
from the road. So it's they're nice and
wide in the greenways that you can
really whip through the city of Ardut.
Can't wait to see how big our team gets.
I think it'll be big. Oh, I'm sure that
I'm sure the as soon as I get the the
two boards other two boards going,
Cookie and somebody else will be out.
That's good for I'm stoked on it for
sure. Got me sold. We'll see you guys
next time. We got a little bit more.
We're going to make it back.
The braking.
Oh, the braking is amazing, dude. It
teaches you how to ride a skateboard
differently than you ever would have in
the past.
Which way are we
going? Straight.
Back at the fun truck and right on the
bottom blinking. That means that you
used most of your juice up on the
bottom. They just wink. That means that
you're just about out of Am I out of
fuel? Uh, yeah, yours. That's the
signal. It's this one here. That is like
means you're just going to run. So, I
can go around the block a couple more
times. I'll be right back, guys.
That was awesome. I didn't think I was
going to film anymore, but uh that was
part one with Matt. Matt's going to fly
away. Got to go back home. He's taking a
plane now. Chris and I are going to
charge up Vape Lounge and Seymour Park
Trailways. Hit the Seymour Park
Trailways. Looking forward to that.
[Music]