[Music]
for some of the artifacts and stuff
after too.
Okay.
Hey guys, welcome to Bubble Man's World.
Bubble Man's World currently over at
Chris Bennett. Thanks for having me
over, dude. Hey, always a pleasure,
brother. One of our regular Hashurch
panelists who was uh lucky enough to or
we were lucky enough to have you come
back yesterday and share a little bit of
your historical information on cannabis
and all things cannabis related. Today,
we're just uh kind of thinking we're
going to have a little bit more of a
conversation on uh the knowledge that
Chris knows. And I thought while we were
doing it, we would puff some bowls. So,
I brought a little uh D420K dry sift and
a little West Coast concentrate bubble
hash and a little Heavenly Days flour
rosin. So, that's kind of a nice little
I feel like these three guys right here
are sort of doing it the solventless
quiver as high a quality as it can be
done right now. So, did you press this
yourself or No, no, he they pressed it
up for me and and brought it as uh
pressed flower rosin. So, Oh, cool. Very
nice. Rockstar. I know a cultivar that
Remo is uh quite fond of. How how much
weed would it take to get a press like
that? You know, it's it's it's a
difficult sort of to know, but I'd say
anywhere between 8 and maybe 22%, eight
being pretty low, 22 being pretty high.
It's the internet, so there's always
going to be someone saying, "Well, I get
30%." I get Well, okay, but there might
be a moisture content.
But it's pretty simple to literally take
a hair straightener and squeeze a bud
that's a g
weigh and you'll get a real quick idea.
I think it's an amazing way for
dispensaries to test cannabis that comes
through their doors to find out what
kind of canabonoid and tarpine profile
they have on it. Not necessarily like a
readout on a GLC or an HLC, but pretty
pretty obvious when you squeeze a bud
and you get a big shot of of resin. Hey,
look at that. That's so awesome. What's
your cat's name again? Shankar. Shankar.
Boom. Shankar. Boom. Shank. Dude, I'm
doing it right now. That is so awesome
that Shankar went and said hi to the
camera. All right. I wish I remembered
one of my uh full
boom boom mahadev. Boom shankar. Boom.
Haranja. Harihanja. The one that I
learned years ago was like boom shankar.
Alohaka balanth. Yeah. Ombalanth is
definitely one. That's like one that the
crazier they can get pretty loud. We're
talking about of course Babas in India
lighting chillums and some of them are
quite the character and you'll see them
really say out uh like a prayer or a
what would you call it? A puja or a Oh,
like a little prayer. Yeah, it's a
prayer. It's a positive vibration put
out to the universe right before we
light up the chillum. So, uh I'll show
you some antique chillums too later.
Beautiful antique chillums here. You
know, I loved my trip to India. It was
definitely a never to be forgotten
experience, but uh I think Nepal is soon
to be on the You should go to Nepal with
me. Yeah. Yeah, for sure. We got Mark
Ros. They're probably getting ready to
relegalize the whole hash thing there. I
bet. And I'm watching the West pretty
seriously. When I started the hash bag
company, bubble bags, and Mark was
manufacturing for me. You could go to
Nepal during Shiva Ratchery, and the
king still released the ornament log
that they that they came out of the
king's chambers, and the ornament log
was full of puja and flowers and
incense. and charis. And it was free
Charus for the Babas. Google that. How
far back does that one go? Yeah. Yeah. A
long time ago. Incredible.
Well, you know, the smoking though of it
and chills and pipes that it's thought
to not come until after the discovery of
the new world and tobacco smoking and
they would eat the hash, they would burn
it in temples and they would drink bong,
right? But uh or you know other
dectibles as well other preparations of
food but the smoking and chillums and
stuff like that this general view is is
that that came with tobacco smoking and
then it really took off with weed
smoking you know. Well I'll tell you I
definitely didn't meet too many babas in
India that were smoking pure chillums.
Yeah. They were all mixing with tobacco.
Yeah. Yeah. And unfortunately for me,
not the kind of tobacco that I would
have preferred like the Jamaicans when
they mix with tobacco. It's very much
Jamaican tobacco that they grow in the
bush. In India, for some reason, it's
cigarettes. Yeah. And so it's strange
because you think cigarettes cost money.
It's an added amount. And Bubbas, for
the most part, you know, at least the
ones that I was hanging out with weren't
really what I would call like monetarily
well off. Yeah. They don't own a lot of
things. I mean, some do. You can see
babas with fancy watches and and cars
and the whole nine yards. It's India so
they have every aspect of availability
that you could possibly imagine. But
most of the Babas that I met were very
much you know humble like a holy man you
know like a guy that's walking
everywhere he goes. They don't often I I
the few babas that I actually made
friends with didn't go in vehicles. They
wouldn't go in in electric vehicles and
planes or anything like that. They were
walking everywhere they went. And you
talk to these guys and they're telling
you about their trips to Nepal and
they're talking about Tibet and they're
talking about the south of India. That's
a phenomenal amount of traveling on your
feet to really wrap your mind around,
you know. Absolutely. And of course, the
thing that blew me away, it's not like
they're taking roads and stuff. They're
like these babas from Nepal come down
for like a one of these events, a big
holy event like a
kumba and you can see dudes literally
with purple legs that have been coming
out of the mountains walking in the snow
for days, right? Wearing just a loin
cloth and you're like, "Okay, that seems
like a medical emergency." Yeah. But it
it doesn't become a medical emergency.
They just they just go on with their 6
to 8 months later, their legs turn back
to the normal color. I was just like,
"Holy shit." Yeah. And some of those
trails are old, man. Like they're like,
you know, people have been walking that
same trail for thousands of years. Thank
you. When you say old, you really need
to define that it is many thousands of
years. Their history goes back far. And
that's you feel that vibe when you're in
India sitting on the Ganes on the banks
and you're hanging out with these holy
men and you're smoking chillums of
charis that was grown in these same
mountains. And for me, you know, like I
don't personally follow any of their
religious beliefs, but I was intrigued
by them and uh honored to learn about
them by being immersed in them. Yeah.
Right. You know, cuz people always ask
me, "Oh, are you a Rasta? Are you I'm
like, I don't know what my religious
belief system is. I'm certainly not an
atheist. I guess I believe in energy."
Yeah. You know, that's usually what I
say. I believe in energy. Energy comes
and goes. Well, I've studied a lot about
religion. I really like the whole Sheba
thing. you know, there's like so much
cool stuff about it and absolutely uh
some of the texts are really great and
uh well, would you not say that a lot of
um some of maybe not a lot of the
Rastaparian belief system comes from
that vein? Yeah. Yeah, definitely. You
know, it would seem from what what we
know that uh Rastaparianism is like a a
symbiosis of Bible-fed uh Christian
slaves coming into contact with Indian
migrant workers. And thus you have the
chalice chillum and kellyweed and the
dreadlocks like the sadus wear. Even
even the flat Jamaican patty I swear to
God is a flattened samosa you know like
it's like a samosa that they just
flattened out and made into patties. I I
definitely feel that as well. The dreads
for sure all of the the dreads that I
met in Jamaica who always turns like
ganja you know it's definitely Indian
term. Well, for sure. Uh the the longest
dreadlocks that you will see in Jamaica
generally will be on uh a [ __ ] as they
call them, but it's basically a African
Indian uh mix, right?
Very cool. Yeah, my buddy Indian, he's
he was he is a [ __ ] as well. Great
guy. Uh has dreads that are
14 or 15 feet long now. It's got to be
hard on your neck, I'll tell you. He's
only got three or four of them, but wow,
it's amazing that hair could grow that
long. Yeah, I know. For sure. Here's a
dab for you, my friend. Okay, it's all
ready to go. Or Yeah, just slide it into
the into the You want me to actually do
it? Yeah, sure. Yeah, get good there.
There you go. Bubble it up. You're
bubbling? Yep. Yeah, the Taurus is such
a nice smooth
pipe. Boom. Been puffing bowls with this
guy for at least 20
years. At least 20 years. There you go.
Not too shabby. Yeah, definitely. Little
bit of flour. The intake, right? Two I
always say two thumbs up for two tears
down. There you go. If you can get a
tear in each eye from your rip, then you
have done almost everything right.
Well, what uh what say we show them some
fun uh art artifacts? Yeah, for sure.
Well, you know, yesterday we were
talking about the Cythians and uh
so the Cythians basically did the burn
it in a bowl type of thing. Is that was
Yeah, they would have like brazers that
um they would fill with hot rocks,
right? And uh yeah, Ben has an
incredible one at his museum right at
the front door. Oh, wow. In Barcelona
here. Just give me a second. This is
stuck in there. Oh, no problem. Take
your time. Kind of fun to check out. The
uh Chris's place is uh well ripe with uh
artifacts. And so this is like a cy a
diarama of some cythians there. And you
can see the guy's got like the horn cup
in his hand. Oh yeah. And uh um this is
how they looked like. They had full body
tattoos. Very interesting race. The men
fought uh in battles alongside the
women. Uh I mean the women fought
alongside the men. uh they had a a
transvestite priesthood. Um so they were
a pretty interesting ancient culture.
They were and uh um what's the timeline
for the cyians? Oh, you know Cythians a
blanket term for all these indo-uropean
tribes. Uh um so it's kind of this tribe
but this you know it's like 2700 years
ago uh 2500 years ago. Herodotus around
500 BC wrote about the Cythianerary
ritual where they would uh take the
heated rocks in a brazer and put it in a
tent and then throw cannabis and then
howl with pleasure, you know. Um and
then that was later found um to be uh
correct through archaeological finds by
uh Sergio Rudenko in Russia and uh um
they found the brazers and the tents
that were doing it. And then more
recently
um there was this find of uh gold cups
and bowls that were used for drinking
cannabis because they were also uh
drinkers of cannabis, right? Um and this
was mistakenly reported as bongs in the
mainstream media. One one paper got it
wrong, one big paper and then everybody
else uh uh got the same mistake wrong.
But the archaeologists involved uh say
that that that was actually used for
drinking hyoma which follows in line
with my last book cannabis and soma
solution where I was shown these
indo-uropean tribes were drinking
cannabis and a soma preparation not the
ammonita mascaria has been been widely
suggested right um you know cannabis and
other things and there's been other
archaeological finds like uh uh Victor
Seranadi's find in the bacteria margana
archaeological complex of temple sites
where they recovered uh uh residues of
cannabis, poppy, and ephedra, and
fossilized impressions of cannabis seeds
at sites where they were making the
sacred beverage. Uh um and that even
this even fits in with that amazing find
in China of 2,700 year old perfectly
preserved cannabis indica. Uh um and uh
this is female cannabis that was grown
for its psychoactive properties, which I
considered a spiritual thing. And it was
fun found with the mummified remains of
a Caucasian man in China. Uh um and this
is the Guushi culture that was living in
uh China from about 2,000 BC to about
400 BC. And uh they were known to be in
trade with this uh temple that I was
talking about in Bactria Margiana
because they found items at both sites
that came from either site. And um as
well the cythians that were found with
the gold cups and bowls with the same
preparation, same ingredients that they
found uh in this bacterium margar
complex uh opium and cannabis mixed
together uh um were known as the Helma
var gatherers and they would uh transfer
the weed growing up in this region in
China, you know, back into the Bactria
Margiana archaeological complex. Can you
imagine the level of knowledge that the
Vatican probably has about all of these
sacraments because it was of course
their mission to replace all of those
sacraments. Yeah. Well, the dark ages,
you know, is like, you know, really the
whole period and the rise of Catholicism
is was basically through the suppression
of pagan and gnostic cults that use
cannabis and other anthogens. Any
plant-based medicine, they were
replacing with the the blood of Christ.
Blood of Christ. Yeah. The wine and
stuff. Although, you know, it's
interesting like uh um there's this
common belief that in 1484, one of the
popes uh decreed cannabis a devil's
sacrament. And uh Tom Hats is a friend
of mine who speaks Latin and wrote a
great book about witches ointments. He
went back and looked at the Latin
documents. Makes no reference to
cannabis at all. Uh um there are some
other papal bulls where they're you know
against elixirs and potions associated
with witchcraft and cannabis may have
fallen into that category but cannabis
isn't specifically mentioned. And
there's even a 12th century pope that
wrote about cannabis wine and prescribed
cannabis for a number of medical
ailments in some treaties although this
pope was later accused of witchcraft uh
um after he died you know. So uh um it's
it's an interesting relationship.
There's also this like uh I'm writing
this book right now about uh cannabis in
the occult. It's called cannabis arcanum
liver 420. And one of the interesting
things I found out is there's this whole
in the 10th century in England there was
this holy uh oil comes with all these
prayers and stuff like that and cannabis
was one of the ingredients in that and
uh um a a 12th century magical text uh
sephar raziel which uh uh came from uh
originally from Jewish sources but was
very popular in in the medieval period
in in Europe. It has a uh recipe for a
cannabis ointment that's used for
scrying in a mirror. And so they would
rub this cannabis based ointment with
other herbal ingredients and then they
would look into a darkened mirror until
they saw a vision. Kind of like looking
in a crystal ball. And it's interesting
because right up until uh uh the 19th
century there's these guys like Lewis
Halons and uh Dr. Pascal Beverly
Randolph and other cultists that were
using cannabis in exactly the same way
as this 12th century reference to this
cannabis ointment in in in the sephur
raziel. And so there's like 8 800 years
of continued use of this magical recipe
of cannabis that we know of that we know
of. And then if you consider that the
ancient references to cannibosum, which
a lot of people have probably heard
about, were in fact Hebrew references to
cannabis. Then Moses becomes like a
shaman who ingests a psychoactive
substance, cannabis in this pray, burns
it on the altar as an oil, you know, and
then he speaks to the Lord in the pillar
of smoke uh over the altar. So this is
an act of catnomy, which means to uh uh
um see visions and smoke. And cannabis
was also used as that. They would burn
lots of cannabis along with frankincense
and myrrh and other substances and
create this smoky atmosphere that was
both psychoactive, but the smoke itself
was the physical element that the demons
and stuff would take form in like where
they'd be able to take shape in where
you'd be able to see them. May have been
just the effects of uh the psychoactive
properties mixed with the visuals of
candles. It fits so well when you have
experienced psychedelics. Yeah. Yeah. If
you've ever experienced a psychedelic,
and when I say a psychedelic, like for
me, I'm not really talking about like
you took an ecstasy pill, I'm more along
the lines of like uh you know, you
obliterated your ego with Yeah. You
know, you've eaten quarter ounce of
mushroom or something. Mushrooms, done
some or smoked some DMT or dropped
dropped some powerful LSD or something.
You know what I mean? Any of those.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And you know,
uh, ingested cannabis can be really
strong. And a lot of these people were
taking, uh, uh, ingested amounts that
would knock you out even for a day or
two. And then they'd come back from that
experience with a vision and that would
be considered reality, you know. Breeder
Steve dose. A breeder Steve dose. There
you go. Yeah. He he would take uh him
and do do you remember his friend Wayne
from way back when? Oh, no. I remember
they had a they had a film container
full of just trikes. So it would have
wouldn't have been like 99% heads
because they didn't have access back
then but it probably would have been
like you know at least 30 or 40% heads
and it was a film container so it was
many many grams and he just cooked it
put it into brownies and him and Wayne
shared the whole thing and they
definitely like Steve I think lost 36
hours. Oh man. And or one of them was 27
one of them was 36 like just
unconscious.
I remember Kirsty telling me like she
was like had to check to see if Steve
was breathing cuz he was just like not
moving. You know, it's funny. I have
read a number of accounts of people
putting into a deathlike coma through
powerful cannabis extracts to the point
that they've been thought dead. There's
this book uh written in the 19th century
by this Dr. James Brad and uh it's
trance and human hibernation and he goes
to India and he sees factors and there
say okay I'm going to die and I'm going
to be buried in the ground and I'm going
to be dug up in a few days from now and
I'm going to come back to life and uh he
said that they were doing this by taking
powerful cannabis extracts it was like
this famous
faced them out and your body like uh um
William Oshanaugh writes about putting
people into a state of catalpsy and you
can actually move some it'll just stay
like there like they got rigam mortise
or something like that. You know what I
mean? Uh um and uh um I love that he
knows all the terms for these words. The
first the first anesthesia was in fact a
preparation of cannabis and wine in
China about 100 AD. And that guy was
performing operations and stuff uh by
knocking people out and then uh um yeah,
you know, it's it's pretty interesting.
Goes to show you the power of cannabis.
I'll tell you one thing. I had a friend
who ate too much one time and he was in
the bathroom just having a bad trip
trying and he was coming out of the
bathroom. He wasn't even going to the
bathroom. He was just coming out of the
bathroom and he got stuck in this
position and he was like, I can't move
my arms. His arms were even up a little
more or something. And I remember him
like not being a like even us trying to
like push his arms down seemed like he
was made of freaking concrete and it was
it was actually really not a good
experience. It terrified him for sure
and it kind of freaked us out for a
while. He was like that I would say for
close to an hour, you know. I'll show
you this video later. It's uh um it's
this video of this kid, Nova's kid,
takes dabs of all his buddies, right?
You know what I mean? And he freezes and
they're like he's frozen and he's
like and they go in there and mess with
him and finally they start tugging him.
Then he starts to come and he's like,
"Whoa, oh this isn't good, guys. This
isn't good. I was frozen in time." and
he totally uh freaks out and then as
he's freaking out he starts going back
into it again.
They're like, "Hey, he's doing it again.
Stop him." And it's totally legit. Uh um
and you know, it's funny because one of
the most amazing things about cannabis
when you first use it is this sense of
time distortion. You know, a minute
seems like a second. And so they're
literally like freezing in time. You
know, I I kind of think that there may
be some tongue relation with cannabis
and the conception of time because the
grim reaper, he holds a scythe, the
ancient cythian tool used for harvesting
cannabis, right? And uh um time kind of
begins with agricultural time on the
seasons of growing and following that
type of stuff. And then there's this
whole time shift. And the pygmies in
Africa, they say that they've been
cultivating cannabis since the dawn of
time, but it's more likely means their
conception of time. And one of the ways
you could kind of perceive of time is
having the experience of a
differentiation in time where a second
seems like an you know a minute or you
know what I mean or or something like
that and that would kind of help you
conceptualize that's a pretty heavy
philosophical um the idea of time you
know just a kind of stone thought you
know what I mean but well I think the
congalles came from the pygmies. Yeah.
Cool. So, we get to smoke that that and
it was and and I also heard the story. I
heard Al the Alchemist tell the story
that it was it was it was meant to be a
gift. But the Congalles was meant to be
a gift. That's what it you know. So,
it's uh if you've got it, gift it. Well,
go uh the py say that God gave them
cannabis so that they would be healthy
and happy. Wow. And uh I think that
we're all appreciative of that gift.
Would you like to try a dab of the
bubble hat? You know, I'm so high off
that last one. You probably have to wait
a while. Maybe I got pretty high off
that last one. Then I kind of got
mellowed out by the second one. But
here, I'll take this bottle. I puff uh
cannabis all day. Vaporized generally,
but you know, I probably not like what
you call a heavy user. I probably go
through about a gram and a half a day.
Maybe if I'm at work smoking joints, I
smoke a couple of big joints or
something like that. Well, I definitely
see that you puff non-stop throughout
your day. Yeah, I spread it out. You
know what I mean? It's like whatever I
just I like to keep a good kind of
stone. I make my coffee, I get high, and
I kind of keep that level of of stone. I
find the dabs, you know, man, it can
just knock me out of commission. Pretty
good for an in-depth uh conversation
about what you love and what you know,
though, cuz you've been doing some
pretty good rambles. Oh, good. Yeah,
I've been enjoying it myself. I You want
me to show you some other stuff?
Absolutely, dude. I always appreciate
all the stuff you show and all the
things you talk about, cuz I I admit I
know a lot about cannabis. It's one of
the things maybe that I know the most
about, but I don't know almost anything
about everything you talk about. Like I,
you know, a really interesting thing. I
got this for myself after I completed my
last book, Cannabis and the Soma
Solution. And this is I had it made into
a necklace. Is a about a 3rd century AD
gold coin. I like that. Uh um gold coin
from northern India. And it's a Cythian
gold coin because the Cythians dominated
in northern India uh um from about uh
3rd century 3rd century BC to the 4th
century AD. And uh on this side it's a
Cythian king and he's all dressed up
like Shiva. He's got the trident. He's
got dreadlocks. Got a serpent there. And
he's got his like you know the Shiva
carries around his drug jar there. He's
got his little uh basket there. And um
uh um the Cythians actually embraced
Shiva when they showed up in India and
uh um Shiva of course and they had the
love of cannabis and Shiva of course is
the lord of cannabis right and so it's
hard to say like Shiva is thought to be
an indigenous god to India like Cali as
well the rest of the Indian pantheon
Krishna Brahma uh um Vishnu all these
types of figures came with the Aryans
who came in and wrote the vetta and
brought the religion, right? And then
these guys were adopted is is is the
idea, right? But uh um it's it's
interesting because those stone age
images of Shiva where he's like in lotus
position and all the animals around I
forget what it's called. Uh uh um but it
like stone age image of Sheba way. Um,
and people have uh there's one scholar
who's been comparing that to the the
Celtic stuff like the goorop cauldron
where there's that sinos figure with the
horns and he's got all the animals
around him and stuff and saying that
this is all part of this same cultural
complex. And with this recent news of
the spread of of uh Indo-Uropean spread
of cannabis, which they're, you know,
calling in the press the birth of
Western civilization through cannabis
culture and the first, you know,
agricultural cash crop cannabis and
opening up the whole trade routes that,
you know, saying basically that the Silk
Road was more of a hemp and highway and
it goes back thousands of years. If that
is true, then we're talking about
something so old, a religious kind of
sacrament and herb that's just so old it
goes right back, you know, like they're
saying, uh, this spread happened about
5,000 years ago. Uh, Indo-Uropean
spread. And we have examples of cannabis
at Celtic and Drewic sites and also up
in China with Indo-Europeans there and
then Afghanistan and the bacteria
margar. have the evidence and then into
India with Soma that this is all just so
old and it's so special that in this
time we're just kind of figuring it out
as we're finding out about all these
medical benefits of cannabis all of a
sudden this agent history is starting to
rise up and archaeologists and
anthropologists are going that western
civilization grew out of civilization I
mean Carl Sean said that uh uh cannabis
was likely our first agricultural crop
and culture grew out of agriculture you
know what I mean absolutely well Dr.
David Allen said that probably the first
human suckling on a brass was induced by
that munchy effect that canabonoids
produce. It's, you know, it's like
everywhere that we went when we started
cultivating this plant, it was growing
in night soil. light soil is human waste
and it literally grew in our piss and
[ __ ] and we were putting oursel back in
that soil and uh um it's growing there
and it's taking in all that stuff that's
been through us and then we're ingesting
it and then putting it back in the soil
and you got to think that there's some
sort of
like
biological relationship here that's like
you know they're calling them some
modern diseases endocanabonoid
deficiency you know what I mean well
Because it seems like the more you study
pharmaceutical drugs, you realize that
most of them are trying to do the job
that your endockinabonoid system would
do naturally with essential amino acids
and and canabonoids, whether
endogenously produced or inhaled through
phytoinabonoids. Either way, those those
get the job done. And uh it's it's kind
of I've always said why, you know, when
people are like, "Oh, I saw that little
girl, she was having all these seizures
and then they put the oil under her
tongue. It was a miracle." I always say
it really wasn't a miracle. It was an
endockinabonoid deficiency. And then the
canabonoids are obviously very I mean
just if if all your system did was put
your immune system and your central
nervous system in homeostasis, if that's
all it did, that would be incredible in
its own right. But everything else
that's going on and all that we will
learn in the next 10 and 20 years of
actually being able to study the science
of this while simultaneously uncovering
the rich historical past. I mean it's a
pretty it's like building a jigsaw
puzzle from our perspectives. Chris
Chris and I have been in the cannabis
activism world for 20 to 25 years, maybe
Chris longer. Um, and that's uh that's
like a a a better portion of our lives.
It's more than it's more than half of
our lives that we've been doing this. So
to see this jigsaw puzzle that almost
started with just one little piece.
Yeah. You know, and we and it was like
whatever it was that made us believe in
that piece that made even through all
the propaganda before Jack's book and
before the learning and when people were
telling us it was bad and believing it.
Yeah. But feeling that it was good. That
feeling that there was something
intrinsically good in this rel I would
go out and hide in my shed in my
backyard in in the freezing cold weather
15 years old and smoke joints and just
be like the feeling that it gave me and
that connection that it gave me was so
important to my well-being and to the
choices that I would later on make in
life that I I can't even uh Yeah. Yeah.
Know for sure. It's like the forbidden
fruit syndrome. You know what I mean?
And it's like you're told in the garden,
go eat that and then you go eat it. It's
like wo your eyes become open and you
kind of like it's this fruit is so
special. Yeah. It's so It's not like
just any old fruit. No fruit for sure,
man. Not that any old fruit is any
fruit. I love fruit and you know it's
like I've been I guess I started around
89 90 and I just have to say like just
how much it has proved itself over and
over and over. each new like medical
discovery, each new, you know,
industrial use and each, you know, and
then all this history kind of starting
to rise to the surface and stuff, you
know, it's uh uh it's really phenomenal
and it's a really uh uh I feel blessed
to have been a part of like the whole
whole rising of this this herb up into
the into the mainstream again. You know,
it feels like it's been a one-way
street. No matter what they try to throw
at us to make it look like a 180, like
we're going the other direction, no
matter what they throw at us. From the
from the 14th century Cairo Sufis that
had their teeth ripped out in the
square. Yeah. Right. For eating hashish
to, you know, the California grower in
1999 who's he got busted three times,
but he's going to keep doing it because
he believes in it. It's it just can't be
stopped. It's like you pour concrete
down and then it grows through the
cracks. That's right. If the highway to
hell is paved, it's one thing that's
going to break its way to through the
pavement and that's a plant. You know
what I mean? And it's an opportunity on
so many levels for humanity to go back
that greener route. You know what I
mean? Uh uh um because you know we can
replace fossil fuels with hemp fuels and
uh we can even make batteries out of
this plant. We can make all our clothes
out of it and move away from soil
depleting cotton. You know what I mean?
Paints and oils and all these other
stuff. assume that as a whole if we made
more environmentally friendly and
biodegradable through the use of this
plastics you know it's endless paper you
know we cut down 50% of our trees for
for paper these days you know what I
mean toilet paper toilet paper wiping
our ass with our futures as jello bafra
would say when he gave his hand you know
uh years ago you know and so and then
then it's like this medicinal qualities
of it and everything we're just finding
out about it you know curing these
little poor children of epilepsy you
know that was thought to be demonic
possession ession back in the ancient
world and cannabis actually uh uh um
appears in ancient recipes for you know
the the relief of what was believed to
have been the hand of ghost and other
things it was called and uh um you know
it's it's just so incredible that you
know to watch that happen and see these
parents who like are losing their kids
you know they're going to die from all
the medications and then they're they're
living and starting to thrive you know
it's heart-wrenching for sure it's nice
to see it happen it's it's also that
then you get to the point where but you
don't only help the sick people, you can
actually use it as a preventative and
prevent people from maybe having those
seizures or having uh later on in life
heart disease, heart heart disease and
diabetes and stroke. These are things
that consuming canabonoids can help
prevent as well. So then you get into
that aspect of it and then we haven't
even really touched on the spiritual
aspect of how it makes you feel and how
it seems to connect you with something.
And when I when I hear people call
cannabis an escape. Yeah. I just think,
wow, it really isn't. Yeah. It's like a
circle naturally forms when you pass a
joint around. You know what I mean? You
let out the herbs. What What other
things do people pass from hand to hand
and that's that takes place? You know, I
think there's different ways. you know
for for Sufis and uh sadus I think a lot
of uh of the drive to using cannabis was
like almost increases your attention to
a level uh that's meditative where you
can start to blow away your ego and just
get down to that common essence of us
all and all the thoughts can drift away
you know you could get lost staring at
the wallpaper for 20 minutes that's
actually like a form of a trance you
know what I mean and it's all how you
direct that energy though you know what
I mean intense is everything with
cannabis so if you're like, you know,
smoking blunts and dope and listening to
gangster hip-hop, you're not really
going to be getting the same effect as,
you know, a sadu who's partaking of his
chillum on on the river gan ganis before
he sits down to do his yoga katanas. I
can I can definitely say I've done both
and they are very
different now. Not to uh I'm not putting
anything making any judgment. Exactly.
Not putting one over the other. Clearly
saying that you will get very different
experience. It's a magnifier, you know,
it magnifies wherever you're in and set
and setting and intent and all these
things uh pay a role. And I will say
that I think if you take the time to
find out about the religious history of
cannabis and the history of this
incredible plant that that will become
part of your intent because everything
you know is what creates your intent.
And uh um the more you find out about
this incredibly magical spiritual tree
of life, soma
uh you know, the holy ganja sheepa,
whatever you want to call it, the plant
of immortality, the Chinese, the more it
cloaks itself in the magic and myth of
our ancestors, you know, dude, [ __ ]
right on, bro. You're you're awesome,
dude. You're a good dude. I'm just
loving it. That's uh that's poetic,
really. You know, I was thinking as
Chris was sort of on that last end of
his his uh his speech there that uh
we're going to be doing some boosted
boarding later right after this
actually. We're going to get on these
boosted boards I guess. Well, or maybe I
don't know. Chris has so many different
ones. But that to me, like to be able to
do this, talk about this plant that we
love, the history of it, share it with
you guys, but then go and do a nice
beautiful nature ride on an electric
skateboard. That's my meditation, man.
You know what I mean? It's like I'm
telling you inspire me, dude. I mean, I
wouldn't be on these boards if it wasn't
for you. You're definitely Hey, man. I'm
I'm glad at 54 I'm still rocking stuff
like this, you know what I mean? It's uh
it's a blessing, you know? And I think
uh Herb keeps you young at heart, you
know what I mean? Yeah, I feel the same
way. People tell me all the time, "Oh,
you look young, you act young. You seem
like a younger person." I'm like, "Well,
it's it's just uh take care of yourself,
you know? Here, I'll show you these
antique chillums and a couple other
things." I would love to see that. Yeah,
I was just going to say take care of
yourself, you know, pay attention to
your diet. Whatever it is, make sure
you're eating the best quality food that
you can.
So, these are 19th century chils. And in
the center there's a um sadu. And uh um
sometimes these sadus will do things to
show uh um I don't know like it's it's
it's kind of sadistic, but they they'll
do things like hold their arm up to show
the power of their will. Dude, I met a
guy like that at the Kumba. Yeah. Yeah.
And so this guy's arm has a has a trophy
in this position, but there he is with a
chillum. You know, it's an old uh
postcard. And how old is that though, do
you think? Uh this is probably like
1920s or so. Okay. Yeah, I was going to
say cuz that's insane. I might have to
go through my pictures because the
picture of the guy I met at the Mahakuma
had been holding his arm up for like
some insane amount of years. It was a
stone. His It didn't work
anymore. That would be wild if it was
him. 90 years old. No, he looked like he
was more like 60. But that's that's
India, too. I've got all these really
great like 19th century books as well.
This is called Keith, a life story in
nine phases. And uh um it's a story of a
uh
uh of a guy that astral travels well on
cannabis and starts having an affair
with another man's wife on the astral
plane. Really? Um and the illustrations
from it are just fabulous. I was trust I
know I have a couple of them printed up
here but uh I can't can't find it. Very
cool. Uh um yeah. So this guy's this is
really fascinating little book and it's
got great illustrations of people
smoking weed and uh uh um like here they
are um puffing down before they get off
on the astral plane there.
Um and uh yeah, I've got all sorts of
cool books like that. You know, I'm I've
been researching a lot about magic and
cannabis and stuff. So, uh I'm stuck by
this guy Pascal Beverly Randolph who was
the first huge commercial importer of
hashish. And he he was an interesting
guy. That's an impressive title. Say
that again. Uh first commercial big
commercial importer of hashish. And uh
um I've they got all these old
advertisements for his hashish and stuff
like that. Roian, which is a kind of
secret society, alchemical occult secret
society. And they were using cannabis
and a lot of those secret societies back
then, particularly Rosacruian groups.
And Randolph, he had two extracts he was
making from really good hash. And uh um
from the sounds of it, it almost sounds
like one was more of a CBD type of thing
and one was more of a THC thing because
they had uh different properties and
effects and stuff like that. uh um and
he spread a lot of uh of cannabis around
up until about 1875. Really fascinating
guy. Another guy, Pascal Beverly
Randolph, has this book, Sanctuary of
Spiritualism, and it's got 15 firsthand
accounts of people ingesting three grams
of hashish. They do it in like Turkish
coffee, you know what I mean? Stir it in
real gooey hashish, drink it down, and
then they'd have these super powerful
experiences. And so the person
afterwards would write down their
experience. And uh this makes up this
book. It's 15 firsthand accounts and
just really interesting um visions and
some of the ideas that they're talking
about that were coming to them in these
states really parallels ideas like
quantum physics and other things that
we're we're finding out in science. And
it's interesting just how deep a
knowledge you can get from that sort of
uh introspection and even more so
sometimes with the use of substances
like cannabis. That's awesome. Well, I'm
inspired. I'm uh I'm ready to go ride
Boosted Boards. I think I'm going to
bring my camera so you guys can catch a
little bit of the vibes on the board. I
didn't bring my GoPro, but I'll hold my
video camera. I can do that. And uh
yeah, thanks for having me over, dude.
Always a pleasure, man. It was awesome.
Thank you guys for watching and stick
around. We're about to go boosted
boarding.
Groovy.
So, you want to go to North? Hey guys.
So, we are out uh in front of Chris's
place. We've got the electric boards.
Which one you got there? This is the
Evolved Bustin deck. Uh it's great
board. Uh what I like about these boards
is they got the double bushing trucks
like the old G wings, you know. Oh [ __ ]
look at that. Uh um so they're really
carvy dual bushings. Um and it's get
gets a lot of range. This one I get
about 15 miles on I think, you know, if
it's uh pretty steady terrain and uh
yeah, nice flexi deck, you know. And
then this one beside me is the Boosted.
We've had it on here before. It's a
really solid build. They got a really
nice tight electronics and brakes and
stuff like that. The brakes on this one
are a little looser. Not as carby, but
better for high speeds. I I'd say this
is my main commuter. So, if I'm driving
in the city, it's it's the board I drive
to work on and stuff like that cuz it
could stop really good. It stops legs
and uh um it's got a lot of torque for
going up the hill. Real limited range,
so probably about four or five miles for
a guy my weight, 200 lb, you know. Uh um
so it's it's got its limitations. This
one it's all about the carve for me. You
know what I mean? I like to carve it out
going down a hill or and uh it's really
nice and light and you can really melt
some uh range out of it. Downside uh the
way they got the motor set up. These
motor plates have a tendency to snap. So
I've got to take it careful over any uh
breaks in the cement. You want real
smooth cement for this one. But they've
also got an all-terrain setup. And the
all-terrain setup's great. air tires and
uh handles gravel roads, bumps, and
stuff like that. I've got their latest
version uh um coming soon. It's got dual
motor, so it'll be a dual motor,
all-terrain uh skateboard, and it's
great for driving right over train
tracks or whatever. And still got a lot
of speed and uh a lot of range as well.
Well, I'm ready to hit the road if you
are. Okay. Me, too, man. All right,
let's do it.
[Music]
Oh
n man, set up the machine. What kind of
strain you have there? This one is so
clean and
clear. Come
on. We
[Music]
dab. It's time. Do time. We dab.
Da da
dab. It's a double
do. Fresh from the extractor. 100% pure
conjure. I just hope this a clean and
pretty like
gold of use. is good for just being
ninefold. Good for the young and the
whole every
soul. We
ding
ding. It's a doo time. D
time
[Music]
ding. It's a doo time. So ding do time
diving in the morning diving in the
evening diving at supper time. Ding when
you're weary ding when you're lonely cuz
we're feeling
fine. Some people ask me what is
dabbing. I've got to show you my dabbing
machine that my virgin bubble man
bringing hand
with
dab
[Music]
time. It's good for the end of Canite
system. Oh, lovely or
[Music]
great.
La. Yeah, we dive
in.
Ding. This is a d time. A d time.
Ding.
Da da
dab. This is a doo time.
[Music]
Doo. Hey.
N. Hey.
Come on.
Ding.
Ding. This is a doo time. Doo d time
time.
[Music]
D. All right.
[Applause]
[Music]
WR my strike lightning as the morning
break. My heavens open wide. The sun was
up in my face. The wisdom of the wise
keep with a
sweet try to perfection smoke in the
city. I love the
streets from the we get the
full rising. I love the street. I take
away the rest and consume the meditation
mind to CV1 and
TV2 receptors in the brain and body
happiness for me and
you get your cannot
[Music]
be
that try to for the city. I love the
sweet
[Music]
tri. I love the sweet
tri I A L
cannabis patient. N E D I C A L
cannot make it better. I can't do
without many many
[Music]
I hear I
like the
office. I love the sweetness.
[Music]
I love
child. Heat. Heat.
I
know. I know.
[Music]
Free your mind and rock and free your
mind and
live. Free your mind and comm your mind
and dance. Distress distress.
Distress
distress. Distress
and save the life for yes. Distress
[Music]
distress. Yes.
And save your life. Oh yes. Will blind
you like a bat. Oh yeah. And grab you
like a rat. Oh, and treat you like a M.
They will tie you like a knot. A kn. And
they will mismeize your eyes people
before you realize. Oh yeah. They tell
you dirty lies. They will show you like
a
dice. Distress
distress.
And save your life for Yes. Distress
[Music]
dess and save your life for yes to sense
the sign to keep you down. They use you
and show you all around. No
follow in every man to sound a sound. So
you got to listen to yourself and know
which one you must choose and which one
you must
use. Don't get
confused. Oh no, no. Free your mind and
rock and free your mind and
live. Free your mind
and free your mind and dance. Peace.
Peace.
Peace. Be stress. Distress
[Music]
and save your life. Oh yes. Distress
distress
distress. Yes.
And save your life for
your step. Stepping at the right place.
Walk. Walking at the right place. Move.
Moving on the right place. Move.
skip on the right
place. Running on the right dance up on
the right dance. Uh-huh. Distress
[Music]
distress.
Distress. Yes. Distress.
And save your life
for distress. Distress.
Distress. Distress,
distress, distress.
And save your life. Yes. Distress.
Distress. Distress.
Distress. Yes.
And save a life. Yes. Yes. Distress.
Distress. Distress. Distress.
Distress.
Distress. and save your life for
Yes.
[Music]
Dress triceps.