[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
bubble man here and I'm actually just
getting in my truck here about to head
down to see Chris Bennett who was
apparently released a new book and you
know on my way I was thinking oh geez I
got a I got a I got a charge up the puff
Co but luckily in this particular
vehicle about this wonderful 115 volt
room Shaboom sorry about the terrible
quality there for a second so I am going
to charge up my puff Co while I driving
to the city
nice and easy plug it in boom plug it
into here drop it into my cup holder
which it actually fits quite beautifully
and I've got about a 20 minute drive to
get to Chris's I think we're gonna do a
short little interview with him talk
about his new book that he's got coming
out and yeah after that we were thinking
of getting on the boosted boards or the
Evolve whatever one he plans to bring
out today and maybe do a little bit of a
sea wall around Vancouver's downtown
area there Stanley Park at least so of
course I thought bring the camera and
film a little video so that's what I'm
gonna do and I'm gonna bring you guys
along
[Applause]
[Music]
Chinese strike light CS the Martin right
my game is open way this one was ugly my
pecs the wisdom of the White team
against that straight
[Music]
home joyously paparazzi I love the
street
the way the nest
a ps4
I'm sorry I got her
if I study Chinese but not
[Music]
music
/ I accept that you brush I ain't
dropping the monkey because
the slip
[Music]
Tracy faker :
original indigenous here got
nothing I
give me my
original indigenous here can't
[Music]
I
all right welcome to bow man's world
everybody I'm here with Kris Bennett's
Jesus how would I even introduced Kris I
don't have to introduce Chris he's been
on - church enough you guys know him as
the cannabis historian he's been writing
books about cannabis Dell dwelling into
the occult connections with cannabis and
he has oh he has written oh he's saying
hi he's written another amazing book
here what's the title Lieber 420
cannabis magical herbs and the occult
that big one serious serious thick book
what do you think kitty mr. kitty
look at that right there about 800 pages
of madness marijuana madness magic what
number is this for folks for you this is
my fourth well two co-authored books and
this is my second personal we were
talking earlier a little off-camera your
cat is America's we were talking a
little bit earlier off-camera in regards
to you know sort of how chris has been
able to from writing his other books
been able to finally compile and create
these connections that he's found over
the years yeah yeah well you know one
thing leads to another and having a
background with different cultures and
their historical use of cannabis it
helps to understand later references and
how they came about and stuff like say
for instance Islamic influences really
influenced later Europeans of cannabis
and you can see this in things like
magic via like magical texts like the
10th century Gaia al-hakim which refers
to can
was translated into the picker tricks in
the 13th century was translated into
Latin and entered Europe and it's one of
the pivotal documents of Western magical
traditions it was kind of starts with
this you know and that has a recipe for
instance for a pound and a bit of
Turkish resin mixed with snake blood and
other ingredients of birch in order to
invoke the messenger of the moon in the
pillar of smoke that forms over this
fuming pile and so you know that's what
way and then another way is in alchemy
you know figures like Abba sienna and
gabber well Nolan Arabic alchemical
figures and before them is all zero so
made reference to cannabis preparation
is the tincture and whatnot and this is
why we form these sorts of references in
the works of European alchemists like
Paracelsus and Cardinal who have recipes
for cannabis infusions in their works in
the Latin again so yeah you know so we
don't have any knowledge and this kind
of helps to bring all this together
Katz there's the camera sometimes yeah
it's very unique information that you've
got I have not read the book Chris was
just telling me you're the only person
to be able to interview me that hasn't
read the book yeah but it's pretty new
it's pretty new just came out April 20th
and so it you know it comes out on the
actually in 1918 April 20th Aleister
Crowley and a guy who I learned while I
was writing this book actually lived on
my street year in North Vancouver and
decode that I grew up in I did a
cannabis ritual and
comes out on the centennial anniversary
of that it came out centennial
anniversary yes damn that's awesome
well definitely I can tell you if you
guys are gonna pick up this book and
you're going to read this information
it's not going to be information that is
common knowledge and like I feel like I
know a fair bit about cannabis over the
years I've definitely well didn't do it
geek tout on it pretty hard but Chris's
information is always stuff that's a
surprise to me it's always new and I you
know I don't actress know all the names
but over the years he's definitely
educated me too Rabelais and to Crowley
and to some of these different guises
connections with cannabis and I'm always
looking more forward to sort of
connecting more of the dots as it's done
through you know 11 and 12 and 13th all
the different centuries that this
information has passed through it's it's
incredible really well you know we're
I'm lucky to live in this like pivotal
time when things like google books where
they've scanned like all these Medieval
and Renaissance era manuscripts into
Google Books
and you can search through the word
searches and cannabis and Latin is spelt
the same way as words in English so
you're able to go back into a lot of
these variations and then when you know
other spellings that the variations that
as well you're able to search all these
documents and then it's just a matter of
finding out what the references say
where you can find in the identification
of cannabis and so I know some Latin
translators and hired some Latin
translators and was able to find a lot
of really cool old recipes and
information that nobody's ever really
written about for centuries you know so
it's pretty fun stuff and pretty
interesting as well
cannabis because I gotta give it up to
some of these old alchemists from back
in the day they really had to seek this
[ __ ] out oh yeah they were they were
they were doing a lot of experimentation
you know like a guy like Perry calluses
for instance his recipe for cannabis or
Academy which is a texture preparation
was for epilepsy and we see all these
people getting created for epilepsy now
this is like you know like 15th century
16th century and you know he's already
you know we're well aware of additional
qualities of this herb for that
particular debilitating purpose you know
we got a wondering how many feet how
many tens of thousands of people have
suffered between the 15th century when
he came up with that information to
today where it's like you know he took
Sanjay Gupta or whatever going on CNN
it's it's you know and it's a lot of it
is children suffering you know and not
know I guess we always feel that
children suffering is obviously a little
bit worse but suffering is suffering
people suffering is kind of a pretty big
down yeah well you know in the aging
world to treat people of something like
epilepsy it was comparable to exorcisms
even I was gonna say they must have
thought they were epilepsy was thought
to be demonic possession well into
Medieval Renaissance times so yeah you
were like a miracle cure you know you've
exercises demon right out of them well
interesting that off-camera before we
were talking I was started talking about
how I feel that cannabis it's this sort
of weather metaphorical or whether you
want to think of it as exactly that it's
it tends to close these you know
metaphorically I I this is my own
personal opinion but it seems to close
these portholes in which demons possess
people and whether that's you know
people thinking bad thoughts people
doing bad actions
you know people getting hammered
on different drugs when they don't seem
to be themselves and then the medicinal
components of cannabis helping regulate
and getting people try illogical
functions back in order getting their
endocannabinoids system into homeostasis
that really would be the opposite of you
know the demonic possession of epilepsy
and all these other ailments you know
it's funny because in the ancient world
a lot predating germ theory there was
this whole theory about different demons
that were present you could see that
they were present by different ailments
and symptoms and stuff like that and so
if anyway you know how to cough or the
rash on your groin but while you had
this popular demon you know and that's
scary yeah so that was but it kind of
followed a lot along the same lines as
germ theory but of like contagion and in
symptoms and all that type of stuff and
that's going back fairly far so let's go
back like thousands of years yeah so
yeah we're gonna hit the popco while we
talk a little bit more about Chris's
book and then we're actually going to
head out on the boosted boards perhaps
the evolve will make a an appearance
what we're gonna do the seawall see well
yeah for sure sounds great yeah as I was
saying to mark earlier I'm only doing
interviews about the book of people who
read and even read it but a hugh
electric skateboard and you want to go
for it you can rip on it electric
skateboard then i can bypass that
particular rule if we go for a ride so
well I appreciate it and I will
absolutely read your book man there's
you know for me there's an enormous
amount of information here that I don't
know and you know like you learning from
writing writing your books and
connecting things and putting the dots
together to be able to see these
different patterns I look forward to
that as well well you know so it's gonna
take obviously reading
it's it's this is not light reading this
is seriously heavy reading like that you
definitely have to kind of turn up the
intellect a little bit yeah well you
know it's like I'm out to prove stuff so
it's like takes references and citations
put notes and bibliographies and makes
for a slightly drier although I try to
keep it entertaining with weird facts
looks like a great book man what are
some of the highlights that you've you
enjoyed the book you know I love the
stuff about the Templars you know
there's been claims by a number of
authors like Robert Anton Wilson and a
doctor Libra or a book about medieval
medicine Lily and you know deseos the
Templars had this cannabis wine this
preparation of cannabis aloe in a palm
wine and I started digging around trying
to find that and I could find no
references to it but I did find that
cannabis was seized at two Templar sites
and their raids considerable amounts of
it where the form is described and they
had some sort of a contract with
Saracens Arabs to grow cannabis for them
in Spain and Arabs were particularly
known for growing the industrial variety
campus and what year what year this is
like 12 13 century oh wow and so it adds
credence to these of these claims about
the cannabis wine and also a pope who
was friendly with the Templars
temperature around for a few centuries
and before they were accused of their
heresies they were quite friendly with
every part of the Catholic Church
basically right and a pope who was
friendly with them released a medical
treatise that included that cannabis
infused wine for a number of ailments
and in the same time period mason
Villere Donna corked his Masonic Germany
he spent time in the Holy Land it had a
bunch of illustrations of different
masonry techniques from one of them but
the only page of written text and it is
Anna cannabis infused woman so it seems
likely that there was some you know
awareness of that that for preparation
coming in and there's this interesting
connection then the Templars are very
connected to the whole Grail mythology
and the term Grail itself has a
neurological connections to the gras
which is the vessel that soma and the
Persian counterpart soma and were
partaking right and it's like a holy
vessel where the psychoactive beverage
is taken in and there's some interesting
stuff in that in that mythology and
others have suggested there may be some
connection between the Grail mythology
and the hashish infusion used by the
Templars medieval sometimes enemies
sometimes allies known as the hash
machine a group of Islamic heretics that
are reputed to have used a sheesh and
there's controversy about that and I
answer a lot of that controversy over a
lot of the historical material and my
view on the hash machine is is this is a
carryover from the earlier Persian
Geraci and traditions where we read in
the first few centuries ADEs accounts up
these Persian
Psychonauts taking credit us appears
wine
and in otherworldly voyages under the
influence you know I'm talking poke
extracts like sometimes they drink like
as much as seven cups of these cannabis
infused wines and these guys would be
knocked out for a couple of days
and then they come back and report these
visionary experiences they have in
Leavenworth it was thought to be that
their soul had left their body that's
where these type of ideas came from for
people having drug experiences you know
so were you kind of along the lines of I
saw cops damnit speak recently and he
brought up terence mckenna's stoned
monkey theory of the sort of like how
consciousness got this spark yeah into
into really all these different things
that we've you know the creation of from
engineering and like complex
civilizations and all these different
all these different concepts do you kind
of come from the belief system that
psychedelics and psychoactive can assure
you know like a dr. Jasser a guy what do
i do just hit yeah it's all ceramic yeah
we've come a long way as we're talking
about the history of cannabis from you
know thousands of years ago as we
literally hit the most up-to-date sort
of future is a latest these guys what a
trip to try this yeah for sure
very cool so you're saying about just a
doctor Jeffrey Garten
cannabis be appearing at the time of the
Great Leap Forward many of these like
advancements in human culture took place
invention the wheel and chrome fire
these type of things you know we know
that
the natural evidence that for at least
five purposes our relationship of campus
goes back or twenty five thousand years
you know I mean so evidence we which
puts it puts its use in to get close to
the time period puppy great leap forward
in amenities like technologic very
cultural advancements were made you know
I mean they they speculate it was the
the ability of cannabis to cause new
novel ways of thinking you know right
and we know people are oh there's always
a group of people that are afraid of new
novel ways of thinking or even change of
any kind in general and so as you do
research like this does it seem as
though the prohibition of cannabis has
been around for almost as long as
cannabis there's always been people that
have felt greatest by other people using
cannabis for a long time you know you
see this with the disappearance of some
a oma in in Persian India and also you
know psychoactive substances in general
you know it's like religions like
Christianity Judaism their religions
that you're taught you know it's not
really about your own personal
experience it's more what's the stories
in this book or this is what we believe
in anything that offers like a hands-on
experience you know type of thing or the
concept and there's bad lies within you
it's a real threat to that higher always
they seem to replace all of that with
faith yeah psycho don't you know have
your own experience like just have faith
yeah telling you is is accurate and that
it's
although you know I have known people
who have used their religious belief
systems to help them and I certainly
don't mock people's religious belief
systems but I guess I do mock you know
what I mean it's like I just see like I
take a look at the world around me and I
just see so much problem caused by this
stuff and so much of it seems like so
much hooey the more I you know look into
it I select I've really studied religion
for a long time you have you've gone in
a lot deeper than I have for sure for me
it's just not my five I'm like that's
what you want to do no problem I always
am refreshed by some of the things
you'll say on Facebook and in some of
your posts where you just like
no-holds-barred guy here it's like yeah
and it's true you know it's right up
there with it's hard to not connect
religion with prohibition because it
seems like since religion has been alive
they prohibited
thoughts experiences you know yeah
different different things there's
always putting these rules that really
would be construed as a type of
prohibition oh yeah yeah not for sure to
the extreme really and it's all part of
the human experience you know what I
mean like these things you know a lot of
these things may have served a better
purpose in their original times than
they serve us 2,000 years later and
people are trying to force this
bronze-age laws and mentality on 21st
century men it's just like you know
pretty ludicrous it's absolutely
ludicrous in that sense when you think
of these things that are
thousands of years old but I mean even
even when these guys wrote you know the
Constitution for you know the u.s. just
like you know 1776 or whatever that
thing got and that's it doesn't really
kind of you know with it like just to
simply record to like the gun one like
to bear arms and protect one thing used
to be like holding it and pushing it
down and now it's like submachine gun or
whatever yeah absolutely there's been a
lot of change maybe it might be a good
idea to update the scriptures yeah
absolutely
I think the badge apples pretty well
taken things to the limit so if Jesus
doesn't show now then you know I think
they should probably day yeah he's got a
very short period of time to show that
this one I'm sure those guys that do
what they can to get Armageddon going
and in the Holy Land
sure well we have canvas on our side so
we're very lucky yeah well you know it's
like my whole experience with cannabis
actually started with the religious
experience I had in like 89 90 reading
the Bible and you know reading the book
of Revelation stoned and
in the last chapter about the Tree of
Life in the book of Revelation with its
many fruits is 12 matters of fruit and
its leaves for the end of the nations
and that's really what set me on my path
that was like the life-changing moment
you know what I mean so as much as I
could write it you know at the same time
I realize its role in the you know in
the collective consciousness in human
history and I think that what cannabis
offers just a new way of looking at that
whole thing and I think when you really
understand the history of cannabis and
its role in you know Hinduism and
Sikhism and Taoism in Buddhism and
Judaism and Christianity Islam and
Christianity in my arcades particularly
here on the western edge and you take a
look at these references to cannabis and
the way it was used it becomes as much
of a threat to fundamentalist religion
as Darwin's theory of evolution was to
the myths of Adam in the image of
creation in Genesis because it shows is
that the prophets of the Bible in this
case say Moses for example if we take a
look at the claims about the Hebrew term
kind of Boston being cannabis which have
been around for about a century now you
take Moses and he's takes about nine
pounds of cannabis you know pitching in
but somewhere in cinnamon and some holy
oil and he places this on his body and
then he takes him in this oil and he
places it on the altar of incense it
goes outside the enclosed tent the place
of the meeting and he speaks to the Lord
of the pillar of smoke over that altar
of incense he becomes like a shaman
you know and Sharman's like in South
America and Africa today and just
executive plan actually interpreting
this is so going in my attention or
spiritualism you know a spiritual
possession or something like that and
this is something that these fundamental
religions have rallied against right
under they've come with
and we can see it is a medieval
Renaissance period of the cases of both
magic and alchemy and the church's
reaction to these things in the use of
plants and so it's a real fundamental
threat to it because it's like the first
hand experience show which is what they
don't offer and that's something they
try and suppress but it also reveals the
the originated rise to suppress honey
witchcraft stopping peyote and mushroom
adjusting religions and that so I think
it's very symbolic on a cultural level
you know yeah absolutely man it's it's
heavy for sure hopefully we don't have
too many more centuries of prohibition
and of this mentality of this group of
people that just seems to want to
prohibit this plant it just seems like a
great crime against humanity that has
gone on for centuries well you see what
it does get out how it blossoms you know
what I mean it's oh there must be like
over a hundred and fifty dispensaries
here in Vancouver and many of them are
thriving and people there are pleasant
and happy and all walks of life for
coming in and get
Canopus and there's almost like a
community center a type of atmosphere at
some of the
people really do feel a connection over
this verb and it's one of the few things
in this world that we pass from hand to
hand like that and hand to mouth
in any sort of ways and it's kind of
like the people's natural communion you
know well I'll tell ya I certainly
experienced it at 4:20 this year with
the tens of thousands of people I don't
pretend to guess how many were there
some people say 20,000 some people say
50,000 some people say 100,000 there
were tens of thousands of people and
it's always such an incredible
experience on the stage watching
everyone light up right at 4:20 and see
this cloud of smoke rise up and it's
really quite a powerful thing I'm sure
that the same way that there is power in
in focus focused thought like prayer
yeah there you know that that's a ritual
right there you know I'm really lighting
up and all the positive vibes no one
getting hurt and no one fighting and no
one yeah if that was a beer garden
should we put it on fire well we know
that because it's happened during the
NHL city doesn't talk about because the
NHL pay for the the wreck of the city
but these you want to like cry the Blues
about what I said I saw a market posted
something recently in regards to how why
we need to still be able to do this
because it's it's that we're proud of
our culture yeah and it's the same way
pride is proud of their culture yeah
it's not illegal to be gay anymore but
it doesn't mean they can't still be
proud of their gay culture and they're
gonna have their parades and they're
gonna have their gatherings and it's our
victory day now you know back to you
after legalization
it's our nectary day man they said you
know I mean we suffered a lot to see it
happen we've seen her friends jail
worse and with one it's our day man I
feel it well thanks for joining with you
yeah let me join you for that matter
here at your place and it's always
really interesting to hear we have to
say I'll definitely look forward to
reading your book I'm gonna pick up a
copy for sure and hopefully you guys do
as well where can they grab a copy as
you find it on Amazon just search Lieber
for 20 I look him up pretty quick and
yeah yeah check it out and there's some
in-depth interviews on our culture
podcast and on reality sandwich I'm
about the book you can check out as well
I'll put the links in the comment
section of the video and in the meantime
I think we're going to hit the boards
and bring you guys with us eat go for a
little sunshiny Vancouver days
skateboard with us yeah for sure man
it's gonna be right awesome stay away