hey everybody Welcome to Bubble man's
world you know here is where we dive
into the vibrant Universe of cannabis
culture and tonight we're thrilled to
introduce a new segment the Cannabis
Journal Club hosted by none other than
Dr David Allen and myself bubbleman Dr
Allen is not just any guest he's a
retired cardiovascular and thoracic
surgeon who has also served as a
professor specializing in the endoc
cannaboid signaling system with his
extensive background Dr Allen brings a
very unique perspective to the table
enrich by his experience as a veteran of
the drug War join us as we explore the
latest in cannabis research policy and
science with Dr David Allen on the
Cannabis Journal Club welcome
David good morning good afternoon now I
guess yeah it's good morning good
afternoon good evening there's people
all over the world so let's hit them all
all
right wonderful so yeah today we're
going to be talking about the mother of
all hanabono patents is that correct
perfect please give us give us the the
knowledge all right um I'm going to give
it a A Brief Review of the mother of all
cannabis
patents and uh it's it's entitled
cannaboids as antioxidants and
neuroprotectants patent number
6,630 57 it came out in October 7th of
2003 and um we're reviewing in patents
and U scientific articles about cannabis
and and the reason we're reviewing
patents is because the patent office is
The Keeper of the truth because you
can't make any mistakes uh on a patent
application and get a patent number
assigned to it so it in effect is The
Keeper of the truth and um this cannabis
patent
um 6 comma 630a 5 7 came out on October
7th of 2003 uh and was issued from by
the Department of Health and Human
Services which means this as a United
States
patent uh and uh it proves in this that
it decreases the size of a stroke by
half or
50% and
uh
so this patent uh proved this by doing
an experimentation on rats where they
uded uh middle cerebal artery of the
rats for a time period and open the
artery and then looked at the brains
afterwards and found out that that the
the size of the stroke was 50% smaller
and so that's hard scientific evidence
that this works in an animal model and
it's kind of a sin that this has not
been tested in
humans since 2003 because uh everybody
going to the hospital with a stroke or
heart attack might have had
their uh mortality morbidity improved by
taking CBD or or THC and this proves uh
in this that THC and CBD both are uh
efficacious in decreasing the size of a
stroke and they prefer CBD of course
because
it doesn't fully bind to the CB1
receptor and therefore it doesn't get
you high whereas C THC does bind to the
receptor and and gets you high and that
would change your neurological
examination
so um C CBD doesn't bind onto the CB1
receptor uh very strongly and THC does I
have a question yes what is the
comparable medication for the reduction
of stroke after after these operations
do they have because I remember Dr Brent
Reynolds telling me about like uh tumor
medications that shrink tumor in like
they shrink the maximum they shrink it
is
10% they cause neuropathy in like 85% of
the patients so they have to stop taking
it and this drug does billions of
dollars in profit annually and in the
meantime the comparable like the
apoptosis cannaboids is like whoa the so
is there a comparable medication CU When
you say 50% that's obviously a massive
number are maybe people aren't hearing
it that's pretty profound from the heart
surgeons per perspective no I don't want
to talk about oncologists because
they're the enemy uh but
uh
so
um so what was your question again just
just whether there was a medication that
offered this lack
of all right so there are some other
things vitamin C and other things that
are antioxidants but they don't
generally cross the blood brain barrier
where CBD and THC does and so has good
penetration and this this patent is is
based on the scientific evidence that
CBD and THC both stop reperfusion
injury and we'll go into that uh in
another uh segment of our uh articles
but uh basically when you when you stop
blood flow to an organ uh the cells that
are farthest away from the blood supply
die first so the center of the the
stroke starts from the very center and
then there's a surrounding area
of cells that are stunned but if you
return the blood flow to them they'll
return they'll they'll they're still
alive
but the center is is dead but the
surrounding tissue is is um hindered and
it's it's and what happens in in Strokes
is is when you reap when you restore the
blood flow to an area that's been cut
off from blood
supply what happens is uh some chemical
processes that make the stroke worse and
it's called reperfusion injury and what
happens is uh when
you put the blood flow back to the area
that's been denied oxygen and blood what
happens is there's a massive release of
a
neurotransmitter called glutamate and
it's a it's a
neurotransmitter and it it does some
harmful things what it does is it causes
calcium to go into the cell
which kills the additional cells and
makes makes the stroke worse it's called
reperfusion injury and that was my job
as a heart surgeon to prevent
reperfusion injury and when I read this
patent the first time it it had some
information in it that really changed my
life as a heart surgeon it and it says
in
here that uh CBD and THC I'm
paraphrasing is uh uh can be used for
Alzheimer's disease Parkinson's disease
Down syndrome
HIV M cardio infarction or treatment and
prevention of
interoperative or
peroperative hypoxic insults that can
leave permanent Strokes
basically uh and
following open heart surgery requiring
heart lung body bypass machines such as
coronary artery bypass graphs cabbage so
I read this back right after 2003 and I
knew wow man this is like a miracle and
I couldn't tell any of my fellow doctors
about this because it was out me as uh
somebody that was promoting the Cannabis
science and so I really I was afraid to
even share this with other doctors
because it would affect my
income and
so um maybe your freedom too
yeah and um so this information is
actually hidden in the literature
because this scientific uh literature
basically requires you to have a
biochemistry uh degree so you can
interpret the gibberish that is in this
patent so 90% of the people that would
read this pattern wouldn't know what
they read unless they uh were told what
to look for uh and so that's what we're
here for we're here to interpret
scientific jargon into easily consumable
language that most people can understand
and once they get educated in this
hidden information they're going to be
able to affect the world in a way that
will make this even more
widespread
so
uh so that's what our goal here is is to
to spread the information that's hidden
in the scientific jargon and make it
easily consumable so you can tell your
doctor about this and I can bet anybody
that's watching this if you ask your
doctor or heart surgeon if they know
about this cannabis patent cannaboids as
antioxidants and neuro protections they
won't have any
idea uh about its ex
existence and uh so you will be able to
teach your doctors about this and this
will change
society agreed so to do a quick short
breakdown on the things that Dr David
Allen just broke down down from this
patent you've got the antioxidant
properties which cannaboids have been
identified as having antioxidant
properties independent of nmda receptor
antagonisms making them potentially
useful in treating a variety of
oxidation Associated diseases we have
neuroprotective applications which is
the patent specifically notes which Dr
David Allen just spoke about the
potential of cannaboids and limiting
neurological damage post ischemic events
like stroke and intreatment
neurodegenerative diseases such as
alzheim Parkinson's and HIV dementia
then you've got the non psychoactive
cannabinoids which emphasizes the use of
non- psychoactive cannabinoids like CBD
for their benefits without the
psychoactive effects that come with high
doses of THC thus avoiding toxicity
issues and then finally the research uh
and potential you know this document
includes data from experiments showing
that cannabinoids like CBD can act as
potent antioxidants with some efficacy
Superior to traditional antioxidants
like ascorbate or Alpha talker all uh in
certain context so is that kind of a
good breakdown on what we're saying
that's exactly right and so uh and CBD
this this patent proves that CBD is safe
in large doses extremely large doses
even if you give it
chronically it doesn't have any side
effects to it yeah and if you didn't
miss the major hypocrisy of this being
the US government the patent stands out
because it acknowledges the medical
potential of cannabis compounds while
the plant itself remains classified
under restrictive legal categories in
many many regions it's federally illegal
almost throughout the entire United
States except maybe in elv musa's uh
living room yeah that's that's exactly
right
so there it is
thanks everyone for tuning in for our
first episode of the Cannabis Journal
Club we'll get a little smoother as we
go along we'll figure out how Dr David
and I are going to bounce off one
another and uh we're going to continue
to bring you great information like this
if you have information that you want us
to cover you can reach out to me at BC
bubbleman
icloud.com and please if you haven't
already join to be a member for the
Cannabis Journal Club we're going to be
doing question and answers and we're
going to be doing shows at least weekly
uh thank you everyone for tuning in and
uh thank you Dr David Allen for sharing
your wisdom with us today my pleasure
bye for now