per hey welcome everybody to the
Cannabis Journal club with Dr David
Allen and BC bubbleman uh the Cannabis
Journal Club is where we review and
interpret United States cannabis patents
and scientific journals with concise
overviews of complex scientific
literature in an understandable and easy
to consume manner to explain the
knowledge hidden within the scientific
literature we do not claim any medical
utility but we do advise you to obtain
your own copies of these public
documents and share them with your
doctors and your family so without
further Ado I will introduce Dr Allen
welcome thank
you hi I'm Dr David Allen and this is
cannabis Journal club and we're gonna
throw you a little bit of a curve today
normally we just talk about cannabis
science but today we're going to talk
about God so what does God say about
marijuana
so on the first first page of the Bible
Genesis 1 129 it
says and God said behold I have given
you every green
herb which is upon the face of all the
Earth and every tree bearing seed and
for you it shall be for
meat so God wants us to eat
herbs now Romans 14:2
says some May eat all
things others who are weak eat
herbs and Romans 14:3 says let those
that eat herbs not despise those that
don't and let those that don't eat herbs
not judge those that
do so in the King James Bible it says
it's wrong for man to judge people using
herbs and and uh in Exodus
30:23 you can find
the recipe
for God's holy anointing
oil and uh you will be surprised that
that cannabis was part of God's holy
anointing oil in the King James version
it says sweet calamus but the Hebrews
call it
cannaboss and so that's cannabis
and that's in God's holy anointing oil
you should check it out and show other
people
so we hope God is happy with with making
us
and we hope God helps us spread this
information so thank you this is
cannabis Journal
Club thanks for watching everyone we'll
tune in again soon peace out