Hey everybody, welcome back to the
Cannabis Journal Club where we review
and interpret United States cannabis
patents and scientific journals with
concise overview of complex scientific
literature in an understandable and easy
to consume manner to expose the
knowledge hidden in the scientific
literature. We do not claim any medical
utility and of these government patents
or scientific articles. We advise you to
obtain your own copy of these public
documents. We will also make them
available when we can through the
description in the description of this
video. Uh, I'd like to introduce Dr.
David Allen and we're going to get into
today's show. Dr.
Allen, you're you're good to go, Dr.
Allen.
Okay. Thank you, Marcus. Hi, I'm Dr.
David Allen. and I'm a retired
cardiovascular and thoracic surgeon and
I'm self-taught in the science of the
endocanamonoid signaling
system. And today we're going to review
my original article
uh entitled Ignorance is not bliss. You
can get a copy of this article by
looking up cannabis digest and Ignorance
is not bliss.
And what happened was I I was trained in
cardiovascular surgery, but my career
quit me in Mississippi. And so I
obtained
a medical license in California and I
moved to Sacramento and started a
cannabis practice in
Sacramento. And I thought to myself,
well, I've not been taught about this
science and I had to train myself in it.
and I can't be alone in this. So I
thought I need to figure out what
colleges universities are teaching in
the science. And so uh myself and my
three employees
uh called 157 medical schools in the
United States. And the study was only
for the United States and it should be
repeated in other countries and should
also include veterary medicine schools
as well. And so in the summer of
2013, we called 157 medical schools and
asked the directors of the
curriculum three questions.
Do you have a department of
endocanabonoid science with a director?
Are you teaching the ECS as an organized
course or is it even mentioned in any
ancillary courses like pharmarmacology
uh pathophysiology
neuroanatomy and the answer was only 13%
of American
universities teaching physicians even
mentioned the
ECS. So this is a a science that is is
completely ignored by the medical
facilities and uh it's kind of like your
doctor not knowing the circulatory
system or
the nervous system or or any of its
other major components. And so the ECS
is a master control system that
regulates all
physiology. Um and
uh should be included in all medical
schools and
and you will find out that many times
the patients know more about this
science than the doctors do. And so my
study was was made entirely to
expose the hypocrisy of not teaching
this science to
physicians.
And so please obtain a copy of this.
It's printed in uh Cannabis Digest
uh under ignorance is not bliss.
And uh what we what we did was we we
called these
uh colleges and asked for the director
of the
curriculum and what they were teaching
uh medical students. And uh we found out
a lot of resistance to our survey. I
would call up and say, "Hi, this is Dr.
David Allen. Can I speak to the director
of the curriculum?" And they would say,
"What's this about?" And I would I would
tell them. and they they would be
astounded because many of them had no
knowledge of what what I was speaking
of. And so they were suspicious and and
were reluctant to give us any answers at
all. And so we changed our
tactics and uh when my employees would
call up, we would pretend that we were
medical students or premedical students
looking for universities to apply to
that would have a special uh knowledge
in this new
science. And so that worked pretty well.
And we started getting a lot of answers
from the medical schools and and uh the
employees of the
uh director of the curriculum. And we
found that a lot of their their
statements showed extreme ignorance of
this uh study and and like why would we
teach this kind of science? This is a
medical school. Why are you asking these
kind of
questions? And so, uh, please read the
article. It it has a lot of statements
that we collected from the medical
schools
themselves. And,
um, so
can I can I give can I give a can I give
a quick cliff notes on just what you've
said so far because you're getting into
you're you're almost at results. So what
uh this article really the sort of
cliffnotes of it is number one the
significance of the endocanam
cannabonoid signaling system um it's
considered a crucial medical discovery
likened to the advent of sterile
surgical techniques. It acts as a master
control system which of course Dr. Allen
just uh mentioned preventing disease and
combating aging by managing physiology
cellular communication and scavenging
oxygen free radicals. Then we get into
the medical potential. The ECS has vast
therapeutic potential, particularly
through cannabis, which could really
shift medicine from symptom management
to disease prevention. It's implicated
in reducing diabetes, stroke damage,
heart attack scars, heart attack scars,
and combating cancer via tumor growth
inhibition, reducing metastasis, and
induction of apoptosis, which all of
these things are keywords that you can
go punch in and learn about. Next, we've
got his survey methodology. He went to
contact the curriculum directors at 157
US medical schools asking about the ECS
department organized courses or mentions
in related classes and
immediately receives initial resistance
which led them to posing as prospective
students to gather responses more
effectively. The fact that they even had
to do this and then next resistance and
ignorance. Responses ranged from how do
you spell
endocanabonoid to dismiss? We don't
teach anything like that. Many schools
showed unawareness or reluctance which
sometimes questioning with some
questioning the surveys intent. Now
we're getting into the results and I'll
let Dr. Allen continue.
So our our survey study uh proved that
only 13% of American medical schools
even mention this
uh science and nobody has organized
courses. There's no directors or
departments of this science.
And so
uh one mistake that I made is after we
did completed the study, we mailed
copies of the studies to the directors
of the
curriculum, which didn't have the effect
I wanted it to have. I should have uh
mailed the the copies of this article to
the dean of the medical school which
would have more impetus in changing the
curriculum to include this in their
future
uh studies.
So
um this is exposing the ignorance of the
medical school which is which was caused
no doubt from the drug
war. So the drug war is trying to
suppress this science and
so my entire life has been to try to
expose the medical efficacy of cannabis.
And it's it's fairly hard to do because
uh there's no place that you can
actually
uh publish studies anymore regarding
this. So this study needs to be repeated
uh in Canada, in South America and in
Europe and should include
uh veterary medical schools and my
suspicion is the veterary medical
schools will have more knowledge
uh and and they will be teaching this
this science more so than than the human
medical schools. due to the political
repression basically. Exactly. Yeah.
Which the article argues these political
barriers, not scientific merit. So we're
getting into this dangerous thing where
it's like something other than
scientific merit is being responsible
for the restriction of the ECS and
cannabis research. Obviously, the
government's classification of cannabis
as a schedule one drug creates a catch
22 which limits studying that could
prove its safety and efficacy. So, how
about some positive exceptions from the
article?
Well, a couple of schools mentioned that
they were doing some studies and
research and and uh would would include
this in in their future lectures and
stuff, but
uh so uh we're hopeful that uh that this
study that I've done and I just did this
with three employees, so this study
could be repeated and and will show that
this is a science that's worthy of
doctors and veterary medicine doctors to
learn about. And uh so that's my that's
my impetus. That's my motivation is to
have doctors learn about this so they
know more than the than the the patients
that are coming to them
uh with questions about this science. So
it's a call to action, right? The study
urges medical schools to integrate ECS
education, comparing its neglect to
historical resistance against sterile
techniques. It suggests public pressure
on deans to adopt this science. If you
want to reach out to Dr. Allen and
myself, please do so. You can reach out
to me at
bcbubblemanicloud.com. And I believe Dr.
Allen is
cali215gmail.com. Did I get that right?
Yeah.
ci215 docgmail.com.
I'd be glad to answer any questions you
have regarding this science. And uh you
know cannabis and is a neutrautical that
should be in the diet of all humans and
animals. And maybe even more important
than that, it's a metabolic
necessity and maybe even a metabolic
imperative because they proven if you
block this
ECS that sperm cannot enter the OBM. So
you need a a functioning ECS for
conception to occur. So without a proper
functioning
ECS, conception won't occur and may be
responsible for many uh uh women not
being able to full-term birth a child.
So this has great implications and
should you should put this cannabis and
hemp in your diet. And actually hemp may
be more important
uh a medical substance to be put in your
diet than even marijuana.
Yes. While breast milk contains both uh
uh endockinabonoids and essential uh
amino acids and hemp is pretty much
cannabis is the only plant that produces
all of the essential amino acids uh
including the three that children
require for organ and bone development
as well as phytoinabonoids. So it's
almost this breastlike milk substance
that cannabis produces in two of its
forms. And I'm glad you hit on the
broader implications because cannabis is
framed as a neutrautical with
antioxidant benefits, not just a
pharmaceutical. And it could potentially
revolutionize medicine towards
prevention. You know, you Dr. Allen
questions why ECS study is suppressed,
linking it to funding and political
interest, which I don't think is a very,
you know, big jump. I think it's
probably very accurate. Um, maybe we
want to finish off with some of the
historical parallels uh that your
article references.
Okay. Well, there was a a doctor in
Vienna who was an OB/GYN doctor. And
um they had two hospitals that delivered
children at in Vienna, a doctor's
hospital and a midwife's hospital. and
the doctor's hospital had a uh massive
death rate for for birthing children and
the the midwives hospital had much
better results and so Dr. Sema Wise was
uh doing an operation an autopsy on a
a woman that had died during her child
birth. And what happened was his
assistant got a they were opening the
abdomen and the abdomen was full of pus.
It's called purplal fever and was the
cause of death for many women. And so
when his assistant cut his hand two days
later he died of sepsis of the same
thing that the woman had died from. So
Dr. She knew that there was something in
the pus that caused this reaction and
killed his assistant. And so he started
uh scrubbing his hands with uh
uh caroxyic acid I believe and it was
costic and it caused people's hands to
be red and inflamed. But uh he proved
that by handwashing that they lowered
the infection rate in surgery. And so
that's this was before microscopes and
nobody knew about germs. So this was
before germ theory. And so he was
washing his hands and he was trying to
get the other doctors to wash their
hands and they all objected to it
because it wasn't
uh known science at the time. and they
actually ran him out of town because of
this. And
so just suggesting that you should wash
your hands before surgery was a new and
radical idea and was rejected by the
medical
establishment. And so today the medical
establishment is ignoring the science of
the endocanabonoid signaling system. And
so we're trying to get people to
understand that this is this is a super
important
science and we want everybody to learn
about this because it can affect you and
the family, the people in your
family. So uh please look at our other
uh studies we've published on uh
cannabis and heart attacks. showing it
that it decreases the size of a a heart
attack by
66%. Another article we reviewed proves
that it it decreases the size of a
stroke by
50%. And so this is amazing information
that could save the lives in people in
your own families if you learn about it.
And you want to know what the world did
to Dr. Ignes Semlowise? It wasn't just
the medical establishment denying and
ridiculing and mocking him for washing
his hands, if you can imagine. But in
1865, the increasingly outspoken Seml
Weiss allegedly suffered a nervous
breakdown and was committed to an asylum
by his colleagues. Now, what happened in
that asylum is he was beaten by the
guards very badly. He died 14 days later
from a gang greenish wound on his right
hand that was probably caused by the
beating. How insane is that? The guy who
brought handwashing to just save lives
ends up getting probably falsely accused
of a mental breakdown by his colleagues
cuz they loved to do that back in the
day when people stepped out of line.
Forget about destroying your life. We're
just going to put you in a mental
hospital. And then in the mental
hospital, they damn near beat him to
death. And then he ends up gangrinous.
And his hand, the very thing that he
learned to wash to reduce this type of
fever, is what kills him. It's so sick.
And it almost parallels the way Dr.
Allen was treated when he came out just
asking if they even taught about this
process. So you can see we're dealing
with a very unique group of people who
are not willing to hear uh what is being
said sometimes so much so that they'll
take it to the most extreme level. Uh
and that's what happened unfortunately
to Ignas Semawis.
That almost happened to me as well. Of
course it did. Of course it did. So
listen, the call to action is if you
think you can help, we are going to be
organizing this program again in the
near future. We're going to uh acquire a
bunch of interns, hopefully people that
are in veterinarian and in the medical
world in some way, shape or form and
we're going to kind of build a team up
and we're going to start calling these
uh hospitals again and these medical
schools. And what we'll do is we'll make
sure, I guess, that we create a really
proper template to approach them so that
they don't get the claws and the and the
fangs out. You kind of got to come at
them from the side angle like Dr. Allen
did. If you come at them too direct, uh
you could end up in a mental hospital
being beaten to
death. And that, my friends, is Cannabis
Journal Club. Anything else to add, Dr.
Allen?
Thank you so much for this uh for this
platform that we could spread this news.
Uh we want interns to help us because if
you help us do another study in Canada
or or South America, your name will go
on a paper that will be that will make
history. You could have your name on in
history by exposing that this science is
not being taught to physicians and we'll
find out if veterary medicine doctors
learn more about this than the than
their human doctor counterparts.
Awesome. So, thank you, Bubble Man.
Yeah. Well, thank you. I love doing this
project with you and I'm looking forward
to staying more consistent and releasing
at least one of these videos uh a week.
Uh and I guess for that we'll see you
all next week on the Cannabis Journal
Club. Thanks for watching. Thanks for
your support. And if you can give a
little thumbs up on the video and a
subscription, uh of course we would
appreciate that as well. Thanks
everybody.