hey everybody Welcome to the Cannabis
Journal Club just to guys give you guys
a little breakdown uh cannabis Journal
Club is where we review and interpret
United States cannabis patents and
scientific journals with concise
overviews of complex scientific
literature in an understandable and easy
to consume manner to expose the
knowledge hidden in this scientific
literature we do not claim any medical
utility and of these government patents
or scientific articles what we advise
you to do is to obtain your own copies
uh of these uh public uh documents and
we will often have them um Linked In the
description of each show that you're
watching so we'll make it very easy for
you uh to access that and then you can
share them with your doctors as well and
that's kind of what we're looking for so
I want to welcome Dr Allen to the show
he's going to drop some gems on us and
uh the floor is yours Dr Allen nice to
see you
good
morning yes I'm Dr David Allen and my
co-host here is Marcus Gary
Richardson AKA bubble man also known as
bubble man and this is budley green and
budley green says herb is
superb amen that's where we come
from beautiful I love it today we're
gonna be yeah we're gonna be talking
about a a another patent so please share
with us the number and what this patent
is uh is is going to be about today all
right thank you so right to the
point um there's two US
patents uh for cannabis and diabetes
they're both labeled the same name
treating or preventing diabetes with
cannab dial the first patent number is 8
comma 071 comma 641
the second uh patent is named the same
treating or preventing diabetes with
canabidol and it's patent number US
2000700
99987 A1 that came out in 2005 the first
one came out in
2011 and
um I don't know why they're both named
the same I think it's because uh B
basically we're reviewing uh two lab
animal
experiments and a human study with it
with this
uh with this
uh uh chapter of
uh cannabis uh Journal club and
so uh both of these patterns are by are
authored by Professor Dr Raphael mulam
and are out of of the uh University of
Jerusalem and um it's interesting that
they would have two pattern on cannabis
treating diabetes and they used the word
preventing which they kind of prove but
it also kind of alludes to a cure to
diabetes and so you'll have to read this
yourself to come up to that
conclusion um so they mentioned that in
these pattern that diabetes is the most
prevalent endocrine disease worldwide
and the mortality
morbidity uh associated with this is
unbelievable uh because a lot of people
go blind a lot of people have
amputations a lot of people have to go
on renal dialysis because of diabetes
massive cost to the health system and
the cost is
unbelievable uh and so if if we could
give you something that would help your
diabetes or help you help prevent you to
develop diabetes then uh We've helped a
lot of people so the complications to
diabetes include a bunch of
stuff um blindness heart attack Strokes
kidney failure
amputations uh and these people uh that
have to go on dialysis they have to have
multiple surgical procedures for Venus
access so they can can uh put them on
dialysis machines and then there's
paranal dialysis too so there's a lot of
surgical procedures if we can opening
them up to susceptibility of infection
too I'm guessing
absolutely so
um uh so the two experiments they did
was the first one was they were trying
to do uh transplants of uh the beta
cells of the pancreas the beta cells are
the ones that produce the insulin and
they noticed when they did transplants
that the immune system attacked the
transplants and it killed all the beta
cells and so they they studied uh uh
these transplants and they found out
that if
they uh gave the patients cannabis or
CBD that the transplant cells survived
if they didn't give CBD then Almost 100%
of them would be dead and if they did do
give them CBD about 87% of the cells
survived and so this is a
remarkable uh
finding and the second uh animal study
they did was they used these uh
specially uh raised mice they're called
mod mice and this is a strain of mice
that develop diabetes within the first
month or so of life and so they're
excellent animal model for studying
diabetes and
uh so in the in the
mice um they found out that
uh that uh they it delayed the
development of
diabetes and they have have a whole lot
of evidence and these pads are extremely
long one of the pads is like 50 pages so
it's a strain to go through this and so
we read this stuff so you don't have to
so yeahh we're getting that's really
powerful that's really powerful I mean
it's saying that 100% of untreated mod
mice develop diabetes and only 53% of
mice treated with CBD develop diabetes
that is insane that's like half the mice
didn't develop diabetes and so this is a
mouse breed to to that's develops
diabetes and if you could decrease the
the incidence of Diabetes by 53% in this
mouse
group um and this is just preliminary
stuff they really have not done this on
humans there is a human study uh called
to It's called The N haanes NH H NES and
it has a Roman numeral three behind it
so it enhs three and this is a human
study where they found that uh people
that were using
cannabis uh had a
66% decrease in the incidence of
diabetes than people that weren't using
cannabis so that's a human
study and
um
so uh they found that the lowest glucose
levels were found in the group of people
that had the highest prevalence of
marijuana
use and and nonusers had two to four
times more likely to develop diabetes as
marijuana users wow and uh this you the
use of of CBD had no was not associated
with any other diseases like uh
it didn't cause any heart failure or any
other trouble so it's safe to use in
large doses and even given chronically
so uh this is not hard evidence that
CBD stops all diabetes but it's it's
kind of a bunch of
indications that uh it can have a major
effect and more human studies will will
be done in the future I'm sure but since
CBD is so
safe and you can't hurt yourself by
taking CBD according to the science that
we know so far and so if you if you
think that
you have diabetes or getting to be where
your sugar's higher it would I would
definitely put CBD in my diet and um so
none of these studies are what happens
when you eat cannabis or eat hemp so
hemp may actually be a better medicine
than marijuana in a bunch of different
uh disease States and we don't know
which state is which uh it actually
seems that Tac and CBD work in
conjunction with each other and uh most
diseases are are helped with a
combination of these two products right
other than uh isolates but since uh CBD
doesn't get you high and you can take uh
a boatload of it and not hurt yourself
then uh really the government should be
doing studies on what is the incidence
of diabetes when you eat cannabis or eat
hemp and so that will be done in the
future and uh
so we're trying trying to give people
evidence that they can show their
doctors because if you ask your doctor
do you know about the two US
patents on cannabis or or CBD and and
diabetes they won't have any idea that
this even exist so you'll have more
information than your physician does
because they don't teach this in medical
school um and I know that because I did
the study it's called ignorance is not
Bliss it's in cannabis digest and we
called my office called 157 medical
schools and we asked them if they're
teaching the science and only 133% of
the medical schools even mentioned this
science and nobody has organized courses
and so it's very likely if you're a
student of cannabis that you may know
more medical science about this than
your Physicians and your heart surgeon
so well there's there's always this
protective component and and definitely
big shout out to uh you know Raphael
mulam uh I was going to put my picture
up with him when we originally mentioned
him so I'll put my picture up here here
I am at the icrs in Liden Holland
meeting meeting the the the man himself
and for those of you that don't know
about rafhael Mich mulam you can go down
that Rabbid ho very very cool but even
at the end of his study in conclusion
they said marijuana use was associated
with a decreased prevalence of diabetes
prospective studies on humans and
animals need to be clean to need to be
completed and they do not recommend the
use of marijuana for patients at risk
for diabetes they just did this study
that showed you could reduce it by 53%
in mice that were bred to get diabetes
yeah they're afraid to say that oh my
God and and God bless them they have to
be I get that but this is what Dr Alan
and I are trying to get past this this
confusion and this can you imagine
reading this patent and going through it
and then at the end coming and saying
they don't recommend me doing this it's
like but the patent said that it reduced
the and and I don't think people can
wrap their heads around of the
importance of these mice that were bred
to get diabetes are way more susceptable
than the human race grp population
getting diabetes some are more
susceptible some are less susceptible
but it's not like every human being gets
diabetes within a month of being born so
you got to think that that is a that
that number of 47% that didn't get it
must have been it it would be way higher
in mice that weren't bred to get
diabetes and if you guys don't know
about Dr mulam you should definitely
learn about him I believe he should be
put forth for a saint Ood because of his
work St
mulam certainly was like a saint when I
met him just the kindest kindest man uh
God he must have been 90s something
years old there when I when I met him so
really cool uh great breakdown on that
patent I'm sure we'll have a Q&amp;A
potentially towards the end of the week
where if you guys and I'm sure listen
brain tumor
and uh you know some of the other stuff
we've covered
antioxidants this diabetes one is a big
one an enormous amount of people suffer
from or know loved ones and close family
members who suffer from type 1 and two
diabetes this is very interesting
information I don't need a doctor to
tell me that I consume cannabis orally
every day I do that for the preventative
aspects that I don't even really know
100% scientifically what they are but I
know if cannabis is a part of this
endocannabinoid cannaboid signaling
system it's it's it's got to be
preventative as much as it is
medicinal all right well thank you very
much for having us today and we hope
that people can use this information for
their families so I recommend putting
cannabis in your
diet I also recommend that I'm not a
doctor but I have played one on TV isn't
that what Marcus uh what's his name used
to say I'm I'm not a doctor but I play
one on TV anyway we'll finish it with a
budley green quote and budley green says
herb is superb so thanks a lot for
watching the Cannabis Journal Club
thanks to Dr Allen for sharing his
knowledge as always and uh we'll see you
at the end of the week for the Q&amp;A yeah
peace out every remember J over evil God
over evil live it live it see you next
week all right