welcome everybody to the Cannabis
Journal club Volume Two with Dr David
Allen and bubbleman we've got a doozy
today so I'm gonna hand it over to Dr
Allen go ahead Dr David Allen good
morning this is cannabis Journal club
and we'd like to thank God for this
opportunity for us
to
provide super important information that
could save people's lives in your own
family so without further Ado we're
going to go straight
to
uh our work so we're reviewing
cannabis scientific articles and US
patents regarding cannabis and the
endocannabinoid signaling system and the
ne our next subject is uh this super
important uh patent that
we would like you to search out and
print out yourself and read it yourself
and
determine uh
whether this could help you in your life
so this is not medical advice I am a
doctor but I'm not your doctor and we're
giving you information that your doctor
probably doesn't know and so you can
take these patents and show them to your
doctor and he will be shocked and
embarassed embarrassed that the medical
schools didn't teach him about this so
today we're reviewing a US patent and
it's called therapeutic uses of
cannabidiol compounds and it's US patent
number
20110 slash
one excuse me
sl01
58973 A1 and it was in June 24th 2010
again so that's 201
97381 and here
is here is this patent and that there's
the name I don't know if you can read
that or not but and here's the patent
number and I showed it as well I shared
it on the screen so yeah and
um one of Dr Allen's dictums is never
believe any anything the government says
so even government patents are under
question but they are The Keeper of the
truth because you can't lie and get a
patent number so we want you to download
these these patents yourself and
determine if this has any application in
your life and so
um the most important part about this
patn was it it proves that it decreases
the size of a heart attack by 66%
now people can review this article and
they can claim well maybe it's not 66%
maybe it's 60% or some other
number and then criticize how they did
this study but what you can't argue with
is your eyes and so in this pattern they
have these strange
photographs I can share it you don't
have to show it I'll share it let me
share it on the screen there you go it's
got the uh no CBD treated with CBD go
ahead so this is proof positive that
cannabis decreases the size of a heart
attack and your eyes can tell
you uh when you look at this Photograph
the white area is dead heart tissue that
doesn't take up dye and therefore it's
white and the live heart muscle takes up
the dye and it's covered is colored in
black and so you can see the difference
in these two hearts the one on the top
is one that's not protected with CBD and
the one on the bottom is one that's
protected with CBD and what they did was
they took animals and they gave them CBD
um and they liated the front side artery
of their heart the L left anterior
desending artery and it's it's a real
super important artery and when they cut
the blood supply to this artery causes a
heart attack and they sectioned the
animals after the heart attack and
determined that if they had CBD it
decreased the size of a a heart attack
and this was also uh verified by enzymes
the uh people that the the animals that
didn't have uh CBD had higher cardiac
enzymes indicating a more massive heart
attack and so this patent proves several
things it proves actually that it
decreases AOS scerotic plaque by about
50% and changes your blood it lipid
profile it improves your blood lipid
profiles and so I'm sure no if you're an
cannabis activist not one of your
activist friends have ever told you this
no doctor ever told you this and so now
you have information that your doctor
does not have and it and CBD decreases
the uh incidence of plaque formation by
50% and uh it says here that CBD
provides a novel safe and effective
treatment for various cardiovascular
considerations with fewer side effects
than traditional therapies so this works
better than anything we have currently
they used to treat heart attacks with
with steroids but it was found that the
steroids interfered with uh the healing
process so they've abandoned using
steroids for this but it's a complete
sin that there's not
been human trials in this
uh because 50% reduction inside of a
heart 66% reduction in size of a heart
attack is the difference between life
and death and so
you could learn from this and save
people's lives in your own family and so
that's why we're doing this and we hope
that uh we can get people to help us
spread this
news um in this patent it uh it
mentions that
CBD might be
incorporated in coronary
stance to prevent in instant restenosis
or failure of the coronary stance with
CBD
so uh now human Studies have not been
been done on this and and you wouldn't
want somebody's heart to be sectioned
after a heart attack just to prove this
so more animal studies need to be done
and clinical studies proving uh cbd's
efficacy in strokes and heart attacks
our last
uh article that we reviewed was
cannaboid uh cannaboids as antioxidants
and neuroprotectants and
that uh patent proves that it decreases
the size of a stroke by 50% but this
patent proves it decreases the size of a
heart attack by
66% there so there's a
commonality CBD helps in both strokes
and heart attacks and and probably a
bunch of other diseases
that are not even known yet so uh we
want you to print this out and learn for
yourself and teach your family members
and your doctors and anybody you know
about this amazing evidence that
cannabis cannabis compounds does provide
medical utility and which means it
should not be schedule one which means
no medical utility and not safe under
doctor supervision so that
photo should have ended the drug war
because it proves that at least one
compound CBD and there's proof that CBD
and THC both provide this kind of
medical efficacy and it's not because of
either one of these compounds binding
onto the CB1 receptor it's due to other
mechanisms other than locking onto the
CB1 receptor
so um right the patent the patent
suggests that cbd's cardioprotective
effects may be mediated through several
mechanisms so you
mentioned uh its ability to treat heart
scars uh and part of the broader
potential for treating various
cardiovascular conditions and you also
included uh the Improvement of blood
lipid profiles
um can you mention a little bit more of
some of the um mechanisms that CBD can
offer cardioprotective effects like its
anti-inflammatory interaction with
adenos Etc well all of this is not
delineated perfectly because basically
it's illegal to study anything about
cannabis because as a doctor you can't
give cannabis to a patient it's illegal
and so they don't allow any medical
studies because of this and
so we need medical studies and maybe one
person that's watching this can show
this photograph of the difference in
heart attacks to their doctor or to A
legislature and and prove that CBD this
this is not just
a a crazy story about cannabis working
this is proof but government proof that
cannabis has Medical utility and so we
want other people to learn about this
and other patterns we're going to
review
and uh we
want God's help we want ja over evil
live it yes we do over evil live it I
love it so unlike THC CBD does not bind
significantly to CB1 and CB2 receptors
which avoid voids the psychotropic
effects while still providing
therapeutic benefits I can see patients
having an appreciation for that
especially with all the propaganda about
cannabis I've seen a lot of people who
are interested in using cannabis
medically be terrified to use cannabis
medicinally from the Decades of
propaganda that they've been fed uh so
this is all part of kind of breaking
through that um the patent proposes uh
using CBD to prepare pharmaceutical
composition positions for treating and
preventing heart scars for improving
blood plasma lipid profiles uh for
reducing atherosclerosis plaque load and
enhancing overall cardiac function so
it's a pretty incredible patent it
really does all go down to that photo uh
that we showed earlier with the uh
Hearts uh tissue scarring with out CBD
versus the scarring with CBD you don't
have to be a doctor to look at the
picture and see that it's an absolutely
mindbending difference yeah it's
profoundly different so um yeah very
exciting um we will be it's the
difference between life and death of
your
grandma right it's so profound we can't
really explain how profound it is to be
able to reduce a heart attack even by
50% 40% 30% let alone 60 plus perc
that's getting into a very high range
almost 70% % that they mentioned in this
uh in this uh
patent very interesting anything else Dr
Allen well
uh we need help in this we're trying to
spread this scientific knowledge you can
help us in this and if you want to join
our army and if you have special skills
that can help us with audiovisual stuff
we would like your input and maybe you
can help us in spreading this super
important
uh information and you know I wasn't
always an activist I was a heart surgeon
and I've saved hundreds of people's
lives doing cardiac
surgery and I knew about this these
patents years ago but it couldn't speak
to it speak about it to any
colleagues uh because it would affect my
income and so
uh we're trying to I I knew this
information but couldn't even talk about
it and and that's part of the
propaganda and if you and and now I know
when I look on the internet now for
these same patents that I've had in my
in my possession for for 10 or 15 years
and now they're hard to find on the
internet Because the Internet is trying
to there's groups of people that are
collecting scientific articles on
cannabis and patents and stuff and
they're actually hiding it on the
internet and the fact that you've never
heard of this is proof positive that
that the drug war is affecting the
knowledge of medical utility because
that goes against schedule one and they
they're trying to keep it cannabis
illegal for for the rest of their lives
and so that's an evil purpose and jaw
over
evil jaw over evil I was telling Dr
Allen about ja over evil recently my
friends from Jamaica the gentleman Joe
who passed away at a young age from a
brain aneurism uh interestingly enough
and all the younger artists kabaka
pyramid and and chronics and this whole
group of of artists that were under Joe
they all sort of paid homage to him
through the J o e j over evil and so
whenever we say J over evil that is what
that means uh appreciate your time as
always Dr Allen we're happy to continue
to pump these uh episodes out and uh
thank you for the people who have
supported with membership we are still
allowing non-members to view but we
really do appreciate the people who have
uh signed up so far for the membership
for the Cannabis Journal club and we're
going to keep trying to uh you know pump
out at at least one or two of these a
week for you guys so may uh just keep
watching bubbleman's World on YouTube uh
and we will be back very soon with
another episode of the Cannabis Journal
Club thanks so much for your time Dr
Allen uh always uh educational and
always uh uh heartwarming so thank you
for
that I'm so appreciative to be on this
and allow me to to spread this
critically important
scientific education so thank you so
much absolutely I appr thanks for
watching thanks for watching everybody
we will see you uh hopefully within the
week ciao for now yeah CIA