[Music]
hey guys welcome back to Bubble Man's
World um today we're going to go over
part two of cleaning that sift not sure
if you remembered I cleaned this guy out
a little bit the other day it was really
really nasty it was uh covered in this
stuff here not sure what exactly this is
but it's not hash it looks quite a bit
like what you would pull out of a carpet
with one of those carpet rakes from the
70s but uh yeah
so this is not really sift that I would
normally clean but because I did part
one I wanted to share part two with you
guys so
I've got my screen set up and I've got
my cards for carding I've got my little
brush for brushing away the resin once
I've carded and cleaned it there's
usually a little bit left over on the
screen that I need to get away and it
doesn't really card up you need to
actually have the brush to to clean it
off you can use your uh wind you can
literally blow on it and it'll it'll
clear the screen as well so I've got a
little bit of resin in here you've seen
this before where I give it a little
shake and it falls little rain little
rain
so we'll just get a little bit there
I've got a variety of cards I've got a
couple of uh um paper cards that are
obviously a lot less uh sturdy and
strong than uh like a hotel entrance
card grabb this one out of Toronto the
last time we were there um so this is a
quite a strong plastic card and it's the
one that I'm going to choose to use
today so basically this is the thing to
watch this is the process and because
it's such a slow process
it's it's hard for people to figure out
how to do
it you know you want to push this
resin through the screen and it's
actually going quite
nice because there's such a small amount
of heads uh most of the contaminant will
of course push through the
screen and this is slow work you know
not not the slowest slowest work but
it's definitely fairly slow work work
what I like to do is I like to create a
pile get it all into a pile so it's
together and then I like to card it nice
and slow and hard over the screen
keeping sure that you clean the card
always this is once again lowquality
resin so it's not coming up on me I'm
not worried about that but say this was
Mass from the great Gardener uh that
barb is a very very tricky resin and
you've got to be very careful when you
card it in fact I could almost guarantee
that I would not be able to card the
Barb in this temperature right now uh I
usually have to go and do it in a in a
colder environment so you can see I've
carted quite a bit of that resin through
the screen just even in the couple of
minutes that I've been talking here and
that's because there's very few heads in
this
material
so we just add a little bit
more
all right and this is the slow process
this is the slow process of taking that
resin you can see I got a nice little
pile
here
right a nice little pile of
resin and in about 5 minutes of cing
I'll turn that nice little pile of resin
actually let me move that for you so the
light's shining down on it you see it a
little better without the
shadow move that shadow out
too all right give give a nice better
view of the screen so people often ask
do I need the big screen what I say to
them is the more surface area the better
you see how with just that tiny little
bit of resin I just covered a huge chunk
of the screen so this isn't an
impossible uh you don't need the the the
the tiniest piece of screen to do your
work it's nice to have room and that's
why often people think that these
screens are only uh for an industrial or
a huge grower not so if you have three
or four grams of dry SI to clean you can
do it over these screens quite
efficiently all right so you can see we
got some hairs in here a little bit of
contamination sometimes you'll also uh
realize as you're working that there's
parts of the screen that will stay
cleaner than other parts of the screen
and what I mean by that is generally we
work in the middle of the Stream so
you're going to have the majority of
your resin is going to get trapped in
this section of screen sometimes when
I'm carting and I'm finding that it's
not really um
picking keeping the heads on top it's
not really pushing everything through
it's keeping everything on top I'll take
everything over to the corner and I'll
get into this sort of you can hear how
it's a different
sound that's because these corners of
the screens are notoriously much cleaner
than the center because I'm always is
working on the
center now if your resin isn't super
super
sticky you'll be able to card it much
the way I'm doing right now now if
you're dealing with some extremely
high-end
resin you're going to cause yourself
problems first of all you got to card
softer one of the things to look for and
this is a really important tip while
you're carding if you can see right now
I have a nice nice clean um resin bed
I've laid down on top of the screen it
allows me to find my
contaminant much easier by bringing it
to the surface like these little
hairs and it also allows me to look for
grooves now when you're carting as the
resin uh heats up it's going to want to
melt to your card and it creates these
little balls of resin and those little
balls of resin will create create little
Pathways in your resin as you're cing if
you're cing and you don't see these
smooth lines but you see instead
Pathways in them almost like little
roadways you need to lift up your card
and you need to clean it with your
fingers and those bits that you clean
need to go into the corner you do not
want those bits going back into your
resin it will make it literally
impossible to clean the rest of the
resin so keep that from happening keep
your card
clean and uh yeah I mean really I've got
a good I bet you I'll have another hour
before I push all this [ __ ] through this
screen so I'm not going to record the
whole thing but I'll come back uh here
and there as I'm getting down on the bag
and uh getting the resin piles a little
bit higher I do have um a pile of just
pure heads well it's probably not just
pure heads but it's pure as it's going
to be with this particular stuff and
I'll macro that for you guys just
dropped a little pile of it as you can
see I'm hugely worried about it um so
yeah we'll end up with the heads on top
we'll end up with some swaggle
underneath and I'll come back and I'll
show you guys uh the piles and I'll show
you maybe another little clip or two of
just this process of caring and if you
guys have any questions please ask me so
I can you know I want this to be as
simple as possible you need to apply
pressure different L depending on the
resin it's much like water hash when
you're wicking out moisture at the end
right before you're getting ready to se
or microplane those are the subtle
nuances that give people difficulties
those are the things that make people
want to ask questions how do I do this
how do I do that they're the
unknowns because they change Always you
can try to be ready for them but you
just never know it's based on the
quality of your resin and once you
purify resin depending on its quality
it's going to act a little bit
differently so I think I've given you
most of what I need to tell you today
I'm going to continue on here and carve
this
resin and uh yeah you can see already if
you guys want to have a quick little
Gander that I've
already pushed quite a bit through you
see the
pile let me do the one arm here um you
can see the pile H right here so it's an
enormous amount of of contaminant that's
uh that's in this material like I said
maybe
90% it's got nasty hairs on it it's you
know I'm sure someone somewhere thinks
this is great but
uh I assure you it's not so we'll get to
uh we'll get to cleaning uh a lot more
of this powder out I've already been at
it for quite quite a while and uh I'm
going to be at it for quite a while more
so get that back on
[Music]
there well thanks for watching Bubble
man's world and we are going to be back
in a little bit here just going to do a
little bit more cleaning come back and
show you what I've done take some macro
photos and we'll be done part two sorry
it wasn't a higher grade resin but you
know what I'm thinking I'm showing
everyone the highest grade resins and
the cleanest that you can get them and
I'm thinking that we need to start a
little bit more at the foundation at the
base of of the audience of everyone cuz
we don't all start with the best
material so why not go over something
that's a little bit less than uh you
know awesome and uh show how we can get
it a little closer to something
something really nice worst case
scenario once I've cleaned this out if
it's still unsm smokable and has a
terrible taste um we'll do a coconut oil
extraction and we'll get that resin
we'll get those cannaboids into a system
and we'll make them we'll make them
worthwhile so right on
hey guys welcome back I have got my
clean
piles I don't want to turn them too much
but basically this guy right here in the
corner he's the sort of almost the
darker one but that one is the
first right here is the first this is
the second piled into one
pile
and last but certainly not least often
you'll have a little bit of resin on
your screen still so rather than lose
that that
just brush it
off very good idea to clean your
screens I'll also take this one outside
and I'll bang It On The Ground that'll
loosen anything that's sort of stuck in
there and I guess what we're going to do
is go into the original bag I usually go
into the original bag that I was given
the product with with the
swaggles and you can see we have no
shortage of
swaggles so this is the majority of what
that sift
was my nose is so itchy from having it
in the air I wish literally everything
in my office is covered in resin right
now my my crop is covered in resin my
desk is covered in resin I
mean
resin all right
so hey you're always going to end up
with most unfortunately I mean unless
I'm cleaning someone like Matt from a
great Gardener who's got a really nice
percentage of heads generally in his
sift I can get he he usually gives it to
me and it's already
50% heads I would say this was less than
5% heads potentially the lowest head
content I've ever seen but we could be
wrong I'll uh I'll give it a little way
out and we'll see exactly what we're
saying so at the end here this is one I
usually get the the brush really
working it's never going to pick up as
nice as a card or sorry a a card is
never going to pick up as nice as a a
brush the brush just basically gets
every drop of resin off the car off the
cardboard so and of course you can use
anything you want I use cardboard
because this is swag and I don't care
about it um if you want to use glass or
you want to use a plexiglass or you're
welcome to catch your catch with
whatever you like glass is really nice
nice it tends to be heavy and it tends
to break so you got to be careful with
that I like to carry my screens around I
like to take these screens with me when
I go on trips you guys have SE me
traveling through the airport with this
thing I always take it with me so we are
left with a bag of talcum
powder almost the original
size and we are left
with our couple of piles here so I'll do
a little macro photography show you what
we got here in each pile it's not going
to be super impressive but I want to
show you guys and let you know what we
are dealing with and what we have to
work with I might even take a dab I do
have resin all over me which is uh you
know it's something that the bubble man
deals with on a regular basis covered in
resin all right so I guess what we're
really what's left to do is have a bong
rip so I've got some of my fresh frozen
Astro Boy right here ready to go
so stoked on this fresh frozen Astro Boy
that I grew with my uh my med1 actually
a lot of people have been asking me
about med1 it's uh it's what I've been
growing with um you can get it through
um Green Planet they've got it sorted
out I'm going to have it on my website
soon because so many people are asking
me and I I've always liked selling
things that I believe in it just it just
makes good sense to me and a lot of
people ask me what I'm using so there it
is I'm using medic one and uh yeah good
old Green Planet here we
go well thanks for watching Bubble man's
world I hope these tips have helped you
guys out I didn't show a lot of the cing
because the cing is boring and it's a
simple process you need to be not
carting like
this okay but cing like
this you want to bend that card down and
you want to use some of the surface area
on the card to push those contaminants
through the screen it's going to be a
lot easier when you have a lowgrade
material and you just see everything
disappear through the screen it's not
really what you want to see you want to
see some things bouncing around and you
want to see that resin going from
almost like a fibrous planty material to
a grainy Sandy material and once you get
those fibers and those capitate stocks
and cyi hairs that cellulose material
once you break that through the screen
you're going to be left on top with
these these almost little Stone ball
rock type things and those are the
glandular triome heads and you'll see
that when you get your Purity up above
80 and
90% that pile will change drastically
even to the naked eye of the trained
hash maker okay so here we have uh quite
a few piles you know more than normal um
remember all of them combined were what
the sift was I first showed you in part
one cleaning out this
crazy carpet likee
material that is I don't even think
capitate stocks or cyith hairs I think
it's another typee type of hair that is
non cannabis that has contaminated this
guy's batch I have no idea what kind of
hair it is I've looked at it under the
microscope it's beyond strange anyway
after that what I did was I pushed
everything
through about a 100 Micron screen and I
ended up with um well it was the 107 it
was a it was 107 so I ended up with this
on the bottom this was the bottom tray
so this is the bunk or it was the bunk
and then I ended up with these on top
these are the same grade these are like
microns then I put everything on top of
a 70 uh Micron screen and I got this so
this is about as clean as I could get it
it still has little hairs and tiny
little pieces of contaminant that just
seemingly were impossible to clean out
um I haven't dabbed it uh per se but uh
it's not really acting usually when I do
this with say mats the whole thing would
pick up it wouldn't break like this it
would be already um stuck together and
same with uh uh this one over
here uh there we go so there's all the
piles you can do this with your um twoos
screen kit and you'll be left with these
piles and this pile all together uh you
can do it with your four screens uh kits
that I sell the wooden kits I used one
of the wooden frames uh just to run it
through super fast this this was made
like really quickly uh this one was the
one that took all the time so there it
is your
grades the
worst the second
best the
best thanks for watching Bubble man's
world
[Music]
m