[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
today we're going to do a coconut oil
extraction I had planned on using um the
Cannabis leftovers from my wet washing
which I still plan on doing um but what
I'm going to do today is we're going to
run um a couple of grams of some
beautiful Barbara dry sift and a couple
of grams of some full melt OG cush
bubble hash uh so I've basically pulled
off the recipe from one of the websites
it's real simple we've got our crockpot
we've got our two cups of water we've
got our organic coconut
oil we have our hash
a spoon and one cup to measure out the
coconut oil so basically um what it's
saying we want to do is um put a put a a
cup of coconut oil into the crock pot so
that's the
start and I guess we'll turn it on low
once we do that just move this over
here all right so lift up the [ __ ]
prop crock poot
lid get some of this yummy coconut oil
out oh look at that it went right into
where it needs to go
bonus because that would have been a bit
messy this is a little bit melted not
completely uh as solid as I've seen it
get so it's probably not going to take
too long
to to melt in the crock pot and so
because coconut is such a great fat uh
100% almost fat um what it does is it
does an incredible efficient job job
it's literally like the efficiency of
water extraction for pulling out resin
with water and ice this is the
equivalent with the coconut and it's my
preferred oil to work with I find it to
be the healthier of most uh it's one
that doesn't get affected too negatively
once you when you heat it up and just
generally coconut oil is awesome who
doesn't love coconut oil so we'll get
that into the crock
pot
[Music]
I had a tiny little bit of extra in
there so it would uh the little bit I
lost in the cup
piece will be um not too
detrimental coconut oil got to love it
so we get that on the in the crock
pot we turn the crock poot
on this is an old crock poot I borrowed
from a friend of mine it's probably from
the 70s which is also kind of
cool um so yeah we're going to uh we
turn that on low actually why turn it on
high when you can turn it on low so
that's important and they're asking to
use dried uh
material um plant matter I'm personally
using bubble and sift so we'll put that
in direct after that um once the um
coconut oil has melted we're going to
put the resin into the coconut oil mix
it up a little bit get it get it
somewhat melted and
then then they want us to add many cups
of AR water so yeah 5 to six cups of
water and like I said you don't have to
worry about the water um not all boiling
out because what's going to happen is
that water when we freeze this whole
thing at the end the oil and the water
separate and usually you can just
puncture a hole through the top and drip
out the water so we're going to show all
this whole process so we've got our
coconut oil on
low simmering away
here and uh yeah I guess what I'll do is
I'll come back once the coconut oil is
liquefied and we will put in the hash
we'll watch that melt and and dissipate
and then we will add our water and at
that point it's just a matter of
flicking it on to high closing the lid
and pretty much leaving it for about 6
hours so I hope this uh is going to
teach you guys something that you didn't
know before and uh we'll get back to it
pretty soon here see you in a
bit all right the coconut oil has
liquefied there's one little bump left
we'll wait for
that there's our Barber dry sift and our
bubble
[Music]
hash
all right welcome back guys we've got
our coconut oil turned into a nice
liquid on the crock pot on low took
about 40 minutes um and now we're going
to I thought about how I was going to do
this um you know a lot of the recipes
call for cheesecloth a lot of the
recipes are using plant matter cannabis
leaf stock trim Etc um I'm using
Straight hash I called my good buddy
d420 K who's already done a little bit
of this with herb as well sift and he
said the sift just melted so beautifully
as he dropped it into the crock pot I'm
hoping I can get a similar uh effect
with uh the hash that I've got here
breaking up the bubble uh a little bit
smaller it's in kind of turd size pieces
right now like a a a mouse turd type of
thing just trying to break it up a
little bit nicer it is melty and it
should literally you know there's very
little to any plant matter whatsoever in
this hash uh it's just pretty much
glandular heads
so I think it's going to melt quite
nicely in the
oil and that's what the filters are for
if not I've got a 25 micron uh bubble
bag that I'll be filtering all of this
through to capture any wax membranes or
small amounts of plant matter that
somehow make it into the material and
we'll filter that out so for
now I
guess the recipe says to add the um
plant matter first add it up in there
and then pour the water in so that's
what we're going to
do all right
so show you guys this with the camera if
you
like okay so I'm going to take this
hash we're going to put it in here here
into this beautiful crock pot with
coconut oil so we'll start with the
sift all right so there's the
sift and now we will throw the rest in I
got my pressing screen
here little piece of bubbl stuck there
little bit of sift on
there a little there we go and there is
our product inside the
oil so I guess we could stir that around
a little
bit I'll get a spoon and I'll stir that
around a little bit and then um we will
add the water and we will steep for
about o I want to
say 6 to 8 hours that's this is going to
be going for so I'm going to go get a
spoon give this a little bit of a mix um
we'll add our water in r o or distilled
water and we'll let this steep for the
next 6 to 8 hours and we'll see what
we've got going on okay see you in a
bit all
right
so four G of hash really really clean
hash like pure as pure can
be in the crock
pot and we'll turn that on to
high and we will also add our
water
[Music]
okay all right so we've got our water
we've got our coconut oil melted down
we've got our sift and bubble um melting
into the coconut oil we've added that
couple of cups of water um you can use
four to five cups of water depending on
how long you're going to be steeping for
uh I've put in a couple for now and we
we will probably put in a couple of more
Let It steep for 6 to 8 hours we're
going to open this up and we're going to
show you what we got so stay tuned hey
guys so the crock pot's just been
simmering for a couple of hours now I
haven't opened it yet uh I'm going to
open it and give it a little bit of a
stir just for the sedentary uh bubble
hash and sift that's still sitting there
um if you're using cannabis uh it's good
to definitely stir once every hour or so
but you don't have to to each their own
I'm not saying one way is better than
the other this is the first time I've
ever done it so I'm just going to lift
this up
gently give that coconut oil a
stir oh
yeah that felt right a lot of the
material that was in there just
dissolved right away so I'm going to let
this steep for a couple more hours we'll
come back and stir it and after that I
believe we're going to freeze it up in
the fridge cool it off takes a few hours
as well and we'll uh po poke a hole
through the top
filter out the water and we'll see what
we're left with okay okay welcome back
guys we have uh reached the 4-Hour point
and it was it was going pretty good it
was actually seemingly boiling and uh I
just started doing that hopefully I
didn't take it too long but uh I'm now
going to filter through a a a bubble bag
light 25 micron bag into a glass Pyrex
dish we'll just gently pour this
extremely
hot coconut
oil into the
bag all
right just filter that
out through that
screen and see how it just comes out
it's extremely hot
still very
[Music]
warm but with the helm of this I should
be able to squeeze it all right
out very glad to have this bag helping
me with this
job this is very hot coconut oil and
water the two are mixed
together
okay
another way which I do with when I'm
making bubble is you can fill the bag up
with air from the
top and slide your hand
down use the air to
force the material
out it's not water hash so you can be a
little bit more rough with it not too
worried about the squeezing aspect just
be careful you don't touch the oil cuz
at this point it's still very warm I
didn't want to let it congeal and turn
into a hardened material cuz that would
make it really hard to go through the
screen all right
so pretty much there on that little bit
left little hair keep that out let's see
what we got in there yeah that's just
the bubble that's left in there with a
little bit of
oil have to wash that
out
okay one last good squeeze and we'll
call it a
day all right so I'm throw that back
into the crock pot um this we now let
cool and I believe it's going to be a
solid uh couple of hours that we'll be
putting it in the refrigerator for and
the water that's still left over here
will separate from the coconut oil the
the oil will be on top the water will be
on the bottom and uh we'll show that on
film what we do with that when it's done
looks
good thanks for
watching safely tucked away in the
fridge cover for any
contaminants I'll give you the proper
light
there we go right
there it's the proper
color all right so there's the coconut
oil starting to solidify on
top and you've got
the
water on the
bottom all right guys we're back um it's
a little bit later tonight it's been
about 8 hours of sitting in the fridge
and the coconut oil has hardened you can
see on the top layer there that's
coconut oil and on the bottom is the
water so simply put we're going to put a
hole in the Coconut
layer cut a little bit
out and we'll pour this water
out
oo release the little faster than I
expected but it's okay it wasn't a
nightmare the coconut oil released with
all the water almost slid right in so
now we're going to slide the coconut oil
out and onto a paper
towel um if you've used uh cannabis
material uh you'll have some plant
matter stuck in the bottom mine as clean
as can
be there it is you L clean cup of
coconut oil and you can just lightly
dampen the paper towel and this will
absorb the water from below we're left
with quite an interesting color
water I'll have to give that a shot a
little bit later on and I'll be melting
this back down and getting it into my
containers so I'll get back to you and
show you the final product in the
containers with a nice view in the
background and uh hope hopefully you've
learned something from this coconut oil
infused extraction concentrate thanks
for watching Bubble man's
world welcome back guys it is the next
day and I have um cooled the coconut oil
um extract infusion in my refrigerator
uh it was a big top piece I showed you a
picture of it um I took that piece and I
broke it down and I put it into a
smaller
container and um it didn't quite look as
nice cuz it was all just broken bits and
pieces so what I did is I actually set
it on top of my amp for my stereo and it
just it just heated it up just perfectly
enough to melt it down and create a nice
even
flow of
coconut isn't that
nice nice nice access right there
beautiful color that I got out of it
because I didn't use the um the green
plant matter although a lot of you have
asked me why the water so I want to add
the water has a few uses um it's very
helpful if you are using plant matter
green material um the water ax is a bit
of a filter for the chlorophyll and
keeps some of it from going into your
final product but what it also does is
it cools the batch down and it allows
for a slow steep without boiling over
those canabo so the water is definitely
key you don't have to use it if you
don't want to but I'm calling it key and
I'm definitely using it if you want to
get a product like what I got here and
you can sell see my color isn't too too
far off I've got a bit of a golden
almost a yellow color compared to the
white that is the coconut so not too bad
at all definitely didn't get the green
tinge that many have have gotten I'm
really happy I took uh a tiny little bit
last night and slept like a baby um
depending on how strong you make it I
would suggest if this is new to you that
you try very small amounts um just a
little finger tip you know just a a
little the tip of a knife type of thing
and sort of build up your um your
tolerance I guess you don't want to
be uh getting too high taking too much
at a time the the the real point of this
I mean if it is for you to get get
really high then you can eat a lot of it
but the real point for me and for
sharing this with you today is to get on
feeding your endoc canabo system daily
feeding it a little bit at a time not
destroying yourself not being so you
can't um do your daily day-to-day uh
things the important things that you
need to do your work and whatnot but at
the same time feeding that endoc canabo
system bringing those levels up and and
removing any uh ECS deficiency that
could be going on in your body so thanks
for watching Bubble man's world and I
hope you guys try out this coconut oil
infused idea I'd love to see it give
your replies in the video and please
subscribe subcribe if you're not
subscribed and share if you haven't
shared have a good one guys
peace