hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
sorry for such a long delay in a show
you know I still have some footage from
Jamaica and a little bit of footage from
Spain of course I managed to pull off a
couple of has churches while I was defly
Ill you can still hear it a little bit
in my throat I've barely begun to puff
and I wanted to give a shout out to our
good buddy concentrated X who I
mentioned on hash church last weekend
this is his logo right here for for
those of you that haven't seen it and he
can be found on Instagram at
concentrated X give you the actual um
his actual address so you can find him
uh I'd rather you have it accurate than
not so it is
concentrated c o n c n t r a t d e ex
and that's his Instagram account you can
check him out the GU uh given me some
really nice kick Downs in the past
beautiful cuts from uh DNA uh the
strawberry banana cut and he's got some
some God Bud that he sent to me as well
and some beautiful rosins but actually
that's not what I want to talk about I
want to talk about the latest package
that came in from concentrated X and I
wanted to photograph it but I thought it
would be really cool to show you
actually opening
it I've got uh some ice water extraction
Buble hash 120 Micron always first run
really like his packaging and the way
he's put that together there you can say
he's got DNA genetics and that is the
sour diesel uh Reser of Pata I believe
said it was one of the most unique uh
tasting sour diesels that he ever had
he's got a little bubble man on there so
big shout out to you concentrated X
we're going to open that we're going to
photograph it and we're going to smoke
it here today let everyone know how that
is and then he sent me a little God Bud
uh flour resin organic God Bud flour
rosin so that's also nice little
packaging that he's got there going
on I'm sure that uh you could probably
hit him up direct for these sorts of
things there's some
PK uh organic pink cush flower rosin
says on the back
there and then finally some bubble has
rosin so this is a05 of a gram and it's
his g mix so it says bubble has rosin
made from a bubble has mix of various of
the strains from our Gardens gmix 100%
solventless extract so he's got some
nice little packaging going on there
he's sealed it up real good and I'm
quite excited to open it up for you here
today now we will do the rosins but
really what this is all about is this
Sour Diesel bubble hash that we're going
to try out so let me get my
Dabber he's always got these nicely
sealed and I always feel kind of bad
that I have to uh break the label to to
get it open I always feel like it's uh
you know basically it always looks like
that once you've opened it I haven't
been able to open it much smoother than
that so here we go we're going to go for
that first
smell oh
damn oh wow that
is I hear what he's saying there that's
a really unique bot
okay looks like absolute fire in there
not sure if you guys can
see but uh we're going to get in there
with the macro lens in the real near
future
here man does that have a really nice
deep sort of earthy fragrance going on
in the
background that is very unique for sour
diesel all right well what I think I'm
going to do is I'm going to stop the the
recording here for a quick second do
some wonderful photographing on this bad
boy we'll come back we'll smoke it maybe
do a melt video and uh then we'll see if
we have time to hit up these Ros and so
uh we'll be right
back all right so I managed to get some
really beautiful photographs of that um
Sour Diesel and I guess really now it's
a matter of taking a nice rip of it I'm
definitely ready to do so stuff is
absolutely
beautiful so
always seems even more beautiful when
things are stashed away in half grams so
there's the hash for you guys to
see the camera's going to grab that for
you yeah yeah it's quite nice quite
nice really nice smell too we'll take a
small dab
because I'm not in a position to be
taking any huge dabs right now as much
as I'd love to just take a nice
reasonable size dab here off some pretty
darn and fresh tasty
quartz and this one's for you
concentrated X once again thank you so
much for your generosity and uh yeah you
guys can check him out on Instagram
going to fulfill this video with all the
macro photographs at the end and I guess
uh there's just one thing left to do
let's puff this
hash
hard to describe it's got a really
unique flavor to it for sure nothing
that's overly recognizable as a sour
diesel to me but what wonderful tastes
again almost reminiscent of the
strawberry banana but different quite
different in fact really nice great job
man glad that you're out there out east
taking care of business making up uh the
good water hash and the good dry sift
and uh thank you so much for your
generosity I'm uh hope everyone enjoys
this little short video and uh we'll see
you real soon here on Bubble man's
world one just Royal alongside one
[Music]
spot
yes
again highest of the highest
look at
me
red head people always ask me say why
you so humble I don't smoke Co that's
why I don't
Grumble s
me