[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and today I'm going to be reviewing a
really really great guys product uh you
probably know him from Instagram if you
checked them out at
concentrated X so that's the word
concentrated with an ex ex at the end um
I've got a wonderful variety of products
from him the guy is super on point for
his ability to choose and find uh
cultivars that have absolutely beautiful
expressions of their tpine profiles and
their cannabinoid profiles uh he's been
uh sending me stuff for a little while
here and he's got himself into some
really nice DNA genetics he's got a
beautiful cut of strawberry banana and
so he has sent me a little 120 Micron
bubble hash uh from the strawberry
banana he has sent me a little bit of
the golden Berry uh this is 120 microns
as well and then we have three different
rosins so we have the cookies and cream
dry sift rosin with kosher kush dry sift
rosin this is head stash he's written on
the thing and he gave me another one
cookies and cream Kos cush dry sift
rosin head stash and those are both
rosins and then of course here's a
bubble has uh strawberry banana rosins
so these strawberry bananas just have
the most incredible flavor profile on
them when you pull them out people their
eyebrows go up if you exhale a hit of
this people are around you asking what
is that so great job on that and then of
course he actually sent me some bud as
well so I've got some cookies and cream
here on the case this is from uh the
cultivars came from exotic genetics
right off the bat I apologize for the
darkness today um I wanted to get myself
lit up as beautiful as possible but for
whatever reason today I'm just not
having it I've got the back light on me
I hope you guys prefer the view over a
bright bubble man but uh I don't think
it'll stop us from doing a really nice
uh review video on these products and of
course I'm going to photograph up close
macro each one of these products so you
can actually see what it looks like uh
close up
we've got ourselves a little bit High
here going I think we're good get myself
up to about
5.95 boom there we go and what to start
with what to start with
well ah I say we start with the bud cuz
that's what everyone starts with I've
got a nice little vaporizer I'm going to
grab and I'll be back all right so the
vaporizer I grabbed is of course the
grasshopper um this came from Vape fiend
in London and uh yeah let's get this
happening little bit of an empty bowl to
be cleaned
out which is never a big deal with the
grasshopper it comes out so
easy get it all
out there we
go give that last little
blow make sure everything's cleared out
nicely just cuz you want that nice taste
in your rip and this is particularly
lovely
herb so we want to make sure that we
maximize it and don't have
any leftover remnants in here so for
those of you that don't know about the
Grasshopper Vaporizer this is a great
little unit really clean really easy
fits in the pocket does not look like a
vaporizer like most of these pen units
um it really looks like a pen as you can
see a little bit dark as I've mentioned
before but you can still see this is a
great little unit great little
grasshopper unit and uh we're going to
put a little butt in there we're going
to start with the concentrated X review
and really all you have to do is hear me
in a review you don't really have to see
everything what uh you will see is very
clear very bright macro photographs of
these materials as you can see right now
here's the bud that I'm about to pull
out beautiful kaix formation on this
product and uh as always just grown to
DAR near Perfection and we just stuff it
into the uh into the the vaporizer here
I don't usually hit herb this way I will
admit I'm more of a a concentrate guy I
would probably take this herb and squish
it in the sasquash Press uh but I
thought for the review that it would be
cool if I started
uh with a little Vape hit out of this
particular cookies and cream this isn't
the first time I've hit the cookies and
cream of course exotic genetics gifted
me some uh
99.9% uh dry sift from Cuban uh year and
a half ago or so when we were in Jamaica
and that was really nice I took some
pretty epic photos of it if you don't
remember uh you can check them out on my
Instagram as well as Cuban's Instagram
and so this unit is real simple you push
the button once you get a line of red
lights in the bottom there's like 10
little dots and within about 3 to 5
Seconds you'll see that it will reach
temperature those dots will turn blue as
it just turned and then I usually give
it a little bit of time and gently pull
wow really really nice flavor on that
Cookies and Cream came in really nice
and light and vaporized um good cont uh
moisture content on this Bud by no means
does it break into powder when you break
it it actually squishes and it's more
marshmallowy so that's always nice we've
got this on maximum all right let's give
it a
shot all right here we go
really nice flavor profile on both of
those
rips not sure if you guys are catching
it it's a fairly light Vapor um I'm sure
if you stuffed it more and turned up the
temperature you could get a a bigger Rip
but you know for me for vaporizers the
rip that I want I'm going to get out of
my mother's ship in the sapphire denail
dish this is more just like nice nice
tasting nice nice flavor you know give
you a little bit of a buzz
too this is also my wake and bake today
so I can tell you from three light rips
on the vaporizer it is lovely great job
as always concentrated
X concentrated evolution
craft cannabis products organically
grown hand water and trimmed naturally
sourced nutrients never sprayed with
chemicals why because quality matters
and that's one of the reasons I love to
support concentrated
X nice packaging as
well all right well me turn that guy off
I guess we need to get that Dabber out a
little bit there we go and out she
comes fairly nice little unit it's got a
real nice tight little screen laser
perforated on the inside and then it
also has a little laser screen
perforated on the inside of the uh
mouthpiece which is classic because the
last thing I want to taste is remnants
of pot coming through in my mouthpiece
when I'm hitting a vaporizer so that's a
real deal breaker for me Grasshopper
Vaporizer along with some uh cookies and
cream via exotic genetics through
concentrated X so I managed to clean the
denail all up here for the next little
part of our adventure I'm not going to
lie I'm looking pretty forward to this
get this nice and
clean oh what should we do should we go
into the rosin next because I find yeah
I find you know for me the best the best
the best
is the bubble hash that's my favorite
I've got two of them right here so why
don't we start with um well why don't we
start with the head stash cookies and
cream kosher cush dry sift
rosin as always beautiful packaging you
smell it right away with concentrated X
it doesn't take long before you open the
package and it's on point got some real
lovely looking shaty stuff right
here tiny little bubbles really show
that it's uh yeah it's it's stable you
know I can flip it off of the
parchment and uh it's a fairly stable
product right there so let us have a
little dab of it and we'll talk a little
bit about
it super clean you open up concentrated
uh excess products and there's just no
contaminant whatsoever which is always
nice to see uh as you know you're going
to be paying top quality for a product
like
this all right so let's do this dry sift
rosin from concentrated X via the
cookies and cream and the Kosher Kush on
a freshly clean Sapphire dish that I
can't tell you it's just white as white
can be really lovely I'll do some macro
rips of the bubble hash at least as for
me rosin isn't really something very
exciting it's an oil watching oil melt
into a liquid is kind of a no-brainer
but when you see a solidified chunk of
hash melting into uh and bubbling into a
liquid there's something really quite
visually stunning about that so we will
make sure that we sell uh we share those
with you so here we go grab your Dabber
if you got them grabbing it to grab the
Mother Ship let's do this 3 2
1 oh my God that was so nice that was so
light flavored I was expecting it to
really pound me but the Kosher Kush
seems to really have
Gass up that cookies and
cream very very very little product left
on the Halo dish I am just going to
quickly grab a Q-tip and we'll be right
back grab a nice handful
here wow that was really really really
nice
rosin um very very little
left over on that
rosin which is great to
see it's definitely what I like to see
anyway um you don't want to see a ton of
wax membranes or whatever it is that's
getting left behind it's nice when the
rosin uh you know boils away to almost
nothing pardon me while I catch my
breath I ran down three flights of
stairs to grab the
Q-tips all right so put the cookies in
cream and the kosher sift dry sift that
is definitely head stash these are both
the same so we'll put them over there
along or actually we'll put them up here
with the cooks boom and
boom next up some strawberry banana
rosin this is a strong
cultivar um cookies and cream Kimbo Kush
I've never found them to be
overwhelmingly strong as much as I love
the flavors and the Purity and the
beautifulness of the resin uh which is
often the case I have to to ad met with
a lot of different cultivars
particularly ones that taste incredible
Calo being a perfect
example however with this strawberry
banana it really does have oh this one's
butter oh my God it really does have
this incredibly high turpine profile
that I'm telling you when you hit it
when you taste it when you have that
flavor profile pass across your palette
uh it's unmistakable and you will
absolutely remember it in the future so
we're going to take a nice little
nice little dab of this buttered up TP
Rich strawberry banana rosin and it is
bubble has rosin for those of you
wondering jeez okay here we go
yeah I'm not sure what the THC
percentage is in this strawberry banana
but it's definitely
high with a very unique tarpine profile
as well that modulates it in this
powerful sort of way that you actually
very much
feel
instantly once again very little residue
in the um in the dish maybe a little bit
more on the strawberry banana than there
was on the dry
sifted
material always nice to make sure you
clean both sides of the dish if you get
it dirty on the outside it's easy to
wipe up boom boom boom get it
clean it's always nice to keep these
things clean cleaner we can the less we
have to clean them all right and what I
mean clean them I mean like the longterm
plugging it into my whip into a
different denail that set at a much
warmer temperature sure cuz I know
someone's going to say how do you clean
your dish bubble man how I clean my dish
is simple I unplug my whip I plug it
into my Dil that sits on top of my
dabinator and my denail sits around 1,00
to 1100° fah and uh it turns this orange
hot the the flat coil and it basically
takes about 10 to 15 minutes if you
actually are q-tipping it and keeping it
clean if you let it get crusty and
someone's hitting some nasty stuff at
too hot of a temperature and they're not
q-tipping it and it's blacking out uh
that'll probably take about an hour an
hour and a half at that temperature to
just clean right out you can usually
walk over and just blow into it uh and
it'll just clear this uh light light
colored dust that seems to dissipate to
nothing um that's of course my stash
that I'm puffing on it it may be
different for you in your stash but uh
I'm sharing my own experience with you
here today so let us move on we've hit
the two rosins the dry sift rosin and
the bubble hash rosin we've hit the bud
which was very light but tasty kind of
set the motion almost almost like uh a
little sip of orange juice before
breakfast if you will so uh we've had
the eggs we've had some toast uh let's
get into the meat and potatoes of this
breakfast which is kind of funny to say
as a vegetarian um I'm going to go for
GB as I did just hit the strawberry
banana and he's got a nice little method
that he um he seals these jars with a
sticker that goes all the way around so
you definitely want to use something
sharp that you can kind of scrape away
at the stick
er um not always the easiest to open
I'll have to admit but uh I guess in
that sense they're not opening by
accident which is always a good thing
when it comes to stash and
containers and it also really lets you
know like if you open this to look at it
you have absolutely breached the label
there's no trying to trick anyone into
thinking that you have not opened this
when it's been opened so I do appreciate
that there we go I usually just pull the
little remnants
of material uh sticker that are hanging
just so they don't end up in the
hash and uh yeah go give concentrated X
if you haven't already uh a follow on
Instagram good guy posting beautiful
photos and good information of his grow
and his compost teas
Etc uh would you look at that I'd love
to show you guys this but it's all on
the side it's all on the side
it's never fun when it does that
especially because a lot of it is Fallen
this is one of the reasons I personally
am not a huge fan of the
um parchment paper
inside um a plastic little case like
this I find that I might have just
preferred the hash to be right
into um let me put that down there just
right into the case but uh We've saved
the day nothing too uh brutal here
happen I've managed to uh get a nice
little piece out of here it looks like
it's kind of buttery so I'm going to
have to not be able to pick it up the
way I normally
do
but get a little heat happening on our
Dabber a little heat can go a long way
there we go picked up a nice chunk not
going to lie my mouth watered a tiny
little bit as I picked that
up and so this is very very valuable
stuff that you do don't want to if
you're leaving it open you don't want to
be leaving it in any situation where it
could be bumped and knocked off the
table because let me tell you grown men
will weep grown men will weep all right
let's hit this concentrated x 120 Micron
bubble
hash uh strawberry banana no golden
Berry that's right all right it's a new
flavor I haven't hit this one yet let's
give it a shot smells beautiful
interesting yeah that's a different
profile
completely has a little bit of a berry
taste going in but it's it changes into
a fuy kind of cush but then at the end
when you exhale it's got this soapy sort
of thing going on
yeah I taste that Berry on the
inhale kind of taste it on your lips a
little bit but a really interesting
middle part to this that's uh
fuy definitely melted in a very unique
way left a a quite a bit more residual
on the screen obviously being bubble
has um didn't melt right away did not
melt right away it kind of uh sat there
for a second made me think for about
half a second that maybe I unplugged the
denail and that it wasn't on anymore and
then I saw it sort of slump and start
melting usually a sign of a product that
is a little less melty than more melty
but I'll tell you the flavor and the
obviously kind of hard to describe the
high being um behind two rips of uh Ros
and dry sift and bubble hash and
vaporizer rips of kind herb obviously uh
I can describe the effects that I feel
after I hit it on top of what I've
already hit but I'm not giving an
accurate description of the potency of
these particular cultivars concentrates
uh through the wake and bake as you if
you uh you know if you did that it's
going to be substantially different than
uh hitting them all in a row the way I
do but um I'm a fi
so and perhaps I will add wake and bakes
uh just not on this particular video but
you might just see small little wake and
bake videos hit the YouTube I'll try to
do a wake and bake with each one of
these in the next couple of weeks uh and
in the meantime I guess we are down to
our last
cultivar uh the strawberry banana bubble
HH 120 this is amazing I've already
smoked like a couple of grams of it it
was just spectacular uh took some
amazing macro photographs of it which
I've already shared on Instagram and I
will share on this video and uh just
impressive you know really really nice
nice nice product uh lot of energy and
time goes into um controlling the
variables to come up with a product like
this so so my hats are off to you
concentrated X it's uh it's a lot of
work you know it's not just about
watering some plants there's a lot of
work that goes into finding these
cultivars and then growing them properly
uh etc etc it's not easy easy as you can
see because otherwise everyone would
have these products and uh clearly they
don't all right so actually let's use
this one seeing as that one's a little
hot these carb caps get hot I'll tell
you doesn't take long sitting on the
Halo dish at
580° uh before it gets fairly hot all
right here we go strawberry
banana straw
Nana this one's got the little top on it
I like that
oh she's on the side as well but that's
okay that is just such fire definitely
showing this to you guys right now look
at that oh my goodness very nice very
nice see if we can't scoop a little off
the lid
here this is sticky sticky icky very
nice very nice
it's uh like marshmallow it's got the
perfect perfect you know sticky sticky
icky you know you could put a poster up
with this stuff which I used to always
talk about you know people would ask me
or you know is this good is this good is
my bubble good and a lot of them were
doing it via the computer and so I would
ask them can you put a poster up with it
if you take four small pieces can you
put a poster on the wall that is great
hash this is a poster hash so to you
concentrated X for the last rip of this
small little review I do appreciate all
your kindness uh and I appreciate the
access that you're offering to people to
a be able to acquire this beautiful
product so keep doing you and uh here we
go what the [ __ ]
all right well it's officially a good
review man maybe even a great review
because indeed as you guys can see the
the whip somehow got unplugged a little
bit and it did turn off the denail I
don't even know what I hit that golden
Berry rip at I think I'm going to hit
the golden Berry again here but uh for
now I've got the strawberry banana
loaded up loaded it up real nice and of
course I should probably clean this Halo
dish that is uh smoking off from the
remnants of the hit that I hit at uh oh
I don't know room temperature so I
thought that was funny usually I would
edit stuff out like that but uh why I
can show you guys my failures as well as
my successes and uh it's something uh to
laugh about anyway so I thought it was
kind of funny I'm sure you were like
what the [ __ ] anyway let's do this last
rip from concentrated X take two on the
strawberry banana 120 Micron bubble has
from concentrated X here we go
oh now that's the stuff and all that's
my favorite by far of everything from
the dry sift rosin to the bud to the
bubble has Ros and the bubble hash hits
just like I guess I am biased being
bubble man and all having coined the
phrase bubble hash and uh having sold
bubble bags for the last 18 years
actually happy birthday to Fresh hedes
my company which turned 18 years old uh
back in 1999 we started that company
Three Doors Down from where I'm sitting
right
now so very cool yeah well shout us out
one more time fresh.com bubble bag.com
uh if you yourself want to go out on a
limb and uh find yourself as uh many of
us have wanting to make some hash you
can check out a variety of hashish
making tools uh over at fresh.com as
well as bubble bag.com uh from dry sift
uh mechanical screen separation we have
kits two screens and four screens
multiple sizes uh Bubble Bags uh as well
uh on the website there in all 1 Gall 5
gallon and 20 gallon sizes four bags to
eight bags and even available in lights
standards and Originals all breaking
down the price so that uh you know you
can uh still afford to be a hash maker
without having to break the bank all
right shout out to concentrated X much
love brother for all beautiful products
here uh I've enjoyed it impeccably uh I
urge all of you once again go follow
concentrated X on Instagram uh and if
you want to follow me on Instagram I am
found at BC bubbleman and do me one last
favor head on over to YouTube check out
bubbleman's World on YouTube and give me
a subscription there uh and uh yeah
we'll hopefully start putting some great
videos up for you to enjoy all right
everybody and you know what I just
realized how stoned I am that I told you
to head on over to Bubble man's world
you absolutely have to be on Bubble
man's world already watching this video
so subscribe if you're here give us a
thumbs up if you like the video and uh
we'll talk to you guys next time on
Bubble World Peace Out
[Music]