all right guys welcome back to Bubble
man's world uh we're going to take the
congales cuts quite excited about this I
have to say uh just waiting as for as
long as I did to acquire this strain and
uh it's I've had it just a couple of
weeks and now I'm already able to take a
clone or two so got a couple of pucks
prepared here I've got my Remo's Roots
rooting gel in the house and I've got my
congales so I think we're going to go
right from the top here
my little scissor trick with a little
bit of little bit of gel on
there all right so I'm going to come in
here at an
angle take that
guy give a nice little
dip find it its new
home all right
one
congales number two coming
up number
two I think you're over
here yes I do
indeed all right number two
well that felt great to take a couple of
congales clones and I'll keep you guys
updated on to how long it takes them to
rout and uh hopefully we'll be able to
give at least one of them away keep
watching Bubble Man's World
Peace