all
right wait a few seconds here till we
get sorted out with everyone coming in
all right all right all
right as promised I've got some red
congales tpin with a little well a very
little but I can show you a bigger piece
here some congales bubble has
rosin which I can I can assure you is of
the utmost highest
quality really really been loving this
right here going to be sad to see this
last little piece go you can see the
quality anyway I hope everyone's doing
great today wasn't sure what to sort of
make the topic about today what kind of
things we were talking about hello there
Lisa and Dustin in the house it is
awesome let me tell you it's completely
ridiculously awesome so I've dipped a
little bit of it into the congales
Tarpin the red Congo Tarpin for those of
you that missed it that's what we're
puffing on right
now that is what we are puffing on you
can kind of see the reflection of my
computer screen on it right now pretty
sick hello Ron and welcome Fletcher
archive in the house Chris Gamble and
Zach aen what's going on dude Jonathan
muchin well morning from Australia
welcome Carl I think I need to take this
rip I have been using my um sick Dish as
my carb cap on my Sapphire and it works
quite well gets a little hot after a
short time but uh Graham dab my God not
even close I'm not doing a huge giant
dab I'm doing a nice little dab nice
little little little guy here it'll be
quite enjoyable I promise
[Music]
turn it on
John Congo bubble hash rosin actually
Phil the hash was squeezed into rosin
and that is what we're puffing right
there I am Cameron I hope you're
enjoying yourself good to hear see you
dude you going to come for a visit one
of these days
soon well what's it
like first of all the Congo by itself I
love the Exotic uh flavors of of those
turpine profiles that terpinolene that
is that sort of hazy piny and exotic
smell is it's high in terpinolene let's
just say once you start dipping into
tpin of course that changes everything I
don't know for those of you that have
been trying out the Blue River turps but
they really do change the end result of
the hit you get it in your lips you get
it all around it's it's a beautiful
tasty thing hey there good morrow
Michael Manning and David pki Cannon
flab 421 in the house
well we've had 25 people react to our
video great I don't even know what that
means but um I'm just glad that you guys
are all in here I think we got about 100
people
probably wearing my whole plants Frozen
shirt today love that thanks Aaron for
turning me on to those guys any sneak
previews on topics for nest chks you can
let us know
about well I am trying to get my friend
soon Neil in who's a very brilliant
doctor and talks all about the
cannabinoids the endoc canabo system and
the uh the anti-cancer properties and he
really is putting out information in a
way you know that is as solid as it
could be possibly put and I think I've
been trying to get him I'm hoping that
he's going to be on for episode
102 it sure would be nice to have him he
would be nothing but a bonus uh I'm sure
Dr Natasha will be showing up and
sharing her time with us and uh all the
rest of the regular panelists along with
maybe something or someone new I never
really know every week I I want to put
the energy in time into sort of you know
I I I I wish I could be you know really
making hash Church a thing that I was
putting a ton of time and energy oh look
at that sweet skunk dab that just came
off of there just had to share that with
you guys that is some sweet skunk right
there can see how reflective it is
pretty trippy psychedelic almost
yeah he sure is so I'd really love to
get him on
there uh I think he would be a great
addition that is for
sure where should you send your resume
uh in regards to going on hash
Church well Trey I know nothing about
that except what Todd has told me uh I
don't think of him as a liar he has
proof he has a
video I I stay out of things like that
but obviously Todd is my friend uh he
told me that a long time ago I never
felt it was important I never felt like
it was my um responsibility to share it
but obviously if something like that
happens to you in life it's a it's a
touchy subject especially if someone is
in the community what do you do do you
hush hush hush the way he has quite been
for a long time or or do you finally say
Hey listen this is what's going
on cuz a lot of people in this industry
you know would appreciate that knowledge
now who knows if it's ever as cut and
dry as he said she said but having your
voice on a 911 tape definitely does not
sound good hey welcome Christopher
Cole just not stopping just not stopping
that's going to go for a
while oh sweet's going for the
win oh you know Brandon I did hear
that's terrible news I don't like to
hear that myself it's weird that they're
choosing certain ones and not choosing
other ones you know I wish they would
get off the it's such a tricky
situation because you have it's money
right it's all about money it's the
ability to make money we know that the
reason we all started selling pot in the
first place was to escapee their system
of money if you have to be a slave to
their money you know you're not able to
do the things that you want to do and so
in the beginning for me as I learned
about cannabis as a young person and I
was working hard shitty jobs and double
shifts and gas stations and that sort of
thing I sort of quickly realized that
just finding great herb and sharing it
with my just my circle of
friends is is a wonderful beautiful
thing and so that grew obviously to the
point where I felt like the whole world
was my friends and I wanted to I wanted
to get it out there to everyone and uh I
guess that's really what it's all about
right now is that is that profit margin
because obviously Canada has said that
we can have this people can grow it
people can buy it people can you know
now can we sell it that's the last sort
of right that we're waiting for and Mark
Emery did a really beautiful interview
recently if you guys go on my Facebook
um page and it's not the most most
recent post that I did but I will go
down I think I posted it just yesterday
and it's definitely worth checking out
it's a 5minute interview with Mark and
he basically says Hey listen you know
the people that have been that have been
torturing and harming people over this
plant for the last 50 plus years are the
same people that now want to be a part
of it and you know that's utter and
complete [ __ ] why should they have
any say in it he also says which I
really loved uh hello from Barcelona
Lorenzo nice to see you my friend he
also says that but um uh people who
don't smoke cannabis should have no say
in where cannabis is sold because it
doesn't affect them it only really
affects people that are buying cannabis
where it can be bought and sold uh so I
thought that was a brilliant point you
can go on my page and it's just a few
it's a few things down right below the
honeybees you'll see Prince of pot Mark
Emory on the future of marijuana
legalization in Canada they should have
use the word cannabis but that's just me
yes we do hey how many of you are going
to come meet me in Toronto at the karma
cup because I've decided I'm going to
get behind Sarah Sunday she's put a lot
of hard work into this thing I went to
the first one there's not that many
Canadian events that occur and uh I love
Toronto Toronto's rocking it's a good
place where I can link up with a lot of
people from Ontario that I talk to uh
through hash church and through my live
Facebooks uh as well as people who live
just across the border whether they're
in New York or whether they're in uh
even as far as
Massachusetts or wherever just pop right
up over that border and come check us
out October 23rd October 22nd and 23rd
you can check it out at the karmac
cup.com or the karmac
cup.car abis instead of marijuana become
a thing well serious jer's you know it
became a thing when we read Jack Herr's
or herrer sorry Jack harrer's book uh
the emperor wears no Clos back in the
'90s for me 91 92 93 and by 94 95 we
started realizing that you know a lot of
this this the use of this word marijuana
stems out of like a racism and a hatred
of black and brown people Mexican people
and you can kind of see it if you go
back and you look at it it's not really
uh uh yeah exactly it's a Spanish it's a
Spanish word that suddenly people were
saying in English but it definitely was
not uh used in a positive way and I
think that uh because it was this
certain agenda that tried to make
cannabis look so bad uh turn cannabis
into something different which was
marijuana the drug that would make you
crazy or end up you know making you do
crazy things uh I just don't use the
term that much I prefer the term um
cannabis for all of whether it's
industrial uh hemp or whether it's you
know high-grade Recreation whatever I
call it cannabis so for me it's been a
thing for a long
time like a long time 20 years maybe and
I'm sure for other people maybe longer
it just really depends on if you come to
to grips with that sort of hairy
anslinger propaganda and how it how it
stems out of racism you can't support it
damn I don't know Trey you know sooner
than later I would like to think I have
so many things going on down
there what is it like events in the
states um well Stephen it is going to be
a bit of a festival more so than just a
cup but obviously she wants to have you
know the glass blowing community she
wants to have vendors with a little
village that you can go through and Shop
she wants to have educational seminars
like hash church and these live
Facebooks that I do she's invited myself
and she's invited normal Canada to try
and uh organize as many good people
doctors and patients and uh uh Growers
uh Etc processors uh to discuss all the
different things that we love to discuss
about cannabis so that's one of the
things that I'm quite excited
about yeah right on Steve Ola shout out
from Winnipeg Manitoba my hometown East
clonan boy right here raised on Bowman
Avenue right off Henderson Highway
eventually mov to McLoud close to uh the
number one
Highway yeah I think it's going to be
cool you know I'm going to be there uh
Tony might end up being there I'm not
sure if he's going to make it but I will
be there for certain with tpin in hand
doing the tpine bar and the tarpine
taste uh taster uh Booth so that should
be
fun why do people still call it a drug
well I guess because drugs are
plant-based medicines that we use to
heal ourselves and then there's the you
know the fact that the the plants that
we're using could could be considered to
at least have drug content based on what
we uh Define as drug uh I also don't
like the term drugs where it turns into
a sort of you know an uh they're not
calling an pharmaceutical drugs they're
calling like cocaine and heroin and
methamphetamines and cannabis drugs and
I'm definitely not down with that myself
but
uh what do you call it if not drug um I
call them you know essential dietary
molecules um both essential amino acids
as well as phyto canabo
and um tpin
are are molecules that uh have healing
properties have incredible properties if
you want to call them a drug that's fine
with me I'm just saying I don't like the
term drugs when trying to put down uh
illegal substances over legal
ones yeah exactly Phil it's derogatory
when you usually when you say drugs it
sounds derogatory I guess it really
depends like anything what the energy
and the and the and the message behind
how it's being said uh I get my TPS from
the Blue River tpin we are in the
process of actually going to be
producing our very own Canadian Blue
River tpin here in the very near future
so that's quite
exciting is that what you would say to
someone in a quick convo I'm not sure if
you've noticed Jeff but I don't really
have quick convos for instance hanging
out on YouTube or uh Facebook usually
lasts an hour my my my hash Church goes
for four hours at a time I like to give
people time uh as much as I can anyway I
I I have to admit I have very few short
short conversations in a day and many
many many long ones it's awesome do I
have a favorite mushroom strain yeah I
think I have a favorite mushroom strain
I have all sorts of favorite mushroom
strains let's start off with my favorite
one to pick locally here in British
Columbia uh I love the cyan Essence
which are called the wavy caps um they
grow in um
usually on on Like Straw or they grow
out of grass depending on what's
underneath the straw usually it's got to
be wood chip for them to pop up and you
can find them all over the Lower
Mainland it's quite amazing um hey
what's up Ken
Johnson shroom shroom shroom yeah you
got to love the
shroom hope to have you safely in the
state soon maybe even in Texas in a
couple years when we can build a
giant dude I'd do it down I just wish I
could come down it's uh it's crazy you
know definitely hey what's going on
there Ken Hayes we got the wavy of the
UK 600
mics uh like an umbrella cap yeah I used
to pick them all the time don't get me
wrong they're not the only ones I love I
also love seman seadas which are simple
liberty caps but very strong very fun to
pick very wonderful Vibe uh when on them
uh and I also love Bist B sistens are a
little bit more rare in the sense they
contain uh bosy and nor
bosy which are chemicals that definitely
seem to produce uh hallucinate
hallucinogens you know it's their they
they produce hallucinations they produce
almost for me anyway cartoon like
hallucinations um so different from any
other mushrooms I've ever really taken
mushrooms generally for me aren't that
hallucinogenic usually I'll see things
quickly happen happening in um in
Shadows and if I take a knif like over
five or six gram which is a lot that's
not really like a hangout with your
buddies sort of dose um then I've seen
you know flowers and plants growing out
of my chest and other pretty intense
things that uh weren't there don't let
them scare you Craig they'll show them
they'll reveal yourself to you they
really will teach you so much if you if
you allow them to it's uh I have a deep
respect for the
mushroom no doubt Casey ker why do I
recognize that name did you just write
on your Facebook post the other day like
telling like randomly just nobody off
but basically everybody who read the
post cuz I remember that name and I
remember reading a Facebook post that
said something about kiss my ass or
something along that lines I was I
always kind of it made me think of the
vages of Facebook and how people will
post these vague things it's like man
you need to like explain exactly why
you're saying that and direct who you're
saying it to put this on YouTube please
yeah well maybe we will Robbie it's kind
of turned sideways I usually like to
turn it the other way for a Youtube
upload but maybe I
will yeah DMT is insane dimethyl
tryptamine Terence McKennon really
turned me on to the DMT also turned me
on really quite to the uh to the
mushrooms as well for those of you that
haven't listened to Terren or read his
books I do urge you uh go check out true
hallucinations or uh the in visible
landscape which he wrote with his
brother Dennis check that one out it's
definitely worthwhile and then I also
like to uh sort of you know tell people
to listen to his various talks that he
did uh at The esam Institute and other
different places in California
definitely worth checking
out no I yeah it might not have been you
Casey but man it was someone telling
someone off without saying who it was
and I I see it on Facebook all the time
I'll just go you know re post down and
see something that someone said and it's
like
it's like man am I now I am I supposed
to want to know about this now like
you're trying to Peak my interest hey
welcome Tim oh Robert I am going to be
trying to go back to Jamaica next month
all sorts of things uh to get done there
we got some exciting things to talk
about soon I hope dude the talk about
whipping the
motherboard I'm not even sure what that
is Mitchell but you can let us know
archaic revival yeah archaic okay it's
good I've I I've read them all I like
them
all really Trevor well that's awesome
for me it was always the Bist that could
get me there but never just
psilocybin tried to friend you no luck
oh dude I have like 5,000 friends just
follow me and that way we still um you
will see uh everything that I post and
that's what I always tell people even
though they seem to be disappointed that
I don't see what they post but generally
if you're not following like imagine
5,000 people follow you and then like I
didn't know how Facebook worked
initially so I just click accept accept
accept which made me their friends and
then I started seeing the most [ __ ] up
[ __ ] come across my Facebook feed I'd be
like wow like who the [ __ ] is posting
this crazy [ __ ] and so I started having
to delete people I thank God for
different sort of social experiments
they do in the news because you know
they'll post people will allow
themselves through news stories to uh um
unveil their own racis ISM or hatred or
nastiness and so that made it very easy
to go through Facebook and lose a ton of
people but uh for those of you that want
to be my friend on Facebook I suggest
just follow me you'll get all the
information and uh it's it's better that
way for
sure Daka scary dark outside it seems
It's someone knocking at my door I open
but nothing here I don't know what's
going on it's midnight here in DACA all
right SoJO all right
society makes folks this way sometimes
yeah I guess so I'm not too sure it's
also social media which is a social
experiment on its own self that we're
you know actively engaged in currently
right now so that's fine welcome
jeppi jei CK Galant toi it's a that's a
solid uh solid Italian name right there
yeah people do seem to be angry it's
true oh yeah well Trump was just one for
me I I allowed the Pokemon go Trump um
videos of cops arresting beating killing
what all that [ __ ] like all the [ __ ]
that you're super upset with in society
now I'm not saying that you should sweep
it under the rug and not expose it don't
get me
wrong but you know at the same time your
social media feed is what you follow and
allow to be shown in that feed and it's
uh I don't think it's a good idea to
have that much negativity just buzzing
all the time and making you think a
certain way and making you react a
certain way so my simple reaction was to
unfriend the people that posted all of
that stuff and uh I was at 5,000 for a
while and I don't know what I'm at
anymore but it's definitely like 4,000
or 3,000 oh [ __ ] it's actually 4,800 man
am I accepting
people I don't know I got to keep going
through maybe it was only a couple of a
couple hundred people that were driving
me insane maybe we should have another
dab before I go what do you guys think
will you join
me will you join me hey welcome Todd
young pbl sag in the house old school
buddy of mine from from way back really
way back 20 years man 20 years this dab
is for you Todd I still got my pabble
sag shirt but it [ __ ] got a super
stain on it so I don't get to wear it
anymore but I've never brought myself to
throwing it away I have my OG pabble sag
shirt all right I hope you guys are
taking a oh wait should we have a TP dip
here Jesus are you kidding me of course
we should have a TP dip I think we
should have a turp
dip Cherry AK-47 for the
wiin Cherry
AK-47 profile for the win all sorts of
goodies in there you can check it out at
Blue River extracts.
CA oh yeah that would be great Michael
that would be great but uh you know I
don't know Joe
personally and it is kind of a random
with like Joe would have to want to do
that you know we could never ask Joe of
that and that's the problem that uh you
know you can't just go to people like
that and say hey it would be great if
you used all your traction and your
awesomeness to like expose my much less
traction show uh you know he's he'd have
to love it if he saw it and he thought
you know what this is something I can
get behind to think what these guys are
doing as good I'm going to help them out
then awesome but uh I don't know if
that's ever going to happen I think uh
you know we're just going to keep
chugging along hopefully making the
right choices because the internet is
very reactive and all it takes is one
bad choice and all of a sudden people
turn their backs on you but uh as long
as we can keep sharing information and
people can keep learning and bettering
themselves I think that's what they show
up for you know I don't think they're
showing up for any other reason than uh
than that and that's a good
thing uh no my my opinion is not that
ignorance is bliss you know I had these
arguments years ago when I stopped watch
uh reading the newspaper and the media
because these stories are manipulations
and yes they are happening but it's like
back in the day who was it that stood on
the corner in Compton in California and
showed about statistically how murder
rate had gone down but the way the media
portrayed the murder rate in the area it
had gone up like 800% so although less
people were being shot the media was
showing more of the stories when people
were getting shot so all I'm saying is
don't let the
media control your thought pattern it
doesn't mean you have to be ignorant
because nowadays we have many more
sources to go to for news but we just
have to be careful if if we just take
our social Medias which were originally
used to take down regimes like in Egypt
and like to to to show to expose
corruption but you just continue to
repost the same old CNN and uh NBC and
all these other different major news
outlets you're really not getting
anything other than the same news
they've always been giving you and I
don't think it is too hard to believe
and understand that the media is a
extreme form of manipulation they're a
huge piece of the puzzle right now when
it comes to um disseminating out
propaganda to control the masses through
their particular agendas which is have
you smoke lots of cigarettes and drink
lots of coffee and drink lots of booze
while working many many hours uh as a as
a drone these These are the these are
the experiences they want us in and it's
uh it's no it's no surprise that in the
Cannabis industry you see a lot of
people that are trying to escape that
you know just trying to escape that and
cannabis kind of gives us that ability
when you first you know when I first
came across it and the ability to sell
and trade it and make a few dollars and
although that prohibition profit you
know turned out to be uh to come with a
large karmic debt and good people ended
up you know going to jail and being
busted and having their lives uh
destroyed it still is what it is thanks
Sean I'm glad you're uh I'm glad you dig
it dude
yeah Michael you know if it happens it
happens you know I'd never asked Todd
for that but if Joe Rogan and Todd did
that one day and or Joe wanted to come
on hash church I think it would be
amazing to say the least I like what
he's doing I like his audience I like
that he's a smart guy and he shoots the
[ __ ] and he talks about interesting
things and people they hear when he's
talking and the people that he brings on
his show although I don't watch it a ton
the few times that I have watched it
it's been quite enjoyable they're real
people having real
conversations no I do not but I'm
excited I took it
I do not fish off my boat I'm not really
a fisherman I have a lot of friends that
are fishermen they have special boats
for fishing
with everything you could possibly have
uh but my boat is a competition ski and
and wakeboard towboat so we mostly just
have fun we crank the stereo and we puff
dabs and we pull people on the um wake
board wake skate wake surf skis
kneeboards the odd time in tube I'm
puffing on some
congales this drop down was made by
Corey and it is absolutely beautiful you
won't be able to see it but right on the
top there's like a phoenix in the
Millie I don't think
it'll hone in on it properly but it's a
really cool Phoenix that spirals out you
can barely see it
well I do appreciate all of you coming
and sharing your time with me as always
I'm sure that uh you guys have better
things to do with your day maybe I'll go
shave this uh this kind of getting out
of control beard anyway have a great day
guys I hope it's a wonderful one it is
my sister's birthday today so wherever
you are if you want to say happy
birthday Janette bubble man's sister
I'm sure she will get the message
through the Ethereal vibrations that you
put off anyway thanks guys peace out