[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh I'm sitting out on my deck right now
as you probably all recognize I'm sure
at this point in time you recognize that
view and I've got here in jeez it's got
to be in about a 5 to S gallon pot I
don't know what it is you guys probably
do uh and it's a congales this is the
infamous congales she's about 2 and 1/2
ft tall right now has a beautiful stink
to her and she is um going to go into a
bigger pot I'm thinking to put her into
a 20 gallon next time I transplant her
and uh this is going to be my outdoor my
outdoor plant for this year I'm not sure
if I'm going to have to pull it in a
little bit into my Giant 10 foot tall
tent just to give it a little bit of
help flowering even if I have to bring
it under my um the roof of my house here
just off my deck and use my um King
Spectrum the LED um uh is it the light
spectrum the Spectrum King yeah that's
the one the one that Johnny B got me and
uh help flower this guy uh lady out cuz
um well we'll see when she starts
flowering I want to grow it real big
though get it 6 7t tall at least so stay
tuned for that and uh uh oh I wanted to
tell you about Periscope a new app that
I'm using uh you got to go follow me on
Twitter BC bubbleman on Twitter and
through that I'm running this app called
Periscope where I can go live any
anytime any second you can download that
app as well and follow me as BC bubble
man and it's just a cool real neat way
to live stream from a push of your
button on your phone and so uh yeah I've
been playing around with it a little bit
and having quite a bit of fun so I'll
leave you now with the congales the
beautiful beautiful BC
[Music]
sunset