[Music]
dude
John D you made it that's
it all right thanks bro
happy to help man you called me and I'm
like I'm there and he's like welcome to
B man's world sorry to cut John off I
just wanted to welcome the audience and
let them know that John just rolled in
with the brand new denail the 2.0 and
apparently there are a couple of new
things in here that Brian and Stevie
wanted me to check out should we rip it
open or what well you know I picked it
up and I opened it and looked at it and
went I got to get
here if I go any farther
all right well let's I just saw stuff
like that there's a lot of stuff so turn
it around too well first off first out
the
box we have the
whips so this
is uh titanium nail post whip same as
the original one that I have cool that
one very cool very cool um oh here's the
quartz
one
this one is the quartz whip same thing
right there um these were actually all
packaged up obviously when John walked
in it wasn't the first time he walked in
we just wanted to let you know we wanted
to show everyone Us opening the box we
opened it real quick and then we put it
back in here so when you see us pulling
things out that aren't wrapped up don't
think the guys at denail aren't
packaging this impeccably they are they
did and we were stoked but we're sharing
it with you new now as if we're opening
it for the first time which really about
20 minutes ago we opened it for the
first time so here's a new product um
this is the
new post heater you can see the old one
here little bit of a different product
it's got the nail already screwed in
there which I did just a few minutes
ago get that out oh it's spinning up top
that might H so that's the new post
heater a little bit different I'll be
taking good photos of all these products
as well so we can get a good idea
uh it's always nice to see them up you
know really close that's the titanium
now that was pretty cool when I saw the
post um okay let's pull the well this
these are the two power
cords um I'm going to plug it in the two
sections one thing we haven't done was
we have not plugged in we have no idea
what the part's going to look yes and
this secondary power cord it came and I
looked at it I thought it was a little
bit strange and lo and behold it comes
with a remote control that allows you to
turn the unit on from a distance so I
thought thought that was a really pretty
cool little I mean not that I mind
leaning over and clicking my denail on
but I have to admit I thought that was
pretty cool of them all right so you
want to get that on there do you well I
was thinking maybe seemed like you were
having a bit of a difficulty well no I
was deciding if I was going to tear into
it got to do it if I was going to cut it
got to tear tear
tear so like when I got the call I was
uh I was actually at um canas culture
chq and talking with the the people
there
and all right you want to plug that into
the wall around the corner there I'd go
the other side go all right so here hold
this we'll get rid of this
box now here's the new 2.0 denail custom
Bubble Man Edition sweet I thought that
was really really cool let we put that
little was really awesome they've got
dry sip gland heads which is probably
your dry sift cuz I sent them photos I
can't remember if it was yours or Sam's
or mine or but it's it's very likely it
could be yours and then they did my logo
in there really did a great job on that
the unit is quite a bit smaller than the
last denail I'm uh I have one here it's
unfortunately not a plastic uh just a
plastic bodied one just give it a little
unplug so I can show you guys the wood
box version is right here and here's the
2.0 next to it so obviously the wooden
box is um addition
size added there's a smaller unit inside
there but it gives you a pretty good
idea that you know I'd say they cut this
denail down by about at least one3 and
close to half it's pretty good
eh I'm like I love it oh I'm going to
hit you're getting the first hit out of
it how about that oh wow look at the
colors in that oh can I have that of the
box I wanted to actually open those all
out if that's
possible thanks brother
so this was typed and it says oh bubble
man bub man all right so this should
also have yes that little guy goes there
so these
three three new quartz pieces that they
sent these are a long time coming cuz
they've watched me use everything from a
rure bowl to a can9 pipe and these are
quartz I believe they're quartz um carb
caps and so there's the quartz bowl and
you can see instead of going around the
outside of the bowl it actually fits
around the inside and makes it a lot
more
stable check that guy out there's the
bowl and I think they sent a couple more
versions let's see what we got
here oh wow fancy how about that one how
about that one it's like a little
mushroom top with a little head on it
there cool cool that would that would
snug in is it yeah oh nice I like The
Snug that one snug well the other one
wasn't as snug as you already felt it
right yeah that is nice snug I like very
nice so we got that one we got that one
we got this last one before we can hey
we've got to try this remote control
thing too probably
uh so what do you do you just turn it on
oh wait we got to put the whip in first
so there's the other uh uh carb cap
quite nice it's got slits on the inside
that go on the outside oh yeah those are
slits that's an outside one that's an
outside one for sure no and it's also a
Dabber will that be for the titanium
this one's also a Dabber I'm not too
sure see you could carve with that
that's how my carbs would fit but I'd
say that's just as good I I'm pretty
sure he knows I hit only with quartz but
we'll ask Brian should we be using these
with the quartz or the tie or can we use
them with both probably doesn't matter I
think we're about to use them allall
right now we're
going we are why you think I'm here look
at me I know you're you're ready
actually John off camera already took
the most gigantic of rips so he's
completely I well rounded right now oh I
would say just uh functioning a lot
better yeah that was some of d420 K's
dry sift that you hit there out of the
Swiss perk that's a nice thing all right
so there's our little remote control
here's our whip cuz we're going to go
quartz we are going to go quartz John
and of course we're going to hit that
mother ship yes we'll pull out the
mothership for this this is uh the
cleaner of the two bongs that I have so
probably course got yes me as well I
have some very nice full melt dry sift
but uh if you want to fill yourself up a
bowl of your own first I totally
understand I'm going to smoke the dryft
which dryft well we're going to have the
dryft that we have from DK I yes I have
some dry sift from d420 K and then I
also have some dry sift that I
made from from their resin I actually
have that here too Yesa that's what you
made you're on
it okay so shall we plug this whip in
and see
uh all right let's try this unit out and
see see what she's
saying got this part in between that I
don't quite understand it is plugged in
see if we got to turn this
on I suspect this has no batteries no
that has no batteries so here let's take
this and plug it in direct without the
remote
control and that
way I think we'll get our
temperature yeah it's turning on it's on
at 72 right now
there's a battery oh you got a little
battery in
there and the battery is not F so let's
see what temperature we're going
to all right she's
climbing I love getting new toys you
never know you know you never know I
remember the first time I got my first
denail it has two switches at the back
of it and I had only hit the one and I
completely thought that it was not
working and in the end it was working
Beyond perfectly I just had to sort of
get on my own uh uh inability to use it
so we're climbing up 294
332 wow it's a nice little small unit
I'll tell you excellent well we'll plug
that in in a bit and we'll try it out
cuz that's pretty cool I know I just
like had a you know it wasn't working I
was like check it out it's got a button
yeah lights up it's it will work but
we'd have to plug it back into uh this
little piece right here that came with
it and I guess got sound it does but it
doesn't really
explain I guess it just has this little
button you push the button and this
little button goes on
guaranteed well should we try
it we'll let this let's we got to let
this get up what are we at 6:30 I know
we just got to plug that in and plug Ang
controls that WR oh I like how it's
lowered my bowl on my last um denail I
they sent me an 18 by mistake and I all
my bongs are 14 so I have this piece
between my denail and the and the pipe
and it was it was putting the nail right
here so this is going to be oh wow yeah
I just noticed that right now quite a
nice treat to smoke like that last time
we were doing it and that thing was
getting a little close yeah even now
when I was carving you on this one it
was touching your hat I know so we do
what we have to do we're not too fussy
but it is nice when things can work out
a little better than uh than
that I think they did a really nice job
like that's just like you know what the
box is Sleek I really am going to miss
the zebra box I have the zebrawood I
have to admit I um I sold my other
denail to d420 K you can check him out
on his YouTube channel and you've got
your YouTube channel up now too don't
you I've had one for about 5 years I
mean you're actually doing something on
it I'm going to do something on it right
right right so he's had one for 5 years
but now he's actually doing something on
it so you might want to check out John H
Bell what is your YouTube John H Perell
perfect John H Perell check out his
YouTube he's going to be doing his own
content as well CU he can't he can't
just give me all his awesome content
he's got to you know promote his own
page and he wants to explain to you his
grow and uh what he uses and how he does
it so lots of you have had questions for
me go over to John H brell's uh YouTube
page and you can uh you can learn the
right now on that questions from you
page is just uh well me fighting in my
injury so you can actually get to know
what I'm about then where I came
beautiful well I I want you to have the
first hit on this well you know what
that's
that's it's great I'm going to you want
the gold Dabber do
the one then n
FR I think it's more than I think
appropriate that one you know
turn the half you know that video of us
doing the fresh frozen is almost at
10,000 hits now W yeah it's neat to know
you know that people are watch you know
what I'm I'm talking with people and
like I was talking to you there uh on
the weekend people coming over I'm
talking again today and and everybody
wants to know hey how am I doing this I
want to get away from this shatter and
all this I I've used two bags my whole
time how are you making it melt and I'm
like well if you want to just go to a
bubble man's world and uh learn yeah
yeah well that's you know what and
that's why when they ask me about how
you grow and what you use I just say you
know go check out John Bell's page
cuz he he's the man that's doing it he
knows what he's doing he can answer your
questions better better than I can I
can't answer your questions at all so
it's not even a matter of answering them
better I just I'm not John I don't grow
his his resin I just get to I'm lucky
enough that you bring it over and you
share it with me well I think a lot of
people will be quite surprised of um how
small of a garden that are run and what
I do and stuff like that and how it just
gives me this quality of life you know
what that's important for people to see
you know in the world of the internet I
know that it's great that people love to
assume large big you show only pictures
of colas for the longest time and you
know for me as a photographer I've gone
into many many many Gardens and I've
actually had gardeners ask me like not
to shoot their distance shots they want
macro shots but they don't want me
shooting their Garden from the door you
know they're like oh it's not that great
it's not that clean and I'm like you
know what it's it's it's your garden it
is what it is and it's why does
everything have to be a multi-million
dollar grow room you can grow this plant
in a small space and take care of you
know a multitude of problems 10 by 10 10
by 10 you know like look at Phil we went
up to Whistler to meet with ph he's got
his room full of tents yeah he's got his
two tents in there great I loved it
smile it made me smile too Phil's a good
guy I'm not sure if he's got a YouTube
channel but if he did I would be giving
him a shout out right now
and now we're going to hit some of uh
d420
K's
deri
yeah oh I'm really excited to hit the
brand new D now I can't tell you I
didn't do the dump when I first did it
so it melted time to get
Ohio there we
go
I think I like that one better for
the that was the best carb I've ever
used yeah I think that I I don't even
know why but that was just
so right away I can tell Tre did you
hear the sift boil when I dropped it
in two thumbs up denil Stevie Brian you
guys are doing good things I love the
fact that you're constantly pushing the
boundaries you're constantly upping the
quality of your product you're
constantly um looking to Pioneer new
things we're going to continue to hit
this
denail as well as um use all three
dabbers that we got from you I'm I'm
going to try that one right now and uh
just want to give you guys a shout out
check Dell out on their web Facebook
page it's uh
D- nail yeah I always tag it great
prodct such a great little unit I love
how this one is just just so tiny and
remote control remote control talk like
click hey man let's just go over there
here yeah know it's ready to go don't
worry about it wellow we got to plug it
in and use the remote control should we
do it yeah we'll shut her down unplug
her and plug it
in and turn it on check the front let's
see if it's on
what we doing yeah it is not on all
right so let's hit that button here you
want to hit it over there yeah sure all
right so here we
go on it went I heard a click on the on
the wall so I knew right away that it
went on just again a really cool little
thing obviously you could probably buy
this component yourself but it's they're
adding it it's important to support the
people that are pioneering the ideas who
are making these things work it's it's
not always the most important thing to
try and oh I could probably go buy one
of these from it's like support these
guys they're doing good things and I I'm
just really stoked to be uh to have
gotten turned on to the electronic mail
we got to bypass the torch thing we
never torched I torched really remember
got little bit all these little videos
that I've done I torched and I would
torch I was I was dabbing dry sifts I
was doing that on all of these dab bars
that going I start dabbing dry with a
torch and people were like no way and
like the flavor was awesome so I was the
guy dab Dr so I was torching but I was D
Dr I totally bypass torching yeah I did
I never I don't I've never owned one you
puffed and then you went right into a
sublimator and then you went right into
the D had the Ember yeah I you know the
ember's great very very tasty flavor
saver I sometimes Miss putting the
screen on there of with the full melt
and bubble hash or it just looks proper
you know yeah this here you don't really
get to see it as much but you can but um
like when I'm at home on my bong is nice
to see that he's like it's true I'm
going to put like a little what is that
so this is the the final thing and I
believe I believe this is a a ceramic
insert that will fit
inside oh they sealed it off for
sure we put dry on there all it's the
it's the the flavor saver apparently so
oh that one okay you would know you know
this is ceramic instead of titanium so
little white disc tie nail
fits right in there and it actually sits
right on top I thought it actually
settled down into it no wej from that we
have to we have to do some uh I wonder
if it fits on the quartz as well
wouldn't that be wonderful just I bet
you it does throw it
on at like just throw it on know
wow
interesting little ceramic
insert I guess we got to have a hit of
that I
guess it definitely makes it to me
seem like the way it fits anyway first
bounce beautiful the way it fits is not
something you'd want to pass around I
think the way this is sit there you'd
want to put the pipe where you need it
and then take the hit right off of it do
you want me to load it up for
you what do you want what would you like
John you want your first bounce yeah
this is this oh it's so tasty you're
you're the one hitting it first so you
can tell me on the way
out cool first one to hit the ceramic
flavor saver
disc you think it's hot um
well I don't think ceramic is going to
take very long to max out on its
temperature but we could give it a few
more minutes cuz I can honestly be
honest I don't know yeah I'm no expert
on Titanium or quartz or ceramic I
listen to a lot of you guys argue on the
internet and I find it somewhat
laughable particularly when people say
that the titanium is medical grade I I
hope you guys understand that means that
it's uh graded to be put inside
someone's body not to heat up red hot
and smoke resin off of I got some
medical titani of course you do but it's
medical grade why I know because it's in
my neck but they're arguing that it's
medical grade and that's why it's better
to smoke off of yeah I'm going to take
them the tiny amount of my neck and
smoke on it do neck
dabs maybe you could just bend a piece
out put the little hole there you could
dab come on anyway we're just be
babbling but honestly I don't pretend to
know the most about this I'm bioassaying
it all I don't like the idea of the
metal as much as quartz ceramic seems
pretty cool but from what I've read
there's qualities of ceramic so I guess
that's another thing to do research on
it's important for you guys to do your
own research John can let us know about
taste right in a minute
here how was
that tell us John tell
us as you can see the size of that
hoop and the
flavors I mean some was left on the
Dabber oh I know it was melting on but
wow it looked killer I think it might be
a better one to dab with
snakes snake wow I got a nice little rip
from that that was like a thing this is
just literally the tiny little bit that
you didn't
finish probably be a better idea with
the with this particular stuff to to dab
it's
good oh look at that D that was
beautiful
that was two great big clear domes like
you would believe yeah see that that
that's what I we just talked about what
I was missing and then you pull that out
and then it's right
there so that would be your first bounce
so it's probably about
98%
97%
wow that's
interesting I like that I do
too we needed more than
one break that one
no I mean CU there's see what a cool
concept yeah we were just talking about
having to put a screen on there what I
was yeah literally and and kind of I
thought these inserted into the bowl I
really did I never thought they would
sit on top but I love the idea for
photography for the visual that the
thing we were missing that we were
literally just talking about I know
that's what was so cool about that was n
it doubled up like wow yeah oh huge
domes those would have made a great
video with the clean white ceramic in
the bubbling Dome that was beautiful
we'll try to get one it's dirty now I
don't know how clean I'm going to be
able to get the ceramic how porous it is
but maybe if I flame it I'll get it
white hot oh if you flame it that's
where you get like kind of anything I
don't have a flame though isn't that
ridiculous it's why this quartz nail has
never been cleaned I need to torch that
thing anyway thanks for joining us we
babbled on for longer than we need to
but really the bottom line is the denail
is is a killer product when combined
with a pipe like the mothership and a
quality resin like what John myself and
D4
20K have been sharing with you all to
make wet wash uh water hash and dry
sifted just give some education on clean
sift yeah when those three are combined
wow they're just an
absolute P
Trifecta so true medicine yeah true
medicine thanks again for coming out
John appreciate you
bringing the 2.0
by super
appreciate all right
[Music]
peace