[Music]
hey welcome to Bubble man's world I'm
here with d 420k in the house dude
welcome thanks man crazy to have you up
here good to be here it's been too long
it's been like multiple Seasons since I
saw this guy not on a Facebook or a
Skype type yeah it was last winter the
winter spring and now in this into the
into the July month of summer so you
just rode up on uh on your Harley must
have been a bit of an epic adventure for
you very good ride he's he's at least 10
plus hours away to give you an idea if
he beines it and I know he didn't beine
it no I went the long way cuz it's
better when you're riding absolutely
well we're uh definitely going to do a
little bit of that today we've uh you've
brought some of your you know world
famous dry
sift that was the first Frozen that it
stuck to there man does that stuff reak
that is just incredible that fresh
frozen so this was powder it was it was
just beautiful sand there now it's like
a little like a ball I'll photograph it
for you guys so you can see it it's a
nugget o it's got that nice cushy smell
to it as well OG OG y OG tried and true
so this is that full melt clear Dome
that we all know d420 K so well for hand
presses finger presses just instantly
into a
goo and uh man I'm looking forward to
taking a big old dab with the uh bubble
man's world's
audience man that's nice oh it's uh it's
a treat I love it we're not messing
around with small dabs today we're going
big as usual yeah
exactly Darren's
around big dabs will
flow nice you put the little cheese
plate with the berries and the fruit on
the table too well I like to have a
snack when we're uh in between Puffs
right cleanse the
pallet
true just give the nail a little bit of
a
cleansing here we
go
nice man the Melt Factor on that's
incredible it just boils
eh it's exactly what it
does very fine fine amount of uh of
residue which of course will be
um when when you're dealing with hash
and not
Oil we're always going to be left over
with that tiny little bit of wax
membrane don't be alarmed let it smoke
off and then just blow it off the nail
it's not something you need to be uh
feeling that you have to
inhale the first part of the hit at
first 90% is just so good that's that's
what I I love doing
the you got all sorts of nice treats in
the House eh yeah well this is uh what i
g what I gave you there and this is some
stuff that's that's cured up since the
last time you were up oh yeah that's
been curing since then and it's uh in
the glass jar you know it's Whited out
you know it's done that thing but you uh
showed me the method there one of your
videos there on how to get it gooey
again absolutely pretty pretty
straightforward and Y and uh works well
but I you know for myself if I'm if I'm
dabbing it like that I like like to have
that consistency but it sure is
interesting how like how the resin can
pull moisture oh man like especially
when it's left open for any amount of
time yeah especially coming down here
yeah like it's uh it their presses up
nice though yeah well this stuff is uh
is new I made this last week it was just
sifting I was sifting literally well two
hours before we left on the trip my my
uh my bro chance from Iron heads he uh
he come down and picked me up so I was
sifting about two hours before that just
finishing up putting that stuff in there
well we're going to definitely send you
back with some new screens we got the
250 Micron and the 180 Micron yes I'm
very excited for that the quick little
trick you know you just this is a real
quick trick with the 250 to the 180 you
can throw your material over it very
gently lift up the two screens and you
should have a very clean high percentage
of gland heads I mean you know nothing
compared to how much uh Darren's making
on on a regular basis using carding
techniques but I look forward to hearing
about what he comes up with with the two
extra screen sizes and how he starts
playing with them same here um I I like
it I find the different like what I got
here is two different screen sizes one's
the uh 70 Micron or 73 one's the 107
one's the 107 and uh I like the 107 I
like the 107 a lot the I've even caught
it on the um 120 I've even got heads off
that and they're so fat you look at them
under the microscope and you take a to
of that and you yeah no it's definitely
interesting how uh you can separate the
different profiles and the different
effects via just the size of the
glandular Tricom heads I mix both the
the the grades just cuz I'm a bit of a
pig that way you got a nice big fat dab
there yeah I'll be able to talk for 15
minutes while he's hitting that cheers
so we're basically going to do a few
different things today we want to take
you guys for a little bit of a SE to sky
highway motorcycle ride we've got the
GoPros mounted on the Harley's so we'll
do a a little bit of that um we want to
get out on the boat and take you guys
out on the house sound a little bit just
float around maybe bring the denail or a
pure hash joint and chill out for 15 or
20 minutes with you guys out on the boat
and then we will also potentially go
into the city today and maybe we'll see
if Mega ill is open see what they're
saying if not we'll find another spot
where we can go potentially have a
session down at the uh cchq or one of
the dispens yes sir yes sir so we got a
full day planned with you guys here
we're definitely going to do a whack of
cool stuff I'm super looking forward to
getting on the Harley I can't even tell
you yes I've been on it for three days
now steady it's just I can't get enough
of it well the last time I probably was
on mine was probably with you driving
around riding around so I'm ready to
ride big time ready to
ride for uh for those of you that don't
know my my Harley I have a very um
different connection to the bike my
father of course um he passed away on
the bike I had purchased it for him for
his 50th birthday and he by the time he
was 55 him and his wife uh hid a deer
and they were going quite fast on the
highway and all that were involved
perished so I fixed up the bike and it's
sort of how I visit with my dad so I
haven't been thinking about him quite as
much lately it's been nine years since
his passing as well as his wife so
it'll be another day for me to sort of
awesome connecting it's an awesome way
to connect for sure so while we're
cruising around you you know that I'm in
my head talking to my dad and his wife
so looking forward to that too it's a
beautiful day for it it's a beautiful
day and we're surrounded by cannabis
what do we got here we got that's the
Jamaican seedling that's 7 and 1/2 weeks
old was it Lamb's breath that was the
Lamb's bread the bread of the Lamb yeah
the bread of the Lamb um then we have
John's medic Kush John Bell Sharon is
medicine good guy John Remo the urban
grower has shared his medicine of course
as well this is the UBC
chemo and then uh this is the first
cut from the Jamaican and it's already
rooted and happily growing and in fact
you can see that it's missing a top and
that top is in my cloner and it's
red so I already have a clone from the
seedling cloned nice so I'm ready to
start sharing the jamaic see what it see
what it looks like when it's in full bud
yeah exactly it freeze your face or
something you're telling me like yeah
totally numbed out my mouth that was 20
years ago it was in 1995 so 19 and a
half years ago right wow January
February March April May June July
October November like substantially like
about 19 .2 years ago now there's the
now in that process how did you store
your seed was it in a special container
was it in a freezer in a fridge was it
just in a drawer yes all of the above
none of the last um I took care of it I
knew that keeping it cold was essential
so um for the longest time it was just
in a sealed plastic casing and then
inside you know a little container
inside um the fridge now after probably
several years years of being in the
fridge maybe upwards of 5 to
7 I put it in the freezer and now I
remember kind of being like I wasn't
sure if the freezer you you don't want
the freezer to get too cold you can't
have it like crystallize the embryo
right so I had it in a freezer that was
basically turned substantially down but
it still produced ice so it was
still excuse me no problem these rips
are
intense so I mean uh you know for most
most of its 20 years it was in a freezer
for some of its you know for a third of
it it was in the fridge and I dare say
there was probably a year or two that it
was just at room temperature so which is
incredible cuz the last seat I brought
back from Jamaica at room temperature in
this warm weather cracked in my pocket
it was basically cracked before I put it
in paper towels so and that one's now
growing you've seen it it's almost 3 in
tall it it wanted to grow so we've got
all sorts of Life blooming forward from
these Jamaican trips of course just got
back from Jamaica I was there with John
and some other friends we were working
on some projects there that we'll
hopefully be able to talk to uh if they
pan out and if if the future allows us
to do so and so I'm back to Jamaica in
10 days back to Kingston so I'm glad uh
I'm glad I caught you while you were
here I'm doing this trip to before we
get married me and my honey next month
man doing a trip with uh with my bro
chance and his wife and that's really
nice a good time and has have they done
trips before chance and his wife um this
is his first trip well not his it's his
wife's first trip on the on a a long
trip right she's done a couple few hour
trips you kind of got to give him props
for that because it's really not easy
dude she went from Dawson Creek to
Prince George first leg of the trip
that's about four or five hours that's
good then we went from Prince George all
the way to CS we robbed the cops at like
12:30 at night and she didn't complain
for a second about anything she just
troop through we pulled over put some
sweatshirts and some Leathers on that's
pretty TP not you got to give official
bikers lady cuz I'll tell you it's uh
doing those 5 Hour tours I've I've
driven across Canada and it's just like
it's like 23 24 hours she's slugged
right through it very impressive and 5
hours at a time on a bike is enough yeah
especially if you get into any sort of
weather changes and wicked rain or
something it can make 5 hours to seem
like 10 hours props to you Jess good job
yeah no no doubt good job well I'm
definitely ready to put a couple hours
out on that bike myself I don't know
where you want to head out but we should
uh we should definitely figure out which
direction we're going to go in we can
come back later and do the sunset out on
the water on the
boat good good time we could uh call
Mark the weed guy see if Mega Hills open
today and see if we can't get down there
for a a medicated Pizza yeah that'd be
into that for sure awesome well we got a
ton of [ __ ] that we're going to do here
guys you're coming along with us so
we're going to have a few more Puffs
here surrounded in these beautiful
cannabis plants on on this just epic
Bluebird beautiful British Columbia day
beautiful day we'll uh we're bringing
you with us
so stay
tuned
the of
my the
[Music]
universe
something
s
p
[Music]
com
home
the
time
know
come
all
she was killed at the age of
23 yeah killed in the highway super you
know beautiful girl
and yeah you know dynamic human being
and basically uh this is her spot you
ever want to stop on the highway she's
got a
bench epic [ __ ]
view pretty much
uh pretty much
awesome oh [ __ ] dude I'll tell you that
was a sick little little ride that was
fun nice little rip so we're here at the
Shannon Archer Memorial you've seen me
stop here before have a puff on the uh
on the bench that she's got back there
beautiful spot in memory of the
beautiful girl really no tragic that
that stuff has to happen um do you know
about water or do you want to hit this
dry we can do it dry we can do it dry
yeah let's do a dry rip on our uh next
off we'll hit the uh we'll fill the
cooler up with Waters and ice so we have
water for nextra time it's not very
often that the focus isn't 100% THC but
when you get Darren and I on our bikes
THC just takes a back seat to getting
onto the highway and I mean this highway
was built for riding for riding and our
bikes were built for this highway yeah
it's supposed to we supposed to hit this
highway no matter what so it's a pretty
beautiful thing yeah so I grabbed some
dry sift off the uh off my desk
there if you want to uh do the heating
upage of the no you know I'm never sure
on how long I heat this up for just heat
it up till it kind of turns a little
orange you know make sure you can kind
of it is a bit tricky outside I'd say
hold it good and close like that kind of
on that one side away from the you know
like right where you're hitting it on
that other side perfect right there just
kind of hold it up against the side
there and once it gets nice and hot
we'll dab this little
dab so this is the Pacific Ocean behind
us you've seen me out there the other
day on my boat we got killer
whales uh Pacific seals Pacific Whit
sided dolphins sea lions you know giant
octopuses the whole nine yards the
Pacific Ocean is definitely stocked with
epic ocean uh mammals and and uh fish
very cool you ready I think so let's
give it a
shot it was
ready pretty smooth for a dry hit too
nice nice those little Hitman baby cakes
look at that dry sip beautiful keep that
in the bike all day it'll turn into a a
go of Goo a gooey goodness just in the
sun right now it's starting
to all right
so we're not sure exactly how far we're
set we're heading up we'll stop at
Shannon Falls and check out the
waterfall we'll uh maybe stop it in
Squamish and check out the new Gondola
um maybe we'll go past Squamish and go
check out Alice Lake which side did you
heat
up
oh
yeah well we've taken our rip we're
going to relax here and enjoy the view
till we've uh feel the full feelings of
our medicine wearing off so we're safe
to drive we're going to get back on
those bikes and rip up towards
Whistler
pretty nice looking Place straight
across over there
Beach
for
turn it off hello okay we're here we got
to Shannon Falls this is uh one of the
Epic stops if you're heading from
Vancouver to Whistler Shannon Falls is
generally a spot to stop at it's one of
our taller waterfalls even here in
Canada aside from maybe Niagara Falls
which is epically huge beautiful here
beautiful even seen it this this one's
pretty sweet the creek starts right here
it's literally right behind us there's
people there's a little creek and then
it's feeding out
from up in behind those trees up there
you kind of see it it's serious
[ __ ] so I guess uh we're just
going to walk up here right D [ __ ] yeah
did you want to go have a session at the
base of that thing or what sure why not
it's kind of what I'm feeling let's do
it it's kind of what I'm feeling drink
the water when we get there yeah and
fill the pipe up with water more
importantly I've stood Under The Falls
it's pretty awesome I mean it's
summertime now so the Falls won't be
falling quite as uh you know they won't
be quite as Raging as they normally are
in the winter but um definitely it'll
still be a humbling experience to stand
underneath
it yeah this is all new a lot of this
stuff this all is new to me so we can do
the trail we can walk in the trail so
there's the fall right
there I'm going to have to bring my
honey here yeah this is a good spot to
bring the girls I've definitely brought
my wife here many of times well she'll
be my wife in it next month and then
this is also the beginning of the Stow
Miss Chief if you notice that giant rock
of granite as we rolled in around the
corner a huge chunk of granite that's
called the chief and that's a pretty
epic
trail so I say we head in this
way there some Boulder hoppin some rock
hopp
absolutely so this is all coming from
the waterfall feeding out
and going right down and feeding into
the
ocean and upper
everywhere that's awesome in
here so we'll have to climb up through
the falls into the
uh might have to put the GoPro on for
that
footage although I could probably hold
this
camera you good
D I'm a little bit cougar like on these
rocks yes very cat-like you are very cat
all
right this is awesome
hey
just one of the many super [ __ ] cool
places that you can check out in Shannon
Falls epic size trees and rocks that
have collided and collapsed de's over
there climbing up a tree like a maniac
he's got himself into a Zone
there pretty
beautiful
you going to go around that
way I'll see if I can meet up with you
up
here yeah we'll meet
up careful of that rock it'll be
slippery
wow
dude this is gnarly right here super
gnarly right through here in the saage
is there yeah here
too
hey
D definitely come around this way you
end up on top of this giant
boulder
[ __ ]
we're getting there buddy this is some
kick-ass climbing
bro for
real this is the real [ __ ] deal
bro I haven't done this in a decade or
more
Darren I used to do it all the
time super
cool
right I wasn't able to have the camera
on that one but we just came
around this
corner so it was sketchy we did it on
our stomach diesel up there he says
we're getting to the
waterfall [ __ ] right let's [ __ ] do
it
D the tenacity of the hash smoker shall
Prevail what's
up yeah man
we're going to head up smoke a
bowl did you say glaucoma yeah [ __ ] yeah
had to get in the Cannabis
drops
it's been some years since I've been
here
awesome [ __ ]
ad this this is the [ __ ]
Bro oh yeah now I can feel it in my
face there we
go we made
it bottom of Shannon
Falls super powerful place lens's going
to get covered up with water sorry it's
very misty
here D you made it yeah brother [ __ ]
ho sh ass bubble man's world we're
smoking hash we're driving Harley's
we're floating in boats and we're
visiting epic nature sites like Shannon
Falls I think I'm going to get my shirt
off and go stand over
there catch up with you guys in a
[Music]
bit
we just confirmed so we're here oh yeah
super
easy these rocks are going to be
slippery as [ __ ]
though this one's
[ __ ]
holy [ __ ]
bro yeah
[Music]
buddy this is
BC away from here I
know
get in there bro I'm telling you got put
my here I got
it
[Laughter]
yeah
buddy
dude wow powerful yeah Power powerful
[ __ ]
dude
for
what a beautiful
spot haven't done this in years dude
thank you for whatever reason today we
inspired
it touch and go
right we just trucked up here
hardcore I might take us back the far
away which is a creek and they'll just
take us down without any of this
gnarly
off yeah exactly exactly we probably
won't be able have the to right here but
we can go have it right there or down in
here around the corner literally on that
Flat Rock over
there I took off my waterproof
phone
yeah yeah it was just like wet a little
bit you
know got that on camera yeah I went
there too it's where you stand it's
where I've stood before I don't think
I've ever stood anywhere different and
I've only done it a handful of times in
my life
bro it's
unbelievable unfuckingbelievable
dude come on [ __ ] off it's just showing
me your shoes I wanted to change the
camera around oh I might have [ __ ] my
camera up a little bit
oh
yeah might have got a bit
W
exactly
beautiful British
Columbia with Shannon falls behind
me and the Pacific
Ocean with the
mainland Sunshine Coast Squamish up this
way the Big Chief and just epic 30 to
40t fall on either side this is some
seriously dangerous
hiking so because Darren and I like to
stay safe while we hike we're going to
have a bubble has session you ready
Darren [ __ ]
[Music]
yeah all right guys Darren and I just
soaked under Shannon Falls we stood
under there and let the power of the
waterfall smash us down on wow
powerful first time here thank you thank
you for that man that was beautiful good
hike up lots of rock cofin and stuff I
haven't done in 20 plus years and then
standing under that waterfall right
there on that
rock wow [ __ ] right here nice nice
nice so we figured we'd take a little
rip um maybe guys can put some water in
the bowl now that we're near so much
water I'm going to do it real quick all
right I'll hold on to the jeels tell a
little bit about our about our trip I
guess oh yeah I think we're going to be
heading to a place next and dve
something to eat some of the fine uh
food and Squamish or Whistler or
somewhere our bike end bike trip ends up
uh I think this is the most you know
I've Liv by this place probably a dozen
times but never stopped here what a
treat any of you ever go by this place
if I go bu this place again and I'm with
friends or not stop it in no matter what
what a
place the Beauty and the energy of it
and then to have some nice dry sip full
melt Just Killer OG dry sip
half what better way to toss it
off I can't think of anything better
wonder how bubble man's doing with the
water oh look at that here he comes back
he's a good climber this guy he knows
what to do made it dude got it through
the water in the baby
cake oh there we go all right he not so
sure footed in
here all right
so we got that bad boys you want to grab
that and those you up the GB first and
then
myself how [ __ ] awesome is this the
beautiful British Columbia allows you to
cruise around enjoy her parks and her
waterfalls and her lakes and her creeks
and her rivers and her
oceans her
mountains I'm giveing you nothing buddy
no maybe we're maybe we jump the gun on
the having a hit we'll see what
happens
done might be
empty that's too
bad we're out of fuel we came all the
way up to have a rip and we're not
having a rip because we left the red
torch which was a little bit bigger down
on the bike so we save this we carry it
down and we have the rip with the bike
I'm
easy all right I found some trippy
sticks we're still having a [ __ ] hit
right up here at the fall do this up
buddy
[ __ ] yeah nice and light but nice and
tasty
oh PE
[Music]
W I've got some OG this morning and I'm
feeling good light it up you know me
load it on food a real ganja smoker and
I really love to burn the gan Community
concern good friend
good smoking
because smoke weed
reason car any
Seas me up
[Music]
bless and I
make got from
Central a
[Music]
good call
the take the smoke take it daily so
Theon want to arrest me tell them gadg
not the is necessary
toe when we're smoking smoking
s it shouldn't cause no B gja to the
world yes when we're smoking smoking s
yeah shouldn't cause no
[Applause]
Bal
[Music]
the get a l we call that filter
real
[Music]
smok bang
bang def to the
maximum like the words come off me Tong
so them
try light it up in the morning time
light it up in the evening time light it
over when the night time come and
Bop time we CH people want a bang bang
we defend to the maximum light it up to
any we it listen M on the microp we're
smoking
smoking and it shouldn't cause no B can
do the
world yes we're
smoking smoking s minia it shouldn't
cause no B
G to the
world me G with the people want give me
the make me light up again with the
people give the make me light
up
o
see I got room for you here or should we
just take two right
out awesome dude once again
pound all right yeah fish and chips we
just went to the sushi sen killer sushi
place here in Squamish and and got
denied they don't open for a [ __ ]
hour are we waiting an hour no [ __ ] no
no so we got the Wigan Pier here this is
old school one of my favorite fish and
chips place in Squamish can't tell you
how many times on my way home from
Whistler I've hit the wig and Pier so
they're always
open let's go have some wig and
Pier mus right on awesome want to go in
first
Hi how are you hello
good inside or out awesome Straight
Ahead around the corner you want to just
go in or keep going out or let's go in
yeah then let's go right into the corner
there it's cooler inside yeah yeah
that's what I'm feeling that's what
we're looking at that's what I'm feeling
ridiculous we got to do the video we're
filming for the YouTube
channel telling you this is going to be
on Bubble Ma's World here we go
thank you yeah
buddy that was incredible ninge it out
though
yep
totally we should go have a puff down on
Pepe
Gringo
so or do you want to sit right down on
this bench in the shade over
here
I'm going to have to run over to my bike
and get the butane
guaranteed all
right all right guys welcome back this
is uh Darren and bubbleman d420 K we are
uh we're stealth dabbing in Squamish
we're in the Squam not very stealth but
see over there you've got the diamond
head up there got some other surrounding
mountains over this way the Wigan Pier
with d420 K hitting it hard [ __ ] yeah so
yeah it's true we're not very stealth
but we don't give a [ __ ] we're we're
medicating this is it we don't give a
[ __ ] well it's getting it's right gra
now awesome ready to go you want to take
the first rep no the first one's yours
buddy all
right
very nice rip on this beautiful
afternoon so far we've had a nice
session at the house we've ripped up on
the motorcycle stopped at the Shannon
Archer Memorial we stopped at Shannon
Falls climbed up to the base of the
falls and let the waterfall Smash down
on our shoulders that was humbling [ __ ]
that was awesome I'm still wet from it
then we came we we came to Sushi Cent
which is right across the street from us
here they're awesome sushi place locally
in Squamish totally denied they W in
opening for an hour so we hit the Wigan
Pier one of my favorite fish and chip
places to hit on the way back from
Whistler this was ready to go buddy it
was delicious wasn't
it you likeed your fish loved it very
tasty thanks brother you bet you I had a
9 to 15 o pieces
a Cod yeah that's what I had cod fish
and chips [ __ ] dead
then this for dessert r Treat we're
going to have to do another rip though I
think the first one did the job but
another one will be I'm down with that
I'm down with that always two is good
can't fly on One Wing right no it's true
you need two wings so let's Wing up
let's Wing up I just got a call from
Phil from True genetics he's at my house
right now cutting mother clones off of
my mother's told him to do it he's also
brought me some strains apparently the
Ortega and some other things I'm not
exactly sure but we're going to head
back there right after a couple more
rips we're going to bump into Phil and
see what he's saying and maybe do a
little bit of uh genetic talking and uh
puffing absolutely our thing you know
he's ready to go all right you're
good it's great we're hitting this and
across the street is like a woman she's
got her dog on leash she's got her young
son with her they don't even look it's
not it's almost becoming more of a
normal thing to just see a couple of
dudes dabbing on the side of the road
digging
it cuz them greedy
[Music]
babyon
you ready buddy I'm ready here you
go all right cars everywhere bikes
everywhere I the
birding mying
good
I roll up roll up to perfect how we do
it let that bad boy cool down for a bit
so basically we're going to jump on the
bikes here in about a minute we'll be
right back with you guys we got the
GoPro for the
road we're going to keep this day going
[Music]
guys Mando do M do the planter of the
trees and the gja
farm I love the G more and more each and
every
day I love the G more and more each and
every day on
iise this morning
[Music]
morning I see the new
days everyone got their own thing doing
doing
doing me up got to have some
s each and every
day I love the G more and more each and
every
day I love the more and more I
it to give it let them grow I'm from the
hills of men know the best of smoke
fisers in my hand I trim my weed and
don't mess with Coke when I mix my ganja
butter in the pot and I watch them Comet
Choppers fly over my crop as I light my
back with blood right on the mountain
top and then I
[Music]
said we and yes we pass G on
the moving it moving it I love the G
more and more each and every
day I
love
each we got the highest gr from outo the
Indo check out my SE TGA genetics rooted
when I my I'm cooking rattles snaking
living in the redwood trees till up the
soil and then we feed organic Nutri
farmers of the
trees was grown in the backyard SE roed
in the
ground
love
and each
[Music]
[Applause]
every
[Music]
St
move
over
welcome back to Bubble man's world we're
sitting here on the deck just got off
the bikes with uh d420 K and Mr true
genetics himself is in the house Phil
Pearson good to see you buddy good to
see you too man nice to be here nice to
come home and see you up on the deck
surrounded by all my plants that uh well
I guess we're about to do a little bit
of that sharing is caring um for those
of you that get a little upset have a
little minor aneurysm when you see that
I'm sharing strains that you feel I
don't have the rights to share um you
should turn off the video right now this
is uh you won't want to see this is what
I'm saying uh if you get upset when I
share genetics cuz we're about to kick
down a good dozen strains aren't we you
definitely are man it doesn't strain so
we got we got some strains from Johnny B
here we got some strains from the doc
Atomic we have some from the great
Gardener uh some of my own that I've
collected and and and planted so so yeah
man if you want to uh get yourself a
pair of scissors tossed over from the
sidelines
beautiful little pair of like those
little Katy scissors I like them good
toss we got some AF so we got right off
the start we got what do you got the
Afghan yeah let's get the Afghan let's
get the
Afghan all right so this one is uh of
course from the house of the great
Gardener uh very reminiscent to me of
the old school Romulan that Romulan Joe
used to have it's one of the first
things that I've seen in a long time
that had that smell and that
taste oh yeah look did this guy go he's
going large good call I like to go large
Woody Dr Tomic said the same thing when
he was here the other day that's the
only way to do it man and then many
people said no that's not true which is
great cannabis is the dichotomous plant
where you just have so much one guy says
one thing and it's like no the other guy
swears against that one thing they're so
resilient it's awesome it'll do anything
it'll do the opposite it'll do the two
opposite things and then people like no
I'm doing it right no I'm doing it right
it's like dude you're both doing it
right and simultaneously both doing it
wrong so exactly Barb is right next to
you
there the first two that he picked
Afghani and Barb great to share I know
the great Gardener is happy to share his
genetics I mean most people are that are
selling them because they sell the
genetics so whether you're sharing them
or not people are able to buy them and
acquire them so both of these two the
Barb and The Afghani are purch
purchasable in seed form via the
Vancouver Seed
Bank and we should be probably hitting
bowls while he's doing this what do you
think Darren well you feeling that I
didn't want to interrupt be rudge but I
was just about to dude I'm about to
crack into your hash bro go for it
that's the that's the uh cured up from
November last November and this was all
like the day before I left well 5 days
ago but I let it set up for a good month
on the screens before I sifted it all
out
just clean as [ __ ] it's
uh oh
yeah which one's that it's another Barb
another Barb another Barb Barb [ __ ]
Barb he [ __ ] Barb get in the [ __ ]
car Barb the it's time to [ __ ]
go R the tayor park boys Barb Barb Barb
Barb set Randy Barb Barb
Barb all right what's it's like a little
like Treasure Chest as you pull one out
I know hos number 10 this is from Johnny
B thanks Johnny hay OG skunk cross I
think you should take a break for a
second and have one of these of those
man I think you're right go for it dig
yourself out a nice talk to that all
right let me just clean the Dabber try
her out because we can't have dirty
dabbers going into the clean these are
little blocks those are
that's block s cute yeah oh I'm so happy
concentrate the H oh you got some nice
little clones
there that's a tough looking plant very
Barky on the I'll tell you this one was
so loose at first I remember remember it
being just like it was so weird it had a
tall stock and then it had this like
Mass just right here and it was like
kind of falling over and loose and I was
just like man I don't know about that he
OG skunk and John was just like you
should probably just hold on to it then
it got better and better and better
bigger and bigger I've seen the in the
SI it looks all of his OG crosses have
been great so far I mean it's hard to
not like it's hard to hit something with
OG and not come out with something
pretty good I've yet to see like a
terrible that OG is always such a such a
treat it's a Powerhouse it uh it gives
good quality a lot of lot of strands
when they when you crosses oh I've got
that headband for you as well that I
collected up at weed MD and or not
weedmd oh the chem
dog1 that was from uh it was Boys in
Ontario exactly yeah what what about
that let's let's talk about that they
they have a patient sealed up and they
used it for cluster headaches or
migraine headaches apparently their
patient's consuming a half a day to keep
his cluster migr a day oh hey whatever
you got to do right uh yeah I'm pretty
much all right hos it up same way man so
I also have um once we get you these
eight cuz you're taking a couple of each
from the the four that are here I've got
some more in the cloner and we'll go
check out that afterwards and see what
you can uh see if we can't grab you a
couple of clones out of there sounds
good to some of the 107
screen a little 107 yeah between this
guy digging digging for hash between
this guy cutting for stash this is great
I got my custom denail in front of me I
just tore up the Sea to Sky Highway with
my buddy on the Harley we went and
climbed to the base of Shannon Falls and
let the water fall Smash down on our
shoulders and humble us it was quite
good very very good day and I think we
might do the sunset out on the boat it
still could happen beautiful beautiful
day here in British Columbia I'll tell
you all
right nice big tall clones we got all
eight already no no no no had only four
what else another hos and another
Afghan so your Afghan is over
here maybe want the
hos afgh I like that a f g e n i where's
the torch in the case um I'm not sure
actually I'm not sure to clean something
up or oh I no I wanted
to give our friend a a taste well dude
the Dil can pass off camera it's got a
huge long whip all right just pass on
the whole thing you go off camera
action we'll use some of this cured up
stuff for a while let you try that first
yeah pass him
uh pass him this
too pass him so much [ __ ] that he has to
like literally be like how the [ __ ] am I
supposed to grab all this with two hands
fucker's giving me a bong with a nail on
it and then he's got to pass it back
right after think he's professional
though you see that I think so he
handled it hand it just fine that's our
secret guest off camera we'll never tell
you who he is I'm not even going to tell
you it's a he it could be a she could be
a [ __ ] hermite for all you
[Laughter]
know no offense F
cany take yeah no offense um here you
want to exchange you've already taken
the hos do you want to bring it up here
I got yeah you going to leave her down
there but out I put down boom There You
Go sir thanks
brother no he's clearing he's he's
gearing up here he's only got a couple
of left and uh they're both OG ROM
crosses literally like and how I haven't
I haven't seen any of that stuff
finished from Johnny B how is that stuff
which one uh really nice all like I said
all the OG cross is have been killer so
I mean you can tell just look at the oh
dude it pumes
yeah exactly stinks that hos as well is
a rer that plant right there is one of
the stinkiest The Afghani as well you as
well try one of these it's funny cuz the
sweet skunk the Congo they don't stink
quite as much in veg they still have a
good re they got a good nose on them for
sure but anything afghanica I found in
my opinion man like the ogs like The
Sweat
Band anything like that just stinks B
like the sweatband cut I gave you still
s you want to drop that one in
thanks
awesome smell that Astro Boy burning
again or something that's weird just
just starts we'll take a hit
as fresh frozen yeah once you guys
finish uh doing this taking these clones
will uh you've got two more clones to
take so yeah Kai told me it was lovely
you stopped by the other day and had a
session yeah it was good it's definitely
good it's not too shabby well he said in
all the years he's been friends with you
that's the first time that he's had a
chance to sample resin that you did your
exactly all the way right he said he
said that just he's never really thought
about that before want to gra that guy
over thanks
bro yeah nothing that you from from
start to finish all right last one how's
that for eight Quick Cuts four strains
boom bam boom uh so we just gave you OG
cross with ROM we just gave you the hos
number 10 make sure you remember that
number 10 then you got the Barb and you
got the
aghany so next up I'll take you over to
the AA cloner
power a plethora plethora goodness and I
got a little bit more for you over there
and then uh you can show me what you uh
brought for me oh lovely did we ever
bring some stuff but super sweet we're
going to Puff a few more bowls here he's
just finished taking these Cuts we'll
probably get these into the cooler
actually the Cooler's right here did you
want to go through real real quick let's
go through it man let's do that while
we're hitting bowls so we got yours
right there those are nice and secure in
the shade definitely wouldn't want to
take Cuts this fresh and put them in the
sun they would harsh out and droop over
it wouldn't mean you couldn't bring them
back stress them out it stresses them
out it stresses me out yeah when I see
them I'm like you know what that's
stressing
me sweet skunks all like laying on their
side it's like no going to have a stress
free start
exactly forever it's keep it happy keep
it stress free all right we make you
happy andess first this is
um that uh I selected through bag seed
that just got quite a story behind it
it's some of the best OG that I've ever
seen reminiscent of what uh what D sifts
with and uh it just I had to keep it
it's some [ __ ] flame OG that's for
sure beautiful and you're the only
person that I've given it to so I like
that yeah secure do you have something
to put it in you want me to hold on to
those why don't we just go in
here flame OG flame
on awesome let's just get that all lined
up
nicely I need them to be not stressed
out
there we go all right so flame OG and
this is Orga ortea that's really old
school seeds come on where how what uh
when did you collect these seeds um I'm
not allowed to tell the person or my
relationship with them but they're an
extremely good friend of mine and it was
something that they Acquired and had for
years even before I was even of age I
love Ortega and uh this is like a strain
that we used to have back in the day
Ortega is actually um the Ortega crossed
with Cinderella 99 watermelon which is
smacked with the Apollo 13 is the Astro
Boy which is right behind us here right
here crazy is that eh family they're
Family Guys Are Family So a family
friend gave me gave me those seeds umti
that he he's from Europe he saved them
for a bit and then gave them to me uh
quite what a recent a few years ago and
uh yeah they he was just expecting me to
keep them as a gift a Sen germinated
very nice quite quite awesome and I like
that it's it's it's an amazing it's
always nice when a breeder brings you
something that they themselves didn't
breed but it's like an old stable it's
like here you should appreciate this
it's the Ortega like come on [ __ ] is
Wicked Strong produces dppy crazy resin
and it's narcotic in in its high there's
no doubt about it I know the Ortega well
I have smoked a lot of it so then you
got something some more of your work
yeah this is some work uh this is true
genetics you guys produce this Yep this
is something that uh again this is an
extremely complex hybrid it was Med man
silver uh silver skunk cross to Rockstar
uh selected a very skunky blue cheesy
gross smelling phenotype I hit that with
my Sweat Band F1 mail and came out with
the sock sweat and the sock sweat it it
doesn't that sound attractive oh yeah
the sock sweat smells stinky dude like
jam to jamy stinky like blue cheese sock
sweat JS dude come on this is great
riding for three years change in your
sock Sweat Right exactly D you nailed
them I feel pretty sweet about that
right there um you also in the tent we
gave you a sourberry cross sweatband
which we call Barry McDuff that's a
that's a really big guaca hitter Barry
McDuff is in the tent awesome and Sweat
Band F1 sweatband F1 the The Strain that
you use to produce the sock sweat yeah
and the Barry MC excellent and the berry
McDuff okay so Berry McDuff is sweatband
and sourberry you remember that bag
that's sitting in my freezer that we
never wash this together I'm putting
this together yes I know so busy that I
can't even afford I can't afford time to
go wash resin with my friends pretty
pathetic actually we tried twice we
definitely tried twice with a broken
hand I even went over to your room with
my lizard so we'll get these into the
cloner here real quick there's six right
here that need to go into the cloner um
we've got in the cloner right now that
you're going to be able to gain access
to uh quite a few strains some are
rooted some are not so uh we're going to
hit a bowl of the Astro Boy cuz you
haven't hit any of my fresh frozen yet
and then we're going to go dump these
into my cloner pull some more out for
him and I've got in there just to name a
few medy Kush my Jamaican uh the East
Coast Sour Diesel hash plant etc etc etc
it's endless when you start sharing it's
kind of like wow what happened if you're
in scarcity like I started with with two
and now I have like 28 it's called love
and abundance look into it sharing is
caring sharing is caring I mean
seriously dude [ __ ] is like peanut
brittle I teach that to my grandkids all
the time that's what you teach your kids
and your grand kids I go to the room
they hand me a car or they hand me a
train one of the toys cuz they want to
share with me and have fun too all the
time of course so it's you know you
teach them at a young age and it works
out to the end I guess but some people
just never some people you can't share
you don't like the sh
it's true all right so back up there
with that this is the peanutty brittle
very nice watch the [ __ ] melt dessert
hash pure dessert
hash
Sizzle you can hear that Sizzle on the
camera bet there's no way you can't it
just boils
oils it just goes then silence and a
clear dome for like a substantial amount
of time oh and then you get this rip
that he's about to get followed by the
oh my God I can't believe the taste it's
on my lips it's in my throat took the
words out of my mouth Buzz [ __ ] dud oh
my God right from the top of your head
right down like a [ __ ] blanket all
over every part you can taste the
parentage and there's so much man I love
that and even if you're smoking OG out
of that next you're still T an AST boy
after smoking OG which to me I've never
smoked anything that dominated over that
because had such a strong taste but C's
like the Congo just lingers man it
really [ __ ] lingers was that for some
[ __ ]
maneuverability that's aent yeah like I
said this was found in my freezer so the
sizzle is more from the fact that
there's moisture still in it water but
do you see it melt oh man it's like ice
cream man
clear we found it accidentally under my
fridge door yesterday no way my son was
opening en closing it and pushing all
this food into the back and I got under
there and I was I pulled these two
pieces out I was like I was like wow he
thought he was in trouble I was like
thanks Tosh oh
no I was like thanks
bro that's awesome good job so uh yeah
Taster's Choice we're going to give a
rip to our friend off camera and we're
going to uh go meet you in the office
where we'll show you the cuts that he
brought and we will uh holy [ __ ] [ __ ]
give them the new ones it's [ __ ]
killer that's the one that tastes so
beautiful man I don't even have anything
to
say see that's the
one all right okay Jesus
Christ all right so we're in my office
we're at the power cloner I've got the
strains that you gave me I'm going to
get them into here and then uh we've got
four more empty vials for you you have
the you need these these vials and these
vials so did you grab that marker yeah
awesome all right so probably won't even
need that I'll just uh let's say the
first ones we're grabbing are Jamaican
perfect
man you know how I feel about that
land that's it the
loms
bread finding anything land pretty
non-existent these days
so true story yeah man and you know I've
been after I actually asked you about
the Lamb's bread sometime during our
winter sessions what did I say you just
said it's really really hard to find
um I have some but it's really
completely forgot that you had the beans
actually um but you said that it's just
basically hard to find non-existent DEA
spring in Jamaica all right so what's
next in hear from that would you like
sweet skunk would you like Congo would
you like did I I didn't grab sweet
outside did I so sweet outside so we'll
go sweet Scott sweet
Scott what a great strain to give away
watch your back you're sitting in front
of your
camera sweet
skunk another one I've wanted for a
minute so yeah this is a real nice one
oh man she's going right to work she's
got a lot of work to do excellent yeah
well that's good um here we got some
water right here oh no we don't I've uh
released all this water I'm going to go
grab some because it's important we get
some
perfect
all right
so there's a sweet
skunk those other three and I will fill
them up both Jamaicans
couple squirts bring these right up
to there you go one
anyway how excited are you I haven't
given these Jamaicans to anyone yet
you're the first to receive them I'm
probably someone who wants it not the
most but wants it really bad I'm glad
that I can just give it to you man
without any weirdness without any oh I
know man I'm really happy you can too I
really appreciate it um we know that
it's going to breeding work patients
medical use at the very bottom line
right bottom
line it's not going to get hoarded by us
either so look at this what you brought
me OG Orga sock sweat come on it's
awesome dude so all right we've got
these
guys get them out
all right so I would say look at that
seedling already I know I saw that J
just growing out like crazy Jamaican
that's the Jamaican that I just cracked
yeah the little one the little one
that's stuff look all right so I know
this has this look at that
NL so rooted NL um we've got sweet skunk
and Jamaican though that we're going to
give you right off the about
so
um sweet skunk and jamaic these are all
sweet skunks right here so here's a
sweet skunk roots are just starting to
numb out on that
one is it big enough you going have to
cut it a little bit just with the
scissors slice them in there sideways a
tiny little bit it's a nice St like
these roots are going to go right
away all right so there's a sweet
skunk next up another sweet skunk so
here give you this nice little one it's
got a root how's that for a pull it's
cute got that you want to cut that open
a little bit with the scissors those
small cuttings got really big yeah well
these are nice little stocks and I don't
want to damage
the all right there you go sir
M Jamaican
so Jamaican I know there's some roots on
these Jamaicans so I'll try to give you
ones that don't have Roots because they
don't go through very nice on
that oh they every single one of them
well and actually I have another these
are Jamaican too so I grab some of these
as
well Perfect Look at
that I think that we'll just won't have
luck pushing the Jamaicans through here
with roots on them
oh I've taken has such big
cuts that uh I don't want to stress them
out any more than they need to
be so
Jamaican darn
you all
right
Jamaican killer so that's four yeah and
you can go ahead and plop the Clones
that I gave you because they have tags
right on the cuts all right so now we're
going to do
these these can go right in here as you
are correct because they have tags right
on the cuts how professional is that oh
running a a large a large license
breeding facility I don't even need this
much I'm going to cut these down quite a
bit I just did it in half a second you
lots to work with it's plenty to work
with for sure that's very good so we'll
give this
guy you know at least his inch and a
half to two Ines
below I'll probably trim this Leaf out a
little all
right
so that was the OG yeah that's the
OG
beautiful there's another one for you
sir mhm stripped her a little bit on the
way out but all right she's
o she
is I just really walk through the room
last night and uh it's basically like a
Jumanji jungle in there and tried to
figure out what nice what you would like
to have that's basically what well I got
to say all this seems like a real nice
surprise I never talked to you about any
of this so I wasn't really expecting um
a big slurry of uh beautiful
genetics now it seems as though since
I've been giving them away I have to
admit they are coming more readily like
this not just because people want but
people seem genuinely
to want to share of course man that's I
wouldn't be a breeder I wouldn't be a
medical
breeder it would just go against
everything that I'm about and and you
need to share that's why I started
reading in the first place not to just
cure my own disease and illness was to
spread it onto other people and I've
done exactly that it's definitely the
righteous thing to
do it's definitely the righteous thing
to do all right so that was Orga I
believe Ortega we did what two
ogs yeah OG OG Orga
Orga you get them in there pretty good
bud I gots to admit you do you do oh
yeah
these to be much longer than I normally
do they're pretty big and Woody that's
that's okay though it's very
[Music]
good if you put them in the uh the auto
like that they'll just they'll grow to a
half a foot you don't talk oh yeah I
noticed that myself with my
cuts like yeah aeroponics is really
really ficient yeah it's efficient no
it's hard to deny it no you can try it's
just hard to flush if you're fully
completing where the other two did I
only take out two for you
um four two sweet skunks two and two so
we put those four in I need to make room
for two more so what what do you say
next we give you the congales cones
congales coming right
up cono cono here's a couple cono let
starting the
root start and S the
rout excellent so they're all good
they're all healthy and good you want to
take a couple of The
Congos do you have uh oh what are you
what are you writing on there Congo
right now mhm
Perfect all right
so
Congo mhm it's Congo you got two Congos
mhm There You Go sir a little bit loose
not too too loose but a little bit Mar
heat all right another Congo the real
deal Congo for any of of you out there
watching that would be that Real Deal
Congo whatever that means it's the Congo
it's the thing we know is the Congo yes
hello I'm going to be growing it out and
I'll assure you when it's h flowered but
my source was quite good so I wouldn't
be too concerned with it um s oh yes
East Coast s diesel now let me find you
a couple that don't have Roots perfect
there's two right there nice little ones
guess you want a bigger one thanks very
much flab by the way one but after that
one for a minute too give you this
bigger one this is like 10 years of me
searching for genetics and they're all
one person's balcony this is pretty
easy if only this was easy 10 years
ago yeah well you know there's your East
Coast Sour Diesel
one um Co Sour Diesel
to all right these go sour diesel
too that gives me a few more sights to
work with I just gave you four so let's
see I can put your
sock sweat how's that for a string sock
sweat wet There You Go sir the female
mother was it it looked like skunk
number one and just blue cheese cheesy
cheesy it was it was rotten man like Rog
Hill skunk with a little bit of fruit
just super
gross the dock in all there super gross
in the greatest way oh in the best way
possible
only yeah I can get you dog and now we
haven't gotten that to you
yet just doing the sock sweat one more
for
you yeah I just really thought you'd
enjoy the uh everything about that stram
socks way yeah the the resin is
phenomenal man it looks
great it's a
keeper oh better cut these down just
makes life so much easier in the air
cloner I see people all the time oh you
shouldn't do that you shouldn't do that
it's like listen of course you should if
you don't have the room you don't if you
have the there so many reasons why you
should but exactly there's so many
reasons why you should doesn't affect
the plant in a negative way it trims it
down it gives it room and it prefers to
have that room over the big healthy fan
Leaf that's we go the two sock sweats
are in I'm secure I guess there's two
more that we're going to cut what do you
need there doc
atomics okay
uhoh oh good one that's a jammy perfect
and this is going to have roots oh
you're so lucky there's two that aren't
like all rooted out the roots are going
to get damaged sticking them in there so
this will be somewhat sensitive it'll
probably droop over I can see Roots
starting in this one there we go right
down to the Head it'll probably be a
little droopy but it'll be
fine it's just cuz it's been a while
since we turned the the cloner off now
the Clones are starting to
hopefully that will secure
there do you have any any more room in
there at all I'm going to make room
right now yeah um because I have these
lovely Mex te a planet to yes so we've
got I've got I can take three to four of
those right
now shall
we take away bro okay please have fun
I'm going to have fun now it's my turn
sorry about the video being so dark guys
it was just such a bright day out there
that we thought uh we'd close the back
here and maybe be able to get uh some
decent
uh all right what we got here ni little
clones here and
there I'm going to grab four still be
nice to not
have
World Pho taxi you see that three
leaves yeah that one had some really
cool
deformities there's a couple things
going on with this
one came from bag seed from the max tea
and the two other mothers that were
growing were just look like Time
Monsters
and he just GW from seed y yeah
absolutely grewed from seed threw a
couple in his garden and
uh not sure how it's going to how it's
going to end up come Harvest so he wants
to wants to reassure that he's got some
Cuts yeah well it looks like he's
reassuring that right now because the
cuts are ending up all over the place
this is a real mutant dude I know like a
serious mut oh I
know it's crazy I guess you don't really
mind where I cut no man not at all it's
going back to veng for for a
minute jeez look at these clones they're
like starting to shrivel up on me some
of them can you please put the lid back
on and turn the the pump on please um if
you want to write me a few small labels
Mech tea or whatever you can even do it
on uh like an old business card like
even write like that like four little
Max Mex or
something how many you those be those
will be secured I'm going to grab four
okay that'll be all
secure may be a little choppy chopped
but hey that's what happened when you
share the
Clones when you share the
Clones the reason water there not meant
to be kept in your
basement yeah well it's a different time
nowadays hey we're all sharing isn't
this
nice Max TAA from my buddy
Ben small
world one more
excellent yeah just throw these on top
of these little guys here she has some
little labels yep I'll take a picture of
it and that'll be all got to be so
gentle with this little guy give him a
little spot
delay that
in give these guys a little
mess
yeah the harmony is like
drooping
drooping the wonderful thing about these
guys just put the thing back on turn the
light
on and you're back in business so Phil I
want to thank you brother so much dude
for the genetic kick down thank you Ben
thanks reeferman thank doc Atomic thank
the great Gardener uh thank d420 k
thank John
Bell and anyone else that I'm forgetting
that has passed on strains Remo the
urban grower we got your UBC chemo cush
we're going to make sure it goes home
with uh with Phil as well he's just
cleaning up all the mess that we made
but uh thanks me out thanks for watching
Bubble man's
world all right
so what is this again Phil the sweatband
sweatband F1 F1 the F1 the one that you
when you came over to my
house clones of that were roaring in
that little 4x4 ah yes yes yes monster
nuggets all right awesome well here's
another little gift from Phil in the
crew at true genetics some of their work
it's absolute pleasure get it into my
garden and of course you know what I'm
going to do with it guys I'm going to
turn it into hash and see what it's all
about out cuz that's all I really do
care about when it coms to this
particular aspect of the plant the
medicinal aspect really getting that
profile off of there and checking it
out dude awesome I'm going to have to
chop this guy down he's a little tall
from my life what I'll do honestly right
away is I'll probably cut here take a
cut and I'll get this will be a clone
and this will be a clone so I'll get two
cuts off of it just this little top
right here two cuts we'll go right into
the cloner as soon as I figure out
something else to get rid of so we need
to get these into your cool cooler soon
and uh there it is we'll keep uh keep
you guys peeled on uh both you've got
your YouTube channel going on no not
quite yet just theam you should get one
yeah they're going to get one true
genetics it'll be up on true genetics uh
I'll put the link in my um YouTube
channel comment of this video and uh
yeah you'll be able to watch what he
does with those and you'll be able to
watch what I do with these so pretty
stoked man found it out awesome
buddy it's looking I'm just going to go
home and sift it anyways
oh all right so back in Toronto on our
first trip John and I went and visited
those guys they had a real nice show I
think it was 150 liks or something can't
remember their names but uh super nice
guys if you're watching thank you
remember you gave me the uh what is it
chem k91 Kem 91 they said it was good
for their cluster migraine or migraine
headache patient I mentioned Phil one
second [ __ ] fman
[ __ ] all right let's start that over
let's start that
over all right one more thing I wanted
to mention while Phil was still here
back in gez was that March May
end of May yeah I missed a call from you
it champ it was Champs we were visiting
that nice 120 light 130 light facility
John and I got invited to uh by those
fellas I can't remember their name but
if you're watching remember you gave me
the chem 91 you said it was good for
your patient with cluster migraines or
headaches and we mentioned Phil we you
gave us this I haven't touched it or
opened it since and I'm putting it in
your hand brother you got the cluster
migraine headache so sift that up and
get some dabs and see how it does for
you it's uh nice to see it come full
circle months
later June July that's 3 months that's
almost 100 days so thanks guys pretty
sweet all right guys so we're winding
down here what a [ __ ] day dude
awesome day man kill her [ __ ] like
you know um motorbike riding eating good
food seeing nothing but incredible
Mountain scenery and RI tough the whole
time ripping up and down the highway
dude the [ __ ] waterfall the waterfall
I hope you guys enjoyed all of it today
you know we were just going to do a
little W uh wind down kind of say good
night and then Darren was like why don't
we smoke one of those [ __ ] hash
joints bubble man [ __ ] I was like [ __ ] I
think that's a good
idea that
one
oh man that was a nice one those
waterfalls with the with that water hit
you in the back coming off with all that
height and everything like that was just
pure [ __ ] energy powerful goodness
coming off of that mountain Mother
Nature at her best cooling me
down was incredible very
impressive yeah it was all around the
board killer we were we're going to go
out on the boat tonight but I think what
we'll do is we'll start tomorrow out on
the boat and we'll wake up early we'll
head down to the boat and we'll go out
on the water smoke a pure hash joint
listen to a bit of tunes maybe go for a
little swim in the ocean sure maybe find
some dolphins go find some dolphins and
go swim with them they're [ __ ] cool
to swim
with never done the uh Mexico Florida
thing where you swim with dolphins but
they're like in captivity no me neither
definitely did the uh jump into to the
middle of the ocean when tons of Pacific
White St of dolphins were all around me
yeah that it was kind of freaky like you
could You' be like these things could
kill me if they
want go fast oh dude one time and you'd
be but they don't they're really fast
and they're slick and they move all
around you and you just feel like you
know like holy [ __ ] like these are multi
hundred pound you're at Mercy and they
can they can swim at you so fast and RAM
you pick your whole head right off they
see like a conscious animal though I
have to
admit so the sun's Sun's down here on
the house sound right now both Darren
and I are lit up from my metal HED bulb
that's behind me it's beautiful with the
whole garden full of lighten up the
whole you know when it's dark out here
it lights up the whole neighborhood it
does the trees behind I looked at it
last night I was standing out here
smoking one just thinking hm cool I love
it yeah I mean one day I hope to have
the greenhouse behind the house here but
for now it's uh it's a decent facility
I'm happy with it I'm I'm able to grow
my mothers and my plants have a couple
of tents for
Blooming it is getting hard summertime
is is tough I don't have any special uh
air conditioning or anything like that
so my tents get warm definitely going to
end up with uh with potential bug
problem if I don't uh you know cut the
crop down that's in there now it's fine
but the new tent is like I seen some
white flies in there going to have to
[ __ ] figure out what I'm going to do
there well you know the good thing is is
that you have enough that you can take
them out individually clean them up put
them back take them all out clean it up
in there like you don't have especially
the stuff that's not flowering yet and
you don't have to use anything with it
you could just rub all everything off
rub all the leaves everything like that
you really want to get down to it not
use your you any anything any Solution
on it yeah not in bud anyway pre-bd like
this I use safer soap yeah for sure give
them a couple shots of it a month and
just make sure everything's down that
way when people come and grab cuts from
me I'm secure in knowing that I'm not
giving them a bunch of bugs but my
mothers do hang out outside all day long
so you know the safer soap is going to
be essential especially with this hot
summer heat now it's [ __ ]
kicking I'm going to find a bed and
breakfast for tomorrow yeah I looked at
a bunch up on Airbnb you got a whole
bunch of options oh
nice I tried finding that on my iPhone I
couldn't get it Airbnb it's an app I
couldn't find it I have to look got that
your spelling WR cuz I didn't a i r b n
b BNB BNB not a n b but BN V just an N
between the two
v's so anyway end of a great [ __ ] day
tomorrow's puff
Wednesday we're going to see Amir who
hung out with us in h Barcelona and was
yesterday or a couple of days ago at the
Flav's Birthday Bash Extravaganza so
we'll see Amir tomorrow we'll see Johnny
B tomorrow John be right on right on and
uh who who knows who else we'll see on
this beautiful puff Wednesday that's
going to be uh we're going to wake it up
early man we're not going to be messing
around for puff Wednesday so I got a lot
of editing to do tonight where are we
going to do puff Wednesday are we going
to do it here we going to do it at CC
headquarters we'll start puff Wednesday
with you and me out on the Pacific Ocean
out there right there right in between
here right there yeah right there you
seen that like you catch that right
there that's where we're going to right
no right there we go right there right
there
there so that's where we'll be tomorrow
morning and uh we'll bring one of these
pure hash joints so we can hit that out
there start it off right just a just get
baked completely wake and baked style
well actually we'll do our wake and bake
here yeah with some Wicked ceramic Dome
rips the ceramic uh uh little haven't
tried that yet I've got the black
ceramic and the white ceramic we're
going to have to hit both just to see
what the flavor is see if there's a
difference in you know in flavor with
the same
hash
beautiful puffing on these hash joints
is quite
enjoyable yeah I
like Anyway guys we're going to finish
off this spliff and uh we'll leave you
with a little shot of the sunset thanks
for watching Bubble Man's
World
Peace
[Music]