[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh got a special guest in today d420 K
and uh this is kind of a little teaser
video that we're going to give you uh
Darren's been uh anxious anxious to get
some of his sift pressed up here into
some rosin uh he's uh his denail press
is still on uh the back order but uh I
guess what we're going to do is we're
going to give them a little taste give
you a little taste and then we're going
to film an actual like full video where
you have uh I've got this is this is
some jars that we got put aside for it
but I got about the same amount of jars
as well to do double that amount pretty
much we'll pull out the big preps right
now I just thought because it was a
short video and I didn't want to have
this giant thing blocking us here on the
uh on the couch figured we pull out the
small unit cuz you haven't even tried
the small unit yet no I haven't no no I
want I want every one of the units
though just because they're they're
tools I like it's like a mechanic a
heavy duty mechanic a hot rod mechanic
you got your tool chest I want these
tools for my [ __ ] shop yeah for your
quiver for your solventless hash quiver
you got all right well why don't we get
to it you got some beautiful NL yeah
some Northern Lights me and
uh me and uh old Jakey this looks
beautiful it's it's really nice it was
uh it was the the screen of the 73
screen that before I really did much
sifting you know the that little trick
that you showed it's like a solid like
50 to 60% head I'd say yeah I'd see that
for sure looking at it under the
microscope it's you can see a lot of the
crystals all right well I guess we could
load up a little pressing screen I've
got a little 25 micron screen here that
that uh we're just going to load up and
wrap up sort of been I guess the
technique that I found to be the
simplest so
far I'm sure lots of different people
are doing lots of different things but
uh too much oh no you can pack in a
whole whole whack more
good probably most of what's loose and
maybe even a bit
more okay let's bust a little bit looks
nice bust some of that loose one of my
first Ros in videos was doing dry sift
and I haven't really come gone back to
it much since but uh here we
go beautiful more or less I think that's
a fine amount I mean it's hard to say
what that is like whether that's a
couple of grams or four grams or no
three maybe two I don't know well I find
the pure the the pure the heavier right
yeah yeah
totally for sure find out in a in a
blink here once a week uh as we press it
out so I like the idea of using a a
having a screen that's a little sticky
like this cuz it does make it a little
bit easier for closing it
up how big of a
piece um you know what if you P pull out
a little bit more there well it's about
like that and then I would just do two
of them and we'll put one on top and one
on the bottom okay I give this a tiny
little bit of prepress just to get it
sort
of ready for
business there's that Mothership on the
corner of the table again while we're
pressing little put one on the botom one
on to then I guess here yeah all
right here actually let's do this way go
like
this go like this kind of give it a
little bit of a press this way or
forward O Okay forward yep all right so
what this the first time I got to use
this thing happy dropping that on the
floor yeah this will be good you can you
can do well n spilled so but you're
right spilling it would would have been
damn damn near drug abuse so let's see
what kind of a squeeze this gives off
it's not going to give us tons of room
on the side but we want to close it up
all right then it's got a timer that's
set up on it you can leave it even for a
little bit longer on the than the timer
or you can open it up give it an open
it's coming out the size there we
go oh yeah look at
that wow we better press that again yeah
yeah in like in like for 5 seconds in
because it's so much it was coming out I
could see it see it on the pan there
yeah yeah I was like
whoa that is just beautiful [ __ ]
beautiful and we will press that again
let me just get that off for you drop it
there for a second to show these guys
what we just pulled out cuz of course
they want to
see let's see what we got here
you see that
guys it's kind of hard to tell you go
ahead and do it and then that one there
we go that looks absolutely beautiful
real nice color I'm going to give it a
little taste of course
Sweet let's get a little bit off this
pan here I've never actually had any
rosin on my might need a little bit of
uh parchment paper to wipe that
clear Let It Burn get it off the let's
see how well this collects too oh yeah
real nice real nice see got a collection
on that
mhm well that's enough for a
dab sir you go for it are you sure yep
gentleman and a
scholar this is thesis on uh bong
rip I said that loud almost scared me I
was like zoned right in on that hoot
just looking at the
Melt
wow
wow that is insanely
smooth how's the
flavor Northern lady growing growing oh
nice building nice came out literally so
smooth now I can now I can feel that
grabbing
excellent and this has been curing for a
long time too holy [ __ ] man did that
come out
nice I get bet you we get a couple more
presses I think it would have been the
only thing now you see the difficulty of
using a smaller unit you only have so
much
room for things to go
down so this time I think we should give
a 5sec
press cleans up so nice hey
I'm going to grab the uh camera and show
them because uh oh man I want to be able
to really show
that without the Shadow and I keep
making a shadow cuz I'm
a I'm a
Noob
yeah d420 K is in the
house hey don't you blow away
[Music]
real nice quality there
D thank
you and we're going to do a whole video
on squishing this dry sift up this is
just the beginning this is the teaser
video what uh you guys are going to see
if you keep watching is you're going to
see all of this dry sift get pressed all
different screens too all different
grades one from 120 right to uh 110 the
90 the 73 they're all uh this is just
some Percy for right now before we do
the actual vid and do it all because we
got four I don't know how many more jars
how many jars did I give you do you
remember there's 1 two 3 four 5 6 7 8 9
10 11 I have at least four yeah so we've
got all this to do we were going to do
it today but I want to go to slip knot
tonight yeah and [ __ ] check it out
like I haven't been to a heavy metal
concert in a while and we're pressed for
time and we want to have the proper
parchment paper so the fibers and that
sort of stuff that bubble man mentioned
in hash church on Sunday exactly we get
the proper stuff cuz we want no
contaminant because this is
absolute solventless let's finish it off
with one more rip and I'm going to tell
you guys that I'm going to take macro
photographs of this and share it in the
video because I can tell already from my
naked eye the quality uh under the lens
is going to look r ridiculous because
bubble has creates a certain type type
of of look to the rosin dryft produces a
different type of uh rosin as does
flower rosin so you can see we still got
a really nice light color with a little
bit of darkness in there uh the flavor
and the the smoothness of the rip is
just unbelievable it's like we got rid
of everything that was harsh in there uh
then it sort of delays and comes and
grabs you at the end but uh another do
another squish on it yeah let's squish
it up do it up for sure
I knew you were going to love this thing
[ __ ] yeah
man careful of the mothership there you
bet can you hear it sizzling open her
up booah so you got a real nice uh yield
on that first one we're going to still
you could still do it a third time and
what I would do is tell you to fold that
in half half yes just fold it right in
half put it in between another piece of
parchment and that'll be the third one
that's the one I'll leave for like a
good little chunk of time yeah just fold
it right in half maybe even once more if
you want why not just to just to make a
smaller spot I mean the bottom line is
as it should for that you've got the the
power and the press to to squeeze that
out pretty good okay let's take this and
move it somewhere
too sure to the edge of the table just
joking on the floor
so I'm not taking a chance at all here
go that would be bad moment for me
beautiful
right another little maybe you want to
see some of this come off the
paper just so nice holy
smokes oh it's so nice check that
up yeah I could pick up a big chunk of
it there and show them what they
got if you guys want to see more of this
keep watching Bubble man's world this is
just the
teaser we'll see you guys soon peace hey
yo
why the Tim feel good give me
[Music]
a one man HR man real purpose of the
weed that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
mind after we gave by this expression
the purpose of the we let I VI the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time gja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying we have been traveling to Kingston
about 20 M hours sleeping on like the
clock fresh vation with trees and with
flowers
me
[Music]
me I make pass pass pass and then
off and pass that pass that pass that
now