[Music]
hey what's going on everybody bubble man
here with Mr d420 K in the car not the
house car not the house the car in the
car we uh we are sitting here I don't
know where we're like near the water
near a real fancy Cactus Club and
something that looks like maybe the
convention center oh I think that's the
Olympic uh torch thing there yeah it
looks pretty cool looks pretty cool we
might go check it out afterwards but for
now I haven't done a video in so long
I've been flailing I figured hey why
don't we just at least have a little
couple of bowls and we'll shoot the [ __ ]
with the with the
audience so yeah I got some hash if you
want to uh torch up get you ready or
torch you up okay for that
matter A Little Torchy
wary oh
[Music]
yeah you got the carb cap mhm we'll do
it for 35
seconds yeah I like a nice low low dab
low temp dab off the quartz absolutely
it's always nice I get a better to a
nice nicer RI R it seems and you always
know when you hit it right is because it
won't turn black on your nail it'll kind
of stay like the low temp dabs really
don't go black on the nail that really
is something that's going to happen when
you've got your nail heated up much uh
well much hotter than say 800° or so 7
or
800° I'm sure when it's glowing Orange
it's 12 or, 1400° I'm not sure of the
exact temperatures as I don't use a
torch uh super often but um awesome
thank you d
I better pull one of those out here on
the Vancouver
session pretty beautiful day just kind
of overcast cloudy but not overly cold
so I love that whistle well that a
beautiful day yeah I always kind of
appreciated when my pipes had the little
bit of a whistle to them Slinger always
made a good whistling pipe I tell you
that marble Slinger can blow some nice
glass miss having him on this side of
the world miss having them up in this
country used to uh have incredible
access to Glass back then was much uh
earlier days but definitely miss having
sling in the area getting miss having uh
you know getting to see him and hang out
with him on the
daily on The
Daily oh don't go down at that angle
thank
you [ __ ] melt you everything in your
car oh yeah in an
instant in an instant so that's a nice
red got the uh timer going right there
probably give it a 25 to 35 seconds
we'll see what the uh what the amount
is thank you thank
you I'll take your Dabber when you're
when you're finished oh will you sure
will you take my Dabber when I'm
finished I will take it and I will keep
it all right just kidding much
appreciate it 27 seconds let's do
this got
[Music]
it well that was damn near perfect it
was good good taste on that very nice
near 302 weight was
good shout out to the West Coast
concentrate guys puffing on their hash
as
always yes I've got to see those boys
and and uh pop some bowls with them
we've been trying to hook up and have a
sash since I've been down we always do
good guys always down for good sash we
get just [ __ ]
baked I love it
indeed you down for a Rosen rip yep you
bet all righty
do little rolls and
rip There You Go
sir un for you quite a bit of stuff
going on around us there's a lot of
people just in the downtown core area
walking around back and forth suits over
here worker dudes over here here
everyone in between it's pretty chill
Vancouver's always been a chill City I
have to admit I never felt like
um like I'm really doing anything
wrong you know you don't look around
like you're worried about someone seeing
you because it's just nobody really
cares at all it's uh not really an issue
it's a very puff friendly City I guess I
would go out and say I would be very
surprised to see someone come up to the
window and say hey what do you think
you're doing
particularly why tell them to [ __ ] off
well you probably would it it's easy for
us too though you know obviously the
only illegal part of this at this point
in time would us be driving away after
uh hitting the dabs uh I'm looking
forward to more tests being done and
people maybe being able to even go in
for a test where you get tested at the
DMV under the influence of cannabis just
to make sure that you can drive that way
I I myself know that I can but I
certainly don't need to go push it so I
usually just go for a little walk after
after we have a session like this and uh
come back afterwards and and drive away
but sitting in our car in this area
puffing our meds which we both have
Federal licenses for I would say is
definitely uh 100% legal might throw the
cops off if they were to drive by and
see it assuming that we were probably
going to be driving away right
afterwards they might have a problem
with that but uh we're not knowing that
we have our licenses and we are
medicating they could just look at us
like some [ __ ] bong rip and punks and
you know what the bottom line is the
bong rip RI and punks and the license uh
medicated Li the license for medicating
they're both the same thing other than
one is a perspective that it's okay
because it's legal and you have
permission from a special group of
self-interest people agenda versus the
other people who are just like I'm just
doing this because I know it's not
morally or ethically wrong and I'm going
to that's right I'm going to enjoy this
so and it's unfortunate that the police
harass that type as well when it should
be just uh you know oh look at those
bong ripping punks well how about it's
look at those young
guys burning over there I wonder what's
going on I wonder if I could have a to
where over there no no that's I'm
joking he [ __ ] always get me mad [ __ ]
where what where over there that's
that's right just around the bushes
there just over by by North Vancouver
cross the water jump on the sea
bus good fun well we're going to finish
it off with one last dab rosin and then
uh well maybe we'll take them for a
little boot over here who knows we'll
see what happens this could be the end
of it right here it's uh it's been hard
to get off my ass and motivate to
filming videos to go visit Gardens to go
you know make hash I've just I've got to
get uh I got to get REM motivated I've
been fairly busy doing other things but
uh I will try my best and in the
meantime lots of other great cannabis
content websites out there for you guys
to
uh for you guys to check
out feel pretty pretty iry here down in
the uh downtown Vancouver today yeah me
too I like this little area it's quite
it's the new
area everything is new
did you heat this up already yeah it's
21 seconds in all right you got
the thank
[Music]
you baby dab baby dab that was a little
one I was surprised it kind of felt like
all of it just blew off without going to
is that a slip slitless or a slit slit
let's see know just a sec lift up take
the
thing ah
slitless oh yeah slitless and the the
bowl that's right yes I think I might
like the
slit I have the slit on the other on
another
bull ah that dirty slit dirty slit you
got to clean that dirty
slit peace out