[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh I'm here with d420 K and we are uh
we're up at Cypress Provincial Park
Lookout so you're going to hear a lot of
cars going by you'll probably see people
in the background over there sort of
looking at this pretty beautiful City
View in the background in between D and
I you can see that uh the city of
Vancouver's back there we'll probably
show you guys another little Glimpse I
did a video up here uh some time ago
with Johnny B so you might remember this
view but uh we never actually sat down
and kind of did the session like we're
going to do today I've got uh I got my
new plasma Mini battery so this this is
a real nice little unit just turn that
on give it a check boom she is live yep
here we go a nice hot rod water bike
coming up the GP up the oh yeah so let's
tell our story as we're waiting for this
to heat up um what a crazy
story [ __ ] got speed dick coming up the
mountain we did get a speeding ticket
coming up the mountain that's true we uh
we had a little bit of uh we got a
little excited coming up the early part
of the mount you can hear these guys
ripping because what did the cop tell us
after he gave us first of all he gave us
a huge break we were so much over the
speed limit that he could have impounded
the bikes and given us a $400 ticket
each uh whereas instead what he did was
he gave us a $120 ticket $138 ticket
there was a discount on it if we paid it
early I think he said it would be 120 or
125 bucks no uh taking the bike which
was huge and uh you know what I just
remembered this is my 2.0 D oh no it
should work let's hope this works I've
actually only used this battery with my
dabinator I haven't tried the denail on
it so it's possible that if the the
electronics are too powerful in here too
much wattages wattage is needed and this
isn't enough uh we got this for the
backup brought back we do have the
backup and uh hopefully this will turn
on but you know what I don't think it's
going to I think that it's just going to
turn off and it's not enough power what
a bummer I totally spaced
that would have been nice to
uh here we go it's up to 93 that's 3°
hotter than it was
no now it's going down it's funny cuz
I've had this problem with my denail uh
just not working with the batteries I
don't know what kind of electronics
they're putting in here but they are
good because I'll tell you they pull so
much power that a giant battery like
this uh you can't even basically uh heat
heat up a nail with it so yeah it's cool
it's weird all right well you want to do
the Torchy action yeah you bet cuz I did
bring a couple of varieties of nails I
brought that little stain uh little uh
titanium ium one that I was showing you
earlier which is this guy here and then
I brought the Banger as well so we've
got both the quartz and the titanium I'd
like the Banger the quarts just because
that's that's what I like the most let's
do it you want to set it up and start uh
getting it going here sorry about that
guys I'll try to get this going
eventually uh it seems as though if I
want to use my battery I'm going to have
to bring my dabinator it seems to be the
tool for the job uh this denail just
doesn't seem to want to run off of a
battery so until the those guys get that
organized I think I'll probably just
stick with my dabinator and uh thus the
reason we have a quiver of these tools
in our Arsenal cuz you never know when
uh when one might not be able to get the
trick done while uh while the other one
simply
can having a good time yep all right so
we got the quartz Banger in there we got
the torch we got all sorts of varieties
here you want to hit some raws in
I'd like to hit some rosin dipped in my
Harmony dry sips all right let me pull
something
else and this harmony dry you know I had
I had such a problem with my stuff
turning and caking out when I'd come
down to the coast because of the
moisture right yep well then we were on
Hos Church there and I asked a Cuban
grower and yourself like what's uh
what's the deal with
uh with that like how come it cakes out
like that and you got to cure it for
more more time yeah get it dry and what
I did is I did that I cured it and even
I I brought it down here in my pocket on
my motorbike all the way down from front
storage to back here nice and it's still
nothing but Sandy
beautifulness I see the difference on
the Cure big time that's
awesome all right yeah I got get
SC all right here you go brother thank
you little bit of D nail for the D
Man minus the
nail I've had I've been having quite the
time with this battery thing and it's
this is I was so excited to finally get
this going with the battery and be able
to show you guys I got a battery the
denil works on it and I I'm so sorry
that uh the Dil does not work on it but
next time you see me and I'm out about
I'm going to have my dabinator and big
shout out to maximillan for producing a
unit that it's a little bit different
from D now but I'll tell you the unit
works on both UK power uh European power
and Canadian power and it also works on
this battery for whatever reason so
we'll continue to troubleshoot with
denil cuz uh I of course love to support
those guys but man that was a tasty rip
you better you better set that up yeah
definitely down for one of those and
it's nice to have the Torches the backup
which is what I told you to bring isn't
it
yep I kind of knew what was going to
happen I already had it though of course
you did just in
case oh that's so beautiful look at this
guys bit of rosin dipped in full melt
dry sift the Holy Grail of melts you
know that top grade full melt bubble
hash or full melt dry sift
99.9% heads really hard to beat guys
really hard to beat
all right so I'll give it a little
second there I'm learning this culture
of you know keep feeling the nail with
my with my hand I have to say I still
I'm not good enough at it that I really
appreciate the the denail for that
reason where I just know the temperature
not not to mention also when people
watch this video they'll notice that
whenever the torch gets lit it dilutes
our the sound of our voices and you
can't hear the stories that we're trying
forun is a bit of a pain in the eyes a
little bit you know a little bit yeah R
him that's
okay what a great hit yeah it was that
was a beautiful hit for me too you know
one thing I seen guys doing uh it was
the um I think it was the van City
extract guys with the Q-tip yeah they uh
they were doing um they they put their
iPhone on the timer and
time at 45 seconds after they got the
cryst the courts red or orange time at
45 seconds and then hit then do their
hit they do 30 seconds some do 25 45
nice cooler hit and you know that sort
of thing so that's pretty I like I like
that just different methods I guess and
if you really wanted to get tactical
grab one of those little laser pointer
things that do does a temperature watch
what the temperature drops to after that
45 second well that's why I want to
invent a torch that has that built into
it oh man so you're just torching with a
little LED readout and it tells you when
the thing has reached the temperature
you turn your torch off you do a double
check yeah we're at the right
temperature you can hit right away don't
like the idea of waiting to have a hit
mhm you know and wasting your your your
butane when you don't have to and
wasting the butane when we don't have to
man I'm so glad that our bikes are still
here and not impounded that was really
you know what we always hear the stories
about the bad cops well we're here to
tell you today that Darren and I dealt
with a pretty decent cop he had zero
attitude he was Zero suspicious of us he
could have easily ran our names and
found out we both had felony records uh
he just was decent you know what I'm
saying like he he he he gave us a break
on a $400 ticket and he didn't impound
our vehicles for 7 days at $70 a b a day
which is another like 400 500 bucks so
it ends up being a$1 th000 pinch when
they give you that ticket and they take
your vehicle away way so instead of that
happening D and I each got $120 pinch
and 5 minutes later we're sitting at
this table um enjoying some bowls of
some beautiful rosin and dry so got to
like the way
uh that worked
out I wonder what people think when they
drive by on their bicycles or they just
happen to be walking by and they
see this big tattooed bearded guy with a
blowtorch in his hand heating up a fatty
piece of glass
I hope what they think is damn son I
think that's d420 K and Bubble Man
hitting the Mother Ship over there we
you know what it's all be do we should
head on over there and they should well
you should absolutely if you see us in
uh in public and we're filming a bubble
man's episode and you just kind of
recognizes for whatever reason
absolutely come right over interrupt and
become a part of the show we uh we
definitely wouldn't say no to that yeah
I've taken guys right back to my place
and got them so bank they didn't even
know their name and I and I met him on
the sky Train they were yelling at me
down the street one day yeah d420 k out
the out the window in traffic right in
Vancouver I'm like what the [ __ ] that's
just [ __ ] awesome yeah and then I'm
on this and then on Canada day I'm on
the sky Train and then the same guys
that were yelling at me go hey d420 K we
we the guys that we yelling at you
remember I'm like you're the only guys
that have done that yes I remember
they're like where you going I'm like to
to the Commercial Drive one and they're
like well we're going there too I'm like
you want to get baked they're like [ __ ]
yeah I got him peeled on the dry sift
[ __ ] loved it man how's that love
doing that [ __ ] peeled I love that [ __ ]
got them peeled and when he says that I
really do believe they were peeled
perhaps if you were the guys that d420 K
peeled out that day feel free to leave a
comment in the comment section and let
us know uh your side of the story and
how things went and how peeled you
actually were cuz I bet you he's
downplaying it you guys were really
peeled very soon well you're so I just
got it how long was that that I was
telling that story after I heated that
up and everything cuz I got it like it's
not
even 40
seconds and the taste of that low temp
dab of course was [ __ ] phen
phenomenal really good really good that
RW it in the dryp just that's why I you
know I love the low temp dab I love the
intensity of a hotter rip I love the
idea of producing a rip that is both of
those things you know the best of both
of those things and neither of the the
the the Lesser parts of those
things truck pulling
in look at that we've already condensed
quite a little bit of
rippage
well go for some of this crazy reddish
purple that's some seriously looking
fire wow and tasty too
it is pretty ridiculous I squeezed some
rosin out of it and is absolutely just
freaking
ridiculous dude you can't even like
touch it I bet you I could squeeze rosin
out of it with my fingers I bet you 100
like bucks I could
do yeah just be
like I can feel it on my fingers just
touching it leaves a clear oily
residual it's awesome pretty nice and
cooked going to back it up with one of
these
though man the motorbike is so shiny
yeah it feels nice when you pick it up
it's not so great when you leave the
place and then get a ticket but who
would have known that that guy was a
police officer following behind us from
like miles back yeah we were doing a
buck 40 on the freeway just [ __ ]
ripping that was fast ripping just
cruising too fast and then up the hill
[ __ ] just being [ __ ] kids on bikes
I guess not obeying the law yeah not
necessarily being dangerous I wouldn't
say just maybe going just a little bit
over the speed limit so uh well we got
caught as uh as generally we do when we
do things we're not supposed to be do
you know normally I would dispute
tickets and stuff because it's it's the
thing to do just in case the cops on
vacation or I wouldn't dis whatever but
you know what one thing they do these
days is they pay cops double time now to
go to court and to test and actually to
go like that because before in the old
days you dispute it and sometimes the
cops would be off duty and they'd be
like I'm not going in on that day and
[ __ ] wasting my day off and they just
wouldn't show up for court you'd win
[ __ ] no ticket no point you're out of
here that happened quite a bit but
now that's that Ducati again that thing
is insane yeah it looks it looks like a
[ __ ] bullet yeah what was that you
were uh telling the story about uh
[ __ ] St I can't remember I had it
[ __ ] people are going to [ __ ] laugh
at this man they'll have to rewind cuz
they won't know what we were talking
about how many how many potheads does it
take to screw in a light bulb I don't
know what what are you talking about
what do you think we're all [ __ ]
stupid just cuz we smoke
pot oh [ __ ] told me about yesterday was
I just [ __ ] laugh it's
awesome I'm going to finish it off with
one more
Ripper because I should
burnoff d420 K residuals
here smoke those off get that's what's
nice about quarts you can get it so nice
and clean
yeah tastful C is looking pretty sick it
is
yeah such a nice view from up here
especially for like fireworks or any of
that sort of stuff
[Applause]
right let that cool off a little bit
before I rip it
[Music]
up didn't get it really as clean as I
would have liked to but you know
what hot as [ __ ] hot as [ __ ] how hot is
[ __ ] we need the laser pointer
and for anybody out there that's
concerned about us smoking and riding
we're going to sit here for another four
or five hours we'll be here for a long
time and [ __ ] hang out and let it
wear off and all that before we actually
yeah we're going to watch the sunset
yeah we might share it with you guys if
you're lucky but uh Maybe not maybe not
you never know know run out of battery
time but we could plug that battery into
yours into that chargeing like we do who
knows true enough got it covers all
right well [ __ ] a that was good good
little uh Cypress pulse uh rips wanted
to [ __ ] give you guys a video haven't
given you guys one for a while aside
from the Dil press review and of course
hash which is weekly try to make more
videos in the near future and
uh thanks for watching well
[Music]