[Music]
well [ __ ] a welcome to Bubble man's
world D4 20K in the house dude it's like
you live next door but you actually live
10 hours away yeah I love it it's uh I
like coming down here well I'm really
glad that you did uh I always appreciate
you coming down but today is obviously
it's a special day it's a special day so
uh de's been working his ass off for
well for months actually but uh in this
particular instance he had a little bit
of a kickdown that he was going to bring
the bubble man and I'll get I'll just
let you uh let you talk about what you
got there well let's open it he gave me
this jar yesterday and I did not open it
waiting for him cuz I really wanted it
to be open together and well he he told
me he wasn't going to open it and that's
why I didn't but I think he's crazy for
not like he shouldn't have said that so
he could have come home and just hit
every one of these and been like what
the [ __ ] is that [ __ ] in there you know
like but wake and bake I haven't had a
puff today not a single I I hit my
Apex nice once or twice just cuz I can
right well that's the thing with the
Apex I just smell that
mixture of everything oh my God like you
got that diesel under you got the diesel
in the cush right away they like playing
with one another there's the Holy Grail
there's Goji ogi there's Brooklyn mango
holy CRA it's a it's a plethora
parchment up so I guess what we're going
to do here today is we're going to do a
little taste tester we got the mother
ship out with the quartz Bowl we've also
got the silicon carbide bowl over there
on a fresh whip I brought the Swiss perk
just so that when we flip whips from the
D we'll be able to have another 14 mil
pipe to put the the hot quartz or
silicone carbide into so look at you
like a kid at a candy store I can just
see your smile in the video I'm like
[ __ ] these all teeth you couldn't slap
the smile off my face I wouldn't [ __ ]
try just being
honest oh [ __ ] that's uh we OG you know
it's not it's it's been cured up for a
month it's not um it's not overly cured
or anything the resin heads if you
looked at them up close they wouldn't be
wrinkled like little raisins type thing
in the curing process so you could take
it and just basically well I love that
it's still powder it's done right I
really love that it's still powder like
I can but I can also tap it and it's
still powder yeah so it's an instant
press but it's still powder of course
I'm going to show you up close video of
each one of these hashes as we o as we
as we uh open them so yeah you can
really see that uh I think you should
hit hit that one this little hit that
you just dabbed out yeah well I accept
that cuz uh now now this one here
there's this is there's there's a few
ogs now it's from the same OG but
different screen grade now with that
static with the static parchment paper
trick yeah the that's a carding
technique as well and stuff what it what
it does is um it sure does I'll take the
the set of four screen wood set from
fresh hes and I'll take the once once
I've got it through my big screen and
before I start doing the static I'll
card it through the different levels
yeah that's a great idea and then I will
then I contaminants out through those
screens yes but the thing is is is I
separate the heads on the different
sizes of the screens so this is a little
darker than than it should be like than
the other OG but it's because it's a
different screen size and as you can see
it just melts like water what screen
size is this one I believe that's the
the uh
yum even the ASN tasted pretty good but
the first hit tasted really nice really
like a nice uh
intense OG
flavor with a tiny little bit of that
sharpness in the throat where it kind of
grabs you give you a little TP
TP hit there you go brother well that
was beautiful really nice so that was OG
OG 120 so we're going to just write that
down on
here first and then it goes to the 110
and then the 70 right and it's uh
impressive oh let's write that on the
back side one and 120
so there's the first
one
done
beautiful now what a gift to get full
melt dry sift even in just a pile like
that alone let alone a jar with many
many many piles like this we were
talking to Mark Emory uh yesterday we
were we he was on his way out with jod
but uh Darren was like let's uh let's
blaze markdown I haven't had a puff with
him since he's gotten out of jail and I
actually hadn't had a puff with him
since he got out of jail either so so um
we invited him over and I think it was
his first time hitting the D nail this
particular nail he's hit some other
types definitely his first time hitting
a Mothership Fab bag and his first time
hitting some really nice full melt dry
sift and it was neat to see his surprise
as he exhaled it cuz he's been smoking
shatters and butanes and all these dabs
that he's been giving out at the stores
for the last you know month plus he I
think he really noticed the difference
in how oh absolutely you could see it
you could see him notic when he exhaled
it I I'm sorry that I didn't videotape
it for you guys or record it I guess
we're not using videotapes anymore
there's a I'm aging Myself by saying
such a thing but uh no next time I we
hang out with Mark we'll do a little
video and get a couple words from him
and uh show him dabbing out on the
mothership now here's the same OG 70
Micron ah yes you can tell right away
just from looking at it and it was why I
think I was going to guess this was a
120 if you look at it you look how it
looks grainy yes it's heads it's like if
you had a bow of marbles and you had big
marbles in the bow you would really see
the pronunciation of each curve in the
marble that's a really good way of
looking on if you got tiny little
Marbles and you filled the bowl from a
distance it could almost look like the
bowl was full of liquid you know if they
were colored and this is what I'm saying
right here you can really see obviously
you can't you can't go like that to that
and split it up all you're going to do
is press it more yeah I could I could if
I froze it yes if I froze it and gave it
a couple of these absolutely yeah but
then you you worry about breaking the
gland heads what I like doing with that
I I've taken it like I did the Tony
sodas that uh with um the water the
water y um melting right and also the um
the hair straightener yes just in the
parchment paper sure don't need a hair
straightener with this though oh you can
do it just on your own just press it
with your finger and that's it right
yeah I just did really nice color on
this one also I'd say that the the
tackiness of the hash is is unique in
the sense that I'm so used to people
showing me water hash that hasn't been
dried properly um you know this the
stickiness of this and how how strong it
is in the pull and snap it doesn't break
easy and you can just press it right out
real nice so yeah I'm excited to dab
this flavor and so this is the OG again
Micron we are going to be destroyed by
the end of this uh
session which I will add as my wake and
bake
session so you know that feeling when
you have that wake and bake hit can last
a good hour without even really needing
another
rip well that's not going to be the case
today no
I love the um sliding of the piece on
the nice smooth table with the uh Dil
dab rag yes a to WRA that one close that
one up sure I'm kind of just putting
them all here oh yeah perfect and then
I'm going to some pictures later right
yeah we'll go over each one with the
camera and show them yeah that one was
destructive literally
awesome very strong narcotic high on the
OG just just very um you know relaxing I
think of the I wouldn't say anxiety but
the anxiousness that I have today for
getting ready to fly I'm always anxious
when I fly not not because I'm afraid of
flying but I am just yeah you don't like
[ __ ] hate flying man I'm like VA
baracus from the 18 you got to [ __ ]
drug me up knock me out get me on the
plane if you want to take me anywhere
yeah I'm not that way at all I don't I
don't like turbulence obviously but I
don't trip out about it I'm mostly uh
it's the Cannabis the hash the pipe like
having stuff like that for so long and
now that I have a license it's just like
it still feels like I'm not allowed even
though I'm allowed and I don't mention
it I'm not like I'm not really like Remo
or Mark cloaked who are very like
pronounced and loud when they go through
uh the security they they have all their
weed right on them in their bags and
stuff and not sealed well hey you know
when they're licensed upu and everything
you you can do totally but I still
prefer to avoid those uh interactions
for the most part I hear you just
yeah this is the
110 of the OG as well yeah and uh tell
you man it's it's uh that's one of my
favorites the 11
yeah the 11 10 is your
favorite
yes oh yes this is some old older stuff
all Sly smelling that this is at least 6
months old this one very
nice very nice my friend and it's stuff
from when I was carding it with the
iTunes card and not using the static
trick and everything like that right
well it sure looks great yeah it's well
it goes to show you you know like uh the
carding techniques that I've been
sharing for I don't know 5 to 10 years
now will get you exactly this place that
we're sitting at the static parchment
trick gets you there faster it do so
it's just any anytime we can increase
yeah of course you still need those
screens to do it the [ __ ] purest man
you're not just sucking heads up yes
you're pushing contaminant through and
that's the key with with the way that I
do it I separate you know I got the big
set of screens I do initially then I
take that and I separate it in the
smaller screens so I about each grade
and then I use my parchment paper I
don't use the parchment paper until then
just because it's the parchment paper
will pick up too much heads while I'm
doing that and I want to separate those
grades like we just did here so it's
darker lighter which is which is why I
sell those screens that's why those
screens are there to separate when I
have a four screen set in Wood they have
different microns to do exactly this to
separate out the heads that's what
they're there for they're not to clean
there's only one cleaning screen screen
the bottom one the 70 Micron so people
always ask me what are these other
screens for I'm like to capture heads
that are bigger than those screens and
those heads are substantially every
single stage is sub bub bag process of
course you want to separate them we
separate all of our resin glands in
water hash why don't we want to do it in
dry sift I mean honestly watch for the
10 screen sift kit coming soon well yes
but and you can look at it if you're
looking at it on on the on the medical
charts that they have now with every
single glandular sized head everything
about the THC molecule and everything
that it helps you out with so if you
separate everything 1 to 10 even 1 to
four there's different medicinal
qualities in each separate one as you go
different for each person I don't know
them all myself because they're
different they're not it's not a
standardization it's like for one guy
who might get the most out of a 73
another guy might say no I don't like
the 73 the 120 hits me where I need it
yes and so it's definitely this is why
Bubble Bags went from a three bag to a
four to a six to a seven to an eight bag
system when all of my competition was
claiming that I had no idea what I was
doing uh that I was using way too many
bags and um you know aside from payload
who actually added a bag they have a
nine bag kit uh which I just have never
felt the necessity to do I've played
around with those numbers and haven't
had enough requests but uh yeah there's
these little things things there's back
in the day there were bags sidewalls
that now Nick uses those sidewalls came
out 10 plus years ago and in fact Bubble
Bags experimented with them I just found
that because of the cost of the screen
and the it just didn't seem to to me a
make a better product or do anything
like people say it drains the bags
faster um I've I never found that I can
drain a bag in under 10 seconds yeah
jerk and puller I how you can pull a bag
tug or whatever it
is yeah exactly that's what we'll call
it the yeah I like that well what do we
hit four three that's three number four
is a is a older cured OG both 6 months
just just feel it oh yeah you can tell
right and and the smell of it is uh is
substantially different as well yeah of
course well what's that that's going to
be our and we've been talking about this
uh Horatio was talking about off gasing
of tpin but alcohol tpin um you know
hydr these like um alcohol-based tpin
that seem to evaporate out the quickest
that you I smell them in the fresher
fresher ones in particular with sift
that maybe the material's only been
dried for like weeks or maybe a month or
two compared to stuff that was dried for
a year like a cleaner like a pine salt
strong yeah it's like strong and so when
you cure hash you those are so volatile
they off gas in the Cure and they're
gone and when they leave you're left
over with the these now subtle um tpin
more subtle but not that can also come
across very very strong in their scent
which is so strange to me that something
that strong could have been suppressed
sometimes by one of these alcohol tpin
that are really not even that strong of
a smell it's just like a blanket where
you can't access those other those other
smells and then you cure your hash it
doesn't take a genius to get the same
kind of hash and there's so much
learning in this you guys like you have
to understand like how you learn is by
separating out all your grades curing
your hash not just like making it the
same all the time and smoking it right
away you know some of this has come to
me in my dreams too in my sleep I've
woken up and been like holy [ __ ] and
almost got up and went out to the shop
to try that little method yeah dude I
believe it when you're thinking about it
I've got a I've got a box at home that
um and a list that I'm going to this is
my plan on my next video Wicked and uh
it's which is d420 k d420 k YouTube yep
so you should che check that out it's
it's going to have I've got a list of
things that are positively charged and
negatively charged and I have mostly
everything on that list in this box of
of tools to see exactly what charge is
the best what holds the best charge what
picks up the best what deflex the best
you know whatever it is yeah plus I've
got I've got this Tesla on order oh
Tesla coil this little yeah so I'm going
to I'm going to see what it does with
that too and there's there's so much
that just playing around yeah but you
know the parchment paper is the most is
is the collects the most separates the
the worst like it it really helps out a
lot yeah it's a quick quick process well
you know it it's it it cuts the time
down like less than half so shout out to
me m McMan maze I just grabbed the wrong
bom m
YouTube thank you that was uh that
[ __ ] trick works change change the
game in in in in my eyes you know
another game Cher cuz cuz the the the
iTunes card for me yes the iTunes card
for me was like uh you know I discovered
the little bit of the contaminant and
then the good clean I was like oh cool
so you know I I spread that I shared
that because of course why not and then
uh mhm he was telling me and his
comments that that was an influence on
his part and then he uh come up with
that parchment paper and holy [ __ ] and
you can you can follow it right back to
skunkman Sam through M to Darren through
me through skunkman Sam like yeah and
all well it was like for me it was
direct from I was lucky enough to have
my information come direct from from Sam
just in the sense of just learning about
sifting because first all he really did
was show me sift and so then I was like
I gotta get like I didn't know how he
was making it but I looked into you know
hashish and it was like screens and I
already had a multiscreen ke box and it
was like okay do this we need more than
one screen and so I finally got to a
point where I got to a tighter screen
and I was like okay like I can card
contaminant through which only worked
because I did it one time accidentally
in the very very cold mhm and it changed
the structure of the resin it changed
everything people are trying these
techniques in too warm condition if you
can't get yourself steing your resin if
you can't get yourself into the right
conditions which is cold cold cold if
you can do that then you can start
playing around and doing all these
really cool experiments that may or may
not hit for you they're going to have a
better chance of hitting if you have the
resin in the condition that it needs to
be in which is a dry and B cold dry and
cold
yeah very nice a ni and one thing I was
I that was REM Ed of me with when you
were telling me about your screens and
stuff like that before when I got the
screens in the beginning when I got the
tumbler and there's that that stuff I I
figured that what you carded through the
70 screen the bottom cleaning screen was
the [ __ ] everyone thought that yeah and
of course that is what what the what was
taken from that everyone thought that it
was right up there with 70 um OG another
OG yeah um well we haven't even hit this
one yet have I did did you yeah I
pressed up a little hit the [ __ ] going
on behind for 20K what's wrong with you
it was nice it was uh it was it was diff
it wasn't actually as enjoyable as these
ones this one was nice still melted just
as much it just didn't I think some of
the turkey well you know what it is I'll
tell you right now
okay Sugar Leaf yeah bud oh there you go
that's there you go I don't know why I
didn't tell you that I totally [ __ ]
well you did just now yeah
yeah
[Music]
yeah yeah yeah
yeah dos that's the absolute difference
yeah Sugar Leaf and Bud oh it's a pretty
substantial difference night and day
yeah AB in in dry sift anyway I find
that there's some sort of a haish plant
matter cellulose taste that is passed on
and I've even how you explain it to me
so they can do it
themselves how how you get that smell
how you acquire how how you know it's
either from bud or from the leaf well
you know what it would be the difference
the easiest way to tell would be to put
a bag of leaf into a you know put a
bunch of leaf into a little bag and put
a bunch of Bud into a little bag and
just open those after an hour of them
off gassing and sitting in the bag or
jar and open them and smell each one and
one will smell like hay which will be
the leaf it's just chlorophyll or
whatever it is that's present more in
that like in a lesser con it's in a
higher concentration than resin glands
whereas butt is just so stacked with
resin glands that you you can get the
nice smell obviously it's nothing
compared to when you extract just the
heads yeah and then that smell is like
just the P the but it's just
unbelievably different and smell taste
totally everything you know the buzz is
is still killer from the Sugar Leaf and
you know this trash turns into your
stash quite easily like
it's that it's still [ __ ] melty and
killer yeah it melted into a liquid for
sure
coconut oil infused with uh THC I love
eating yeah I woke up with mine this
morning got to have
it for you
D really nice flavors and just an
amazing uh smorgus Borg of even though
that's all OG so far there's been
nuances and differences in the different
size heads from the tpine profiles and
the cannabinoid profiles and then
hitting three bud and then going to a
leaf and then going back to a bud I
believe
mhm absolutely pretty good I'm
absolutely blasted it's crazy because
we've got one two three four five six
more to hit well that's a lot that is a
lot W okay that one do
here did you mark that no that's the one
just hit went worked out okay that's the
one I just
hit and then yeah getting out of here
tomorrow it'll be
good it will be good looking forward to
seeing uh the crew in Jamaica looking
forward to seeing
Tony yeah it'll be uh I'm sorry that I
missed the conference that was just
there recently I really tried to make it
out but my schedule was just not
allowing me to leave for that that
period of time so more was as early as I
could get
out so strong such a bite in the lung
that just uh yeah it was really
nice
super
that keeps you from really
talking yeah totally like bite yeah I
like the uh head space of it it's really
like intense in the head like super body
numbing in the sense of like any pain or
discomfort you have is definitely gone
in the high of this this strain which
obviously people know OG is
extremely extremely
medicinal for sort of you know pain
relief and that sort of nerve damage and
whatnot I've heard a lot of people say
OG has been the one for them well or any
variety of we list a couple of here and
I'm going to let you take a pick which
ones you want to try here next sure
one's called HS I call it holy [ __ ] holy
[ __ ] because it's basically a you know a
a mixture of some bags that I've got
some of my Bros with their medical
licenses and their gr shows that bring
me some of their Leaf their Sugar Leaf
and uh I forget what it's called that
sort of stuff and it's just a few bags
of Swag that's killer stuff I always
call it a lucky day profile but uh yeah
I call her holy [ __ ] the lucky day and
then we got the Holy Grail cush oh more
holies all of this hash is holy holy
water we got the Goji ogi oh it should
be holy GOI holy [ __ ] Goji OG this is
just question mark it's just a big
question I don't know what it is it
should be holy question then we got the
diesel that's tasty flavorful tasty
tasty that's the one where once you hit
it all every other hit tastes like that
and then uh we got some 70 Micron of uh
I don't know I don't know question am
again so I don't know I think uh you
know the diesel is a dominating flavor I
get like it's like the Astro Boy that
Astro Boy it didn't matter what I what
we smoked after the Astro Boy hit still
tastes like Astro Boy of course crazy
super strong so these will be the same
way because it's so strong so maybe
we'll go we'll take these two out cuz we
know the names of them yeah the holy
grail and the Goji all right let's do it
up let's GOI down all righty Goji Goldie
apparatus for all you fish headss out
there and um this is the these are
carded and from sugarleaf as well not
the bud
okay beautiful well I can't tell you the
last time I sat down and just hit like
10 different full melt dry
sets
cheers oh [ __ ] this is like a
would be like a Legends of hashish
towards
uh yeah well if we have a Legends in in
uh Canada ever i' i' i' definitely do it
I'd like to I would like to enter a
competition or try it out just because
uh what would you enter out of all of
these that you brought what would you
enter um Diesel and OG the duo I would
enter too yeah absolutely and you know
there's other strains we're working with
that hands down I would enter as well I
would put in some entries and if I was
uh to know that I was doing this you
know within a year something like that a
year in advance I
would I would make some of the the
utmost purest prettiest hash that I
could ever make and I would put it away
until then and I would open it maybe
three times to let it gas off and then
seal it up again yeah until then and it
would just be it would be something a
beautiful thing something [ __ ] right
from
right from love man period it's all I
could say I guess it be the best way to
describe it couldn't come from anywhere
else I love making the hash I love
sifting it it's I'm a person that has no
patience for a lot of different things
and you know all that [ __ ] High strong
[ __ ] crazy son of a gun but this I
have a patience for all day had a very
nice
taste um grabbed me for sure got me a
good head Buzz
just still taste that difference between
the bud and the leaf absolutely it is a
it is a difference
yeah yeah you definitely want to be
bringing sift made from Bud to Legends
oh yeah there's there would
be I would it's so smooth and like it's
the difference might be subtle to some
but it's massive to others well to uh to
the judges of those types of
competitions
yeah you this stuff wouldn't even be the
the the the leaf even though even though
pure good everything it is and the
microscope everything still different
than the bud and and and and if somebody
had a lesser quality but from Bud right
it would win over that because of that
flavor that that after and those guys
would be on it all over it particularly
uh Sam and
Dave well that's why I would enter the
bud would not even waste the judge's
time with sugar beef I would keep that
for myself in my and smoking that one's
got me coughing for sure like not just a
turpine cough but that little bit of
that that difference whatever that is
whatever that taste and smell is from
the leaf to the bud it's weird cuz I
really rarely got that in like that it
seemed to wash off in water because I
remember running batches of water hash
from Sugar Leaf and I mean real Sugar
Leaf real trim not no fan Leaf at all
and it came out
spectacular like as nice as the butt cuz
I ran the same bud before as well and
just thought oh this is going to even be
nicer and we were kind of like okay it's
it's still a 9.5 or whatever but I don't
know we were just thinking it was going
to be a
yeah oh my golly
doodle Holy Grail eh the Holy Grail cous
it's the cush man you got any of them
you know reason I say it like that is
cuz uh um what is it Bill Clinton yeah
in the movie
uh Pineapple Express okay I don't
remember he's talking he's talking to
Seth Rogan I think and or not Seth Rogan
Seth uh oh I think I now remember he we
Whispers over or something and says
something this is the this is the OG or
this is the something cush it doesn't
say cush he says
cush this is the cous
this is the Holy Grail cous it's the
cous man you guys need some cous get
it's made out it's made out of really
good Sugar Leaf
actually you know what there was a batch
that was made with Sugar Leaf and with
bud this might be the one with Bud
because it looks really nice and it
smells really nice it has that smell
we'll just have to see once we smoke it
cuz we'll be able to tell them yep true
like I'm leaning more towards the line
of it's from the
just from the look of it and the smell
that I had
mhm yes uh well once again I'll need for
the herb
iron no no not at
all if it needs that it's not clean
enough and I need to clean it some more
right that's the way I look at it or
it's Whited out and you got to heat it
up a bit now the Whiting out what's the
bad parts of that is there a bad part to
it cuz I've you know I have stuff that
I've that seems to be Whited out and it
still melts beautifully and smoked
killer and I get I mean you know the bad
part is the longer you let it go that
it's okay here's the bad part get it
tested and see what is making it white
out if it's just Tarpin and it's natural
then probably nothing's going to be
wrong if water is present then mold can
occur and if there's mold in there and
and that's that's kind of like from my
perspective the older guys that every
time they ever have seen it it's to them
told them water has that hasn't been
dried properly generally cuz that's what
it was back in the day now we start
seeing it with some dry sifts is it
because the tur too fresh was done in
the ice ice cold so the resin heads were
frozen nice and add fresh like that and
then put together so that moisture is
doing that maybe yeah you know maybe so
it's it's hard to say that really we
don't know until we get a lab and we
start testing these things it's all just
a bunch of people sitting around and
theorizing about oh I think it's this
and I think it's that and it's great
they're all cool ideas and Concepts and
thoughts but none of them are basic uh
based on reality as much as based on our
assumptions of reality that's right
there's no fact there's no fact in any
it unless there is fact behind it and
someone out there knows about it send us
the link I'd love to learn more and
more
absolutely you know it used to be about
smoking [ __ ] dope and all that kind
of stuff and it's taken the the world
has taken it in such a
greater picture it's just uh it's true
did you hit that not yet hitting the
cous
well I'm definitely the highest I've
ever been the day before I'm flying out
of the
country then again I've never left right
after a Legends cuz that would be crazy
to try and wake up the next day after a
Legends which is literally like what I'm
doing right here except with 27 to 35
hits all in a row all in a very short
period of time probably the length of
this video non-stop just bang bang bang
bang and there's really only a few
people that can sit at the table and get
that done I'm telling you like it's you
start sweating you start kind of like
holy [ __ ] and you got to pace yourself
too like you'll notice I'm not taking my
regular siiz monster well I don't take
monster dabs but I I do take dabs that
are much bigger than I would uh than I
normally uh take than I'm taking right
now well B baked but uh yeah it's
flavorful it's delicious and uh still
got four to
go how was that one for
you one to the
head oh
yeah awesome these are looking great
dude got them all nice
L maybe we'll start the next row right
here and do three
rows take your time brother that was a
that was a big one Darren's just taking
full size the biggest rip that he can
take he's like oh [ __ ] okay I can do
this
cut shut it down all these weird edits
in the video d fall dir fell down again
this video actually took 14 hours to
film we just cut it down
49 minutes that was uh that was the most
enjoyable hit off off of all of them
because I the pins and needles in my my
whole head Tangled I seen the little
stars [ __ ] doing the loops and I
[ __ ] had to hold my head down serious
that's awesome yeah I love rips like
that we got four M to go the fourth one
the diesel flavor I'm almost [ __ ]
scared of both that really yeah oh not
me man I'm looking forward to that one
cuz it's so do it of course so much
flavor yes it is flavor but you know you
you you love the flavor more but I I I
love the flavor too but the power from
it really surprises me like it uh it
bites me and um I don't know maybe the
turps get me high on it higher I don't
know but like uh yeah it could be it
could be modulating the effect if you're
smoking like 10 rips of OG before you
hit the diesel that could definitely uh
shut tone it down well just give you a
really good high on your diesel thinking
man this Diesel's super strong it's like
okay cuz generally when I say that I've
never considered Calo uh the diesel um
some of the Tangi is some of these
strains I've never thought of them as
the most powerfully strong strains what
did you think do you think it came from
bud or Leaf I think it could have come
from Leaf it's possible I think so too
yeah I didn't you know I I took the
first smell I smelt Leaf then you were
like and it smells pretty good then I
took another smell of it was smell more
smooth yeah it's got a nice Amber kind
of reddish
color that Holy Grail cou well this one
I believe is from Bud excuse me it's the
70 um yeah I don't smell the any leaf on
that one it's the 70 question mark the
what the [ __ ] I don't know the the what
the [ __ ] all right
well here we go
again well us should have to have them
now before I leave dude I've got so much
[ __ ] to do today that I'm not doing that
what I'm laughing please keep it down
okay yeah oh yeah no problem it's a big
house you can na find the corner
somewhere need Oreo
Oreo hey tough
guy come here buddy oh he is in here I
was going to say if he hasn't come by
now he might not be in here come get up
here you see this guy tough guy man huh
you're the toughest little doggy I know
he's a pretty tough tough dog Oreo's
been uh probably not even allowed up at
the table and he's being bad right now
he's been hit by a car he's been
attacked by raccoons he's been um taken
by a coyote Tak him to go eat survived
the mall a raccoon tried to eat him too
yeah trying to eat it was it was a
multitude of raccoons actually
unfortunately buddy yeah they [ __ ]
gang beat him man yeah they they pierced
his throat 15 times you can feel it when
you rub his throat he's kind of got
these Ripples and oh yeah yeah that's
where he got
mangled little sons of [ __ ] you think
of how hardcore that is he's had his
throat mangled oh that's worse than a
[ __ ] outright gang prison R he's been
hit by a car which is like well like
getting hit by a car you've been there
you know what that feels like and he's a
little [ __ ] 8B dog that got hit by a
car oh totally this guy is so tough man
he impresses the hell out of and then
taken the equivalent of what would be
the equivalent of like having like a
multitude of dudes in Bell clavas up
next to you in a van and put a bag over
your head and pull you into the van and
then stab in the animal world well he
was just in the mouth and it was shaking
him a bit so they weren't quite and he's
got a titanium hip and it's mounted on
both sides goes right through so I think
it had its teeth on his titanium and he
couldn't really sink in so we ended up
dropping for that titanium that's
unbelievable man lucky for that car
hitting yeah everything happens for a
reason eh somehow some way that's what
they say man
that's what they say Oreo cookie you
tough guy little
Oreo I love doggies I love animals
they're
cool I keeping around just in case you
know zombie apocalypse and you got to
eat them to survive or something you
never know right they're the first ones
to go he might be a he might be
breakfast for
you hey little sausages that one had a
real nice I would I would say that it's
very likely that that came from Bud okay
buddy have you no you're hitting
everything after
me much smoother delayed
cough could be from the bud I believe it
is actually just a bunch of the bottoms
of the bags of Bud pretty pretty strong
definitely feel that throughout and you
know after taking this many hits people
are going to how can you tell if it's
it's like listen you can tell believe it
or not I'm going to go wash my hands
this this level of uh of quality um
every time you hit it you are going to
feel an increase and potentially a
change in your high especially if you're
hitting different strains what what was
the strain
Darren SE oh 70 Micron question mark we
don't know what the strain is so that
was interesting it was different from
the other things that he has here
probably a collection of a multitude of
strains cuz it had a very complex flavor
to it musky and cushy but something else
maybe some of these other you know uh OG
or GOI or maybe the um e some diesel or
something something that's changing the
profile very nice very
nice so Darren's just washing his hands
um maybe I'll hit the next one while
he's uh doing
that
oh
HS holy
[ __ ] I says
pardon oh yeah there's a lucky day I
said want to get n of those doggy oils
off my fingers into my pressed piece
right ah you're precious that's right
into my pressed piece that's right thank
you oh god oh look at that SP it that's
okay it's going in the bowl soon so this
has just been a great session this is a
70 seven eight yeah we just hit eight
Darren's hitting his eighth rip I just
finished mine number Nine's about to go
down here it's holy [ __ ] then we're
going to hit the question mark and
finish it off with the New York City
Diesel super Orange Citrus flavor but
not just lemon it's deeper it's valine
merine oopen I don't know there's a
variety of tpin in that orange that
makes it that orange it's uh I would say
it's the difference between if you know
what orange oil is versus um delemon the
one single tpine extracted from Orange
Rines look it up Google there's a
difference and the difference is is
orange oil is stacked full of mono cesco
and and tpin and Horatio does that right
he does the delemon yeah yeah you've had
his product very strong very very strong
yeah you feel it instantly right from
your head to your toes you just like a
blanket going over you yeah you you do
feel it I like that a lot not unlike
this
Tri yeah I mean the first time I hit um
Horatio oil and I've only hit a few holy
[ __ ] holy [ __ ] holy [ __ ] um I've hit his
oil uh just maybe three or three times
now and um the first time I hit it he
was like okay you got to hit it like he
was directing me how I should hit it and
I was like okay it's his oil it's his
his Vape he's got it all low temped out
he's like it's going to be about a 30
second hit so he told me I was like okay
I'll I won't suck too hard I'll go real
slow and steady and so I I started
hitting it and then he was like oh I
want you to hold it in for about 10
seconds just hold it in and then blow it
out real real slowly while
I do this of course I'm ripped instantly
and then get a message from my wife that
I have to go
home so it was like really smoked that
yet tell you and how was that did you
well it was like uh you feel it right
down to your toes yeah it was completely
you know very high yeah much like I am
right now actually it uh it works really
well I like I like that product he uh
it's impressive and it's clean yeah it's
it's it's clean and you know holy [ __ ]
dude holy clean is is uh is important if
you're inhaling it into your lungs and
your body and you want to use it for
medication and all that it's uh I think
it's important even if you're just
recation we all deserve it that's the
way I put it and then it seems to be
like cuz I'm not trying to be an elitist
or anything I just really feel that
everyone deserves the best they all
deserve this level of quality they
deserve they deserve to be able to grow
the best their own self in their
backyard and a greenhouse to make enough
to make medication throughout the winter
time and their oils and their tinctures
and their age their medibles and
everything just to keep themselves
active with it and keeping their own
cannaboid systems fed and keeping
healthy it used to be happening at one
time at one point in in the world but
you know maybe one point one one time
again we're getting closer right it's
all about the medicine everybody should
be able to do it that one was sharp on
the throat probably the uh the um from
Leaf yeah nice but sharp out of all of
the in fact the sharpest by far out of
all of them let me know if you if you
see that or if that's just a unique
thing to me could be off to the ninth
hit the ninth hit I really felt like cuz
I was taking the hit and I was like
halfway through I was like right on and
then as I got about 3/4s of the way
through I felt it before I exhaled it
and I didn't feel any of that with
these not a single so I don't know I
know if it's uh my own sensitive throat
after nine rips like he said or if it's
um if he's going to be feeling a little
bit of a sharper rip on this
one you know you do become an elitist
when you just get this many beautiful
strains put in front of you and the
bottom line when you have this this many
you can find one that's shitty well they
can't another way of saying it is they
can't all be the best yeah that's right
you know what I mean especially when
some of these like four or five of them
are just outstanding like made from Bud
obviously the color is lighter the smell
is Daner the hit is harder and stronger
and tastier [ __ ] come
on holy [ __ ] yeah yeah sharper y did you
get it um when you were taking the hit
or not until after taking it all right
cool so then there's definitely
something it's uh it's made out of leaf
too right that's the Sugar Leaf yeah but
there you have other Leaf ones that
didn't give me that sharp of a RI
it could be because of uh anything a
million variables the size of the heads
the screen size yeah the contamination
in it exactly what yeah one thing that
might have gotten in there that we're
feeling that shouldn't be in there like
you never know but I know that there
wouldn't be anything like spray some
sort of spray on it some sort of
nutrient
spray or yeah there there's NE oil I
would taste right away yeah there's
nobody can hide that from me there's
nothing in it sprayed on those plants I
didn't taste anything in it it was just
sharp I'm excited I really just want to
hit that diesel but let's uh hit this
surprise that could be the oldest stuff
too that oh there you go yeah yeah yeah
the driest you know what I'm saying
totally and this this is a thing
sometimes when you evaporate turpins we
were talking about this earlier you can
lose harsh ones in the curing process
and release really beautiful ones
however it does work the other way
around where sometimes you lose your
tpin that were smooth and now you're
left with these harsh ones and uh yeah
it's just a matter of us learning which
Tarpin are those what is that degreg is
it temperature is it light is it you
know what how are we getting to these
end results we we can see the
differences in all the hashes and their
subtle you know color differences and
and flavor and taste profiles even in
the same strain separated out into the
separate screens which people ask me all
the time why do you have separate size
heads why do you have four size screens
in the wood and then only and but
different four size screens in the metal
and it's like because the four screens
are for separating heads you're never
going to like there's a cleaning screen
in that kit too but really that kit
should be a three- screen kit that comes
with the metal framed larger kit because
those are just to prepare you to take
that resin and then go over here drop
tune it well yeah drop it through the
two screens you know card it with
parchment over the 70 and then man I'll
tell you at the end of the day you're
pretty darn happy with the results
question mark question mark question
mark it's uh what the [ __ ] I'm not sure
dude I'm going to hit some what the
[ __ ] oh this
diesel I'm most excited about that one I
have to tell you it is the tastiest it
is the most like to me this diesel is uh
to the diesel is to you like the asra
boy is to me nice you know what I mean
like when I when I hit that Astro Boy it
was just like what the [ __ ] is theace
wow it almost makes you want to get up
and start
running just yeah Astro Boy definitely
has that effect that's
c99 Z Diva question mark what the [ __ ]
what the [ __ ]
pretty darn nice pretty darn
flavorful don't be blowing
parchments very nice little tiny bit
sharp but I think that might be because
I just took 10
rimps and then got sharpened by this
guy oh I'm excited for the diesel cuz I
know exactly what that's going to hit be
oh you know what we should do we should
put the silicone carbide nail in and do
all of these again and talk
about [ __ ] yeah let's do it oh my God
holy [ __ ] that'd be [ __ ] I'll do
that's part two coming soon yes dude
that's such a funny
[ __ ] [ __ ] did you hit this [ __ ] yes
I no you hit that one cuz that's the
only thing keeping us from Miss I can't
be uh
diesel [ __ ] wimping out no [ __ ] on
a hit you're not wimping out dude you
[ __ ] championed out on all these rips
come on this is ridiculous
yeah I don't even do this at home dude
come on it just we didn't even plan to
really do this it was kind of like we
weren't thinking we're like yeah we're
just going to sit down we're going to go
through all the flavors and I don't know
I thought there were five or six in
there I didn't count them I didn't open
it that uh Diesel's next this a
diesel and this is a
70 question mark Or I don't you the 7
yeah that's the what the [ __ ] yeah this
just the what the [ __ ] not even know
what size screen it is yeah it's totally
what what the
[ __ ] oh my God it's putrid
putrid it's almost too orange turpy like
holy [ __ ] does that thing
week like a baby diaper almost when I
smelt
it it was just
likeo lemony
I could taste the lemon as I was
inhaling for a
cough holy [ __ ] it's you know smelling
like that fresh after a to hurts my
lungs just like a
tote holy [ __ ] yeah you're going to
enjoy that one yeah think that one's
going to send it all we're going to have
an outright [ __ ] dual panic attack
we're finishing off okay bubble
man's we're just like I'll see you later
yeah okay bye I'll you'll just see me
walking down the stairs I'm out of here
bye holy Christ they falling down the
stairs
that sh out of my
coffee
awesome
Stanley Stanley
are shout out to Stanley how you doing
Stan hey Stan thanks for all your great
equip thanks for all your [ __ ] Goods
man lunch kits and clothing and work
gear Stanley's the man I would normally
blow that out but not in such presence
of so much open dry sift I just don't
want to see black bits of carbon [ __ ]
yes of course not I would cry oh would
be contaminating them can't be
contaminating the hash after it takes
[ __ ] hours to decontaminate made it
months to [ __ ] grow
it it takes a while before you harvest
the heads and you know if you
really if you really want to harvest the
heads in the most proper
ways yeah you you dry it in the in in in
your best you know if everybody has
their temperatures and their methods and
and uh we've been I've been told a
method just recently that I want to try
and that's a a 14-day cure at
56° hanging on the plant trimmed up
right like hanging on the stock not all
just the whole plant Johnny be telling
you about that uh no actually uh my
buddy Jake somebody told him
that uh down here awesome yeah David
Allen was talking about that a little
while back and uh John really was like
receptive to it he was it really harvest
the heads proper I went I went and
visited um a fairly big the heads I
guess before the Harvest yeah and I went
into their cure room and um it was very
cold uhhuh I was like sweet good on you
guys cold enough not to preserve the
tpin it's I think it's 57°
58° have mold spores starting to grow so
if you have it like that then you can
have that process happen but if you take
it down to 56 55 MH you don't have those
those mold SP preservation of the tpin
dude you walk into the room and it
smells but it doesn't smell like what
you know of your room to take that and
harvest it into your into your uh your
um butt into your hash right you
couldn't take it off that the 14 days
and then Harvest it because the resin
would be too [ __ ] soft and beautiful
oh yeah it needs to Beed it would it
would then have to be dried exactly in a
completely dry room no humidity low
humidity low temperature still yes and
just let it do its thing for maybe a
month or two yeah exactly before you
even move those things off glands those
gland heads we want them to raisen up a
little bit you know they don't want them
as these giant water balloons with
perfect edges around the heads It's like
because here's why here's why too with
my parchment paper when I'm doing my
parchment paper part that that uh that I
learned from from par the parchment
paper parchment paper it it'll or even
the iTunes card when you're doing it and
it's and it's fresher and it's not cold
enough you're going to just smear heads
and it's B on your C you're not going to
get a complete easy complete surface
going ACR you're going to have all these
beads absolutely which I've talked about
in my videos of how important it is to
clean that card and if it's doing that
that your your situation is that you're
not cold enough or you're heating it up
too much by being too fast too hard on
it yeah but I'm telling you if you get
it cold enough you can beat it up pretty
good yes you know what I mean like cold
enough is like in the minus degrees not
like 50° doing it up there in my shop my
wh BL steam out of my breath yeah if it
can be- 10 or- 15 or- 20 like guaranteed
you will see differences in those
temperatures in the way the resin gland
reacts to being cleaned yeah yeah so
it's nice he's got the super cold
weather we've had a super mild um winter
oh we had a super mild winter too like
right now it's Ines we had maybe uh we
had maybe a week you were dressed up
pretty warm in we had a week for for
some really cold couple of weeks but but
it's been in the in the pluses and in
the low minuses when January January
it's raining we got the we got the
Winter Olympics are happening up there
this month this next month starting and
all the snow it's been yeah and it's
been raining and it's just the worst
winter I've seen in Prince George when
yeah it's it's rough up here too like
the snow even if you look across at the
mountains there's like no sow no and
there's a little bit over on the back
glaciers here but it's like wow is that
a lot of rock face oh there's some up
there compared to what we're used to but
you know now we are um baked on 10 rips
Darren's going to finish it off with a
New York City Diesel 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
this is number 11 for uh Darren I just
did my 11th it was absolutely
spectacular tasting I hope that you guys
tried to do the d420 K Bubble Man
Gauntlet uh dry sift Gauntlet we don't
expect you to have a denail or a
Mothership whatever kind of pipe or way
you've got to smoke it we accept and we
uh throw this Gauntlet down to all of
you that are watching watching 11 rips
in whatever the time of this video is
won't you please try and stay conscious
I am not done yet so I'm not you know I
could fall down D's going to take us
out with a
rip thanks for watching Bubble man's
world guys I appreciate it peace
[Music]