[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh we are here in downtown Vancouver we
got our special guest Brendan dabs in
the house from bub dacious how's it
going we got many many dab delicious
stickers so of course we're going to
show you one and of course uh Horatio is
in the house as
well we're here at the what is this the
Cannabis economy conference is that the
name of it it's definitely a unique type
of conference uh it's happening right
below us here I could show you later on
with the camera we're kind of on this
little rooftop Terrace and uh it's quite
private and it's all round T events it's
been different for sure somewhat
interesting there's a little bit of uh
one-on ones going on but I have to say
the most most interesting conversation
that I've heard since I've been here uh
was the conversation we were all just
having about tpen and the modulating
effects and how we've all come to learn
about these different things and that's
why I wanted to turn the camera on
hoping that we would uh have a little
bit more of that conversation give you
guys a little introduction to this event
that we're at there are no cameras uh
being brought in but uh uh we'll still
end up having a couple more sessions
before it's all said and done so why
don't we just have a few dabs and uh
maintain our conversation that we were
uh yeah I mean it didn't take long
before we're like tp's danger we know
you all want them because you see us
with them but why are we acting so
conservative now that um we've
experienced them MH and um that's a hard
thing for any public to swallow I think
you have a strong voice in this because
you work with the tpine delimine and one
of the first things you mentioned to me
at your house which was not something
that most people would have mentioned I
think they would have tried to sweep it
sweep it under the the rug but when I
was asking uh you you know how you would
remove this orange liquid from your
clear liquid and then brought it back to
a clear liquid we were talking about
what's in that orange liquid and you
know the the the sort of uh politically
correct or not politically correct but
the sort of you know the the the
business savvy uh let's protect my own
ass person would have said it in a way
like oh those are the Citrus oils that
are not delimiting and one of the first
things he said was those are that's like
the Mystery Oil that's whatever it is I
mean it could be from this plastic gas
that the delimiting comes in and you
were really aware that tpin can be
costic they can literally break you got
to I met somebody downstairs at this
conference and they're like what you
extract with hexane and I'm like that's
funny I extract with cyc hexane he's
like what's cycle hexane and I'm like oh
it's called the leonine um I extract
with a solvent stronger than you and I
understand why you extract with hexane
for medical purposes not um for
recreational dabs um and the amounts are
working with he's really happy with how
clean he can get his product in the end
and I'm like you you know as well as I
do how much stronger hexane is than
typical um light hydrocarbons he's like
yep and I'm like well then you have a
perspective on how powerful lening is
and it's just one in an array of
potential um things
so if you don't respect it in the same
like basically you have liquid butane
it's that powerful of a hail I'll just
is that g I'll just take all of that
rubber and incorporate it into myself if
you don't respect it in that way um you
can get really [ __ ] up so um the fact
that I take clear got the red I'm like
all of this red was invisible and
everyone said that was clean Delan it
was food it was food gra and I'm like
smell this you know if you put this in
your body it ain't good it is the
craziest thing I don't know if you saw
the video uh when I went to htio it's
called Horatio's inner sanctum and he
brings me into his place and he shows me
a variety of things but it is the most
powerful thing you could see it's he's
got clear liquid in a jar and it's
delemon and it is not uh distilled or
not cleaned yet it's just food grade
it's just food grade so then out of that
through his own processes he's extracted
this nasty orish red liquid that came
out of the clear and then he was left
with clear again but two clears do they
look the same they both look clear like
water and then in the middle he's got
this jar of like and it is it's bad it's
like he even showed it to me when he
allowed it to um dry right out into a
cake or into a a waxy it just does not
polymer yeah almost like a plastic so
nasty dude that it was just like it's a
very powerful lesson for people to no
matter what process you are doing
because of course in our community we
support a variety of processes I'm known
as a a solventless guy I love the
solventless quiver but we have friends
that that run hydrocarbons both of these
guys are in that list uh delemon and
butane you use what else other than
butane I use just butane butane but then
you also do water extraction you're
you're not a one trick pony no which is
what we're trying to kind of promote
more and more and more Horatio is also
not a onetick pony he makes Incredible
uh dry sift I know that he has the
ability to make water hash he makes his
delimine extracts uh he makes all of his
purified uh thcas and the tpine
extractions so uh we're not trying to
promote any one thing over the other as
much as really it seems like the mission
today and from now on is to unveil and
uncover as many of the footprints that
are leaving behind negative aspects in
any of our extraction processes whether
it's molds from water uh whether it's uh
rubber gaskets from delimiting that
hasn't been cleaned properly uh whether
it's mer capatin present in dirty butane
that was bought in lowquality cans at a
grocery store these are things that need
to be discussed and if we can stop sort
of dividing ourselves eles from one
another and sit down as as a group which
we're doing right now it sort of moves
the the it forwards the conversation in
a in a greater way in my opinion we all
learn from each other for sure
absolutely well I mean everyone always
forgets I'm like you understand butane
created me I didn't understand boiling
points and it it was all through the
rise of that era um that's kind of why
like when we ever get a chance to shoot
the next series of videos I'm going to
go through a whole another side of
contamination that has nothing to do
with principal swing all the way the
principal names like is butane bad I'm
like no butane isn't bad we all know
we've smok the a joint and we can Huff
that now there are other ways in which
if butane is run in this way if this
filter isn't cleaned often really the
underside of um bad extraction artists
you know people who we always hear the
situation W it was a closed loop but why
did it blow up oh they never replaced
their gaskets never I'm like
that that is literally comparable to the
Simplicity of cleaning your water with a
water filtration system and it becomes a
wonderful thing while you're replacing
your filters and the minute you stop and
I've talked to Addison about this the
other day is that now you are con we
we're always concentrating that's what
we're doing so when you all of a sudden
stop removing that filter what you're
doing is you're still concentrating as
that thing's breaking down I'm like
where did it go that rendered into the
oil you've been getting rid of your
filter as soon it starts to break down
it's no good it's no different than
maybe all the mold is coming from not
establishing proper protocols for bag
cleanup immediately after use that's
probably the mold isn't even in the grow
half the time it's in mold is everywhere
it's like floating around but the last
the last R surfaces I'm like if the weed
was clean if someone was really thought
they did their best how could they [ __ ]
it up I'm like it would be that they
didn't know how to clean their bags
properly when they not well they know
what everybody knows and they everyone's
learned but what do you do in a pinch
what do you do when you're under the gun
do you need to clean it with a alcohol
but throw it in the dryer is that a way
to basically addressing this new world
where individual users are becoming
producers I think commercial uh level
extra actions I mean the the bags were
originally really you know for the
personal user they were never something
that was supposed to be set up for
commercial production uh you can produce
commercially with them of course but
it's it get get back to that yeah are
there small little bits and pieces that
are getting caught in the screen like I
think a stainless steel screen with many
hundreds of gallons uh you know the
mixers that go down into the into the V
the conle the conical cones those are
like things that you can run 25 or 50
lbs at a time you know you figure out
your thrashing versus how much material
is there versus water and ice and you
can really basically get it down so
you're getting your extraction ratio on
point you're not wasting by consistent
yeah you're becoming consistent but uh I
don't don't think that that'll be
that'll be done in stainless steel Vats
with chillers and you know I do like
things that can tolerate fire yeah I do
like BL it might kill me but I can
convience you know you can fly to
Jamaica with a pair of brand new bags
and then leave them behind to to someone
to have a little some opportunity it's
just yeah you got to be careful with
what you leave behind because there's no
way that the majority of people are
cleaning their bags the way I clean my
bags I don't think the majority of
people that that the thing is people end
up joining the um we talked a lot today
about the gray Market this new spirit
where anyone can become good some grower
could find out he has the gift in bubble
hash because he grew the right strain
sure and now he becomes the dude and
Instagram blows up but it doesn't
necessarily mean he came up at in a
culture in which he's learned the rules
to provide for people um they're very
different things and what so he was good
when it was all between 10 and 50 g but
as things go up as fatigue goes up as
you start getting secondary employees
everything what do you mean you didn't
clean it well we got to go capping it
yeah it's a I think a lot of people have
become caught up by joining some level
of production industry that's beyond the
personal on the homie you can poison
yourself you can poison your homie you
can punch your back but um as soon as
you could say money gets involved um
there's a different Karma very true
there's a different Karma completely
especially when you know when I talked
about this of ways that we're in this
gray area of removing ourselves from
what I call the prohibition based dollar
the profit margin that exists based on
prohibition based on I can make money on
this because if he gets caught with it
he's doing 20 years wow you that that's
a great profit margin but it's a totally
horrible profit to make you know what I
mean I like the idea of cannabis
becoming more of a positive profit
margin where it is medicinal it is fun
recreational it is preventative it does
have incredible value so let's charge a
little bit of money for that but what we
give them in return the people that are
paying for this is standards is the
highest quality of Standards so that
they can acquire the safest you know
best quality medicine or recreational
preventative uh product that they could
possibly uh access and that's where the
profit margin in my opinion it's a great
profit margin that's a great profit Marg
you know what I mean it's based on you
trading standards for your profit not
Brandon doing 20 years right well I mean
I think
one of the things about trading that
basically that's kind of why we get in
these arguments about medical because
medical always kind of in says well it
means standards doesn't it where
Recreation means PE PE whatever people
like and is I can get away with right
now which is a shifting what about Ken's
what he quote what he said today the guy
at our table instead of medical or
recreational he said I like to refer to
it as overthe counter and I was like I
thought unique yeah cuz everything
pretty much everything that you can be
sold over the counter has a guarantee do
not harm a within it that you can trust
it's when the guy gives you a
prescription that listen this stuff's
[ __ ] up you can get [ __ ] don't eat
more than two in a day so that over the
that over the counter trust means look
this has been you kind of stake your
karma on it as a brand and um I like the
I like the fact that you know everyone
says yeah I got my standards and it
doesn't [ __ ] up my chest but depending
on where your medicine is going you have
to be your standards have to meet where
it's going not yourself because I can be
a I can be a man that has a generation
of smokers that we're just going to take
it yeah it's not burning my chest and
but that's not that's always a trickle
down [ __ ] I'm like no if you f you
got to interact with your dispensaries
you got to where's this being used
anybody old using this is this being
used to for palea of care um cuz if so
then maybe these lipids or whatever I
have else in my product um is doing harm
again where for my buddies it's fine um
they're young and they can choose what
they want to choose and they like it um
I think there's got to be a choice level
and a jump in responsibility because
anything that could be provided over the
counter um you can pretty much sue if it
hurts you yeah and Sue big time and we
don't have that um here you're lucky if
you can bring back some weed that cuts
your throat well it's crazy all the
regulations on cannabis and they're
comparing it to alcohol and I'm just
like so this has like zero ld50 I don't
know what the ld50 for alcohol is but it
can't be that high alcohol's pretty de
it depends on the person it depends on
the person it can be pretty quick yeah
exactly so it's insane that we compare
it to what I would consider one of the
most um I I don't want to say dangerous
but I guess um it is gu it is linked to
so many deaths alcohol in so many
different uh ways through car accidents
or through spousal abuse or through
liver damage or through there's so many
different roads that lead back to death
with alcohol but it's incredible that we
could be discussing like oh well how
many milligrams should we allow it's
like no minimum like just whatever
people want like if people will buy
10,000 milligram treats then make make
people 10,000 Mig treats like why do you
want to make them eat 10,000 milligram
or worse like what was that guy saying
10 Mig yeah he just wanted to do that's
just over the top yeah the senator guy
he was like I think we should keep it to
10 okay maybe maybe 10 10 so you can
have 100 in your possession at a time
basically was like 100 milligrams would
be your maximum right Gorge yeah but
Bing that would be binge consumption
even baby MJ in the hospital here in
Vancouver is currently taking I believe
a th000 migs absolutely a day so look at
that and think of what he thinks is
binging in the you know she was just
prematurely born and she has all sorts
of problems with her it's it's a pretty
heavy story that's going on here right
now the the the the hospital sort of
took over and they they took um
possession of the child from through
child family services and then they said
that they were going to decide that they
were going to take this child off off of
the ventilator which would have been
maybe a death sentence for the child
saying that oh it's going to have
cerebral paly and all these other
problems uh well the young couple that
that are the parents they fought it got
a court injunction uh are giving the
baby cannabis oil because she has
seizures it's one of her problems and
it's helping alleviate and I think that
that's one thing that like I that I
really noticed about this conference is
is that um I think a lot of the people
that the legislators that we were we
were getting a chance to talk to really
have no idea about these things that
we're talking about like setting these
limits of hey a 10 mgram or 100
milligram is all you're allowed to be
able to have I think they have no idea
about these cases talking I think I'm
like how how can you do that chance to
talk to them it's like limiting research
that's exactly what it is I'm like
that's limiting medical research we
don't know how much it's going to take
to potentially solve spasms in someone
who's been shot so don't tell me we do
know treat it like alcohol we know that
everyone down there said over and over
and over again that it's all about the
patient PTI but I didn't really see any
patients invited to speak I think it
would have been good to have the patient
perspective and potentially get that
really unique a few really unique get
theing some bring in some guest speakers
Jessica Hawkins or the Nia Hawkins you
know just to kind of get a real a real
story on what they're actually a real
powerful story that is UN mutable it's
it's unarguable that's the future they
need to be told what needs to be done
I'm not I'm not getting the regulations
that made makes this ACC to everyone
like me I'm Notting theity of medicine
that my physical body needs I need more
yes I can trust cannabis but I cannot
trust all the in between parties and the
bottom line is it's a benign herb that
has no ld50 so on both of those sides of
the coin one that there are people
children in particular that are
extremely sick and suffering that need
much higher doses than the doses that
these Regulators are even considering
and that on the other side of that that
there is no ld50 for cannabis that there
is no uh detrimental dose that the worst
thing that you can have is just a a
bummer feeling it's like oh I ate too
much and yeah people and there's things
that counteract that's kind of why we're
so anal about what is cuz the thing is
it's not cannabis it's what's on it's
what can get in it's what can get passed
through so it's really a defense of the
plant to find I'm like there's no ld50
for cannabis but there is for what Some
Humans spray on it but the unique thing
about cannabis unlike any other
substance you can name is the Cannabis
comes with its own Protection Agency
which is these nucleation points in the
lungs these non-polar components that
protect the lungs I mean
I I couldn't understand it for years
when people were smoking the thick paper
with the glue on it just like ton and I
was just like Steve cubby was smoking
like ounces of weed a day and I was like
dude that can't be good for you and then
he went and got his lungs tested at some
crazy place in California and they were
like they were telling him that he had
the lungs of like a a young athlete and
he was like 48 years old old or
something at the time so it made me
realize it was before I knew about you
know Jim fra and him talking about what
I just literally mentioned about the
nucleation points and the non-polar
components it really made sense to me
when I learned that and it made me
realize wow that's really an important
factor for the BHO Community or any
Community using non-polar components to
make sure that you remove your nauseous
plant waxes that your product now no
longer has a safety net to protect you
from mhm so that's huge just get rid of
those nauseous plant waxes if you're
going to use a non-polar component
because you won't have polar components
present that are the nucleation points
in your lungs that do protect us from
papers and glues and all these nasty
things that are that are in cannabis
that somehow it's incredible I totally
get you cuz you know it's not like
there's a whole side of us that I
clearly smoke cigarettes with it and
wouldn't live without it and I'm I
wonder sometimes for the lifestyle I
lived I'm like are you saying the
[ __ ] cannabis protected me from the
cigarettes the alcohol alcohol the
boozing the toxins on the Cannabis the
[ __ ] [ __ ] it was handed to me with
and I'm like you know for the amount of
things I rely on today that should have
fallen apart for my current lifestyle
which is working to death in all these
new Realms I'm like yeah you know what I
would have died even now without
cannabis and probably back then so never
take my paranoia for the baby who
clearly can't take coughing up a lung um
right now for the fact that yes cannabis
does protect us against the things we've
done to cannabis but in pushing medicine
because what if there is that 10,000 mg
dose we can't let those um contaminants
also move with the current trends yeah
um to then ruin cannabis again and I
don't want to find out Mr does leave
permanent harm so let's get it out of
there before we ever get to a job big
enough that we concentrate too much of
it and hurt a kid or kill a kid because
she convulsed um still run air you know
what uh we're going to we're going to
pause it on that incredible dialogue is
always great to sit down with these guys
and uh you guys are going to see more of
this this is just the first little part
uh we've got to get down to our next
round table event in 15 minutes so
probably a few off camera dabs and uh
yeah we'll see you guys in a
[Music]
bit
hey guys back here at uh Brendan Dab's
hotel room uh we're just about to go
down and watch Horatio speak on the
stage down there on the rooftop Terrace
and uh he just showed up with
uh TP champagne some turp shamp good
morning hey that's okay Alison you're in
the picture too you're in the video hi
kick your cups we're so late oh this is
so good you guys don't even know we're
having TP champagne for breakfast for
breakfast oh yeah this is so TS thank
you so much brought some I think I
actually brought some and I just based
on can I ask you how is this going to
make me
feel what should I expect well none of
us are smoking so it shouldn't we did
smoke then it might modulate
something um we were doing some uh rosin
dabs well this is some I've only had
this one time but it was really lovely I
saw this oh
the rosin is protected look at that
that's awesome serious carbonation TP
juice right there see the way the
bubbles stack it's very important how
the bubbles stack you got to
stack all right we just have to glur
this and get out of here glur it that is
awesome so funny here here's the
knock okay all right well here's a
toast can I have baby can I have baby I
I don't know what you mean is that the
cup I'm kidding all right look at that
guys thank you thanks Horatio and the
turps and of course the beautiful
cannabis M it smells amazing it smells
amazing and it tastes really lovely and
light isn't that nice yeah that's really
good very carbonated and very delicious
great way to start it that's uh better
than morning coffee that's pretty it's
pretty tasty you throw some sweet skunk
in there uh this one was Kemo Kush Kush
with a little bit of My Little
Pony I Always Love My Little Pony all
right well there it is there we have it
we're uh we're going to head down and
watch her ratio talk we can't film any
of it but uh we'll come and have a
session later and talk to you
guys