okay
hello to the whole team adam bark today
we are going to go through the anatomy
of a concentrate rig
talk a little bit about dabbing talk a
little bit about the different types of
um materials that we'll be dabbing off
of the different types of pipes that are
available
and really kind of going over a whole
broad stroke of the entire process so
when i was originally asked to do this
uh it was told to me that some of the
people in the company had been telling
people about the different products that
we were making
in particular full melt hash and maybe
the question had arisen um how do you
consume it
so today after today's little 101 on
dabbing we should all be able to
understand uh the anatomy of the
concentrate rig the types of rigs um you
know concentrate rig water pipe uh the
types of nails which are titanium quartz
uh there are glass nails but that's
really the cheapest you can go there are
ceramic nails there are electric nails
all of which i have here in fact i also
have sapphire nails here on the table
today i'm going to be going through a
little bit
we can talk a little bit about the dome
vapor slide people aren't using those
too much uh anymore and then of course
the essential dab tools which i have all
here on the table which is the rig
the nails the torch uh the dabber tools
uh and of course the concentrate
containers that are holding the hash
that we'll be dabbing here today for
this 101 we'll go through proper use
safe consumption and how to clean and
maintain these these rigs and of course
you guys should have this document as
well so you can kind of follow along so
to start i want to talk about a few of
the different rigs that i have here on
the table
both of the pipes are from a company
called mothership
um of course you don't need to have a
mothership pipe this is called a faberge
egg this one is called a klein
and this is in regards to the type of
filter that he's blown inside of it so
there's all sorts of different there's
tauruses and klein's and faberge eggs
this is a hollow pipe you can see with
your finger in there only the walls have
thickness and that's where the water is
so both of these are water pipes
both of these can be used either with a
torch
or with an electric nail or even with
the beam that i have over here which
i'll talk about in a little bit
i've got full melt uh bubble hash as
well as a little bit of rosin i've got
some five star bubble hash and some six
star bubble hash meaning when i put it
on the rig
it's going to boil and liquefy and
vaporize in a way that leaves very
little chafe we will talk about what
happens when you hit too hot but there
are reasons why we have all these
different units
uh so i guess we'll talk about first
starters these are our titanium dabbers
you will need a dab tool because um this
material is very greasy
and you'll need to sort of take stick
your dab tool in there uh to get a dab
out so i'm gonna come on over
and do it right to the camera
so we can see there we go let's see if i
can get
there we go
so let's see if that looks good so we're
basically going to stick our little
dabber in here
and just get a nice little dab out we
don't need too much
especially because i'm probably going to
have to take more than one
and generally one is more than enough
for me so we'll just do small ones i got
a little dab right there
we're gonna be using the climb
over here and we're gonna be using the
peli nail so the pelican nail has a
quartz
banger this banger is pretty unique in
the sense that it has a stub coming out
the bottom with a tiny little pin that
fits through and holds this electric
coil in place
the only really thing you need on top of
this rig your pipe and the pelican nail
which comes with the whip and the coil
the banger
and
a
carb cap so these are the
the things that you need you've got your
dabber
you've got your carb cap and the simply
put
we know our temperature is
430 degrees
fahrenheit which is a nice low vape
temperature
it's certainly not going to burst the
material into flames and cause my throat
soreness i like low temp dabs you can
always turn it up if you want to get a
smokier hit if you want to be coughing
if you want to really feel that grab and
there is a reason that some people want
to do that sometimes if you suffer from
pain or massive inflammation which is
causing your pain a really hot dab can
really reduce some of that so we're
going to go for a connoisseur hit here
take the pipe in hand bring it up to
your lips and let go put put your dabber
right in there and rub it up against the
walls until it all melts down into the
pipe and once it's done that which it's
doing right now
you want to get it all off
put your carb cap on
and pull
beautiful
so we put our carb cap back down
now part of maintenance this part of
maintenance we're going to be doing
involves some q-tips
i was sent some silicon reusable q-tips
recently which i think is great because
this is wasteful and we can do better
and then there's oh
edit that out so i do hope we can do
better with the reusable q-tips in the
future
and we've got the dc glass crystal this
is dark crystal glass nature's cleaning
solution uh this stuff is made out of
water caranja oil coconut extract kelp
extract extract of sugar cane completely
non-toxic
and when you drop it into the quartz
dabber it really only works with the
heat but when you drop it into the top
of the of the bong of the banger sorry
it sizzles and as it's sizzling
it just boils and cleans the inside of
the banger to near perfection so we do
this after every dab
and that way the next person that comes
along isn't going to get a dab that is
not enjoyable so this is called dabbing
etiquette it is quite important
you don't want to just a take a dab with
someone's pipe and then not really have
the understanding on how to simply clean
it afterwards which is um
i'm sure most people would be kind
enough to do it for you the first couple
of times but eventually it's something
that
you want to learn yourself
so i was unfortunately unable to find
the battery to this all of this really
is is it's a laser thermometer it sits
under the pipe i'm going to put this
over here because i'm almost well i've
knocked it down once and that was a
second almost knock it down so you can
put it right under your pipe it doesn't
have to be this close by any means it
can be like three or four inches away
if it was on it would be reading the
temperature of the banger so i could hit
the banger with the torch the banger
being this bowl right here i could heat
it all up with the torch
get it to the point where i put it under
here wait for that 430 degree
temperature that i like oh so much
and then that's when i could hit it now
this isn't working and it's great
because i don't have a battery for it
it's one of those square nine volts um i
can show you how we did it before this
technology existed so this is a fairly
large quartz banger so i won't be
heating it up for too long but generally
we used to do it with a timer we would
heat it up for 20 seconds we would cool
it down for 50 to 55 seconds and then we
would take our hit
and then you know the first time you hit
a new banger you can kind of extend the
cool down period or decrease the
cooldown period to find that sweet spot
if it's too hot you want to you want to
extend the cooldown period uh past 55
seconds if it's not hot enough
you would want to maybe start hitting it
at 45 seconds or even 40 seconds so
we're gonna have a hit like that we've
got our blow torch here i've already
filled it up with the butane gas over
here
uh and so i will do
the two methods i will do the timer
method but i will also show you a method
that people have been using even before
the timer came out
and it's quite convenient as well this
is the um basically the same way you
would test a baby's bottle you hold your
wrist right over the banger if it's
really hot i tell people when they say
well how do i know when it's ready i
tell them well how it feels on your
wrist is how it's going to feel on your
lungs so wait until it's cooled down
and feels good on your on your lungs so
we'll get our timer started here
start that up
we'll do 20 seconds
you can see i like to keep my pipes as
clean as possible it's not always
possible but i'll go over how easy that
is at the end of this video
all right so there's 20 seconds
we will reset and start that over and we
will go for a
45 to 50 second cooldown
oops make sure we're not spilling hash
we're gonna hit the uh
wedding cake is what we're hitting this
time first hit was the strawberry banana
i'll use uh a different carb cap this
time
and so you can kind of put your wrist up
there
it's not too hot at all actually i'm
gonna go now we're outside so it's
cooling it down
[Music]
perfect temperature no cough no strain
no heat
just a really great taste
and that for me is really my favorite
aspect of dabbing now understand dabbing
is multi-dimensional and it's more than
what i'm just doing some people really
like hitting hot dabs and coughing and
just like anything people will judge
people that do things differently than
how they deal with them but i implore
you not to do that if people are
enjoying dabs let them be it is our one
of our company's missions to make
product that's uh at the top of the
chain so people that are also doing this
can enjoy it uh you know as as
as much as the medical patients can
enjoy it as much as the recreational
patients i really just want us to be
able to have an exceptional quality of
hash
so people can do this very experience
perhaps in settings like these and just
really get into a great headspace
all right so we're going to clean this
up with a little q-tip
we'll get our dc glass cleaner
there he is hiding over here and the you
know the reason you want to keep these
um bangers clean is first of all they're
very expensive um they sell for two and
three and four hundred uh dollars a
piece
um quartz being a lot harder to to work
with than borosilicate
glass
but yeah it's nice to keep your your
bangers as clean as possible now here's
a little terminology for you when you
heat the banger up way too hot like
heating it up for 40 50 60 seconds and
then only letting it cool down for 10
seconds uh when you put the dab on top
of that it's going to almost burn and
sear to the glass immediately and that
terminology
we call chasing so chasing the banger is
a pretty big no-no in the world of
dabbing etiquette uh much like not
cleaning your your your bowl out is but
really chasing it is a real bummer it
also shows you how powerful the little
dark crystal glass cleaner is because
sometimes the worst chas and what i mean
by that you can kind of see it on this
one if i bring it forward
this is a fairly old unit and it's been
smoked out of quite a bit and so you can
see it's cloudy uh it's a little bit
chased on the bottom here as well so
every time it gets like this and the dc
glass cleaner can't pick it up you need
to fire it with a torch the torch breaks
it down the little bit of dust kind of
gets into the porous course
and you end up with this smoky looking
quartz which is just not as nice
as
the clean
nice big quartz shining in the sun you
know you can really appreciate
appreciate that right there compared to
the chas
so these were both gifts for me but
between the two of them i think they
were uh or they're worth about five or
six hundred us uh and you know when
someone's paying that money they really
want to learn the proper way to use
these bangers and make sure that they're
not doing something that's so
detrimental that they're going to
shorten the life cycle
by a large amount
so
we have a bunch of different types of
dabs here we can talk a little bit about
this is some water hash bubble hash the
cultivar is called wedding cake
we would call it six star as it pretty
much boils away and disappears to almost
nothing very little material left on the
q-tips when you clean the banger
we got some grateful heads here this is
the the jagger
rosin it's very nice it's like honey it
just pours you could pour it out like
honey
it's quite an incredible consistency
very different from these two
consistencies this is more like a butter
on the left here
this one over here is more like a i
wouldn't well shatter really when it's
hot it's super pulley and taffy but when
it gets cold it's like a shatter
the next one is almost like a distillate
it's very saucy and liquidy
it stays like that always it doesn't
change no matter if you don't keep it
cold or you heat it up
this one is some five star bubble hash
it looks like kind of like standard hash
but with a nice orangey
amber outside i'll try to show a
close-up to these each time this is lost
gardens
and then a couple of more
bubble hashes that have been whipped
and almost made to look like rosin also
done by grateful heads
and then we have our carb caps that
we've kind of gone over already quite of
a variety this one's got a little bit of
a tilt to the end of it so when you spin
it on top of the banger
it creates directional flow and it'll
move the rosin or the bubble hash or the
you know solvent dabs that you're
hitting if that's what you're hitting uh
it'll move it around evenly around the
base and the sides of the quartz banger
you'll get a better hit that way you
won't cool down certain spots and leave
other spots warm
there's also a titanium one here we
don't really hit on titanium anymore
this is a combination titanium base with
a quartz bowl that screws into the top
i haven't really hit with that one in
quite a while either
over here i have a d-nail this one's
quite special because this one's
silicone carbide
this is also plugged into a titanium
base but the top itself can be either
quartz
a quartz piece like this
a sapphire piece like this which is
really the top notch in my opinion and
i'll tell you why i think so in a second
and then silicone carbide which is great
for traveling it's extremely extremely
uh tough it's not going to break
and then the
whip on this one and the coil is quite a
bit different you won't see it wrapping
around the banger on this one it's
actually flat and it's a circle like a
like an element and the post goes right
through and the top screws on top of
that so it's all along the bottom of
this almost like a stovetop element
so love that this is the carb cap that
goes with that it fits really quite nice
it's also got a directional um
piece uh drilled in here just a tiny
little hole drilled in at an angle
the reason that is actually and the
reason all of these are directional is
not just to move the oil itself around
and the one thing i don't have on the
table that i'm going to talk about today
are these little orbs or spheres and
they make them out of ruby and they make
them out of sapphire and they make them
out of quartz and i'm pretty sure they
make them out of silicone carbide and
probably they even make them out of
sapphire uh maybe i said that one
already that's a lot to remember anyway
they're little orbs little tiny balls
you put one inside your banger and now
that acts as a mechanism that when you
get that wind going and you start moving
anything or everything around that hot
little orb also peels the resin and
moves it around the base of the banger
at this point in time you're probably
asking yourself are these people
seriously into this this much that he
actually knows about this particular
subject right now and yes we are and i
do and it's something you're going to
want to familiarize yourself with this
is our industry uh this is one of the
main ways that we are um
consuming uh products that we are going
to that we have produced out of our lab
and that we are going to continue to
produce out of our lab uh it is a big
part of the culture that already exists
and i think that it would be great uh
for you guys to have a really good
understanding of all of this and any
questions you have whatsoever please
reach out we can send them off in an
email chain and we can get them all sort
of answered i think i went over
everything
pretty well
we spoke very little about this unit
because i didn't bring the power source
out but it's really quite simple you
know it conducts heat by sitting on the
quartz where there's a heater underneath
the quartz this little bit of metal
conducts heat enough to get the banger
up to temperature where you can pull it
away from and not have any connection
but not having used the torch so it's a
very innovative way it's done by a quite
a young guy down in washington him and
his partner are engineers and they're
just thinking outside of the box and i
like that they're thinking outside of
the box and in fact the company is
called mr hotbox so they are just
selling these right now um it hasn't
really caught on i think i'm one of the
first people to really use it
we can go over a whole variety of ways
in the future on how you can dab without
these particular units because there's
an entire industry that involves the the
switch and the puffco peak and a whole
variety of other units that are not
glass pipes with bangers like this but
have created a unique aspect of almost
like the electric pen
turned into the electric bomb so for now
i will leave you all possibly with one
last uh bong rip i think it makes sense
to hit the coffee which is the lowest
gardens uh organically regeneratively
sustainably grown
outdoors in
ontario which i also love that hash of
this quality was produced
outdoors in ontario
and i bid you all good evening may the
full melt bless your dab rig sooner than
later peace out everybody
so
you