[Music]
alright bubbleman here with my good
friend Chester that I've known for so
long and he hasn't been at the Cannabis
Cup in so long and now he's here with me
yeah we're on our tuk-tuk style bike
cruising through we just came on a damn
square and we're heading to the damp
cranes glass gallery we're gonna see our
good friend Marcel and Dosher and some
of the other American glass blowers that
are in town and we're just enjoying a
nice evening it's beautiful out we'll
give you a little bit of our bike ride
here just heading down a nice quiet
street behind the Albert Heijn and all
in all it's a beautiful evening any
evening in Holland in November that it's
not raining yeah is a beautiful evening
I can tell you so yeah it's a little bit
brisk but you know what it's nothing for
me I don't mind it at all
anyway we'll catch up with you when we
get to the show and show you some phat
glass alright peace out
all right we just got here to the
gallery dampering original gallery we're
gonna go in and see what's going on
my [ __ ] serious equipment justice
whatever
[Music]
giraffe
that's my simple
bars in the hammer
dregg's for the Deaf crane original
galleries that crease gallery website
original battery gallery take us through
this a little bit she's got a really big
it's myself in partnership with the
sound ring of opens this gallery we've
got two more gallery on the canal and
after that and here what we have is a
showcase of the pieces that were
entering for the cannabis stuff we've
got
blowers in this way and the
adaptable precaution for a few hours or
[Music]
come with us we're doing the video tell
us so we've got
nine Dutch artist Hill Cove on the bar
here Oh a beautiful
[Applause]
we're making a video bro look yes we
have our selfie take you can this piece
is the masterpiece of these guys oh my
god tell me about this thing Marcel it's
all it's all about the new paradigm
culture
the marijuana movement
together in the genetics like building
up this structure and carrying this
energy be energy beam hun creating the
product also fond of and Sherlock on top
to represent the Piper's you're taking
my technology sparkling in the hole
technology of manufacturing it out
beautiful well I think you've done it I
think you guys have done it that looks
pretty unbelievable man beautiful nice
with the lights turned off see what it
looks like that
you can see the body
exactly