[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world I
am here with longtime local Vancouver
activist Dana Larson really more than
just a Vancouver activist you've been
doing a [ __ ] ton for cannabis that is
for certain yeah sure I'll take that
coer activist that's all right
absolutely from editing um cannabis
Culture magazine and then getting into
the NDP and the political ring and
getting into sensible BC tons of stuff
you can Google on on Dana Larson
including a variety of uh pretty funny
yet educational books which is the
reason we're here talking to him today
you may have seen the post I put up on
Instagram a couple of days ago of the Dr
SU parody book uh green Buds and hash
well Dana of course is the author of
such parody yes hilarious there we go I
actually read it to my eight-month-old
child the other day along with the help
from my 14 and 11year old and uh I was
surprised at how really I mean the
Rhymes are awesome it's definitely Dr
Seuss like but it's actually quite
educational yeah like you're really
giving education in regards to a and the
way cannabis can help I I thought it was
pretty
brilliant well thanks yeah I wrote this
a few years ago actually I wrote the
poem about four or five years ago and
just put it online it's floating around
on a lot of different websites now but
uh but the art my friend I I he's a very
talented artist and uh the artist
definitely helps make it's a beautiful
beautiful book and uh yeah I'm really
pleased sometimes when I'm writing stuff
it's really hard to get it out but this
all just kind of came out in a big yeah
blurb a big thing and um the art is
definitely on point yeah it's very Susi
and so much on point that you know there
could be a chance we'll be facing some
kind of uh can you see that there I
don't know if I think it's to oh there
you go uh uh that's is some of the stuff
but yeah I I'm a little worried about
the Seuss estate coming down on us in
some way about the art and stuff but uh
all the more reason to get your copies
now before they have any legal problems
true enough I I grabbed mine right away
and uh there's for sale all over the
city a lot of different shops have them
from cchq
uh did you send some back to ignite or
uh I haven't yet but I'll be bringing
some by there but if you want for mail
order you can get them right now from
the Cannabis culture shop uh mail order
is the only place I think that's doing
mail order right now or for me directly
too if you want they're uh $15 $14.95 $5
shipping so for 20 bucks uh you can get
a copy delivered right to your door and
that where can they uh send that to how
do they get that information well you
can send me an email money transfer just
to my email address Dana Dana larson.com
uh and I also take Paypal as well if you
want to contact me for PayPal my PayPal
address is actually book harry.net and
that's H AI r y Harry as in what I'm not
uh well I on my face I guess uh but yeah
Harry pad.net you can check that out or
you can just email me and and figure out
how to make a payment but uh and we're
actually reprinting the first Harry
pothead book again in a couple of weeks
as well so that'll be fun to have both
which is probably your most well-known
par yeah and that's been over for quite
a few years I'm working steadily on the
second
the sequel to it but it's taken me a
long time because there's so many other
projects I got going on but uh but the
green Buds and hash is lovely I'm glad
uh your your children are enjoying it
there yeah I think it's legitimate dude
at first when I saw it I really thought
it was more of a a haha thing and then I
saw it as like this is an
actual this is a really important factor
of how we can educate children without
the sort of I mean I'm watching
throughout the media how they're going
through all the years of propaganda and
brainwashing and how they're now slowly
trying to retract and pull back a lot of
that I think things like this are
extremely helpful to start early yeah I
mean I'm not you know and for kids I
mean I kind of see this as an adult
thing in a way like you know I mean an
eight-month child is going to be amused
by anything you're read no matter what
obviously right they just like the
sounds but normalizes it is what I mean
yeah know to me it's just a fun thing I
mean I don't see anything wrong with
kids talking about cannabis or being
told cannabis is a good medicine or
things like that in fact I think that
probably creates a healthier attitude
towards cannabis than seeing it as this
forbidden thing that you've got to try
in secret and and maybe not in the best
context you know just like I think it's
probably better for kids to try alcohol
with their parents perhaps for the first
time oh yeah uh I think having a
normalized attitude about cannabis is is
similar as well and uh and that but this
is fun for all ages certainly and
grown-ups can enjoy it as well I think
and definely I read it and laughed my
ass up yeah yeah and I justes have a
little more there as well so I've got
and I actually got a whole bunch of
other uh fairy tales and parodies and
things that I've written that are about
this length so we've got the pie-eyed
piper that was actually published in
cannabis Culture magazine quite a few
years ago say that going way and a lot
of this stuff's been sitting around for
a while it takes to getting the artists
in line is challenging getting the money
and the talent and and getting them to
to spend the time doing it but I've got
the pad Piper coming out in a couple of
months we've got another one called the
girl who could turn hemp into gold and
that one actually hasn't been published
anywhere publicly at all uh and so I'm
hoping to put out a series of these
things and in another year or so hoping
to have about five or six of these kind
of books out in a similar format uh but
the other ones aren't Dr Seuss parodies
they're just fairy tales so there
shouldn't be any lawsuits over those
ones I'm hoping and hopefully not on
this one either you know satire and
parody and Canada are allowed uh so I
feel we fall under those things uh but I
admit I'm just a little nervous that
that the Susa State might decide to feel
differently or something who knows but I
certainly you know I love Dr Seuss like
everybody else
andal respect to him or any means and
hopefully he would enjoy this and think
it's a fun Riff on his work well you got
to think that if he ever enjoyed
cannabis in his life that he would
definitely find enjoyment in this
particular parody of his work absolutely
I think it's done with class nonetheless
so MH ah good to be here smoking with
you well there's so much going on these
days unel been uh yeah I'm in the news
like on the media is calling me non-stop
for comment on all these things that are
going on pretty much since 420 from
about 419
every day I've had at least four
reporters calling me for stuff and like
uh and some days it's really crazy but
we've had the dispensary thing happening
in Vancouver and all the kafuffle and
Chang around that Victoria today just
voted like an hour ago 8 to1 to follow
the Vancouver model and basically
legalize dispensaries in Victoria
probably some kind of rules it was
possible that they were going to maybe
yeah we weren't sure we thought we had
support but it was an 8 to1 vote so we
were looking for you know to get at
least five of those nine votes but uh uh
8 to one is really solid on the one vote
against wasn't even really that strongly
against he was more just sort of like
this is ottawa's problem we shouldn't be
fixing their problems for them so that
sounds that sounds really good yeah it
wasn't like he wasn't like marijuana's
cancerous or bad and we should you know
but uh so that's very positive and with
the two biggest cities in BC now
basically telling the Harper government
to get lost we're going to regulate
cannabis dispensaries in the province uh
that is a huge influence and I think
that many other smaller cities and towns
in BC and across Canada are going to
start following that model as well and
it gives you an option you know you
can't just say as a mayor now well the
law is the law and we have to shut them
down because that's the law we don't
have a choice well you do have a choice
and so that makes it a lot more
interesting you know in Colona I've been
talking to the folks there they've got a
dispensary they were raided in January
they just reopened now the police came
in two days ago and said you have 24
hours to shut down and the city
inspector actually came in with the
police officers with them okay it
started off being called the Kaya clinic
and then they got raided and shut down
down they reopened as the okay clinic
now okay yes and uh and so they're got a
thing going weeds has also opened one
there and they're also getting pressured
to shut down in the same way but um but
yeah but yeah so this means whereas in
West Colona and Vernon they've got a
couple of dispensaries each and the city
councils are more favorable so we're
going to see this playing out City by
City And town by town all across the
country as these places continue to well
I got to give props to our mayor for
disagreeing with Amber Rose and disagree
with uh the things that were said which
was basically that I believe she made a
quote and I was it your quote that said
maybe she maybe I'm misquoting her or
maybe she meant to say this wrong I
remember reading someone's words about
it that she said there was no medical
value absolutely she said that over and
over again she said that what she
basically said was that the we have to
provide cannabis to patients because the
courts have ruled that patients believe
that it helps them and so we have to
provide it because they believe that it
helps them but Health Canon knows that
marijuana is not an approved medicine
it's not a valid medicine and and so by
extension basically it's all a hoax and
if you think marijuana is helping you
you're actually deluded and this is the
health Minister this is the health
Minister who runs the medical marijuana
program so obviously you're not going to
have a successful program when the
person who whose Department it is to be
in charge of it uh says it she doesn't
believe it works it's a big hoax and you
just believe it helps you but you're
wrong and so we're actually sponsoring a
week of action against Rona Ambrose this
is something anybody in the country can
do uh basically we're going to call all
of her office phone numbers and health
Canada numbers all day long all next
week and explain to them why Canis is
real medicine share with them science
and facts share with them your personal
stories want their phone ringing off the
hook these these numbers are listed on
Dana's uh page as well as a variety of
other Pages you can search Facebook for
Dana Larson that's senen that's right
and if you go to our website sensible
bc.com campaigns Link at the top of the
page you put six or eight numbers there
yes five phone numbers actually so it's
it's her it's her Edmonton office her
Ottawa office the health Canada office
uh the he The Rona Ambrose's like media
contact office I don't want him to be
able to call any reporters or anything
and then there's one more number as well
but basically we're going to be flooding
their office we did the similar thing
last year when they were telling medical
patients to mix their cannabis with
kitty litter and throw it away on the
curb uh and so we did a one day day of
action last year and it was very
effective and you know if you're mad
about this stuff this is your chance to
vent and to all vent together and if you
have if you're upset about the way
things are going you don't like what the
conservatives are saying and you want to
tell somebody off well this is your
chance to do that to get that get that
uh uh uh energy out there uh direct it
where it belongs to be at the federal
government at the minister of health and
health Canada and the terrible job
they're doing with the program so uh and
if you can do it in the most
intellectually and articulate manner
that is respectful and not uh you know
you can't be phoning up and and and
threatening and and being you know don't
threaten anybody and remember you're not
going to be talking to Rona Ambrose
you're going to be talking to staff
members who work at Health Canada they
they are probably just people who are
there just to do their job and get paid
and they might not even agree with what
their Department's philosophy is so you
want to be firm you want to be clear but
don't be calling and swearing at them or
threatening them or or anything phoning
in bomb threats or any crazy stuff like
that just talk about why but keep them
on the phone don't don't let them hang
up on you don't let them put you off
explain to them why cannabis helps you
why you believe it's important try to
keep them on the phone as long as
possible and uh and just bring these
things forward and we really want them
to hear personal stories about this we
want that whole department buzzing all
week and talking to each other about
holy crap I got another 100 phone calls
today you know this is really bad
clearly people are upset about what's
happening here and we got to make a
change and these are effective tools for
activism in in different cities that you
may live in uh you might not even be
from Canada and you might have you might
be elsewhere in the world these are
effective tools for for moving your
activism forward there's good ways to go
about it and there's not so good ways to
go about it and Dana himself here has
been going about this I mean you're what
are you 20 years in now yeah I'm over 20
years now 20 years in now so exactly I
myself I'm also over 20 years in started
as an activist in pins or something 20
year pin 20 years yeah yeah 20 years
proud absolutely well it's the good work
you know it's uh we're fighting for a
plant that we believe in and not just
for our own uh personal uh agenda
personal reasons to for profit or
anything like that it's really and it
always has been at least for me
particularly for people that don't have
a voice for themselves for the people
that really really need this plant or
need access to it which is why I am a
firm supporter of both LPS and
dispensaries I love the idea of
dispensaries available to people right
now there's not a shadow of a doubt that
dispensaries are saving the Canadian
people from the lp system at this point
in time the lp system cannot provide
enough medicine they're not providing
Edibles they're not providing salves
they're not pro providing the creams
they're not providing extracts that's a
huge hole considering that is the
medicine that's a pretty giant hole to
leave your your patients with so I mean
to me the dispensaries are
I mean they're picking up a lot of slack
right now with that said I still believe
the LPS have a place I still believe
that LPS are important and if I love the
idea of Standards that's what I love I
for that I don't I haven't heard any
dispensary owners saying you want LPS
shut down no I want a better system for
LPS I feel kind of sorry for them in a
way not too sorry because none of them
are really stepping up or helping an
activism in any way but I got to it's
got to be frustrating to have invested
all these millions of dollars be waiting
most a lot of are LP wab be haven't got
their permits yet they've invested a
bunch of money and they're waiting and
even the ones that have are under a
regulatory scheme run by a minister who
doesn't believe marijuana has any
medicinal value the bureaucracy is very
hostile the rules are keeping changing
it's very expensive and challenging and
the patients mostly hate them I see a
lot of very negative LP comments on the
internet and uh and so you so you've got
a lot of challenges there trying to run
this and I think some of them are people
who are just in it for the money others
I think people who Canabis and want to
help people and are trying to do the
right thing and are frustrated you know
by this process and a lot of those good
folks are ones who haven't got their
permits yet actually is what I found the
people that are my friends are the ones
that kind of they're waiting yeah
they're waiting there's a few folks from
the dispensary community that have made
it into the lp like Philip Lucas uh is
working with till Ray and he originally
was one of the very first dispensaries
in Canada back in the day in vioria and
uh and so there is that but what we need
ultimately is a better regulatory system
uh and one that works differently and
one that you know people say would do
you want to buy all your marijuana from
LPS at your dispensary and I say well if
most of my suppliers could become LPS
fairly easily then yes and they should
be able to they're making a high quality
product there should only be some
oversight and some some testing and
things like that as long as they can
fall through the standards as long as
they make it through this I think the
standards is what will
separate the you know the heads from the
stocks so to speak but the standards to
be something that's not limited that's
not those only we're only going to allow
a dozen people it's got to be a fair
system reach yeah a a standard is
keeping a certain bar High a standard is
testing for microbials and making sure
that the Cannabis has not been sprayed
with chemicals which would could involve
just like organic uh testing and farming
does is having someone come and make
sure that you're not doing that yeah
absolutely those are standards not
saying hey only 10 people can play
that's completely absur bad thing no
don't support that at all but you know
my long-term vision for what
legalization really means is that it
should be Farmers growing marijuana by
the thousands of hectares and so it
wouldn't be so much in that kind of
model some people are still going to be
into their perfectly manicured buds for
smoking joints and whatnot but that kind
of stuff I think would fall by the
wayside because you don't need to start
off with the perfect Bud to make a
perfect extract at the end of the
process you can if you're growing it by
the by the hectare and you've got you
know thousands of pounds of resin with
which is rich in the cannaboids you can
tweak that and develop it or or grow the
right strains to have whatever cannaboid
profile you want you know I'm not a big
fan of of some of the extracts that are
made because of the being made in
people's homes bubble hash obviously is
very safe and pure and clean like that
uh but yeah exactly we only use a water
extracted resin for our our uh our our
MJ creams there a nice little right on
the bottom there made with pure water
extracted marijuana resin and that's the
MJ MJ creams. CA uh we've got a number
of different kinds and we're in about 25
stores now and a lot more to come and
there's a lot of research and personal
experience that uh topical salves and
creams that are marijuana infused work
really well for all kinds of stuff we've
been selling these things for a few
years we've added a few essential oils
to diversify them a little bit and it's
got a great ingred in their uh increase
their potency and Effectiveness
medically and uh yeah there's some good
products I think and so we've been
selling them at the dispensary for a few
years now but
but yeah outdoor cannabis grown by the
hectare none of this growing buds in a
basement and everything that's under
artificial and it's a lot harder to like
grow keep to keep buds safe from mold
and mildew and things because it's such
an organic living thing whereas if you
have an extract that you can make at any
potency any level of Purity with any
level of tpin and flavonoids grown in an
outdoor environment that I think is the
long-term future of marijuana and what
I'm working for people can still grow
some in their backyard like they grow
tomatoes or whatever and that should be
out and people will still do that but
it' be more of a hobbyist kind of a
thing than a big moneymaking kind of
thing you know I think that's that's the
future in the long term but it's going
to be a while before we get from here to
there also so no I agree outdoor is
definitely fields and Fields is where
it's it's got to be going the only thing
that put us underground and inside with
lights is prohibition and once
prohibition is lifted there's really no
more reason to follow prohibition based
models I think it will be a slow
transition uh one that potentially in
Canada I think here could potentially be
solved by offering a third type of
license let mm patients have their
licenses let LPS have licenses but don't
limit them keep the standards high and
offer a third type of Licensing for all
those Growers who are currently growing
under an mm license but growing to
produce cannabis for others so that they
sell it let them have another type of
license where okay if you're growing for
yourself you don't need to test for
microbials and all these different
things but if you're putting it on an
open market and selling it then perhaps
those standards should be put into place
to protect the end user no I agree
absolutely like how we do wine on other
things right if you want to brew wine in
your home and share it with your friends
and family without cost there's not
really much oversight no one's
inspecting your wine or anything like
that if you want to sell it in a store
yeah I want it to know it's pure and
it's not going to contain toxic things
and I want to know that if it says
organic on the label someone's actually
checking to make sure it's actually
produced organically and things like
that but the wine market
has got small scale Mitch producers that
just do very limited amounts it's got
medium grow medium producers it's got
really giant companies that make you
know millions of gallons of wine a year
and there's room for all of those and
that's what we need for cannabis room
for everybody who wants to get involved
and who can produce a high quality
product uh they should be able to to
participate in the market if they want
to that that's the kind of future we
need absolutely I agree well thanks for
sitting down and chatting with me maybe
I should offer you a lovely bone yeah
absolutely that sounds very nice little
bit the d420 K sift left over he was
so20 yes Darren good old Darren great uh
hash maker good
friend a little carb
there because everyone wants to see that
carb cap get put on you don't put that
carb cap on you get like 42 comments why
wouldn't you carb your Bros Bowl
man why did you leave them hanging
I'm
sorry that makes a big difference e
because I can definitely see how it uh
huge difference with the little hole too
it just what it feels like after a while
when you put the dab in and you start
taking your rip without this it starts
feeling like you're you're pulling down
this really big straw like instead of
that no I liked it like that it's nice
uh I do not own a dab rig I do not
really dab unless somebody comes over or
I'm out somewhere I you a lot of joints
I just spoke joints but I put bubble
hash and other stuff in them usually to
supercharging that [ __ ] supercharging my
does absolutely excellent well I
appreciate you sitting down with me and
you guys definitely have a bunch of
different things to Google uh in regards
to things that we talked about and order
this book green bugs and hash available
at the cannabisculture
uh.com store or for me directly for 20
bucks Dana Dan larson.com I'll have it
up too at bubble bag.com and uh get them
all you can get them all you can thanks
for watching Bubble man's world and
thanks for coming out all right my
pleasure thanks for having me peace
[Music]