e
C could you close the door please so I
can hear what's going
on is everything okay oh
we yeah we couldn't hear you sorry
I come to the door and David basically
attacks me says thing God we thought she
was
lesan she story nothing wrong with
that not inappropriate but I realized
immediately this was a man with no
filter and a unique
individual and over the
years I
learned how to become friends with him
and to appreciate him and his very
strange
and sometimes inappropriate as of
humor but he was uh he was always very
good to
[Music]
me for a
second so know 25 years a long time
right so years passed by but I remember
really nice memories and when when M and
I didn't have a lot of money she go
let's go over to my mom and dad's to
bite
ribs or sushi or whatever we like B
ourselves over and and he would
always say all by you fly that's right
and I would fly off and go get the ribs
and come back and those are good days
and I remember going to the
greenhouse and uh he was very proud of
his
work but we loved the beans and the
tomatoes and the corn we grow beans and
tomatoes and corn and we would just love
it you know and then of course you know
all the Christmases all all the
birthdays he was always very generous
and uh and then C was born
2005 and he was a really great grand
father
Surge and she was born on Christmas Day
and that made Christmases even more
special the only problem was that he
would buy too many
presents and I'm not kidding serious I
we had to talk to him about it once the
Dave it's cool it's
great but you know we don't have space
for all this
stuff he's like I don't
care I'll buy her as many [ __ ]
presents
want and if you can't deal with it then
it's your problem not
mind some people appreciate
that so we
slides years and like can't we can't
have slide in our
house he's like I don't care SL to stay
here and she
visit you playing with especially Legos
I would come to pick up C catch them
playing with Legos all the
time making whole whole cities and
Villages and then later on barbecue
Sushi he would I he would buy bunch of
sushi materials and I would make sushi
and he really enjoyed the Barbe as well
he's just been a
very
special so I think my five help you up
right almost okay I I want to thank
everybody for being here again again I
want to remind come speak uh I'll I'll
come and announce your name you put
yourself on the list so please keep five
minutes uh and now I would like to
introduce David's granddaughter SI my
daughter
so um I'm going to start off with a
little story that I want to
share um some of you know that I'm
planning on studying film next year and
I actually made my first movie with my
grandfather when I was 7even and it was
called draw a picture and it was a 3
minute movie of me coming home from
school and drawing a picture of my day
and um he was the
cameraman and when we watched back the
videos to edit them together all I could
hear was his Extremely Loud breathing
straight into the
microphone that was the day that my
grandfather taught me the importance of
adding music to film
he taught me a lot of other important
things um that I will remember
forever he taught me that one could
never receive too many Christmas
gifts and um that or watch too many
movies and he taught me that having fun
is more important than being an
adult and and that it's never the wrong
time to make a joke and it's never too
cold to wear
flipflops even with socks on
he taught me that teachers can be wrong
and uh that you have to drink at least
one can of Coca-Cola every
day he he also taught me how to build
the biggest Lego Cities and um taught me
the funniest ways to play with cats and
the best way to make French toast
obviously with an entire bottle of
cinnamon um to him the most important
lesson that he wanted to share was to
never get
old which is a scary one because you
know that growing up and getting old is
inevitable for
everybody and um unfortunately the last
thing he taught me is that grandparents
aren't
Immortal and I used to think he was
Immortal I thought that we had plenty of
time to travel together and go to
restaurants and sit in our lazy boys and
watch movies drinking Cokes all
day whenever we used to say goodbye we
wouldn't hug we would kiss our fingers
and touch them
together
Opa please know that I cherish all the
time we had together even though it
seemed short and I'll keep your lessons
with me forever I love
you than you so there's no particular
order so I'll
just get the list out here
and yeah next Who's Next let's
see would you like come
up I for this
hi guys uh what an amazing Crow of
people here I know many of you some I
don't and but uh beautiful to see
everybody
here uh it's
uh truly an honor to be here
today to life our friend David bman AKA
s the term Legends gets thrown around in
the head of his world these days but not
everybody gets gold Legend necessarily
deserves their title who are obviously
telling in this room who do but Dave was
a legend even among Legends the
proverbial Giant on Whose shoulder we
all
stand as the f as as the first to
publish instructions on how to make
water has co-founded the infamous
Legends of hash's L part competition
held held here at the lebanes restaurant
the artist in the P each November during
the can he was considered one of the
most of the world's foremost coniss of
hash as the co-founder of the world the
world's first pharmaceutical canid
research inet company War P Farm as well
as the international hemp Association he
was a Visionary Pioneer in the realm of
cannabis science and most consequently
as the founders of America first
commercial can SE company and as the man
who first brought many of the most
classic cers here to Amsterdam he was
arly the most influential cus breeder in
history in fact it's not overstating
things to say that every CIS breeder
operating over the last 40 years owe him
a depth of
gratitude heardman Sam as a young boy
here in Amsterdam I'm a local time board
in Amsterdam never imagining that I'm
might someday call him a friend it was
only after becoming a successful
academist entrepreneur and historian
myself that I eventually built up the
courage to reach out to him knowing he
lived here and answer them I asked our
mutual friend Valerie Coral to make an
introduction about four years ago I
initiated email conversation with him
and began sending in pictures of some of
the items I was collecting for my world
of canist Museum project being as
private as he was he didn't want to
speak to me at first but eventually he
began to reply and after many months he
finally visited me at his home for a
sash after overcoming his initial
hesitation I felt like we made a
connection and hit it off I later
invited him to my place to show him my
collection of Canabis arts and artifacts
I started making an effort to spend more
time with him and before long I figured
out the trick I realized that it took
him that if I took him out for a nice
lunch or dinner I could get him to talk
so uh only off the records of course I
was uh always trying to convince him to
let us interview in for the world of
canist but he would never agree as I'm
sure you all know he was not very father
of
J in fact one of my Fest memories with
Dave was in the time that I convinced
him to have dinner with me and and the
world of cist partner Bobby black who as
many of you know for high times for over
20 years Bobby sensing his regards by
the way he refused to at first but
ultimately thanks to thanks to the
promise of a mission and star meal in
the Ura and and by sincere personal
insurances he finally agreed to
come Char characteristically arriving at
the upskill restaurant wearing flick
flops and shirt with canab sleeves
on knowing Bobby was a journalist he was
highly regarded at first but as the
evening went on and he realized Bobby
was the thre he opened up and began
sharing stories again off the record of
course if we weren't if it wer for death
that dinner Bobby would never had the
opportunity know so I'm happy I could
make that happen over the past several
years I was fortunity to share much
meals with da as well as much at his
house where I would sit and smoke with
him discussing our Collections and
listening to many stories or RS the most
in to the most in academ this world he
was controversial and then metic icon
who shot the spotlight forbade photos of
himself to be made public and operated
in the Shadow on a variety of pseuds
such as
SES Pudo Mr Jingles and of
course but of those who were lucky
enough to be let in who actually knew
and considered him a friend he was just
da a devoted husband and a father who
Smiles ear to Bear every time he talked
about his dogs a lovable
cin with a kind heart and a brilliant
mind and a humble weak ner who cared
little for Os or acat but WR only for
championing the knowledge and
appreciation of this miracle
Planet I never did get that interview
but at least I was able to get a picture
with him on ter for the rest of my life
resting SE government in the knowledge
that your love and your legacy will live
on for generations to
come thank you he he did enjoy food yes
he did very
much
okay uh much
pleas thank
I almost felt like I was M for a
second um let me see some catch my
breath for a second stop crying for a
second but these tears I've been crying
since January
27 they're different tears for me
because I'm only 27 days younger than my
beautiful friend Dave and I I've been
thinking of my
own like
to you know but I got three poems to
read if I this and I also got two little
stories first I'm going to tell one
story this is
uh I first met Dave with Rob Clark you
know he brought a little one of nice
but
D made the most amazing hash I
have I mean when I would smoke his hash
I would go into
another and one time he BR me to his
Greenhouse showed me the most amazing
plant but for about at least 10 years I
lived with a stock
this stock that was that this W um
drive and I lived with it in my house
I like a magic
I
and many times I P that stock and I go I
Che go this this what my pants are made
out of is made out of this
stock and this made can too
but I
that St and then one day Doug called me
and
said can I possibly get that
stock I didn't like that
but I already like put so much energy in
prayer into that stock that stock
influenced me so much showed me what
this stuff could be what the raw
material
was and so I gave back to
dog and on the way here today I found
out where that stock lives
now it was with that
guy
and that made me feel so good that Trier
has that St that I put energy into for
10 years it was kind of that wasn't
planned that was going to just magical
because everything
around a
from very mag and one time I went to a
birthday party at of Adams
2003 outside the
par it was a great party
tell plan that and D comes up to me and
he
says he has a ball in his head
a you got to try to
eat
eat that
so but an hour later I went back home my
three-year-old granddaughter she was
there because she's lived in my house
over and she
said so I laid down with
there it hadn't hit me yet it was just
started to hit me
and I said The Three Little Pigs I it
was a mama pig she had three pigs the
first Little Pig went out to build his
house out of
straw and
then my grandaughter like worried if I
died or something you know this like
totally
out I was withered today since 24 and a
half and she still
remembers but Dave's in War me good
enough what that was going to do to
you but we started getting high with
each other a lot he would come over my
house we would spend two three hours
until he had to take his wife's car back
or something he would hang out with me
sobody came over one day I think it was
2008 and we smoked only his hash we
smoked it smoked I was going one minute
left PS okay okay sorry I yeah no no I
okay let meish the car story okay M says
you can finish your story okay okay so
so so he leaves
finally making it down my stairs safely
and and IAL to him the next day he says
sobody not can believe what happened I
go what's the matter he goes my
wife's oh my God that's her favorite car
she's going to I don't know what she's
going to do but I went to go get the car
an empty space I FL some Poli
like it's really terrible 2 and a half
months goes
by C
me the police found this car it wasn't
where he thought he we smoke so much
hash even his has that we were
[ __ ] even maybe more than me I don't
know but that car every window of that
car had par tickets home you SE inside
that car when the police finally got in
touch with him and he could get it back
for his beautiful
wife you couldn't see inside
there I'm gonna have to ask I mean I
okay I GL give some of my minutes to so
I don't have so
much I'll read one B po if you do one po
may we have time later you can do
another thank you so much
you never know about those 1949 or
say okay I read this
one Dear
Dave today I reached your
age I get to turn another
page a favorite marijuana
stage you are missed on the stage
I will never
forget even if cannabist turned
blue your bright light will last even if
hundreds of years pass you turn me on a
lot we both love pot and
plants we never lost our pants we were
courageous and brave neither a na both
teachers preachers
all
right dog if you please come
yeah so after DG is done then we'll have
a slideshow that um Sienna
and okay hello so it's funny that that
order just happened because someone was
talking about the hempstock number one
which actually now is with the then okay
so I'll explain how it came how I came
here um and I came here in about 92 and
we started the
C it's all good dog good bro you
you anyways um
so he got us all started in the business
and um taught us about breeding and I
I'll go to a funny story just because uh
I got to get to that place and
um uh like when we first moved here we
were really young we started the CIA
which was like um hem clothing and
things which all came from you know the
ideas came from uh David and uh got us
into the seed business which it's like
everyone here I see I know through
this and um like Julian how I got into
business
Sor I didn't think I'd do this anyways
so um you know like he taught um about
breeding and everything about the
quality and it's like uh when we first
came it was like if you asked like
someone that was Dutch in the business
they just said oh it's the best and you
say you know and you're like why he like
because it's super you you know so Sam
had skunk and then everyone else had
super skunk and
you're saying super that's
all um so but what he what he taught us
you know we were really young you know
when we started the business and de and
Sam and Rob Clark were older you know so
they really uh taught us how to do
things right I mean we gave our like say
sage and MK Ultra to him he would
quarantine it and um then he would make
the seeds so then those seeds just
spread out it wasn't just me it was most
of the Dutch companies at the time uh he
was making them so that's why everything
has skunk in it and that's how we're you
know very connected uh not just from him
but through the genetics and the breing
that he was doing so this is Julian and
um he came to the Canabis cup once and
had this amazing amazing Sage so I knew
that that was uh from Sam because when
we had regular seeds he was making it
with the skunk number one
so then uh I brought Julian into the
business he's French so I called it lost
Ag and that's just kind of how we all
are interconnected um and it's like he's
the first seed and then it goes out you
know from us to everyone else in the
Canada's World um so
yeah
sorry and you got any of that stage SM
um no actually Julian he didn't bring
any up he just flew up from uh from
Barcelona and um yeah and his
daughter gave me the first the
first so everything is kind of like from
that seed of Sam David was just went out
and it's still out there in the canas
community um and so about three years
ago I was looking through my fridges and
I found um uh some old seeds that I got
from him I was um later on I was like
buying bulk of his skunk and the ones
and I found two strains sitting there
for like I think they're from the mate
90s and I selected uh like 10 of them
and I did germination test on them and
they all germinated so I was like I mean
that's just amazing work and that's
that's what it's all about like he
taught us you know the importance of the
plant and and breeding and quality
beyond anything else you know he was
always the you know more of a background
guy but also you know wanting to do
everything right whether it be H or TC
or canas so heway grateful to him and I
brought everyone that that grows I
brought some of those seeds for you guys
uh so please uh take them and plant them
uh with his memory and take some
pictures
all right so this slideshow
um well they figure out the slideshow I
guess I
can uh reminds me stories of I mean when
I first met David I was like not really
I
mean
okay but my like don't
smoke but why not just just don't do
it so I'm curious I was like so one day
I
did SM nice hit that was
B little stuff in there and to hit and I
went into our space for
about
hours pretty impressive and I was like
oh now I
get now I
know we're making progress over
there okay I'll just move the mic and
hope you enjoy SL shot
oh we should have the
all
is
something
stop
I love
you I love you
right
EX
oh
J
was
yes yes
before
[Music]
that's night
might yeah
me
back
just
you
so free so free so free
okay for
leave
[Music]
oh my God
mustach
St
SC
what
it's broken for
sure broke that glass and fix it with
the toilet paper roll
so
spe
know the f
has a focus
there it is
[Music]
thanks
Diana bring that together
back a lot of memories
yes right so
[Music]
I mean I guess we could smoke some
hash take take 10 15
minutes oh she's saying she can't hear
anymore we're gonna take a little break
just for a few
minutes it's all good so far so good
you're
right that's
yeah you always do bro
Department
this
that's
about
oh for
spe
pleas
f
not
oh yeah
was if
something
I'm gonna grab
this all right we're going to get some
of the session on uh all
right ready just did that with your face
Sam let's go
yes David's
last crushing it oh
wow name only that is a dab that Dave
would be proud of hell yeah damn Lorenzo
wow he's crazy we brought him in from
Italy
yeah Special
Delivery yeah man look at the jar
wow I still have some of the
dab the legend
of from um Michael Rich gave it to me
wow
okay Rich stories are coming out yeah
yeah Michael Rich
yeah we haven't met Brian I'm H I'm
Marcus nice to meet you but I
think was that like in the old
days I live around the corner from
the I would skip the dinner and
come come and experience some of the uh
the Hat yeah
the Hubbly
Bubbly I would I would go to F's house
on toads and I would I I was responsible
for caring those H to the RTI so I would
walk them very protective like like
don't worry it's just like hundred years
old or whatever like 100 years old it's
stressing me out yeah it felt like a
real we created
stand in in
line
[Music]
one I couldn't
well the even people like myself that
smoke an absolutely insane amount
Legends was another level yeah Legends
was something different yeah yeah you
know why it's why Dave was so happy at
Legends yeah yeah because he was like
everyone's doing for this one dinner
what I do all the time every day and but
he's got like a bunch of buddies
doing we were getting so blasted
exactly whatever you do don't smoke with
my dad that was a funny story don't
smoke with my I'm walk around I'll be
back Albert in the nose julan
didn't
see
I forgot no
seem
m
that's
am
I
spe
that
she
know
CP years
Tre
so for 20 years
com
d
to
best
to computer over
here think it's perfect
your for
right she's right
there no one second is
watching go I had to turn my mic off
yeah
hi
[Applause]
hello you were
here I know me too
I'll see you soon Mom I'm look I'm I'm
in the other you look at look to the
right of you a little bit look a little
bit to the right there's a phone I think
look a little bit to the right and down
down down down a little bit to the right
a little bit more to the right yeah more
no look yes there's a phone in front of
you look at that that's where I am yeah
look to the right turn turn turn turn
turn
no other way other other other way yeah
and now look
down down look down yeah I can't hear
you because too many people are
talking oh it's okay I'm I'm I'm I'm
over here I
see yeah because there's a phone by your
chest
[Laughter]
[Music]
yeah oh was somewhere else
I missed the beginning of Paul because
the the sound wasn't on
yet uh I missed the start of yours
because the sound wasn't on oh um that's
I just was saying like how when we first
met you know yeah and that thank God we
thought she was a
lesbian yeah I figured so much you you
few interesting stories about how we
like hang out
nice
nice think um
uh I think that
um already
speaking fall outside it's really
beautiful yeah that's
amazing
nice bye
how
amazing I it why why would I want to put
something on my feet yeah I don't know
protect
them
started taking seats
please and then
so it's quite
soft I think that but I think is better
through my
phone um if Ryan just turns his off for
a second then I can hear turn
volume I
know can you hear me still haly or no I
can hear you
yeah now there's two on is that
better no now there's two microphones on
so one has to turn off okay great so uh
yeah Robert's up oh Robert's not here oh
he'll be back
um maybe Ryan if you would like to say
some
okay okay I'm I'm double dipping here I
I spoke in California
um sure what I'm
say can't
you that better
no um I'm like I was just saying I'm
double dipping I've already spoken in
California so I'm going to try to find
something different to
say I've been thinking a lot about uh
David over the
last month and a half and trying to kind
of make sense
of just everything and losing him and
looking back at his life and trying
to you know just make sense of things
and I keep coming back to this thing
that there was people that understood
David and there was people that just did
not understand David at all I saw
someone right online that they said that
David was a a car wreck with
credentials and I you know I thought to
myself I couldn't be farther from the
truth this was clearly something that
didn't understand who David was you know
if if if you were a car wrecker an
accidental spilling of pain it would
have been the Mona
Lisa um and that kind of art and beauty
and accomplishment just doesn't happen
freely or without intention and I think
that you know if you gave life skill to
people on a scale of 1 to 10 David was
aain like he was so far intelligent and
accomplished beyond what people really
understood that he was and he wore this
kind of HIIT dog costume as a
cloak um in fact once he was you know
when he was in high school the principal
wanted him to cut his hair and his
choice was to you know cut his hair and
comply with the dress code or not
graduate so David decided not to
graduate um because he wanted to live
life on his own terms and like I said
last time David found a way in life to
turn turn all the NOS in life into yeses
he he wouldn't he wouldn't accept that
you couldn't do something and so he
always found a way to make that happen
be getting a license in Holland or you
know finally achieving working with a
pharmaceutical company to develop this
medicine that he experienced himself and
he knew that had this this therapeutic
potential and
um you know like one example is these
you know these soaps that are here
people can come and take a soap or a
shampoo they were made with skunk one
ham seed oil that David produced in
Hungary he he
had the head of the Hungarian research
world who was responsible for you know
the police would hire him to come when
there was a bus they'd hire him to come
and say this Farm was growing hemp
cannabis or drug cannabis and David had
him produce his drug cul car by the
multi-ton load in
Hungary um and and David used to say
there is two types of cannabis breeders
those that need a forklift to move the
Harvest and those that don't and and
David truly was the only one in the
former group right and that level of
success and achievement that he did in
our
industry was so unique it was
so I think it was quite resenting by a
lot of the people in the industry that
they figured out the path how to do the
things how to get the license how to do
the
work and
um yeah how to summarize that
all you do just just to say that you
know David he he I think that the people
that didn't understand him they were
fooled by the hippie dog costum and they
didn't realize what he had going on in
his mind and his game plan and his view
of
life
um I watched those photos and you know
all I see is him having fun and like I
said in California you know David's
really philosophy of life it
was as long as he got up every day and
had fun and caused a little bit of havoc
and learned or taught something new
about cannabis then he was
satisfied and I think that that's a
really a beautiful way to live and um
yeah he's that's that's why he's
inspired to me so anyhow God bless
[Applause]
David thank you Ryan for your
words
Robert introduce myself Robert Le
Carol
friend
davidon um Clos please speak into the
microphone haly needs to be able to hear
you okay very very good Haley hi sorry
um as I was saying
David uh was my
friend um why my best
friend you know I came and I thought to
myself for one thing I need to be really
resilient and strong for you guys for
the family um and and friends and I want
to show strength because um he he meant
so much and I know that we're all
hurting we're all hurting because we
miss
him he misses us just as well and uh I
just want to First have us a toast to
David
Coke David we love you we know you're
here David's here okay he's here
um I I have some strange talents I I am
able to perceive people's pain um their
love um David
was father
husband
Opa um
friend um Hash Hash teacher and
Mentor father figured for for many of us
uh I
would get a video call from um all the
time all the time and uh I would I'd
say i' look at my phone an
Angel
Vasquez
howdy howdy
howdy we made that connection howdy
howdy
howdy all right and um you
know he was a farmer you guys you know
he I would ask him when did you get up
oh 500 a.m. six a why do you get up so
early I would ask him he would say well
because I consider myself a farmer and
no [ __ ] he'd get up that early and I
think that's what he admired about me
and now I have cattle for the past 5
years I've been working very hard on my
farm David saw this and he saw
and knew what hard work can do for you
uh the environment that I live in is is
animals you guys but I I give a lot of
respect to my animals and I speak to my
animals just like as if they were my
friends or people okay and um David
liked that he admired that and he he he
um kind of liked to to see this
environment as he started slowing down a
bit and couldn't walk as much I felt
like if I was his legs a little bit
showing them my artch choke fields that
I was growing my orange Orchards my
cannabis of course cannabis first and I
mean let's face it you know that's that
was the one thing that bam and and
Marcus helped many of us connect with
him from meeting him to to having um
celebrations and things like that and
and that was that was something that
that David was always um happy and proud
of of of certain people that um did
things in his life for him you know now
I want to tell you that that there's a
way that I think that we can kind of
transform this kind of sadness that we
feel when we think about them and it
happened to me you know I'm I don't have
a lot of cookie thoughts and that but I
don't really know how to explain it
first there was
time when I contacted him just before
his passing and we had a very long
discussion he was very positive very
upbeat I can tell you that the day
before that was passing and the day of
and and and which was like wild and it's
hit us so hard because we have no
warning like car accident no warning
nothing just bam and they that now so
how do we process this how do we deal
with it and how do we change that memory
into something Grand something and and
it's happened to me a little quicker
okay it's I still get emotional but I
was working very hard getting Forge for
the cows crying actually thinking of
David and and a double rainbow
appeared now when this happens to you I
mean imagine you got some tears
streaming you look up you see this
rainbow my God that's I that's what I
needed I really needed it and I I
thought well that's that's crazy you
know it can't happen twice you know kind
of thing and uh two days later it
happened again and I called Diana and I
was like Diana look because I called her
and I told her I said
David this is crazy she said I wish
you'd send me
rainbows and I said Diana here I guess
he's only doing them here something you
know and
um he he was really something else I
mean marijuana botney was was was really
dear to my heart I don't think we can
mention uh marijuana botney without
mentioning David Watson and we can't
mention David Watson without mentioning
Robert colell Clark because those two
guys um are like salt and pepper you
know there's that two sides of the coin
well I say salt and pepper you know what
I mean and um it's it's pretty amazing
because uh I would uh you know asked
David hey I can almost hear you in
marijuana botney sometimes and you know
in these chaps and he said well yeah man
that's because I wrote all the cool
stuff and
it's you know and and he had a way of
hiring the best he knew J Jer he he knew
the best he he wanted quality he knew
how to make you strive for the best and
and today um he's not only um a legend
but he he's someone that I think that we
can all want to be like and if I can
just end with this I probably went over
the three minutes that's fine but I I
just want to say that you know he took
me under his wing you guys for Christmas
and and he's known to have a [ __ ]
detective right but he also had a
compion
detector and he saw I was alone and for
Christmas he invited me in to the family
and took me in under his wing and you
guys it it it helped me so much and now
now like I I uh I just I get stronger
when with his thoughts now you know what
I mean like when I think about him now
I'm like I know in Holland anything
super is better so I say super David
help me and he seems to get me through
some hard times you know so he's here
now we love you David we miss you and um
your cat I want to end with that really
misses you
really so I played with him all morning
play with
Oney but he got a lot of toys just like
Sammy he's got too many toys but uh
thanks guys and thank you David
[Applause]
I remember that Christmas it was a Beau
Christmas in
alante h Marcus
Marcus sorry Marcus there he is could
you please come up sir
this this going to be
hard you can do
this I first met David uh well I first
learned of David in I want to say 1996
he had come to Canada and he was at a a
a hemp
Symposium uh that we were having we were
kind of the Manitoba hemp guys at the
time me and my partners were trying to
get hemp growing well we had actually we
had just gotten hemp growing for the
first time in 73 years in our Province
we brought over Zola toosha from the
Ukraine and so we were at this hemp
Symposium and we saw Dave who was
actually he spoke at this uh event and
I've got a pretty high level of
awareness and when I saw him speak I was
just like this guy is different he is
not the same as everyone else and there
was Rumblings and rumors of who he was
and he was this sort of Infamous
character uh I wouldn't really meet him
for a few more years but I would meet
Robert uh conell Clark through my dear
friend Hillary black and she would bring
she brought Rob to my house in the in
the mid 90s and I ended up kind of
getting to know rob a little bit and on
a trip to Amsterdam um I bumped into Rob
and he happened to have a RAR pipe with
him and he smoked some of this dryft
with me and he said if it don't if it
don't bubble it ain't worth the trouble
and that really stuck in my mind I'd
never seen hash melt like that little
did I know that that was David's hash uh
and in fact that was also David's saying
and so when I started my company uh in
1999 fresh hes I used that as the as the
slogan uh if it don't bubble it ain't
worth of trouble well about I want to
say 2 days later but it probably was
more like 2 hours later I get this like
email from this like
skunkman yahoo.com
and he's like if it don't bubble it
ain't worth of trouble do you know who
first said that and I was like yeah oh
[ __ ] okay I was like I was like okay I
got this I replied back I do know who
said this I know who you are I have full
respect for you I will never use it
again if you don't want or I'll pay you
to use it what do you want me to do and
for whatever reason that seemed to be
the right combinations of things to say
to Dave because he slowly and this is
1999 for those of you that have known
Dave a long
time he was a little bit more difficult
to to to connect with in 1999 and he was
in 2010 or 2015 it was really uh and and
that was because of his dedication to
his work he had this incredible
dedication to this work and as much as
he did want to have fun as well he would
sacrific the fun that he could have to
make sure that the work that he was
doing was executed properly and so that
was why you know no pictures and much
more of a private life but somehow
through this bubble bag thing I managed
to you know meet him at the Pack's party
house for the first time and we were
like school children all excited and
Giddy and I remember we he smoked a bowl
of hash with me and he said look look
when it's really good it's it full melts
like that and I'm like oh yeah and look
it's got a clear Dome and we're you know
we're geeking out together and we're
creating language and vernacular that
will be used 20 years from now that we
don't even know we're doing you know it
wasn't many years later that we decided
um why don't we you know what if we
could take all the people at the
Cannabis Cup in Amsterdam and run them
through your bubble bags and just
collect like the 73 heads and that
became the legends of hashish dinner and
so it was an amazing honor to be able to
throw that party with him over the years
I you know we never celebrated often
people said oh you guys are like weird
celebrating yourselves you think you're
Legends and we were like no come to
Legends we're not celebrating ourselves
we're celebrating City hi we're
celebrating the garden of kafur we're
celebrating actual hashish Legends and
you know Dave definitely said one day
when I'm gone you know I want you to
celebrate me and we will absolutely be
celebrating Dave at the next Legends of
hash dinner uh I want to thank everyone
for showing up here today I want to
thank Dave for letting me into his life
I had no idea when I first met him and I
was more of the student how much much I
had in common with him how much my
family had in common with with him and
Diana um going to Jamaica with them and
spending that time and realizing how
amazing he was with with my daughter and
my
son I love you Dave you were my friend
and I miss
[Applause]
you thank you yeah all right yeah he was
a got say you da love the
kids he was a
kid I think you're the last
one can I sit in the chair sure of
course of course
no way
[Music]
more yeah I'm still recovering from
SP my voice is also not quite there so
I'm not going to make this very long but
I came here for
D actually How uh met the first times
was at the
CIA uh when uh I showed my machine and I
don't even know how I got there but
somehow David and Robert arranged it and
I was there and they unveiled it and I
think it must have been David who had
some material to everything and he was
put in the pollinator and the triome
challenge happened and the is sitting
back there
is there is so many some had just
arrived I think from St with Jack har
Ben drunkers was there and it was an
amazing evening for me i' never hardly
met any of
them so here we are David you meant so
much for me and just being accepted as a
friend was already so much for me thank
you
[Applause]
thank you m um all right
well that's all the people who asked to
speak so but uh I will wrap it up a
little bit by saying I told you guys in
the
beginning we have more time for some
those PS too oh yeah we do have two
poems yeah
okay would you like that Diana Diana
would you like to hear the
poems EXC would hear the poems
[Music]
dear Angel
Vasquez s
says you are a cannabis
Guru a cannabis
goto a shiny
example of THC
ample getting enough in a puff really
knowing your stuff and teaching and
preaching courage never a drudge for me
a bright light his influence not slight
he entered my heart never will
beart and this one I wrote this
morning I I just woke up I looked at my
phont was exactly
420 so I
wrote I woke today at
4:20 knew I would see
many loving
Souls helping to fill
holes left by the dear
departed Dave you were
chartered when you got CED
definitely not R [ __ ] you didn't get
popped didn't get stopped you pass with
flying
colors I lost my
MERS but I'm here remembering you dear
never forgetting you even if cannabis
turned blue
[Applause]
[Music]
thank
you okay so um like I said in the
beginning I said I remember the first
time I met David very vividly and I also
remember the last time I saw him so I'll
share that with you and
Parton last Su song was
Christmas my daughter my daughter's
birthday and I remember saying to Maya
when he left he said
goodbye and he drove
off I remember saying that was a good
day that was a very good
day thank you
[Applause]
please enjoy yourselves we're here till
[Music]
o' maybe you could ask the people sign
the book and take
a please if you can sign the book
something say something about David
share a memory and also please take some
care of this products if you like
stop
recording right done I just wanty to be
able to keep