hey guys welcome back to bubble man's
world I'm sitting here kind of crouched
down because i want to get everything
fit into the picture i got my macro lens
set up I've got the Faberge egg with the
D nail set up and I've got the brand new
deep-dish banger so this is the deep
dish banger it's really quite neat
easily could insert the first part of my
pinky all the way down before it hits
the bottom then it has a separate piece
that's underneath it with a hole in it
that the the coil fits around really
nice little unit what I wanted to do was
I wanted to get see if I can find some
I'm good enough nope alright let me get
this going so we'll get this recording I
want to give you guys both shows so deep
dish banger with some barbed 90 micron
now here's a really cool thing that I
not sure you guys will be able to see if
I just remember this quickly go put that
hand in and safely now it has condensed
in the stem of this so you can turn it a
little bit you can see there's some oil
that's run down there it's just this
perfectly clear oil so earlier I
actually scooped a piece of this out
from Johns deep-dish banger and it's i
think i'm going to get real quite
excited about the prospects for a second
of being able to get a clear reclaim
Horatio at first just said you know it's
just reclaimed who wants that blah blah
blah blah but then when he saw the way
it worked and the way it was sort of
actually have a small piece of it that
John left I grabbed off of jones up
jones d banger I pushed it into this
little bit of dry sipped and the way it
came off blue Horatio away because it
just cleaned so perfectly so yeah let's
see if we can't scoop a little of that
perfectly fresh oh yeah that's like a
clear oil it's pretty unbelievable of
one rip
got a little bit there another room
this deep dish banger just really wanted
to show you guys in a short little video
I'm also going to attach the part of the
video that came in from the macro lens
to see how I haven't checked it out yet
but we'll see how good it looks and yeah
hope you guys enjoyed the video and you
can check these out at d dash nail com
use the code bubbleman with a capital B
and a 10 at the end of it you gave
something ten percent discount thanks
for watching us