[Music]
and we are here with uh bubble man the
man who's responsible for all of this
madness
here why the hell did you take this
crazy project on Mark
um you know that's kind of a hard uh a
hard question to answer it's been a year
and a half in the making it was this
space was originally supposed to be
um a space for my manager to have an
office if you could believe it or not
that's all I needed for the Bubble Bag
Company a small little office space and
on a beach in Jamaica I had a friend
call me and say I found the space for
you it's inii ini Commercial Drive
that's 11-11 Commercial Drive and I was
sitting on a beach in Jamaica thinking
that I could just be sitting enjoying
the bubble bag thing for the next 10 or
20 years and watching my kids play on
the beach thinking you know maybe I
should start more projects maybe I
should maybe I should give back more to
the community rather than just try and
hoard for myself and sort of undertook
this project of getting this space
trying to turn it into a something new
that isn't easily categorized you know
and I always had the idea of making it a
gallery space and so this really was our
the birth of our Gallery we've been here
a year and a half and this was our first
show and it was the birth of the melting
point I couldn't think of a better theme
to have uh to start have started us out
with so tell me what the intention was
in bringing all of these Glass artists
in their work together why did you want
to do that specifically um well that's
directly related to um a relationship I
have with marble Slinger the glass
blower so um me and him have been
talking about this I mean really we've
talked about this for years and a year
ago
um in combination with me getting this
space and not knowing a name and all
these different things over a year ago
now there was a showdown in San
Francisco at a gallery called the
melting point gallery and it was a it
was a pipe show and I had I wasn't able
to go I'm not allowed down in the US but
I had I saw pictures and a little bit of
video of the show and it it really
inspired me I mean the name inspired me
so much that I called the gallery
melting point Gallery so that was a big
part of the inspiration and then just uh
my relationship with marble Slinger and
uh the last few years have just been
sort of on a collision course for this
event to have happened you know he was
he was my inspiration and I think I was
kind of his inspiration and he really
wanted to show the people up here that
there's an entire community of glass
that we don't know about because there's
this border that keeps us divided like
I'm not allowed to go down there they're
afraid to come up here because they feel
that when they go to the Border they're
they're offering themselves up to the to
the chopping block even when they're not
doing anything wrong so I mean that
that was kind of our inspiration right
there you know this is the first event
of its kind in Canada which is very
exciting I think so I mean I'm I'm I'm
not everywhere in Canada at all times
but I haven't heard of such an event
happening and I mean honestly I'm a
glass collector and I know a lot about
the glass Community some of these pieces
blew my mind absolutely blew my mind the
themes the concepts the construction
okay so here's the tough question mark
which is your favorite piece oh almost
imp possible to answer because there are
so many different themes you know I like
so many different pieces in the show for
so many different reasons uh the first
piece to to come in was the Jason Lee
which was the that incredible motorcycle
piece that was actually a combo of of
Jason Lee and uh Steve hops I believe
was his name and they did an absolutely
outstanding job really I mean it was the
first piece to show up and we opened it
up and we see this this motorcycle and
it just blew the top of every 's heads
off it made us realize that this show is
going to be impeccable so also um the
Amber piece the DJ right behind us here
the DJ and the break dancer is just I
mean it doesn't you know words don't
even need to describe it you just need
to see a little bit of a picture of it
or see it in in real life and it's so
accurate and with the jewelry added on
to the to the pieces and little things
like gluing a little tiny curly strap
from the headphone down to the turntable
every detail was was perfect I I really
enjoy that piece a lot you totally
successfully wiggled out of my very
tough question so I'm going to ask it
again in a different way if you could
choose one of these pieces to add to
your collection um as um a smoking
device is something that you're you know
inhaling your favorite resin through so
we'll narrow the categories a little bit
so as a puffing piece which one would
you choose to add to your personal
collection I mean really that is so
difficult to answer it there's there's
multiple pieces that I the max piece is
so impressive to have that I mean you
really you hold that in your hand and
you feel that you could really take over
a small third world country with that
pipe like a like a gauntlet holding it
up in front of the people it's uh it it
it could be the one but honestly the the
Amber the the max um there's there's so
many that I love it's hard to choose a
favorite honestly the Jason Lee they're
all great the artist all did an
impeccable job and honestly if I had the
cash I'd buy every single one of them
and then I would have a pipe party where
we would hit every single one of them if
I had my way what do you think was the
greatest success of the opening of the
show last night um I think it was a
combination of things I think it was
just you know the artists showing up and
really being positively pumped to have a
venue to be able to display their art
which is now a criminalized industry
down in America where they live the fact
that we really topped it off with the
living raw foods we had the outside
access with the fire twirlers like it
just seemed to always keep getting
better and for me I I didn't even plan
it all my you know like a lot of it was
planned by my manager dandi and Aaron
had components we were all compon
components that were compartmentalized
almost up to the very end where we just
sort of went click click click click
click click click like Lego and put them
all together so everyone did their part
and played their part impeccably and I
think that's what made it go off as well
as it did yeah so a couple of people
have used the word movement around um
this art and can you explain to me what
that means to you in terms of this art
and these um pipe making artists um
being being a part of a movement what
are we moving towards where are we
moving from well you know what I think
we're we're really this pipe art is
really um sort of a Frontline for
cannabis activism I mean a lot of these
guys have been in spired by cannabis but
they are not allowed to come out of the
closet with it because down in America
just admitting that condemns your work
so you know they don't they're in a
they're really they're in a they're in a
place where they need to make their
decisions based on fear and I think part
of the word movement is to try and you
know remove fear from your emotional
vocabulary step up out of the fear and
that's what I mean man these guys are
making these pieces any every day it
sounds ridiculous to you guys out there
but literally they can they can get
arrested and thrown in jail they can be
fined thousands of dollars they can
spend months in jail for blowing glass
pipes that have no traces of resin in
them but merely for sending it over an
imaginary line that was just put up to
divide us just to create more division
just to fill jails so it's neat that
Canada bordering America can be the
venue for these guys to come up you know
it was uh very much the same for the um
the modern artists who were fleeing
Germany and the Nazi Germany time 37 in
Berlin fleeing into Amsterdam and having
these incredible
um squats these huge art buildings that
there's a few old ones in Amsterdam that
have famous names but these people were
fleeing there to just save themselves
and save their art the the fact that
these guys make pipes is an expression
of their freedom and their it's being
condemned where they live so anytime you
do that it's uh it's a big deal and
that's why the word movement comes comes
in they're they're a movement and
they've got to lift themselves up really
what I want to do with all this is I
want to start stop the divisions we
constantly divide ourselves even even as
a community of pip blowers we can Divi
divide ourselves and and put ourselves
into little balls and it I just like to
break the bubbles get things out into
the mainstream and show people that this
really is
Art it really is thank you you did a
fabulous job all right
and do we get to have it again next year
is this going to be an annual event
absolutely we'll do it next year we're
going to start planning it already we
definitely want to have panels of glass
blowers we want to make it like a maybe
even a two-day event but we'll
definitely have a gallery show that will
be uh that will Top This blowers out
there you can start working on your
pieces for next year's show yes start
working on your pieces guys and
girls thank you thanks
Hillary Marcel thanks for sticking
around a little bit so that we could
chat today the day
after um I want to start by you telling
me about this insanely beautiful piece
here tell me exactly what it is and what
it means to you and anything else that
you want to say um this is a piece is
called arity I made it in uh
2003 um
it's well you can see the tag here it
says an artistic cycle describing the
evolution of a medium from its Inception
through necessary function to a pure
expression for its own sake and it's
kind of about a human uh every time
humans get a hold of a technology it's
usually just a matter of time before
they turn it towards artistic expression
and some
technologies actually get turned to a
point where the artistic expression is
the primary purpose of utilizing the
technology and that's kind of what this
piece is about is it's a you know you've
got this sand and people from Sand they
started working with glass and glass was
natural for preserving food and for
making bowls and functional objects of
all kinds and so moving through that
people started making these functional
objects and then they started
making they started decorating them to
make them fancier and stuff and it
eventually at some point with glass it
became the function became the
decoration rather than the vessel and
the first first place or the glass
article and so that's kind of what this
is about is it's like there's all these
things you can make a bubbler you can
make a goblet you can make a bowl you
can make a distilling apparatus for a
science for a pharmaceutical company but
then you can also take the same medium
and make this thing that has no purpose
other than to communicate or
to fulfill my fancy as a maker and who
is this
creature um I I wouldn't say that it's
so much of a who I mean it's kind of
a you know a
phoenix Phoenix Rising sort of an entity
you know it's a it's an energy creature
it's a being um I don't know that it is
personality for and when you started a
project like this did you know like did
you already have a vision in mind of
what it was going to turn out or does it
get a life of its own and and grow into
something other than what you thought it
was going to between start and finish
what I usually do is I just I come up
with an idea like something I want to do
with it before I come up with a form so
for this piece I was interested in kind
of conveying an idea before I was
interested in making a form per se and
so it's
um it's can be a harder way to go
because you have to you come up with
this thought this something that's worth
spending all this time CU it takes it
took us three months and thousands of
dollars to be able to make this so to
take all that time and all that energy
and just do something that might that
doesn't really have anything behind it
that's just a thing just doesn't it
doesn't seem worth it to take all that
time and energy so we always try and
have a an idea going before we even
start melting glass and usually before
we even start drawing
form that's stunning I'm glad that you
spent the time and the resources because
it's totally
mindblowing so last night was a pretty
amazing night and I'm wondering as an
artist what the significance of last
night was to you um it was it was
definitely a good time I mean you know
it's really nice to get this piece out
and uh have you know have people see it
and appreciate it you know the the art
has to be seen if it's not seen then
it's just my as well not exist in the
first place and so every opportunity I
get to get it out there and have people
experience it the way that I do or part
you know start to you know have that
experience with it it's really I like to
see that I like to have people get that
chance
to to see it thank you for bringing this
Beast up um in your uh in your Homeland
down there in you know what to us as
Canadian seems like you know Land Of
Darkness although I know there are some
very bright spots has the environment
that you work in changed significantly
with you know Ashcraft and all of the
sort of bad guy Crackdown on the on the
pipes programs that's happening or is it
a little bit further out there are you
feeling the impacts in in your work and
in your environment I think it's you
know honestly it's a
really long-term thing like I don't feel
that there's been this like huge shift
in the recent past I mean things
happened and some people were uh their
businesses were confiscated and they
were taken to jail but that's also
something that's been going on steadily
in the states and around other other
countries for a long time and it's more
a matter
of a cycle of um this because it's a
gray area and because it's sort of a a
semi Market it
has just sort of a mixed bag of
attributes that are in some ways helpful
to the independent artist in some ways
not I mean for instance one of the
things that's really
helpful about it being semi Market is
that no there aren't corporations with a
lot of money to just walk in and take
over the market for instance
um with a clothing company like for
instance seedless you've got this
seedless company and they're making all
their their clothes and stuff but at
some point
a company with overseas connections to
have all this stuff made can walk in and
just either try and forcibly buy the
company and take over that brand and
turn it into like part of the corporate
Juggernaut whereas with the glass pipes
that's much harder to do because of the
legal issues a company with that much to
lose and that much investment can never
take that course of action you know
that's not going to happen the same way
and so it's kind of leaves room for the
little guy for the whole time so it's
it's definitely a mixed thing that it's
hard to really like completely
um I just don't like to have a totally
negative outlook on it on anything for
that matter but see the opportunities
and just about anything exactly because
there's the world is messed up anyway so
you know you have to just look at what
is really there and op capitalize on
what's there whatever it
is so how long have you been blowing
glass class for Al together uh just
about 10 years so in that time you have
invested yourself into a huge amount of
Art and incredible pieces that have now
been spread out in the world that are
off in other people's homes and if there
was one piece that you've made that's
made its way out there in the world that
you could have back which one would it
be and
why the one piece that I I would like to
have back never actually left my
possession you've got it I've still got
it that it's very good Forward Thinking
nice SP yeah no it was a it's a fish
2000 I made it for the fish show that
they had at Big Cypress in Florida it
was a New Year's show and it was about
God I forget how many people were there
40,000 people or something but we got
there and it's uh it was the first piece
where I'd been working on these other
pieces that are around here there's
number one the over there and this is
number
three this is some pieces from that time
frame this is about 1999 hold it nice
and still so like this piece was
um built in
1999 it's called number three at first I
was numbering these uh fancy aquatic
pieces um they were I'd been
experimenting with large scale stuff
for maybe half a year or something but I
was really kind of uh holding my punches
on the pattern work a little bit to
because they're so risky to make the
technical process of joining so many
parts was difficult so I wanted to have
minimum amount of work in the pieces so
that when they broke which they did on a
regular basis they would it wouldn't be
such a big deal and when I got confident
with the construction I started making
these bigger and elaborately decorated
pieces like that one over there is
number one in the case and then this one
here is number three but anyways at the
end of 99 I decided to make fish 2000
and I'd seen my first fish show earlier
that year and uh it
um after my first fish show I was all
stoked on this on this band I was like
oh these guys are just great I love what
they're doing with the crowd and with
the energy and like getting everyone
involved and so I um spent like a month
trying to figure out how to make a glass
piece that was going to repres present
this thing that I had seen this con
concert and so it was like this long
process of all kinds of like couch
meditations and just like really I spent
all this time thinking about it finally
came up with the design and uh executed
this thing it was like I barely finished
it in time to get on the plane I was
literally warm in my suitcase getting
ready to go had been scheduled to go
home to my parents house for Christmas
and I just couldn't get on the plane to
go there cuz I had to finish this piece
it was just
like it was nuts but it's um it ended up
being a cluster of dolphins spiraling
around each other there's five six
dolphins in it plus a bunch of fish and
it's a bubbler that hangs on the wall
it's really terrible that I don't have
it or a picture I could probably Supply
a picture for you if you need it um but
it's you know tall the Dolphins are each
dolphin is decorated with a different
color of dichroic and then they're
joined and they're dancing in front of a
spiral that has five different colors
dichroic one for each dolphin and
they're spiraling together and the
dolphins that are hooked together the
sections that are hooking each dolphin
together is that same
spiral tube stock with each of the five
colors so each of the energies is
represented going through as these
dolphins are like spinning around and it
was I was going through I mean it was
just amazing at the
show uh we were just puffing that thing
so tough cuz we got to the fish show and
there was no no one had anything to
relax with there's no herb anywhere they
just like it just ended up being this
crazy puff session the whole time like I
have no idea how many people experienced
that piece but it was it must have been
a thousand at least wow I mean
and you hung on to it um H is that piece
not up here because it's been used and
so you didn't want to bring it across
the border um it's not up here because
there wasn't time for me to prepare it
to cross the border yeah so yeah I mean
it's it's definitely you know plus it's
become so valuable to me that it
Crossing International bord something
that can't be done in a hurry it's not
that I'm scared of it but you know you
have to be got to be careful exactly
yeah
so what is next for you you know like
this piece here seems to me like it
would represent sort of a pinnacle thus
far in your path as an artist do you
have ideas of where you want to go next
um I mean I just keep wanting to make
more of these more of these large pieces
and um installations and stuff I'm
really looking for I have some ideas to
make some pieces with several uh figures
or Sentinels like this size in like
arrangement to fill fill a space or
cover a room or something like a
different thought about making a piece
with the like
um I I see these guys as kind of like
Sentinels or Warriors or you know people
entities that are in doing battle or
whatever so I I kind of want to like
arrange some of these guys with like you
know in a line like a formation and then
have like the black hordes of like you
know scorpions and just like worms and
you know I've been doing some really
like dark experimental stuff with like
really buggy looking forms and stuff so
I kind of want to bring them to br br
together exactly together the dark and
the light exactly well thank you for
your incredible work and for taking your
time this morning and hopefully you'll
come up to Vancouver and place some more
you know you make it up here once in a
while I do thank you thank you
nice good
enough Max yes welcome to Vancouver
thank you so the crazy piece in there
that you blew I never seen anything like
that
before what what was the inspiration
behind that beast and what do you call
it and what is it and tell me a little
bit about it well uh I make a lot of
pieces that that are similar to that and
uh I guess I kind of think of them as
some kind of like a a lightning storm or
a thunderstorm type of theme
um I think my inspiration is probably
just growing up in the Northwest and you
know I feel like my glass is kind of a
representation of uh you know like the
nature and all that you know it's kind
of how I see the world uh put into glass
so I guess that's
part of the inspiration at least how
long does it take to create something
like that like how many hours of work
are we talking about there uh I'd say
that there's roughly like a 100 hours in
there but there's time you know there's
sitting and waiting or you know uh time
that it takes to heat up you can only
hold a piece that big for a certain
amount of time so uh you know it took me
about two weeks from start to finish
doing 10hour days and how does it puff
does it does it can you smoke out of it
does it smoke
well is a more of a looker it's 100%
functional um but you know it's also
just an art piece you know uh it's never
been
smoked
and that's a little easier to travel
over International borders to get it
into shows that way it is easier you
know FedEx likes it better when it's
clean so uh totally um how is it for you
being a glass blower in America now that
you're starting to turn into Mordor down
there you know you're in like the the
land of the the dark and oppressive I
know that glass blowers are potentially
under a hell of a lot more pressure and
facing a lot more risk than they used to
yeah how is that for you in your world
and how's it changed like what are the
risks that you're facing now compared to
what you were a year ago or two years
ago well you know it's it's just a lot
different um before I don't think there
were any potential risks you know it's a
it was a non-issue and now I guess uh
there's certain States and even
federally uh people are saying it's
illegal to make
paraphernalia um which is kind of absurd
you know I view what we do as something
Beyond just paraphernalia you know if
you look at a lot of the pipes and
especially the pipe that you were just
talking about I think uh you know it's
beyond a functional level of art glass
it's something that um would not be
marketed to Children you you know it's
things that uh you know it's something
that you would see in a stock broker's
house or something yeah
absolutely um so what are the what are
the actual risks now to or or sort of
not so much the risks but the the
threats that of of what they could do to
glass blowers like I hate to dig for the
scandal of stories like do you know any
stories of glass blowers that have been
sort of facing nasty things recently
I've never personally met a glass blower
that's gotten in trouble blowing glass
um at least in Washington State uh you
have to you know intend it as
paraphernalia um for it to be considered
paraphernalia and so that's kind of a
fine line I think uh you know a lot of
police and Washington have seen glass uh
you know and not confiscated it you know
they appreciated his art I think you
know the laws passed by uh you know the
administration in the states right now
and Ashcraft you know it's uh it's not
something that represents the country as
a whole you know it's a it's a small
minority that thinks that way and uh
they happen to be the ones that have the
power at this point yeah so um have you
had your pieces in a show like this
before like a proper art show no this is
uh the most properly I'd say they've
ever been displayed um most galleries in
the states are afraid to bring in
something that could be construed as
paraphernalia
um so yeah this is the first time
congratulations I think it's fabulous to
have all of you guys brought in from all
over and all these incredible headpieces
and you know showing them off to the
public like uh you know that you're
artists because you are great thank you
very much so welcome hope you have a
fabulous time in Vancouver and uh keep
up the good work definitely thanks
been an incredible night here at The
Melting Point listening to Jazz smacking
on raav raw food and talking to some of
these incredible artists that are so
thrilled to actually be showcased
artists um so thank you for tuning in
and after a monthong Hiatus the black
show will be back in action and we'll
see you next week so to then take care
of yourself
[Music]
I
always you on your way out
[Music]
so we're here with uh Chris and amethyst
art maker and art lover what did you
think of what you saw today in all those
glass
boxes did you see anything cool yeah
yeah what was cool the drummer and the
break dancer the drummer and the break
dancer was very cool did you see the
cool one hanging on the wall there was
kind of like a head with flowers coming
out of it no no maybe we'll go look at
that one afterwards cuz if you like the
break dancers you might like that one
too and this guy made it hey I know him
you know him you hang out a lot
really not enough but yeah it's a Betty
of
yours so you know this guy does this
glass blowing thing yeah have you ever
seen him do
it
no no probably so the okay you can go if
you want you want to stay okay excuse me
technical difficulties here there we go
now we're sett okay so that piece that
you made in there is incredible and I'm
sure that you hear that all the time
um we'll just have to lean in and share
a mic
here your pieces are really different
than a lot of what else is out there you
don't seem to have the pipe Drive can
you tell me just a little bit about like
what's your stick what's your passion
what what is the thing that motivates
you to make what you make why do you
make it that's a tough question 10
questions in one sure sure um where am I
coming from
well let's see I live in Bellingham
that's a good start thanks welcome to
Vancouver thanks it's good to be here um
so I live in Bellingham and I uh work at
a shop in town and I live in town and
uh I have a tight little community of
friends and um in in my shop we have
like kind of really good group of people
and so right now I'm at this spot you
part of Amber's Harum no no you're not
in that Collective it's uh it's Brock
Marvel and uh Scott deppy and Ivan
Barrow and uh Johnny Sternberg and kais
medok and myself and it's pretty cool so
there's like six of us in there do you
know some of those other guys to Tim
Cook yeah these are all your buddies
there's seven and definitely one my dad
your dad which one's your dad that's Ian
got it yeah all right so I'm I'm in a
good group right now and I'm just in a
good spot and um I'm having fun and my
work is
uh I don't know that piece in particular
I drew um I was just drawing some like
real rough sketches and
um I really don't I can't really offer
much explanation for it it's just
something that I I made and I worked
through probably was about um a month in
the making just like different parts
that I'd make and I I knew it was all
coming together I didn't know EX L how
but um it was like a real rough sketch
and then made parts
and it's so stunning it's totally
stunning do you find that there's a
market for your nonm smokable
pieces that the one pipe that I have in
here is the second like
real pipe that I've made um bubblers
it's the second bubbler that I've made
and uh I made it
I made it for
myself and so I don't really have a
market as is right now I don't have a
market at all selling pipes because I
don't make them but I sell a lot of
vessels and some sculpture that I make
mostly like mostly vessels with
different
um different cane worked sections and
like I make teapots I make te- bowls um
I make teapots that you can put on the
stove and boil water with I make wine
glasses I make um I wish that we had a
teapot of yours here I would love to see
you when your teapot probably happen
that'll probably happen I need to
uh I'm I'm working on finding more um
venues to show my work and I'm really
excited about this gallery and this show
in particular um and really for me to
kind of to be in this is it's a little
bit uh it's different because like it's
it's a it's a movement that's been
happening for a little while and um and
just like I guess I'm just in the show
because I made a pipe um it's cool and
I'm really I'm really excited about it
and I'm just excited about it I don't
know that's awesome yeah it seems to be
sort of a common theme that everybody's
really thrilled to be showcased as an
artist rather than next to the Rolling
Papers it's it's much like it's long
overdue it's is really deserved this is
um the way I see it what's happening in
here is an underground art movement
that's just now like starting to get
attention and it's gaining momentum um I
think it's I think it's amazing and the
world is just is ready to see this it's
something else
and I don't know maybe it won't ever get
like really large mainstream attention
but it's uh it's going to happen
anyway I think it's really cool I think
so too and I think your work is
absolutely incredible and uh I hope you
come and play in Vancouver
somewhere and do you live in Bellingham
too Y and are you going to come and play
in Vancouver some more
I don't know have you had any fun here
yet mhm yeah you've had some fun I hope
you come back and visit some more I will
can you say happy Canada day for me
happy Canada Day hey
toal
[Music]
here's where all the action goes
down where all the goodies are made yeah
did you get a piece no but I'd love
one you my friend thank you very much
yeah [__] n got the best the newes
are taking over this
[__] hey n in the house finally here
nobody nobody told me it's was going to
be this hot I I brought a [__] I
brought an ice pipe son of a [__]
melted here's a nice pipe right here
they Ser upat H the treats were probably
done now there just some ra designer
going around that stock can I grab a
stock of celery over there yeah
[Music]
[Applause]
she
what's up what you're creating in new
genre here with your life I mean you
know when I first met bubble man and his
incredible $20 Shelf with $20,000 worth
of Glass on it he was the first glass
collector first time I ever heard the
name Jason Lee first time I heard the
name marel Slinger started seeing these
pieces I understood that this was a
collectible medium this wasn't just into
your local head shop so you know you
guys are creating a whole new genre
as you go along with this artart form
it's not just into the head shops
anymore collectors are coming on this is
the first
real Rick and mortar indication you've
seen I've seen of getting all these
pieces in one place together to really
drive it I think this is going to be the
first of many that's just my you know
what I see I don't know you guys see a
lot more of it you live in but I mean
just from my perspective seeing all
these P this a nice show at one time
together I mean you're going to see this
written up in different articles you're
going to see it show up in different
places and you're going to generate just
the vibe and that height is going to
generate more people saying I can buy
this I can collect this you know there's
there's a lot of people out there with
money that will spend
gun I know I had the background picture
of Marcel looking at guns I'm like
that's pretty perfect
I got to go talk to them while they're
holding those
guns on the it's okay on the
camera I got talk to these guys thank
you guys for talking we'll
talk what's up with these
guns let's talk about it I I don't mean
to point at anybody in a bad way I
really don't see that's part of the
entire deal though that's one of the
best start pointing at somebody you're
like that check that out is that you
rais your whole life not to point
absolutely it's great you see how
uncomfortable I've already made you I
love it that's the whole what was the
idea you were saying about the Smoking
Gun part of your statement there it you
see your friends yeah check check out
Chris is our buddy look at
him what the [__] is that why would I
put my mouth on a [__] gun and
smoking out here you see how it works it
works so
well let me see that
thing so what is that is that a pipe I
like the way this one fits that
one it's a gun
why did you make a glass
gun that's a pipe to make people help
really so is it more did you make that
more as an art piece or more as just a
functional pipe it's a performance piece
how does it
work and
then how does the performance part of it
works you shoot yourself I think it's
interesting the way people hand the
you see the performance
involved it just shoot it at your
buddies and everything yeah gun your
friends down turn weapon on so what does
that to do with smoking what does that
to do with herbs and smoking why a gun
why why are you gunning your friends out
with a pipe why is it a pipe why you
need that part of the performance
there's not a pipe you won't stick it in
your mouth and you won't have the the
discomfort Associated watching people
doing obviously like more of it ins
suicidal Act
why uh why not a dildo then maybe said
it was killer I love it a dildo would
work
too I'll one
of let me ask you ham about your
motivation behind rebirth through
scavenger
tree what's up with that
piece yeah did you see the what do you
want you want the story or what yeah
what's here whatever why up with that
piece it's a pipe it's a sculpture what
I don't know it's a tree it's a
scavenger tree and it's found a pile of
some for gotten dead bones and it's
consuming them hungrily gly and it's
eating its bones but see the bones are
clean and there's no guilt associated
with these Bon tree didn't kill anything
it's just a
scavenger but through its consumption of
the bones it's
uh it's causing the regrowth of
Man Bones it was but the guy is trying
to break
free he's struggling to get out of the
very thing that's uh leading to his
rebirth so what about the bowl and the
carb and the mouthpiece and the fact you
can smoke out of it why why make that
sculpture a pipe to express that what
does the pipe aspect have to do with it
you have to use it in
sitting on so is it meant to
function
ceremoni what about these other
pieces those pieces are old I don't
remember those
pieces what do you think of that Jason
leaes I think it's so cool look at it
it's awesome why is it cool
though because it's a thing not just a
bip
why why let me ask a question in terms
of your glass expressing yourself
through glass why bother making pipes
why bother why a pipe if you want to
exchange if you want to pass stuff
around why not why not make it a goblet
why not uh why is that the function cuz
who else is so enthusiastic about cool
glass then then people want to buy
p
no who else is so
enthusiastic I don't know
so like how did you get into blowing
glass because of pipes
or no I saw some guy at a county fair or
something when I was like 11 years
old and I knew that I was going to blow
glass and so when did when did just
start blowing glass like when the first
time you ever put
it I got a little butane torch once when
I was about like 16 or something or 15
or something and I tried to glass and
then go and then I bought like a welding
torch from the welding store just
like oxygen tank and a pair of snod
grass special $50 water glasses and snod
grass glasses snod grass specials yeah
50 Buck
Sicky what year was
that 6 years ago or
something8 home and served melting some
glass
that was like then you when did you
break your first
pipe heard about then you know pipes
were just like happening right so it was
a
good like had you seen anyone else blow
glass before you actually went out you
saw someone you're 11 and but like you
know no I started blowing glass in
Coralis and all the other cool Coralis
guys were ahead of me a little ways and
right about the time I was starting to
blow glass they all left to move up
Seattle andham and [__] so then it was
like me alone and like I knew you could
blow cool glass cuz you know like the
mobia shop and [__] and uh but there was
nobody there to like show me cool glass
I did weird [__] like sticking wire in
there and trying to like melt rocks into
it I remember I met you a I worked in
that 49 Street shop that mobia shop for
a while I remember you meeting you when
you came out once to like and you know
Jason really I you know I didn't know
you at
all the piece you brought up then was so
much more standard compared to your work
now like it was more like you were
trying to text you were it was like
double layered inside out I think or
something like that or like I don't know
I'm trying to remember what that piece
looked like I don't
know all
right I'm so to see these old pieces
so what do you think is coming
next this like uh operation pipe dream
scare you away at all from making glass
that change anything for you
no how do you mostly sell your
work I don't know
yet just getting back to it
been on Hiatus yeah I've been making the
GB it's my life it's my life it's my
life and it's your life it's your life
it's your
life but if we come together for one
[Music]
life we're coming from behind be
spiritual
Warriors are on a
mission showing the world
of spiritual Warriors tring from
behind ding for over that this
[Music]
time so let's turn let's turn the
tables yes I and I come to turn the
tabl turn the Paradigm around yes deep
program and
[Music]
reprogram free
mankind spiritual un
Warriers are on a
mission showing the world
of spiritual Warriors trotting from
behind trting forward at this
[Music]
time the mindset of the people
children true two children seeking for
the via the way
to go through I and I come to freedom
freedom with the light in the
[Music]
K Spirit you
Warriors are on a
mission showing the word
of spiritual Warriors tring from
behind ding forward at this time
spiritual and
Warriers are on a
mission showing the world of
a spiritual Warriers tring from behind
ding forward at this time
[Music]