he
[Music]
so we are here on Commercial Drive at
the belting point where there is a first
time ever in Canada event happening what
we have inside here is a show showcasing
some of the most incredible glass
blowing artists from around North
America this is an incredible collection
of headpieces that are usually carefully
protected that have been brought up here
by hand by most of these artists who are
absolutely thrilled to be a Canada where
their pieces can be shown as the
incredible art that they are rather than
being persecuted as uh drug device
peders so to speak so come on inside and
have a look at this incredible event
[Music]
our
sence a lot of
[Music]
and and you get to hold it in your hands
it's awesome because you never could
hold that that moment is cool it's a
really interesting moment because it's
like you can touch the glass and feel
the texture and like feel the form in
your hand and understand it that gives
you a whole new understanding of the
glass honestly you know like cuz it's
one thing to look at the glass but run
your finger around the surface to feel
it cuz some glass purposely not smoth
some of they purposely totally smooth
shapes and like when you're a glass
blower and you stare on a piece of glass
while you're working it we have a
different perception you look at the
wall thickness in a way that I don't
think Norm people normally look at you
know what I'm saying because
I don't
know yeah yeah but to hold that piece
and feel the technical it's Chris
McElroy my man what's the deal
Chris so your piece you have a wall
hanging here is the last thing we have
not put up cuz I don't know how to put
it up without
[Music]
[Applause]
ask
question how they hold that
would
[Music]
just
here have
we can also do amazing things
like I really like
[Music]
I missed it that's
good that's good cuz this fun TV boys
they use
anything so knows that I'm
still okay
[Music]
me figure it out I don't know put on top
[Applause]
forac I
must spectacular
[Music]
I'm throw my jar in
here all
right um
[Music]
you
marel up
where's our door guy oh there he is
[Music]
B you didn't
so we are sitting here with Infamous
marble Slinger the artist and organizer
who's responsible for all of this chaos
here tonight although the chaos is seems
to be getting under
control what what have you created what
what kind of a beast is this that you've
built well I didn't really build
anything I'm just trying to actually
bring together um kind of a whole
movement that's sort of been an
invisible culture for a long time which
I don't know I'm kind of calling the
glass pipe art movement for lack of a
better better term but it's basically uh
a bunch of artists that Express
themselves using uh lamp work Boral
silicate glass and um uh they make lots
of different stuff but a lot of us got
involved with glass or Express um
ourselves through really intricate uh
glass pipes so just putting that
together in the setting of an art show
to honor these uh pipe makers as artists
and um check out in one place all the
different styles and Aesthetics and uh
and that have developed uh in the art SC
basically the couple of blowers that
I've chatted with so far seem so stoked
to have somebody um want to showcase
their work and showcase them as artists
you know like few people seem a bit
chuffed you know and that's that's
[ __ ] excellent I think um the thing
is is a lot of people are just unaware
um that this whole culture exists and
that um that that pipes glass pipes have
gotten to a point where they're more
than just something that's functional
but they're used as a a term a medium of
artistic expression like lots of other
functional objects have been used
throughout many different cultures
throughout history um of people
expressing themselves artistically
through a functional object um people
have been expressing themselves with
through pipes throughout history in all
different types of cultures Native
Americans made pipes uh African tribes
made made different types of pipes um
and those were a lot of the first
examples of of of uh cultural artwork or
um folk art and um this is just another
part of that historical cultural cycle
um a culture that a lot stems from
Grateful Dead culture and the Grateful
Dead lot and people just making small
functional pipes but being inspired by
lots of different aspects to want to
make them more decorative and and
express themselves through that um it's
actually really interesting to to to ask
each individual their motivation of why
they want to make a pipe in the first
place because a lot of these people are
people who could have such a high level
of proficiency with the medium of glass
and are also getting to a point
expressing themselves as artists where
they could easily make it a functional
pipe and they could Market themselves to
a whole different audience you know the
more
mainstream um just culture um and also
you know there's the complications of
things like operation pipe dreams and
John Ashcraft and the uh whole gray area
of legality that makes you wonder why
would artists that have such visions and
have such skill levels with this glass
want to still make it so it could
function as a pipe and that's um what is
your answer to that question for
yourself as an artist honestly I got
into into to Glass the idea of making a
functional pipe um so for the function
of the pipe um once I started playing
with as as an artist I was an artist
before I got into the medium of glass I
discovered the medium of glass um I
looked at it really more at first as a
craft and as a way that I could just
honestly make a living by creating
something with my hands and selling it
as opposed to having a job so at first
it was more a monetary thing yet I was
interested in the meeting and learning
medium and learning it so making pipes
enabled me to every time I made a pipe
that was a lesson in lamp workking glass
and understanding how the glass flows
and blowing the glass and every time I
could pipe was a very sellable thing so
when I can sell that I could afford to
buy more materials I could afford to buy
keep myself going with the medium
because it's very expensive the glass
materials that have the overhead of a
glass shop to um uh every aspect of it
just to actually have a kiln and the
Torches and everything and um and that's
before you've even created something so
what it is was every single pipe was a
lesson in learning how to do it like the
the roots of the glass that we use is
more in a scientific thing well we use
borosilicate glass which is uh people
know it's Pyrex which is just a brand
name for borosilicate glass
traditionally um a lot of uh the
borosilicate glass there's lots of
different types of glass that are used
for different reasons to create
different things so for instance some
people like the most common form of
glass blowing is blowing out of a
furnace so you could blow very large
stuff by gathering um big gathers of
already hot molten glass um but that
glass works at a lower temperature so we
can stay molten the glass we use is
harder glass that works at a hotter
temperature so you know You' you know
you use Pyrex plates in a microwave or
you can use them uh they're they're cook
safe and and um so you they're also used
in Laboratories and buns and burners and
a lot you traditionally they're used
more mostly for scientific apparatus um
besides that artistically you've
probably seen people lamp working Boral
cic glass maybe in a mall um or at a
carnival making mostly little types of
trinkets or at Disney World making
Donald ducks and Mickey Mouses um it's
just in the last I'd say 25 years or
even less that people have started using
this actual type of working glass and
this sty this type of glass to express
themselves more artistically as opposed
to scientifically um now the
interestingly enough the reason that
pipes are used this type of glass is
because of the function um if you're
going to use a lighter and light the
pipe constantly if it's going to be the
soft a softer type of glass not Boral
silicate but a different type like
furnace glass it will crack due to
stress of having too much too much heat
on it so this type of glass we use to
create functional pipes um is is from a
SC comes from a scientific Roots now as
pipe makers and people inspired by
everything everyone has their own
inspiration CH so I can't speak for
everyone but a lot of us Trace Our Roots
to a man named Bob Snodgrass who is one
of the first people that was actually uh
trying to put some kind of coloration in
the pipes using gold and silver fuming
which is the famous color changing pipe
phenomenon um and he was also involved
in going on tour with the Grateful Dead
and selling his small color changing
pipes there on the Grateful Dead lot
which got a whole psychedelic culture
interested um Mor at first through the C
through the function but then if you
think about what people were smoking
through those pipes and about that sort
of the Grateful Dead scene and the
artistic movement surrounding that that
just bled over to pipes and young people
who would don't want to who want to be
artists who want to work for themselves
maybe don't want to get a job they're
done touring with the Dead they went to
people like Bob Snodgrass and the people
he taught and that culture spread to
other people and the more it spread the
more people got ideas to try to make
something more these little pipes that
snotty and and his and predecessors made
were treasured little items by people
and so it was fun to try to come up with
new Aesthetics and new ways and be
unique and people started putting their
signatures on them and coming with their
own Styles and from there it's just
going off where now if you come forward
another 10 or 15 years from when
Snodgrass started putting that stuff on
the dead lot we have all sorts of uh
actual companies that are creating
torches and and new types of color glass
that's coming out the color and pattern
the glass and and all sorts of uh
different techniques from other styles
of working glass are now being
Incorporated by these young people and
manipulated into these pipes and so
there there's a huge social aspect to it
there's a economic piece of it too
there's a huge economic piece everything
from uh it doesn't just stem to the
paraphernalia industry and people
selling glass pipes it goes even it goes
before that the prequel of that are the
companies that are making the color
glass and the companies that are making
the Torches they've gotten to a point
where they're actually they haven't
shied they shied away at first because
of the controversy of the idea of the
culture of making glass pipes but
they're realizing now that that is what
their biggest Market is and they're
marketing directly to that I'm talking
about the color the people who make the
materials we use the technical stuff the
Torches the the color glass the raw
glass they're marketing directly to the
pipe makers because the pipe makers are
a huge percentage of their Market and
that's the reality of it at this point
um so the industry sh you know it's like
anything everything is interconnected
you know nothing is in and of itself the
pipe scene does not exist in and of
itself um and do you think that this is
the uh the this show tonight is
significant in the way that it could be
a shift in the way that um Glass artists
are perceived and the way that they're
perceived and the way that they're
exposed to the public as well you think
that we might start to see more of a
trend of glass artist being showcased as
artists rather than next to the rolling
papers I definitely think that's the
idea that's the goal and if we're at all
successful at that then we've
accomplished our mission I have to give
a lot of uh props and thanks out to
another glass artist friend of mine
named Brian mcau who signed his pieces
as gasp and uh in 2003 March it was
March 9th I think 2003 he threw the
first ever glass pipe art show in a
gallery down in San Francisco it was
actually called the melting point also
it was the inspiration for name of this
place and um he had the same idea
amongst us he's actually a peer of mine
that we went to art school together and
stuff and so we knew each other before
we even blew glass pipes and anyway his
his uh Vision was the same as what we
were talking here of like removing them
from the setting of next to cannabis
magazines and uh next to Rolling Papers
and next to things and see the idea is
we're trying to F have people focus on
the art and the fact that it functions
as a pipe honestly is secondary to these
artists including myself and so in
instead of if you surround if you
surround these pieces in just other
paraphernalia and propaganda that's do
with cannabis it's not necessarily that
I'm against that it's not necessar I'm
for that but what that just says is that
this piece is used for cannabis in his
paraphernalia which is is not even
that's a whole another issue that I'm
not trying to tackle in this statement
here but what I'm trying to say is by
putting the pipes on pedestals by
putting them next to other art pieces in
an art gallery having an actual art
opening that's catered that where the
artists have their titles of their names
where they make an artist statement that
all is putting the pipes in a context
that other art traditionally has been
put in and as a result it validates
these pieces as art and not just pretty
paraphernalia or or you know what I'm
saying like so that's really important
and that's where my friend Brian AKA
gasp was starting that in San Francisco
in 2003 he conceived this idea for his
show before operation pipe dreams
happened tell us about operation pipe
dreams I don't think that everybody
necessarily knows exact what the
parameters of that is is the name of uh
there was actually two operations
operation pipe dreams and operation Head
Hunter and they were particular uh
initiatives uh com working in
collaboration the DEA the Department of
Justice and a bunch of other government
officials um launched a a a full
Federal um investigation and finally
they a Roundup where they ended up
arresting 51 people um we kind of have a
the date that they actually announced it
and launched it was February 24th 2003
um and there were a whole bunch of
different companies that were
advertising openly on the internet um to
sell things like you know uh glass water
pipes and uh and glass pieces and stuff
and uh they were paying taxes they you
know thought they were staying within
the law by uh saying people they
wouldn't sell to people under you know
not no minors no one under 18 of age
could be could purchase their products
and they were for tobacco use only etc
etc without any warning at all the de
and the Department of Justice kicked
down the doors of these people um seized
you know a lot of their property and
their businesses and freeze their assets
and uh Tommy Chong who was uh one of the
people involved in his business his son
was running a business called uh Chong
glass got arrested he's actually the one
person that ended up in jail a lot of
other people on house arrest some of the
more notable people I can remember off
the top of my head that got busted were
Jerome Baker bongs or water pipes excuse
me and uh I don't know a bunch of
different companies but 101 north um but
yeah it was basically you the the
federal government has a definition of
paraphernalia and it's kind of like in
the United States there's just like a
lot of huge gray areas and so the
federal government decided to like you
know act on their definition and force
what they thought was the law in terms
of defining these pieces of drug
paraphernalia even though these people
thought they were within the law so
basically what they did
was if anyone if anyone was curious
about whether or not glass pipes or
paraphernalia was legal or illegal they
were trying to establish that these
things were illegal but it's still a
great area cuz there's still people
obviously arguing that they're either
for art purposes they're for tobacco
purposes they're for legal herb
purposes um so it's you know it's one of
those things it's like but the risk has
increased for blowers well basically
what they've done is the the the the
federal government has said that
federally it's against the law the state
laws are all individual and different so
state by state things are different um
one of the things they were going after
at first mostly pipe drains was uh
Interstate trafficking so people who are
like doing basically they want the
people a lot of money who are sending
stuff from one state to another um what
they what the federal government is
doing at this point they actually
launched another operation one year
about to the date of operation pipe tram
called operation pipe cleaner where
they're doing the same sort of thing
they're basically uh they're encouraging
local law enforcement to go in and clean
up their local area if they so choose so
police and all sorts of different areas
and we're getting reports from
everywhere all over the United States
all places in Texas to Virginia to
Upstate New York
to Illinois Detroit all different random
places I incidents of local law
enforcement deciding to give warnings or
confiscate pieces or Raid places so it's
kind of like you know based on the local
the local constituents but the federal
government is giving their full blessing
and encouraging it um so it's not only
is a something that happened like in
2003 but now we're in 2004 and they're
continuing the initiative so there's a
huge gray area a lot of all the we
almost almost all the websites that at
least coming out of the United States
that sell anything that that you could
be considered for paraphernalia no
matter what they're pretty much you know
shut down um glasspipes.org is uh is a
is a nonprofit um uh Gallery page that
uh some people have put together that
any glass pipe artist is uh welcome to
start a gallery and display their work
and so it's kind of open so a lot of the
stuff has been being channeled through
that site right now excellent so you
know the heat is on so to speak on the
glass blowers you've done a fabulous job
of pulling all these Folks up the artist
seem so stoked it's a beautiful night
and uh they're playing some jazz so I
think we should go catch a tune right on
thanks I'm ready to check it out thank
you
[Music]
I'm
you let
[Music]
me why not take
the and why not
[Music]
Rel
next
[Music]
and then next year it's going to
[Applause]
[Music]
be take you
are you shoting
for leave that up to the
pros know what were you saying about
those books you were looking at with the
pipes and art or whatever tribal books
that have been around for you know they
show these pieces that are hundreds you
know sometimes thousands of years old
you know ppes they there I mean and they
weren't just a functional thing they had
art on them know car they spent time
making them and you have to remember
that like most of them are ceremonial
pipes so like they're meant to be used
you know in very specific yeah very
specific times something you know like
Christmas Easter I think a a lot of the
first it seems like I wonder when when
did the idea of Fine Art come in where
people made art that didn't function CU
it seems traditionally if you look back
to like cavemen or whatever you want and
also ancient cultures come to now seems
like traditionally the first signs of
artistic expression came mostly in the
forms of functional things like from
what I've read and like things that got
you intoxicated especially were made
more decorative so it be a pipe or even
just like a a vase or some kind of like
vessel would hold like intoxicating
beverage or something like that would be
more decorated and artistic you know but
it seems like that's like there there
wasn't like it wasn't a necessity necess
they make like a peeking hang on your
wall or a sculpture that just expressed
your how I felt for someone to take back
to their cave or their Hut you know so
the first forms of artistic expression
we're going to lie at more of a
functional thing like everyday thing
you're using someone might start
decorating a little more a spear or
something they drink out it or something
they smoke at it you know what I'm
saying
look how far we come yeah
exctly you find when you like pull the
camera out everything changes like I
said some people are comfortable with
cameras some people I'm going to like I
want to keep it on at all points like
hey I'm thr my camera out you need to
find out your tally lamp setting cuz
look well yeah are you watching look at
the front of my camera is it on is it
off I don't know it's on okay you know
what I'm saying yeah well that's the
thing see sh I'm like I turned the red
light off so you don't know if it's on
or off how do I do this so that way like
I can just roll in and be talking to
somebody
sometimes I mean I would you know it's
like there's people that I know that are
like down to be interviewed and are like
totally into like promoting their work
and I know there's like things that you
just don't need to put on sit there like
take a bunch of people smoking unless
we're all talking and like everybody
seems Co
that's the idea I just want to have it
non salant but I don't want to waste the
battery too much that's why I didn't
have it totally like
whatever you can't just put me like oh
we're having a great conversation now
I'm pulling my camera
out yeah even now like always know
camera or a video camera video
camera so what do you think of the glass
it's [ __ ] awesome what what piece
sticks out to you oh my God okay there's
so many for so many different reasons
like don't you better not be no I'm not
doing anything do you see Chris
melroy if you remember his name he had
like a little bottle they're all like
brown and black very technical
very col
he doesn't even
make
I'm ready
for
not she she does my
tattoos hey Bonnie this is Matt and
Misha they blow
on
Bonnie do you do tattoo artist.org is
that you or someone else okay she does
want to show me that she she does like
glasspipes.org glass artist.org
they're just exites I just help out
on no was our little trade project is
like okay it's like you know on the
end we have a mess back here we need to
take care of it looks like like people
[Music]
cses bring the Gage
Downs you
[Music]
think yeah
where is
[Music]
I'll a c
joh just went
downstairs you
[Music]
[Applause]
is this your paper
orer where's we
background what what you
[Music]
out EX
[Applause]
[Music]
did you come to the half
party the end say hi
[Music]
word
so we're here with uh Brian one of the
first glass blowers um that I've known
actually and uh tell us why the hell are
you a glass blower how did you get into
this crazy well um let's see I guess
probably the first time I was exposed to
Glass art was uh up in Aspen I was
hanging out and I saw a Dale chahul
piece and I was like wow if I want to do
art that looks really fun and big and
crazy and also was really expensive not
that that mattered but I was just Blown
Away to see a piece that was had so much
value in it or worth so you inspired
like that yeah I was inspired by the
colors and stuff so that and uh yeah I
loved pipes too and I really enjoyed
that I made uh pipes out of Ceramics
before that a little bit Yeah and then
made a lot of art out of Ceramics too
but snuck some pipes in there high
school style College style yeah it was
great speaking of high school style some
of the pieces that you have in here are
a little uh refle active of high school
style with the yeah the Coke can and the
Apple I basically reverted to real
common pipes that I think everybody
smoked out of that really uh that are
not made out of glass that one's a a pop
can and the other one is a a couple of
apples but I titled the pop can one coca
kilia because really not that into Co
Coca-Cola and I'm really not that into
smoking out of cans totally that's
hilarious um this is a pretty unusual
event that's happening here I don't know
that there's ever been a glass show
quite like this before I maybe there has
but not in Vancouver that's for sure not
in Vancouver and not in Canada not in
Canada really a first for Canada which
is impressive um what does it mean to
you to have your staff in in this show
I'm really proud just to be with all the
different artists I see here because
what's impressive is you have a really
powerful movement that came with the
pipes it selected out some really good
Crafts People and artists and and then
those people are taking it to the next
level and they're ready to like with the
way everybody's building these huge
pieces and the technically and the way
everything's going together we're ready
to push it way over the limit it's
amazing it's going to it's fun to be
part of or at least to be able to
witness this movement I guess so closely
it's neat to have it in
Vancouver awesome oh yeah thank you
[Music]
the I had
boom
[Music]
my camera is
middle of
[Music]
up
and
[Music]
right
there sneaks up on the conversations and
whatever it
[Music]
[Applause]
quiet got a little play
[Music]
[Applause]
so the melting point has recently opened
a
raw tonight have a last show G
they have provided us this
incredible spread of
[Music]
living the these ones are a particular
tasty f
[Music]
you on
may try
[Music]
wow what's that I don't know
everything
[Music]
you