bubble man here with h flab 421 and uh
some of his absolutely off-the-wall
glass collection we've been uh trying to
get together for few months now at least
a few months to watch a good buddy of
mine's documentary that he did on glass
blowing called degenerate art which is
the art and culture of glass pipes and
as most of you already know uh marbl
Slinger put this this little uh
Masterpiece together over the last few
years and I cannot believe that I
haven't watched it but Flav and I kind
of made a promise and we were like oh we
got to watch it with like you know like
50 Grand worth of glass and we'll Puff
the glass out of some some amazing hash
out of the glass while we're watching
the documentary so we have uh I don't
know we've got a good 75k worth of glass
sitting here in front of the table make
maybe you want to give them a little
Lowdown on what we got here FL uh this
is is just a little part of the high
integrity glass collection um we have a
Marcel braa Chris Carlson crate collab
the one that's really the sought after
one yeah all that air trapping is
amazing beautiful with the the cross
sections unbelievable even the down stem
oh nice lovely work basket we oh
wonderful beautiful now we're moving
over to some other ships we got the
flying ball ring by Jake
C that's something definitely when you
brought that over to my place about a
month back I'd never seen anything like
that no yeah this was this was a really
this was really really really popular
when Jake put it out I was very very
very lucky to get it um Row from high
integrity really hook hooked this one up
same with the uh
jakc Fab egg beautiful is that a Marcel
Bowl in there it is a Marcel Bowl it is
bub man yes it is a marale sers bowl
lovely lovely blue ready lines with some
air trapping some nice nice D Flav knows
me well there's many a dome in the house
but uh all of these pieces today have
hash bowls every single one of them so
I'm noticing the bowls this one is a
Dosa also Mothership it's got a Cory and
calmo ready uh Bowl on
Top This of course as uh I'm sure a lot
of you do know is Leather and Lace the
last uh collaboration by Jason Lee and
Marcel Bron one of my personal personal
favorites yeah that's a spectacular
piece it's uh and this is the uh
champion of uh my collection absolutely
this is fish
2000 got some good history with that
piece myself yeah it spent a lot of time
uh with bubble man before uh Marcel went
down back down to Eugene yeah it did it
also spent uh New Year's at the fish
seminal Indian Reservation show in
Florida uh from 1999 to 2000 when fish
hit the stage at midnight and played for
7 and 1 half hourss straight until the
sunrise and this piece I wasn't there
personally but I I got some good stories
from Marcel how this piece literally got
sent out into the crowd and it was just
uh you know Good Vibes that brought it
back so yeah after 6 and 1 half hours
made it back to Marcel amazing this is a
Eric crunk it's a diplomat it's um
Simpsons Millies a lot of chaos going
on some thumb prints on the bottom
beautiful little piece yeah very nice
and then I mostly brought the hash but I
did bring my Nate Dizzle Swiss perk cuz
you got to love the Swiss love my Swiss
perk this was a gift from Nate when I
took him and Steve hops down to the rure
factory in frankenthal Germany to do a
little collabs with those guys both
Steve and Nate gifted me a piece and uh
yeah I can't tell you how much I've
smoked out of this piece and I actually
brought this piece today because we're
going to be using the th nail sublimator
with it so we've got our titanium nail
plugged in right here and sitting and
waiting to go and uh we won't be
starting with it but we'll definitely be
finishing with it so yeah I guess uh
thank you marbl Slinger for sending me
this copy I'm finally opening it I mean
Slinger sent me this copy like maybe
like a year ago I don't know it's been a
long time it was it was one of the it
was one of the first cof coffees off the
press you're one of the first people
that I knew that had a coffee yeah Tak
look at that the G our [ __ ] oh yeah
pretty stoked on this um as some of you
may know um Slinger and I did an art
show two art shows actually together in
my gallery back in uh 0203 I guess it
was the first one was called degenerate
art which uh Slinger had basically
snagged from uh Hitler who created the
degenerate art movement in the 30s late
30s early 40s when he was trying to uh
basically you know show art in a
negative in a negative way and and
degrade artists and so we Slinger and I
borrowed that term for this show uh the
degenerate art show which happened in 02
and then 03 again we did the regenerate
art show and a couple of years later you
know Slinger put together the idea that
he was going to do this incredible uh
documentary and that maybe that would be
a part of it but obviously the glass
scene has been going for a while now and
uh inspired by people like Snodgrass and
other incredible blowers I'm just really
happy to say that I know these guys and
that I'm I'm really excited to throw
this into the DVD player and start
watching so uh let's do that maybe we'll
hit a bowl first yeah I think we should
I think we should I think though I think
we should start with this one I think I
agree with you 100% I think the Carlson
Marcel is first on the list it sounds as
good as as any so we'll just make sure
we have some beine and a lighter oh I'm
sure I got some D over here oh I do nice
big school right be line as well but I
saw you had a spool there so we'll we'll
spool down excellent get ourselves a
little Skillet tool here should we start
with the seedsman hay oh I think that's
always always start with the sativas yes
absolutely there's something else in
here I'm not I can't even remember what
it was but uh it's the seedman haze that
I'm uh tasting in snow
off Mr Flav oh well thank you sir I will
light your Bee Line for you you can
drive it I'll light it cuz that's what
friends are for that's what friends are
for man I'm excited to be here me too
all this beautiful glass the first rip
of the session yeah excellent and we
said we were going to do $50,000 with a
glass well we ended up with about 75,000
here so I think that's going to be a
nice a nice way to
enjoy the degenerate art documentary
boom boom Oh and you finished it Like A
Champion that was about three hits I
loaded him just for you at home
there this little Marcel Carlson Just
Hits so beautifully I got to smoke out
of it on a few occasions at the treating
yourself
uh event which was a wonderful event in
Toronto last month or a month and a half
ago and I got to smoke with it there I
got to smoke with it with Marcel in fact
which is always a treat always got to
meet Chris super nice guy guy one of the
glass blowers I had never met before but
really standup guy and obviously um an
incredible artist very tent here's to
YouTu what a lovely piece
I love the little Marcel
yeah yeah the Sig mes we're going to be
taking our time today during this little
clip that you're watching and we're
going to be smoking all these pieces
multiple times and we're going to be
watching this movie so what we'll
probably do is uh throw it in here soon
pause pause the camera cuz I'm sure you
guys don't want to watch us watching a
movie but every time we take a hit we'll
turn the camera on and we'll make sure
we share it with you guys so if you
haven't watched the generate art yet
head over to Netflix and watch it with
us talk
soon all right so we haven't started the
movie yet we were sitting here both
thinking without mentioning it that
Slinger himself was not representing
here which is insane cuz I have a ton of
Slinger at my office in Vancouver but um
Flav has uh a little Slinger piece here
that he had gotten from a guy who got it
from a guy who apparently got it from
the regenerate art show I don't
personally remember remember this piece
which is strange cuz uh I usually
remember Slinger pieces but it's
definitely Slinger I see that all over
with the honeycomb U marble and the uh
he got a s yeah his sigs and his little
yeah be really beautiful so before we
start the movie props to the man himself
Mr marble
Slinger ding ding ding ding
ding man who got me into smoking glass
pipes ask anyone you smoked
joints long time
ago Slinger couldn't wrap his head
around it I still can't wrap my head
around stuffing a bud into a bowl but
here's some
hash it's a lovely little bubbler
it really is nice to hit a Slinger
mhm let me load it you
up let me puff it down yes puff it down
puff
it it here yes Marvel Slinger thank you
so much for the piece thank you so much
for the
movie you are a great representative of
our culture
absolutely it's uh it's going to be nice
to watch it's definitely nice to see all
this glass it's nice that someone out
there is documenting it cuz documenting
is hard and you don't really realize it
but when you pull back and you document
it's it's almost as though you pull
yourself somehow away from the
experience yes you know I found that
from taping take yourself out of the
experience yeah when I'm taping or doing
photography or recording although I'm
there more so than anyone I'm also
removed from the experience CU I'm
usually looking through a lens and
you're trying to capture the experience
absolutely in its Purity which is very
hard to do when you're actually a part
of it cuz you almost want to take it and
make it your own yeah yeah so it's
definitely when someone likees Slinger
can show you the real culture in the
history of the glass art movement it's
really something special absolutely well
let's not wait another
second push play on that Flav
oh all right we just watched the
introduction and maybe a little bit past
that and uh really killer
editing great start to the movie you
know would you agree oh always yes I
think the personally I think the intro
is uh one of my favorite parts of the
movie I love uh all aspects of the movie
but it's just so beautiful it's all
Serene and really
gets you into the mood for a [ __ ]
like about to experience so very cool
yeah FL seen the movie I have not we've
just kind of got to the snod grass part
and I thought well we should probably
hit another fat piece definitely
definitely so uh you choose um we're
going to go with the ak ak all right
let's load that AK up yeah we're showing
love to the ogs to start
absolutely love
it it's a nice little piece it's really
quite heavy and you can't really imagine
how many like Millies there are in this
thing Mr Burns Wiggum Lisa
Homer
Auto got to have
Auto very
cool here you go sir oh back
you another shot of the
seedsman cuz you can never have too much
sativa
it's nice to see Fish 2000 sitting on
the table it's kind of surreal this is a
piece that years ago um I'm pretty sure
I don't want to say it as fact but I'm
pretty sure we brought Marcel to his
first fish show and it was up here in
Vancouver I think it was
99.99 the Commodore show no that was
since in '93 this was some years later I
only met these guys in '98
and so yeah by
99 um Slinger had always gone to you
know the most fish shows really he had
he had seen them I'm sure over a 100
times um I'm more around the 30 to 40
range but at the time Marcel hadn't seen
one and he came up and got real inspired
and I had one of his dolphin pieces and
I remember kind of you know him just
being there and saying like y That's the
guy that blew it and everyone like
looked at Marcel and he just kind of
like ran away you know he just did not
want that attention at all it was like a
whole crowd of people that had just you
know it was kind of an insane lot piece
to pull out which was the fish 99 um
number three the smaller of the of the
three and so years or a year later he
came up with this piece less than a year
later he blew this piece and I remember
his intention was to give it to fish yes
he wanted to have this in and if it
happened he was going to give it to them
as a gift and that's why all the
dolphins represent you know the
different members of the band
and uh what do you got you got one two
three
four two three four Dolphins which is
the band and then I believe the fifth
one was Paul langad do the sound man
representative of right cuz Paul is like
the fifth member of the band totally um
yeah so then after the fish 2000 show
happened and all these different people
puffed out of it and you know it was
just he kept it it was it didn't it
didn't get go to fish the way it was
going to
and then he decided to clean it and
bring it up to Vancouver and be like
here man the only Vibe this pipe is
missing is your Vibe and so I used to
take this piece everywhere like to
concerts to like my friends head shops
in Vancouver I had a box with all the
white kind of peanut things in it and I
just used to cruise around with this
pipe cuz I felt like it was my mission I
felt like Marcel was like you have to
like when he said you know it needs your
Vibe he meant like me and my friends
friends you know what I mean not like me
at home just like oh yeah look at this
piece no you can't hit it so I literally
shared it like the way he shared it at
fish 2000 with anyone and everyone so
really out of all glass pipes I got to
think this one has had more unique
people that have never even hit a
headpiece before hit that pipe in fact I
was at the uh The Joint was it called
The Joint no Grassroots y uh Blair's old
shop on uh Commercial Drive and I was at
grass roots and I pulled this pipe out
and this guy he was visiting from like
Illinois or something he comes over to
me and he's like where did you get that
pipe he's like was that pipe at fish
2000 heit he smoked out of it man with
Marcel or without Marcel for all I know
cuz Marcel put this pipe out into the
air and it was yeah tour it around for 6
and 1 half hours yeah exactly very cool
yeah no the pipe has a very long history
to it it's been to something like 15
different
States so all right well Snodgrass is in
his bus and he's about to tell us about
how he founded this
incredible culture that has grown
exponentially since the days of uh
making color changing glass on dead
Tour all right taking another break cuz
we need another Bowl butth this document
is really good just watching the uh
Jason Harris interview that Slinger did
talking about one of the first bubblers
ever made on the carile the rap and rake
the rap and rake technique yeah really
cool I got to say I'm uh I'm really
digging this documentary it's [ __ ]
sad ass but uh we're going to be hitting
a little Mothership now JC flying ball
RG you guys you guys got to see this
yeah stepping it up little further back
camera doesn't autofocus is the problem
oh okay look right there they'll be able
to see the quality plus I'll edit some
shots
in of like closeups while we're talking
of like if you want to talk about the
pipe I'll show close-ups in regards to
every little piece you're talking about
okay cuz I've taken great photos of this
piece after you my friend thank
you such a ridiculous pipe for those of
you that don't know there's like this
flower of life like laser perforated
disc at the bottom that all the bubbles
come out of you can't even see the holes
but as they come out they get bigger and
bigger and bigger and bigger and there's
like five or six layers of
bubbles makes for a smooth hit I'll say
I'll say that makes for a real smooth
hit oh a huge Bowl thank
you we're watching
mother ship is um really
the the best filtration their their
pipes give the best toes the smoothest
toes the level of art on them is
parallel to pretty much
none they're beautiful they are
beautiful yeah really nice base too like
the base that you want to see on most
pipes really strong it's not like you're
going to ever put this pipe down and
Chip this base you know what I mean like
it's built but yet it's really artistic
and beautiful as
well all right here we
go
wonderful back to the documentary back
to the movie
one all right we're taking our I don't
know how many it's been but we need
another bong rip we're moving to the to
the fish 2K after just seeing it in the
video oh yeah that was a nice part of
the video all that hardcore uh head
pieces and the headies Alex from hes and
fish tour and you know it was uh I met
these guys in uh orig in '95 I met um
one of them well two of them actually
Slinger and his old
roommate uh Zach who I met both one on
fish tour one in Amsterdam and 3 years
later uh while driving to the gourge
shows in '98 I would pick up marble
Slinger hitchhiking and he was with
Jason
Lee and so I ended up partying with them
at on the weekend and enjoying some uh
some great fish shows and that was kind
of my introduction into meeting all
those guys it was great to see Pedro and
ease and uh yeah just so many of these
different guys that Slinger used to
bring up with him um when they were all
in Bellingham before they moved to
Seattle actually so very cool to be
puffing out of the fish 2000
piece maybe we'll hit another kind of
hash something a little
heavier a little on the CIS
satellite yeah you
know strong Inda for the Midway Point
beautiful look at
that D
Go Fish
2000 great pece
true piece of uh Bor
silic art history right here truly trer
words would ever
said it was nice to see uh my Marcel
pieces in the video there yeah very cool
yeah to see Alex from hes talking about
these pieces and the the sculpture and
the fish and and they showed uh the
picture I was like
huh is indeed in my collection I don't
have many pieces these days but
uh I do have a
few some Marcel's REM
made absolutely three marcelas in my
collection
thank this one's nicer this one's just a
bit bit nicer there's that
[Music]
sound oh yeah this is great what a piece
yeah really
really cool
piece quite
something Marshall marel fish
2000 good Big Cypress
it was at the Big
Cypress love the way this piece sits mhm
true coffee table piece yeah it is
Center piece we've hit the Slinger yeah
hit the Marcel Carlson y we s the hit
the jakc yeah ball rig y we've now hit
the oh we also hit the the AK the AK yep
and now we've hit the fish 2000 so one
more before uh before we restart the
movie I think yeah yeah we're going to
do the Dosa the Dosa
tube wonderful another Mothership artist
excellent
y bought this off of high integrity
glass thank you guys yeah high integrity
glass is definitely uh pulling out the
pulling out all the stops for the
mothership here in BC
it's nice I don't personally own a
mother ship as of yet but uh I can see
it happening one day soon they
definitely H unlike any other
piece I also like that they're not super
loud as you can hear this
one
nice that was a good size hit very holy
Moes very much
so good
stuff Co yeah was a good one been in
there yeah I'm going to get a double I
can't believe how big That was cuz you
literally took so much
twice and there's still some in there so
my bad or good on loading depending on
how you look at it yes
I guess
uh I shall soon join my friend in the
land of the we just took a giant
rip like the feel of this oh that's the
ghost is amazing
[Applause]
artist well
very
nice even warrants a cough indeed well
if you don't cough you don't get off or
two all right well back to the movie
yeah we're at a good part here so we're
going to get back to the movie all right
so we just finished the uh degenerate
Art
DVD amazing it was really good really
really liked it it was uh
I can definitely see the next part
coming in the near future I really look
forward to especially with the
exponential growth that they spoke about
in the movie and how it'll be like
probably in the next 2 to 3 years as
much will have happened that happened in
the last 10 years and it's true it's
true even if you just follow what's
going on from month to month in the
industry it's insane even while we were
watching that DVD and smoking all these
different bowls some kid was pushing new
limits in glass pipe
art and now we'll be uh finishing off
our session here with the uh
jakc fabri
egg Leather and
Lace by uh Marcel Bron and Jason Lee and
the Nate
Dizzle with the sublimator
attachment to complete the heady session
ah
yes love these oh yeah these these are
just amazing these
eggs would you after you sir well I
won't say
no love the base of these
things so
sick yummy yummy
so do you think that the next movie will
be
regenerat like the shows that were put
on by
you it' be hard to say I definitely can
see like I didn't even realize it was
the end I was so enamored by the whole
movie that it just kind of ended and I
was like oh man
like I realized now seeing it you know
now already some years have gone by yeah
definitely
so yeah it's true actually the I think
the latest footage is
20110 2009 maybe 201 in
right yeah it's a treat to be able to
come over to flaves and hit the um the
glass collection I'm as much as I'd like
to say I smoke the headiest of the
glasses I I smoke nice glass but it
really I smoke uh you know one or two
pieces I don't have the variety
like this so it's really nice to be able
to stop by and hit the
collection and what a collection It
is Well much like uh said in the movie
I'm a firm believer that
uh this artc should be in museums nice
you've been sticking bubble hash on your
I have so yes have F I always stick hash
on my pip I in fact I'm sure I have some
probably on this one
somewhere yeah this piece is just oh
it's hard to describe you have to be
able to see it up close and it's just
unbelievable the
staircase the different discs with the
air trop readi thing whatever yeah the
can it's ridiculous yeah it is
absolutely this the last uh collab that
uh Jason and Marcel ever did
together don't know if they're planning
on doing another one not sure well we've
got a
hope I loved some of the big collabs too
I can really see that growing in the
near future where it's it is uh five or
six different artists putting together
this monster piece I know it exists
already
but I can see of that it's quite nice
yeah this pipe is kind of incredible for
one reason and I can't believe they did
it and I love that they did it they got
this like just old school carb on the
side it's just so even though it was
done in 2010 it is a very it's like
everything about it is old school design
very
OG absolutely killer looking awesome
that is a piece you feel it I'll tell
you you don't have to know too much
about these pieces that certain ones
just feel a certain
way
perfect and she just gives you such a
massive
rip massive
ripol I'm going to smoke it right-handed
even though it is intended to hold with
your left hand but
beautiful
piece
wow one of my
faves all of these are my
faves when really they're the flaves
actually there's a lot of people come up
hey are you flave 421 I'm like no yes
but that's not very you
PR well she we uh move into a little
sublation yeah I think we could do a
little uh titanium nail on the Swiss
perk always protect your
glass yeah absolutely
no doubt which one you pulling out or
putting something away no I'm looking
for a specific Pelin which I do not have
on I'm going to
go such a beautiful
glass serious pelic oh okay that's
double
a
double all right you ready for uh to
finish it all off with
the well we've had a lot of nice
different filtrations it's true actually
and a lot of nice ashes very true so
it'll be nice now to hit the Swiss perk
which is always I mean this is one of
those pipes that uh I can hit without
water in it and not be like oh stop and
go put water in it I'll hit it two three
times in a row sometimes no the Swiss
they give a special filtration that's I
100% agree with you that's
nice all right
so want to grab that bowl in
hand you can put it up
here all right we
go hitting the tie
now oh
that's that for Taste yeah really good
for taste nice
yeah every every every time you rock me
with that thing it's
uh it rocks you yeah it's really
good all
right I agree
Dingle
Dango yeah T really comes through with
nothing it definitely came through the
most with with the sublimator which I
have to tell you the same quite a
bit for the unit because a all these
beautiful pieces are all glass and that
we love glass and then again I guess we
didn't compare it to hitting it with a
hot rod or something like that yeah yeah
which is also extremely tasty very tasty
yeah so I think I have one actually I
think I have one that you gave me know
well brought that
up well maybe this time maybe we're
going to do another whole Round And
while we do you guys uh just uh there's
always lots of find something else to
watch on YouTube CU this video is
over peace out and great job Slinger
truly very
enjoyable yeah
really peace