[Music]
hey guys bubble man here and uh today
I'm going to take you guys for a little
boot back behind my house on my dirt
bike um I haven't really taken you guys
on many dirt bike Adventures I don't
think even one we've been on snowboards
and we've been on boats we've been on
Argos uh we've been on snowmobiles uh
we've been on all sorts of fun little
toys even Harley's but we've never taken
you on the dirt bike so I've got some
pretty cool Trails up behind my house go
up there to a waterfall got a little
Zone that I like to SI sit down and and
enjoy usually a couple of Puffs but I
figured before we started we would have
a couple of Puffs so got the mothership
egg in the house the puking beagle
uh quartz carb cap and Dabber as well as
the quartz bowl and I figured we'd start
out with one of
[Laughter]
[Music]
those yummy yummy yummy that was a
little candy kush from the good folks
over at uh Van City extracts thank you
Matthew thank you Ali thank you he who
shall be renamed uh uh
unknown will remain
unknown and uh yeah I think it's time to
put a little herb in now I've got a
bunch of herb here on the plate that was
East Coast Sour Diesel some of my
Jamaican some of the Astro Boy some of
the sweet skunk some of the
congales and some of the Harmony real
nice variety and I've mixed it all up
and this stuff's been sitting out for a
few days since Ramon and Rick were here
last so it
should be pretty pretty dry and give for
some real nice Vapor
rips pull up that down
there all right sublimator vaporizer
hits out of the Mother Ship dab Master
styles
God that tast is so
good it's wild how much it grabs you by
the nuts when you hit this
thing
beautiful let's go climb some mountains
on some dirt bikes what do you guys say
[Music]
there's a warning in the air so I tell
you again that my Living Dead don't go
there there's a tension in the air ones
and ones have a onesided love
affair then go
there babyon creatur Str the land
tonight they're my living de don't go
there papyon
ssts they don't love to
share don't go
there so I say Mr wanty want
your belly I got bus now your belly I go
bus
now say Mr wanty wanty
do you B I got bus now you B bu now
[Music]
there's a warning in the air so I tell
you again that my Living Dead don't go
there there's a tension in the air On's
and ones have a onesided love
affair don't go there
Bon creatures TR the land
tonight they my
living don't go
[Music]
there
systems they don't love to
share don't go
there so I say Mr wanty want
doll your belly I got bust now
your belly I go bust
now say Mr wanty
want you bil I got bust now your B I got
bust now
[Music]
there's a warning in the air so I tell
you again that my Living Dead don't go
there there's a tension in the air ones
and ones have a onesided love
affair don't go
there Bon creatures Dr the land
tonight my living day don't go
there so I
[Music]
say Your belly bu now your belly bu
now say
Mr you B bu now your B I bu now
[Music]
C
a
[Music]
that was
awesome I'm going to turn the other
camera hey guys so I just parked the
bike for those of you that didn't get a
good peek at it before that is the 450
exe KTM it's a 2007 and I am the
original owner since it's been new it's
been mine so this is a little waterfall
that I like to visit it's just in behind
my house took us about 15 minutes to get
up here but I did go to see if I could
get up to the to the higher Lookout
Point for you guys which is really
spectacular unfortunately you saw that
the um when I got up to the river the
other River there's like four of them um
it had taken out the trail so I don't
know what we're going to do about that
that's pretty major I'm going to have to
figure it out but uh I thought maybe
we'd go up there for a little dab
session so let's head up there
wow waterfall
dabbing love me some waterfall
dabbing just got to figure out a good
way to put the
tripod to capture such
things all right so that's connected
now let's
see what we can
do in regards to setting this up so you
guys can see
proper without me breaking my
neck which would be the most ideal
situation all right I'll try to be extra
loud yes we're
taping I think this is as good a spot as
any nice and dry right
here plus I can feel
the I can feel the splash from the
waterfall now I know the waterfalls loud
but it's a nice loud so I'll just talk a
little bit louder than usual so you guys
can actually hear
me I'm going to name this Tanner Falls
Tanner is my son's name I've been coming
here for probably more than 15 years and
uh I've never even thought of giving it
a name so let's break it in shall
we Pitman
all right pit man cleaned it up for
little baby cakes today so it could be
nice and clean for this session I
brought a few different things in the
dry sip
category let's see let's do the
old let's see what we can do
here look at that pretty much the
perfect amount of water in the baby
cake take out a tiny
bit that's pretty perfect got my little
10 mil
nail little Highly
Educated Highly
[Music]
Educated who doesn't want to stay Highly
Educated right it's kind of what we're
all about
and then we're going to hit some Van
City
extracts I
believe
mu yes
mu oo cushy is
[ __ ] almost like a real strong
OG rightow it's nice powder they've left
it in the in the powder right up until
the the time that they puff it which uh
I of course have a huge respect
for no reason
to take your nice dry SI out of powder
form unless you're really about to Puff
it all right well that's a huge
dab to break that in half and do it in a
couple waterfall dabin I hope you guys
are joining me by by the
way just booted up here on the dirt bike
I haven't been on the dirt bike for a
while felt a little bit loose uh coming
up but I'll get used to it I'll start
going out more now that I've uh taken
the the plunge and jumped into the first
ride of the
Season keep in mind I can ride this
thing pretty much all season long it
doesn't really
uh it doesn't really get all snowed out
so yeah pretty much everywhere in BC has
these epic anywhere you go into the bush
I mean it just doesn't even matter where
you end up eventually in some sort of
Epic little nature scene like this with
a a waterfall beautiful clean water
that's going all the way down to the
ocean and the trail that I'm on goes
it's about a 9h hour hike and it it'll
take you right over into the lions and
then over top of the Lions into Cypress
Bowl which is one of the local mountains
that you can ride here uh on the other
side in uh West
Vancouver so I think we got a nice
little glow Happening
Here we cool down fast in the waterfall
but waterfall puffing on Bubble man's
world
woo that was real
fine I'm guessing they call it mu for a
good
reason the [ __ ] is a
killer didn't even take half of that dab
that was real nice
then it's always the challenge is to
find a nice little
shelf to sit the pipe it's a pretty good
one
actually there we
go
so I was really wishing that I could
have taken you to the other Trail
because the lookout is phenomenal the
mountain climb is about another 15 to 20
minutes going a solid 50 to 60 km an
hour and uh
it's pretty cool but this is pretty cool
you guys did get to come on the ride up
here with me we're going to go for a
ride in a little bit once I've chilled
out and relaxed we'll get back up on the
bike this Trail has not for for a long
time it has not been dirt bike friendly
much past here but we'll see how far we
can take it and uh until then enjoy some
of this waterfall
so I think there used to be some little
type of cabin that someone had built way
up there and one time in a big storm it
blew down and that's what all these
little pieces of wood are
from we got here a little butterfly guy
little nature action
[Music]
well that was pretty cool little
butterfly I can tell you from a macro
photographer standpoint they don't
usually hang out for that long I've had
a very hard time in my life getting
macro photographs of butterflies and
hopefully you guys got a nice spot there
he seems to like that rock cuz he's back
again
well he definitely likes that rock
there's no doubt about it I'm going to
leave him be and let him hang out on his
little spot for all I know he's filming
butterfly man's world and I keep [ __ ]
interrupting him so back to Bubble man's
world this is uh the rest of the trail
right here so if you guys want to jump
back on the bike and head down
there I think that's the plan let's do
it
I don't think so
for for
well I uh finally got the bike loaded
had a little bit of trouble with it
getting up there at this angle but uh
she's all loaded up and that's it for
today for dirt bike riding with bubble
man next time I go out I'll try to do
something a little bit more exciting
trail-wise maybe a summit to a lake or
the peak of a mountain and I'll try to
bring some familiar faces with me as
well so thanks for watching Bubble man's
world and we'll see you next time
[Music]