[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble Man's World
um I just wanted to do a quick little
thank you to the the family over at DNA
both Kim and Aaron uh sent a little care
package over and I wanted to open it
here up on the bubble man's world
cameras um always a pleasure to spend
time with those guys they were of course
here for uh New Year's towards the end
of Christmas into New Year's we went and
all spent time up in Whistler together
so that was an amazing time and so they
said they were going to send me a little
care package and indeed they did so this
looks like a little sticker package
right
here
nice circular red Golden Green DNA
stickers love
those love
those ah 10 year anniversary also red
Golden Green you know those are my
favorite color schemes sour cush DNA
genetics another these guys got mad
stickers Reserve approved
pada DNA genetics DNA Army
worldwide oh thanks for the stickers
guys man tell you my Dil case is about
to get stuck
up couple of the uh dab mats that they
had given me last time they were here
and uh Aaron gave me like five of them
and I ended up giving them all away
almost instantly so thank you for
sending me a few more guys muchly
appreciated on
that ah the
Hat the gray hat I'll tell you I uh this
my kids built orange juice all over my
other one so it was kind of rued and I
was really getting used to wearing this
one so thank you
very sweet ah
yes this is going to be
well well used in Jamaica check this tea
out
guys a box out of the way a little bit
there here we
go thank you so much guys really
appreciate that love that t-shirt right
there that's just super super sweet
and wouldn't be complete without
a I kind of call this the dawn style cuz
Don always has one of these cool shirts
on and I always kind of admire them it's
the work
shirt check that [ __ ] out DNA grow your
own really really like that nice green
buttonup shirt I'll be sporting that in
style for sure see you day where I can
get uh a variety of crd shirts made up
like that because that's just
beautiful there was also a shirt in
there for my wife but I took it out and
gave it to her already so uh thank you
so much guys what a really nice uh treat
to receive all these uh sort of gifts
from you guys and uh I'm just going to
take a dab in your guys's honor to the
unity in the
community so nice to be uh ah to have
come all the way you know spent 10 years
in the industry the last 10 years with
DNA and I've watched them absolutely
destroy the
competition just take over the game in a
big way and it's it's exciting that uh
through Yukan we're going to be working
together in the future so we'll see what
kind of projects we can get into with
uh with uh future
opportunities all right so what did I
break up there I broke up some d420 K uh
OG Kush got the quartz pooking be Bowl
in the 2.0 Dil going strong in the Fab
egg let's hit it
[Laughter]
[Music]
well thank you so much guys I will leave
you
with unity in the
community peace
[Music]