[Music]
shaky-shaky
hey welcome to bubble man's world had a
good buddy show up today and bring a
nice variety here plus I still had the
dry sift that I that I made over at with
D for 20k in
Prince George just got back from the
house of the great gardener and brought
back some sweet skunk and some barb
really nice varieties and my buddy
brought some Renee dry sifted like 98
percent heads as well as some Congolese
fresh bubble as well Congolese so I
figured we do some dabs shall we start
with the Congo dry sift Congo dry sift
dab up
very nice very nice
tango and rice IFFT give the tool a wipe
good etiquette never put a dirty tool
into a man's clean hash very important
rule number one potentially of dabbing
etiquette a lot of you wondering can you
dab drop dry sift and bubble that is all
I dab so you absolutely can
next up run a dry sift dabbing it Oh
Renee she's got that close your eyes
property I'm not sure what it is but it
pretty sure we used to call it the funk
all right so let's follow that up with
some sweet skunk 99% pure heads made
this just the other day grown by the
great gardener this is some definite
dank
yeah that's the one let's hit the barb
this is beyond sticky and ridiculous
also it's gonna destroy me cancer I'm
gonna follow it up with another hit so
let's go somewhat reasonable I say
someone reasonable because we can't be
completely reasonable anyway this is
what we're doing here this absolute
ridiculousness share that with you there
now to give you a little bit of a
low-down on these hits that I've just
taken we started with the congolese
which is just a really beautiful exotic
African sativa very euphoric and
uplifting and sativa
very inspiring makes you feel real
positive followed that up with a Renee
dry sift hit dry sift renee is is rare
you don't see it too often but when you
do you get that full full body of
terpenes although I can't say they were
washed away in the water process it was
really the Renee that first showed me
what alcohol soluble terpenes were so
that was a great rip Renee's always
strong fruity smell hazy overtones in
the in the smoke afterwards followed
that up by sweet skunk some 99% heads
that I cleaned over with the grey
gardener grown grown by them too darn
near perfection that rip actually was
the one that I took the break after a
very good hit and followed that up with
the barb
and the barb is the Afghani crossed with
the shish kebab and the shish kebab was
from the red line so there were two
Afghani is used in the original creation
of shish kebab there was a red line and
a yellow line and the red line was the
one that was used in the creation of the
shish kebab that was used in the barb so
going to finish it off now with a little
of D 420 K's OG Kush dry cept and this
was actually made made by him and smoked
by me
here's buddy
well thanks for joining me for some hits
guys Oh peace
you
[Music]