[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
and today we are doing a little review
from one of my favorite companies do you
nail thanks for the shirt boys a little
show-off there on the logo on the back
just receive this from my good friends
Brian Stevie over at D mail and working
with D mail for maybe the last year
since you guys have seen me whipping
around the world with these different
units and different nails you've seen me
with titanium nails you've seen me with
quartz nail ceramic inserts sapphire
inserts and today something different
today we have a silicon carbide that
they've been working on for the last
year flavor testing and terpene testing
thermal dynamics really putting more in
than the average bear into the focus on
how these things work and how the nails
should be heated and the distribution of
heat and how when it's applied a certain
way you would preserve more particular
terpenes everything they change changes
something with the taste so this unit is
I'm not sure if it's even available to
be honest I think it's an experimental
unit they not sure if they've released
it yet I would love to have it in a
drop-down my dropdowns not ready yet so
I'm waiting for that and you know I have
my straight fab that I traveled with
quite a bit and once my quartz Bowl got
broken I got pretty comfortable putting
the titanium nail into it and it fit
fairly tight this nail I like the way it
fits a lot better it's quite loose it
goes in loose and it's not until it
drops that quarter inch to half inch
into the joint that it actually kind of
gets snug so I'm not too worried about
the metal on on the glass I know a lot
of people that are some and I wish I had
the drop down for you guys I'd love to
have this down quite a bit more but for
the sake of doing the review and getting
it done because life moves fast and men
more things will show up I figured let's
do this I saw a 420k yesterday and today
and he brought me a really nice little
gift of some OG Kush DRI cept that is
right here and he also brought me some
New York City diesel man is that the
old-school New York City diesel that I
remember that just pungently orange
citrus winner so that's fun and that's
what we're gonna be testing today the OG
Kush and the New York City diesel one
has the flavor of orange citrus you know
that D limonene that Valens seen mersin
I'm sure there's probably half a dozen
or more that taste and smell like
different citrus lemons limes and
oranges and then the OG Kush which this
particular one is very earthy very
earthy it's it's like Dee was saying you
know it's like putting a little a
teaspoon of dirt in your mouth when you
take a rip of it it is really pretty
much that earthy and I guess just to
mention a few things with the silicon
carbide we don't use a metal tool and
scrape around they were saying not
really a good idea they actually sent me
this lovely little D mail wipe that I
guess when when it cools down just with
water and with this much the same way
you would use on a camera lens it comes
off real easy so I've only taken a few
hits so far so it's relatively clean I
managed to clean it with a little bit of
cloth I did some macro video of that in
slow motion so you can see the dry sift
falling off the off the dabber and
dumping into this dish I'll tell you one
thing about this dish this is like
Chicago deep-dish pizza compared to any
other nail that I've ever seen I mean
the it's no joke obviously you guys can
see the size of that bad boy quite quite
a nice size you could you know the guy
especially for these guys out there that
love taking the monster dabs you're
gonna be quite pleased with the size of
this dish I'm just going to be doing
reasonable size dabs and and of course
in the movie
that I made with the iPhone the 240
frames per second when you see the
melting and the bubbling there is a lot
of smoke coming up they did give me a
really nice carb cap with this nail
which I will show you in a second all
right which is right here so funky
little Devo style carb cap you can see
it just fits right on there quite nice
and then has a little hole right on top
there so quite a lovely little look to
it not huge on the metal myself although
I do appreciate the titanium in the
situation when I'm traveling I've had
the quartz break on me the quartz Briggs
it's like wow what do you do I have no
more quartz Bowl the titanium is an
exceptional alternative for traveling
especially because I can travel and not
really worry about about it breaking so
without further ado I think we're gonna
have a little hit of the New York City
diesel mmm so citrusy the first two rips
I took through this thing was beautiful
and tasty but I do feel that I lost a
little bit because I was unable to call
hate the idea of carving it for a video
and yeah I guess I am gonna use the
titanium carb and not the ceramics oh my
bad I forgot that they sent me one of
these so let's use the one they send me
[Music]
well I'll tell you one thing this guy
gets hot fast you would not want to
leave this carbine here for more than 30
seconds fits exceptional though well
it's got a tiny little lip on the on the
inside I'm not sure if you guys can see
that there but that tiny little lip just
fits in real real nicely
Wow exceptional flavor to taste to taste
test any kind of nail whether it was a
cords or a sapphire this strain I can't
say enough about how strong the taste is
and I've been listening to D 420k talk
about this in our own FaceTime
conversations and in Google+ and hashed
church where each time he takes a hit he
sits there and he he would go on about
oh my god I wish you guys could taste
this and I was always like wow come on
we've tasted great great stuff we know
we know but now as I say here and I
taste it I got to admit deep you were
right this is exceptional resin holy
Christ does it taste good on the lips
like in an orange grove and hitting it
off the new silicon carbide nail head
with the mothership fab egg just a
really nice combination treat oh really
and I think we're gonna get another one
ready soon one thing I would love that
to know is what can I wipe it with right
away you know what can I kind of just
give it a quick little wife I used a
little paper towel that I dipped in
water and I believe that's what he said
in the letter that it would to use this
little Dino cloth that he sent me dipped
in water I'm pretty confident that
there's 80% of his dish left so why
don't we hit the OG Kush in a nice fresh
section we'll go double up on the I'll
see what this is now I hit these earlier
in the quartz and I have to say so far
the New York City diesel tasted the best
off the the silicon carbide egg I don't
know why I will try to learn and talk to
the guys and figure out what are the
thermal dynamics behind heating up the
nail in this particular way and having
it design this way with this size of a
dish and what exactly is silicon
carbides to offer that quartz or
sapphire or ceramic or titanium don't
one of the differences these things
interest
me and of course I'd love to bring that
information to you guys a little bit
more than just a simple review but going
into something a little bit deeper and
letting them know why is this better so
far pretty cool let's have another real
Wow Wow
the taste on the NY CD was much it was
increased from the intensity that I felt
off of the courts it was a or intense
citrus taste but the og og was was this
earthy taste and that taste almost
brought it almost cleaned it up almost
cleaned up the earthy taste and it still
got an earthy taste but it's it's of a
cleaner earth if that makes any sense
geez I wish I would have had a couple of
other people's opinions here I'm sure
that would have been a cooler idea maybe
maybe I will do a little video the next
time I get together with Flav he's a
real connoisseur in that sense and we
can do a little taste testing because
I'll tell you there's something to be
said for this nail the taste on it is so
good that I consider using it even
though it's got the titanium body and I
love the idea anytime I can getting away
from metal I don't know why I just like
the idea quartz makes me happy the metal
look on this my mind I can feel is
judging it yet over on the other side I
have the honest opinion that Wow does
that have an incredible flavor really
incredible now one thing I feel that
it's a little bit missing out on it in
the sense that there's not a tool that I
can scrape around on I've been told it's
not the best idea to scrape the surface
with a hard tool like titanium maybe
over time you scratch and it releases
dusts I'm not sure I'll try to find out
those things as well this is just a real
simple review for today and I'll come
back with a more intense backup once
I've talked to Brian and Stevie and
figured out exactly you know a little
bit more information for you guys on
this nail but from the bubble man's
perspective the taste was great not
stoked on the idea of metal in the pipe
but a simple drop down alleviates such a
worry as long as you know the weight
which isn't too bad it's not too too bad
I wouldn't put it on a drop down that
went out too far just in case but I
think on a drop down that goes
substantially down and up it'll sit
right here nicely and you know I think
it'll be fun it'll be fun well I want to
thank both Brian and Stevie all the
people at D nail for the great work that
they do you know thanks for supporting
me guys and allowing me to help you guys
out with doing cool things like this and
little reviews and given my honest
opinion they never asked me in any way
shape or form to sway they never asked
me to say my opinion is one thing or the
other they just really want my honest
opinion and that's how I know that
they're doing the good work and they're
looking to better the product constantly
so thanks guys for that thanks for the
silicon carbide nail I'm gonna give it a
shot for the next week I think I'm gonna
go back and forth with this and the
quartz and do a little taste testing and
see see what we can find in the
differences of low temp dabs versus high
temp dabs with this particular unit as
well so thanks for watching you guys can
check these products out on d-mail and I
believe I'm gonna be getting a discount
code so if you guys want to contact me
at bubble man at bubble bag comm or
check the comments section of this video
and I'll put in my code that you can
write d-mail with
or get in touch with Gmail email them
whatever and that should get you a
discount off on some products that you
want to buy from those guys so that
would be another great great way to help
support these guys yeah I think that's
it I've puffed a couple of bowls
I'm feeling very Irie well maybe we'll
leave you with one more bowl let's say
goodbye with one more bowl we'll go back
for that unbelievably tasty New York
City diesel Oh literally brought me back
to sohma's like 2003 2000 maybe even in
2003 for
and taste on that is so strong
that is what made tangey popular that is
what made Jillybean popular that is what
made Calliope popular and that is what
made New York City easel popular that
orange citrus flavor thanks for watching
bubble man's well guys
[Music]
you