[Music]
we're here at Eden's danger and we got
some good friends and we're dabing it up
with the
denail getting some full m
bubble oh
yeah
beautiful hey what's up welcome to
Bubble man's world we're here at deeden
in downtown Vancouver and we've got the
brand new denail that just got sent out
to us from uh Brian and Stevie check out
denail on Facebook uh we've got the
quartz nail that we're using instead of
the titanium one we were hitting it for
a while with the screen on top but I
think we pretty much figured out that
the quartz is where the flavors at I got
Flav 421 with me with some sick here
tonight and I got John Bella with pure
99% triome heads on Kobe talk soon
brother all right so we're going to hit
a bowl out of the Dil and the rure what
rure collab is this
um all right we're hitting it 3 2
[Music]
one I think the
best it's really going to hit the dry SI
I just hit the you definitely see that
they're both pink absolutely
wonderful perfect temperature 801 802
800 really holding the variable within 2
3°
F Tasty's ready for
his all
[Music]
right double hit him double hit him it
called ninja yeah ninja
[Applause]
day oh
yeah anyway super Stoke with the denil
so far I'm going to do a showcase on it
in the next Bubble Man world show and
I'll sort of talk about it in a choir
environment but for now stay
melty