[Music]
hey guys welcome back to Bubble man's
world and I'm finally getting around to
play around with the large size press uh
Rosen press from denail uh you've seen
the one with the 5x5 plate it's about
that size well this one is the 15 in by
15 in so it's a fairly large unit um
it's definitely going to give you a lot
more area to process a lot more material
um I'm not going to go and O do an
overboard review on it today I'm really
probably going to focus mostly on hash
as it's outside and I'm not really
confident in the whole for butt it's
very simple you can take a piece of
parchment or you can use an oil slick
and I'm wondering if oil slick is going
to get in touch with denil and there are
if they're going to make oil slick pads
in the 5 in x 5 in as well as in a 15in
x 15 in cuz it would be wonderful just
to slide that right in there put all
your buds down or your hash your
envelope however you're going to press
simply put another one over top and give
it your 10-second press but I do want to
talk a little bit about uh you know
getting this machine getting it out of
the box it's extremely heavy so I really
would want to warn you guys that uh if
you have any back issues or you have any
sort of uh alements that could be
increased by moving something heavy
please get help with this unit it is
awkward uh it's got the top piece here
that screws down to lower the plate and
because it's not tight because of course
you need leeway for the plates to move
up and down you get this sort of motion
in the unit so you want to be careful
with that um once it is on you should
understand that these top and bottom
plates get very hot I've got it at about
120 degrees Celsius right now which is
around 245 to 250 Fahrenheits uh there's
a whole variety of temperatures that you
can use with this unit and I'll talk
about that a little bit but uh first I
want to really discuss um you know the
getting this out of the box and and
starting to get it working so let me
just turn my phone off and make sure we
don't get interrupted there so like I
said you're going to want to figure out
the perfect distance uh with my smaller
unit because this unit I could literally
close it right right to the bottom and
there's a space here uh about an inch or
two at the back of the unit and it
allows us a little bit of leeway uh if
we're not getting enough of a press and
you can
see I'm getting a really good press on
this one so it's it's good enough I
don't need to lower it anymore um it's
got the two units so here's one of the
problems that you're going to have with
this unit if you're using it at a at a
small house and you're not actually at a
car commercial processing facility is
the power uh it takes a lot more power
than the smaller unit and uh for example
the smaller unit I can plug both sides
into one extension cord and plug it into
a plug well with this one if you plug
both of these even onto the same circuit
in your house you'll most likely blow uh
blow the fuse which I did a couple of
times trying to figure out I have one
plugged in over here with an extension
cord and I have one plugged in uh Fair
distance over there so it is much
uh a little bit more um work to figure
out how to get this thing to work you
know it might not be a problem for many
of you you might have it all set up with
your power and you've got this plug here
and that plug there and they're on
different circuits perfect uh but do be
do pay attention to that because it's
something that happened to me um also
like I said very heavy you're going to
want to find out where you want to put
this thing and pretty much leave it
there so yeah we've got uh our
temperatures up to temperature um I was
thinking of of using the oil slicks uh
at pads but you know I think I'm going
to press a good chunk of hash for this
and really sort of uh utilize the
surface area that we have to go with
because you know it's it's the amount of
hash increased isn't the problem on the
5x5 I can keep putting more and more and
more and what's what's the problem is is
how far the rosin the
resin excretes out of the hash when
pressed uh with that little ex amount of
heat it pushes further and further out
and what I was Finding was as I started
going
over around 3 or 4 grams I was able to
push the rosin right to the end of the
parchment paper on the 5x5 unit the
small denail press this being the large
denail press I don't think we're going
to have that problem um I guess we could
probably just get right to it so I've
got myself a pressing screen and this is
a a pressing screen that's already been
used uh to collect bubble hash and I
found it uh laying around and it was a
little bit dirty
uh and what I did was um it's simply cut
in half and I've had the um the piece
removed from the from the edge which is
the rim the the blue uh Rim that went
all the way around there and uh
basically what I did was because it was
very sort of not holding together I just
folded the end up and I stuck it in the
press and closed it for about 2 seconds
and now you can see that this is nice
it's staying it's staying closed and I
so I did it to both ends uh and what it
did is is it allowed me to make a little
pouch
uh basically what I'll do once I get a
lot of the bubble in there I'll fold the
third side over much like just like that
I'll have my envelope and I'll be able
to lay it down uh nicely in the
parchment in fact why don't we even get
that to go
down just like that there we go it's
actually quite efficient for you know
using none of the pressure whatsoever
just the uh the little bit of heat
that's coming out of
there oh not quite enough
there couple seconds out to do it so
yeah that gives me a nice big unit here
nice big filter bag now you can pick up
these screens right now as blotting
screens pressing screens Rosen screens
we sell them at fresh head.com or bubble
bag.com and of course I share a lot of
information with you guys and I'm never
going to be uh uh more happy than if you
if you turn around and support uh
support what I'm doing by supporting my
company uh we try to have great customer
service we try to give you uh the best
dollar bang for your buck and uh yeah so
you can pick those up what I'm going to
do is I'm having my manufacturer develop
these small bags like this um we're not
quite sure how we want to do it whether
we're going to make them fold in stays
whether we're going to sew them all up
we'll figure out what's going to happen
but I want them to come in uh 1 G 5 G 10
G 100 G potentially even 500 G envelopes
and then I also want to have special
ones for uh cannabis flowers uh they
won't be quite like a a pouch but maybe
more like a tube I found some good luck
in pressing with a tube uh of of screen
I wrap it all up and fill it up with a
ground up herb and I've been getting
some decent returns and uh don't get me
wrong after today when you see this and
you're saying oh what about the flowers
are you going to press flowers I will do
some flowers I'll make a little second
review on this for flowers this is the
uh denail large Rosen press uh hash
review so that's what we're going to do
got some beautiful bubble has here uh it
was a gift from a friend these are
breeder Steve strains and uh it's very
gooey and gummy Uh nice quality presses
together good I'd give it about a four
star maybe a three uh in its melt
category it was grown Outdoors um a
greenhouse Dash uh field uh and
basically it produced a a very lovely
profile of resin it just wasn't able
with the with a Canadian sun to get that
powerful enough boost uh to really push
it over the five and six star uh level
but that's not going to be a problem for
us today we do have the ability to
unveil quality so that's what we're
going to do for you I'm going to take
some of this actually let me go get the
scale because I know you guys are going
to want to know the
amounts all right so I grabbed the scale
grabbed another little dish I am not
even sure how much is here it's got to
be 40 or 50 g total here I'm not sure if
we're going to run it all but but uh
yeah this is about 40 g 40.3 g it's got
a real lovely smell to it think there's
some Blockhead and some sweet skunk and
maybe
some some Plum some some nice varieties
from Steve over the years that these
guys are growing and it's you know it
really it really is nice
bubble just not quite at that level for
the bubble connoisseur you know great
stuff for making coconut oil extracts
great stuff for
um all different forms of metes and even
uh the addition of a Remo style
supercharged joint you know great stuff
for such a thing it's not going to melt
up and plug uh plug your whole unit
let's see how much of this we can get
into our
little our little our little unit here
well looks like it all went in pretty
nice get that
up yeah that's real
lovely so I guess the best bet is to
sort of get it all
even so it's there's no empty spots in
the packet
all
right a little little bit of a hand
press
and let's see we got the Mother Ship I
guess we'll wait till we press some of
this loveliness and then we'll have a
little a little a little
dab
so let me get
this open to the
desired size these uh dils are very much
the size of the parchment paper so it
becomes quite
convenient
D all right there's
[Music]
one see if we can't feed that in it
becomes a bit of a a funny thing when
you start playing around with this
parchment that it starts rolling like
that so it actually becomes the smallest
bit of a
[Music]
challenge to get it
in and then get it
straightened which I just apply the
smallest amount of heat I don't want to
apply too much and put uh any sort of
ripples in the in the material but you
might as well get the machine working
for
you and uh this is just one of the
things that I find is very convenient
about it that that little bit of prep
and heat I mean it's basically a large
iron so you put yourself in a situation
where if something's rolled off if if
your screen won't close well I mean one
of the things I found amazing with these
screens is if I take the smallest amount
of rosin and I clip it on each corner I
I didn't have to do it with this because
there was actually resin present on this
screen already so the minute I just
heated it up the slightest bit that
resin warmed up and sort of became uh
like a glue that's holding my screen
together and I definitely uh that's
about the only only kind of glue I don't
mind
personally so let me just get one more
piece of this cut off for you
guys and I'm using unbleached part
parchment
paper this is another uh issue that many
people have been discussing uh we've
been discussing it on hash Church all
the different sort of footprints and the
sort of different things that can be
present in all the different products
pay attention be conscious you know
learn if you learn something it's okay
to uh admit that you didn't know it
before and that now you're going to do
your best to uh to try and keep things
as safe as possible and that's you know
from the example of saying use using a
very bleached uh parchment paper not
really the best
idea um especially with the heat
transfer you don't want to be
transferring uh something like
bleach
so I think we got these about sorted out
here all right nice big size there
get them semi ready like I said I'm
going to give just a little bit of a
press and I know this table's probably
making you guys nervous with the
mothership and
the and the denail Press it's got a tiny
little bit of motion but I promise you
I'm paying very careful attention uh so
I've got this organized uh so when I
press it I showed you a little earlier
there's four screws four Springs on each
side and you know you could get this to
a point where it becomes so difficult to
to to Clos that it's actually close to a
danger especially if you do get it
closed when you open it back up the
whole unit will tend to PO uh jump up
like a like a little frog so be careful
about that as well um I have a good
maximum pressure going uh but I
certainly wouldn't uh you know suggest
to people that uh that they go too far
with the pressure um I think that the
safer units will be the pneumatic
presses the hydraulic presses that have
you know either air or hydraulic that
allow to get that much more
pressure uh when you when you close it
and some of these units work with a
single button or two buttons that you
push together so quite a nice uh uh
alternative so here we go my single
largest press of rosin ever uh 40 G of
bubble hash and what we're going to do
is we're going to get this in here
first nice big thing in
there and then
we'll let's see what we can do here with
this all right there we
go get this one on top of
that my first time actually doing this
but it seems to be okay
working all right guys we got this on
the 10sec timer let's give it a
shot here we go
you can hear it sizzling beautifully
seven six five four three two one boom
you feel that boom snap up when it pops
up all right so let's check that
out Oho
yeah that is just lovely try to hold
that up for you guys to see it's really
quite
something boom and I would say that that
why don't I slowly start collecting it
and we want to make sure because we're
outside in the in the wind here that
none of this blows away of
course
so now this is a fair amount of Ros and
what I think I'm going to do is uh I'll
collect it off camera I don't want you
hearing the sticky ticky tacky I will
give you a few options for how you can
clean this up uh you can put these in
the
freezer get that out of there actually
while it's still nice and warm that's
one good idea actually to do if you
can uh get your packet moved away from
the resin God is that beautiful look at
this guys you see that really beautiful
I don't have the most amount of room
here so I'm going to have to put this
over here for now I can tell that
there's still lots more gooey goodness
left in there so I probably haven't
gotten quite my 50% but
man I got to show that to you guys
again there's a nice big driet of
rosin and you can see uh I will of
course take some macro photographs of
this I know you guys appreciate the
macro photographs and uh well you know
what I think I'm going to do is I think
I'm going to put this right
here and go for another shot this time I
use a single piece
[Music]
all right so let's try this
again grab this gooey Ooey packet of
goodness slap it right down into the
middle actually got a wasp floating
around the rosin right now he looks
quite interested in this process he's
probably like all of you he's been
watching the internet he's been paying
attention to the hype and he wants to
know should I get a rosin press all
right
so there we go go press down on that bad
boy I've got the 10-second timer set
which is very cool uh it just counts
down the minute the actual unit hits
that was 10 seconds give it a few more
shots
Booyah all right and not to
disappoint she squeezed out another
great amount
so I'm going to clean clean these up
real quick all right guys so I'm going
to share a little bit of this with you
just cuz uh it's easy and quick uh I
went and found a marble Slinger pendant
that he did years ago for me actually
this is the bubble man marble Slinger
pendant and uh I just you know I've seen
people doing it with the GL uh the glass
online and I knew it would be easy but
I'm not sure if you can see this middle
section here how it's this really light
it's the greasy stuff that's usually the
hardest to pick up well this is picking
it up absolutely
simplistically so if you've got any
glass I can show you right here the the
shape isn't even that important I could
easily uh move the glass uh at an angle
and use more if I want but I'm finding
that the edge is quite efficient but
watch the speed in which I can pick this
rosin up
I think if I had a frame holding this
Rosen paper down I could do things even
faster tiny little piece broke free
there all right well that is very
rewarding how well that cleaned the
parchment uh even still I can go over it
and grab those last little remnants and
basically clean this parchment up to a
like new substance nice little bit of
rosin sitting on there why don't we move
into uh our second
sheet fold this one out of the way as we
will be using it again and I want to get
the stickiness that's on the back of
this unit onto the front of this unit so
here we have a beautiful uh really
really nice results for this particular
bat
let me
get God the feeling of this is just
incredible I wish I could describe it
picking up literally grams if not an
ounce or more of of rosin off of the
sheet I mean wellow this is probably at
10 gam and the other one was maybe five
G and eventually we could uh we could
get up to the Ounce at a shot we'll see
what happens we still have more uh
ability to press what we have as well so
we'll see what happens with
that just go across
this front of the page here now I think
the best way to remove this rosin will
be to hold uh I'll probably hold the
glass uh much like this and then just
heat it up so uh the rosin can drip off
onto uh or maybe I'll even crack it off
once it's cold I don't know either or
that's a really nice uh chunk of rosin
right there and that's only the first
two complete so let's see what we got
over
here oh that just looks
great doesn't that look
great in the
sun all right so
cleaned up uh a lot nicer this time
around still a little bit of resin on
the edge of this uh of this guy here but
um you can see here how in the center
it's cleaned up really really nice not
leaving too too much rosin on the one
side of the parchment but leaving a very
nice amount on the other side
so all right I'm kind of getting almost
too much rosin on here now it's starting
to get a little bit tacky for
me grab the last little bit of
this oh yeah this is getting way tack
you're going to have to change change my
format change my technique I'm now doing
the the quick pull which is uh what I
usually do uh when it's not working the
wiping technique sometimes when you go
to wipe
you're just not going to get the love
that you're looking for that's not a
problem change it up real quick and you
can be just as efficient uh with your
cleanup now imagine if I used a small uh
titanium you know Dabber to try and pick
all this up that is a lot of rosin as
you can see it is now completely covered
the
pendant
so let's see what we can do
here get a little bit more here this
other side was not cleaned as as well as
I would have liked it to be I did take
just a few macro photographs of the
rosin to give you an idea of the
quality let's get that
closed and there we go there we
go a nice chunk of rosin by anyone's
standards all right guys so uh I've been
collecting I got just over 13 G uh here
you can see it's uh quite thick I'm
going to press it out in a few seconds
here I'll get it flattened out so it
looks like a nice big uh half ounce that
it is uh we used 40 G you know I forgot
that the hash we used was a lower grade
than my uh the stuff that I'm using my
fourstar that usually gives me about 50
to 55% this stuff actually gives me uh
closer to 33 to 35% return uh we've got
13 G so far I just pressed uh a third
let's get that open oh wow that's cra
cracking off very
cool uh this is a small batch I don't
think there's much more than maybe a
gram or two there uh what I have done is
I and I want to talk about a little bit
while uh before I finish the review here
is the the act of collecting um I did go
and grab my little bubble man uh pendant
I know they also have these big stamps
that people are using glass stamps with
a large glass bottom that you can just
sort of do this too uh great idea uh if
you don't have access to that um and in
particular if you've already pressed
your material a few times and you're
getting towards the end of the press and
you're leaving it a little bit longer
excessing more heat um you can end up
getting a material that comes out a lot
less stable than the original batches
this is very stable very hard uh very
thick the last little batch here that
came out was a little less than stable
uh I can still get it collected uh if I
have a trick up my sleeve so what I have
done is I brought one of these uh cold
freuds it's a for paramedics actually
reusable hot and cold compress and it's
been in my freezer and what I do with
this is um how I like to collect with
this is simply uh I use a Dabber for
this particular batch and I don't leave
it on this thing because it'll get so
cold that as you start collecting it
exactly what it's doing it just starts
cracking uh and flicking the stuff away
so what I do is literally move that out
of the way get your thing back onto your
paper and once you've cooled it a little
bit then you can go and do some
collecting and now it's just picking up
like uh nobody's business beautiful
beautiful pickup job so don't be too
tripped out if you end up with a sappy
material you've been you've been
pressing hard uh and you can't collect
it you might think that you can put it
in the freezer uh get it all Frozen and
then try to collect it I find it that is
a little a little more difficult than
the Simplicity of using a cold plate
underneath something cold underneath
even frozen peas for God's sakes uh just
something that you can put underneath to
give it that little bit of cold so uh
when you go back to collect it uh you
don't have any problems this is
collecting really nice just collected a
whole chunk of that parchment right
there nice little
dab Mountain Man dab maybe not not me
not me dab but uh I you know I don't
have a problem with people doing huge
dabs I mean why not if that's if that's
what you do and that's your thing then
uh you know that's fine I uh I'm good
with that I personally like to take uh
many many dabs throughout the day uh
more efficient in size than you know
giant large huge grams but dude I
straight up applaud those that want to
have fun and are blasting uh uh big
monster rips uh through their rigs good
for you so I'm going to have to get back
onto this coolness here just for a
little bit and it just gives me just the
tiniest bit of cold and lets me collect
the resin without uh without it greasing
up and wanting to stay behind on the
parchment paper uh I'm just using a a
task Rock uh Highly Educated uh Dabber
and carb cap to pick this up right now
and uh mostly what you do is you collect
the resin on top of itself so as it
starts building uh you can you can
actually just start rolling it much like
a ball and the minute it starts getting
too tacky just go right back over to
your cold plate or your you know
whatever you have that's giving you that
access to immediately a different
temperature because this stuff is very
very sensitive to temperature changes
all right so there we got half of that
done get another side I'm suspecting
this will be at least a couple of more
grams get us uh up to 15 grams for uh
for the total uh return on 40 G of uh
you know pretty pretty nice bubble like
I said it wasn't melt it was definite no
melt but uh the really nice flavors uh
well grown just not grown to that final
fruition that uh you know us as the hash
lover as the connoisseurs uh like to see
but what a beautiful thing that rosin is
what a beautiful thing that denail has
done to come out with these modified
t-shirt presses with denail standards
denail customer service and uh you know
hopefully sooner than later we'll be
supplying them with some pressing
screens if not please you know it's
always appreciated when you support the
company freshes and bubble bag.com
uh we have your hash making needs
whether it's for uh Rosen presses we
will be carrying these very soon on the
site whether it's for Bubble Bags we
have them all sorts from standards
originals and lights uh whether it's
bubble boxes tumble Nows dry sift
screens whatever your hashish needs are
for the solventless quiver bubble man
and Bubble Bags has you covered so
please support us and uh if you like
this video give us a like down below and
uh if you really enjoy it and want to
see more videos like this then please
give us a subscribe uh we always
appreciate when you share our content uh
your social media is um how we get out
there my social media only takes me to
you but you take me to the rest of the
world so much appreciated I'm going to
continue here collecting this last
little bit I'm going to have to uh go
through my macro photographs I didn't
take as many as you guys probably would
have liked but I got a nice three or
four that can show you the quality of
what was pressed here uh maybe I'll
throw in a little I guess the Melt video
is not as exciting with rosin because it
it's it's an oil it's not a hash so once
you've created it as an oil of course
it's going to have a melt factor of
seven star because well oil is a
material that melts every time every
single time in fact I've never seen oil
in my life but didn't
melt so there we go
collected another couple of jebs we get
that on the scale real quick we'll take
a a final
dab let me get the denail on
here that brought
over always nice to have a oil slick to
put your pipe down I hate that sound of
putting the pipe down on uh on something
that's uh a hard substance that you
haven't uh that you're not paying
attention to and it gives that that hard
that sound that glass sound that you put
down so shout out to oil slick for
hooking it up uh saving bongs one bong
at a
time all right all right so obviously
for a process like this the less heat
the better I'm just heating up the uh
tip of the
um all right let's see what we got
here what's the final number going to
be final number is
13.9 13.9 so let's have a dab of it
because I'm sure it's wonderful
oh yeah nice long elongated let's see
make sure we're up here
300 well let's just collect that all up
and we'll wait a few more seconds for
that to get up to
temperature God it looks like beautiful
bubble uh bubble rosin I should say uh
the bubble hash was a variety of 120
Micron through 73 so there was 73 uh 90
Micron and
120 present in that bubble hash we
squeezed it through a 25 micron screen
uh all 40 gram of it and uh well we
ended up with uh so far 13 G I think I'm
going to be able to squeeze a couple
more grams out just by giving uh what
I'll probably do is I'll open this up
I'll remove it from the large screen
that it's in and I'm going to fold it
upon itself to get it a little bit
thicker I'll put it in a separate size
screen and I'll squeeze that through and
see if I can't get anything more so here
we
go yes I like
that I'm going to turn this guy off here
[Laughter]
here want to thank you guys for watching
if you guys have any questions please uh
comment in the comments below I'll try
to answer as many as I can I do miss
some comments here and there but uh all
in all a great unit just a few key
things to keep in touch uh in mind don't
plug them into the same circuit in your
house or your your uh commercial Place
make sure you don't tighten the unit so
hard that when you go to close close it
it's barely able to open uh we don't
want to see that and otherwise just uh
you know keep your temperatures down uh
experiment you can experiment with
temperatures as low as 90 Celsius uh and
go up to uh or 80 Celsius for that
matter and go up to 120 130 celsus now
in Fahrenheit that's going to be around
190 Fahrenheit uh upwards or 180
Fahrenheit upwards to around
250 personally what I find is when I'm
uh extracting from hash I like to keep
my temperatures a little bit lower and
when I'm extracting with uh cannabis I
usually keep them a little bit higher
however for this experiment I actually
pressed this at the temperature that I
normally press cannabis at it was around
245 F little bit warmer than usual uh I
do have some of this hash that I'll be
able to compare to the uh rosin oil I
should say I have some uh that I made
some time ago and I'll compare it I'll
compare compare the colors I'll compare
the tastes uh see if uh the tarpine
profile was that greatly affected uh by
the excess Heat and the only thing I'd
really add is that if you get yourself a
little laser temperature and you close
this up and you get you're at say 250
fah uh and you pull the thing out like
right away and hit it with the
temperature you'll notice that the oil
itself is going to be closer to around
90 to
120 Celsius so uh sorry not Celsius but
Fahrenheit 100 150 tops so it's all
interesting we're learning every day uh
I definitely want to hear from you guys
and if you have any more questions like
I said just answer them in the comments
and uh yeah that was uh the denail
review we ended up with just over 13 gam
um half ounce made it in a very short
time compared to the video I did with
d420 K and uh the how I'm going to leave
you is
simply by pressing out this little bit
of rosin that we have here and showing
you uh what it looks like uh you know
not in a giant Puck so let's see if we
can't it's interesting to learn how to
uh how to work with this stuff as well
like after you know for me not having
worked with uh oil for so so long and I
I know a lot of you consider this stuff
to be hash but I really still call it
oil I'm not sure if uh that's very
important or not the aspect of uh
whether or not we're going to be calling
this oil or hash but I'm old school I go
with uh what the old school guys were
saying and when I see Robert conel Clark
uh explaining the differences between
oil and hash in um in hashish it just
leads me to believe that there are
indeed um some differences between oil
and
hashish all right there we go guys
give thanks for the Ros and press uh
really appreciate uh the kindness of
denail sending these out for me to test
and uh you know so far the the small
unit I've absolutely loved it uh I love
the ability to CL plug it into the same
plug uh but this unit is a whole
different ball game you really could see
how you could get your production game
on with one of these things and uh see
if we can't get this open here it's so
nice to have this cold uh pack here
because you just you give this a little
a little press just to uh you know get
it get it a
little
woooo I want to get that bottom half a
little cooler top half removed real nice
but that bottom half Is Still Still
Holding On just a little
bit there we
go all right guys
thanks for watching Bubble man's world I
will leave you with the
rosin hey guys so I turned the unit back
on um I had my 13 plus Gams I was doing
the math it just didn't seem like enough
what I realized is I hadn't shown you
what the hash looked like on the inside
of the screen and I sort of wanted to
show you guys that so when I opened it I
noticed that uh right away a lot of it
looked very like almost this palish tan
color almost uh not white but whitish
and it sort of shows that oh
everything's almost out of here but when
I opened it further in the inside
trapped between the two layers of very
very dry material uh was still what I
would consider a decent amount of resin
so I turned the unit back on I just
literally did another press which uh you
can see right here is uh is decent
substantial even
oops I'm getting some problems here with
this
parchment I'm going to have to open it
up again with the co with the help of
the cold
so always best to not forget this thing
it's uh it's extremely
convenient so yeah sometimes if that
stuff's not opening properly this looked
really greasy I did have to use a little
bit of excess heat to get at it but uh I
suspect there's another couple of grams
there at least a gr and if I were to
press it maybe one or two more times I
could squeeze another gram out each time
just having to use more pressure I did
press it off camera but I had tightened
it even more you should have seen the
way this thing kicked up when I uh
lifted it up it felt uh like I won't be
doing that again going to open it up
just a tiny little bit on the back here
and
uh last little bit
of the
way better to be safer than Sor I
suppose that came off quite nice so you
see another big nice press through the
XL uh the thing about that's really nice
about this is that I would have be hard
set to do this in my smaller unit uh I
was nowhere near uh you know 40 G I was
pressing four and five grams and it was
already starting to uh oh yeah that's
starting to feel better now it's
starting to feel a lot less sticky than
it's been there is a couple of sticky
spots in each middle uh and we'll get to
those let's see if we can't clean this
up nice and quick this stuff just turns
to shatter almost immediately uh upon
the contact with the cold in larger
amounts it'll stay together yeah now
it's just shattering we'll just take it
off and put it on the oil slick a little
bit picking it up here with the
uh Highly
Educated
gabber this why I was rolling it around
and then it gets to a point where all of
a sudden it won't roll anymore and it's
uh you know the the power of the oil
overtakes
uh the the weakness of the parchment so
just be careful and be patient as I said
that a piece of rosin just jumped up
onto my
wrist but yeah be patient in your
collection this is actually quite a bit
I'd say this is going to be another
couple of grams so I'm feeling better
about that already I've gotten my
returns up uh in the 30 percentile 30 to
anyway and uh that is a lot better so
never jump the gun and throw your your
end product away always always well it
doesn't take a brain surgeon to believe
when you when you open it up and you see
that it's gummy and sticky this is not
what it's supposed to look like so for
people that don't know that that's
something that you can learn of value
right here in right now uh when the
material is done hash in particular it
really won't have any stick left to it
uh you'll be able to you'll be able to
know that you got everything out and as
long as you're doubting and you're
thinking I don't think I got everything
out you probably didn't so uh go with
that and uh get back to your press and
uh give it another shot each time like I
say you can experiment around with the
different amounts of heat that you're
using the amounts of pressure that
you're
using all right so I did bring the ra
the rosin is over
here kind of wouldn't mind finding out
what the excess extra is that we got on
here all right
right actually I don't need to do that I
never have in the past I've always just
closed it it's the beauty of rosin and
just pulled them pull the
pin usually twist it a few times just so
it doesn't hold on to a lot of excess
but there we go let's see what we got
there two G 1.9 G so that was a good
press you know leaving that behind could
have uh well would have been
detrimental this is another great way to
clean uh Raw rosin up using itself as
the main clean you got rosin on the
sides of your parchment paper you can
clean it up pretty good like
this let's see what we got
here all
righty beautiful
beautiful get that back in there this is
too hot right now but eventually once I
turn this uh uh back down uh you know
quite a bit like uh it really only needs
to be warm rather than hot uh and I just
will give it another little press and
turn it into one solid piece but I think
for now we really are going to have to
hit another batch of rosin see how that
goes all
right loosen this a little bit
there we go fairly hard you can always
lower it and and raise it with this
piece here but obviously not when you're
in the middle of a
press there we
go here we go
again get that on the on the cool plate
and I suspect this is uh really getting
down to it now maybe a gram there maybe
a half gram every little bit helps I'm
certainly not going to say no to it I
will continue to collect this and once
I've got it collected uh next we're
going to open up the packet uh the
screen uh envelope and we'll uh we'll
see if we can't show you what's inside
over a/ ounce 15.5 G I added all the
extra right here it was actually a
little bit more than I thought I was
going to get but the part I really was
interested in doing with you guys is
showing you what's in in here so um you
can tell uh close up I'll bring it to
you uh you can see that there's a little
bit of resin here but for the most part
the screen is actually fairly clean
there's some here as well and this is
old resin that was on there earlier that
I mentioned so if we flip it over to the
other side we got the same thing we got
these two Center batches and that's
where the resin was really feeding out
but you could see that the rest of the
screen maintained quite a beautiful
Clarity so these two little spots in the
center tell me that there's the tiniest
bit more resin for me to acquire but I
did want to kind of open this up a
little bit and show
you what is inside of here so you can
see how that little bit of resin that I
put on there at the start really closed
that up nicely and that was a a little
bit of bubble Ingenuity I love to hear
what you've done with bubble uh I've
done a few varieties of funny things one
time I got myself out of a locked
bathroom in Jamaica using bubble and
some other things so there it is that's
what it looks like right there you can
see towards the
edge that it's quite done and then as
you go into the
middle right you go into the middle and
you can see there's still some resin in
there there's still some good gooey
goodness so I'm going to continue on
pressing this um uh it's not going to be
part of the review I will let you know
in the comments section but uh I've
already gone overboard on this video and
extended it longer than I thought I
would by coming back and doing the rest
but uh there you have it guys denail
press large in the house um I got to
give it uh I got to give it a couple of
thumbs up for certain it's definitely an
a uh efficient unit if any of you
realized the last time d420 K and I did
a video uh where it was turning uh you
know the half ounce into uh uh or an
ounce 30 gr into a half ounce uh that
was a much nicer bubble uh that took us
almost 3 hours using hair straighteners
two of us we both ended up kind of
giving ourselves a little bit of a
shoulder injury on it it was kind of
ridiculous so if you're finding yourself
with a with an injury due to a hair
straightener uh this unit is definitely
going to be for you so thanks for
watching Bubble man's world everyone and
uh we will look forward to seeing you
all next time
[Music]