[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and uh today I'm pretty excited to be
bringing to you a little bit of a review
on the brand new enail press Rosen press
so uh they basically this is their beta
test their first uh batch out the door I
think they made only 100 units uh they
took an already existing t-shirt press
which you might very well recognize uh
the plates are 5x5 so 5 in x 5 in and uh
it's a really really well-made little
unit I mean you could pick these t-shir
presses up I think for pretty much $300
or
$400 uh and that is exactly the price
Dil is selling it for as well
$350 on a pre-order at dna.com there's
probably only about 40 left so I jump on
those quick and you can see unlike a
regular t-shirt press which would just
have the one heat press that heats up
one plate the other plate stays
cool what we know from rosin and guys
like soil grown who really forwarded and
started this uh excitement up on
Instagram with uh when he first squished
a bud uh we know that both plates being
hot are pretty essential for for the
process to work so denil added a second
controller uh these are denil uh units
inside and basically it's just like a
dil you turn that thing on you turn that
thing on I have it set on Celsius so um
I'm looking to press around 200 212° fah
today not the highest temperature not
the lowest but somewhere in the middle I
know that I can go around 15 to 180 and
still you know potentially preserve more
Tarpin I know that I can go a little
warmer uh upwards of 250° and really
make sure I get every last drop I'm kind
of coming at you guys from the middle uh
when you get your own press by all means
play with every temperature and every
pressure um right off the bat one of the
things I'll tell you when you get this
unit is there's a big knob on the back
uh this knob when loosened allows this
to move on the wheel and it also lifts
and separates uh the plates higher apart
from one another
so uh when you first get it they're
going to have it set so when you've got
this all the way closed and you put this
all the way down uh it's that's it it
doesn't go any further there's still a
bunch of press here I'd have to turn the
unit because it's quite a bit of
pressure on these Springs that I've that
I've put on there uh and anyway uh what
you have to do is you have to undo the
one the top one from its little unit
right here which is a super simple
twist and then unplug it's four pins uh
I'll leave it plugged in for now cuz
it's heating up but what you do is once
you unplug that is you can actually spin
this top lever uh this top plate and
bring it down lower to create more
pressure in your um in your clothes so
I'm going to get this thing into
position just so it can actually show
you uh the pressure that it takes to
close this particular
one so not a ton of pressure I'd say
that's uh nowhere near the 1,500 uh PBS
per pressure that it's appar able to
take but um I'm sure it's some hundreds
if not close to you know 8 to 900 lb of
pressure uh once again I could spin that
plate even more and make it even harder
but be careful when you close these four
Springs down and it really
grabs the unit can jump a little bit or
when you go to lift it up it can really
pop up with some serious pressure so you
know stay within your safety zone
especially if you're a patient you don't
need to be hurting yourself be extremely
careful of these plates as they start to
heat up um the whole thing is going to
get hot even up here will get hot
eventually so uh that's why they've got
the big caution hot surface sticker do
not touch these uh with your the plates
with your fingers you know try to keep
your hands away even from the outside of
the top plate uh I'm talking about after
having it on for for quite some time as
I like to to leave mine on so we are up
to
100 let's see what we got yeah I got
100° set on the temperature so uh
they've both gone up to about 110
115 and I'll just wait a few minutes to
for that to drop as that is a little bit
warmer of a temperature than I want to
rock right now um it's because I had
them closed for a while there and I
guess we'll discuss what we're going to
be pressing today um I'll never go back
to the hair straightener I'll tell you
that much right now that thing is a done
deal it was great for getting us through
the door uh but the Press even if they
made a smaller version like a little
tiny version which I think Dil is coming
out with uh that'll blow away uh any
hair straightener as well it's really
nice to be able to close it I also like
to use my ear and get close to it as I'm
closing it uh you know for the 5 to 10
seconds and part of me wants to let it
sit longer the way Jeff Church the
Cannabis Reverend I always noticed he
would leave it that eight plus seconds
whereas other people would pop it open
at 5: it's all going to be a personal
issue of whether uh where people much
like a nail heating up a nail and having
people tell you that it's too hot even
if you're enjoying it or telling you
that it's not hot enough because they
don't enjoy it uh the pressing will be
no different um if you overpress you
will overheat up the material um so far
from the bud rosin that I've done it's
come out very very light even when I've
let it left it for 10 plus seconds now I
am going at a lower uh temperature 100°
uh Celsius which is only
212 but um you know the the nug really
squeez squees out beautifully the hash
squeezes out even nicer so I suggest let
we look at some rosin real quick while
we're talking about Ros and I I made
these just yesterday um I made this
first one which is very much like a
shatter uh it's very glossy uh it's not
Snappy in the sense that it just breaks
so if I tapped it with my finger it
would absolutely just shatter and break
and I can I can break a piece off like
that and it's just extremely stable even
when I broke it off it made this
beautiful little snapping sound so this
rosin I made from this bubble and this
bubble is about a fourstar bubble melts
pretty good definitely doesn't disappear
to nothing um smells and tastes great
smokes great um and no surprise there
that It produced a really beautiful
quality
rosin um then I took some of this three
star bubble that I have now this bubble
is was a gift it's it was grown nice it
was I believe an outdoor crop of a
variety of breeder Steve strains and
it's nice it's just not what you would
call a a four five or even a six-star
it's really just a three star because of
its melt Factor now it has a great taste
it's very aromatic when I open it but
people aren't excited because it's not
really a dabbable product um I pressed
out some of that
yesterday and we got an absolutely
beautiful product here um and I'll show
that up close up on the camera later as
well and that came from this stuff right
here so you can really see now this
isn't just putting lipstick on a pig and
and prettying it up what we're doing is
we're extracting the oils that are
present in these thick wax
membranes uh and we're we're extracting
and and pressing those oils out and what
it what it's doing really is is it's
unveiling much like bubble bags unveiled
quality when it decontaminated resin
Heads This is now unveiling quality
that's hidden
amongst a shitty grown triome head or a
wax membrane that was too thick or
something that affected it that the
resin itself there's still a quality in
there once you decontaminate it further
and this is really proof of that because
I'll tell you anyone that smokes this
and then smokes this I mean it's easily
a three to seven star uh jump and then
just I was playing around and I pressed
uh I pressed some for a friend yesterday
as well so this is just another little
another little little pile of
that beautiful
stuff get that there so I can turn it
around and show you get a little piece
of the parchment on there and that's uh
that's the same stuff just really golden
and uh aromatic it's got the the the hit
of those breeder Steve strains I believe
there's Sweet Tooth in there there might
be
Blockhead maybe a little grapefruit
really a nice uh combination of the of
the smells there and of course the rosin
just uh made it absolute
fire so we'll put those there at the
front on display and then I say why
don't we press up a little some
something why don't we start with a
bud um really easy process here uh I've
been using these raws that Horatio
Delbert left for me which I got to say
dude like thank you so much I didn't
even realize how essential and awesome
that would be so breaking off a small
square of the uh parchment paper you can
also use oil slick if you like like now
people are going to have issues with
both of them you know I'm using this
unbleached you know the best possible
stuff that I could personally find but
who's to tell me that in a year
someone's not going to find out that
something went into making this that
isn't ideal to be heated up and
transferred to the resin so I urge you
all to constantly think about these
things don't use just any old material
and when we get to the pressing screens
that we're going to talk to about well
when filtering the hash I really want to
make sure you guys don't cut corners on
these particular things get the best
parchment you can unbleached is is ideal
H and uh as well get the heat pressure
uh Heat stamp authenticated uh pressing
screens so you want something that goes
at least to a
300° and then I would want to say a good
100° under that so um you know the oil
slick pad I believe goes to 500° but uh
you know you'd have to contact them to
make sure of that so I snapped off a
little Square I bent it in half I've got
a tiny little nugget that was left over
from Glenn at the my uh sorry your
medical cannabis uh dispensary in
Winnipeg Manitoba I urge you guys to go
check out their Facebook page and give
them any support that you can they're
having a lot of problems with the city
of Winnipeg they're having a lot of
problems with the Winnipeg Police um
they need support they need help and
obviously the people in Winnipeg are no
more or no less Des deserving to have
access to good clean medicine at a good
price than the people of British
Columbia and we have over a hundred of
these and our City's ready to regulate
them so we've got this down to a little
over 100° I'm just going to put this on
there nice and gently and then we're
going to do a
squeeze and to use my ear four five 6 7
8 9
10 pop that open after
10 looks like it's squeezed out a
different a decent amount of
resin not a huge
amount but definitely a small amount
I'll come show you guys there in the
camera you can kind of see the
derbs and now that'll probably just
squeeze out to a dab but there very well
may be um a rip left in that butt as
well uh it was a little bit bigger than
what I normally do and it seems like
there might be still a little bit on the
ends so I could give it another press
but uh why don't we collect what was
there I just used uh a Dabber got this
beautiful little wooden Dabber from the
good Folks at Dil uh clean out the tiny
little bits and pieces of the herb that
you
see takes not too long and then uh
gently scrape it up yeah it's this is
already shatter it's already flipping
and flicking and got to be careful with
collecting of this stuff uh I have found
that it's almost easier to rub the stuff
off the parchment Jeff Church style
that's one of his sort of techniques
that he showed me originally and I
didn't always use it I was more of a a t
like tap and and lift but for certain
resins I find that the technique that he
was using was definitely on point for
efficiency uh and just overall ease to
do so yeah this is really nice this
stuff is like really beautiful colored I
think that it's probably going to be a
good idea for us to get a picture so I'm
not going to pick it all up off the
parchment right now I've got some on the
Dabber here area to to work with and by
hand it's just it becomes even more uh
difficult oh yeah this is really nice
once it's been collected you can see
that it's a pretty much a clear
white substance that we squeezed off the
bud very
nice very nice indeed oh we'll take one
more shot and then we'll take the dab
and then we'll get back to more
pressing more pressing that's what we
need to do
oops woo caught it that's what I'm
talking about ninja skills fresh dab of
what I believe was called Grape God out
of the sick
nail so one of the things I found about
the unit to be extremely uh convenient
uh having it here just in the last
couple of days is that I can find
nuggets of things that I've grown or
gifts that I've been given that I don't
really I'm not that often into
vaporizing I seem to be really much more
into dabbing these days and so to be
able to just take a flavor and press it
through this machine for 8 to 10 seconds
and be able to squeeze out uh a dab or
two dabs I've had some of the congales
squeeze out almost three dabs for one
small Bud uh and I did bring a few other
buds I thought we could go through just
as a a sort of test um this was a gift
from Horatio as well and I believe this
is the silver haze so it's a nice little
sativa lower off one of these little
buds here and just put that right in
there I'm just going to reuse the same
parchment even though there was a tiny
little bit of resin still in there um
overly worried about it and there is a
thing called the pre- squish that you
can do I've heard uh soil grown talk
about and some other people I have done
it most every time uh I mention it now
because I just put this button and
actually didn't do that so um it's
something you can do it makes it a
little bit easier to get
in you can really at one point in time
with your
ear here it's sizzling
all right so I'll show you this little
guy this little super silver haze bud uh
squeezed out a little bit more than the
last one nice little uh collection of
rosin on the plate there on the
parchment paper and you can see that the
butt itself uh I usually just pull it
right out while it's hot and
uh and it comes off real easy I I don't
know if other people have a different
technique if they're letting it dry or
whatnot but but uh yeah there's all
sorts of different way really
no I'm sure a lot of different people
are going to come up with a lot of
different ways to tell you how to do
this I'm just trying to give an my own
honest little opinion and review on this
machine so far I absolutely love it um
that is enough Bud collecting what I
wanted to do real quickly was show you
guys um a
collection collecting using uh a
pressing screen I'm going to actually
cut a piece of this pressing screen
down we'll just go like
this like
this so there's a nice little piece we
can make a nice little envelope with
that simple like that like that close it
on both ends you know put maybe a a gram
or two of hash in there and we're going
to press it through uh through the
machine here and show you guys what it
what it's like to press hash so um we'll
start with the better stuff might as
well do a little bit of each one this
stuff is bone bone dry and has really
congealed itself into this um tupperware
container all
right so I wanted to use my scale I
don't see it
anywhere we'll go by eye I can tell you
from this stuff as I have already done
it this stuff here will yield
50% uh this stuff which I thought was
only yielding about 33% I squeezed it a
few more times and actually brought that
up to about a
45% so this is almost giving 50% as this
is giving easily 50% and I've never even
gone back to repress this because uh I
was so happy with the 50 particularly
because it's like I said it's really
only a four star so uh getting that 50%
is uh pretty
nice all right so let's throw a bunch of
hash in here now I just did this
yesterday and weighed it out quite a bit
uh quite a few times so I'm going to
guess that uh I'll probably be pretty
accurate with a couple of grams and uh
we probably be left with a gram Patty of
hash afterwards and a gram of rosin so
uh another thing that I noticed was I
used a few screens that were dirty that
had these uh these oil marks in them
from you know the rolling the ball and
doing it with the hair straightener and
what I found was I took one of those
screens and I wrapped it up like this it
was all dirty and I the first press I
put it through the denail press the
thing basically cleaned the screen uh so
that was pretty
interesting all right let's see what we
got
here I think we could put a little bit
more in there think I'm way
low there we go so basically just
folding it up like a joint upon itself
and folding it back and instead of doing
the the ball technique that people are
doing I've kind of Fallen uh grown
accustomed to this tube or
rectangle and uh it's interesting it
definitely leaks very nice all right so
for this piece what I'm actually going
to use is a larger piece of parchment
that I pulled off yesterday when I was
doing this very same thing and uh it
just gives more room for the oil to
press out and uh it was a little bit
easier for me to load as well so here we
go this is the bubble hash two three
four 5 6 7 8 9 10
so what I usually do with this now is I
take it and put it in the freezer just
for a quick shot let it harden up open
it up and collect the resin and then
repress again we're back we've got this
should be usually able to open it real
quick quick and most of the resin will
stay on one side of the uh of the
parchment now it's just a matter of
collecting it so I lift out gently the
the pouch in the
middle a little bit of resin's going to
always sort of stick to it but we'll get
that in the next press because we're
definitely not done pressing this and
then just collecting with this really
simply I just
gently collect it upon itself now first
I'm going to make sure that my piece is
absolutely as clean as a whistle because
I did dig it around in that hash and
there's a bunch of little grains of hash
remnants on there so now we'll collect
it
up nice and tappy tacky very sort of
sappy
stuff got to be careful with it at first
uh if you're using a a tool like this is
you don't want to tear through the
parchment paper so you just have to kind
of gently pull the stuff off the top by
you know collecting it basically with
itself as mostly anyone that's collected
this rosin uh for a short period of time
has learned that it becomes very easy to
collect when you use the rosin itself
and not the actual tool of course that
takes getting some on your tool first so
nice press here actually real nice press
uh when you get larger amounts it
becomes even easier in my opinion cuz it
just you can hear it it just rolls right
off
you hear that just collecting upon
itself quite nice uh very very beautiful
stuff uh I do have some photos that I'll
share with you that are of basically
this exact hash uh pressed and rolled
through yesterday uh that way I don't
have to spend most of the time on this
video uh re photographing the resin for
you guys but I while we're talking about
this I can show you what this resin's
going to look like or at least what it
looked exactly like yesterday in the
photos that I took and you can see that
the honeycombing effect is very
pronounced and very strong uh as it
boils out of the uh pressing screen and
out of the hash you really get this
shatter like
honeycomb um look to it and it's it's a
pretty cool effect you know I'm I myself
am glad that I really just stuck with my
guns and my belief systems that I didn't
want to do solvent extracts and I I just
I waited all these years years for all
these people enjoying and I for what I'm
happy to say that for the last 10 to 15
years I haven't been inhaling solvent
extracts it's not something that's uh
you know and hoping that the person that
is making them was doing a good
job so we got a nice little ball right
there in fact I did get my scale so even
though we didn't weigh it at the start
we can weigh it
now let's do that
boom do a little tear it's about a05
just for those out in YouTube land and I
love how the rosin just literally will
pull right off the
stick nice little dab right
there and that is .9 of a gram so let us
press it again and see what we can
squeeze out of it
at about the 7c mark there I could hear
it starting to sizzle and it sizzled out
a little bit but certainly nowhere near
what we got it's probably 0.1 or2 which
will bring this up to uh a little over a
gram and then we'll uh we'll open that
up and we'll see we'll see what we
got so I'd also like to press some of
this hash for you guys just to see uh a
different press in effect I'm not going
to put quite as much in that way we can
actually use um uh the parchment paper
that I've already pulled out just some
smaller pieces I will do like a gram or
something and you can see the ease and
the wonderfulness of this unit where you
can just sit here having fun and in a
few seconds pull off a gram of rosin now
I do have the large unit this is the
small one 5x5 I have a large one that is
three times the size size 15x 15x 15 uh
it is in the other room and it's going
to be my next review I'm not sure I'm
going to be getting that up uh before I
go camping so I wanted to really push
this one through and make sure you guys
saw how cool these units were and if you
have the opportunity get yourself on the
pre-order if you're on dils page and
you're looking to buy anything else uh
you can use the code stay melty all one
word uh and they'll give you a nice
little discount on your order the
pre-orders of this unit are already so
cheap there is no discount available
through that code so please don't bother
and uh yeah let's collect some more
resin here let's see what we've
got yeah each time I lift it up it's
cleaner and cleaner and cleaner there's
still some resin on there but we're
definitely getting
cleaner all right so let's collect
this nice collection o it's already
quite quite hard some stuff I find bud
in particular that is very dry or has
been quite long cured I find that the
rosin from that even at a low heat and a
low press it comes out like like dust
like literally you go to collect it and
uh I find it a little bit easier to heat
it heat up the tool a little bit to to
get it up there because it's just like
dust and you go to click on it and it
just flicks and flies away so yeah I
think this is easy easily going to be
another point on here maybe a point
two decent amount definitely more than
uh what I would take on a dab but uh I'm
no mountain man not sure if you guys
have seen that guy do his like 20 G dabs
and stuff although you know what all
these guys that are taking huge dabs I'm
super impressed that you can circular
breathe but uh I don't know for me if
you're going to impress me and take a
huge dab I'd like to see all the smoke
go into your lungs in one shot and then
come out I I think that would be
something to work for if I was uh
personally in the uh big dab game so
let's see what we added to
that let's see what we added to
that nice parchment too I'm amazed it
doesn't just rip but it
doesn't without barely even touching
this
like barely touching it I just get a
nice beautiful well done piece and uh
I'm going to guess that it is over a
gram
now
1.7 and this was .5 so it's 1.2 G and uh
oh you know what just for shits and
giggles let's give it another tiny press
and and see uh if we're able to squeeze
anything out we will leave it even a
little bit longer this time
like over 10
seconds well it sizzled out a bunch more
there's no doubt about
it smells great doesn't have a burnt
popcorn taste the color is still really
beautiful Amber Amber esque I wouldn't
say it's any darker than the last
two and let's just keep raising the
limits I think we're going to find that
we have uh more than two well that we
had more than two gram of hash in there
it'll be interesting to see if it's only
a gram of uh husk left we'll see here
soon I'm going to weigh that for you
guys as well and give you that idea um
the pressure on these things because
you're going to ask and I'm going to
write it in the comments comments is uh
between 1,200 and 1,600 lb of pressure
depending on how tight you set it up and
there's four Springs one on each corner
of the plate and it's uh they definitely
each have a decent amount of pressure I
personally haven't found the need to go
much harder uh I like the idea that it's
not super hard to close and open uh I
don't really like the idea of catching
the thing in my mouth and then otherwise
uh yeah it's just been a really great
unit temperature- wise I think it goes
up to
400° Cel I could be wrong I haven't
tried to raise it but I heard that the
the temperature range is quite nice it's
that of a t-shirt press so I would think
like 0 to
400° um it could it could be Fahrenheit
I'm really not sure I haven't gone I
personally don't want to go over 200
plus fit so I'm really trying to keep it
low and there's another nice little ball
of that and what I did the other day
easily enough I just opened it
up and closed it back
upop pulled a little out there right at
the end just a little bit of the
circle good to give it a little spin
actually now you don't have to do what
I'm doing right there if some of you are
like oh he's exposing it to more heat by
all means if your [ __ ] is ping tarpine
so much uh you don't have to do that
last little bit you can do what I just
did with a very low low temperature and
I'm kind of just being lazy to do it in
the moment what I did how I did these
ones was once I turned the unit off and
it went down down down down down in
temperature and they were very much just
warm I then just put it on and gave it a
little bit more pressure and uh pressed
them out so that's an option that you
have to do as well but keep it in mind
if you do have material that's uh
already lacking in tpin or the water
hash washed most of the those tpin away
or for some reason you're not really
rocking a ton of tpin uh then you know
something like that could only diminish
them more uh avoid doing it so let's see
where we're at should we weigh this
now can see it's quite flat there's
still some stickiness to it but it's not
very dirty I have to say if I can get it
open enough without without too many um
seams you know like little ripples in
the screen you can usually pull the hash
off uh in in you know almost a single
piece I'll just grab these sort of side
pieces
there there we go let's find out what we
got here is it a gram is it a gram and a
half what do we got it's 1.4 and I'd
easily think we can get it up to
1.5
so I'd say we had about close to 3 G of
hash and we got an almost 50%
return so yeah 1.4 or no sorry 1.3 and
1.2 it was about 2 and 1/2 gr and we got
about a 50% the the Ros and uh
ways I would say let's see real quick
plus the0 five this is
1.9 minus the5 is
1.4 so 1 .4 and
1.4 there you go people well it's going
back and forth this one between 1.3 and
1.4 but basically what we got there was
a 50% return we took a fourstar bubble
and we turned it into a sevenstar Ros
and and uh if you guys want to see that
up close cuz I know you
do that's what we got right there so
it's quite
nice sappy and pulley and uh I suspect
uh as it hardens it will become more of
a shatter
likee all right and that was what I
called the darker one that was the one
that turned into this when it dried
which is absolute shatter so uh you can
kind of tell at this point that the
Colors oh yeah they're pretty on point
this might get a little darker yet cure
out uh it was a dark water hash it was
quite dark now this one had a more of a
blondish tinge to it uh it's still is a
dark water hash but uh it squeezes out a
very golden kind of nice material and uh
let's see what we're going to do here
we're going to squeeze out one more uh
batch of the screen here we can even
weigh the screen it also weighs about5
if I can get some of this excess bubble
off tiny little bits that have squeezed
themselves into
the oh well we'll call it
six so we're going to weigh it this
time and uh try to do like 2
G unless it's just way too little and
we'll bump it up yeah that's three right
there so let's just do three
G and see what kind of returns we can
get on this now this is uh like I said
three star bubble uh mostly because the
Canadian sun I don't want to diss it
resin wise it's very hard to produce
really high quality dabbable product uh
in a lot of the parts of Canada because
the sun's just it just doesn't have the
power of those The Tropical Sun or the
you know the Californian
Sun all right so that's all kind of
loose in there luckily the edges of
these are now sticky which I find very
convenient that I can just push them
closed and uh I'm going to collect it in
the same piece of parchment I've gotten
it pretty clean already in the past so
we're going to go for an 8C one for the
first one so count it with me one
two 3 4 five
7 eight Just Hear It giv her couple more
seconds we got a nice little uh splotch
come out
there like I said I usually like to put
it in the freezer but I'm not going to
run back and forth each time what I will
do is is I will
dab um another sh another little bud
let's squeeze out another bud and see
what we can find that one is empty this
one is
not all right here we
go that's I can't wait to actually dab
the sativa Bud that we hit the haze but
let's try one of the other ones which I
believe was chemo yes the chemo here we
go of course he's a big chunky nuggets I
can just use even a small one and that's
more than enough I do find that uh with
the Ros and once again soil grown with
all the the tips it's good to break the
buds up uh into smaller pieces and he
finds that he gets uh he finds he gets
better yields when he's brok broken a
butt up into a few smaller pieces than
if he just uses uh one large piece of
Bud so let's try it out soil grown I'm
going to press these three little buds
one after the
other and I'm going to give it the pre
squeeze we
go
two all right so we look at this one you
never know what you're going to see when
you open one of these it really can go
any
way and as you can see we got some
derbs so the
chemo was good good
producer as was the Super Silver Haze um
I'm a super silver haze guy a haze guy
of any kind really so I'm going to go
for that and uh it's also quite nice I
will uh collect some first and then
photograph it with the macro lens so uh
we can see what we got
here clean that off a little
bit titanium clean so nice not a bad
idea to have the nice uh the the the
sorry the the the tool a little bit warm
too it's picking up beautifully but I
can tell you if I didn't put this in
with that little bit of heat from the
denail uh this would be shooting all
over the place so this is the super
silver haze gift from
Horatio much appreciated brother always
uh I always know when Horatio passes
something my way that it's gone through
it's he won't just give something that's
not great great he seems to always give
his best and uh it's one of the things
you got to love about the guy anyone
that gives their best you have to have
an appreciation for AKA
compassions uh the soil grown and of
course all the uh people many many years
before that that were probably pressing
hash and old
Barnes and uh you
know squeezing oil out of these giant
you know tonnages of hash I'm sure that
was considered uh quite a special treat
so super silver haze out of the sick
Mothership
combo definitely has a very strong
sativa taste right off the bat very
uh like spicy and
exotic more towards you know the sandal
woods and less towards the sweets and
the and the flavorful uh fruity ones
really appreciate
that and uh yeah we've got our piece
cooled here trying to remember where we
were for a second I was like did we
press that or did we press not press
that I'm going to leave these other two
little chunks of
nugs uh to go with the chemo here on the
side and get back to collecting uh of
this
resin which has now uh been cooling for
a bit here
oops got all baked you can see that it's
really quite nice right there and I bet
you I could peel this
yeah look at that
not too
shabby you really start to learn the
resin when you start to get involved
with it and play around with it and uh
it's another thing about rosin that I
really appreciate that it's uh it's
really educational for people to
understand when they say oh I put a butt
in and I didn't get anything you know
was it the wrong temperature was it the
wrong pressure you know possibly but a
lot of times it's not going to be the
wrong pressure or the wrong temperature
what it's going to be is the wrong bud
and for people to be able to be told
that or see that for themselves without
taking it as like an affront or an
assault on their own personal ego but
allowing them to swallow that and say
you know what just find better and
knowing the difference when you find the
better it's quite something with the
buds to just press a single Bud
sometimes a bud will literally squeeze
out four four to five times more resin
than another bud and uh that says a lot
about the genetics and the grower and
what was used and and all of those sort
of variables so there's a nice little
Clump we got there out of our first
first
batch collect that on there get rid of
those little guys put that back on the
collection plate
see what we got
here let's see what we
got all right that's 8 so guaranteed
there's more to be had uh we'll squeeze
this out a couple more times and if you
guys have any questions about the Press
um I urge you you know I I do know some
things but definitely hit up denil they
are the guys uh - nail.com uh you can
hit up Stevie you can hit up Willie you
can hit up Brian they're all great guys
over there and they're definitely into
customer service and helping and you
know keeping the dialogue going so
they're good that way we got a little
bit more squeezed out
there definitely not a ton it seems like
with myself I get about
80% in my first squeeze but then uh you
know that last 20% or even sometimes
less than
20% the quality of it looks exactly the
same as the First Quality it doesn't
look any less quality and it would be
interesting to find out about where in
the resin head the oils and the
cannaboids are existing and which ones
squeeze out first and if they always
squeeze out you know the same quality
each time because it's all the same oil
in the sack or if the the quality that
goes out first is better than the
quality that comes out last or vice
versa uh these are things that really
interest me and I I I think that we'll
find answers to these things in the
future as more and more people play and
I really I really could see licensed
producers and the bigger companies
starting to figure out that this is an
amazing alternative to uh Hydro uh
carbon extraction particularly the um
butane hydrocarbon extraction uh as
myself I don't have a problem with the
delemon one it seems like a pretty solid
way to uh produce an incredible quality
medicine without the worry of of course
burning or blowing yourself up very
badly so rosin is definitely going to
take a hits uh on butane it's it's going
to it's it's hit hard and it's great
because it's who who wins in the end are
the people that are no longer inhaling
uh non-quality product now are there
going to be problems with Rosen
absolutely we've already talked about
this people using bad pressing screens
people using too much heat too much
pressure pressure uh people passing uh
chemical uh molecules onto the actual
oil through the transference of heat
it's definitely something we're going to
have to pay attention to and not act
like it's the end all be all uh I'm
always going to have a place in my heart
for full melt wet washes and full melt
dry sifts that's just the way it is uh
it'll always be like that and uh this is
just one more thing to fill the quiver
uh of solventless quiver so yeah we've
got about a gram of oil here what did we
put in we put 3 G in so yeah this one
was the one that was 40 that I brought
up to
45% by squeezing like many times so we
will
squeeze
until she's no longer
giving anyway so that is rosin in a
nutshell that is the denail rosin uh
press love the fact that they've got the
two digital controllers to control each
plate you can keep the temperatures
accurate it's got a decent amount of
pressure here that you can produce more
if you're interested by just simply
turning that plate around and uh as you
can see the ease of use uh it's hard to
deny uh it's definitely a lot easier
than sitting around with a hair
straightener I think uh I guess I'll
probably laugh at myself one day for how
long I did the hair straightener and I
never even got a big hair straightener I
had the tiny little one that was absurd
and ridiculous and I might just take
that hair straightener put it into here
and press that hair straightener just to
get rid of it once and for
all all right collect the last little
bits of
this like I said if you guys got any
questions throw them in the comment
section I'll try my best to answer them
uh if they are a question that I need to
forward you onto dmail uh don't take it
personally I'm not trying to pass the
buck I just know that they'll answer the
question way better than me my um
experience with this so far is very
limited I just got my unit the other day
as did uh soil grown you can check his
Instagram at soil grown and uh yeah
check us out squishing buds squishing
hash and uh this is the first of many
videos that you're going to see I'm
going to be making water hash in the
near future as I have quite a bit of
material saved up in my freezer and dry
sift we're probably not going to see
unfortunately uh until the weather cools
off a little bit and it has been very
very warm uh here for the last uh oh
jeez I don't know three months it's been
a warm one let's just
say all right get that up to
1.1 G so we've got uh what did we have
three Gams we're just above 33% right
now about
36 and what I'm guessing is cuz I did it
the other day if I just continue to put
it in the press and press it down uh now
the nice thing about the large large one
which we'll talk about in the next video
is that you can really put a big amount
with a big giant piece of pressing
screen just go to town and literally I'm
going to go for maybe like a 30 G like
an ounce of bubble press and see uh see
how that turns out you can hear it
sizzling a mild Sizzle will do you don't
need to cook it but uh it's a good idea
when you hear a little bit of that
Sizzle cuz you know that it's
traveling it is TR traveling out of the
hash and it just keeps uh you know like
I
said returning now smaller amounts each
time but this is definitely more than
like right there is a dab that I just
collected and that's another
dab know here's here's another dab right
there
collected and maybe another one here and
one last one all along the bottom here
so four or five dabs collected uh or
like I said if you're you know insane
and just love to hit monster monster
dabs then this is one dab or half a dab
you know it all depends on how you look
at it uh I think of it in a medicinal
aspect as something that uh is going to
give relief to people and uh some people
need more and some people need less and
I respect
that all right this will be the last
press that we do on this love the ease
of use um I can't say enough about it
really pressing buds pressing different
types of hash surrounded in rosin and
super happy about it go get yours at
dna.com pre-orders 350 bucks they are
going to get more expensive probably 400
450 I have no idea but uh they're
basically selling them for less than you
can get a t-shirt press for and they've
put more work into them so it's uh it's
pretty cool they've done a great job I
appreciate what you guys are doing as
always and uh still squeezing out rosin
from this bubble I think uh this last
one might be a hit what do you say take
it take us out with a
hit these are the uh breeder Steve
strings so yeah at first when you try to
collect them just at first they'll be a
little bit too liquefied and they they
they just want to smear but you give it
just a few seconds in the open area and
quickly uh they start to harden and you
get that more Snappy feel and if I leave
it even longer what'll happen is as I
hit it with the tool it'll literally
flick the hash away so thanks for
watching Bubble man's world guys uh I
will have all these links and different
things that we discussed uh in the
comment section uh if you haven't
subscribed please do if you haven't
liked the video uh well if you don't
like the video then don't like the video
but if you did like the video it doesn't
hurt to give us a little thumbs up there
and we appreciate that and uh thank you
all for your continued support bubble on
[Music]
hey Tim
feel
[Music]
me one manr man
real keeps me
going the purpose after the weed that to
the mind
purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose after weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of dying
we have been traveling to kingst about
20 M hours sing on like the clock fresh
vegetation with trees and with flowers
[Music]
off me one Bigg and if
bigger
[Music]
pass I make
pass pass pass and
[Music]
then PA that pause that
now after we keeps me
going the purpose of the we that to the
mind purose after we