hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and today I'm here to talk to you a
little bit about one of my favorite
tools that I use on a regular basis you
guys see me traveling all over the world
with uh this tool and although most of
you are probably thinking it's the
mothership it's actually the denail that
I wanted to talk to you about today so
this is my 2.0 from the from the good
Folks at denail Stevie Hughes and Brian
schroer and I've been working with this
company for maybe a little bit less than
a year now I'm relatively new to the
whole dabbing scene and um I got turned
on first via the sublimator and quickly
found that uh the ease and the wonderful
just hit that you get from a from an
electronic nail in particular the denail
because that's the company that I ended
up going with after doing my
research I found that uh the guys at
denail are really pioneering and moving
things forward they're not just looking
at uh copying uh an existing company
that's out there but they've done a lot
of basically they did a lot of what I
did as as bubble bags and bubble man
when I first came out I was as you know
I was not the first uh bubble uh bag or
Bag company to release the water
extraction process there was one other
company before myself and uh that was a
two bag system and I feel that denil has
really done um I guess its customer base
a service much the way Bubble Bags has
done uh its customer base a service cuz
as you remember in the beginning Bubble
Bags was a two bag kit quickly became a
3 four 5 six 7even and an eight bag kit
and that increased the quality of the
product and it increased the quality of
the final product that the customer was
able to get so so I was going to take
you through a few things that Dil sent
me recently they've been sending me so
much stuff and I haven't really made a
perfect video just for them so I wanted
to I guess first go over the old uh
titanium nail uh that they have they've
got a two-piece nail here I do believe
it's just a two-piece yeah the bottom
part does not screw off on this one so
it's a 144 no matter what and then uh
the old style of element is right here
and that's how you attach that
that so this is the old thae nail a 144
and this was the one that I used uh with
denail for for anytime that my quartz
Banger wasn't working which I have on
here right now a pooking bee it is a
little bit dirty sorry that it's not a
little bit cleaner but that's the
pooking bee and that's the 20 mil coil
so the the bowl is a little bit bigger
than say the 16 which you can see right
here comparably they are quite a bit of
a different size one fits the ceramic
disc as well as the um Sapphire disc a
lot better and that would be this one
and this is the one that we're going to
do the sapphire hits on I will talk a
little bit about this pooking bee quartz
really like this this was my savior in
Amsterdam this year because I pooched my
20 mil cord I pooched my 20 mil cord and
I was forced to use um a smaller cord
which I'm not even sure if I have that
particular cord present here oh here it
is right here so this is the new
uh Kevlar wrapped whips that Dil are are
selling now and you can see that this
particular um coil is a 16 so it fits
that bowl perfectly and in fact it also
fits the new titanium nail so let me
show you a little bit about what these
guys have done they've made it a
wonderful that you can screw off the
part this is the 14th that fits into my
bowl you can screw this off and you can
get it in either 18 or 14 so you don't
have to replace your whole nail now the
nail is a little bit different in the
sense that the coil is going to go
around the top of the nail much like the
quartz bangers and they've offset the
hole to the side and it's quite a deep
dish so you can really fill that up if
you're looking to take monster rips I
also like the way they've allowed it to
split in half and if you want to collect
um some of that condensed reclaim um
this is really wonderful stuff for
putting on skin ailments this is great
stuff for removing moles or putting on
scars anything that you've got on your
skin that you're kind of not digging the
oil that condenses in these nails is
really an effective medicine for those
exterior skin problems you could also
use it to cook into metes and Etc but I
just personally use it on um different
skin things that I have I actually
removed a mole from my neck using this
very
thing so let me just get to the next
part here I've got a couple of other
quartz bangers from puking be these are
dirty ones they're both direct injection
so this one's obviously a slide that
just fits into the bowl and this one's
an actual you know goes on proper you've
seen me use this before um uh on the
Dosa from
Flav so um I've also got the new dog
housee from uh denil which is the um
quartz Banger uh all pooking be quartz
with a quartz Dabber with a quartz
um um cap cap so a carb cap so while you
drop your your HIIT into there you cap
the hole as well unfortunately I broke
this one in Amsterdam but uh how it
works uh simply put is you use the coil
it goes around like that and then it had
um it had a u on it that went around and
dipped into the piece some of you may or
may not have seen that on the channel
earlier but today what I wanted to
really talk about was the new denail
inserts these Sapphire inserts are
absolutely killer I'm not joking um the
ceramic was not even comparable they
sent me both their black ceramic and
their white ceramic a variety of white
Ceramics as denil was looking to get the
best possible ceramic that they that
they could get and on a side note um
speaking of ceramic Hive has a ceramic
bowl that now denil is working with so
I'm really happy to see Hive and denail
working together to produce the utmost
quality of ceramic because as you know
when we heat these things up if we're
using cheaper materials there's going to
be off gassing and there's going to be
things that we don't want to bring into
our
lungs so without further Ado I guess
right off the bat I'm going to take just
a straight rip I got some uh real nice
Astro Boy melty bubble here that I've
had curing for months so we'll just do a
little quick rip of the Astro Boy
and yes I'm using a hive ceramic carb
cap Dash
Dabber great little tool I picked up in
Amsterdam as well I picked up a highly
educated task Rock uh gift from my good
buddy Buddha from so thank you so much
Alex really nice kick down and I have
using it quite a bit but it is in my
other bag and that's why it's not here
God The Taste on that asra boy is candy
likee so we're going to open one of
these ceramic uh sorry
Sapphire the sapphire inserts and one of
the things that I really love about the
sapphire insert is that it just hits so
smoothly it's it's it breathes a
different way than the ceramic that I've
hit so far I find that when it's on the
sapphire that it's seems to give me more
of a hit like as if it was on a screen
that wasn't plugged as opposed to being
on a screen that was very plugged up
with carbon and and Ash I just don't get
the same pull and same taste but the
sapphire I'll tell you it has really
opened my mind to enjoying hitting bowls
with the insert now originally these
yeah these inserts were originally
designed to go inside um I guess I guess
they were origin designed to go inside
this kind of a nail my nail of course is
a special nail um let me see this one
might have it yes this
one uh originally when they made me my
titanium nail I asked them to shave down
the middle piece so you can see in this
one it's been shaved down and because it
got shaved down the the sapphire piece
does not fit and funny enough that's why
I started placing my sapphires on top
and I guess a lot of people are doing
this now uh it it wasn't really a tech
as much as it was a mistake and Brian
laughed quite loud that's how it was
supposed to fit this is how these are
supposed to fit on uh your nail they go
right inside however I never hit them
like that personally I love the idea of
placing it on top of of of a quartz and
then allowing the the viewer to see the
hit melting and and bubbling away so
without further Ado why don't we do that
why don't we throw one of these ceramic
stacks on top of the Dil and give you
guys a little
[Music]
show we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do with purpose
of
dying well I imagine the there be some
cops setting
up upon your scene inter in my that and
behind your me and my
te all right so that was the tastiest of
rips that was the CBD Renee that first
rip on the sapphire insert I can't even
begin to explain to you the level of
taste that is coming off of that not
your standard Renee or your standard
canonic but a mixture of the two Fruity
Fruity goodness no doubt about it very
impressed and that was uh Matt Baron
from the house of the great Gardener who
crossed a canonic with a Renee to come
up with his CBD Renee really delicious
stuff um I have very very very little of
it left but uh there's what it looks
like and this is just dry sift that's
been cleaned to 99% heads or
so so next up what we're going to hit is
we're going to hit some of d42 K dry
sift this is OG Kush he gave this to me
probably a year ago now close to a year
ago because I believe I went up there in
December to visit him last time and
that's when he gave me this it's in one
of the 420 jars so it's one of those
glass light proof jars and I'll tell you
this is some greasy greasy [ __ ] I'm not
sure if it's going to allow the camera
camera to grab on but you know what why
don't we show you a little bit of a
better light over here all right so here
is the d420 k6 see if I can get you guys
in a little bit to see how this stuff
just absolutely G right
out dry
SI no wet washing on this particular red
is not here to trick the
M it is only here to do
pury
[Music]
stuff
right well wow that d420 K sift was
explosive I'm sure you guys saw it on
the sapphire insert the way it seemed to
grease from the outside out just the way
the water almost water-like substance
seemed to just release and melt puddling
across that Sapphire insert I'll tell
you I was excited as I saw it I got to
take a really nice hit very strong still
a year later well cured in the jar I
haven't been keeping it in anything
other than room temperature I've lost
this thing probably 10 times since he
gave it to me it's the only reason I
have some left so that was a beautiful
taste I think what we're going to finish
it off with denail style is some well
I've got the Astro Boy dry sift and I've
got the sweet skunk so I mean let's
finish it off with sweet skunk I got a
little bit of the sift right here
beautiful beautiful stuff super melty I
had this at the Cannabis Cup with me and
it was holding its own amongst
everything that I saw um I saw some
beautiful hashes from the likes of the
the Tricom heavy extracts guys the melts
um Tony had some amazing turpine added
stuff the turp Melt um Ramone who won
first at Legends had some incredible dry
sift um a few other friends um brought
really nice dry sift and some other nice
wet washes that I saw while I was there
in including uh archive Fletch brought
some nice stuff from Cuban grower and uh
Johnny B had some stuff from Horatio all
in all the dry sift was lovely and I was
happy to say that the sweet skunk as
clean as it was held its own with all of
them so that's what we're going to
finish this video off with if you guys
have any questions about Den Nails
please get in touch with me whether it's
uh in regards to the quartz Bowls the
new tie Bowls the whips the units all
the different levels I'm hoping on
having my own bubble man Edition denail
out soon and even without that that I
still of course support the company and
will be selling their regular products
which you can check out at Fresh
heads.com that's two hes one at the end
of fresh and one at the start of hedes
one word fresh hedes so yeah let's
finish it off with a sweet skunk Bowl
[Music]
guys is not here to trick
the it is only here to do its purpose of
time gja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do it purpose of
ding been tring to
kingon give me
one well that was absolutely delicious
the sweet skunk is one of my favorites
it's got this fruity slightly sweet
taste but really what it's got is an
overwhelming exotic sativa Haze taste
that you get on the exhale as well as
when you smell it in the air absolute
pleasure I definitely urge you if you
can find the sweet skunk in its pure
form not the island sweet skunk uh
that's a good second if you can find it
only but if you can find the sweet skunk
it is a strain worth having in your
garden so I'm going to leave you guys at
that I hope that you enjoyed my little
uh review of the denail and some of the
tools that they're uh pioneering along
with their Sapphire inserts uh and their
quartz poing bee bowls and their
different whips um I just uh I'm really
happy to support those guys and I think
they're what they're doing is a great
job releasing such great products to the
people if you have have an interest in a
denail product you can give us a call at
1866 melting uh and talk to us about the
product if you have questions or you can
go right onto our website at bubble
bag.com
and uh you can purchase yourself a dil I
think we have the 2. O's right now the
highest level of denail available but we
will be getting the mid and uh lower
level which is the 250 to the $500 model
and those will be available on fresh
headies and bubble bag.com
sooner than later so thanks for watching
guys I hope you enjoyed the video and uh
we'll see you next time on Bubble man's
world thanks for watching