[Music]
full
yeah he's Mike you ready to go yeah
ready to go ready to go all right bubble
man's world I'm just here with uh the
originator uh as many know is soil grown
what's up guys Phil here how you
doing just uh hanging out in this hot
day you know High Times Cannabis Cup
better than rain yeah a lot better than
the rain but uh it's going to get a lot
better once it starts to cool down you
know yeah so we were talking on hash
church about uh how many events they
were having in a row
and now doesn't I feel doesn't it feel
better to just kind of have like all
right there's a SoCal and a North Cow
just two a year oh oh most definitely
yeah it's just like it just like it gets
watered down having it so often you know
people are going to them every week and
it just starts to burn it out I feel
like it becomes more of a reward getting
getting to go to these things you know
every so often like you look forward to
it you know it allows us to network uh
and it's almost like a little Retreat
like if you do it the right way which
this time was good there was many days
here um you know you get three days and
then you kind of get to you get to
interact with a lot of patients and then
different different people in your
industry by Third Day which is today
it's like I'm kind of going around and
being able to kick it with people oh I
agree 100% dude uh having like the
two-day events or the one day events
they're cool and all it's just you know
you get so stuck at the booth on those
those those first days the first day one
and two and it's just like you don't
really get a network or or meet the
people that you were looking for you
wanted to meet so that third day it's uh
it's it's it's important I feel like you
know it's it's great for that part of
the event the networking this is my
favorite day cuz I get to sample
everything yeah so a lot of people also
um don't don't know you also make hash
rosin too right correct yeah and water
hash and water hash of course so not
just flower rosin and uh you were
showing off a little bit earlier over
here and so pick out your uh if you had
to give me your best dab of the hash
rosin um or say just of your say resin
category and oil category cuz anything
that's press hash you know would be oil
so give me give me your best hash and
give me your best oil doing some dabs
right on let's do
it let me get the uh let's get the 159
through 73 OG glue bubble hash and then
uh let's do the uh orange cookies OG
glue live RZ and flow RZ and blend so I
like to blend the rosins too you know so
rather than just
uh rather than just having uh you know
flour rosin or live rosin or you know
just one specific strain having the oils
and being able to blend I feel like uh
create you're you're you're basically
able to kind of create your own flavor
in a sense so are you are you actually
mixing the flow rosin and the hash rosin
yes together yes okay so it's like uh I
haven't really played with doing the
live Ros or the hash rosin and the
flower rosin mixes but I mean they work
really well cuz a lot of the times the
hashin talking about this uh the other
day cuz we made a why we call it our
grease is we're taking bubble hash rosin
with tpin and then there's flower rosin
with tpin and they're distinctively two
different totally
different everything from from uh the
texture to the to the you know the
visual to the to the experience 100% and
uh as far as taste too you know that's
cool we're all kind of I was talking
with Frenchie last night too everyone
that's really into you know into their
own into their own like type of making a
pass it's like chefs you know it's like
if I was Italian chef and he was a
friend Chef you know and you and You'
like establish yourself as chefs and
you're kind of creating Your Own Way
exactly it's like an art that's why it's
like an art you know it's because that's
where it's like it's it takes that
creative mind to take the steps to play
with it you know you go out of the box
you try new things rather than following
what you learn and what you what you
think is the best you you explore you
know and that's what's fun about it and
meeting the other people and all the
others that are doing the same thing
it's it's great all right so now that we
know you're making uh Creations what
what' you pick out for me to try orange
cookies is up first so right here we got
some orange cookies this the orange
cookies flow Rin blended with the OG
glue live rosin there's your okay and
explain live rosin to to the audience
what that is exactly what are you what
exactly are you doing that makes that
live R okay so first of all we are not
pressing fresh frozen buds it doesn't
work when you press fresh plant I mean
some people may have some techniques or
tricks to it but as far as like the best
ways and uh the most common way that's
going to end up sticking I would say is
going to be to wash the fresh frozen
into a to a water hash drying it and
then pressing that I mean that's really
that's what live rosin is that's what
live rosin is and really basically fresh
Frozen full milk fresh Frozen full milk
pressed into rosin that's what our
grease is the wash and squash 100%
that's what our grease is
yeah I mean it's as close as live rosin
you can get for the for the rosin side
you know what was that orange cookies
yeah it tasted like an orange soda with
like hints of uh sugar
cookies here Phil this is ready that's
interesting cuz that tastes more like a
a that tastes more like a really clean
hash oil it's a way cool way you combine
that
I felt it to my front of my head like
right away too now we have you try the
OG uh glue that's ice wax yeah that SAA
now I'm going to try the ice wax I
really wish you were here
Marcus but uh somebody's got a host is
that who's on the other end of that
marus Mr Bubble Man somebody's got to
fill in the
rooll I was like he needs somebody to do
bubble man uh like like World Tour here
and he's not in the United States so I
volunteered to be the host to try
everyone's dabs so we got some covering
I'm taking it upon myself to try all the
dabs that he would be trying yeah okay
here's your OG
icex so this one's for you B man OG og
ice wag this one's for the B man buddy
yeah
buddy rocking that soil grown dab oh
yeah it's immediately so much
stronger that's a hash it oh yeah I feel
like the water hash wow definitely has
the
most expansion on the
lungs heavy
High almost a more Full Spectrum
High rather than just like the the flow
R and noticeable is like when you smoke
hash and people think of
chal old school way of smoking hash you
Genera a lot of carbet a lot of smoke
yes so from the flower live ra and
really clean a lot of less a lot of less
smoke so a different way of expanding
the lungs it's almost like a pure way to
hit the collap laries this one hash is
like a little bit more Smokey so it
blows it up and gives you that old
school exp don't need as much smoke but
we're used to taking the same size hit
so now we take that same hit and it hits
us harder cuz we're used to a cleaner
smoke half that size exactly well and
when you're doing oil it's yeah exactly
there's less contamin in it less carbon
and I feel like that's why and most
people like that are out there what I
like to do is when I heat my quartz or
silicone carbine or have it on a my uh
nail or something the most important
thing is that when you're anytime you're
dabbing full Mo you press it out I
always bring it into where the heat
source is test the side of whatever
element dish that you're using and if it
starts to nicely melt and bubble right
there then you know the temperature is
right to go ahead and drop it and let it
fall into the rest of the dish if you
see any kind of burn or a little
Browning sorry that's an indication to
pull back and wait and wait 15 seconds
or more and then try it again and once
it hits the side of that dish um and it
starts to Bubble then you know you have
the right and that's something I'll do
often times when I'm like I'm about to
do a dab and I forget like the time or
how long I was counting I'm like oh I'll
give it a little tap and it kind of
gives you an idea like oh you see that
little tap it just stays nice and clear
oil rather than charring so that's why I
think that's why I think people don't
understand that or appreciate for first
run 30 second or one minute agitation
runs getting the first most beautiful uh
array of tricomes is that first shaking
of the tree to get those tricomes in one
uh first wash right and then you get
that you're looking for this five or six
star so when you get that you're getting
these like volumptuous like on a macro
level grapes these perfectly preserved
heads that are fitting a certain screen
size on the first agitation and it's a
delicacy and it's expensive and you got
to take smaller dabs pressed out thin
and you have to be able to do that dab
test with any kind of heat source so
that way you can actually have this
medicine last a lot longer and
appreciate it better yeah most and those
short runs you know you're you're
capturing those heads that dissolve the
fastest that's why you want to get those
and short quick
runs I feel like no I feel like that's
how you're going to capture a lot of
those tpin you know especially in the
water has yeah I was going to say I
really appreciate the way that you're
also looking at tpin uh and how you're
preserving them in your process whether
we're using Sash and a lot of the times
when people you know the collaboration
really that we're doing is we're using
the sasquash V1 and the V2 with a
California air now that's uh in a
complete but it's in a silence box oh no
[ __ ] and it has a flow adapter so every
time you hit it keeps that 80 on the
pedal and it kind of hits the whole time
and there's no sound and so that allows
us to control the plate temps you could
always shut the f top one off or keep it
to 100 and the other one at 180 so even
even with flower rosin to simulate the
effect of the V1 cuz there's certain
things that I like about the V1
especially with hash is that colder
plate on top sometimes it down temping
allows it to do something different than
having a constant heat you that's
awesome dude and you see that's like
that's the experimentation with like
each individual artist themselves you
know they decide to go well I'm going to
try this instead of just sticking to the
same and that's what's beautiful about
it and that's where we stumble upon
these new new textures and just new new
versions of the oil and it's just it
that's what's great about this dude most
definitely yeah so I'm excited for uh
what's to come with you you got a really
strong fam and uh the stash squash is
doing good we use it for piranha we use
it for uh bubbleman Blue River
collaborations um I thoroughly enjoy it
I stand by the product I you know when
you're pushing pounds and pressing
pounds all day long over and over and
over and over that's when you find out
if you have something that works yeah
most definitely dude it's built to allow
us to be artist it's the Beast dude it's
S I mean it's for production it's for
boutique it's for however you want with
this machine you can manipulate it it's
full control if you want to press water
hash and you need to press very very
slow I mean you can lower the PSI on
your compressor yeah and and you can
have full control of the speed as well
as the temperatures and and you know
it's uh as well as the strength of it so
so whatever you want to press if you
want to throw in in a quarter pound and
you want to go crazy you can do so but
you know that's a whole another that's a
whole
another ball game you know you have
production level and you have more of a
connoisseur level yeah we call it
artisanal or Boutique cuz we always do
things and we finally were able to get
some of our stuff out and like we got 50
gr of a Jack Frost we were jumping up
and down it's 100 half grams just
because trying to get that kind of
quality into production is really hard
but if we didn't have sasquash and a
team and kind of this in for the last
year we wouldn't be able to start
getting into that so it's hard sometimes
when you're like an artist and you uh
get stumbled upon with your tools you
know so I have to give my hats off to
like using the right tools makes it a
lot easier to be able to develop these
different type of new techniques as well
now I think tools are an important part
of the trade having proper tools having
the right resources allows you to have
an advantage in this uh this part of the
industry yeah and then finally the most
important part is is the quality of the
herb so 100% everyone's like oh I got
this like trim with like Smalls can you
press this out let me know same thing
with turps it's like well I mean I
really want to take the oranges from the
tree when they're ripe and perfect big
oranges not these little baby ones or
not the ones that got rotten and fell to
the ground or not just the
peels you know so you're only as good as
the farmer so like you got the tools
down you got the skills down and if
somebody doesn't give you good FL
flowers there's nothing you can do about
it that's a whole another part of the
game is being a a turp hunter you know
you got to find that quality and a lot
of people uh claim to to have it and do
it but you know it's it's really it's
it's
really not that easy to find you really
got to look around and and you got to
look past all the [ __ ] and all the
hype cuz there is a lot of hype now when
I talk to Farmers you're like so what
did it test what's the microbes what's
the pesticides oh I didn't test that
you're like all right well when you do
let me know give me all the reports test
a couple different batches of it and
those are really that's like super
important especially when you're dealing
with this this is I look at this as a as
a tester as well it's like give me an
ounce of your material if youve passed
all of your pesticides and microbes and
everything like cool give me an ounce of
your material if I press it out and it's
like 5% something's wrong with the resin
it's not us it's not the machine and you
know what and I don't always blame the
grower because there's a lot of times
where for instance this uh the Sunny D I
mean it only put out 10% but the the
other strains I got from the grower I
mean I I hit as far as like 25% you know
so it's like there's phenomenal strains
but some strains just don't produce the
oil or the heads just don't feel they
just don't feel like the others you know
so yeah they could be um when you look
at sometimes there's uh different types
of varieties where there's stocks that
line up in perfect grids and they're
spaced with bigger heads and then
there's stocks that line up very tightly
and take up every space with tiny little
heads and when you go to wash resin uh
it's very hard cuz it'd be like a lemon
tree that was solid full of lemons on
the outside that made it harder for them
to move okay and so these little tiny
heads can come off like almost like
harder raisins right and when you get
into something like this I found the
moisture content the time the length the
heat you could get pretty good at trying
to get as what what you can out of it
but it is like a fruit that sometimes
doesn't want to be squished and so you
have to find different ways and uses of
those varieties um or or they get phased
out from that's it if if you're if
you're working for concentrates and it's
not working for you and that's what you
do okay but if you do it for flowers
sometimes those flowers are very
enjoyable just cuz they don't produce as
much oil so what was in the orange soda
cuz it tasted like like an orange zesty
soda so that was a orange cookies uh
flow rosin blended with the OG glue live
rosin OG glue live rosin okay yeah that
was good
well I appreciate uh hanging out and
everything did you do did you enter
anything into the I didn't n it was
really short notice like I knew this was
coming but I wasn't sure whether or not
I was going to be here been real busy
with like a lot of the other projects so
uh I kind of scr to get stuff ready for
this this was like a last minute thing
staying up till late in the morning
barely sleeping barely eating knocking
it out just to be here you know but
uh definitely I'm going to be entering
in some of these events this year
well much respect as always um and
appreciate it yeah dude great talking to
you