[Music]
full
so this is some drive that's been out in
the sun for like two days it's been hot
as [ __ ] and it's still nice and glittery
oh wow yeah so the voice that you're
hearing could only be one man yeah who
that the one and
onlyest finest that's right grower
that's right so we just left sasquash
and he showed us some cool rosin but you
know I feel wrly there's only one person
in the game that's doing like really
when you talk about hashish and you talk
about resin I mean this is what
99% looks like it's just perfect little
heads they look like little Bubbles and
this has been in the Sun for a while and
that little gooiness is just the the
heads kind of melting and and becoming
like
uh part of this uh process where the
heads are breaking down and the tpin and
everything are coming together for the
first time uh but the preservation for
that to be for hours is incredible I
actually uh have bought three G myself
yeah in the street we call that
greasy like the diamonds so we these
have been out in the sun for 2 days it's
been really hot I the surface of this is
right here like 100° or something um
it's been out in display all of this
hash right here is vacuum dried not
freeze dried
it's a technique that I've been using
since I started making hash uh it's
similar to freeze drying where I use a
backing pump to pull a pressure and I
have a cold trap in line to capture the
Ice uh but it's a lot more I don't know
cheaper you can get a 1.9 AI oven for
like 700 bucks and a good vacuum pump
put two or three in line and you can dry
a lot of hash for day so these here we
put them out uh have you ever taken a
really turpy uh rosin and put that under
vacuum seen what that does I've done
that before if you yeah that's why I
don't rosin my or vacuum my rosin more
so what I do with these rosins here I
press them at a temperature where they
already start to nucleate and because
it's five star it I don't know I almost
think it's because I'm in Oregon as well
in my cold room it's just a natural
higher humidity when you press it it
will come out uh shatter sappy and then
have some nucleation and what I use is
just a little bit of heat and just a lot
of whipping to agitate the oil I'll
stick it in the back and the back will
be I don't know 110 degre or so it's
already waxing up by itself pretty hard
and uh I'll pull it back at like 15 and
shut off the valve just to Puff it up
and what happens is all those little
bubbles they end up waxing yeah and they
get they gave it like a fat texture but
because I don't pull a long back it's
like the shortest part of my process it
doesn't lose a lot of but yo you don't
know how many times I've had
loudes and I [ __ ] it up yeah without a
c trap straight going into like a vacuum
po well when I made the uh vitamin CBD
oil in the emerald cup when I first came
out to California I had uh you know 30%
tpine uh content it was all this crazy
unbelievable flour oil and flow rosin
and I had so much of it I actually put
that under vac like what you just said
and tried that and it white muffined and
I was like and I shut it off and it like
left in this like perfect white like
muffin you know cuz there's so much tury
stuff like that and it just no it just
stayed like that and then what happened
was I let that stay for like 12 hours
just in its place and I slowly
decompressed it and when it came back it
was like this crazy consistency that was
um like the solventless sa that's where
we kind of got that from um and then
it's funny cuz I I was trying to now do
that without um doing that cuz like you
said if you go too far everything's gone
yeah well with cold traps you can always
re it but I try to to preserve it as
long as I can you know so all this resin
here besides the collaboration with the
dryft and the rosin was all grown by my
wife indoors from our first crop in
Oregon and um washed my meat I was happy
it was the first time I've washed in
months oh that's why you have such uh
the motherload here yeah yeah it was
like you came out you're like you know I
haven't watched any resin in a while I'm
going in well the the thing with
California is that it it cost a lot of
money to build a cold lab to have a cool
bu the proper size AC electricity and
[ __ ] like you have to be pretty die hard
about making hash and a lot of cats like
with this type of temperature they can't
really wash you know they're like winter
washers but I have a pretty good lab I
can wash whenever hottest days of the
year and I take advantage of it man I
come out here and I try to offer the
fire to people that would normally buy
it at Shops give them direct wholesale
price and bring us much as I can so I
can have a good selection yeah you get a
lot of good feedback we a lot of people
that came through patience that came
through they were like really excited as
as I was uh to grab you know different
different types of sift that you have um
there's a lot of people even in the sift
world where I like oh I got 99 right and
there's like so many people that claim I
got 99.99 it's like you just take a
macro camera now I have a little
keychain that does 20 on my iPhone you
just go and look at it you're like if
you see any contaminants you're like you
don't you're not even close like 85 to
like 90 you but you could taste it you
can taste it yeah so when I first
started making dry SI I never had like a
scope so I would like I remember the
first time I would get like cleaner and
cleaner and cleaner the color of the
hash would change and stuff it got to a
point where it would melt just like
water hash and any contaminant or stocks
or things like that I like acquired like
like a taste for it you know so in my
process it's a pretty stony one you like
make hash and test daab and uh you get
pretty high in the process but you find
out you know you got a quality
controller well the first time I did get
a scope it was beautiful what I saw for
sure recently I went to uh to a buddy's
house and he had like one of those uh I
don't know if it's an electron
microscope or whatever it is it's like
some crazy microscope and he put the
hash on there he was super psyched right
and what he saw just blew his mind and I
looked at it it was blown up no just all
heads just
Bo oh mean it took some of yours yeah oh
put it okay okay all head looks like
eggs yeah yeah that's what it should
look like when it looks like beautiful
little captured eggs everywhere like
soft eggs you're just
like it's a good type of hash to make
but that's still your proprietary type
of tent right yeah you know I just try
to keep it lowkey cuz when I um won my
first Cannabis Cup I really came up out
of just hard work you know didn't really
know anybody in the game doing my own
thing but a lot you guys Denver yeah and
I were you were you in Seattle in
Seattle I saw you in Seattle too so um
not a lot a lot of fake people came on
through and stuff and you know and it
made it kind of sour to me and I'm like
I don't know I'm like a private person
so I taught a lot of my family and my
close friends like people that really
love me they know how to do Cub Tech but
other than that I just like to share the
joy adive to people and I give them a
lot of tips like people that are often
coming in the game if I there's a screen
that they can use it to like you know
improve their quality by a lot or a
drying process a curing process I almost
gave it my all my techniques out in
pieces and parts you know yeah I'd say
the same thing when everyone's like
talking about tures I'm like well I mean
the industry is Cutthroat you know and
like when you work really hard and you
do have a family around you you kind of
do have to hold on to what you can to be
able to survive first you know so you
don't get swallowed up so people have to
respect that part in the in the
particular game and it's Cutthroat right
now and uh I do the same thing with with
with uh the tpin it becomes a little
circle and then try to you know I can
imagine when you first started making
tpping a lot of people came up to you
right yeah that's the type of [ __ ] I
don't like I like I like real people you
know so I [ __ ] with you well I
appreciate it man thanks a lot H yeah
and good luck thank uh up there today it
looks like we're in the same category so
I'll feel I'll feel honored if I could
take second to it uh cuz it's like
perfection in hashes I've taken second
to you before man either way one of or
another it's nice to be on the podium
yeah right yeah it is and it almost
feels like these these type of events AR
going to last forever no that's just so
beautiful though it really is feel free
to take it out of the container if you
like well let's uh let's dab it real
quick before these Awards which one
would you like that one yeah let's do it
let's do your cookies and
[Applause]
cream put
my sc's out of
Washington and X1 Best Booth in Michigan
giving off free Dabs out of the scars
and three first place glass if you're at
a connoisseur level at this you probably
have something really good to complement
that many huge yeah there's as many
Tricom heads in this as smoking a fat
blood except he's about to smoke it all
in one dab one dab yeah all right here
we go ready
wow it's so a f
[Music]
St was it hot or was it
good so
good oh cuz you know like that much
smoke should have like just made me
cough
horribly was super smooth for sift it
was probably like a/ quar gram it was
F definitely I would say a quarter gr
quarter gram of Sith to the
Head wo
thanks for doing that and uh good luck
on stage today hope you see I hope to
see you up there you definitely earned
it I mean cookies and
cream so good have you tried the water
house no for another D let's do
it this job doesn't
[Applause]
suck Bubble
Man we've got you we've got you covered
don't worry we're dab we're 5 minutes
away from uh the award
starting yeah let's do the dab
though this one will be quick now that
the rig
is
damn God
damn it's been getting
CED look at those little
heads reminds you of per perfect
sand passion a beautiful thing look at
that when it's stable damn it reminds me
a lot of oil wish I had a piece of
parchment you want a big dab again uh
not as
big see if I can get there go all right
well he's like you want a big dab again
I was like not as big he's like all
right well let me give it to you bigger
you ready yeah
this Micron is the same as the dry SI
that you just smoke but translated you
know from LPI to
[Applause]
[Music]
Micron did you enter that
too wow
that's incredible it's a good it's a
good stream man my boy breathes
fire it's like just the essence and
light sweetness of a cookie in that
cream it's like a standard like when you
eat ice cream if that's like a base to
everything yeah and it's just for the
quality it has a very high yield and
it's hard to find that you know in hash
it's a one of a kind uh cross for
sure oh well my brother I'll see you
over there if we're that close