[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh I'm here today with a new product
from denil that's actually a new old
product um these guys sent me one of
these it's got to 6 months to a year ago
and it was one of my favorite uh nails
or you know dab tools if you will that
I've ever hit and I think it has a lot
to do with the fact uh first of all what
I'm talking about is the Deep uh or not
the Deep the dog dish the dogghouse dish
so this is the dogghouse dish here I'll
give you guys a little closeup on it so
you can kind of get an idea that's
that's what she looks like fits a 20
mil coil and it's at a 45° angle this
time last time it went all the way down
it was about like a 180 uh so it sits at
a different angle in the pipe which is
totally okay no problem and I'll show
you it also came with a cool little
pickaxe little beagle was having a bad
day apparently that day and he decided
he would make a a pickaxe and the
pickaxe of course is the Dabber and the
carb it goes right in there and carbs
that
up so today I've got a few p pieces on
the table uh I've got my Dil all set up
I believe it's about
266 de right now and so that's as simple
as that let's go for an egg hit
first let that drop down nice at the
angle you can see it's just the side
opens perfectly for a real nice hit now
the reason I think that this unit is so
nice and why it hits a little bit
differently from most everything else is
everything else I've hit from
denail is open the whole top is open or
you know almost always the whole top
yeah I've got this hooked up to my fab
egg and basically I just wanted to take
you guys through a little rip uh I've
got three different rips here I've got
some really nice Dry St from d420 K this
is the last of the last that I found
from a gift he gave me ages ago took
some macro photographs of this and it
just looks surreal the way it pressed
out in the parchment paper uh I've got
some really nice bubble hash here
um the flavor on the dry sift is OG Kush
uh the flavor on the bubble hash lo and
behold is OG cush um I'm taking one tiny
little dab of
Horatio's uh LH and I can't tell you
what the strain is uh with this
particular batch but I've just got a
tiny tiny little bit but I thought it
would be cool if we hit some dry sift
some bubble hash uh and some L all
through the deep dish or sorry the dog
housee D also also has another Bowl
called the the deep dish and that's
that's a completely different uh unit
it's open at the top it's not completely
sealed with a little hole in the side so
uh this is the one we're going to be
going through today and I'm just going
to let this get heated up a tiny little
bit it's probably good to go uh oh my
little picket got my little picket in my
pocket here my little
Dabber so let's start we hit that little
bit of L for starters out of the um Fab
egg thanks Curtis of high integrity
glass art and uh yeah this is pretty
interesting you can kind of turn that at
an angle if you want to hit it real nice
and just here we go dog
housing all
right
very tasty nice small rip of the
lho um always always a pleasure uh
hitting that uh this is the distillate
of Horatio so it's really smooth and and
it's just uh fully activated uh I can't
say enough about it it's definitely a
real true medicine uh in regards to
cannabis uh next up we've got uh the
bubble has and the dry sift I think I'm
going to hit the bubs first and hit the
dry sift last the dry just looks so so
darn nice such a nice little
treat see what we can get here this is
just gumming up in the sun here try to
get a nice
substantial substantial uh hit here I've
got wasps Landing all over me if I look
like I'm doing a dance every once in a
while it's because wasps are actually
all over the place uh this summer
they've really uh yellow jackets have
popped everywhere I've killed probably
10 in the last 5 minutes of filming this
episode and I see C3 uh already back for
for more so I might have to pause the
video and go smack some wasp ass around
but hopefully not hopefully I leave them
be they leave me be that's pretty much
easy
enough all
right second rip this time a little bit
more substantial some bubble hash in the
in the dog house let's do
it
the
flavor in the dogghouse is just there's
something going on with the preservation
of the hit uh the way that the Heat
Can't burst off up and out you put the
hit in and you literally have it sealed
uh immediately I'm sure it's more
attuned to hitting with a carb cap where
you put your dab on your carb cap and
then you drop it onto that nail whether
it be quartz or titanium and you get
this really nice sort of different type
of
hit uh based on not allowing that
initial thrust of heat and and reaction
to explode out of the top so I think
there's more to it than just catching
the smoke or the vapor there's also
having that contain and of course that's
why we love carb caps this to me just
seems like you know a brilliant design
because it's basically it's a carb cap
and a Dabber in one and it's a unique
function uh that's a little bit
different from most of the nails like I
say with that full open straight up and
out the way things want to go when they
react on a hot
nail so I guess uh we'll do one more rip
here be nice if this just didn't roll
I'm going to take this and put it in the
torque us one of the nice things about
uh the doghouse dish is that it's really
easy to transfer almost as easy to
transfer as um a drop down it doesn't
get hot you can pull it out pretty
easily and uh yeah goes back in pretty
nice
so and as you can see it can be
left-handed or right-handed depending on
how far you turn the the piece so let's
uh
see if we can't get some of this dry
sift in
there this dry sift is huge I'm going to
really have to shove it into the
hole
yep that's the
one like absolute
candy
wow another thing that I really love
about the dogghouse is when I put a big
rip through it like
that it just it the preservation is like
times 10 I can't even tell you the taste
of how candied
out that that was there was definitely I
would say a little bit of the uh diesel
uh the not the East Coast hour diesel
but the New York City Diesel this s sort
of
oranges almost candy esque mix with um
D's OG Kush and you know what I mean
honestly I found the bowl that he gave
me 11 different kinds in and 11
different flap so I guessed it was OG
Kush it tasted substantially like OG
Kush but uh you know hitting it through
the uh the dogghouse like that there's
something else going on there for
sure and uh it's very enjoyable I took
some lovely macro photographs of the
hash just a few shots to show you guys
uh What uh what I'm dealing with here
and of course I'm going to share those
in the video and otherwise you guys can
check out Dil for all their products uh
they are at
dna.com I will put their website in the
comment section if you haven't liked the
video please give it a like if you
enjoyed it and uh if you're not
subscribed Please Subscribe always
looking to grow the audience and uh get
more people to share this information
with also if you are purchasing this
from denail uh you can use the bubble
man code which is St day melty s a y m e
l t y one word and you can use that on
dail's website and that'll give you a
bit of a discount um I love these guys
what they're doing they're they're
always sort of pushing the envelopes and
uh they really have been a crucial part
of how I have decided to inhale my phyto
canabo as well as many many people
across the planet so shout out to Dil
for always doing a great job and uh once
again and uh beagle puking beagle you
are incredible dude I don't say it
enough but uh thank you for all that you
do we do appreciate you uh there's a
whole world of people out there who are
using your quarts right now and they
they they know you by name and they know
that uh that you stand for Quality so
thank you for that thank you denil uh
this has been a a nice little review
feel free to uh leave a comment down
below if you have any questions I'll try
to get them answered and uh in in the
meantime May the full melt bless your
bowl sooner than
later peace
everybody free and
rock free and live free your mind and
and free your mind and dance
Dess
distress
and save your life oh yes
yes and save your life for yes babyon
will blind you like a bat oh yeah and R
you like a rat oh W and treat you like a
mat they will tell you like a KN a KN
and they will misiz your WI people
before you