[Music]
I would describing him as being a a free
spirit and a character and uh again I'd
like to thank him Alo we've been in
connection for almost five years onlyy
met him last night for the first time
that's part of the reasons why he's here
on this platform he brings another voice
to this space so it's wonderful to
actually get to meet him and uh have a
drink with him last night and it's gives
me great pleasure to introduce Dr Bob
n thank you Hut and thank everybody
especially the organizers because this
is what has to happen everywhere around
the world and is happening everywhere
around the world thankfully so um what I
want to do is talk about things in a
very different fashion than um what most
people are accustomed to and in fact
what I really want to do is I want to
bring together the
spirituality with the science because in
fact anything that's true has to be true
for everything that's true so whatever
is real in spirituality whatever is real
in science there has to be a junction of
Truth between them and I feel very
satisfied personally with how I Now
understand what I call the physics of
life because if we are going to try to
explore how to promote Health both in
terms of individual health but in terms
of Social and planetary Health we should
have some idea of what life is I don't
think anybody in this room would bring
their car to a mechanic who didn't know
how a car worked but we go to doctors
who don't really have a foundational
understanding of what life is and this
is true sadly of of our scientists and
the whole scientific medical
establishment that that we all live live
under and The Tragic Truth that I've
come to realize for myself is that we
are living in a world of false use
Donald Trump's spr fake medicine and
fake uh fake science in many respects
because of how we have not moved beyond
the kind of thinking that really
represents 100 Years of wonderful
thinking and wonderful creativity but
never got us beyond the stagnation
of of the kind of Revolution that's
required in for us to move on to the
next level of humanity the the
Consciousness that we've heard spoken of
and for me that is simply a natural
unfolding of an unfolding universe and
that's what I want to try to convey
these aspects uh of what is going on so
what I'd like everyone to do I figure
out how to move my own thing here
um would be to basically forget what
you're thinking about what you think you
know and just go with what I have to say
don't over criticize it listen to the
whole story as much as I'll be able to
get through because it's really
impossible to do it in this amount of
time it takes about two hours to give a
fairly full-fledged overview of what I'm
talking about but the aim is that the
kinds of details that for example Ethan
does a wonderful job of presenting and
they're so essential for us to
understand but what we need to do is
understand them in the context of what
life is and how those things impinge on
that process and one of the overarching
themes that I'm going to talk about has
to do ultimately with the energy sources
that cells use to power themselves to
power life and to manifest itself in
everything and it turns out that those
energy sources have profoundly different
uh values to them and the kind kind of
things if you look at literally all of
those various chemicals that you saw on
the board earlier today the Turk beans
and the flavonoids and all they all for
the most part have a common mode of
functioning even though we can look at
the specific Pathways if you stand back
and you say what's really going on
you'll see that most of them turn on fat
burning via kise and the magic of
turning on fat burning is that that's
when cells are
recycling and what they're doing is
they're Rec cycling their damaged pieces
and how were those pieces damaged they
were damaged when we made energy
efficiently by utilizing carbohydrates
and what's known as the electron
transport system so it's the dialogue
between doing things activating things
your muscles your your pancreas your
hormones your brain all of those things
are always done with a foundational
activation of calcium and that has to do
with the origins of life so what I
really want to do is give you a flavor
for a different way of think thinking
and understanding what life is what life
is a part of because it's all part of
this expansion this uh the unfolding of
the universe basically and we have been
part of a chemical reaction a chemical
reaction that has gone on since the
planet formed we we'll start there we
don't have to go back to the Big Bang
all right what I try to do is keep
theory in a functional mode because what
I'm interested in is life liberty in the
pursuit of happiness
so we will see where we get and all of
the physics the foundation of all of my
thinking comes from Noel lauan Ilia pin
who was one of the truly great Geniuses
that Humanity has created and um what he
does is he creates a whole new vision of
just everyday reality we are involved in
an unfolding of the universe and as it
unfolds it creates time it's not like
time is sitting there with the clock
because that's the way we're train to
think about it but there's a process of
unfolding and intrinsic in that process
is the evolutionary process and in order
to have Evolution you have to power life
and in order to power life you need
these energy sources and it's the way
they work together the combination of
doing things and then protecting what
you're doing it's the same in society if
what we do is build and we don't recycle
and we don't care about the pollution
we're generating Society will collapse
the reason for that is because Society
is an echo of the physics of life so we
will
continue so a key concept here is that
life is a dynamic fractal now who who
knows what a fractal is just so I get so
a lot of you know okay so I'm GNA I'm
going to just give a quick picture here
actually a little quick movie of a of a
fractal I can get my neck together can't
Mo it should just be playing why is it
not
playing get out of this mode I guess I
don't know where I am it came up in an
unusual place and I didn't fix it anyway
maybe I'll just have to bypass the movie
which is a shame it's a nice
movie here we go can
do so when a fract
oops I got
it oh
well oh now I have to torture myself
more
why there's always something maybe I
should just move on anyway a fractal is
an algorithm whereby it generates a
picture an image of some sort and it so
happens that the algorithm allows you to
reiterate the the math and it'll
regenerate images so you can like scope
in like you could look at a little piece
of my ear and bring it up and you see
another ear and then if you look closely
you see another ear and you bring it up
you see another ear okay so it'll repeat
patterns by a mathematical algorithm so
what I'm proposing is that we look at
let's see if I can get anything oh no
I'm going to have to fool around with it
a dynamic fractal and what what a
dynamic fractal in my version of reality
is is that every time you reiterate that
algorithm you change it and what do you
change it based on you change it based
on your first algorithm changed the
environment the environment changed you
if you want to adapt you now have to
change back to the environment that you
changed so it is this constant process
of unfolding and that's what evolution
is and we again are all part of this big
chemistry set but we make the mistake we
have the illusion that we are
individuals and in fact the way I look
at things is I look at the planet the
big chemistry set and within that
chemistry set you have the biochemistry
of humanity and within the biochemistry
of humanity that there are certain rules
as to what's going on in this unfolding
process as we get smarter a key concept
here is that it's not that we evolve in
time it's that Evolution the power the
flow of energy generates the time and
equilibrium which is the way most of our
physics and most of our chemistry has as
its Origins what's called reversibility
of time because that allowed simple math
and that simple math allowed for a very
powerful development of of of Concepts
in the field in particular say
thermodynamics but it was all based on
equilibrium when you have equilibrium
you don't have flow and you don't have
time because everything's already done
at equilibrium so there's a new field of
physics and this is what pene created
called far from equilibrium
thermodynamics so it's what happens when
energy is flowing and in order to
formalize that mathematically so that
you can have like the logical proofs
that everybody will universally accept
they had to actually create new math in
order to break the symmetry of time
because the physics that we're taught in
our schools says time can go backwards
well are you getting younger when's the
last time you drove your car and the gas
tank filled up you know those things
don't happen there is an arrow to time
and what pin's work was did was he broke
the symmetry so now we no longer have
this reversability of time we have an
unfolding of time and that unfolding is
driven by the flow of energy keeping us
further from equilibrium so a summary
statement that's very important I think
for people to understand is that health
is defined in my mind at least by our
distance from
equilibrium and as we age we return back
to equilibrium the complexity the
negative entropy of our chemistry
decreases and what I want to talk about
is how that's happening why that's
happening how the energy of our food the
fat versus the carbohydrates has a
profound impact on the ultimate outcome
and I apply these things to myself as
well uh just so we have a reference
point here I've been using cannabis for
53 years on a daily basis I start the
day by eating at least 100 milligrams of
oil and I do that a few more times
throughout the day but I've reversed a
lot of my conditions by combining my
cannabis use with my neutrals that
ultimately manipulate metabolism I will
be 70 years old in December right I feel
that I have been
successful you know I I have a lot of
pain I have a lot of things going on
I've got my whole body is arthritic you
know I'm H B27 you know what that means
I don't have analing spondilitis because
I've used cannabis my whole life I am
positive for the rid Factor I've got
Gout I've on and on and on but you see
I'm fine I can go right M you know
because I apply not just cannabis but
everything else that I'm telling you
about all right
so these are Concepts that I want you to
start to think about because these are
not things that we think about and
they're rather mindblowing
so um first of all there's about 50
billion tons of DNA on the planet so
we're talking about a very successful
molecule all right and then every day a
person makes approximately their own
body weight in
ATP well you know that seems to be a
little bit of a how can I be making that
much of ATP when I'm not getting bigger
you know it's flow you make you break
you make you break you make you break
okay and that's what flow we are flow
dependent structures that's what pin got
his Nobel prize for the concepts and the
math and the understanding of what flow
dependent structures are so a human cell
has about 2 meters of DNA in it and if
you took all the DNA from a person and
you stretch it out it would go from here
to the Sun and back 400 times think
about that how small this stuff is every
one of your cells has a two yards of DNA
in it 2 meters of DNA think of what must
go on when that cell replicates because
you can't even see the cell and you got
two meters of stuff twined up in there
that's got to replicate you can't make
mistakes or you come down with cancer
and other illnesses
so this is total lunacy when you think
about what I'm saying here and then to
top all that off a single free radical
molecule could kill you a single
molecule one time could kill you all
right why because if that molecule hit a
critical base in a critical Gene that
was controlling cell division and your
DNA repair system didn't see it and your
antioxidants didn't quench it before the
did the damage and your then your IM
system doesn't see that you now have a
cancer cell and then you go and you do
chemo and that selects for drug
resistance we'll go into that and then
you finally go back to cannabis and if
you're lucky you're able to overcome the
Damage Done by the chemo and if you're
lucky you get rid of everything but this
it's not that simple and I I've got
about 90 YouTubes out there that
describe a different version of reality
my version either I'm insane or
everybody else is insane all right and
it's open for
debate but I'm very confident in what I
know because I it's so integrated and
it's always answering all the questions
that are asked when I read all of the
papers that I read which is all I do I
sit around stone I'm ad I got the TV on
I got the computer on my lap and I read
all day every day other than being a
slave with my
children
so all right now it gets even crazier
one molecule can kill you everyone of
your 15 trillion cells every day
sustains 20,000 of the damages where one
in one cell one time could kill you what
does that suggest to you to me it says
we must have an incredible amount of
biochemical complexity devoted to
preventing us from dying from all the
free radicals we're making and I believe
absolutely that is the answer and it's
the free radicals that guide everything
because as we do things we make them as
we make them we create damages DNA RNA
proteins fats everything gets oxidized
by or reduced depending on the type of
free Radical by free radicals they react
with everything all right
so what we want to be able to do is keep
that at a sustainable level where we're
able to fix the damages that are caused
by the free radicals and a rate
proportional somewhat to how how much
we're creating it's kind of think of
your bathtub you know you have a if you
have the water running and it's going
out the outflow if you have it right you
can just keep it going right but if you
have too much water it'll overflow or if
you had the plug out you know and you
weren't keeping it right it'll it'll
drain right we are the same way we are
filled with the organization of Life the
Holy Spirit if you will but it's not a
static entity it's a flowing entity
coming from you know as coming from the
universe it's all part of this
continuity all right so half of us in my
mind is meaning on a cellular
biochemical level is devoted for us to
do things and the other half is devoted
for us to be able to fix the things so
we can keep doing things we have to keep
growing we have to keep moving further
from equilibrium your chronological age
is not what matters the fact that I'm 70
is not what matters how far am I from
equilibrium is what matters and you know
you could be 6 years old and Dy because
you're Clos to equilibrium you can be a
100 years old riding a horse running
around because you're further from
equilibrium all right that's what it all
is it's all about organization that's
maintained by the flow of energy through
you
so and these are some quotes that just
really capture the concept of this
constant creativity you know when when
when the Bible says man's created in
God's image well what is God's image
creation
creativity see for me God is generalized
Open System Dynamics the flow of energy
right but it doesn't matter because no
matter what your religion is people it
will accept science to a certain degree
you know most people will not walk in
front of a car because they have some
concept of momentum you know falling off
a roof they understand gravity you know
so what I'm saying is that once
everybody understands what I'm
suggesting if I'm right I'm not totally
insane or maybe both or neither then we
will see a transition occurring because
what we are as individuals are not
individuals other than that we are
quantized probes of that Collective
human biochemistry and what are we
probes for
adaptability that's what evolution Works
off of adaptability you're not the
biggest you're not the strongest you're
the most adaptable you're not the
smartest none of that is what matters
it's how it all comes together so you
can adapt to survive and that's what
your cells are trying to do all the time
as we keep trying to do things and kill
ourselves in the process so one of the
most important take-home messages I'm
going to say it right now before I
forget because I'm a total Airhead all
right is that you have to shift your
balance of carbohydrate intake and fat
intake you want to take more healthy
fats and less carbohydrates especially
like you should never drink sod any of
that crap that's just like ridiculous
nonsense for your body all it does is
promote free rical doesn't give you any
help and it helps all the age related
illnesses diabetes heart disease think
about it use a little Common Sense are
you going to have clogged arteries if
you're burning fat if the fat is what
clogs your arteries no but what you
don't know because it's not generally
accepted as reality but happens to be
fully 100% true is guess what you make
fat out of
carbohydrates and why do you make the
fats out of the carbohydrates so you
won't burn them and make too many free
radicals and kill
yourself but it turns out that that fat
is proinflammatory as well so it's only
a temporary solution and other solutions
that our cells have to not die from
producing too many free radicals is
they'll make fibers so your fibrotic
diseases are all an effort of your cells
to stay alive because either by genetic
mechanisms because of your problems
genetic problems or because of your life
history in particular the food you eat
and the toxins you were exposed to that
is what leads into these problems that
have to then be recycled burnt up and
gotten rid of but you can only do that
if you're building enough and recycling
in an appropriate fashion all right so
anyway the more deeply we study the
nature of time the better we understand
that duration means invention creations
of forms continuous elaboration of the
absolutely new because this second is
different than that second and that is
the absolutely new that manifests itself
in life and
evolution and another one of his saying
is we are actually the children of the
arrow of time of evolution not its
progenitors and this refers to for those
of you in you know quantum theory where
Schrodinger's Box you know you have you
have a cat in the box and you throw some
cyanide in but you know the cat is not
dead or alive until you make the
measurement that's the foundation of
this reversible time based physics which
Prine blows out of the water with what
he's done so the it means that we don't
create Time by making a measurement
we're part of this unfolding
process so here's an an example of one
of these flow dependent structures this
is an example of something that is
counterintuitive to us what you're
seeing is a liquid in a peaker dish so
there about 10 MLS okay which me amount
to like 10 to 20 something molecules
we're talking about billions and
trillions of molecules and when you heat
them what every what we're all taught in
school is that the molecules will move
faster they'll rotate faster if there's
a reaction will occur faster what we are
not taught is at all the possibility
that something like this could occur and
it's the spontaneous formation of
organized hexagonal convection cells
what what I mean is
this I'm taking that and turning it on
its side so you're heating it below the
hot molecules are going up the side of
the hexagon giving their heat up above
and then the cooled ones are coming
through the center and you're forming
like a Bucket Brigade for
heat how can that happen it happens
because by those structures forming they
are generating more entropy more waste
to the universe the simple way to
remember it is collections of molecules
like us will get smarter as long as we
can make the universe stupider
quickly all right that's the way things
work that's reality right so in this
case here we're looking at a thermal
gradient generating the organization in
the next slide you're seeing a Redux
reaction a reaction where chemicals have
electrons that they want to give to
something else and something else wants
to take them that's electricity all
right bio El electricity we call
redox so what you're seeing here is
another petri dish and chemicals were
mixed together and thrown in in there
and
spontaneously organization occurs you
can see the organization because there's
an indicator in there that tells you
whether the molecules are oxidized to
reduced so you see that there's a
heterogen they're not all the same even
though we would expect it to be all the
same it's a liquid so what's going on
there all right it's showing you that
flowing energy organizes matter and by
doing that it's making that reaction
occur more rapidly so that in the end
the potential is dissipated to the
universe ierse quicker made the universe
stupider quicker all
right so now I'm going to show you a
little video of it this one of the
reactions I did in in the lab and you'll
see the color starting the bottom of the
tube because when you do it in a test
tube it's more three-dimensional but
there's another factor that I want to
emphasize to you when this thing finally
starts happening you it'll move up from
the bottom come
on come on I should shorten this
video is it working maybe it wasn't
working oh
no it sounds like it's working but oh
there you go oh you have it and I don't
okay so what you'll see is obviously
it's random right there's no possibility
that there's any organization left and
from the bottom there you'll see a blue
color which indicates reduced molecules
and you'll see that it'll move up and
disappear and then come back there it
goes and then it'll come back and do it
again these are periodic reactions
driven by the fact that you have slow
potential of electrons and matter gets
organized but what you think what you're
seeing think about there are two things
you're seeing organization in space and
you're seeing organization and time as
it comes and it goes we are nothing but
cycles of coming and going of
oscillations of reactions and
chemistries and electronics everything
vibrating together all right and what
you're seeing if you think about it you
got your heart rate right that's a
temporal structure a structure in time
you got your breathing you got menstrual
cycles all of these things are natural
oscillations that come to a point where
we can kind of measure them and see them
but on a subcellular level for any of
you who've taken psychedelics and mahasa
and LSD and you know the flowing Cosmic
beauty of like psychedelics that's what
it looks like in yourselves
that's what's going on it's that Harmony
where everything's moving with
everything else weaving together and
it's all driven by the flow of energy
stop beating you die stop beating you
you you know the structure the flow
dependent structure goes away that's
what death is it's a far from
equilibrium phase
change back to a state of lower
organization so whatever if there's
anything with Spirit somehow that that's
captured okay I don't understand s
enough but I'm open to
everything so what I'm going to show you
in a second is a metabolic
map anybody remember
that now the the problem with this map
is it's too
simple literally because what they what
you're looking at here is a snapshot in
time you're not seeing any flow
therefore there is no time okay so what
you're seeing are all these possible
chemical reactions in their linkages but
what you're missing is the thing that
makes it alive and what makes it alive
is when it's flowing all of those things
every one of those points has an enzyme
that allows the reaction to occur
because the reactions in your body would
not occur unless you had enzymes that
allowed them to occur in room
temperature okay otherwise we would not
be here okay so all of those things have
enzymes all of those enzymes are
controlled in terms of their function in
terms of their trans
translation from RNA in terms of
transcription from DNA to RNA and in
terms of the genetic architecture of the
DNA as to whether something's available
to be expressed or not so the whole
thing that makes that alive is missing
all right and yet this is we're not
taught that aspect we're taught oh we're
get this metabolic map know well this is
nonsense unless you can make it and
relate it to
life
and what we'll see is that our cannaboid
system is the overall regulator of
everything in your body from conception
until death so your immune system
digestive system cardiovascular system
skin bones muscle
everything is
regulated from conception until death
every time you get hungry it's because
your brain makes into canids you give
yourself the munchies the reason the
plant works is because it's how you work
and this plan can tap into how you work
and the reason Pharmaceuticals are total
[__] for the most part is because
they're founded on the wrong principles
and I say that using a pharmaceutical
every day that's keeping my heart in
Rhythm all right but that there's so
much more that I can't talk about
related to that just we don't of the
time but the point here is that what we
have to be able to do is manipulate our
biochemical flow in a way that keeps us
further from equilibrium and as we age
what happens is the weakest link in our
flow dependent biochemistry is what gets
us all right my genetics makes it all
this inflammatory crap that I deal with
all right had I had other diets and
things that I do I probably be dead now
with a heart
attack but thankfully I'm not so you
know again back to the Psychedelic
picture you know you want all that
harmonizing flow and you don't want too
much disruption
all
right so Evolution n life naturally
selects for survival of flow dependent
structures through adaptation as long as
adaptable conditions and sufficient time
is allowed okay where I want to go with
this as I want to point out some things
that I believe are incredibly important
and totally revolutionary and sadly the
scientists will not talk with me about
it because I've rejected them and
they've rejected me and I'm happy with
the separ ation in general other than
the fact that if they knew more of what
I know we would all be better off
because instead of pedaling poison we'd
be able to start manipulating the
biochemical flow when you make
xenobiotics the way the chem the
pharmaceutical companies are making
chemicals all right for long time I
didn't you know I it didn't bother me
that much I'm thinking all right so you
have this chemical it's going to do this
then it finally dawned on me well if you
don't have the pathways to synthesize
the chemical and you don't have the
pathways to break down the chem is part
of the normal healthy flow what happens
well they'll get broken down by means by
which we get rid of you know some of our
garbage but you don't know what products
are going to be made along the way you
don't know where they're going to go and
what they're going to do because they've
never been part of the flow they haven't
had selective pressures working on them
so for the most part they're not going
to work other than to generate side
effects and give you temporary belief
and this one of the one of the really
scary examples of that is with
chemotherapy because and there's
peer-reviewed literature showing you
what you do is you select for the drug
resistance and let me explain what that
means in my mind because that's
completely different what what it means
in everybody else's mind all
right your cells in order for them to
live have to constantly be adapting to
their environment they've got to be
either muscling or thinking or seeing or
smelling or whatever they're doing
they're doing something
okay they have to be able to
know when they have to what they have to
do to adapt so there's like a layer of
of how we deal with free radicals
because when we use the electron
transport system we make energy
efficiently but we make it dangerously
because that's where most of our free
radicals come from so we have this
dichotomy we want it we need it that's
what powers Evolution and that's in my
mind what powered the evolution of
humanity it was the cv1 receptor which
first appeared with the
vertebrates not invertebrates
vertebrates okay once we got our brains
in the vertebrates we had the CB1
receptor and what we what it does on a
molecular level if you understand how
things work and all the other stuff
starts to become apparent to you what
what the cv1 receptor does is it
regulates calcium channels among other
things but the calcium channels are
important because they activate
everything and if you're eating too much
sugar and then the calcium is part of
the signaling that's saying to the
mitochondria you know burn more sugar
burn more sugar but then you make these
free radicals and the system adjusts to
it all right because remember the system
half of it is just to survive the free
radicals so it's adjusting to what's
going on by shifting all the biochemical
flows so think of a road map a city you
want to get from here to the other side
of the city you got all those
possibilities some are high speed some
are slow speed some are broken that's
the way it's going through you the flow
okay and what you want to do is to be
able to optimally get from one side of
the city to the other without damaging
everything and with that in some proper
time so what the pharmaceutical industry
in general is doing is working on the
level of the differentiated cell the
cell that's communicating with its
environment and putting out more ideally
uh entropy and taking in negative
entropy order okay
but
when you turn on recycling what the
cells do is they stop talking to their
environment and they say I've got enough
problems that I got to cool what I'm
doing and I got to fix me it's kind of
like Trump for president in a
sense America no cell first the cell is
now to saying I don't want to deal with
the world anymore I'm going to fix
myself and if that can occur then that
cell can go on to live a healthy part of
you or if it can't if it does it but it
doesn't do it in the right way then it
becomes a cancer cell or misguided
immune cell for autoimmune diseases etc
etc etc ultimately all age related
illnesses come from these excess free
radicals so where was I going with all
of this yeah so your electron transport
system remember one molecule can kill
you every year you make about four
kilogram of superoxide which is a free
radical and which is again why I
emphasize how much of what we are has to
be designed to protect us and guess what
that's why I'm here because we're now
going from I'm explaining why we can
manipulate things on a biochemical basis
but how do we do it we have to know we
can do it and then we have to go and do
it so that's all part of the system
getting smarter and what's happening now
is the Earth the chemistry set of the
planet is undergoing a far from
equilibrium phase change and what that
means is we see our weather patterns
changing we see our financial situ see
before a phase change occurs before
there's a far from equilibrium phase
change the variables of the system
instead of vibrating like this they
start to go crazy and we're seeing that
everywhere in the world right now we're
see it in our Pol politics we're see it
in our finan
we're seeing the tides we're seeing the
weather so the planet is undergoing a
rearrangement and what I believe is that
rearrangement is part of our Evolution
as well and that I don't know how many
of you know my blip blip story you know
you can divide the world into two two
categories of people people who have
above average cannaboid activity and
people who have less than average
cannaboid activity now if you don't make
enough so you're more unstoned what's
that going to mean anxious uptight
fearful you know all the crap we see
because the people who run the world are
what I call Blitz backward looking cedo
fishing people and you know the Bible
says it the meek shall inherit the earth
well who are the meek and they the
stoner said all right so you only stuck
me in jail for 20 years you didn't give
me life [__] you is my answer you know I
mean this is just ludicrous we're
talking about a god-given plan whatever
God you want to talk about we're talking
about growing lettuce in our backyard
I'll shut up
we're
done CB2 turns on fat burning CB1 allows
you to burn sugar safely that's why your
brain needed it because it's so
organized it'll fry without it it's
always hot anyway it can't get any
hotter all right so sugar burning your
heart 6 % of it comes from fat burning
why make free radicals when you don't
need them stem cells burn fat that's why
they don't age you need CB1 to turn on
electron transport so they can
differentiate make neurons and
[Applause]
bl as you can see this man has a great
deal of
energy he's not and he's not going
anyway he's here all day so please uh
catch him at the lunch break cuz I know
he'll love to talk
more there a lot
Bo