[Music]
we're filming I'll be I'll be like
welcome welcome to both man's world
welcome yeah today were sitting with
mark cloaking the weed guy and a special
guest dr. David Allen who's in the house
today and I actually met you the first
time at the cush cop - Health Expo last
year okay he's a 30-year heart surgeon
yeah yeah I was gonna say actually if
you could tell everyone a little bit
about yourself just a quick couple of
minutes that's a good start and how you
kind of got into this I mean I'm excited
today
the reason I'm excited today is the dr.
David Allen is to me he's like an
endocannabinoid specialist you know a
lot of what I've learned about the
endocannabinoid system and shared on my
channel I've learned through dr. David
Allen so he's a professor of kendo
Catholic system yeah so let you tell me
about that well I'm a retired heart
surgeon and I have been using cannabis
since I was 17 years old
and and used it virtually every day only
you know after work and I knew that
there was something special about the
about cannabis that had worked better
than other medicines and as I finally
decided I wanted to go into just
cannabis research and quit doing heart
surgery so that's what I've done
and we're finding out to dis new
Sciences it's gonna change medicine so
that's what we're talkin about
absolutely and change the way we look at
cannabis as a medicine because it was
actually you that mentioned to me at the
Health Expo last year in regards to why
we don't need prescriptions for it and
I'm not sure if you remember saying this
but you said it's a preventative
medicine there's no need to prescribe it
we should be allowed to use it as a
preventative and then you mentioned well
it's actually diabetes and you know we
conservative nutraceutical and what that
means is it's a nutritional thing that
your body uses kind of like broccoli or
something that improves your nutritional
health and the animal can monoi system
is a mechanism that controls whether you
could diabetes or not it controls
whether you get cancer or not and a
bunch of other things and we're finding
out that really when we eat cannabis we
augment our own body's natural ability
to heal itself and so smoking cannabis
helps you as well but we're actually
finding out that eating cannabis
especially if you eat it raw it has a
much more potent medical effect that's
crazy so it's not looking at liking raw
cannabis so this is actually like a
nutritional supplements like a food so
the healthy food when the war is over
and cannabis is finally legal and this
will happen you'll be able to go to
Walmart and buy cannabis that's going to
be in your cereal and and other food
stuff and you
get your children it won't get them high
I like the juice bar idea to or people
be growing large amounts of play clones
kind of like they do with the the we
prize just juice and you got the fresh
you know you all of you if they blended
also get more the fiber these like an
Orange Julius I really wanted to do that
I mean but Julius but you ain't be
getting high of it but wouldn't be cool
to have a whole bunch of clones
continually you don't again
oh no absolutely and you just basically
juice and i'm like 'i do wheatgrass
that's pretty unique it's pretty
incredible time that we can find out
another chapter and how incredibly
beneficial cannabis is to mankind can
even dogkind know it affects everybody a
little differently and infects some
animals differently and this dog it is
extremely strong on it lasts for a long
time and we gave it a little piece of
cannabis cookie one time and it lasted
almost three days and so what that means
is that some animals have enzyme systems
that degrade cannabis that are different
from other animals and so it's not
really delineate which breeds tolerate
cannabis better or what what size animal
this research is still needs to be done
I love when you ask a question or make a
call like the doctor just goes right
into its site mm well that's lovely
doctor color knowledge and and that's
what really needs to happen I think it's
a message to other doctors that are as
intelligent as you who are kind of blind
to the real facts of the benefits of
cannabis and one day they're gonna have
to be held accountable I think of dr.
Gupta who wrote that time magazine
article and has since retracted in and
actually did a couple of specials on CNN
so he's doubling down on marijuana
I say well I thought that it's almost
like they're being up to Soho you know
like as doctors they welded a girl stuff
did they even study the endocannabinoid
system well funny you should ask
last summer I did a study where we
called all the medical schools in the
United States were called 157 medical
schools and we asked the directors of
the curriculum if they talked key
endocannabinoid science to the students
they if they had a director of
endocannabinoid science if they had a
department if they talked the EECS as an
organized course or if they even
mentioned the EECS in any ancillary
courses like pathophysiology
pharmacology or neuroanatomy and the
answer was only 13% even mention it and
nobody has an organized course or a
department with a director and so this
shows that the doctors that graduate
this year are not going to be
knowledgeable in the ECS which is a
control system that controls everything
we're finding out that that even
conception if you if you block the
endocannabinoid system you can prevent
sperm from entering the ovum so you can
prevent impregnation if you block the
endocannabinoid system so it's a real
important system
so you need to tell me they've left out
a piece of the anatomy of the body
teaching medical doctors and all these
school it's kind of like your doctor not
knowing that there's a circulatory
system or a nerve receives at least that
important so what you said about it
earlier and how it regulates your body
into the deciding factor on whether
you're going to get diabetes or cancer
is or you would want to know about that
system yeah the importance of this is is
really we're just kind of coming to
understand the full meaning of what what
really the importance of the ECS is and
it's virtually the key of life it is the
Fountain of Youth and because it stops
antioxidant stops oxidation from
happening to the cells and many diseases
that we now currently have names for
will no doubt in the near future be
found to be defects in the either
production or degradation of the
endocannabinoid molecules that your body
produces I love hearing this I love that
you're sharing this with our audience
and that you've been sharing this you
know with many audiences throughout your
Facebook and through the loot guys
YouTube page and any speaks that many of
them alberta's and stuff because it has
to be absolutely I saw him speak so the
importance of all of this is is this if
we're going to be preventing diabetes
then we're going to be preventing
everything that's associated with
diabetes so we'll be preventing
amputations
we'll be preventing kidney dialysis and
we'll be preventing dock blindness and
there are studies that prove that if you
use canvas for 20 years or more just
even smoking it then it decreases
so diabetes by 66% so what is like a
miracle it is a miracle when you think
of both the suffering and the emotional
state of mind that you would also be
decreasing and all of that people that
didn't have to get dialysis is terrible
for people to have to go through that
really they wouldn't have to go through
that there's all these politicians that
think they're doing right by passing
laws that make marijuana illegal and
arresting people they really don't
understand that they're trying to pass a
law that would prevent her own family
from having a stroke or heart attack
they'll understand that they're
preventing science from advancing so
we're just killing people causing
suffering but that can't be accidental
though unfortunately I'm not trying to
get into a big conspiracy rant here or
anything but they do sell sugar well
that's what I mean like it seems more
like an agenda than it does an accident
how do you accidentally spend you know
hundreds of billions of dollars on
propaganda and lies and somehow like
even guys like Sanjay Gupta I believe
there's more of him out there I don't
believe doctors are bad people but I
believe somehow a system has been built
to specifically it prevents them from
talking yeah if you're actually he's
famous enough to do so if your income
stream comes from that realm then it's
hard to challenge that realm because you
know channels your income stream
absolutely brutal so he literally got
you by the bank accountant to me it
seems like some of the most important
information going right now to share
with a family member or loved one or
friend that you know is in any type of
element right now there's so many
different elements
that can be fixed by simply feeding your
endocannabinoid system just from these
deficiencies people don't even know they
have them and it really it seems that
these endocannabinoid deficiencies make
you think different and and really the
people that are making the laws you for
the most part aren't using cannabis and
they passed laws that they think sound
reasonable but on further examination
especially if you smoke pot you can see
the folly in the laws that they passed
and they think they're reasonable but
people that smoke pot kind of understand
they can't be reasonable yeah and I
think that folly is a real danger to
make something look bad you know that
that that mistake that they're making it
doesn't make them look bad it's it's
just so easy they don't think properly
if you smoke cannabis you actually think
better than if you don't smoke cannabis
and so you're kind of inhibited if you
don't use cannabis sure not to mention
they're putting out something that's
such a lie that when they put out
something that's the truth how our young
people supposed to acknowledge the
difference when they see one thing
that's clearly folly to them because
they also perhaps smoke cannabis or know
someone that's using it in a distantly
or recreationally and they know that
those things are not true
and then there's stuff like alcohol
which kills people and they can see
that's it's a direct contradiction well
alcohol is potentially one of the most
dangerous drugs we have speaking of
which Prime Minister Harper a huge party
this is not an eighteen-year-old girl my
boy somebody see alcohol poisoning is
really dangerous you can die from that
yeah people do die from that it's
definitely you should have thrown a
party what about
much press I'm telling you we would have
been there when the government is caught
in lies it makes the population mistrust
and that is well and and so what it
really does is in the creates a an
animosity between the people and the
government which affects the government
on other levels that's how the
government needs to be truthful for the
people to really you know trust the
government well if they want their
foundation to be made out of like stone
instead of sand they should be truthful
and be honest and have a highly wrongful
board I'm easily or at least you know
what you get with that guy you do know
what you get with another shirt and if
only we could get someone that you don't
wanna get if we could get someone who
you know the same way but isn't actually
like that like a good just like this
goes back to people that aren't using
cannabis people that aren't using
cannabis these generally this type of
person they the people that want a rule
and control are generally not the same
people who want to grow cannabis and use
cannabis that's that's the real people
that want to control other people become
presidents and become directors and
become the head of the whatever they're
generally in their own right on a
different path it's also the industries
that they control that they're trying to
keep it away maybe they don't agree or
don't care about pot but they sure do
care about the forest industry or the
pharmaceutical industry and what it will
do to that yeah well I'll tell you 25
years ago
it was such a different world in Canada
and literally I'm not sure how long it's
been now about 94 it's over 20 20 years
since we got our first Hempfield growing
in Canada and I'll never forget my
ex-partner from back then martin saying
this will change the way people see it
when they start seeing this stuff
growing on the side of the road it's
just going to it's kind of
and you know in Manitoba it would have
been like this I'm surprised too many
people don't know it
marijuana and hemp are the same things
the main element female that was another
little fib we had to tell our government
you know that hemp was a distant
relative of cannabis we used that very
wording with the Minister of Finance and
agriculture and we felt like it was a
viable it was okay to tell that fit of
course and the THC limits were so low
that sure you could probably raise the
THC limits even in that strain if you've
read it over the course of the amount of
time 30 years probably 40 or 50 or
whatever but still it's it's there it's
genetics is there it's in the literature
it's got to be in there exactly point
zero one you can never get rid of it why
would you want to well for us we wanted
that at that time just to get hemp in
the ground like it was also an okay
thing because we got slack for people
TMC's been a rune pot it's just crazy
people were freaking out the bar these
were I suppose its supporters they're
jealous you're good
we're all doing it for the people
absolutely cool well what about the
ritualistic use of cannabis for
thousands of years and what do you think
about it's only been in the last hundred
years that they really bastardized it
and it's before then it's been used you
know in tradition from all sorts of
different cultures and races from like
the sit-ins the Egyptians I mean that's
it's only real it's very bad in terms of
math in terms of mankind it's only
really been a very small blinking time
that it's been illegal and persecuted
like it is so I guess someone trying to
say is do you think that it's gonna get
reversed or do you think it's just
complementation of well I'm trying to
control plan it's crazy how a government
has spent all this money and energy
and built up all these weapon systems
and information systems to fight a plant
and the plant seems like it's women and
it's win because the the war is based on
false information lies as one lies right
and the plant you can't they these
people think they're passing just laws
but they're passing laws against
something that will stop diabetes so how
do you and what bizarre world does that
make sense where you can pass a law
against something that sure's disease
what about the lack of hard evidence of
physical side effects from cannabis
that's never been presented I find not
just a travesty now well no dead bodies
is what I'm trying to say you know
slowly how can this be when there's
millions of people being killed by
alcohol and cigarettes or do you
understand I'm saying there's a reason
we don't know more information about
cannabis and it's ill facts is because
they don't allow scientists to study it
because of its classification si si si
si one control substance act
si si one class schedule one and the
only reason this the CSA has five
schedules and they're all all illegal
and canvases schedule one and the only
difference in schedule 1 and the other
schedules is in a Schedule one
scientists can study it without special
permission that they don't give so
essentially anything in schedule one the
scientist or doctor can't study and
sulfur was made schedule 2 it would
still be illegal for people to own but
doctors could study it and they they
seemed
to use the excuse that if doctors were
studying that they would have stashes of
it that could be diverted to the public
for non-medical use and that doesn't
hold water but the truth is the whole
scheduling was made to prevent
scientific study so we made knowledge
illegal by this method yeah that's a
pretty impressive thing God's fingers in
your dog yes that's a terrible blow
right there when they did that and that
was I believe from 1937 from the
narcotics
well the Controlled Substances Act was
it came into effect in 1970 okay but it
really they had to make what happened
was in 1937 they passed the marihuana
Tax Act and that made marijuana illegal
except for medicinal use it was illegal
and to have marijuana you could have it
legally if he had this it's a tax stamp
which they didn't give out so basically
and you had to have the marijuana in
hand to get the stamp and so what
happened was Timothy Leary was busted at
the Mexican border his daughter was
carrying some marijuana and he was
busted and he went to jail for a very
area
I heard him tell that story and what
happened was his he was sent to jail for
a long time and he found on appeal his
lawyers argued that if you had to have
the marijuana to get the tax stamp that
that was self-incrimination and
therefore it was
constitutionally illegal and the court
agreed with Timothy Leary's so for a
short time after that that Court ruling
marijuana was technically legal in the
United States but people didn't know
about it and what it for it forced her
hand because they they had a legal
loophole that people were not using and
so what they did daddy calls that a
legal loophole and so they designed this
control substance act in a fashion that
that they thought whoa now how could we
make marijuana illegal so no one can
ever make it legal again and so they
came up with this crazy classification
the CSA one is three three points that
has high potential for abuse and since
there's no criteria for what that is
that that makes it an undefinable thing
and then not currently used for
medicinal use and as we all know that
prior to thirty seven that it was one of
the most prescribed medicines but they
get around that by saying currently and
then the third thing was not safe under
physician guidance and so and since
can't physicians can't prescribe
schedule 1 substances that held true so
they use this triple threat of a
criteria to make marijuana illegally in
a really unconstitutional
it was definitely a prief near fatal
blow to cannabis for a long time because
I do remember Andrew Weil did a study in
1965 one understands if they're sorry in
Turkey what if they're it was being
prescribed you said the most previous in
1937 it wasn't there any doctors
protesting like hey now I can't
prescribe it was useful I'm saying there
was and there was only information too
though how information was passed well
there was a large amount of doctors that
were being arrested and thrown in jail
for still using cannabis tinctures
because every major pharmaceutical
company was prescribed ad
they had preparations using cannabis
tinctures and other things and so the
doctors were still using them and and
what happened was the AMA kind of made
an amends with the government and
allowed it to be taken off the
pharmacopoeia and so the year prior to
that they were had arrested ten thousand
dollars a year after that they arrested
like seven doctors or something so
taking the most medicinal plant ever off
of the pharmacopoeia right and so it's
like a bizarro world and that's what it
was where where these people for
ulterior motives make something that's
healthy for you in legal something they
could save your grandmother's life so
it's it's crazy how this law developed
it's so multi useful you can see here I
was like but I thought of it or your
child's seizures yeah we were like again
where you're only like saved my life so
yeah it's really a big heist an amazing
thanks it is I mean I feel blessed on
one point in the sense that even though
we're still fighting for our rights
we're able to have our little gardens
and we're able to grow our own medicine
but it's still under the threat of being
taken away and I just think wow well
they've made it criminally more illegal
to girl marijuana I know we have one
side of the barrel
here medical use with on the other side
ever has been making it along mandatory
minimums
which even some judges have already been
like we're not doing that
the other goal enforcing it you know and
it makes sense because he wants to fill
his private prisons yeah so so how do
you make it illegal if you if you had a
substance that you could eat and it
would didn't get you high and with
decreased incidence of diabetes by sixty
six percent and your doctor can't give
you any other medicine there's no other
medicine that decreases incidence of
diabetes by two percent so if your
doctor could give you this stuff that it
would do this and they would make them
law against that that makes the lawyers
and the politicians of passed these laws
were pretty ignorant when you jamón
examine their laws under the truth of
what they're really doing absolutely but
well if you examine the actual true
agenda they're they're reads they're
brilliant because they're their evil
agenda means evil and they're really
good at their evil and that's how they
can pass those laws they're not doing it
accidentally you don't Amin it's for
such big money and why are they doing it
well it's because these companies that
certain companies 90 percent of their
payment management medications alone
just pain management I think it was a
double threat - I mean that him was the
the tree in the streets one of the
largest industries in North America
50,000 commercial products exactly and
then on top of the pharmaceuticals they
had two really powerful industries that
were logging for it and owned by only a
handful of people I think people need to
realize that the pharmaceutical industry
was family-owned basically back then and
even with the hemp the way we've been
allowed to grow it here in Canada
we were young activists when we fought
for that right and when we got it we
were so happy to get it so happy to
change the law from experimental to
commercial but then what then we're
growing it for seed and the seed oil is
too expensive to run engines on so we
can only sell it at high-end grocery
stores where you can put it on your
salad like that is a failed hemp
industry in Canada the fact that all we
have is hemp food that's all we got out
of it from 15 to 20 years ago there's
still no fibre being produced there's
still no creek there's still don't have
metal there's still no all of these
products that we should be producing out
of hand yeah you know so I still feel
there's a long way to go for that as
well you know the same way we're
fighting even still forever and even if
you don't use marijuana these marijuana
laws are used against you to restrict
your freedoms so really just this
marijuana the issue it affects everybody
even if you don't use the cannabis well
I mean in Canada it costs you money to
be able to enforce these archaic laws it
costs you to get the police and the
judge and the sheriff's and the jails
and they don't even follow their rules
like they make rules and then don't
follow them like sovereignty wrote rules
that say police from other countries
aren't allowed to come into other
countries and police well then how did
the DEA come up into BC and take Marc
Emery away and how did I saw them you
know strong because I saw them arrest
him when Michelle and and Greg and like
take them away they were nuts insane
yeah and they also used our own police
services to execute it with them oh yeah
absolutely they were puppets
yeah and I always think to like there's
a lot of countries that never happen no
mind you imagine like Japan going into
China and police in the Army just came
into the
BC or whatever Mars also anybody here
always when I make this point it said
Mark had no charges in Canada so I like
he got some crazy charges like even get
five years for in Canada
well that was clearly a personal
vendetta with the US government had
against mark not only because of his
outspoken activism but what's more
threatening than a an activist is the
wealthy activists who will put all his
money into his activism like sending
Americans bail money and helping
Americans move out of the US and the
Canada and just like he just he's been
spreading the word to overgrow
okay never use any plants you just hand
it all back as it was coming people like
mark charges too much for seeds it's
like he gives it all the way that that
listen when you go to a silent auction
and it's for some cool event that you
want to support do you think the intent
is to pay less for the auction item
you're going to pay more that's I'm
actually a little somebody exactly and
that's what Mark was doing with the
seeds and he didn't want to have to
explain it to everyone listen you're
paying more because of what I'm doing
with the money so aren't you stoked to
be watching what I know about what you
got with mark is what you going I got
twenty thirty different streams and
different scenes for mark and they
always were bang on I don't think people
realize you actually gonna you know
import those just go buy on them and
ship five thousand different seeds into
Canada I for one I'm looking very
forward to getting mark back to DC he's
gonna be a star they will wait and
hopefully be giant with this and yeah
this is good you know drug wars failing
cuz this is his last gasp and what we
need to do is make sure people get
involved and make sure that the new laws
that come out make sense and don't
punish people for using them
that helps their diabetes it helps her
anxiety it helps her sleep knows me I
mean either way from back in the day
when they pull the teeth out of the
hashish leaders in Cairo in like the
14th century they were trying to that
was their version of like the controlled
substance act or any of these other
preventive to getting us not to use this
magical plant like spending billions of
dollars and like David said I think
Canada's might be winning this war you
know pulling their teeth out in the
square didn't stop these guys from
eating hash I think at that point they
could have figured it out listen these
people really like this they are willing
to have pulling their teeth out with
like brutal probably not even well-made
pliers like the fact that they probably
use cannabis afterwards for they still
use it they still kept using it they
still gathered they still use it to this
day people aren't going to stop using
this plant and the fact that you know
that's why we're going to kashgar it's
in the west of China
I mean to the north to Japan where that
old money wasn't the 789 grams of
procured cannabis it's the oldest
pharmaceutical you know I found some of
those seeds from that ya know they gave
some to curses for stuff man Sam yeah
yeah so when I was in his house one day
and he just he was like he's like check
this out and I was just like I was like
what is that I think it might I can't
remember if it was some of the weed or
it was just the seeds I think and he was
like those are the oldest seeds like
ever found or something yeah the oldest
house beautiful yeah because in the
desert he also has the world's smallest
seeds from my belief net Paul and the
largest scenes from China which look
like small walnuts okay yeah small what
like small like maybe that big way
bigger than any seed you've ever seen
like
or five times bigger I heard in Kashgar
they have the world's largest outdoor
market every Sunday and people not be
the Nepali market and you know that hash
kind of feeling the Muslims seeming out
in that little area so I fear and I know
they like nothing amazing just putting
cash bearing your stuff okay yeah well I
think it would be cool is to go
experience that sort of feel of this
crazy market that everyone from all over
comes into China that area and has a
crazy people working and then yeah and
you know what the world's changing to
all these places are getting cooler some
friends of mine that own a seed company
we're still we're telling me that people
from like Iraq have been ordering lots
of seeds
yeah I think so but it must be getting
cooler there's all the books that they
haven't done it in a while I don't know
like just the fact that people are
quartering seeds and going back to my
YouTube account I know it's like crazy
countries that people are watching the
analytics right I'm like whoa yes Saudi
Arabia no I was going why not we're all
people right yeah almost we live under
different rules I was in the sere lekha
the mount lavinia hotel and I been there
for a day and I came out the front desk
I use like I know you know yeah never
been this early in my life rain say no
no you to rains a younger guy when I was
like oh my god granny I was like all the
way in sere Lincoln cars I don't know
that many subscribers email yeah you get
a three and still meet that guy I know
it's just crazy I was the unique thing
that so small goes usually when I have
an experience like that I feel like I'm
exactly where I'm supposed to be me - I
feel like yes I gave a $20 tip when we
left which is nice he was very happy
that's that's what I call charity is
when you like really need somebody you
know the money's going like directly to
their family it means so much to me
I'm absolutely good people don't eat
like I don't mind sharing news but like
a lot of time it's like it's not very
one-to-one you don't see really needs
going this is going into charity they
probably got a great infrastructure and
some of them were good out there and
have a low low low overhead
I'm sure it's the opposite but you just
like actually go person to person and do
something nice for him
absolutely so it's nice little traveling
it's easy to do nice things for people
yeah one Allstate like start by being
nice in Canada it's pretty blessed here
I mean I know we have poor people here
but in reality we have great social
programs welfare check the food bank
there's lots of ways to live a better
life and even even disabled people are
incredible ability or your Medicare is
all cover and all that stuff so when I
travel it's like exactly so I'm you know
it's not a perfect system obviously but
health care alone a bone marrow
transplant I heard that's a quarter of a
million in the state our government
scheme is licenses to grow meat that's
true that well they gave to us we had a
Supreme Court ruling forcing them to
give us access before that before that
well I mean just applying Terri Parker I
could take it to Supreme Court force
them to allow us to be able to have
access no we never did for for hemp we
just were like we wrote in and that
minute I tried you're the licensing we
like can we get an application he said
there is no application so we created it
by sending in our kind of this is what
we want to do and then they sent it back
and they said no I got to do this this
and that we do all that and that went on
for like nine months just back and forth
and that's sort of how and they did it
with us
they did it with Jeff Kahn and Jill
Strobel in Ontario and they did it with
I believe they were also some guy in
Alberta he's not the first year nothing
for all the no sorry Saskatchewan
Manitoba and Ontario I believe with the
three provinces that did it and was
awesome well that's an amazing thing now
to hold in your life dear to your heart
absolutely hemp is only in its miniscule
stages in Canada
you're saying the products it's not
producing it so that's true I open
liberal government and some hungry
Alberta and Saskatchewan farmers the
site is like thousands of bankers never
your salmon running the biodiesel and
all that stuff even the oils or because
no like I said if I mentioned it earlier
right the the way they've got it set up
is not it's it's that the oils are too
valuable 2008 still that's okay oh yeah
we were hitting 2008 I forgot about your
children
we were hitting the bubble from 2008
this is 6 6 plus years old actually
smooth it's good it's really nice and
it's uh not quite shattered consistency
of time machine it would be so what
would make it more viable because using
for fuel because the process once
because the value they put on it go to
the supermarket and seeing how much that
oil is valued reducing it's like
everyone's going it's because of the
cost as well to produce it there's no
good infrastructure set up for that to
be on a huge level with a continent type
level yeah and then America is a beast
how many people and consumers are in
that country like Canada can be growing
head full-time just to the fuel America
even though America themselves could
grow I think
it's about 6% of their marginal land not
even their good land could grow all the
BTUs at least it could back in 2000 for
the entire country and that was a jack
herer
hamper Emperor wears no clothes off
halation mm-hmm all right be nice I'm
baked spend a couple of hours here you
guaranteed to be fully medicated it's
gonna happen it's gonna happen there's
no doubt such things I love that you
have such a variety well I mean we
deserve it don't we we do deserve it we
deserve it and when I say we did I mean
everyone kind of my whole trip on my I'm
always showing people how to dry sit and
wet wash and just giving all the tricks
and tips away to people so they
themselves can can experience what I
like to call the unadulterated
cannabinoid hi is it such a gentle
energy it's such an incredible energy
that we've hit I've learned that we need
shirt growing and grade is super
important I'm less impressed with trying
to grow it greater those days I'm trying
to isolate it greater I like the
isolation factor it's nice all right
well I want to thank these guys for
coming down and talk and thank you the
whole world story dude guys thank you
David thank you for thanks so much the
knowledge is amazing and you're
definitely applying here in the hab
industry I had no real idea I think I've
seen a couple photos of you before maybe
but while just like amazing stories and
doctor you're such an expert in the endo
counting system and just your life
experience alone I feel privileged being
with these two awesome guys so things
are happening awesome man thanks for
watching guys peace
you