Howdy.
I I I just wanted to mention too I I
think it was Marcus that was talking
about the the cannabis being grown at
Mississippi State. Two points. Number
one is Dr. Oullie believed in medical
cannabis. Absolutely. Uh point number
two was
that they were given a contract by the
NIDA and they had to fulfill their
contract. The NID wanted uh XYZ amount
of cannabis of a certain variety with
certain potency and blah blah blah. So
uh it wasn't up to Dr. Sole to decide
what to give them. It was you know by
contract. uh he personally developed a
uh THC uh deposit suppository and uh he
tested it on himself and uh he he he
believed in it. He knew it worked and uh
I I think he really did want to do a
better job but it was it was beyond what
he was contracted to do.