some I it was a really interesting
discussion uh just so our audience knows
because I'm not sure everybody is tuned
in on this tell them what EC is and why
it's
important yeah so EC it's the electrical
conductivity that it it's the measure
that reflects the the the amount or the
concentration of nutrients in in a in a
sample or at the at the root Zone
depending how how you how you're reading
from which stample is starting so the
the E is the con in simple words it's
just the concentration of nutrients here
giving to the plant or at the root at
the root Zone and that that has a direct
impact on your on the on the osmotic
pressure at the root Zone and so which
and the osmotic pressure has a direct
correlation with water absorbance and
water uh movement within the within the
plant and and so obviously a direct
impact on the growth on the yield and
and the other point as I mentioned
earlier is with our uh uh goal to to to
maximize the water stress to obtain more
cannabinoids and Turpin that comes with
some secondary effects like uh the Dr
the huge dryb backs we are aiming for uh
they result in in uh higher ACS which
means Building Salt building within the
uh the roots Zone and so that's why we
have to use balanced recipes uh and make
sure all what we are delivering to the
plant is uptaken and not just uh
building within the road
Zone yeah abely that's great you know I
mean as a
chemist and and you know as a scientist
I I I love this connection right because
um uh certainly like if you think about
uh you know you think about electrical
conductivity in plants or in soil what
the H you know that that's like some
electrical measurement that you should
be making on a a phone or a device or
something right it doesn't necessarily
compute with some people on why
electrical conductivity is important in
living systems but I think you explained
it
beautifully and um you you know that we
do have we we do we do have these at the
beginning where we we where we just
started we were using the runoff uh and
then with some probes we do the EC
readings in the runoff but as Marcus
mentioned sometimes we have these high
values of EC in the runoff but at this
at the end we we started using some
probes to read the EC within the the
root Zone and we found that there is a
gap so the the reference of using the in
rock and I know in soil with the pull
through me method it works in soil you
should look at the run up in Coco as
well but in rock I think it's better to
to make it's more accurate to make the
readings at the RO at the root Zone uh
to have a to make better
decisions super and it's not specific
for any any one salt right it just
basically gives you an overall level of
how much ionic material you have down
there right so it's not specific for
like a nitrate or a sulfate or anything
like that right that's the leaf analysis
so the EC would give you just how spicy
you are in the in the in the in the in
your recipe at the root Zone but it's
the leaf analysis that we give you in
details how much nitrogen you have how
much calcium magnesium and it's it's in
there