[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
I'm here with my good friend and partner
Ashley and can oid research and
development and a new friend that we
just made today Ryan so good having you
here with us Bud glad to be here yeah
man so Ryan and I are going to be
heading to Negril in about an hour or
two I've rented an SUV truck and in fact
here's the poster right here we're going
to go actually this is this is the
poster for the soccer match that we're
going to be coming back from NE Grill on
the 8th so Sunday we'll be at the soccer
game before that we'll be at the
stepping High Festival uh Ras Bobby from
I am media putting on at uh is it K
Cayenne Beach or Shay Cayenne Beach yeah
so that's basically starting tomorrow in
the next day Tony and I are Judges and
uh I guess I think we're supposed to be
speaking as well so pretty excited we're
going to film a little bit of the
journey from Kingston uh all the way to
Negril that's going to be about what you
think three and a bit three and a half
three and a half hours yeah maybe four
if we stop for patties and dabs and dabs
and So speaking of dabs of course every
time we start an episode of bubble man's
world what does bubble man do well
bubble man takes a dab why not have a
nice little dab of some beautiful resin
here and get ready for uh I'm I'm
excited today cuz I'm driving I love
driving I don't so much like being a
passenger
[Music]
very nice so uh are you in between
Kingston and the grill you spend most of
your time in MO Bay or where where are
you spending your time these days I'm
actually in monteo B manage B on
breakfast called The Mint Retreat my NT
Retreat oh yeah is that uh uh does
Veronica work there or that's not the
same place as uh Maurice okay yeah yeah
I phoned uh I had sent the the contact
info to friends of mine that are in
Jamaica right now they looked at renting
that place so that's great yeah we can
uh we'll put that link up so you guys
can check that place out another place
to come check out when you're in Jamaica
uh in Montego Bay and uh yeah we won't
be driving well we'll be driving through
Montego Bay but we probably won't be
stopping cuz I really want to get to neg
grill uh you know as early as possible
it's already almost 1:00 with a 4H hour
Drive we're looking at uh 5:00 and
sunsets at 600 so we we right now this
minute we have about an hour buffer
before we miss the sunset it's probably
pretty likely that we're going to miss
the sunset maybe we might catch it
that's okay did you want to hit a d here
no I'm good man you're good you good as
well well I'm hitting another one from
these for these guys and then we're
going to get out to get on our way jump
in the truck and uh head to Negril by
the way it's been over 10 years since
I've been in Negril just over 10 years
last time I was there may have been with
with skunkman Sam and Rob
Clark so this is a real sort of return
to one of my favorite zones I know Ryan
was telling me that it's changed quite a
bit but uh I have to admit I never hung
out on the beach too much I was more of
a Cliffs guy always rented up in the
cliffs and stuff
so all right
I think we're going to head out guys so
uh thanks for watching for the few dabs
that we that I took and uh this is going
to be a fun adventure trust me heading
to neg
grill all right so here we are Ryan and
I got the car we're driving through the
streets of Kingston and I guess we're
heading over to NC Grill I'm pretty
stoked about this aren't aren't you
feeling it Ryan yeah I'm feeling it nice
go do some dabs Ryan just had his first
dab ever like about an hour ago and I'm
feeling that probably probably still
feeling that was going to say and we're
doing a little left side of the road
driving I guess British rule huh those
damn
Brits so yeah you just want to give me
directions as we head out we're going to
head down Hope Road
here yeah we're going to turn by
um the the next ride we're not take the
next ride by the St we're going to go
right by what's up Deon house ah the
Devon house right at the Devon House are
these not signals when I turn this is
this not how you signal this car cuz
signals on this side there they are yeah
not right very cool I'm so not used to
this
car look you're carrying it again like
that oh it's automatic for you
mhm so yeah it's very hot day in uh
Jamaica even the Jamaicans are feeling
Summer's on the way February's over
we're into March and you just feel that
sort of Colder Mountain Air disappearing
don't you think Ryan yeah a little bit
of a hotter hotter days throughout the
in the cities especially it's coming on
to Spring that's why I that's it right
we're getting into that Spring
weather awesome well we're going to give
you guys a little shot here and there as
we drive probably not going to record
the whole three and 1 half hour drive
but uh thanks for joining us on our
adventure
guys so this is a m main road that takes
us to the highway yeah this is
Washington Boulevard
okay seems like traffic's moving a lot
faster the boulevards I guess are
bigger yeah this is a fairly new road
more outside of the
city so just heading up to the toll road
here this will be the first of two toll
highways that will take to get to N
Grill this one is the one to moay
correct y so it goes through Ochi and
then moay or does it skip Ochi it goes
through mon in the Hills all right sweet
well that'll be some nice footage for
people to see obviously this is pretty
sweet you got cane fields on the right
here and on the left and so you've heard
the songs if you continue to burn down
the wheat we're going to burn down your
cane Fields well those are the fields
right there and they're worth a lot of
money cuz they produce cane
sugar they make rum and all sorts of
other things out of it so it's uh it's
definitely a value here in Jamaica and
it's one way that ganja Farmers many
years ago anyway sort of used to fight
back a little bit if their fields were
taken or burned like all
right we're going straight here straight
yeah awesome that s of thing right there
high pro and the tell
here the hustle is on there you go
[Music]
and we can talk a little bit so just
tell me when you're recording recording
now
awesome all right so we're just heading
uh we just came out of Clarendon about
10 minutes ago M from Kingston and uh
now we're heading into whatever everyone
knows as the flat Bridge so you can see
the road's gotten much tighter there's
huge trucks in here and there's a lot of
traffic and it seems as though right now
we're in a situation here's a big one
coming uh this guy's huge um that we're
in a situation where it's one lane so
flat Bridge we're here we'll show it to
you guys soon for the world
the oh this is really
beautiful Little River here side of the
road
I'd be really happy the one and only
flat
[Music]
Bridge which is to get us over this
water this guy's got the right size
mangoes holy Christ see you get out of
you get out of Kingston and then all of
a sudden look at the
mangoes dude I'm telling you why should
we buy some
mangoes not that there won't be mangoes
in the grill but those are nice
mangoes I love mangoes yeah the mangoes
are on ER but on the bananas yeah all
right flat Bridge give him a little show
to the right and the left see the little
water there and cars have been blown off
this
[Music]
thing oh it is oneway traffic
huh very
cool yeah just a minute of this it's
real
nice
[Music]
this guy wants to pass the truck so
bad please don't yeah a good shot right
here beautiful can't see the riv on the
road getting into the hills yeah this is
a really good shot right
there
beautiful well this is uh just a little
piece of the action that you guys can
get when you come do bubble man's tours
you know we're trying to set this up
we're probably going to start it up as a
first time sort of a rather than have it
be an open tour company we're going to
start it as like an initial event so
we're not sure exactly when but there'll
be a time in the first one I'm going to
come down and I'm going to be here for
it I'll be making hash with you guys
I'll be taking you through ganja Fields
I'll be uh you know giving you that vibe
that we portray in bubble man's world
what I like to call the real Jamaica you
know when you're able to remove yourself
from all-inclusive hotels and you're
able to get more into accessing the
people rather than employees that are
working at at at at nice hotels you have
a much better experience you know you
get to eat local food get to hang out
with local people have good
conversations learn things about the
island for people who have been living
here their whole life and then uh access
different parts of the culture from the
Rastafarian beliefs the sex from naab
bingi to uh 12 tribe to Bobo Shanti
these are all different um I call I
think of them almost as like wise men
you know they all have different
information from their scriptures and
their belief systems and they've you
know it's come out of hundreds of years
of slavery with a little bit of
Christianity mixed in there and then the
rest of farian ism through the prophecy
of uh Marcus Garvey and the music of
Paul Marley and of course the crowning
of the black king of Ethiopia Emperor
Haley Cassi so these are all just pretty
cool things that you can learn about
better than learning from it on Google
in my opinion and look at where we are
look at the VI where you just can't
really beat the experience if you like
reggae music you want to come to Jamaica
and hit that Reg music trust
me listening to it here is so much
better than anywhere
else
keep then to the right yeah around the W
Street oh we get then to the
highway the mo Monique Golden Grove oos
Ros Toll Highway all right well we're
down that looks like cops on the side of
the road yeah that is
cops and what do they do just pull over
everyone you know they're not really
supposed to be there because I don't
think the government even owns this
road China owns this road I think so
yeah
Jesus that's insane so those cops are
out there they're they on China's road
yeah
exactly I can go on the the Lane right
yeah is this what we call the fast lane
yeah right lane is a fast lane right I
was figuring cuz the guy behind us is
going about 150 km an hour flashing his
lights on me like yeah 110 is not fast
enough for
me I'm pretty sure he call show it so
we're just on the toll Highway what's
this Toll Highway called the Monique
Moni um bypass Moni bypass so the
Chinese built this beast and Cuts right
up the mountain we're about to show you
guys around this corner how it
goes you can see it just
cutting right
up much faster than driving right
through the hills the old way through
those little roads that turn and TW and
twist this is obviously going to be a
much faster
ride oh we left at 2:30 today so we'll
see what time we end up in the grill
more than likely probably 6:30 after
Sunset but we'll
see
perfect what's this area we're driving
through this
[Music]
is
my
medicine some call
it some call
itana
Mona herbs burner man listening to Jesse
Royal and Richie Spice rolling through
the hills of Jamaica we're probably
about maybe 15 10 minutes outside of OI
we'll have another 100 or so kilm to get
to Mo Bay we might do that within the
hour and uh then we're going to stop
real quick at Ryan's have a dab session
grab his suit cuz he hasn't been in a
grill in probably well not quite as long
as I've been there but four or 5 years
and he's going to uh he's going to go
for a swim as I plan on as well when you
get to that Caribbean Sea on the west
side of the island it's hard not to jump
into the water let me tell you
so see you in
moang here we are getting to the what is
this the northern part of the Island
North Coast North Coast here oi you can
see the uh all the neighborhoods and the
hotels just below these tree lines it's
a little bit hard cuz the well the
road's a little bit rough and Ryan's
having a hell of a time holding that
camera solid so good effort though
Ryan another
road all right so we're in s Anne Bay
just past Ochi between oi and mo bay
oceans to the left there Caribbean Sea
actually and uh we are looking for a
juices or a tasty I see it now as I said
juicy I saw the name
so we're just going to go grab a few
patties real quick here so where should
I pull over behind this guy or
[Music]
[Applause]
something first food of the day juicy
Patty
soya not too shabby I got to say I also
like the uh the vegetable ones with
caloo but they didn't have any of those
so we've got our our little they're kind
of like a samosa the little flattened
Patty I often wonder if it had anything
to do with indentured slaves that came
here on their own recognizance from
India back in the day they might have
brought the
Samosa maybe over time we got flattened
down
anyway definitely worth checking out
when you're in
Jamaica
well it has
been 3 hours 3 hours since we've been on
our road here and it's been a relatively
beautiful drive I mean you can see
Jamaica is an utter and complete
Paradise so much fauna growing
everywhere just exotic flowers and trees
and shrubberies it's just obviously a
pleasure to to drive through the country
we were getting a little bit of a bonus
in the sense that the sun's coming out
now but we've had a little bit of over
overcast clouds and that's been good for
us we like that that uh keeps it cool in
the car without the AC on so give thanks
for
that oh yeah look at that guy's flying
on the
kite we must be getting close to Mo
Bay yeah this is um pre Mo Bay trani
we're in ah trani I'm almost in
F hey guys back again we're just and mo
Bay waiting for Ryan to go get his
toothbrush and a few things that he
wanted to bring with
him and uh yeah we haven't had any dabs
yet I just realized that we should be
dabbing so I realized every car has a
lighter for cigarettes I don't smoke
cigarettes but I can dab a little dabble
on top of the lighter when it pops out
and I can certainly take a ghetto style
hoot and that's what I'm going to do so
here in MO Bay we're actually at the
mint Retreat just out side of Maurice
Ellis's mother's place or at least she
works here I'm not sure if she owns the
place or if she works here but I know
she's a part of it in some way or
another so that's pretty cool guess we
might have to turn this car on to
actually get this lighter to
work and I guess there's always the
potential chance that the lighter
doesn't work as well in which case then
I will not be using this particular
Dabber we'll see fingers crossed
otherwise in 1 hour we're going to do
some nice smoking oh it's hot this is on
voice
anyway
delicious we'll uh catch up with the day
Sunset looks nice ehy yeah we're getting
a good little Rays shining up past the
trees there it's looking good it's
beautiful pretty much don't need the
shades
anymore
and we've heard rumors we've heard
rumors that the police might be shutting
this event down but uh well you know
what rumors are rumors we don't need to
put much energy into them let's just
hope that this event is going to go off
without a without a hitch and I'm just
looking forward to meeting some long um
you know some local gardeners some local
farmers and uh seeing seeing what they
produce for the cup pretty excited and
of course it's going to be great to see
Bobby
dread and uh the rest of the
crew
not
100% driving through the trees I like
this when the trees Touch Above the road
y you're saying hi to each
other going up on the hill
here
big sprawling golf courses beside
us I don't know about you Ryan but I'm
pretty looking forward to some dabbing
yes sir seems like we haven't been
dabbing for many
hours dab
withdrawals what's that I didn't get the
first oh no problem so this is the town
of Elgen just rolling through here
probably another maybe 20 to 30 minutes
away from neg gril it's really just uh
around this mountain but it's it's quite
a little bit of a distance to still go
and we've lost our sunlight so it's
going to get darker and darker but uh
that's
okay go straight straight yeah excellent
get this this is
great
all right we're not in Elgen anymore
where are we at now we are in
what's Sand Bay Sand Bay all
right lots of people out in the streets
this
evening it's getting
darker this is called Lucy oh this is
Lucy yeah oh okay keep going straight
right
all
Lucy Lucy I've been to
Lucy all right there's our first sign
Guys neg
Grill hey first time guys first time in
over 10 years riding in in the grill I
can't tell you how this feels really
excited I wish it was daytime I wish we
would have made the sunet but I feel
blessed to be back in the grill we're
not quite in the grill yet this is just
the sign leading us to the grill I'll
let you guys know when we get we're
going to go down a nice long road
that'll be very empty on either side
with just Beach on the right and then
we'll get into the hotels at the
beginning of the 7 milei Beach and uh
well we'll see if we can't find Beach
comr strange for me to be staying on a
touristy Beach but but uh our place on
the cliffs fell through and we really
wanted to get a place that was big
enough that we could entertain uh the
Cannabis Growers that were going to be
meeting at the stepping High Festival so
I guess uh that's basically why we did
that so otherwise we would have been on
the cliffs but uh still pretty excited
to wake up tomorrow and walk into the
water on the 7 Mile Beach where I was
married in 1995 20 years ago today well
not today but 20 years
ago it's good all right guys guys so we
are heading into Negril now this is sort
of that La last long stretch that's
going to take us in water's right on the
right side you can't really see it
there's Beach there as well and uh we'll
start coming up pretty soon to some
larger Hotel
structures uh sandals and uh all those
sort of all-inclusive places that I
consider Nightmares From Hell but
they're there and we're going to go buy
them and we might even be staying kind
of in the middle of it all I mean my God
I think we're right next to Margarita
which is I'll tell you at the end of
March when it's spring break that's not
the place to be if you're looking for a
bubble Man's World experience anyway in
Jamaica good oh good man I'm just
driving into the grill right
now
yep where you
at where's your
pet
Roots bamboo oh nice that's on the
beach how far how far are you from
Margarita
Ville yeah I'm next door to
it yeah so I'm going to go there right
now I'm at the beach comr and uh if you
guys want to come over and visit you're
was 10 guys we just drove into the grill
and it's 710 now I'm not a big oil guy
but you guys know that my hash melts and
boils like oil so you know it's kind of
fun 710 in the grill instead of 420 I
would have like to have done a 420 we'll
do that tomorrow but uh for now we're
going to head over to the beach comr and
we are going to get down my buddy Kelly
Castle who I've known for basically 25
years I grew up with this kid in
Winnipeg one of my great friends we we
had a ton of Life Experiences tripped
balls together on psychedelics gone to
Great concerts and just all in all had
had a really neat experience together
throughout our life we've been separated
from one another for the last 10 to 15
years we've only seen each other a few
times but every time we see each other
we really feel that old kindred spirit
to uh friendship that we have and that
we've always had so I'm going to
introduce you guys to Kelly and his girl
and then also my good buddy Chester who
you guys may remember from the Amsterdam
videos when I take the tuck tucks to go
to the Cannabis Cup Awards I got Chester
next to me um his son Paris is in town
from Ontario and we're going to
hopefully hook up with him and get some
dabs going with him as well so super
excited guys we're almost
there so this is the spot yep all right
so where do you think we go over here um
this looks like a Lobby what this looks
like a Lobby right here it does it does
all right well I guess I'll go quickly
check in and see what's going on here at
the beach comr
hotel hey guys welcome to the beach comr
on megr beach we made it dude what was
that 5 hours 4 and A2 4 and
1/2 all right well that's cool we put it
we put our time in and now we're here I
didn't quite realize we were going to
get such an incredible room that was
right at the pool there's all sorts of
touristy people over there that uh well
they may or may not be surprised by us
hitting this Mothership we're going to
be a little bit lowkey as we don't want
to attract too much wrong attention but
uh at the same time after 4 and 1 half
hour drive are we are we dabbing we're
dabbing hey I got a call from Kelly
Kelly what's
up we'll come right to the end walk
right to the pool and you'll see us
dabbing see you
soon peace all right well that's my
buddy Kelly Castle who I haven't seen in
a long time most people are just not
going to know what this
is
actually look what we got for
temperature 82 I forgot to turn it on so
we'll do two things we drop that dab
flip this switch put that back on
there and then merly wait for this
number to get up to about
700° one of the things that I really
love about the denail is how easy and
quick that it heats up I often forget I
drop a dab in it's easy to drop it out
as it's sitting right there and then
just to turn the thing on it's already
at 150 so we might not even get up to
temperature before Kelly and his girl
come through the door so I'm pretty
excited to have them actually good good
old friends that I haven't seen in a
long time you know
yeah feels pretty good to be in the
grill I got to say after 10 years it's
different because I I kind of despised
the beach not really into the touristy
aspect of it I've always really liked
the clips
I'll tell you I do look forward to
waking up in the morning walking
straight out here and being on the
tropical Seven Mile white sand beach of
Jamaica pretty
sweet the sounds of the sadas and the
Crickets in the background we got
ourselves a beautiful two-bedroom Suite
here with a nice big open kitchen at and
uh living room so we can you know have
some of our our friends over from the
stepping High Festival we're really
hoping the rumors aren't true that the
stepping High Festival is on and here
comes my friends they found
me what's
up hey we're
dabbing oh
[Music]
c yeah oh
cool yay look we're recording
too you guys
are nice how this is my friend
[Music]
Brian all right awesome you guys want to
grab a seat we're just finishing up a
quick little we just got in the grill
and we're having a few dabs on the uh on
the
deck how's your guys' place it's uh it's
not what I
expected
yeah we've been uh you pretty awesome
Place years ago I thought your first
place was awesome yeah first place
awesome there was one that was like a
private Villa by
[Music]
the you guys kind of like helped me
decide actually cuz I was helping these
guys when they told me they were coming
to Jamaica I wanted to help them get a
place or get get in touch with some
people and I'm now doing Bubble Man
tours I want to like offer the bubble
man V Jamaican train where if you watch
the videos and you see that kind of vibe
yeah that's the vibe I want so I met
with uh NTI yeah Niti and Ryan this
morning and N is like super on it like
organizing all the aspects of he works
at the mint by the way the the first b i
you guys Mo
I back
What's mar Valerie so yeah Ryan works
there
yes that's like one of the first places
but it's good to let let me know all the
different places you stayed at and which
ones are top and which ones are bummer
cuz I want to offer a full you know like
people who want to do hostiles and super
cheap I want to offer that want to go
baller want to offer that too B Bell the
last place we were in was wicked ma the
ma ma like down here blue
[Music]
ma the best
half
hour you probably know where it is Ryan
it's right by Ian Fleming airport yeah
Ian Fleming got airport right before
it's like the second house it was
awesome like I woke up this morning in
my bed I can see the sunrise and the
ocean yeah the well I think you guys are
doing it right with uh you know staying
in a variety of places and I you guys
really having a benefit cuz you're in
the center of Canada you come down to
Jamaica pretty much every winter You
Don't Have To Be A Millionaire to afford
it you like moved to DC and now it's
like have a couple of kids and now it's
like to go to Jamaica it's 10 plus
$1,000 oh I got a fly to Toronto those
flights
aren't yeah so four to five tickets $6
$800 piece then from Toronto I have to
fly to
J so there's no Vancouver to to Jamaica
place literally is a twice as expensive
trip if you guys live in it's the one
really big bonus of living in the
Prairies and living out east they make
it that way every year how many New
Yorkers come here a lot because they
make the ticket so cheap 300 us bucks
and you come to Jamaica return it cost
me 13 to, 1500
bucks his uncle was in oi and he paid
200 yeah for
yeah I believe heard I've heard in
Ontario and
like no they just don't organize the
flights that way right yeah that's
exactly why not enough people want to
get out of Vancouver can afford to get
out of
Vancouver
[Music]
okay my my original dad buddy right
here let go go go go this thing hot hot
hot every second it's more of a vapor
hit like a steam pipe than an actual
he's never dabbed before he dabbed today
for the first time and it was really
interesting hearing his perspective on
it and how different he thought it was
he just kept like he kept putting the
shades on he's like I was like what's
wrong I don't know like it's not it's
not wrong it's just different he's like
I love the way you said that it's not
wrong it's just different he had a
filter on his eyes or
[Music]
something
so stoked in a couple hours Tony and
Maurice will arrive Tony just flew in
from Colorado he's my business partner
down here very cool dude and uh yeah
we'll be dabbing it up I'm sure I'm so
happy to be in the grill dabbing with
the mothership and the rasa drop
down someone vacation right yeah some of
you come to
reconnect
we just walking across the street stop
she freaks up
crab like run across the
street listen when I used to sleep on
the beach in the '90s on in a tent you
hear the sound in the morning you'd open
the tent you see like 40 of them like
that tall and literally the first time I
saw them I thought man those things
going [ __ ] you up you know what I mean
like all this they decided to all attack
you listen i' be up that tree right
there it's like spider fish no [ __ ] that
anyway this is going to be cut short I
want to hang out with my friends but uh
we'll talk to you guys later in a bit
when Tony RS
[Music]
peace