you want hit some full melt Yes
[âm nhạc]
[Vỗ tay]
Man
[âm nhạc]
full
m
[âm nhạc]
Yes
Man
[âm nhạc]
Yes
Man
[âm nhạc]
yes
Hwa
[âm nhạc]
buem set up machine What kind of Strain
you have
there so clean and
clear Come on
[âm nhạc]
fres from the
ex
[âm nhạc]
ganan and pretty like
Gold us
good just And fold good Young the whole
[âm nhạc]
every time
time
[âm nhạc]
When ling cuse We feeling
fine Some people ask me
What I've got to show you mying machine
that my bu Man
[âm nhạc]
bring
time time
time It's good for the end of can
system Oh lovely
[âm nhạc]
great
yeah This is a time time
[âm nhạc]
timeb
come
[âm nhạc]
on is
time
[Vỗ tay]
in Action I
reaction
m Welcome to
the
[âm nhạc]
Herbal
her
[âm nhạc]
Herbal 50 km cru
cru find
[âm nhạc]
We
Herbal
specialist
[âm nhạc]
Herbal Herbal canab
specialist
herb
Herbal
herb pull me over and You Search
tr It
Up and give it a sff
turn yes and i also
got full m edibles all
that dry make you cool and relax and if
you get some you come
[âm nhạc]
back Man Herbal cann
special
Herbal Herbal canab
herb
herb give me
this
ginawa
Na
know
i