[Music]
hey guys bone man here a beautiful snowy
day here in British Columbia once again
thought I would do a little bit of a dry
set so pulled out the dry sift table the
great gardener Matt was here earlier he
dropped off some cannot spotted this big
bag of sift here it's pretty clean
actually no not not terrible terrible
quality but a little bit puffy when you
see the bag smoke like that when you get
the sift floating in the air there's a
lot of stuff in there that's light so
it's pretty soft too so we're going to
take this we're going to clean it up
because I'm using only the single clean
screen right now I've also got my little
field master it's about a 500 micron and
what I'm going to do with that isn't
going to drop a little bit of hash in
there and push it through with the card
so when it falls onto this screen it's
just nice and even for me and I can use
the card to sort of card back and forth
so snow is falling on my screen right
now so we're gonna have to figure this
out all right so hey I guess I'm gonna
go get my card and come in handy
okay welcome back guys
basically was unable to film in the
other situation the snow is literally
the line is right here and when the wind
picks up it comes in and it goes on the
screen so although I want to be outside
for you guys I have to pick my position
well so basically this is just another
quick little dry sifting video I know
you guys have seen me do this great
gardener came and dropped off some
catatonic it's probably about a couple
ounces here two or three ounces I've got
my single 70 micron screen that we're
going to be carting over and lately
instead of just dropping some of the
resin down what I've been doing is I've
been using my little field master which
is a 250 to 500 micron this particular
ones 500 and I just put a tiny little
bit of the catatonic in here you know I
don't want to be working too much at a
time right there I've also got a piece
of cardboard two pieces of cardboard the
big kind of silly one is just to keep
the one that I put down from getting wet
and then I've got an actual flat piece
of cardboard that fits my screen
perfectly so basically using the iTunes
card that mr. Darrin taught us about
we're just going to gently push this
through the 500 micron screen I can
already see a ton of hairs things
gathering on this screen that basically
should stay out of the hash quite
something actually let me see if I can
show you guys what we're left with there
hand side that little little guy so you
can really see there's still some heads
in there but the majority of it is
actually pistol hairs still a couple
more little blue balls of sift on here I
don't want to push the hairs through so
more gentle you are the batter and then
usually at the end I just bang it I put
it in this corner here that's sort of
like my somewhat contaminant it's almost
all hairs I've never actually seen that
this is quite a little effective tool
give it a little blow there's a lot of
red hairs in this product it's going to
definitely be something else to to fix
so we're just going to card this resin
back and forth gently and with a nice
big card we're going to be pushing all
these little system repairs and pistol
hairs and stigmas and such we're going
to be pushing right through this screen
give you a little bit of a closer look
alright so a little bit of the closer
look so you can see here how how that
crumbled up like that we want to kind of
work these larger hairs out of our pile
get left something along these lines two
cards or resin back and forth and of
course when we're carding the resin back
and forth we're creating friction so try
to keep your card clean don't let it get
dirty and try to keep the pieces that
you clean out of your card over to the
side because any little any little
things that don't want to go through are
only going to interrupt and cause
problems so I'll be carding here for a
little while to come back when we can
show you what we've got left on the
screen
all right so we have quite a bit of red
hair in this stigmas pistol it's so what
I've done is I've put my 220 on top of
my 500 the 250 sorry and so what I'm
doing is just a real light sifting to
try and catch those hairs is there's
quite a few of them and they're making
it very hard carding so we've got the
two back together
this is a really gentle sorta you can
see it falling clean you can give it a
little one of these even card or gently
brush and so this is doing is its it's
leaving the red hairs on top of the
tighter screen most of them don't get me
wrong a lot are still going through
because I'm not being overly gentle here
you can see as I give it the wok you can
see that gold colour disappearing or
that red colour orangie colour of the
hairs appearing so nice light
a lot of contaminant a lot of stigmas
and pistol at hares and simple as just
being very gentle you know push those
heads through lovable balls or breaking
up as I do this gentle process whack
down and we'll see we're at about 90% of
stigmas let's see if we can't zoom in on
that and show you very contaminated as
opposed to this stuff here that we're
about to card and this here has been
already carted so we're making headway
all right so just doing the light to
screen gently brushing through the resin
night you can see I've clean I'm getting
a lot of the red hairs out and so as you
can see I've got a couple of clean piles
here all I've done is stack the 250 and
the 500 and I've just been gently
brushing the resin through this screen
I've piled up a bunch of red hairs here
which you can see there's quite a few of
them not sure how much cleaner I'm going
to try to get this it's it's producing a
lot of contaminants so it's making for
difficult cleaning to say the least I
think I'll just put all of this here
still quite a bit of glands and now
that's actually gone a little more gold
and now and then you can see on the
bottom of this screen it's about to
release the resin so I'm gonna get
carding these guys a little bit off here
and yeah a little those hairs out and
I'll start carding this and
we'll get back to you that's going
through real nice so you see once you
get once it goes through so nice and you
get this real nice color you can kind of
move that on up to this other work pile
here and I'm just going to keep doing
the same thing gently carting through
the contaminants and at the end I'll
lift the screen and I'll show you what's
on the cardboard so I'm gonna keep on it
here
[Music]
just pushing the golden color through
and eventually getting left with mostly
just the red hairs stigmas bottom on the
brush a lot of them contaminating the
screen you want to keep this as clean as
we can and it's very difficult with
these little guys but nothing a little
nothing a little brush won't fix all
right so
[Music]
super important to keep your tools clean
when you're using tools you can use the
bubble box screens for this I mostly use
these because they're metal and it just
seemed to make sense today while I'm
doing this that hippie as cold as
possible and then there's the tray of
the nicely lightly sifted
we'll just get that card out and we will
once again carve the resin this is just
kind of an extra thing I'm adding here
in order to remove these red hairs hey
guys just finishing up this can of tonic
I've managed to clean the hairs out and
I'm slowly cleaning I've got a couple of
piles of heads on top here I just sort
of did a better version on these ones
than those ones and then there's going
to be still I mean really these are
basically the same thing carded on top
of the screen under the screen is the
majority of what was in this bag and
here we go for the last of what was in
this bag just dump that right in there
you get resin on your hands leaned it
off gently
[Music]
I always clean it up all right do some
gentle gentle gentle
brushing isn't gentle and basically this
is a method I've been using to clean out
red hairs I don't use this method all
the time this particular batch for
whatever reason was just covered in in
the stigmas so we got to get rid of them
that's what I say we don't need them and
I'll try to clean this pile at the end
as well see if we can't run these
through the screens gently in
alright we got a little bit here to
clean yes these hairs on the way even a
light little breath we'll take them away
so just nice and gentle parting this
resin back and forth when you can see
right away it pushes a lot through once
you get it clean if you put it on too
dirty these little stigmas these little
hairs they're gonna keep it from
happening
so wouldn't take you too long this is
basically what I've been doing the whole
time going back and forth and I can
already see a nice color change on this
this color is already nice
all right I'm gonna continue on here and
we'll catch you guys in a little bit all
right so we've gotten ourselves a couple
of piles here these are my two carded
piles I carted this one the longest of
the nicest I usually like go with color
I have a little microscope as well that
I can use and get down right in there
and see this one was a pure wave here I
went with carding today I've been
working here for over an hour and a half
now so what I managed to get was a giant
pile of systole
some I'd say about 90% heads and then
some 95 plus percent heads so with
carding that's pretty darn good we can
lift up this little guy here go drop
them off gently right here keep him out
of the rain and whatnot we want to show
you what the majority of that material
was because it was a pretty big bag that
we had going on there I'm gonna show you
a little bit closer so you can really
see what we're working with here
contamination wise we got a decent
amount of it and this is definitely not
for my pipe it's probably why there were
so few full-size heads in this catatonic
I suspect there's still a lot of heads
in here in the 45 to 50 micron range but
I managed to get out all the ones above
70 which is what you can do as well with
these screening techniques that I share
so if you have any questions you can
always reach me oh man double-bag calm
i'm also on you know kick @vc bubble man
I'm on my facebook page at bubble man
Freddie's and yeah we're easy to get in
touch with
for a bit rest of that back into the can
tonic bag I mean once again always comes
in handy if you got your little little
brush it's just that next level of
cleanliness really clean up this is
contaminant so it's not really as
important but sometimes when you're
picking up your pure headies it's nice
to know that you're getting them all so
I didn't weigh that at the beginning I
guess I could have but no worries
because I can weigh it now and basically
it's the exact same weight I'll separate
it into a few piles your head ease
almost pier head ease I don't think
there's a nice looking rip of fairness
a big old pile of crap we shoot red
hairs and crap now there is some heads
in here that will get one last run and
here we have complete and total talcum
powder get one it's a saline bottle
it's uh just contaminant let's bury the
lens st about a rough one
so I go give ocean sea breeze we got our
number one grade we call it first we got
our number two grade
[Music]
see if we can get the actual light on it
it's not that easy so that's a decent
quality right there
pretty pretty clear with heads and that
is our second grade we have our third
right here which is the talcum powder
and then even worse than the talcum
powder we have called our fourth and
this was an extra process that I had to
do just to clean this schwag out of the
hash so let's end your dry so people to
dry sips got the edge to it you got a
lot of work to do anyway so there's a
catatonic one two three and four
[Music]