[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh today I'm going to go over something
with you in regards to the infamous hash
Whiting out uh also known is buttering
we've seen it with water hash where the
water hash wasn't properly dried the wax
membrane was still hydrated when it was
pressed and this allows the water to
become trapped with those resins that
are inside the glandular triome head um
today we're going to be dealing with dry
sift but um what we found was sometimes
with the dry sift when we keep it real
nice powder um if it heats up in any way
shape or form it'll grease up and stick
to itself and generally if you allow
that puck that's once stuck together now
it seems to work almost as as though
it's a desicant it literally pulls
moisture out of the air and re I guess
it it creates that white effect where
that it just Butters out I have a little
bit of the Barb that was bone dry powder
when I brought it to um the treating
yourself show and what I've done is I've
broken it up uh it's kind of buttered
out I've broken it up onto the uh oil
slick and I've laid it down here on my
stainless steel barbecue um I guess the
drawer that's right next to the barbecue
it's nice and hot heating up in the Sun
and I'm going to show you how to Simply
with a little bit of heat um we can get
this stuff back to a nice shatter
product a nice dabbable product so I'm
going to pause the camera going to flip
the camera around and show you what I'm
doing and we'll uh get right back to it
okay all right so the the surface of
this um stainless steel is hot not not
extremely hot but I'm guessing that with
just a little bit of
pressure I'll be able to get this stuff
fairly pressed now what I'm also going
to do not just with this sort of
pressure you've got two different things
that pressure create uh an enormous
amount of pressure will create heat and
that heat will help uh with the process
of pressing um sometimes when you get a
buttery hash like this and it doesn't
want to press completely this is
pressing pretty
nice a little bit stuck to the top there
so you see we got a a decent press there
a little bit of a a hair stuck in there
so how I could help this as you've seen
I've already Pro it's pretty decent but
it's a bit still crumbly but how we can
help this is with a simple lighter and
just fan the top of the
hash fan the top of the hash try not to
burn
yourself nice and gentle
Fanning because it's windy the hash is
uh is heating up slow and then we'll
give it another real nice press and I
can feel it already in between the oil
slick that it's
um that
it's a little softer this time now
there's a gazillion ways to do this um
people do this by by uh pressing it in
their shoe sometimes oh this one's going
to stick a little bit more all right so
she's stuck on that side which is
perfect because now we'll light the
other side with the
lighter and a real gentle lighting I'm
not really getting it to to Bubble Up or
anything like that
just lighting it and moving it around
Fanning it to give that little bit of
heat that will allow us
to just give it that final
press and then what I like to do after
I'm done with with a press like this is
I'll go put it in the fridge or the
freezer just for a few seconds not the
not a super long time and I'll put this
in the freezer we'll open it up and
we'll see what we
got all right so we've just taken this
out of the
freezer I was only in there for about a
minute but now you can see we've got a
nice dabbable
product um from something that was
completely uh Whiting out you can now
keep the dabs in one whole
piece and uh yeah there it
is a little bit of a press a little bit
of a heat uh another way you could have
done this really simply put I could have
put boiling water inside of this um
lemonade
glass and just literally rolled over the
hash with the hot water inside here
that'll transfer enough of the heat to
melt that resin up bring those oils back
out and get yourself a nice uh dabbable
product I think it's time to go dab a
bowl all right so our little piece of
hash dabbing it up
[Music]
he