[Music]
bubble man here in the makeshift grow
room that Ron just put together not sure
if I'm getting cut off right here but he
put this table together I've got some
screens we're going to kind of be in and
out of the room getting this table ready
for some uh standup dry sifting and uh
yeah we'll be back go to the
corner going down so we don't shake
right the glasss here that's right a
little T glass after right perfect yeah
beautiful hey what we lose we lose
all right
so
whoops you should see to catches did
Mark look
at really I I hit this with this is
falling over go around there so that
you're going to put up on here yes you
got that I sure do
buddy might do something different but I
think it's going to
work just get it on there just smooth
side out yeah look at that
made glass yes now the glass is that's
the face up okay so this is down right
that's up cuz the bud just set it face
up it doesn't matter it's where all the
hash is just listen because I can't hold
this up any longer so you just have to
execute what I'm taking now that's no I
want you to put it up face up yes the
face up that way is face up okay all the
house no it's not you're oh right cuz
the B was
underne thank you for not like sometimes
you don't have to understand you just
have to cuz this is real heavy for me
I'm having a hard time holding it in
fact okay we oh there we go what do you
think there is like 5 6 7even lbs of
wheat on there Jesus no I don't think
two two well this that looks like at
least
two still it's a lot of weed should we
take these out uh no leave them there
for a second second we don't need the
anymore I'm going to figure this out
this is my 200 no this is my 300 so this
is a
screen that we'll put aside okay I can
make in here no that's not a good spot
I'm thinking maybe and possibly right
here okay move bit Yeah can move these
guys a little bit yeah this is
perfect put this guy this is a 50 Micron
screen nothing follows through it
exactly okay it's very tight so that'll
be safe there you want to put these
blocks underneath this one I think it'll
be a good idea yeah just what you follow
you so yeah if you lift this screen up a
bit you'll see that that the majority of
that resin this resin right here is
right there okay oh yeah KN I had
already felt with my fingers on the
other side the side that had the herb
that's not where the resin was really
that's is no movement I oh when it was
wet I moved it but otherwise I haven't
touched it absolutely great hopefully
hopefully it works good what else could
we use we could use put this look at
that right
there I'll wa for that for well this is
just something that we can put resir the
buds in okay the Finish What is that in
there right now it's it's just a
leftover residue from I'm going to rinse
it out real quick
first okay I'm going to take this off
cuz I'll get one off all right
so we've got a couple of pounds of herb
on our 200 lines per in screen this
is 140 Micron 140 mic on this screen
it's all buds popcorn buds this is
definitely like people would buy this
this is 100% like sellable
herb but uh we're not going to be doing
that with it we're going to be
extracting the resin off of it we've
also got some of this stuff which is
herb that was run through the spin Pro
the I'm not sure if you guys are
familiar with the little spin Pro one of
the trimming machines but that is what
that was run through with these are just
little popcorn buds bottoms of the
plants that never really you know
there's still some substantial nugs and
they
are perfectly dried
so should be
good so I've got a piece of glass here
that I'm using as the
base I
usually go right onto a
a 70
Micron
but I've
got the glass here it should make for
nice photographic and
video there's already a tiny bit of dry
sip on this just
from oh this looks like it's been really
dried properly Ron huh it looks like
it's been well well dried it's the resin
is very um just out in the room orange
no nothing else just going on it
excellent well let's don't heat it all
set up our
screen do I get in the way of the camera
if I go over there if you stand right in
front of it you'll be in the way but
only there otherwise you can go stand
over there problem a second yeah
yeah all right
so almost did you bring that thin in
right there all right so water I think
what a good idea will be is to for us to
put some of this Herb in this
bin and make make some room off of our
table the
flaw yeah it's not like you can't dry
sift with this much material on a
screen but I find it's nice to just make
a little bit of
room this is a lot of material I know
you you don't think so but please this
is a couple of
pounds okay there that's good so we'll
put this right
here right next to your element there or
your little
thermometer try to keep clean I try to
keep a nice
clean we don't
want well yeah right and if you end it
up on right here it's going to end up
going how was it supp glass had some cut
glass pretty good not it's it's great
great I love it you cut the glass too
yeah very nice cool I had Di and double
the Ed I mean it's it's nice to have you
know it'll be nice to see see the res I
took the H with me and showed him it at
the glass Speedy Glass I said this is
cash I want it to be perfect size so a
little
bigger that's
[Music]
awesome nothing you get that through
that screen I said yeah that's funny no
no that's how it works so I'm just
gently sort of gently remove removing
the buds can you check the back of the
camera screen and see if my head's cut
off at all Rong it's right in there but
but is my head out of the camera shot
perfect cool I always like to know I
hate to do videos for you guys and then
have be like halfway out of the camera
or something so yeah so yeah this is
nice if you look under here Ron while
I'm moving this around you can see the
resin falling yeah you see it yeah isn't
that nice now the more the more
aggressive I am the more contaminant
will go through now of course it's
always easy making hash with half a
pound of bone dry bud that's covered in
resin this isn't a
real difficult thing we're going to get
a good amount just because we're using a
good
amount so I'll gently move these buds
around and then what I'll do is we'll
lift the screen up and we'll check the
resin we'll pile it all up with the card
into my first pile and from there I'll
Dr dry sift probably more with this
particular M uh material and I'll put
the second wash of this material over
here not that it's a wash but the second
sift and I sort of do that with each
material when I'm done this I'll put it
in another bucket and we'll take the
fresh out of here and we'll sift that
and that first sift will go into the
pile next to the pile of this first sift
once I get those piles then I'm going to
clean each one individually through the
tighter screen which is sitting over
here I'll doing I'll be doing cing
techniques and uh you know it's funny
right now we're in a room it's not super
warm in here but I can easily be outside
doing this right now I think when we do
the cleaning on the second screen we'll
go outside and do that part we got the
cold why not we'll probably show you
that guys that tomorrow uh tomorrow
morning so all right
so what was that a couple that wasn't
much rubbing at all eh 4
minutes okay okay so got a little bit of
powpow
there I'm going to be gentle though you
see how stuff somehow managed to get
through it was probably there
before I thought I had cleaned the glass
super good but it's very easy for little
pieces it's also what I
cleaned um underneath the glass cuz
sometimes if a leaf is under the glass
and you think you know you think it's
over the glass you kind of try to clean
it a little harder
[Applause]
than really loving the color on nice
yeah it's a really you know when you're
making dry sift I know people think it's
great to see this golden or this white
almost clear hash you know those are
immature heads that have not been cured
this is Hash that fresh frozen basically
right you take the fresh frozen bud and
you run it it makes beautiful bubble but
it it doesn't have that same like dry
cured look that you get from from the
dry
sift what do you think of that little
pile Ron not bad eh not too bad you know
it was very gentle the quality looks
like it's
there and the of course I'll need to
clean it sh yeah we're dry sifting here
Darren we're just doing our dry sift we
got it going on we're making a little
video for YouTube so we've done our
first screening we'll probably go back
to doing much more of the same thing and
once I've got a bunch more piles of this
we're going to come back and we're going
to do our secondary screen so we'll see
you in just a
bit okay I have since doubled my
producing abilities I've got my second
set of screens here on this one I have U
my 110 is the 140 microns and then
underneath that I've got a 70 Micron and
I've got cardboard under that we're not
going to be carding anything right here
but I thought at least it would be a
good idea to get this
material some of it out on the
screen I'm thinking if I can get most of
it
there I'll be able to use this
container to pick up some of this
material we've already
run
so easy
enough scoop it right into the
bucket doesn't matter if I get all 100%
of it basically I just this is material
I've run
once and so I'll putting it over to the
side for
now right here
actually and
then get some of this
guy over clean the screen a little bit
you always want to make sure you're over
glass if you don't have your cardboard
that's the nice thing about having the
cardboard piece taped under the other
screen now keep in mind I have two
screens and the resin is only going to
fall onto the second screen that second
screen is not going going to be
releasing anything
readily uh through it that's really
where you have to do the carting work
and that doesn't happen just easily
so we're
okay very tough work I I would like to
not have the space that I have between
these two screens right now I'm getting
a lot of uh
contaminant so what I think I'm going to
do is lift this up push it right to the
end I don't want that contaminant
falling through it's cleanliness is
Godliness in this you really want to
keep a nice clean area you don't want to
be too violent of course this work can
be done with a tumbler you don't need to
do this the way I'm doing it I like the
Hands-On feeling I like the Hands-On
approach it lets me know the resin that
I'm working with how sticky it is how
much is present just from doing a quick
little bounce like this and of course
we'll probably bubble all of this
material when we're done so I'm going to
be doing this for a short bit longer and
we'll show you what we
got all right so we've
gently gently rub the buds over the top
of the screen and we're going to sort of
lift it up real gently here and see what
we've what we've
acquired really nice
color right right texture it's very
grainy I'd say we
uh we got a real nice material out of
this all
right time to make some dry
sift it's cold night out there boys
that's nice and
cold nice and cold
[Applause]
all right so this bud is cold it just
came out of I don't know minus
10 so I can feel the cold in this
Bud nice material to be dry sifting and
I'm putting quite a bit of material on
there
but why not we
can we'll just do some nice
gentle I've
uh yeah I'm going to be in this material
that's how I'm going to go about
cleaning
it um I do have a variety of ways I can
go about cleaning it the way I'm going
to go about cleaning it is a cting
technique and it's easier if I'm gentle
with the resin rather than extreme so
you don't want to really like be super
violent with it you can if you want but
you're going to be spending more time
cleaning that resin it's not really
worth the feeling of like oh yeah I got
so much it's like yeah you got so much
contaminant I just really want the Hees
so I will start grinding down some of
the popcorn nugs to access those this is
extremely dry material which is great
for dry sifting people ask me all the
time hey does it need to be dry pretty
much it's right in the name first word
dry dry sifting dry material it's a good
idea to make it dry it's not a misnomer
it's really it's it's dry we want it dry
and uh
really some of the most successful
stuff is
um move this doesn't need to sit there
in the light like
that all
right okay so like to keep a nice clean
Zone when I'm dry
sifting I don't mind if the leaf goes on
the ground but I really hate it being on
my underlining glass I hate it being on
the glass anywhere actually I would have
normally if you are going to cut glass
for the bottom of your screen I would
cut it the same size as the frame of
your screen not bigger that way when
leaves go over the the frame that you
won't be in a situation where uh it's it
ends up falling on the glass and then I
walk by and I blow it under and then
when I lift up the screen and look you
know you end up finding buds like
that
so let's check and see what we've
got this gently put here nice and
gent and we'll see what we've got
[Applause]
great color on this
resin not sure how
well all of you can see
but it is really nice
color resing
so not an ginormous amount by anyone's
standers but you know another nice
secondary pile
of sometimes I'll
just I guess we can pull out
the actual metal card that I have for
the glass it'll
probably work pretty
good oh yeah it does look at that
oops using a V Syndicate nice little
glass bubbleman card got a couple of
piles
there all right so there's our
material got a little hair in there and
some other things it's by no means pure
heads I would say that it's
um probably a good 70%
contaminant but that's not to be really
that's not a huge surprise I was uh
making it quite roughly
all right and there's our other little
pile doing
[Applause]
great all right so we've done a bunch of
dry
sifting not a Bunch but a little bit and
we're going to take this
screen and just place it gently over
here um never a bad idea to have these
little guys helping you out as well I
don't actually have them over here but
it's a good idea if you do have them
how's it going Ron good great excellent
just got out of the garden did you yeah
done all right so check it
out that's a good P but that's got to be
still clean day yeah yeah I'm going to
clean it pretty nice well that's what
I'm saying all I know is I want I want
us to have it's a great coloror nice
color we should have um this is properly
cured resin and I was trying to explain
to the people out there that you know
nowadays it's a young group of people
making this uh making water hash and
they're all really stoked on fresh
frozen so the resin glands never really
have any time to to dry properly to to
cure properly and when I mean cure I
mean the difference
between the
resin M the wax membrane drying and
shriveling up you can really see it in
macro photography I can show you the
pictures and um the difference between a
swollen full head that's got moisture in
it clearly still and one that doesn't so
we got a couple of nice piles there how
much fluffy more than sticky though I
well because it's still going to be
contaminated by uh you know I'd say at
least 70% maybe 60 yeah but that doesn't
mean I won't get like out of these two
piles out of this pile here I make it a
pile like that of pure
heads worth your time that's I listen
it's going to be great it's always worth
the time so cuz it's always that's nice
it's it's nice you can if you can use
material that you don't really want to
put in uh you know for any other use
exactly nice have use
[Applause]
[Music]
all right so we've got into the next
step here we had the10 line per in
screens which
are 140 Micron those 140 Micron screens
that I was bouncing the 3 to 4 lbs over
um I was bouncing gently at first got a
little more rough uh later on I'm not
trying to get a ton I'm trying to get
quality uh I managed to get these two
piles here this pile actually looks
quite decent even as you see as I broke
it you can see the whole thing moved as
a pile that's a good sign um still
probably 60% contaminant and then over
here uh on my screen on my 70 Micron
screen this is a 200 lines per inch and
the 200 lines per in screen 70 microns
is the screen that we'll work with to do
our carding so I have a piece of
cardboard like
this taped to the bottom of this screen
it's not really going to put a lot of
material through but
um I'll actually uh end up working on
this screen the other way I'm going to
get all this resin off put it on the
glass and then I'm going to flip this
screen over
over and I'll actually work on the glass
with the cardboard off cuz I like to
work on the top of the screen when I'm
doing this part I don't like to be in
the screen you know it like the way it
works out with the herb that's great but
this was a little bit
different all right
so real quick
[Applause]
all right clean off the resin off of
that
screen then we
will take the tape off the
sides all
right that one
I just came over today on the plane
that's why I originally tap these up I'm
always nervous with my screens oops that
they're going to be
punctured don't really want them to
be punctured so when you travel with
them it's a good idea to have them uh
protected like this and this is just a
nice thick corrugated
plywood um it'll protect your
screens and I'm sure that some ice wax
guy out there is going to say hey you
can just use parchment paper trust me
parchment paper is not thick enough to
protect your screen you're going to want
a nice thick cardboard for
sure all right so we got this
guy I'll kind of get this so
ready got a little bit of resin on this
screen so we might as well save it
all
Hees we make a nice picture probably do
it
tomorrow but yeah getting a picture of
just the heads on the glass would be
nice I'm
certain all right so let's
see bring these guys all the way over
here
[Applause]
all
right a nice working space for our
screen because we've got a great size
screen you can understand that you don't
need to
have um a pound of resin to work with to
Warrant this size
screen it's
doable
with a smaller amount you can keep your
separate grades here at the bottom and
then slowly work your carded resin
in the middle now some of you might not
understand what I mean by carded I'm
going to show some photos in this
tutorial of
tricomes and right now I'm going to be
showing one so when you look at this
Tricom you'll see that it has a long
capitate stock that's its body it grows
out of a leaf it's the cannabis plant
and then on top there's a nice bulbous
head and inside that head are all the
wonderful medicinal benefits that we get
from Cannabis uh as well as the tpin and
the terpenoids the flavors and the
tastes they're all in this glandular
drom head and so when we make a dry sift
single screen extraction what we get are
tricomes we get the glandular head we
get the capitate stock we get the cyth
hair which is a non- glandular material
that looks like a capitate stock but it
has no it has no head and it kind of
points out at the end I'll show one of
those as well and what these things are
is they're gold to look at to the naked
eye when they're mixed with heads they
look gold you think you might have gold
I can guarantee you this is massively
contaminated because we've only run it
through the one screen and we weren't
Uber Uber gentle um what I'm going to do
now is I'm going to take this um
actually I think we should do this
outside so I'll set this up outside and
we'll be right back hey how's it going
everybody bubble man here I'm out in the
cies in some beautiful - 10 or so
weather a little bit of a chilly night
there's a lot of snow all around me
um Ron's been so gracious as to light me
up with the T5 so we've got some good
light I figured it was a good idea to
come out here to do the final part of
the process and what that is we've
already single screen sifted our our dry
sift uh we've got three decent piles
right here got a couple of different
cards I'm going to be playing around
with different thicknesses of plastic um
My Buddy Darren talks about having some
good luck with the iTunes plastic car it
says he's collecting a lot of uh
contaminant on one side and heads on the
other so that's great
um we can experiment with a little bit
of that but mostly what I want to do
today is show you um the simple process
of cing the material I can already feel
the resins cold and I love that I love
that it's cold this is a great
environment for dry sifting so um we're
going to spread our our resin across the
screen nice and
gently get it nicely spread
you know much the way I tell people when
they're drawing bubble the
thinner spread you can get it the better
few little pieces of contaminant
there and just
gently carding it over now this screen
is quite light or this card I should say
we' got a thicker card here I'm used to
a card more along this lines I can
really press it through I don't want to
be too hard hard when I'm pressing but
definitely want to do some of that
pressing keep in mind this dry sift is
probably 70%
contaminant um it's great to be dry
sifting in the winter it's great to be
surrounded by snow I hope tomorrow to
make some bubble hash using snow uh to
cool our water now we'll still use some
ice to um actually break the heads off
of their bodies but we're going to use
snow
uh to cool the water and yes when we
cool the water with the snow we will
filter that water through a 25 micron
bag and remove any dust debris rocks any
dirt that would be in the snow we're
using pretty clean snow that we find
just up the mountain behind my buddy's
place here
but it still can have some dirt in it so
it's good to clean
out so this process is a very slow
process it's not one that you're going
to um do quickly um it's
counterintuitive the faster you try the
slower your work will
become uh I can't say enough about the
cold it's really making the resin feel
great and so just gently I've also
should mention I have a piece of
cardboard that I've placed underneath
this screen so it's the same size as the
um screen frame and so not that it's
going to capture a lot of valuable
things but any heads that are smaller
than 70 Micron and a lot of capitate
stocks and cyith hairs will eventually
be pushed through this screen and so of
course it's a good idea to have
something to capture that and so that's
what we have we have uh you know you can
use glass you can use plexiglass you can
you can use whatever you want I used
cardboard in this instance because it
was easy to bring it outside glass is a
little bit more dangerous to to move and
it makes things heavier this table is a
little bit uh uh shaky as well so I
didn't want heavy glass on it so the
cardboard works great for that it's just
collecting resin that I'm mostly using
in metales so so um for a small pile of
dry sift like this you can easily work
it for 20 30 even 40 minutes and in that
time you would clean this pile down
to you know anywhere
from down to 20% of what's here to even
down as far as
5 to
10% so it's pretty incredible how much
you can lose I'm noticing uh in the cold
here that the resin's not sticking to my
card that's really
nice um I'm really quite happy with
that so I won't be filming the whole
time I carred all these resins out but
I'll end up showing you some photos of
the
before uh the sum during and the
eventual after of the product that I
make and uh yeah just thought I'd show
you a cool simple way to do some dry
sifting you've got your first screen if
you're buying a mesh screen please
understand that it's uh it's marked
lines per inch uh that's silk if you buy
silk screen it's always going to be in
lines per inch don't go asking for
micron sizes okay I'm going to give you
a quick explanation right now the two
screens that I promote for my dry
sifting are a 110 line per inch okay a
110 is actually a 140 Micron okay the
secondary screen that I'm using is a 200
lines per inch screen this screen is
actually 70 microns you see with lines
per inch as the number gets higher the
hole actually gets smaller this is very
confusing to a lot of people they don't
understand the differences between the
lines per inch in the Micron there are
simple conversion charts that you can
google and find online you can also buy
the book hashish by Robert conell Clark
he has a wonderful uh conversion chart
in there as well as um incredible
information both historically and um the
technical aspects of making hash and
even the science behind the Tricom so I
urge you to pick that book up of course
Amazon and all these places have it and
uh we sell it as well at fresh.com
so yeah I'm going to keep on doing a
little bit of dry sifting out here it's
2:00 in the morning I'm in the cies I'm
having a great time time we'll talk to
you guys soon in bubble Man's World
Peace
f
for
okay