[Music]
all right welcome to Bubble man's world
sitting back with some good buddies
today I got John B on the left here with
uh some of his beautiful wonderful
cannabis that he grows and uh some of
the dry sift screens that we're going to
be using today uh further left uh my
good buddy Morgan that's my Backcountry
shred buddy good to have you here dude
and then we got the mailman Brothers
here uh from Manitoba we got Ryan and
Mike and uh they're out from Manitoba
they're doing the good work out there
promoting uh medical cannabis and
promoting cannabis as uh health benefits
and we're super stoked to have them here
too so I guess uh awesome [ __ ] we should
probably start with some bowls we should
start with some Puffin yeah we'll start
with a little bowl what did you load me
up here John this looks like some of
your dry sift that will be some dry sift
oh yes strain um I'm I'm I'm thinking
that would be the I think that's uh the
headband the headband all right well
I'll take a little hit of the headband
through the Mother Ship before we get
started here I'm going to hit some
freshly
um something hey Mark first day on
Whistler let's wear suits oh that sounds
good snowboarding in suits so stoked for
Whistler opening this
Saturday 2 weeks before it's supposed to
be opening oh yeah I think it would be
really fun I haven't been of course John
and I will be at the Cannabis Cup in
Amsterdam in about 10 days I've been
there every year for the last I don't
know how many years this will be the
first year that Whistler opened early
enough that I'm actually able to go for
opening day I'd say in about seven or
eight years so I'm all about wearing a
suit and going to represent most
definitely all right so I loaded you a
little bit of full melt bubble hash that
I've been puffing on on the regular it's
a variety of
cushion uh today's really going to be
about dry sift we're going to go over um
I'm going to tell you kind of reiterate
what I've told you before in some of my
past articles um not so much in video uh
maybe once in the tumble Now video this
is really today we're working with the
4T X 2T screens these are aluminum frame
tight screens it's a set of three um
they come in lines per inch and so in
per in lines per inch the top the top
number the biggest number uh which is in
Micron say like a 200 Micron in lines
per inch is the opposite it'll actually
be a smaller number so our top screen is
110 lines per inch that's how silk is
measured uh and that's about 140 Micron
then as you get a higher number 200
lines per inch is the next one that
one's about a 70 Micron that's our
second screen the one that we'll do the
majority of our cleaning on and then we
have the 305 which which is the bottom
screen it's about a 40 Micron and it's
what we do um the last little bit of of
of filming uh of cleaning sorry so took
a took a little rip and uh got myself a
little sideways there
anyway so I also not only want to go
about how I like to teach people how to
clean their resin from which they've
extracted initially out of one screen
but then John's going to tell you guys
also about you know his method not so
much his method but the method he's come
to appre apprciate from you know working
with the screens with the screens over
last year I just found a um a way a
little gentler a lot gentler yeah just
giv a little finess and uh yeah yeah so
that's basically um John's going to use
a single screen and acquire his 90%
heads um I'm teaching people how to
acquire 70 to 80% contaminant and then
clean that up to 90 to 98% plus heads so
that's kind of they both are perfect if
you've got pounds of weed and you can
just run buds then John's uh you know
the way John's been doing it kind of
which is what I'd call a nice gentle
he'll show you in a little bit we'll get
into it uh little bit different and and
it's why I like to talk about it and
sort of get it out there that when I'm
telling people how to clean dry sift and
then someone like John who would never
do this personally cuz I know him but
some guys might be like oh you don't
have to do all that I get pure heads
just like this and then they come on and
they kind of confuse people and say oh
you don't got to use all those screens
you just need one you do it like this
yes if you're in a situation that a
you're not acquiring sift that's already
made B you have enough Bud that you're
you can just make as much as you want if
you're in if you're not in those
situations then you're in the situation
where you want to learn how to clean it
so it's counterintuitive or
counterproductive to have someone come
and tell someone you don't need to learn
how to clean it because wouldn't you
agree how did you learn how to extract
gentler by cleaning by cleaning and Ryan
Ryan just got a bubble box yeah Ryan
Ryan's learning you're feeling it a
little bit too the counterintuitive Pro
of well tell the story about today you
making your your bit hash I I had some
hash that I had uh free extracted and I
thought you know we'll just clean it up
real quick that's the first mistake you
used you used the you used um I love the
story though the way John the way John
told it the way you you hit it a few
times and you're like do you think it
melts yet and John's like no you got to
work it more and then so Ryan gives it
like four more cards and he's like wait
it's got to be melty now and and then I
laugh and said you know what it was it
was 25 after said I'm going to come back
at quter to 9 and says you'll probably
have like a hoot left there cuz he
thought he had like 10 and sure enough
quter to n he goes I think I think there
might be half a hoot left there well
because it's never about what's there
it's always about the Purity but then he
realized that good did M goes oh yeah
exactly oh yeah and and then and then
right away he's like right back at it
like you showed me you absolutely what
about Darren we got another good buddy
who's been absolutely representing he's
he couldn't get it for about 3 months
and it's you'll see why I keep
reiterating this process it does it does
take a while there's almost a finesse to
it and I'll try to get the camera very
close when I start doing the carding
work and stuff so people can really I
mean it sounds silly cuz it's it doesn't
it's not brain surgery but at the same
time there is so many different ways to
do it improperly that are
counterintuitive that make you do the
opposite of what you should really do so
uh we'll probably have a few more bong
rips here uh while we sit and wait for
for the next stage which is uh getting
some of this herb out of the bag onto
the
screen probably yeah we we're going to
use this herb right here for start this
this is no I
understand uh so basically we're going
to get some of this herb onto the
screen and uh John will show some of his
process of how he L gently bounces um
I'll show macro photographs of what can
come out of a single screen bounce when
you're gentle and then I'll also do a
little bit of uh a more rigorous we're
going to clean through here yeah we'll
clean we'll clean down to three you know
there's not going to be much on the 40 I
want to do the majority of the cleaning
on the 70 so that's what all right we're
back John's going to show us how he
likes
to be a little gentle when he does his
uh first single screen extraction rather
than uh you know rather than how the
some people are just manhandling it I
can smell the minute he opens this herb
you can smell it from like 12 ft away we
almost measured it's
12T coffee like smell really nice and
dank really you know
it's just great smell so so what is this
bud is this some headband is this some
um well this this is um oh we really
don't know what we're being told is is
it's a it's a SoMo diesel cross with a
cush all right it it's got a very cushy
smell very very cushy very very nice but
uh basically um how I uh have been able
to manage my paint control is by doing
this
booah booah and the best part about this
is how I do this is I just basically um
I'm I'm cleaning up cuz the way I trim
my weed and uh I kind
of ever so gently drop so gently and you
can already see look at that yeah hands
on absolutely so yeah just for moving
the nuggets out of the way you can
definitely see a lot of heads and
capitate stocks and also pistolet hairs
that's a lot of orange
hairs so yeah this is the first screen
it's a big screen it's going to you know
a lot of the good stuff is going to fall
fall right through
yeah so delicate way to get some pure
heads it's nice to have the hands on
approach feel the yeah and and now I
start breaking and as everybody knows I
slowly just kind of break these apart as
you can hear them snapping yeah they're
definitely dry enough how important do
you believe the dryness and the humidity
humidity content is to proper dry
sifting huge I've came across quite a
bit where I've actually done it right
right from fresh off the stock not fresh
but you know hung like for six seven
days and found a balance with it and had
some great medicine and called je and go
dude it went all [ __ ] gummy on me
right away and and it really comes down
to developing that trione right that's
that's what it is and hey you got to I
hang dry and then I got to cure it
properly and then people ask me all the
time to be dry to dry sift and I'm like
well the first word in dry sift is dry
so I know it might seem a little
ridiculous but truly that it it's dry
sift you don't really I mean you can go
different ways of using Frozen butd and
there's dry ice methods and whatnot but
it it extracts an enormous amount of
contaminant I like the Hands-On approach
to sort of the old school screens I like
the tumbler I love the bubble box you
know this this is kind of a Grower's
tool really you know this isn't for your
your guy home that smokes a couple
joints this is a tool this is a tool for
me getting my my perfect medicine for me
and U they work great to hang your
plants when you're hanging your plants
make sure you have these three scens
under your plants that's where I do this
absolutely why would you rubber M you
know those 4x8 tables I have two of
these set up and I hang over top and
that's where I do everything and
absolutely that's why I always have this
wicked full melt so many heads are lost
in transport and in touching and in
bagging and in all the these processes
that he's completely avoiding he's just
cutting them down and hanging them over
this screen the only way he could
possibly take it a step further is to
grow his plants with screens like this
just under them at all times we I
discussed that and you know what cool to
have a floor made of this there's so
many times that I'm walking in my garden
I brush up against it and I'm like check
this out and I bring a fresh bug we take
a picture he goes yeah but you knocked
off half it'll take like it'll take all
the heads off the stocks and then it'll
leave like three red fibers it's just
like a horrific like a and then you
really start understanding that you're
like wow but as you can see all of that
basically families are starting to come
off now everything like that and yeah
nice I just slowly do this and I do
this I I know
there's a lot of resin underneath here
right now oh there's still in what John
is doing is he's really acquiring the
one to two% of like the best heads on
these buds the ones that are the biggest
the most mature the most eager to
release those will be the ones that are
the easiest to isolate from the rest of
the chape you know the smaller
contaminants and the smaller heads and
uh it definitely is very noticeable I'm
sure John can attest when he first
brought his dry SI by and uh I cleaned
it up for him it was an eye opener
wasn't it oh that medy was so nice and
then I was like oh then we did that yeah
then we cleaned it that day and yeah I'm
going to insert photos uh while we're
doing doing this today and sort of show
you the process um we'll try to do
photos of a single screen extraction but
what we're going to show you for sure is
the process of
actually um the second screen what it
looks like when you don't um Just Bounce
pure nugget when you get like a higher
contaminant contaminant ratio maybe like
50 60 70% contaminant I want to show you
the photos of how it takes you know 5 to
10 minute increments of cing that
material over the second uh the 70
screen the second screen and how um it
how long it takes to actually get it to
purify before you start seeing like less
of these stocks and I'll show those
photos while we're talking about this
process and and you'll really see what
what it is we're talking about you know
what we're talking about is we're first
extracting the glandular tricomes from
the plant matter but the Tricom itself
oh it's the chainsaw guy we're going to
take a break right now cu the chainsaw
guy okay we're going to start over the
chainsaw guy is done okay is he done oh
you know what so what we're doing is
we're there he goes again we're going to
have the chainsaw guy up here a little
bit later on and we'll actually have a
puff with him he's a good guy and and
it's okay that he's we been waiting we
did wait an hour to do this video he
promised he'd be done at three but
that's okay we love Steve the chainsaw
guy and so what I was
saying is that the chainsaw is very
loud we're going to take a
break it's almost 4:20 now so what we
want to do do when we say we're
isolating the gland heads First We Take
the herb we're isolating the the
glandular tricomes the chainsaw the
[ __ ] chainsaw we're taking a
break all right so when we talk about
the chainsaw is now done we're going to
try this a third time when we talk about
isolating the tricomes from the plant
that's going to get us the glandular
Tricom head the capitate stock um the
cyth hair and potentially some small
particle of pistolet hairs or broken
immature heads and and so on from there
that's what I call a single screen
farmer sift from there what we want to
do is we want to isolate the the heads
just the glandular heads there's that
chainsaw just the glandular heads of the
Tricom so that's all I really wanted to
say and soon we'll have Steve the
chainsaw guy up here for a bowl and
we'll laugh about this further uh we're
also going to show you a closeup of how
I clean the resin a little bit so stay
tuned all right so we'll get a little
closer there just discussing see the
quality of the resin a nice white you
put you just put your card through there
gently you can see that it's a
real nice grainy nice white
color it's got the Great Sound it's very
Sandy this is uh not your regular stuff
that falls out of a uh tumbler that's
filled with low quality trim this is
high quality bud this is probably 90%
Plus Dry set so we'll be checking it out
with the macro lens in a near in the
near future yeah but you know what it's
it's pretty clean but let's clean it up
so uh we photographed it with the macro
lens this is really clean 90 plus per
heads will be overlaying these shots
right as I'm speaking and you'll see
them um we're still going to do uh you
can also feel that hear that sound and
feel if you were doing this it's very
gritty grainy sand likee that's a great
sign um you know it's just almost all
heads I'd be very gentle with this and
just ever so
gently pushing the little bit of
contaminant and there there is a little
bit of contaminant it's definitely it
wouldn't take long you could work resin
like this for a very short period of
time and come out with a a 99% pure
heads easily however uh you had a hit
didn't you John yes and it was melty and
beautiful beautiful just
potent as racy you said it it was it's
beautiful yeah well I'm already I
already actually did it this
morning so because I have um the first
part of it that's it right there that's
what you did this morning yeah the color
so so that is actually um under the the
bottom
screen excellent and uh what I didn't do
is I didn't Harvest to the 70s so this
is just a different method that we've
done today which uh yeah so this is is
the one screen below with all of that in
there and I've clean this a little bit
well this just came out superb
completely different you know literally
what I just did the back and forth
motion the carding gently back and forth
uh in a colder environment if you can it
will push through all those other
contaminants if you have hash that's
only 20% heads you can still use this
technique and get it to the point where
it looks and feels and smokes like this
um I guess really what we should do is
uh maybe all have one big puff and say
all is we got the the big benefit
concert tonight that we're going to
that's right too that's where we're
headed and that's the best well that'll
be good I think I got my uh well we've
gotten to my favorite part of the video
what what what part are we at John we're
we're at we're at the we're now
testing what we just cleaned it's time
to bioassay the product Everyone likes
to put their product in a gas
chromatograph I like to put mine into my
lungs get it into my blood stream and
then get it into my endoc canabo system
and then I'll let you know what I think
of it let me uh we always talk about
oh we won't make mention oh but it was
funny I know that was the large
hit excellent excellent you notice how
it just hangs before it drops just I'm
sure you've already seen the pictures of
this uh about of what we're about to hit
as we just showed you they're 90 plus%
clean it since then we did clean it a
little bit for about 5 minutes so we
probably got it up to
95% W and uh a pleasure John always a
pleasure one ding
ding what would you do without the
Wesson
seriously thanks for their cards all
right load one of those up for Mike
I didn't even exhale that whole head oh
my God was that
nice as most of you know out there that
have smoked the full melt dry sift it
really is considered the Holy Grail of
hashes now not the strain Holy Grail but
the Holy Grail in the sense of
this it seems to be as you climb and you
go through this cannabis experience and
you learn you know I started with seeds
and stems and green papers with thick
glue and that turned into thinner papers
and eventually we got the stems and the
seeds out and eventually I just got the
butt out and then I got all the
contaminant that it was out in the
tricomes out and now I'm at a point
where I just really appreciate I mean I
wear cannabis and I I eat cannabis for
health but for smoking it I really just
smoke where the medicine is located
which uh is the glandular head of the
capitate stock Tricom and and a lot of
people do talk about the whole picture
of the plant which works with a lot
within a community where a lot of people
like just a culture part of it as Abol
working with it and stuff like that
which also comes in there so many
different um uses for the Cannabis PL
you know 50,000 commercial uses and the
the second yeah exactly all these
different things it's pretty cool so
anyway thanks for coming out everyone
and watching the show and hanging out
with all of us uh we had a great time
making some hash with you hopefully you
learn some tips and we're just going to
keep puffing so let me you oh wonderful
the Hang we'll give you a big old bubble
on on and may the full melt dry sift
bless your bowl sooner than later daily
and then daily first sooner than later
then daily all right one more hit for
the
road actually then we're off to the
concert very excited cheers
guys come
wow peace
[Music]