[Music]
all right all right welcome to Bubble
man's world I'm here with d420 K we're
in his uh hash cave you bet where he
makes his sift probably makes his water
hash out here as well I'm guessing mhm
right there behind you all right perfect
yeah so we got a a substantial bag of
trim little bagal bag yeah nice nice
Sugar Leaf there yeah all Sugar Leaf and
you've got your 4X 2T screen set up here
yes your 200 lines per inch and your 100
yes Bubble now right beside that in case
you got a tumble and your bubble box so
you're all covered you got the whole
little sort of hash area here you got my
little bubble bag I do like to do the
water extraction as well but I once I've
uh since I've been turned onto the dry
sift I honestly haven't used my bubble
bags I feel kind of bad about it either
but you know what John did it for the
longest time until I went over there and
got his Bubble Bags going with him and
now he's like he's he's probably made
three batches without me well you guys
were doing the uh the fresh frozen the
fresh frozen yeah when you can get the
fresh frozen that's that's something I
haven't tried yet and I definitely want
to
try that's next on the on the agenda why
don't you take them through how you go
about doing a batch and sort of uh I
don't know give them a brief description
of the process and then we'll take them
through the process while you're doing
that I'm going to hit that Mothership
all right and uh all righty well right
here I like to take my
lead take it out as take it out of the
bag you know I put my gloves on so I
don't get it cuz I use a lot throw it
all over my
hands put it all over here but only a
little bit at a time nice small handful
I just drop it on just give a little
thing scoop it up put it on top of work
tub and I do that for the whole process
of the bag on the top screen here I
don't grind it up into smaller things
and then let it run through and
everything like that I just take the
leaf and just nice good Doh handed
handful rough it up no problem then once
that's done you go to the bottom screen
switch it around start sifting and start
purifying the product it is
substantially good better than anything
I've smoked is the dry sift in the full
melt bubble and uh once you get turned
on to it and unfortunately you can't
even seem to smoke the joints you can't
appreciate a good proper joint even
after you are turned onto this and
spoiled by it
absolutely well you want to do a light
uh sure do start off and do a light
sifting how can uh I will uh just tell
me where you want me and I'm right over
back I just want to get gloves on before
I start messing around with
it now I got your dry sip gloves
on little resin on there already oh yeah
these have these have been used always
between the fingers and stuff right
M all
right excellent love making house even
when I'm just watching people make
cash well you
know I like to
take all good buddy use little pan
underneath or
something a tough of where come should
have that ready sorry that's
okay so we're just going to do a light
bounce on the 100 lines per inch screen
the 150
Micron let the resin fall down onto the
70 Micron which is 200 lines per inch in
mesh and uh that's where we will do the
carding that's sort of the magic screen
that a lot of people didn't know about
you know the 70 Micron screen is what
used to be the bottom catch plate on a
sift
box I can prepare the next one of those
for you too if you
want you get that one on there all right
[Music]
no that right there got it perfect I
just take a handful
out bounce it off of
there move around a little
[Music]
bit nice and gentle then scoop it up
throw it in the next one the next bin
which will be going into the tumble
now for a secondary
bounce this is really your first initial
going for your quality being as gentle
as possible quality yes you know there's
a there's a sort of multitude of ways to
go about dry sifting but whether you're
wet washing or dry sifting you always
want
to make sure that you don't make any
mistakes that affect the quality of your
first batch the heads that are willing
to fall through the screens
initially are always the biggest the
most bulbous the most mature the ones
that that we all want so if you can do
this process
properly uh it's going to definitely
make you a lot happier with h how your
dry sift turns out some people make sift
like this and that's all they do they do
gentle gentle siftings get a pure
product but they don't really know how
to clean product that is already
contaminated or product that's been run
in a in a pollinator or a tumbler or a
tumble now um these products tend to be
highly contaminated between 50 and 90%
contamination so that's where the
secondary part of this process really
comes in the carting one of the things
with this between this process and just
taking it and say you got a handful like
this and instead of doing the gently you
go like this and you got the powdery
stuff and you got like that and you
start siting up like that what is the
difference is is the length of time of
cleaning it up period right like it's
it's a pain in the ass then it takes a
long time with the cting technique it
absolutely does yeah and that's really
right now the technique that's out there
there's a multitude of techniques that
you can learn to be very gentle and to
get an initial very clean sift but
there's really you know not that many
methods for getting dirty resin cleaned
and right at this point in time the
technique I teach this cting technique
that we'll be doing here in a bit it's
slow and it's and it's patient work but
you get the results and Darren's hash is
a clear indication of
that so you spent quite a bit of time in
the last 4 months making dry sift well
September is when I got it when I got my
screens yeah okay well that's 5 months
and of September yeah four and a half um
August was when I August September was
when I was down there and you guys
turned me on to the dry set showed me
exactly what it was all right pop the
bowl with you yes washed it completely
melt like water yes and then uh pretty
much pretty much put me on my
ass right like really [ __ ] high
instantly The Taste the
flavors the nonc carcinog jenin
everything going into your body that
from the from the leaf material
everything like that was gone and then
uh I was turned on to it so what I
wanted to do was
make your own my own because I have I
have good enough friends that have their
medical licenses I have my medical
license as well to uh to possess and do
my thing yeah it definitely helps that
both Darren and I are federally exempt
and we're we're not actually breaking
any laws right now doing this we're just
uh uh luckily for our Canadian exemption
yeah we're in British Columbia we're
allowed to extract the resin so that's
something that
uh uh ferally exempt people in the of
Canada are not allowed to do which is
ridiculous cuz you know to let someone
use something as a medicine and then not
actually extract the medicine to a
purity where it's actually
useful seems somewhat
counterproductive that's the way it is
sometimes all right going
to give them a little bit of a show
maybe
um we could do a or something yeah we
will I'm going to give them a little uh
show them a little bit of your Technique
here just just drop it on keep the stuff
intact so you don't end up with a bunch
of powder on the bottom of it because
like Leaf matter because that stuff goes
through dirties it
up you know when you get down to the
Fine stuff like this right there
you don't want to keep that on there too
long while you're doing this because
this is the stuff that is going to get
contaminated through there and
contaminate your your prodct yeah I
carred that off immediately so we get
rid of that cleanliness is Godliness as
my mentor skunk the Sam man once or Sam
the skunkman once told me every time you
know you can do it every second time
depending on how much of this you got
but um you know for the first run if you
want it to be the best you could have it
do it every time just just have yourself
a clean surface every time you take a
handful of
it and do you know how long the material
was dried oh this has been dried for
uh 2 3 weeks excellent right now yeah
it's uh it's good it's good to go i'
still like it to set up in the freezer
after I've done it after I've made the
dry sift though to uh let it set up
better cure I know that
um the beginning took me about 3 weeks
to to to get the the full melt dry sift
unmistakably full melt dry
sift I thought I was at the one I
thought I was there at one time while
didn't it you told I sent you a video I
was right yeah here you go full melt
here you go buddy and that was probably
after a week oh two week a week and a
half it was cuz it was close 10 days I
think something like that it I was close
closer to to to it to finding out what I
needed to do then than I was to right so
this is this is important to listen to
because
um you really have to reassign your
definition of what full melt is when
you're trying hard to get full melt dry
sift cuz it's so much harder than
pulling bags when the water does all the
work of separating out all the Chafe
from the gland head this is like more of
an art form and you really have to clean
the gland heads out from everything else
and that's you know you when it first
sizzles just a little bit after a week
of cting and working you think man
that's the
Melt but but it was only the sizzle it
was the sizzle now when I messaged my
buddy sent him the video and text about
he sent me that back yeah it's starting
to sizzle buddy you know it it took a
great big like like a bow and twang boom
out of the balloon and popped my balloon
of I did it cuz I didn't do it yet so
bubble man's uh persistence and your
persistence and my persistence on doing
it not wanting to give up cuz I just
hate doing that it just doesn't
happen I got it and uh I made a video I
posted it up on uh 10 days later on uh
yeah 10 days like 10 days later so don't
expect to get it 20 minutes later like
here he this 10 days
after he did it for 10 days and thought
he had it it wasn't uh it wasn't easy
but once you get to that spot what I was
doing wasal played a bit of a that's
right I was using I was I was using the
tumble now and and uh using it for a
little bit longer than I needed to use
so I was putting more contam on making
more work on myself and constantly
carting that out plus there was also the
thing of not knowing exactly what I what
I needed to use
these cards here are a key essential
piece to De to decontaminating your
product and the final end of it because
you can use it at any given time you
want through the whole process but we'll
show you later on on what I do with my
with the screens that I got on how this
is a key player in every [ __ ] step of
this man and we're going to show you
with the macro lens not just this
regular lens yeah we're not going to be
want like those types that like to hold
out and stay tuned I'll show you the
secret later on [ __ ] that we're going to
show you and you're going to love it
it's it's key AB stress it enough cool
we're going to do a little bit more
working here with the leaf and then
we'll come back and we'll get to the
next level so we'll see you soon
[Music]
peace
we're going to uh we're going to make
some bubble hash tonight
too
so we're just going to just a few
hundred GRS just to show you guys what
we can do with nice bone dry stuff that
uh that it can melt nicely
too de your thing
[Music]
the
so we'll just let it have we'll just
take
the easiest heads to get off of this
here
first
knock the [ __ ] heads out of that
bucket that are sticking to the walls
[Music]
absolutely a couple little
handfuls one and then off don't be too
don't be too rough with
it sometimes you know you can be in a
rush but
you can't be with this you just can't be
when it comes to this slow and gentle is
actually the best process if you want
the purest heads in the quickest way
because uh if you don't you rough it up
and you get all that all this little
dark material that's on the bottom here
you know all this kind of stuff that
gets contaminated in there if you use it
to if you do too much of this that way
uh we're just taking the best of heads
right now we're going to let the tumble
now do the rest of the
work for separating and then there's
more work to be done sifting
that and off and then even by then
there's by no means is all the resin
going to be off this is a first stage
dry sifting gets off a certain amount of
resin uh bubble bags are obviously much
more efficient
and then final processes like coconut
oil or moonshine oil uh would be the
next uh you know full for sure fire way
of extracting you know 99.9% of the
canabo from the plant
matter what's really nice is that it's
cold in here I live in the North
so it's
chilly my shop is
cold not too cold but cold enough that
you know we got a a little
extra bonus feature when we make our
hash up here in the winter
time soon as I'm done mixing doing a
little bit of sifting on this the little
Gentle Touch we're going to have my
friend my two friends come up here and
help me lift the uh screen off and
replace it with the bottom L put it on
top
we'll give a nice brushing all around
these screens and clean all the leaf up
before we even attempt to lift this
screen and pull out the resin cleaned
screen that's right cleanliness is the
best it is cleanliness you're going to
have to clean it you're going to have to
clean it out if you're not you're going
to have to clean it out your dry instead
of just sweeping it off the edge all
nice like you could have in the first
[ __ ] exactly whoops this didn't mean to
get a glass
of It's just sometimes when people are
rough with their [ __ ] I just can't help
it it's dryp man got to be nice got to
be gentle like you you're making love to
it not [ __ ] [ __ ] it God damn it
oop sorry fck I got to get off that I'm
dropping the Fone like how many 15 times
and it's all good sorry guys you're
making hash man it's exciting sorry
man you got nice material what do we got
here OG cush or OG cush trim yeah Sugar
Leaf fan leaves are all picked off
[Music]
well all right well
go set the camera up on the tripod and
get ready for
uh actually I'm going to keep the camera
nice and close for when the screen
lifts
so yes we'll be
[Music]
back important
step everything you drop from the edge
of this thing no matter how careful you
think you're going to be you're still
going to have to pull it out of your dry
sift cuz uh you're [ __ ] up by not
cleaning it
[Music]
right
see what that St for that card mm weird
weird stay
tuned
static you like CH salty is your
friend some cards don't do that some do
the original ones I gave with the bubble
box were insane how much they did it
people were like man these cards are
just getting covered it's like yeah
they're static cards but people I don't
know couldn't get the hang of
it so I ended up putting this the
different card
in do you have any of the other cards
left the old ones the old stock oh yeah
I think I'd like a box of them
myself all
righty clean this up a little bit
more
okay what I'm going to do I'm going to
take this off I'm going to stump it and
clean it up a little bit before we put
it on the bottom okay so here we have
our our
resin optimally you'd want to use a air
yeah Force air works good for
sure okay guys can I get you guys to
give me hand here for a
second I'll get you to one on each side
just lift up a little
bit I'll slide this out
here put her down where this one was
thank you very much guys
and here we are on to the next
stage oh this is when I like to start
pulling out the little
gadgets yeah first things first for me I
get hairs yes
absolutely and uh I do see some right
off the bat so what I'm going to do is
I'm going to get my
tweezers want me to tell you change sure
okay absolutely a balloon rubbed on your
head and ran across that resin before
it's moved and Disturbed will pull out
hairs and dust and debris with static
electricity well you know how you can
rub a balloon and I got grand kids and
have balloons I think I have one yeah I
mean you don't have to do it right now
but it's definitely like a future trick
that you can play around with all right
well we came came inside and we're going
to hit the Dil we got some bubble hash
OG cush and dry sift OG cush should we
hit the Dil at 810 or you guys want to
turn it down good W taste of your rips
maybe
750 760 760 sure so when it's at a lower
temperature you 766 flavor 766 it is 767
it's a pal Drome so be it all
right
[Music]
no
no a gja
planter call me the gja
farmer call me the G
keep G
babon
come big stinking helicopter flow
through the with them call it them call
it we never
when when we fertilizer yet this
Spitting Fire and I'm a with a hot
temper dig up stinking rocket
launcher
theop
call me the G
keep
G
me make do get no meditation I them
could have give it to them sick patient
make meditation I them could have new
medication singers get some
inspiration spread
message a
g call me
garmer
G
call me the
gja the me put
G
come g g g g if you don't want to call
it it if you don't want to call it it
marijana call
it g
all right well we may do another
round but we'll see outside for some
more hash some more dry sifting and some
more importantly tips on how to get your
dry sift clean to 99% pure GL
[Music]
hits yes yo all right guys we're back
just had a fresh denail rip of uh some
dry sift yeah go figure full melt dry
sift so
I guess we're going to clean this resin
we've got the this resin's falling down
from the the 100 lines per inch the 110
lines per inch which is about 150 Micron
it's falling onto this 200 which is a 70
Micron and uh yeah you want to take us a
little through your uh yeah you bet
through your little personalized process
once I've got to this stage depending on
your your uh your resin heads that
you're getting and what you're using
you're either looking at like when we
took pictures and stuff like that it' be
like like you saying about
50% is where it's at right now right now
to me what I've seen in my experience
from using the resin heads I was from
the material I used before which was
using UV rays to produce res more resin
heads fatter resin heads I was getting
more like 80 80% 75 85% heads I did the
same thing as here so there were better
heads in that sort of situation there
are hash making strains there are
strains that are grown better than
others that just are perfect for sifting
they just produc Skunk Man Sam's talked
about it forever how his skunk is an
ultimate producer and when he makes
resin with that it just rains hard and
it rains pure you know the SLE stack was
another one he crossed that DNA genetic
SLE stack with um his skunk and it was
also an Uber producer of
resin so the uh this here strin we're
using is an OG Kush strin done by one of
my one of my friends that does a medical
Garden gives me some of his some of a
sugar leaf and uh it's so stinky and so
nice we uh I love I love playing with it
I love smoking and everything yeah it's
got a good bouquet it's Uber strong it's
crazy strong it's great I mean OG Kush
obviously is a great strain to make hash
with so yeah what what we've got now is
because we've got about 50% contaminant
we're going to have to to do some
carding so I'm going to take the camera
off the tripod for that and it'll just
be kind of closeup of Darren working and
carding the resin and then we'll do some
um it's probably going to take a while
how long do you think would you give an
idea I mean I don't even know what's
here maybe 10 G or something yeah it uh
it'll take me a good hour and a half
probably if I want it 10 to 15 GS going
to turn that down to like 5 to 7 with
the 50%
um contaminant that's in there take an
hour and a half that's important for
people who are watching cuz they don't
really you know did you have any idea
would take that kind of time the whole
part of the taking the time was those
little tiny tiny particulates exactly
that you can't get out without a
microscope or one of those knitting mic
knitting um yeah the big the big uh
magnic AB old ladies do needle point on
big magnifying glass a big magnify those
are great for hash making if you could
get a big square that big and have one
of these lights you shining right down
on it kiwi had one of those glasses with
the light with the lights and one lens
over here jewelry glasses I've got them
ordered I've got a couple pair ordered
on pretty close down I i' prefer a
custom big that's what I would like fat
square that you could just put your
hands under and work with your little
actually making a coffee table I'm going
incorporate that into it just for my own
personal good idea but anyways back to
the particul
when my biggest problem when I was first
doing it it took me like 3 weeks to
figure out how to get the clean and it
was the material I was using which is
this material right now as well so what
I'm going to have to do is what I
stumbled across
is iTunes cards are very very staticky
the back of the iTunes card the iTunes
card comes on this does it not uh yes
yes this is yes exactly good point
iTunes card comes onto this stuck onto
this like that and then you pull it off
$15 card this is what hangs on the on
the wall now this is the card that you
want either side you use is going to be
fine when you're running it one way it's
going to do what we're going to show you
on the video and I'll explain it to you
in very fine detail and show you exactly
how it's done with this card here and if
you stumbl across it doesn't have to
just be this one but this is the one I
stumbled across a certain type of
plastic and it just one that one that
holds a static charge that's really kind
of like the more static charge the more
you're going to you know attract things
to the card so one side is going to
attract particulate the other side is
going to attract P pretty much pure
resin heads and there's going to be some
pistolet hairs and stuff like that in
there and you know like it's it's we'll
get it out but the uh what I I'll show
you exactly what I do all right well
we're going to get him to start working
some of the resin I'm I'm going to grab
the camera and give you a better View
and uh yeah we'll be right back with
that all right we're back with Darren
he's about to uh start working the resin
on the bottom
screen it's got a nice sound you can
definitely hear that it's not 80%
contaminant that scratchy sound on this
on the screen granul granual yeah and
you'll only hear that sound improve as
you improve the purity of your resin
heads cuz that's what we're doing here
here right you understand the quality
has already been decided we are now
deciding the
Purity and Purity plus
quality equals full
melt I like to pick out some hairs when
I see them so I keep a pair of tweezers
on hand
always thank you no problem those was
hairs don't just come off do they
no oh yeah you can I can feel it this
might clean up quicker than an hour and
a half you know but
uh count on it I just said that and it's
probably going to take me [ __ ] 2
hours but it's okay I'll do
it it's always Murphy's Law oh yeah now
what I'm doing
here is um I like to just drag the card
over to take the first layer of stuff
off because underneath that layer it's
like gold and dirt the gold nuggets are
going to fall down more and the dirt's
going to stay on top and if I'm staying
you mean the opposite the dirt's going
to fall down through and the gold
nuggets will stay Oh you mean in the
pile in the pile like this as it's like
this I'm just going to scrape the top
layer off and underneath it's going to
be more granular exactly you'll have
easier that up into a separate pile plus
it's always easier to clean small
piles you know you always want to get
hear that most yeah right so it's
different here boom I'll give her a
flick cuz I like you're always flicking
your screen sorry buddy I use a little I
do that right there that's what I do a
little T I always have a tool in my hand
like that and I crack my card now this
stuff here is you can hear it you can
hear it just
scratching I love it love that noise
because I know I'm close to what I want
to get to well here you know what let's
give it a pause all right and we're
going to photograph that with the macro
lens and see if we've Inc if that is
indeed a higher percentage of heads and
a lower percentage of contaminant all
right we'll be right back
okay from
here so
let
[Music]
I just work my way from this side all
the way over the other
[Music]
side and so you know I've mentioned what
this process is and this is sort of the
simple process that so many people
didn't know over the years and I didn't
know this over the years this is carting
this is gently pushing down on this on
the resin and and spreading it across
the screen not too quickly in a nice
cold environment and what you're going
to do is you're going to push through
the capitate stocks the cyth hairs you
get that hair and uh you're going to
push up Hairs To The Top as you car the
resin as well so any contaminant stands
out and the more you clean it funny
enough the more the contaminant stands
out the more you get out
uh put to the
side that dirty dirty stuff cuz there's
a lot of contaminant in there m right
off the
backat so I'll do a run I'll do do one
side all the way from the top to the
bottom on one one grid
right get all this other little stuff
here I'll have a look at the card mhm
and see okay contaminant there I'll just
take this and put put it over to the
side a little pile up there and then
what I do on the other
side is I'm going to leave that on for
some pictures I'm going to leave the
rest of it on the other side for picture
cuz I just wanted to show you this but
uh then I'll take this stuff I'll have a
sp I'll have a spot on the side well I
do it with my other little screens sure
yeah no problem I want to leave this on
cuz this will be a good
picture absolutely and um basically once
I've made this little pile of this stuff
like trust me after you do this for 2 3
months the pile of this stuff you're
going to have is going to be [ __ ]
incredible oh yeah and then you clean
that up it just needs a slight cleaning
and it's just crazy good [ __ ] so clean
and it's it's beautiful you know ex
exactly what I mean exactly and if you
don't know you need to find out you need
to find someone that you know that does
it you need to find some screens and
order them up yeah get in touch with us
get in touch with us at Fresh headies
we're always down to help answer
questions whether you want to get your
own screens made or you need the sizes
or you want to learn about the
information we'll gladly sell you the
tools as well at fresh.com
um we're always I'll leave this one for
some pictures excellent and I'm going to
start with a new card now once
again iTunes [ __ ] rule man these
cards are the the the whole key that I
stumbled across that helps me clean my
product the
fastest when you're carting
it and I don't really press too hard I
usually just let the weight of the card
do do the work for me and that could be
why it might be taking you a long time
cuz I particularly like to press I don't
press really hard but I I kind of do a
sort of this Stu style
thing you want me to clean on this side
High Tunes down yes please all right so
I would kind of do
like this sort of
thing because you got to really push
that contaminant through and the heads
are stronger than you think now I don't
want to push them too
hard you see that's that's something I
did not know because we never got to get
together just like this no exactly yeah
so it's just like something you can play
around with there's another tool to add
to the Arsenal put it a little more
pressure and then I would just literally
spread it thin and I I don't usually
work this much I would usually work you
know I would
clean a section of
screen and I would go
through you know maybe something
like like this for starters M you know
where I could spread
thin and just sort of start working it
and I might work that for 10 or 15
minutes and then put over a little pile
and then you know get more and put that
in a separate pile and then I get a
bunch of little piles and I start
cleaning through those let's see what
you get on your your heads here too you
see you really
get a nice color on that one side hey
yes definitely and uh it's just
something that that I really love so
much now you see the way the the lines
are there it's not a smooth transition
anymore mhm that's where you
got your stuff on your card you need to
clean off so that's when I'll take when
I see that happening I'll take my card
I'll clean off the side that needs to be
cleaned off from the contaminant I'll
have my pile and I'll start my pile over
somewhere let's just say in the corner
here
here and then we'll see all this stuff
here yeah the little resin melted bumps
yeah that's going to [ __ ] [ __ ]
up yeah it's always good to keep your
card clean whether you need to just have
a bunch of them present or you know you
can really see the difference every
minute or so see the difference not a
bunch of lines in
here it's always good when you're
sifting too to bang your car and clear
clear it of uh you know things that it
might hold cuz those things if your if
your card's picking up a lot of stuff
and you continue to card with that card
you'll melt that stuff to the
card it's just
inevitable but if you want to collect it
on the cards then just have like a
collection of cards boom
contaminant good
stuff and the thing with the iTunes
cards too that I
like
you can flip it around use the bottom
side yeah it's got a good amount of
space on it bigger than your average
card
Yeah so basically to go over this
process again the carding is pushing
through breakable brittle contaminant
I.E cyith hairs capitate stocks um small
particles of leaf uh brok pieces of
pistolet hairs and dirt and debris and
hairs now hairs are generally easiest to
pick out with the help of static
electricity using a balloon you can rub
that on your head if you're not bald and
hold the balloon over the screen and
it'll pull small hairs and little bits
of dust out the cing technique will do
the rest which is going to push through
the breakable contaminant while the
strong gland heads they'll stay right on
top of the screen even even with some
decent pressure you won't push the
tricomes through um the gland heads the
Tricom heads through a screen that is
tighter than the diameter of said Tricom
head so we won't show you this whole
process we've talked uh quite a bit
about uh what's going to happen here
what we're continuing to do Darren's
telling you a little bit about his his
uh process and what he's he's sort of
created to or started to do for himself
from you know the basics that he learned
through fresh headies and
myself and that's what we kind of hope
for everyone we want to set a simple
parameter get you guys producing melty
resin and then from there once you have
that Foundation of producing 98 95% pure
gland heads um then you can start really
playing and experimenting from there
because you've got a good foundation and
you know where you're supposed to be you
know if you're playing is leading you
away from there or leading you above
there yes and if you keep at it and be
patient trust me I don't have the most
patience in the world but it was very
much worth it on every angle on every
level I can't express it more it is
just it's a beautiful thing beautiful
thing yeah
exactly all right well we'll uh continue
to clean here at the res and we'll get
back to you with some macroscopic
photographs of the final cleaned product
and of course um some denail melt hits
so keep watching Bubble man's world we
appreciate your comments we appreciate
your views and uh don't forget to go
follow Darren at D4 uh Mr d420 K on fa
uh on YouTube and in fact I'll have the
link in the comment of this particular
YouTube video so you can just go click
the link thanks a lot guys peace
peace hey guys bubble man here uh Darren
d420 K just went to collect some plants
uh just some branches that we're going
to photograph and while he was gone lo
and behold I took all his dry sift that
he had here and I cleaned it up into
little
piles of
contaminant more
contaminant and then of course our
favorite there's the 70
Micron and here's the 120 Micron so he's
going to be very happy there's probably
a you know 5 to 10 grams or four to five
well four to 10 grams in each pile I
think this one's much slower maybe only
a couple of grams in this pile
sorry but very nice nice little thing to
do for a buddy you know clean up is dry
sift um of course as you guys know I
teach the carting method I've always uh
uh taught this method for the last
several years I don't even know how many
years now but it's an effective method
to clean the glandular heads and it's
what Darren's gotten very good at and I
just thought I would treat him to a
little bit of a secret and sort of um
you know I've learned another
method in the last 6 months that is not
really my method to share but I'm
allowed to use it so I basically cleaned
these piles of dry sift
up for
Darren isn't that
beautiful anyway I hope he's going to be
happy we'll see hey guys welcome back to
Bubble man's world we're finishing up
the dry sift video today with d420 k um
I'm actually out of here in a couple
hours I'm flying out but I still want to
um photograph those nuggets that you
brought by those Freshies those will
look really beautiful so what strains
did we get there we got the OG Kush we
got the Brooklyn mango and the bubak
cush bubak cush okay so those three will
be coming up in macro photography living
hash that'll be really cool growing
crazily too with the UV rays oh right
yeah we'll talk about that a little bit
we'll talk about that a little bit um
also you know we were going to we're
going to finish up the dry sift video
this is the last installment of the dry
sift video um we're going to have Darren
go outside and just basically show the
process that I've been sharing for the
last couple of years of how he cards and
sort of his little tricks and techniques
and stuff the cards that he uses in his
brushes and such and we'll talk about
the screens and whatnot but when he was
away and he went and got um the cut
branches I actually took a bunch of his
dry sift and I cleaned it up for him so
it was like a surprise wow so yeah up
here in the background we have piles of
kind of what it looked like like
originally this is um there there are
heads here stuff the stuff out of the
tumbler exactly yeah this is all below
um 70 microns in size um these are also
some contaminants these these here would
be actually smokable and or metable much
stronger than this particular one even
though to the naked eye this is looks
garbagey and this is lighter in color
but clearly these two piles um this one
was on top of a 120 screen that I took
off and cleaned and this one was on top
of a 70 Micron screen that I took off
and clean so I was able to um use a
method that I picked up uh basically a
method that I'm not in a position to
share just yet but I hope one day that I
am I I promised obviously my mentor
skunkman Sam that I would not mention it
or or show show the method I should say
but I am allowed to use the method and I
can that's respect brother respect you
know took me yeah I waited 19 years to
learn such a thing and now that I've
learned it I'm just going to be very
respectful and uh just I give all the
props to skunkman S you got to earn it
it's a huge thing to look down at this
it looks surreal have you ever felt hash
well no that's the thing like I i' this
is another game another game changer
it's like
it's it feels wild
hey why don't we do a little dab we
could like you know like this here
we'll
just I can't get it off we might as well
do this for the dab here yeah it's a
simple half second of a pinch and this
stuff turns into almost transparent
see-through dabs we'll make a little
video for you guys so you can see it's
absolutely beautiful that is for sure
there you go D thank
you and uh yeah we'll get back into the
shop here in a little bit Darren will do
a little bit of his cleaning we'll show
you what he cleaned under the macro lens
we'll show you a little bit of what I
cleaned under the macro lens and we'll
you know we'll we'll say thanks to
Prince George for having us and we'll
look forward to the next time we get to
to come back here cuz it's been a great
trip met some awesome people sledding
yesterday with noodles and Jake and just
all Darren's friends are just all really
good good guys all
around BR George ain't so bad wow yeah
that is unbelievable actually smooth
is that
not
wow that is uh look at that e that's
pure pness man pure
[Music]
goodness
beautiful tasty tasty see you guys in a
bit all right I just heard d420 pull up
he went to uh grabed some branches for
me to photograph with the macro camera
so let's let him in what's up buddy hey
bud oh what you got there well there's
uh there's some OG Kush there's some
Brooklyn mango some babush oh jeez it
smells good it is beautiful okay well I
was hoping I'd get pulled over so I
could say [ __ ] off copper get away from
my
medication but I didn't so wicked well
let's go hit D denail rips and uh I'll
get my camera ready and we'll photograph
some of these buds yeah you you guys
quick stuff yeah so be we're here uh
with the the freshh Nuggets that or the
fresh branches that uh d420 K went and
cut to photograph and so these are like
untouched absolutely epic
beautifulness oh yeah yeah those
are oh
[ __ ] this here uh zoi
Kush and uh it the GU just
um the formula the lighting this is
grown for the tri chromes so as much and
as as big of Tri Chrome you can get and
the way they do this look pretty fat
nice they don't use a th they don't use
thousand Waters they use 600s they use
UV rays UV lights that hangs all over
the place cuz that's key to building
they uh they do a job they are
incredible of what they do want to throw
that one in there she broke
off now that's the OG Kush now where
would you like to put it so that we
don't have to put it back in so you want
to take some good um you know what I
don't have anything set up right off the
top of my head just put it on the box
here yeah I mean honestly the way it is
it can lay anywhere and I can just come
over and as you know what I mean like
there's enough of it that won't be
touching that it'll be perfect okay so
and then what is this one here that's
also the OG Kush oh another OG yeah it's
Fox tailing out up top there e God it
smells so good anyway I'm going to get
to photographing these right away
they're so beautiful uh let's show them
a branch of each one at least so that's
OG are we going to Brooklyn next no this
is uh this is the bua Kush oh Baba Jesus
that's just a side branch too it's not a
top or nothing it's just a side branch
it's incredible density on this gu
really um big giant fat 2 L size smell
it's hard to hold cuz it's so heavy
unbelievable resin
production huge resin like look at even
the family here oh yeah no no that's why
the dry wash is going to be so nice all
right so that's
Bubba jeez Bubba is one sweet
lady one sweet [ __ ] now we have the
Brooklyn mango now this is something we
are very very happy with old SCH look
look at the fox
tailing yeah that's old school looking
that's cool you know like look at that
there for oh
yeah look at the resin totally different
structural totally completely different
herb Al together but
yet really pretty it almost reminds me
of some of skunkman Sam's skunk cuz this
is the way it grew it just grow nugget
with very little leaf and before anyone
had anything like it he had it he bred
it it came out people were flipping out
over it and that's when I first saw this
I said old school cuz it's all bud you
can see this 1 2 3 four five you can
count the leaves on
it you know yeah yeah
yeah I can't wait to get the uh the
Sugar Leaf from this and uh mango and
and have the flavors of the the Brooklyn
mango the bub aush and the OG I'm going
to get to shooting right away I'm just
too excited I'm going to get my macro
lens going and we'll see what's going on
in these
plants peace D 420k here doing the last
uh last video of the dry sift the final
stage uh on Bubble man's world with
bubble man right now yeah I'm here guys
just off camera de is going to explain
to you guys uh the final step in the
process and how he gets his headyy
headyy dry sift my final step anyways
that I got from you and this is where I
like to finish we could do the big
screens but I like to sit down I got a
screen in front of me I got the big
screen I got the stereo I can enjoy sit
down relax and do it now this side is
the side that I use my brush I use my
card these are my two favorite tools for
the 70 screen
and I'm taking my final product and I'm
sifting it across you know I'll drag it
across like like we were showing last
night and you we thing with
that as we do
that the cart will get
dirty we'll start with a nice clean edge
here you can see that you take your
product and as you're go use only one
side to to drag it the other side don't
drag it with and as you do that it's
what these these cards I find most is
where I get the most contaminant I trct
the most
[Music]
contaminant on this side of my card now
this side of my card I'll take after
I've got some contaminant on it and I'll
just brush it off over here put it to
the side this side has nice clean
looking stuff there's lots of there's
lots of dirted like um contaminant in
there too but it's not the leaf matter
it's the stocks that hold the resin
gland and the resin glands I'll take
that all together and I'll I'll take
that aside I'll just put it on a nice
spot and after working this for probably
10 hours or 3 weeks or so you've got a
nice pile of that really pure looking
stuff clean and then I can clean that up
afterwards and get some nice clean stuff
but as I'm doing that I'm cleaning
this and this card really attracts the
contaminant it took off
probably hours worth of sifting for me
after I sift for a few minutes I look at
the card contaminant
boom I take it off I don't have to do
that every time with this time let it
build up you don't have to scrape it
off now it's all over to the side moved
it onto the one side that pile nice pile
on the card more contaminant let's get
that
off saves pushing it through the screens
and taking more time doing it it
quickens the process I can't stress it
any type of C that the TRX a static
electricity will do that and that is one
of your best friends when it comes to
discarding your your sift
period I don't want to lose too much of
that there's some really nice buildup on
that can you see that bubble man M
that's beautiful so I take that just put
her back in the pile just leave that
there just leave it alone and just get
back to going back and forth on my
sift you can use more pressure for sure
on your your screen okay but it depends
on if that screen is touching is that
screen how far is that screen from
underneath the plate that it's on oh
that much space yes so then that's
plenty enough hey you can definitely
especially because it's cold in
here where that process of what I did
yesterday which was hold the card even
more flat rather than just use the edge
of the card I'll hold it down and use
like a third of the card and really
pancake it out
that process in a cold
environment Works fairly well and you
can be
fairly aggressive yeah fair you know not
overly but fairly you can actually
really press decently on that and what
because the bottom line is the the resin
heads are strong and they will stay on
top the contaminant will break and be
brittle especially in the cold and
they'll push through but they don't push
through easy and that's where it comes
through that you have to do this over
and over and over look at how dark it is
dark
side Light Side mhm that clear as day
one's green and one's
gold and this stuff here you can still
do if you took this stuff here and use
bubble man's
method you would definitely get some
more out of that oh yeah exactly cuz we
photographed it yesterday and we'll
inlay that photo there's definitely
glandular heads still on The Greener
Side it just tends to
[Music]
a slice and I hope to learn more and if
like bubble man said if there's stuff
you're learning please share we'd love
to hear about it oh yeah we on D we'll
see you guys later peace
guys it's been 4 days it's been great
it's been an awesome trip to Prince
George I got to say this guy right here
knows how to host a person he's showed
me his town he introduced me to his
friends he showed me his dry sift it's
just been a great trip absolutely
totally stoked so much it was our
pleasure every minute of it yeah we're
definitely going to hang out with you
soon again when you come to Vancouver
good but uh yeah I hope you guys all
enjoyed watching and I hope you guys
make your way to Prince George one day
and check out d420 K on his Instagram Mr
D 420k on YouTube and he'll have his
shop up uh sooner than later on his
website so stay tuned for
[Music]
that