guys welcome to Bubble man's world I was
just out here playing around with my
plants doing a little bit of gardening
cleaning them up and whatnot and I
noticed I had some Barb some 99% Barb
just sitting ignore the numbers it's
definitely not 160 or 190 but I had some
99 uh% Barb and it was sitting it was
just sitting over here while I was uh
working away on the plants and I heard
the wind blow it and I saw it I saw it
go oh no oh no well that's why we make
our sift clean right there isn't it hey
you see that that is bone dry powder
that is stuck to this card harder than
you can imagine it's not coming
off so people say to me oh oh be careful
bubble man while you're making your hash
you don't want that to blow away
oh that's how you stabilize and clean
hash peace out