[Music]
car that they had today that we drove
even just from 5 minutes ago I think
look they're changing on the Fly hey
welcome to Bubble man's world everybody
I'm here in the backseat of pre's car
and we we going to the dub Club is that
correct prey yeah we're with Ernie how
you doing and Chili's in the front yo
we're going to check out a little
Kingston authentic dub Club every Sunday
night on the jack Hilltop every Sunday
night on the jack Hilltop and we're just
right in front of the ja Hilltop so this
is going to be a pretty quick uh quick
little trip for us to get there little
jaunt all right so what you just go
around the mountain down and around and
up yeah perfect it
perfect prey
perfect nice see why I like Drive D
what's up Alpha you safe I'm going to
drive that oh you going to drive
[Music]
here lead not unfollow well looks like
we've decided to turn around we're going
to dve the other way up jackville okay
all right
man sounds good to me you turn in
and the adventure
begins all right we've
uh We've jumped out here because there's
a really nice view of the city right
here Kingston down below got the dogs
barking beautiful
man the Chili's chilling out what's up
lots of animals is barking oh yeah chill
it out bubble man is here bubble man is
here look in the
city overlooking the city beautiful
Jamaica yeah so we just got to go to
jaill get some dab enjoy some dub real
authentic Jamaican music yeah good food
and just live it up it's perfect love
let's do
that
a little
dark oh
yeah way too for us boom nice leaning
right in face good it's all
good all right all
right driving through the
jungle all right so we're right on Jack
Hill here made it
around what did say about that present
Skylight
dry so you
know we're heading down now
to see what's going
on Good Vibes a Good Vibration of
Jamaica the day 3 days after the
election things are getting right back
to normal people don't have time for
politics and more so therefore we're
just getting back in the groove everyone
going to work you when going to school
time to move on hey time to move on so
that's how it is things has
changed
Skyline cdle love
Jamaica
always stoked to be in Kingston and on
our way to the dub Club first time here
at the dub Club I believe for
certain I didn't fa so for what feel
sick oh
no what's
up no more no more Bing on this for
reverse
okay all right forward ever backward
never I
thought that's how it is up here that's
how it is
up look at that parking spot
yeah
got work this over gu work this
over he's like it's beautiful out M you
can walk man imagine being this guy that
parked here he's not leaving till the
end
no he's in it to win it he's in it to
win it
bro
on all right what's going on
one by one one by
[Music]
one did you go
now the DU
[Music]
Club
bub man bubble man yeah man yeah man
[ __ ] follow the [ __ ] man how you
doing man what's up what's up man I saw
you I'm kind of SC dude we're on Bubble
man's world right
now we see you
[Music]
soon
and you
[Music]
get the
M
all down
[Music]
the
deliv
[Music]
BS yeah this could be for the guys huh
oh yeah which one's
this oh
hor
cool hey what's up
man
[Music]
what's up man what's up man bubble man
yeah yeah yeah you're good yeah man
really good really good happy to be
[Music]
here
what
on all
[Music]
right really nice
yes
chil don't
[Music]
wor
lies the area we play one more draw for
the man
called L
up
[Music]
that
dude
oh right
there
[Music]
yeah
holy
[ __ ] it's [ __ ] heavy
[Music]
bro
H yes
[Music]
[Applause]
sir yes sir
gab lion
viub yes
[Music]
sir
w g people are you
[Applause]
[Music]
ready
nevering
one together
[Music]
said
hey guys so just finishing off the
evening here it's about 2: in the
morning I figured I'd finish off that
little dub Club jam with a bong Ripper
too I've got all sorts of wonderful
things uh Ernie and Chile are taking off
tomorrow so it's just me and Ashley for
the next couple of days and then he's
taking off and I'm on my own for a week
after that I'll be cruising around to
West Morland and looking for some fine
herbs to make hash out of as always and
in the meantime why don't we do a little
dab I'm
thinking super Tangi super
Tangi super Tangi yep that's on point
right there let's make sure this doesn't
get up much higher than 580 do some low
temps Tangi
dabs yeah you could really feel the
authenticity of that event tonight
really nice to see kis ey see Cali p uh
see Exile the Brave and uh just a whole
bunch of great people uh jamilia we saw
Jamila um chinis uh chennis Smith's
daughter and so uh hopefully we'll link
up with her again and this is just the
beginning of the videos here in Kingston
this round I haven't been able to do
many I've done a hash church and a
couple periscopes but uh I wanted to
give you guys a couple of authentic
videos from Kingston so this will be the
first one why don't we have a
[Music]
dab God got I love those 2 a.m.
dabs pure
oranges
so I'm going to head over to uh Negril
in the next couple of days I'm going to
go check out the stepping hot Festival I
have the full flyer right here
so some good friends right here uh we
got
uh oh King
Charlo young
Jr Empress Min not
we got loyal Flames we got China Smith
we got tough like
iron a Becka from midnight and uh what
else we got we got uh third gear and c p
we bumped into Cali PE tonight at the
dub Club so these are all going to be
great artists that we'll be able to
catch down at the stepping High Festival
of course it's the 13th annual one 2
a.m. in the morning and I'm gearing up
to go to bed so thank you guys for
watching this video and uh we'll catch
you next time above Man's World
[Music]
Peace