[Music]
hey guys I'm uh back here at the hotel
room going to actually take a little rip
out of this one of one osphere inside of
an egos spere egg inside of an egg 66
white Opals absolutely beautiful piece
from Mothership thanks again to high
integrity glass art for making it happen
always a pleasure to be able to enjoy
some of your beautiful glass I've got a
little bit of rosin here and a little
bit of d420 K dry sift I think I'm going
to hit the rosin along with the dryft uh
the rosin is from Flav and the dryft is
from d420 okay might as well make a
party of it it's a little bit windy out
here but that's I think we'll be fine
who was making it
[Music]
better better better better for man yeah
yeah
yeah cens of the world listen and hear
we're going to be hitting a lot of sick
pieces today this is just going to be
the first of many and uh yeah it's be
the 420 epic glass session with bubble
man and uh I've already hit a few pieces
but on camera earlier just at my house
there straight Fab at the Swiss perk to
start it off we're stepping up the game
and we're getting into the osphere
inside of the
osphere the 66
op all
right we got our ofz in hand our dab and
let's have ourselves a little
come go they will
go got to play our
parts hey my brothers and sisters
unite as we write a new chapter in life
chapter in
life one without the hate and The
Strife let's show love and peace to the
world and others will see and they will
follow they'll
follow
follow Mayers will come and they will go
they will
go it's a fact of life some come and
some
go send us someone send us
someone who will do the rest send us
ones who will play their part
who will give their all of the
[Music]
cause