[Music]
all right here we are in science world
kind of
[Music]
and you've got the genjou people busted
deck nice
Arvid machines man this is gonna be fun
I haven't done this in a long time I'm
very looking forward to this
there we go lock the truck up all right
well I suppose I will follow you sir
Chris
[Music]
yeah that's pretty good all right I give
you guys the show here which is
generally Chris
chris is the show what a great vibe this
is Vancouver
haven't done much fun stuff like this
since I hurt my leg it's very happy to
be doing this right now with Chris very
very happy
[Music]
my life it's my life it's my life and
it's your life from behind
[Music]
from behind riding from behind ready for
this
and showing in the word our village you
are why we are driving from behind
Friday forward at this time
[Music]
[Applause]
in here
nothing
maybe money
[Music]
well a patrol discovered
original indigenous here back
[Music]
give me my
original indigenous fear kinda
[Music]
I'm not big enough
watch your back bones man well that was
absolutely delicious I think it's time
to get back on those skateboards don't
see where we can go oh session on the
other side sounds good
[Music]
a big
ah stop
I
[Music]
nothing
[Applause]
[Music]
seventy-three r19 my
not her buddies if I resign Charlie's
not her vagina
I
[Music]
it must be
woman over Adam septic you barge in drop
it
noise angry bitter sleep in
also got high tri-c's make a cooling
you must come back
by this time chalice upon our values
[Music]
my buddy
but now
[Music]
further minds set up a machine I kind of
strain you up here so I'm so clean and
clear
come on dive in dive dive dive dive dive
and a Bugatti is forever do times
whatever do times time to dive in dive
dive dive dive dive dive dive agape it's
a pebble two times two times fresh from
the instructors ten percent pure
attention
let us work this away from me nitrogen
like on their words of use this good
fast just be nine-fold good for the
young on the whole us with that beam
that time time time time time an hour
that means it's a cover two times never
do tiny tiny
[Music]
coming in the morning stopping in the
evening dining at suppertime
daddy when you're weary Ivan Lendl only
having cars we're feeling fine
something perhaps we want to stop it
I've got to show you my copy machine got
my bedroom problem I'm bringing in with
I think that dive dive dive dive down I
got a number 2 times W times time that
I've ever do times I never knew times
done it's good for the endocannabinoid
system Olaf you're great
[Music]
yeah but I've been doc doc time time
time time I doubled up in you see some
time a new times I'd ever do time time
time time time time
[Music]
another night come without me dive dive
dive dive dive
this is the type of New Times never do
change time you dive in dive dive dive
dive dive dive my dog would never do
times that we do time to type in
[Music]
[Applause]
Chinese strike like seen as the margin
break my game is open why this one was
up in my face the wisdom of the way my
gets that straight we touch me
[Music]
for TDC I love the sweet ride home from
the spunk wicked movement rising and
rising I love the street right
got all the latest I'm dying to see v1
and TV to sing
we said that in the brain act but
happiness for me and you
ha
[Music]
yet not media just treat the dance of
inner life
[Music]
Jesse Orosco I love the sweet
he buggy Inari
I love the zhuzh icon
[Music]
Jesse paparazzi I love the sweet
tractor
[Music]
we should have a sash
let's do it right here
looks like a good spot for a sesh
I'm sure mine does too I don't know how
do you tell you it's hard to tell with
that one but I think you still got a
good laugh - it definitely feels like I
do yeah four minutes left on the camera
but we got the puffs go out here pretty
much yeah we're pretty much there so
there's our selection we've got mm-hmm
lost Gardens West Coast collective maple
butter and a little bit more lost
gardens with the puffs Co going here was
perfect landing though Hey look at that
dude I'll tell you it's perfect right
there
puffs go peak for the win
all right well let me get this
West Coast bubble hash
a k47 from lost gardens Acapulco gold
from lost Gardens
and some CBD isolate with some ac/dc
terpenes from our terms
[Music]
here it is
alright so I'm gonna hit this twice get
it vibrate and have a little session
here with mr. Bennett here on the
seawall it's pretty good spot actually
Chris yeah pretty awesome science world
if it's really on the cusp of East Van
in downtown Vancouver really yeah the
border
oh look at this little electric bike
scooter
vibrates ooh oh there goes just as I
just as I questioned it
[Music]
love that CBD
let me clean that out and get one ready
for you the whole minute for Chris to
get his dab in and for us to be done
this video you're probably gonna get
your dab in and as you exhale it it'll
start playing the bubbleman music
of CO Peak convenient you know people
have been given hate on this unit [ __ ]
I've been loved in mine but I'm taking
it all the [ __ ] over the place I'm
definitely not babying it I'm taking it
I'm using the battery till it's all done
and poppin top of it hitting the 20 plus
[Music]