[Music]
what's up de how much buddy what are you
up to dude you're out on the boat we are
out on the boat house sound is this is
this yeah this is the house sound part
of the Pacific Ocean and uh yeah you got
Bowen Island behind you there you've got
Vancouver Island Way Way off in the
distance where Matt the great Gardener
is we swam there last year didn't we we
did yes I was there yesterday and did a
little video showed everyone the
backside of Boyer and I kind of went
around saw Gold Eagle really briefly who
hey take it easy on the mothership time
for rips time for rips man sweet well
let me throw this camera on the tripod
all righty so I can come join you you
might have to uh squeeze your yourself
over one little bit that's perfect
that's more than perfect in fact we
don't uh do LPS
okay and I noticed you found a little
bit of little package of rosin on the
deck or something there of the dock oh
yeah did I actually end up grabbing that
or did I threw it
on oh yeah I threw it into my
bag yes yes yes
yes just going to clean this
down
here oh look at that it fell in the hole
of course it did that was kind of
freaking me out for a second well I did
bring some of my own as well oh and you
know what it's in my little Skillet
tools bam boom look at us I was I was
looking for this last night and uh I
could not find it and then I just gave
up looking for it and knew I'd find it
later and here it is my phone endlessly
makes noises so I'm just going to shut
her down well I think mine is in the bag
so holy Christ what a beautiful
day beautiful day it's really nice soier
and you got the torch we got some rogin
this is great
dude always happy to blaze a session
even always more so
happy to do it out on the boat
absolutely here buddy first torch me
up nice to see the mothership so clean
man that's what I really appreciate if
you're going to have a pipe like this it
should just be like this like look at
how beautiful and sparkly and clean it
is his court swing is clean it makes for
a nicer hit in my opinion and uh it
makes for
me just a more enjoyable
experience well I figure if you have
your carb cap is well or yes I do very
good very good
it's a little dirty that's
okay cap and the reason it's dirty is
cuz I'm not sure if I should torch that
or clean it with with ISO because I just
don't know if I'm going to wreck it if
either way right cuz I know I don't
clean the quartz with uh any isos or any
cleaners you burn it off woo nice
rip I was feeling it nice rip I was
feeling it really nice taste on that
beautiful
taste you know just just just being able
to sit
out in this weather oh you want me to
Tor you out
sure thank you very much yeah being able
to sit out in this weather saying to
just to do this in the sunshine what is
it 9 that's 9:00 a.m. 9:00 a.m. on the
house sound doing bong rips out of the
mothership not just doing any kind of
bong rips doing Ros and
yeah that we pressed up together that we
pressed up together and uh and is just
complete [ __ ]
fire killer go like if you do a big
to you're done son you're [ __ ]
coughing and you're not liking it so I
might just give that like you know a lot
of we'll give it a five count a lot of
people do 45 seconds if you can imagine
I I find it to be too long for water
hash maybe it's it's better for the oils
my hit tasted
Sublime really
nice so yeah we're going to cruise
around today we're going to show you
guys around the house sound a little bit
we're going to head over to gambir
Island right now uh well not right now
we're going to sit here and be baked for
a while but right after this session
we're going to head over to Gambier
Island and we'll go have a session in
hawkett Bay and then uh I guess we'll
feel feel it out see where we go for uh
from from there whether we want to go
deeper into gambir and go on to uh
into the West Bay or Center Bay or we
can head over to uh Bowen Island can
actually go grab a veggie burger or a
burger from this good little barbecue
place that's just right out by the boats
there so cool we'll do something like
that and we'll bring you guys along with
us of course so uh and careful of your
torches I got just burnt there I just
got a touch and last night on the denail
look at that one oh what did you do lean
over it yeah I was like I was trying
trying to read something and I and I
heard it just it get sizzled longer than
it normally should than it normally does
and it it got me good but I put some of
that um Horatio's oil yeah I put some of
that on top of it oh yeah that's a good
and it instantly stopped the burning and
everything like that it actually helped
out a lot so it's fully activated so it
makes sense that it would you know and
you know I I do feel two bong reps are
in order should we do two back to back
you know what I'm uh I'm ready for a
hawk at Bay session but you could H
another one just a quick one yeah just
cuz you know it's
uh one of those days it's a beautiful
morning and I just feel like a second is
in order then you got to hit a second
bro come
on I made I made a a point on hitting a
monster my first rip I have to yeah
that's what I didn't do yeah that's okay
though sometimes you got to have another
trying to do it's the beautiful thing
about cannabis and how easy it is to
titrate the dose
simply take a rib SS it out feel
good you're good ring the paper and
everything it's so gooey oh yeah well
we're in the Sun and it's hot right now
got another boat going
by real nice day to be out on the water
my goodness there are these rare moments
that boat people understand where you
just uh yeah you get a moment like this
out on the water there's almost nobody
out here we're on the freaking ocean
there's killer whales there's sea lions
there's there's all sorts of Epic
Wildlife right swimming underneath us
right now so it's not a lake it's quite
different um it's a [ __ ] total
[ __ ] system man a life system
underneath the one that could swallow up
like that Island oh instantly you know
what I mean so that's the crazy thing
about the ocean right now we're at about
600 ft for depth we're sitting about 600
ft of water you ever dive down and see
if you can hit the ball bom I've never
dove Down Deeper Than 145 ft 145 that's
it yeah 145 ft most people knar out at
about 100 ft they get uh uh the nitrogen
Narcosis I went 285 yeah no I was going
to say it's not impossible some people
have done it it can be done and it
involves different sorts of things like
decompressing and I just just a slow
process to me a deep dive was like 140
145 ft that was like it's dark it's cold
and it's scary it's it's scarier you
don't have as good of a visibility and
most people use their oxygen at such an
accelerated rate that if you go down to
those depths you'll really only have a
few minutes to stay down there unless
you're some super you know if you're
from Finland or Norway they they have
cold Waters there and those guys they
can they always preserve their breath
and any diving that I've ever done
around the world like in Thailand in
warm Waters yeah those guys will come
come up with 80% of their tanks when
everyone else has like 20% left yeah
when I did diving in Mexico we did a 40
foot just on Coral Reef and stuff and I
kept my it it was it was such nice calm
proper breathing that I I lost it down
there longer than the instructor
actually and he went up and I was the
last one on the bottom yeah well you're
from Canada yeah see if you're from a
cold area you will likely be able to
preserve your breath more in warm Waters
than people that are from those Waters
or yeah I guess cuz it's cold for them
eh well it's just like yeah they might
get down there it it's just different
all I know is that makes sense when you
can hold your breath and can control it
in colder water you will be able to use
even less breath in warmer water well
the guys when I was I didn't want to put
the wet suit on I just dove in my shorts
and they're like you're not going in a
wet suit it's it's it's cold in there
like it's cold like [ __ ] as if are you
kidding me well yeah I'll do this rip
here and uh yeah dude rip it up
then we're going to drive to hacket Bay
on Gambier Island right behind us which
is kind of cool that the boat is has
Twisted around now and uh it's showing
us pocket oh it's showing us Gambier
Island as well as parts of the Sunshine
Coast of
course of the
ship man if it's 9:00 and it's this hot
it's probably going to be 30° today
Celsius it's what is that like 100° F
mhm B
Zoom all right yes all right that
worked there it is yeah I'm feeling
super iy right now ready to
uh to get back in the uh in the driver's
seat soon and uh take a little
spin I'm with you on that I love that
just
ripping you can just fly in this boat
it's real nice you know on a day like
today it's safe to go fast also another
thing you got to know about the ocean is
it's not a lake so you have a lot more
things to watch out for out here dead
heads being a huge ordeal big logs
sometimes they sink and they float just
up below the surface so those ones you
can't even see there's nothing you can
do but you can keep your eye out for
anything else and it's uh it's not the
kind of boating where you're you're
yammering away to your friends and
looking away like ocean riding is like
you are white knuckling and staring at
where you're
going you do not want to hit hit a a
tree out
here and there's so many of them I mean
look at the forest that's surrounding us
on all these islands those trees break
they fall they come into the water they
float around some sometimes trees break
uh free from uh the log jams that they
tow up to the paper mile up the the
sound there
so all right well D and I are going to
chill out for a bit and just relax and
enjoy the buzz we'll get going in a bit
enjoy the Morning Buzz I really set
all right so we've just uh crossed the
house sound we were over
there and now we're over here this was
literally only minutes ago we were over
there minutes wellow we did sit for
quite a while and just enjoy the
medication oh man like both of us lean
back eyes closed smiling relaxed relaxed
enjoying the sun on the face and the
beautiful mother nature the in front of
us like this is love nature at her best
isn't it beautiful yep so this is the
backside of gambir islands and you know
all sorts of things to see here once
again Eagles seals sea lions uh the
Dolphins are often seen around this
island so that would be really cool if
we caught some Dolphins there's one of
those dead heads looks like an old
chal the old chal an old Irish
chal so yeah I'm sure there's some good
cliff jumping up here you can see up
there there's a rope with a little kind
of climb down there there's uh there's a
whole bunch of I think over here just
bouncing oh yeah ripping ripping like
five or six of them he yeah having fun
that's Bowen Island right there and
there's the ferry to the Sunshine
Coast what a beautiful day it's you know
that fair is halfway to the Sunshine
Coast right now we could be on the
Sunshine Coast in probably less than
half an hour we we eat the fair there
yeah we could although you'd be
surprised he's going damn near 40 40 m
hour I like the
dogwoods yeah those are um our beus
trees the the the the orange ones yeah
yep so those trees what I know about our
beus trees and they have a different
name down in the US I have know I know
of them as dog right well our buus
trees they lose their bark their their
bark H in the winter not their leaves oh
so that's why they're so smooth
throughout the winter they shed their
bark there's a seal up
ahead yeah there's his head come here
buddy
probably go down oh no that's a seal
yeah yeah probably go down when we go by
there's another one up front there are
UTS as well
going
guy dogs Sea Dogs yeah for
real so yeah you know as you get closer
to these islands you realize how
Majestic they are and how really big
they are from here it looks beautiful
but it doesn't look like
this and those our beus trees as you can
see grow right out of
rock serious
trees this little Bonsai sticking out
the front here is pretty sick too
sure Juniper or something
so you know also because it's the ocean
and they don't Mark everything I'm also
leery to go too close to the coast
because it's you know there could be a
rock and it's not really anyone's job to
say that there's a rock there now the
most for the captain to be aware of that
stuff that's it and you know apparently
I'm the captain so is that a bay in
there this is hawkett Bay this is the
first Bay there's three more Bays over
here which are oh something like Center
Bay West Bay
and I can't Long Bay so there's Long Bay
Center Bay and West Bay as well as
hacket Bay these are the three Bays of
gambir on this side nice lot of
population on this island there's a fair
amount of people living I mean nothing
compared to Bowen you know you
definitely can see houses and and
population in in most of the of the Bays
this is probably the quietest one yeah
it's uh what a peaceful place to live
though I that oh yeah dude everybody
knows everybody everybody helps out
everybody very community community
orientated probably and that sort of
thing a I would I would think so for
sure have to be it couldn't be
successful if it wasn't I couldn't see
it it's sure a beautiful place man I'll
tell you that much
abely lots of logs and TR me lots of
dead heads
yeah they often make their ways into the
Bays you got to be a little bit more
careful on the
entrances that must be for
uh not going in or going in those boys
there big ship yeah I'm not sure that
could be that could be where people have
boys for their own boats or it could be
it could have been where they did have a
a huge boat I don't know if it was in
this one or Long Bay they sunk recently
it was a big oh for AIP Marine
underwater sort of yeah some sort of
like build the exactly
exactly that would be neat to check out
hey let's open
this
sorry the bimin is so
low so yeah a hacket is a place where
people come usually with their boats to
camp out and sleep in the bay I think
there might only be a home or two in
here
I've CED out a few times on fishing
trips like that oh look at the bald
eagle
dude he's sitting on the Rocks he's
sitting right on the Rocks
dude enjoying his morning probably had a
couple of fish already fed
well he's enjoying the morning
too oh hello brother eagle
that was cool yeah sorry that we up uh
you know made him leave but glad that we
got to see him
go bald eagles on the rocks in hacket
Bay kind of a cool uh cool little spot
I've brought you guys here one time
before with Flav we had a big Marcel
octopus piece and we had a session in
the bay here so I think uh we're going
to turn off the
boat have a little
session all right so we just noticed a
vessel pull up here and uh it's some
scuba divers so I thought that was
pretty cool as we were just talking
about scuba diving a little while ago
we've been sitting here for quite a
while now we've blown into the bay and
kind of spaced out and even forgot where
we were for a few seconds but uh yeah
here we are that eagle actually landed
on the other side of the water there and
he's chilling out in the
tree proba we got a full
belly
wow
shaky too
shaky all
right well I'm almost ready for a burger
on
Bo yes
we'll do that next does it
will oh that hurt I just
fuing all right hocket Bas session we've
uh only got about an hour of film time
on our battery so we're just going to
try and have a dab in each spot show you
a little bit about what's going on like
some Eagles or some
seals next up is Bowen Island but uh we
hadn't had a dab session here yet
so we figured we
would you ready oh I'm ready you good
buddy thank you brother
back we've got the carb cap up front so
we won't use it right now no problem
actually problem let's do it where is
it I love the carb cap I have to use it
beautiful out here beautiful out
here yeah it really is hey
yep so
killer you need a dab or you have one
already I got one ready to go
excellent we have to do a video uh soon
where we just go out on the boat and
Shred got all sorts of fun things wake
skates wake surfs wake
boards skis
tubes I don't have a hydro foil I don't
I don't have quite a few of the toyss
but I have a few of them in the sense
that uh I get a couple of my buddies up
from Whistler who are are ragers and and
really good on those things it'd be
always the fun to uh fun to see how
that's a big rip you're
taking D 420k is not [ __ ] about
wellow we're really getting blown in
here it's pretty awesome turning the
boat around [ __ ] yeah beautiful yeah the
thing about the
rosin is you can take those big rips
because it's so [ __ ] smooth yeah you
really can you it's so smooth and
Powerful just a tiny little boat hey
just Trucking people back and forth on
his little dingy
yep well diving next stop Bowen Island
Let's Do
It free m and rock come free and live
free mine and rock come in and free your
mind and dance
Dess
distress
Dess and save your life for yes
distress distress
yes and save your life for yes babyon
will blind you like a oh yeah and R you
like a rat oh and treat you like a mat
they will tell you like a KN a KN and
they will misiz your wi my people before
you ring your lies I oh yeah they tell
you dirty lies they will show you like a
dice the ice
[Music]
distress all right so we've just pulled
on uh to the inside of the first part of
Bowen Island here we just came from
around that corner and this is a really
cool house he's got solar power uh he's
got uh wind generated power and this
particular property he owns the whole
island uh has been on a TV commercial I
think it was for Land Rover if I'm
correct because you can actually drive
you see the two where the canoe is
Darren yeah that little that little boat
well that's a road that he drives his
truck down and then he drives it into a
tunnel on this rock into a tunnel into a
tunnel there's a tunnel in there yeah
and then he comes up at his house wow
yeah dude check it out that is [ __ ]
cool you know what I'm saying right into
the tunnel
dude super cool
wow and is that part underwater at high
tide yep that part is underwater at high
tide so they showed it in that's like
that's like right out of a marble comic
back cave type [ __ ] yeah exactly cool so
that's the back cave right there guys
pretty cool you can see Anvil Island
right through the center
too over here one of
the and save your life for yeah
[Music]
distress
distress distress
yes and save your life for yes the
design to keep you down they'll use you
when show you all around father you will
always wear every to sound sound so you
got to listen to yourself and know which
one you must choose and which one you
must
use don't get
confused oh no no free of mine and rock
and come in free m and
live free mine and rock and come in free
mine and dance D
stress D
stress
deess and save your life for yes the
[Music]
distress distress
yes and save your life for
yes step steeping at the right place
walk walking at the right lane move
moving at the right place
[Music]
move skip skipping at the right Bas run
running at the right lane dance dance
upon the right face dance uhhuh
distress
distress distress
yes and save your life for yes
distress
distress and save your life oh yes beess
[Music]
distress distress
yes and save your life for yes
distress
distress and save your life for yes
[Music]
distress distress
free your mind and live free your mind
and free your mind and dance the
stress the
stress and save your life oh yes heess
stress
Dess
distress
distress and save your life oh yes will
BL you like a b oh yeah and you like a
rat oh when treat you like a m they will
tell you like a KN a and they will misiz
the wi people before you Reales oh yeah
they T to dirty lies you like a dice ice
distress distress distress
distress
distress and save your life oh yes
distress distress
[Music]
distress and save your life for yes the
Des to keep you down they use you and
show you all
around will
always every to sound sound so you got
to listen to yourself and know which one
you must choose and which one you must
use don't get
confused oh no no fre and Ro fre and
live free mind
and free your mind and dance D
stress Dess
Dess heess
heess and save your life oh yes heess
heess
heess distress
yes and save your life for
yes step stepping at the right place
walk walking at the right
all right so we are just pulling into
Bowen Island and uh well Darren couldn't
help himself he needed a rip right away
and I told him I call this rip alley
okay I didn't really tell him that but
just now I'm saying this is Rip alley
rip alley I've taken wonderful rips
right where you're sitting as uh the
boat idles
into
dock quite nice is this where you burn
your uh I don't want to burn stuff so
I'm going to put my Fe done yep sounds
[Music]
good Andress
yes what a beautiful day man just
ridiculous I love these little houses
and everything
along
gorgeous have you been on Bowen Island
before Darren no right on oh first time
we're going to be on it 420 k b island
Cherry in a few minutes well that's one
way to put it why don't I just Jam the
the the no what stop it you go into the
air you're going to wreck your camera
you do that I'll hold it okay then and
steer with my teeth I'll hold on Uncle
you ready there I'm ready my God I don't
know if they'd like it though here I
don't think that's proper boting
etiquette
right I agree I think also that it might
not be proper building eate
[Music]
great what nice little
places these are
beautiful yeah nothing over fancy just
you know a nice nice PL ni ni little
spot
yeah look at that place right
there this little one green yeah that is
so you know i' want more
windows like the one beside it
y nice more deck too it's nice to have
the sprawling deck more windows more
deck deck everywhere there be a lot of
time you spend on that
yeah I'm just trying
that's
[Music]
cool so you will be jumping out of the
boat right where you are I would start
untying the Rope that's on the railing
there that would be very good for you to
do
[Music]
so oh it's not a no big deal there I
think I'm going to even go back one
spot and try to come in to this spot
right here cuz it's big enough and I
don't really need to go in you
know so here we go let's try
this let's see if I can park the boat
okay Darren good
buddy go up front or anything I don't
know don't try to accept upset me when
I'm trying to do this
okay it's very
very [ __ ] I just joking around shut shut
the [ __ ] up just don't want to hit that
boat in front of me I came a little
tight I'm not going to
lie you're doing a fine job well no a
fine job would have been me coming in on
one hit and then just parking the
boat here com don't wor don't worry
want to grab the Rope front too
AE that for a
second kill the
boat all right so we've landed on Bowen
Island the boat's tied up to the dock
looking sweet uh beautiful man let's go
find a dab session or a food whatever
comes first all
right so they call this snug
Cove is this for a good reason yeah it
is pretty snug one of these places I
would swim in with every day hey what's
up Crow greenhous yeah the greenhouse is
sick right
first class and that's his house yeah
and his boat in front of his house it's
good for him look at that he Liv a
dream he's living a dream that
uh that is beautiful cool good job
totally a beauty Greenhouse
too yeah it really is he looks after it
like it's not even dirty no it's nice
although I would have way more food
growing in there I
think great
cous cous you're all about that cous
about that cous about that
cous all right oh the Paradise Grill
best burger on the island what do you
guys say we could try some of that sure
they got veggie
options with some Paradise
gr okay see you later have a good
day 7 days a week 11:00 a.m. to 7:00
p.m. is it already 11:00 a.m. um I think
it's later because I always open late
sweet all right well doc Morgans
I'm
so I'm
Sor it's
okay do you want to do half of the
mushrooms all right well we manag to get
burgers pretty stoked on it actually
[ __ ] hungry good looking Burgers man
yeah she seemed to do a pretty good job
there
I'm ready to try out the
work fairy came
in she changes the landscape
up well eat these Burgers real quick
such a nice little
Boardwalk
Boardwalk the
reads must be old day oh
[Music]
yeah Davies Creek krippin Regional Park
oh yeah so these are Trails I
guess Dorman point is 2
km and then Karne
Lake can hike around the Karne Lake it's
pretty cool keep dogs
out I found out today my favorite
sandwich place is open at 6 a.m. oh my
gosh just what you needed eh yep
oh yeah that's definitely where we're
heading into the back of one of these
picnic table areas and just uh have a
session which one Trails over trail goes
over there Qui yeah
totally you want to run right here look
it's nice I think it's very nice let's
see if we can somehow sit on the side
that you're not going to there we go
it's pretty
sweet
um this going be hitting dry rips cuz we
didn't bring
water wait there's water right here M gu
we won't be hitting dry rips I'm going
to go put some water in the bom you
should bring the torch
he didn't bring it tou we're not having
session it's okay not the biggie all
right so d428 K and I just came into
the what is it the lemon pie what's the
name of the place lime and moon pie lime
and moon pie company company she is with
famous people uh for my YouTube
channel so what did we get we got that
one there the banana cream chocolate
banana cream pie have this one close oh
nice
you need that's what we're about to eat
chocolate banana cream pie holy
[ __ ] you're going to have to swim for a
bit after it yeah I'm quite excited
about this very
excited enjoy the pie
Darren chocolate banana
cream wow
it's
incredible all right so we made it back
we were here earlier but we forgot the
torch and so now we have the
torch all right so uh got to get some
water into the Mother Ship here didn't
bring a water
bottle luckily there's a creek here
that's a darn near perfect right
there I think that'll do let's go sit by
the uh on the beach I think it'll be a
bit of a nicer session all right d420 K
and I are on the lookout for the
ultimate chuff spot here on Bowen
Island Darren was feeling this Trail so
we're going to take it all the salmon
berries I'm going to have to some down
nice big
trees ni big
seers looks
like that's where we want to go there no
this is going to go into the forest and
do a big loop around but I can't promise
it'll be possible to get to the water
from here this is the Dorman Point Trail
so it goes in a
circle Yep this this left if we go all
the way around we'll come out right
here so we're not going to get down to
that beach I don't know we're going to
walk 2 km well let's just give it a
small shot let's see if we walk the
first little
bit well it's definitely up up up and
yeah I think that's exactly it I don't
think it takes you to the
beach unless there's a beach Trail too
this could be a beach
Trail look at this look at this de
yes you were right you were
right I had no
idea I had no idea this is pretty cool
bringing us in through the back
way nice spot for a session
y Beauty
quite
sweet pretty much right out to the log I
pointed to earlier
yep I thinking this one over here in the
shade
perfect
Daron what's that I agree beauty
spot oh my God that what just break the
whole arm and hand and can you open
it
jez
je all right
so man I'm pretty excited about this
little session we're about to have you
can point to wherever you want us to sit
good it's going to be right out on this
sort of
little little tip
I brought some rosin camera's way over
there maybe you can't hear us I don't
know we're here on Bowen Island in snug
Cove we just had ourselves some
impeccable chocolate banana cream pie uh
over at the uh what was that the Lime
Pie Company lime yes uh before that we
had the veggie burger at the Paradise
Grill also here on Bowen Island I had a
meat Burger he had a meat Burger a
hamburger as they call
it meat meat Burger all right so we're
going to use the key for the Dabber all
right always nice to have a
key just cut this right in you know you
start doing this with a key and you
realize that you don't really even need
a
Dabber that a key is a
Dabber all
right that's turn we got here
that's a loud
torch what's wrong
there just trying to get away from the
Flames buddy holy
[ __ ] yeah the wind that can block it
best right
here keep it up keep it up perfect you
did good dude that was so
close that was so
close it was really close wasn't
it did it hanging off the
key the wind reallys down
perfect temp dab let me organize one for
you oh yeah I got a little bit of little
bit of the goodness on my shirt there
roast up zip you got the mustard on your
shirt I got the hash on I'd rather have
the hash or the rosin I guess you call
it all right let me get you a little
little dobles get me
sorted let me get you sorted d420 k
take this off so you don't have to do
the close dab to me be a close Dabber oh
thanks I'd wait a few seconds for sure
oh yeah definitely it's just wanted to
cook that to off too look at it
just all right she's all pressed into
the
shirt carb cap
carb
cap Beach rips very nice little unit
there very nice little spot for uh
puffing on Mothership rips I think uh
well we still have quite a few stops to
make so we're just going to keep on
keeping on on the journey and each time
we stop we share a bowl with you
guys all right here comes the queen of
calano the Bone Island
Ferry coming in to let everyone off
and we're heading back down to the boat
good time on Bing with you brother you
too bro
all right made it back to the
vessel time to uh get everything ready
and head to Horseshoe
Bay all right there goes the
ferry we made it
out take goodbye to Bowen Island peace
Bow Island peace see you next time it's
recording
[Music]
he
holy c
glass place oh yeah in there's
Jack that what's
that Jack oh yeah I do notice that yeah
view that they have too this is really a
spectacular home
DC feris in the
background is really
amazing this place tough
way oh [ __ ]
yeah
stoping I've never seen that Fairy
before that's pretty trippy he's a
little guy he he's a little F yeah it's
just got like a few cars on it I've
never seen it
before it's interesting just sort of
sitting there in the middle of
the
okay this
Kish got give us a wave
you always got to pay more attention cuz
all these boats coming out of here are
like uh tourists from around the world
uh renting
boats not knowing [ __ ] all about the
ocean and this is of course where the
Bowen Island and the Nao Vancouver
Island uh and even fairies come in
Sunshine Coast those three fairies come
and dock right here big fairy docks boom
boom boom
well there's the yellow RCMP boat that's
the RCM SAR one that's a coast guard
vessel for helping more than causing
problems nice well there's a big
boat that's a big
one there some Nies in here
[Music]
oh yeah they're double boating up on
this dock over here so it's full the
government dock that I would have parked
on it looks probably pretty full over
here unless there's a little piece on
the tip I can grab
or we can maybe go over to that one if
the water's not too low it looks pretty
low over there though
[Music]
yeah looks like that's
it dark space
happening
yeah you to do it's
good all right so we just parked the
boat on the on the dock here we are we
are in Horseshoe Bay we don't have much
battery left so we're just going to
maybe go grab a gelato and have a rip oh
and look there's my mother
ship actually ninja response but because
I'm a ninja I know what's the difference
you know what I'm saying yeah so that's
another the ninja
response there's the gelato right here
dude I don't know I want to get some of
this video I wanted to play us a song
how's it going dude play a song yeah for
bubble man's world bubble man's world
what's bubble man's world uh you know in
bubble man's world we educate people
about the wonderful uses of cannabis and
the phyto canabo and the endoc canabo
system okay and so it's really a
cannabis education sort of sight yet
we're just we live a healthy lifestyle
and show that while we're educ about
cannabis okay I like the sound of that I
could do I could do a song I got a song
for you then a bit of an off to beaten
path one you don't don't play when I'm
buing near a fountain but uh since uh
the Cannabis culture you got to be a
little uh um resistant to Authority
here's a piece called recalcitrant and
you know the word recalcitrant the term
no it means resistant to Authority I
like it here's a little bit of a heavier
song for you all right okay my name is
Tori aan Owen by the way awesome t right
[Music]
a
dude that was beautiful recal trinel
Trin awesome pound it out you bet
beautiful cool man give thanks all right
well we've managed to uh pick ourselves
up a little Baskin Robins ice cream D
420k in the house with his rum raisin on
his phone but he says hello right
d yes cool what the what are you doing
filming while I'm on the phone what are
you doing on the phone when we're
filming I didn't even know you were man
we're always filming we we got to share
the times okay I only have a minute left
and I want to do at least a dab before
we leave horseshoe Baye so we're going
to M these and we'll come back for a
quick 60c or less dab all right we found
our spot
all right where we looks like we're good
to go D all right d420 K with his
Horseshoe Bay
dabs [ __ ] yeah
buddy West coasting
it
beautiful all right well we got the
other camera
working we don't need that [ __ ]
camera [ __ ] no so I wanted to show you
this house up here it's pretty pimped
out have to go a little bit faster to to
get closer for the camera cuz I don't
have
uh I don't have my video camera this is
my big camera
all right
so here's that house look at that
[ __ ] house man that is some sweetness
right
there really beautiful place and then
the road goes all the way down to this
other place that is also on the
property and uh you really can't tell
how incredible of a property it is from
down here but he's got a helicopter pad
you can kind of see it sticking out of
the trees there the bushes on the left
of the house see that big circular
concrete
pad pretty pimped out house for
sure how
sound all right d we made it to the
backside of Boer Boer Island this is
like what I call my office cuz it's so
close to home I can just boot out here
in a couple of minutes be out at this
little spot it's almost always calm it's
nice we swam here last year yeah
exactly so you got yourself a rosin rip
yes I'm going to heat up
the C this oh I'll let everyone know off
camera that I did manage to get my
Horseshoe Bay dab in but my camera died
so we're using uh the Canon now to film
with but we've left hesho Bay so my
Horseshoe Bay dab was off camera only
can really see the color difference over
your uh left shoulder
uh it's all blue and over your your
right shoulder it's all quite aquamarine
green really nice color in the water
might have to jump in today I think we
should
Boom ni rip
yeah that was
tasty that was really
tasty join you for the
rip going to Cheers brother cheers enjoy
the bowl dial me up do you have your
little uh your carb cap for this little
unit you know yes I do I use that but
it's in the case here yeah I like that
carb CS it is better it's meant for it
it's meant for it for
sure oh the birds are making some Fierce
noise back
there going something you didn't know
better you could literally convince
someone that monkeys were back
there yeah with the
no is just
ridiculous like a til to that stuff next
buddy
yeah man anytime torch me
up thank you
sir it back and I'll turn it off you
ready
[Music]
perfect some nice boats out in the water
here we got four or five decent looking
crafts all just hanging out it looks
like these guys might get some wake
skating going or wake surfing or wake
boarding one of the waking Sports
that you do while you're awake I like
waking
up is the best part of waking up uh
folders in your cup no yeah I mean need
or rosin in my bow rosin in the best
part of waking up is rosin in your bowl
bowl or on your honey bucket or whatever
you want dude whatever it is wow look at
that that rosin really just melted to my
I'll let that cool cool down a little
bit see how that just go oh
yeah carb cap ready to do this Boyer
Island
ribs I should have carve that for you
got it didn't matter it was a dry
hit oh
it was still great nice but it was a dry
hit was really smooth for a dry hit well
it is rosin it is rosin it's true enough
it's interesting I I prefer water but
that was pretty damn
smooth oh you want that there yeah I'm
going to
uh that's warm a little bit worm I don't
know how well this is look at
this go ahead
there it is there it
is man what a beautiful
day so good all day since super early in
the morning too it'll probably be like
this till 8:00 or 9 or 10 at night
[Music]
so yeah give that like a like a 20 to 30
second count before you drop that rosin
in there and you'll get what is like not
really a low temp dab cuz that would be
more like a 45 to 50c count after you
torch it orange but a 20 second count
for rosin and for foam out bubbles I
find is uh super tasty it's still 20
there it
[Music]
is jet ski is ripping by going like 60
MPH holy [ __ ] that guy is flying
[Music]
beautiful to yeah tasty rips tasty tasty
rip beautiful R well I'm feeling hot
enough here that I just might have to go
for a little
swim I didn't bring towels of course but
I'm pretty much over that too yeah I'm
okay we can air
[Music]
dry all right well that's it that's uh
the end of that long ass boat ride going
to head back to home and uh ah this will
be the first of many boat videos for the
summer but I don't know if I'll do a
longer one than this this was a long day
out on the boat with d420
K we've taken our last few dabs and
we're just pulling up to the marina now
so thank you for watching Bubble man's
world and we will catch up with you guys
next time peace peace
[Music]
open your
eyes open your eyes your
eyes the road of life is so
rough rug
and the Lord you carry is so
heavy heavy
[Music]