[Music]
hey welcome to Bubble man's world
absolutely beautiful um sunset going off
here uh boxing day December 26th we're
almost at the end of the year and I
thought I wanted to put out at least one
more video saying thank you to all all
of you out there who have shared your
kind comments and your good words um
people that have asked questions people
that have learned people that have
shared just want to thank you all for
really pushing the boundaries of water
extraction and dry sifting I've seen a
huge growth in the last just year even
um I even have to thank you know Believe
It or Not BHO you know all these people
that have come to learn about cannabis
through BHO are now finding themselves
looking for something else they're
looking for that next thing and you know
while a certain amount of those people
will stay with the BHO when they'll
specialize upon it and they'll become
you know the the people at the top of
that game the majority of people aren't
accessing really clean good quality oils
um it's dangerous people are getting
injured so it's really nice to see a lot
of people um coming around and
just seeing that that dry sifting and
wet washing can produce equally as
dabbable of a product as you uh often
like to say I've got my denail going
right here I've got um a little bit of
dabbable product right here and I
figured I just share a few bowls with
you here on the last few days of the
year you know send my my wishes to all
of you hope you had a great holiday
season I hope that you had lots of melty
hash I'm going to hit the the straight
fab here with the silhouette of the Epic
uh cloudy Sunset coming in got the
denail set up to the quartz Bowl the
pooking
bee um yeah I got a little um converter
from 14 to 18 that um higher end gave me
from high integrity glass and we're
going to dab up a few hits with
you
beautiful wanted to um you know kind of
go over the year in bubble it's been an
exciting year for Bubble
Bags um with the with the growth of
water extraction over the last few years
um Bubble Bags
has you know both um received the
markets um welcome in how we produce and
sell bags we've I guess what Bubble Bags
has done is we've um listened to the
marketplace we understand that the
high-end Bubble Bags will always have
their place but we also this year
decided to come out with a more
inexpensive version of the Bubble Bags
uh the bubble bag lights you may have
seen the video on Urban Remo's channel
the urban grower on his YouTube channel
of us making bubble together with the
lights or um John Bell and I making
bubble together uh using the bubble bag
lights with his whole uh fresh frozen
plants those are all on on the channel
you can check them out if you haven't
already so that's really been great and
and another thing that's been really
great is the act absolute explosion of
of dry sifting you know for the longest
time I just didn't see a lot of dry sift
and it seemed everywhere I turned this
year from being at when I asked everyone
at the Cannabis Cup this year if anyone
had full m dry sift I saw many hands go
up in the crowd which was a huge jump
from last year's none so that's really
great um sharing this information over
the course of the last few years
teaching people how to do the carting
techniques um you know showing people
how to gently and lightly extract heads
versus uh a rough extraction and a
cleaning they both have their place it's
just been great um saw some absolute
beautiful full 99% gland head hash
probably by at least half a dozen people
at the Cannabis Cup this year so that
was really uh really great to
see and uh my own friends you know John
B um d420 K on Instagram he's been
making some really beautiful beautiful
hash some dry sifting we'll have a video
uh coming up with him in the next uh
month or two I'm not sure if I'm going
to be making it up to his neck of the
woods or if he's going to be coming down
down here but we're definitely going to
get together uh we're going to do some
dry sifting we're going to talk about
techniques we're going to you know show
some macro photography and get you guys
get you guys inspired to make this this
full melt wet wash and dry sift you know
these 99% pure gland heads that were
grown properly allowed to mature and
because of it you get that melty
dabbable product does it dab does it
melt the Purity is only half if that the
real trick is the quality plus the
Purity then you get something worth
[Music]
smoking well favorite products of
2013 let me see most of them are sitting
here with me right
now this Mothership bong I can't
remember being this happy with a pipe in
a long time it was also the first time I
actually bought a pipe in a long time I
almost forgot people have been giving me
pipes for so long and I've always
appreciated it but it's like the
conversation I had with Brian from denil
another product that I've absolutely
loved this year one of my favorites is
that I prefer to feel the sting of
buying a product so I can actually judge
it accurately and really feel that
that's something I like based upon the
money that I I put out it's a big deal
it's it's easy to get given a product
and have that skew your perspective on
how much you actually like it because
often when we pay for things the earning
of money and the spending of the money
we like to compare the value versus that
money so we'll buy something for $1,000
when we using it we'll think was that
$1,000 worth of whatever that product
was that I got no matter the product
people do it inevitably whether they
admit it or not and I I just felt for
the money that I spent on the denail
which was well below
$1,000 I've just been really happy with
it it we took it to the Cannabis Cup it
performed exceptional I love that I can
use it um on a pipe and I can move it
freely uh this piece here is light
sometimes it gets a little bit twisted
which is simply untwisted by just
twisting because the cord is so light
you can actually do it I find that the
cord doesn't get caught on things I I
find that it's not um pulling things off
of my table if I have it up on the table
it's not knocking over jars of hash and
that's one of the things I really like
about this unit I could go on for uh for
for a long time about uh the efficiency
[Music]
it's something to say that since I got
this unit I think I may have lit a beine
like twice and each time I did it it was
just less enjoyable I've just gained
I've gotten used to this sort of hit um
also a product that's not here that I
want to give a mention to which is
really the first product that I got
turned on to this year that gave me
similar Bubble Hits to this but on an
even different level because this
product you can use cannabis combined
with bubble or either or and that would
be the
sublimator I know I've uh posted a few
videos of it before it is a bigger more
Awkward unit I think it's best suited
right now to be brought you go to the
sublimator it's not something you want
to pass around and you have to sometimes
explain to people that it's hot not to
touch much like the Dil I like to tell
people this is very hot and you
shouldn't touch it and so um with doing
those two simple things you can really
uh share quite an experience with
someone and give them a nice sublimator
rip because to this day I got to give it
up to the sublimator for being one of
the tastiest hits I've ever taken hands
down John B would agree with me CU it
was his uh cush as we were puffing I
think he had finger rub and he even one
day brought over fresh cut herb that we
hit through the sublimator and it even
tasted amazing so it's quite something
to check out um um you can check them
out uh at sublimator tocom I believe if
not we definitely also carry them uh on
Fresh hey.com
uh we also carry the denail we however
do not carry the motherships but you can
check out high integrity glass art uh on
Facebook or Instagram for these bad boys
I know they specialize uh in the
province of British Columbia but they
may or may not be able to sell you a
piece if you're outside of British
Columbia you can check it out with them
um another little product I mean I don't
mention too often but you see me always
using are the skillet tools I've seen a
few come and go since Skillet tool has
been around and I still am a favorite of
the skillet tool I love the bucket on
the the scooper I think it's just
perfect for dry sift and bubble and the
little corner piece the little Dabber on
the other end it's perfect as well it's
just I can dab my my bubble with it I
can scoop my powder granul stuff with it
and I just think it's a really uh
allaround great product and one that I
use every day I obviously actually use
all of these products every day and of
course my favorite is the one that my
product makes bubble hash yeah 99% pure
gland heads extracted with the help the
water and the ice are doing everything
for you so as long as you follow simple
instructions and allow them to isolate
the gland heads for
you it's a no-brainer
you can ex expect to have some of the
purest gland head hash you've ever seen
water and ice made that possible pre
9798 um which is when the world really
learned about water extraction and I say
that in a public manner many people knew
about it decades
earlier but more the information was
more uh um isolated
now the information with the Internet is
more it's almost everywhere so many
people know about it and so um that
really changed the game to allow people
to have something at this level I I
remember it specifically because really
before
1999 which was when Bubble Bags came out
and really popularized the method we
really threw overgrow and the timing and
digital cameras and everything just kind
of clicked and it became
that it became you know it was the time
for that information to spark and for
people to grab it I know I hear a lot of
people now saying that it's it's really
happening now because that's exponential
from what all the work that was done in
the late 90s to to you know to 2005 and
then 2005 to 2010 and 200 each time each
you know four or five years it's this
exponential growth and it's seemingly
been like that for almost since its
Inception so look very forward to see
where water extraction as well as dry
sifting will take us in the 2014 year I
look forward to sharing a lot of cool
videos with you I've got ideas of
potentially going to Jamaica potentially
going to Nepal
CMU um of course this winter we want to
do an ice cave session take you guys out
to the pton ice caps by snowmobile and
maybe make some dry sift and some wet
wash in an ice cave you know stay
overnight do some time- lapse
photography of the stars and put
together an nice video for you guys I
hope you guys have been enjoying this um
I'm going to leave you now with one more
rip beautiful
sunset
and feel free to leave a comment I
always love to read your
comments and enjoy the beautiful sunset
here in beautiful British
Columbia
peace
is
e
[Music]