[Music]
ladies and gentlemen good morning it's
an absolute pleasure to be up here and
to be able to say so I see quite a few
familiar faces out there
I feel energy thank you it's my pleasure
now to introduce two people one before
the break after the break the first one
dr. Ethan Russo
Ethan's us neither promise not to make
this a 30 minute introduction of it it
can easily go beyond that but even as a
board-certified neurologist
psychopharmacology research of identify
text just by a technology company
researching and developing innovative
approaches targeting the human
endocannabinoid system from 2003 to 2014
he served as the senior medical advisor
at GW pharmaceutical and in that role he
was involved for phase 1 through phase 3
clinical trials sativex for pain and
multiple sclerosis and also initial
studies there the dialects were going on
down in the states of that he's
graduated the list looks like a list of
most of the universities in
America University in Pennsylvania
psychology University of Massachusetts
Pediatrics in Phoenix Arizona child and
adult neurology University of Washington
is a clinical neurologist in Missoula
Montana for 20 years past president of
the International cannabinoid Research
Society and former chair of the
International Association of cannabinoid
medicines he's consulted or lectured on
topics in neurology pain management of
cannabis in more than 30 US states and
30 countries around the world
and we're extremely fortunate to have
him here today I just like to have a
wonderful note he's also a wonderful
thing
[Applause]
thank you it's a great pleasure to be
here I am afraid we're going to be
moving from the sublime to the
ridiculous but I don't disagree with any
philosophy you've heard so far this
morning I come to you with certainly as
an iconic the establishment but that is
not the way I feel I also may be dressed
in the suit but in my heart I'm wearing
hemp anyway my email is here those of
you who know me will admit that I answer
my email so well please feel free to
take that down if you have subsequent
questions and I may be busy but I will
get back to you so of course we're
talking about the plant cannabis sativa
cultivated cannabis and how this works
among other things it relates to the
endocannabinoid system so we have this
plant wasn't put on God's green earth to
get us high because the plant has been
around a lot longer than the human
species but through a convenient
accident of nature
it makes chemicals that react with our
own receptors these are cannabinoid
receptors cb1 the psychoactive receptor
and CP 2 and immunomodulatory
and pain believing receptor the reason
this works is one chemical in particular
in cannabis THC resembles natural
cannabinoids within us the endogenous or
at endocannabinoids best known Erica
terminal glycerol and the end of mind
and two AG he's bind to the receptors in
the same way that THC does and the
endocannabinoid system is composed of
those endogenous chemicals these
receptors and the enzymes that make that
would break them down now there's been a
great deal of confusion about what we
should call cannabis beyond the hundreds
of slang terms frequently you'll hear it
this is indica this is sativa on my
opinion this is all nonsense we could go
into the Nitty Gritty of what is a
species we know that all cannabis can
interbreed what you really need to know
is what's in it but will its effects be
of course that depends to a certain
extent on the internal milieu of the set
and setting these inevitable things that
we try to
but it is important to describe to plant
what does it look like is it tall as a
short is it broad-leaved as a narrow
leaved more importantly what are its
components not just the kidnappin words
we're going to talk today a great deal
about cannabis as beyond THC the other
components that synergize and if you
will really make it a gift to humanity
rather than a bunch of chemicals which
is the way it's going to sound as I
describe them we need to know the turbid
content the essential oils that give
cannabis its unique scent we also need
to know the smell and taste and most
importantly the effects that it might
provide particularly from a therapeutic
standpoint one manner of classification
that I found most useful is this one
that comes from paper research and if
you concentrating the panel on the right
you'll see that there are a number of
sections that describe the percentages
of the cannabinoids and terpenoids
their proportions picture of the
but and then in the third panel you see
something interesting other plants in
this instance of lemon and some
peppercorns why is that it is because
the terpenoid content of limonene from
weapons and carry off a lien from black
pepper are also common to cannabis also
in the third panel you see nice colored
wedges they give an idea of what people
have reported in terms of the effect
that this has had on and left third
panel you see a description of the smell
and taste when it's inhaled preferably
by by vaporization the bottom panel is
most interesting to me because I think
the terpenoids have been ignored and
these are really the refined aspects of
cannabis that give each type Akim of our
chemical variety sometimes miss named
strains give them their unique
attributes in this instance we'll see
it's very high in limonene this is
likely to produce an effect as an
antidepressant and bright agent and the
carry off lien of the blue very high
mrs. Kermit being an agent that affects
cb2 produces anti information and
reduces pain also at the bottom you see
a very narrow purple bar this is mercy
mercy is usually Pradhan
most key burst of cannabis and is
responsible for the couch lock and
sedation that is all too common with
most commercial types of cannabis but
there's so much more than that as we
follow through this panel which comes
from an upcoming book chapter that it
did with jae-hyun our COO we moved from
the plant into the leaf to the
unfertilized in the flower and
particularly in the upper right to its
trichomes the real action area of the
cannabis flower where the cannabinoids
and terpenoids are produced but beyond
that we have the beautiful chemistry of
the seeds even the sprouts as we'll get
into on so and then the roots the roots
have none of the same chemicals that are
in the flowers and vice versa but they
also have a remarkable healing power
that heretofore has been largely ignored
in modern societies
the chemistry part so these are the
vital cannabinoids the plant
communicates and you'll see a bunch here
most familiar to me THC and cannabidiol
but there are all of these depicted here
have had sufficient investigation to
know
what their pharmacological effects and
what the therapeutic effects may be and
this is the buy synthetic pathway by
which the cannabinoids that remain we're
not going to go through in detail we're
gonna focus on one precursor one of the
parent chemicals geranyl pyrophosphate
and as you see this is a parent chemical
not just for the cannabinoids but if you
follow it to the right it also has a
parent compound for the interpreter
winds
so the cannabinoids and terpenoids are
half-siblings and as I like to say
unlike its unblended family as they get
along beautifully let's talk a little
bit about THC of course this is going to
be most familiar to you and there are
many people and governments out there
that would like you to believe that all
the pharmacology of cannabis relates to
this one chemical this is so far from
true if it were true in 1985 cannabis
would have disappeared because synthetic
THC is marinol became available when any
money was taken it will tell you it's a
lousy drug with no therapeutic index the
difference between the amount that will
produce benefit perhaps on symptoms and
the amount that produces side-effects is
negligible but they're like this with
cannabis it can be like this a huge
merchant of state DM to the right
this does bind to CP 1 in the brain and
elsewhere it of course has pink healing
properties directly it's also a
bronchodilator and opens up the lungs
and there used to be cannabis cigarettes
for asthma the smoke Burke wasn't
helpful but the THC was beyond the
receptor activity it's a very strong
painkiller an anti-inflammatory 20 times
the anti-inflammatory capacity of
aspirin and twice that of hydrocortisone
it also the muscle relaxant that's the
basis for its approval as santa been
excessive prescription medicine in
canada and 20 other countries around the
world and of course it's an antiemetic
particularly in situations like
chemotherapy and we're going to spend
more time i can have a dial TC gets one
slide today I forgot before I can have a
dial so this is non-intoxicating Guinea
here it's non psychoactive that isn't
true because it does affect the brain
it's an anti-anxiety agent that can
counteract the effect of too much THC
it's also an anti-psychotic there have
been now two phase two
trials of either CBD alone or as an
extract in treating schizophrenia with
less side effects than conventional
medicines it is a very interesting
property it doesn't bind to the cb1
receptor but when it's around even in
tiny amounts it antagonizes the effect
of THC now that may sound like a bad
thing but it isn't what it's doing is
counteracting some of the less desirable
effects of THC while also boosting is P
killing and anti-inflammatory properties
it was recently discovered that it does
this through being a negative allosteric
modulator this is a way of saying it's
not binding here or a TC does but over
here and me P it produces live long and
prosper
and as we together I don't know I just
made that up
you've heard that before oh it isn't
neuroprotective antioxidant is much more
powerful than vitamin C or vitamin E in
this regard and me and the future be
used under conditions of insults of the
brain whether it be strokes and injury
etcetera it also is what's called a trip
v1 agonist like capsaicin the active
ingredient in Chili Peppers and so this
is important in treating a number of
neuropathic pain conditions one of its
primary effects over time may be that it
is a modulator at the endocannabinoid
system it boosts the amount of entered
cannabinoid inand amide and inhibits its
breakdown on overtime this may be a very
powerful effect it is a very strong
anticonvulsant I expect that epic
dialects which is a predominantly
cannabidiol extract will be fda-approved
later this year the problem will be when
we see what it costs
that remains to be seen as mentioned in
anti-anxiety agent in high doses CBD
shares with the other cannabinoids a
unique ability to selectively kill
cancer cells while being preservative
for normal cells this is exactly 180
degrees from conventional chemotherapy
where it's generally toxic and you hope
that you kill the tumor before you lose
all your hair or you've got wine so this
really needs to move forward
additionally has a wide variety another
25 mechanisms of medicine that account
for it being a strong anti-inflammatory
additionally how it works as an 18 xiety
it's mediated through serotonin as are a
number of other effects including
disturbances of thinking
in advanced liver disease potentially it
could either fear with slow viruses men
count disease and things like there is
not the likelihood we'll ever have a
clinical trial in those disorders
because fortunately they're pretty rare
a recent one that's interesting is that
CBD promotes bone healing in the future
it may be that this heretofore forbidden
drug is used to treat athletes that
break limbs in sports now there are a
lot of misconceptions about seeking a
recently written articles specifically
addressing those misconceptions one is
on some purveyors will say oh it's got a
point five percent CBD as if that's a
great thing this is a wonderful compound
however it's not quote that's a way of
saying he need a good amount of it to
exert these beneficial effects we've
already addressed this one it is
psychoactive it's non-intoxicating if
for lack of a better word all you will
commonly hear that it's a dating it is
not pure CBD is actually quite alerting
the problem is that most key movers have
keep that you have cannabidiol
any amount also a very high immersing
the couch light factor and so this is
created a misconception in there and we
have proved with eg Ximena like that
this is an alerting molecule
south-of-the-border you'll commonly hear
some base CVD purveyors claim that it's
legal in all 50 states
it isn't it is illegal in all 50 states
it's just that the law has not been
prosecuted I didn't say the way it
should be
because I don't believe that at all but
if you want to know what the lodge
really says it is illegal the problem
being that the Controlled Substances Act
allows hemp stocks and seeds if they're
clean but once you go and extract
chemicals from them it is an exception
to the exception and they're illegal
again another one when this came up last
year in an article where they stimulated
gastric acid exposed CBD to it for an
hour and got some of it to turn into KC
this does not happen in your body it
doesn't hang around for an hour even
though this reaction has been known
since night
forty it does not occur in the human
body and you have known in semantic
equipment to convert CBD in Bettina see
this shows some the same things the
natural history from the count plant
down to the pure crystalline chemical
and as you see in the last part your
body converts it into something else 7
min ago ex-ac media doesn't convert it
into THC you can do that in the test
tube now in each and you meet your
effort less about tetrahydrocannabinol
Baron this is president small amounts in
cannabis from southern Africa South
Africa Zimbabwe etc for a long time it
wasn't known how this worked but it's an
interesting chemical in that at low
concentrations that's in the antagonist
yet cb1 what's called a neutral
antagonist so it's quite different to
run them again if weight loss drug that
was subsequently yanked from the market
as a horrible side effects that actually
knocks down the activity the
endocannabinoid system
it's just occupies space and receptor
and would allay hunger and help with the
metabolic syndrome that is affecting so
many people in Western societies so he
has been shown to produce weight loss in
the obese it's also storing
anticonvulsant and also a painkiller
so unfortunately aside from GW
Pharmaceuticals which has a plan that
has 92 percent of its cannabinoids as th
CV
there's nothing analogous elsewhere but
this could come about with selective
breeding not with genetic modification
to which I'm totally against so moving
back for a second on TV is like teensy
but with a three carbon sidechain
instead of five so that brings us to CBD
P can have a diaper
it is like CBD with the three carbons
sidechain um this is a interesting
anticonvulsant you know that CBD is an
anticonvulsant this works on a different
type of seizures seizures of a partial
onset
focal seizures and maybe that the two
together are gonna make a better job as
presented in the plant now it will also
care a lot about the raw acid
cannabinoids so what the planet
generally makes it's not THC but TCA
tetrahydrocannabinol like acid some will
convert indicates a in the plan if we
look carefully at literature of the past
there were a lot of medical uses for raw
cannabis that wasn't decarboxylated
where you lose the co2 group on the
molecule and this largely revolved
around its anti-inflammatory properties
and abilities to treat a tumor it does
something that teach he does not affect
something called
tumor necrosis factor-alpha it's very
important in certain autoimmune diseases
inflammatory bowel conditions also
rheumatoid arthritis man it's also being
used successfully in small amounts to
trade seizure disorders that have
responded to THC or CBD predominant
preparations now why this is isn't clear
because there's a lot about this we
don't understand it seemingly does not
cross the blood-brain barrier that
filter system that keeps toxins out of
the brain but we know in seizures that
that rate
and maybe it just gets them to the
extent it needs to and people that have
that kind of problem also it's unclear
whether this binds to that cb1 receptor
some experiments of safety on others and
said no it's an inherently unstable
molecule and so if it converts to th see
if you could get some spurious results
bottom line we're studying it so it has
a counterpart in cannabidiol I guess and
CBD a so this is what CBD looks like
before it decarboxylation this is a
natural herbicide
hemp reading plans were infamous for
producing good weed killers also killing
worms and things of this story it seems
to be an extremely powerful antiemetic
against nausea about a hundred times
more powerful than CBD so again it looks
also based on the historical literature
that this was a very very effective
agent in treating tumors if you look at
the renaissance herbalist in europe they
were always discussing raw amp as a
treatment for tumors so a great deal
more work needed there this is taken
from 2011 article called taming TSE and
you see again
a number of different familiar plants
that depict their representative scents
that are also finding in cannabis on
basically the terpenoids are antibiotic
anti-inflammatory there are often things
that work on emotions and synergize with
THC monitor birds are the ones with ten
carbons and you'll see that there's some
different structures but what they have
in common is as ten card ten carbon
structure no nitrogen and all a
difference very powerfully and we'll
talk about some now there's a lot of
fine print here I did this to try and
impress but we're not gonna read all of
these what I want to say what else up I
mean is it is much too little abundant
in modern Canada scheme of ours a lot of
people particularly people my age the
great years of a wax prosaic about the
cannabis of the past because you know
remember that strain you know the one
where you can smoke as much as you like
and still have a clear head well there
isn't much of that around these days and
the reason is a lack of pining paintings
is an acetylcholinesterase inhibitor
acetylcholine is the memory
neurotransmitter in the brain so if it's
broken down too rapidly you forget what
was I saying
okay that's fun if you need to forget
how lousy a day you have at work I'm
going to prick your your boss was but
under other conditions if you're in pain
and you have to work or study you need
this
the counteract that short-term memory
impairment so in addition to that it's
really a phenomenal antibiotic to
broad-spectrum in you know it's just
great for clearing the head the Japanese
have a wonderful term for this they call
it shinrin yoku which is called forest
bathing and for anybody else the fortune
as most of us do to live in the
northwest but life gets you down you
need to take a walk and in evergreen
forest because that mining in the air is
gonna clear there all right next merci
um this is a very useful molecule if you
need to sleep and it does have a
analgesic effects it actually is a very
narcotic liked effect so this practice
is of pain relief that responds to
naloxone no lock zone is the opiate
blocker the same thing they give on the
street on the east side to people who've
overdosed on heroin
Janell okay but this is all too
prevalent due to modern breeding
techniques and produces this couch lock
that you know again some people like
that a lot of people don't and again if
you have to work or study it's just not
conducive to that lightning I've
mentioned before again this is more
common in the olden days but certainly
can be brought back you've all
experienced this if you walk down the
aisle in the supermarket there's a bunch
of artificial limonene in there because
psychologically we equate this with
cleanliness and bright thoughts but
that's not just psychological it is a
biochemical you can do the same thing by
running your thumb on a citrus rind
and you'll get that but this is a very
powerful antidepressant in Japan they
did a interesting trial hospitalized
depressed patients they cut their
depression scores in half got most of
them off other standard antidepressant
drug regimens and it's also a very
powerful in the instrument it has some
other facts that are still being
explored on a thing called adenosine a
2a where THC and CBD both work but three
different mechanisms there's some kind
of synergy going on there that I with my
colleagues are exploring now little ole
this again may be familiar for those of
these still are grandmothers who may
have the lavender about for its various
beneficial properties very powerful
eating xiety agent also spectacular
local anaesthetic
if you cook you should keep a bottle of
lavender essential oil in the fridge
when you get a burn just put it on meat
cover it with an ice cube and the beam
will be gone in a few minutes and
there's almost no chance of a blister it
also has a powerful anticonvulsant we've
now had documentation from my colleagues
Dustin Sulak and Bonnie goldstein of the
presence of a small amount of
in given Kiev are producing the key
difference in the ability to control
seizures and children taking cannabis
first treatment so we move on to the
secretary points we're only going to
discuss one today these are 15 carbon
molecules a little bit higher molecular
weight foremost among these is carry off
lien which is often the predominant
remaining turpenoid in the extracts
which tend to burn off the monitored
monoids
now it's been known for a long time that
this is a very powerful
anti-inflammatory agent but unlike all
the non-steroidal drugs out there and
produce ulcers this is a guest or a
protective it actually prevents that
kind of involvement it was only ten
years ago that it was discovered that
this is not just a terpenoid but a
cannabinoid is small because it works
selectively on that cb2 receptor the non
psychoactive receptor that mediates
inflammation and pain so what we've got
is in the pharmacology wrong there are a
bunch of companies working on synthetic
cp2 agonist that would do the same thing
but they've all failed mainly due to
toxicity modern pharmacology usually
rests around
FIO receptor using a computer design
molecule that will Lodge there the
highest affinity and highest potency you
work on that for seven years spent six
hundred million dollars and find out
that it causes aplastic anemia or liver
failure or something else that's
backwards rather on plants hemp and
medicine for almost all of our history
just a hundred years where we decided in
our hubris that we could do it better
than nature and I think we've been wrong
for the most part this also appears to
be an agent that could fight addictions
to other substances we know from animal
work with synthetics that rats who were
trained to be addicted to cocaine will
stop pressing a lever together when
they're exposed to cb2 agonist so we
could do the same thing with carry
awfully dirty and with no risk of those
toxicities so we move on to what I'd
like to call the cannabis odds and ends
and there's a reason for that because
the
dogs are involved again a lot of fine
print here freed Ellen is us a trite or
annoyed a thirty carbon molecule
none of the tops just in the roots so
this is a very powerful
anti-inflammatory agent again a not one
that's going to be permit all the side
effects from under on steroids
and it's shown benefit against a number
of cancer cell lines
this is particularly intriguing although
the roots don't make a tremendous amount
of this we know one must be working
because they're any number of people
particularly Natasha R is is going to be
speaking to you later that are using
this in artisanal preparations to great
advantage to treat skin inflammation and
other disorders it also can be taken
internally so this is really intriguing
to me because as it is for throwing this
stuff away so we have a neglected herbal
resource of possibly great value here
similarly there's an agent you probably
haven't heard of called canna preen
another potential maintain flam
agent is in a fear concentration in the
leaves and for those of you taking
pictures all this is going to come out
in that article that would be published
in August so if you want to contact me
then we'll get you the key information
and we should forget the seeds mostly
we're dealing with sin Samir ganja the
unfertilized female flowers but when
allowed to fertilize itself it makes
this wonderful seed which is probably
the most complete single food on earth
in that it has a digestible protein in
Destin a perfect balance of omega-3 and
omega-6 essential fatty acids and you
know if you had to pick one food upon
which to survive this would be a good
choice now the interesting Lee um when
you sprout it other things happen Kim
Fleeman is what's called a flavor an
anti-inflammatory chemical it was
discovered about 25 years ago it's never
gonna be developed as a job because
can't flame behaves too hard to separate
from can flavor and be so to purify it's
too difficult which is good for us
it raises the possibility that could be
used as an herbal agent and it's been
discovered that when you sprout this you
increase the amount of canned flavor and
if you have the right caliber cannabis
it's not yes
yep producing cannabinoids so it might
be legal in a number of jurisdictions so
this is a very promising agent for the
future again not affecting cox-1 and
cox-2 with all their side effects to
produce ulcers strokes and heart attacks
to finish off I want to give you some
examples using the fighter facts what
they can do now this is a type 1 plan TT
predominant this is mostly what is
available out there in the realm of
cannabis commerce but this one's called
type 1 climbing and the reason is you
see the big green bar so we have an
agent very rich in THC but yeah low and
merci
elucidation high in mining not having
that short term memory impairment and so
if you needed THC to treat your muscle
spasticity spasms or pain good choice
type 2 plants have roughly equal amounts
of THC and CBD this is the way cannabis
used to be before selective breeding for
the recreational market made it
type one now this one's too high and my
glutes got a lot of CBD which is good
and inflammation and burns the CBD is
good for for epilepsy it's also high in
low which is sort of violet bar down
there so it burns and epilepsy what do
they have in common
my guess is the need for this type 2
legend
type 3 plants are high CBD and and
Lohmann THC this one because it's very
high and carry off lean and he has CBD
predominantly it would be very good for
plane pain inflammation behind carry
ethylene it's also good to treat
addiction so again these are things that
seem very disparate but have in common
the need for these various components
this is another type 3 CBD predominant
um because it's very high in limonene
and low and sedative aspects it should
be very good for a treating depression
and anxiety that's got a fear of them
all another type 3 this one I'm really
excited about because it's not only rich
in CBD it's got a good amount of CBD v
so it should work on generalized
seizures and Cedars and partial on the
carry Halloween will provide reduction
of before
we'll also contribute to it being an
anticonvulsant what we call a wide
spectrum into convulsive it should work
in most of the many kinds of seizures
and finally I wanted to show this but we
left to right we have a title implant
high THC type two in the middle equal
amounts of THC and CBD and type three
predominantly CBD on the right if you
look at the terpenoid bars at the bottom
they look the same in each one so then
having the ability to compare these in
patients who really tell us a great deal
about what the contributions are of the
different components were keeping one
side of the same and we're altering the
balance of the cannabinoids so this is
very promising for future clinical use
and I hope they haven't exceeded my time
I'm happy to answer questions I know
it's your break time and if you need to
leave for any reason
please do so
hard feelings thank you for your
attention
[Applause]
[Music]