[Music]
hey how's it going everybody bubbleman
here and kind of a special surprise
tonight a higher end a friend of mine
showed up with this incredible piece of
glass i'm not sure if um you guys
recognize it but it is a fabulous
tourist klein i guess a fab tourist
climb AKA it's quite ridiculous it's got
the fab the taurus and the climb and i
guess today I'm going to take out the
bowl we're going to take out our detail
it's over here in our their mothership
gently place it in there we had a good
conversation about this on how certain
people might not put that in and I
understand that's fine but certain
people have the ability to do that and
it's okay so I'm doing it right now with
the permission of the glass pipe owner
we're going to take a little bit of the
afghani hits from the house of the great
gardener so yeah let's get this fab
tourist Klein fabulously Torah Singh and
climbing
it's like an absolute champion what a
beautiful piece of glass try to do some
photo inlays of the intricacies of this
fab I'm Taurus and the arts on it and
even the flecks of i'm not sure what
moldavite or something that are in this
green the flower of life patterns
stamped on the bottom even the flower of
life in the in the bottom of the of the
climb shower perk or whatever kind of
perk it is I'm not even up to date on
all these things I just know that this
is a special piece of glass and I
definitely wanted to share it with you
guys at bubble man's world so enjoy
you