all right here we go live on Facebook
with this character Johnny be in the
house and well I guess we should maybe
wait a second or two one for an audience
to come in every way fine you know what
we're building an audience it says your
life we're building an audience so it's
building oh look at that there's a
person there in the room there with us
hey there's six there's thirteen all
right well we can do this now
welcome Jared skully welcome Aaron wait
yes sir in the house this is Stephen
Simon's in the house
Xavier del Mare what up bubble man del
better äj-- is in the house we got a
whole crew of people Scot Connerton
first not quite but first in first 50
back gotta count for something Sam highs
with us John and I have been pressing up
a storm here we went to the to the spot
recently and got these different flavors
and we pressed up well we pressed up the
gorilla cooks and we pressed up the cook
so nine the burner cut and we pressed up
the Teflon which is the cherry pie
crossed with the own no wasn't it the Y
Wi-Fi Oh 43 yeah so there it is these
are the squished pieces that that we did
welcome Maggie Johnson this question
this question so there there I think
we've got a few pieces if we want to do
a 420 rip it is now 417 but really it's
almost 418 so I would say we have two
minutes to get your dabs ready for the
4/20 celebration I'm looking for my well
I'm looking for the carb cap and the
dabber so there's the job oh here this
is well this is another one that works
perfect especially if you're hitting
that little one hey the business to be
the case well you know what nice clarity
yeah we are pretty clear aren't we
how was the Teflon beautiful lovely all
three of these have been quite nice what
do you want to hit well I haven't hit
the Teflon well then let's hit Teflon
scratch it off I wish I could remember
what mine was because I squished
something today but it wasn't the Teflon
I'll hit the Teflon with
Taffet f1 the Teflon doing I like
beautiful chain hey Cal Chang in the
house welcome welcome
Joro Boehm Irie is right Shane Frey Borg
pressing some MK ULTRA right now we got
a few people in the room right now we
are one minute and Counting away from
our 4/20 celebration here on one minute
warning it's the one minute one minute
warning check it out 19150 torch oh you
won't need that I think you'll literally
be able to torch that up in ten seconds
all right and it will only stay cool
it'll get cool in like five to ten
seconds so there are your face right
there are you hitting uh I'm hitting
this little guy right here I've got my
little dab nothing major but a nice
house action is a nice 420 ripped a nice
420 rip well it's cool hey there's
Sandra colas aunty hi Sandy and Tanya
Sean Wolfe nice
all right yeah we got it 18 seconds till
this 4/20 celebration Kenneth Amin
Haynes is in the house actually with his
chalice live and direct from Jamaica
Shelley's Lee welcome nice to not be
alone smoking well I think the same
thing so fantastic stoked that we are
all here for 20 Missa for 20 I'm gonna
take a little extra of my dab let's do
this Johnny be happy 4/20 everybody
that's a great 4/20 go that was a nice
4/20 dab and hey you know the baby
Kate's may be small but I certainly
don't think of it as a secondary piece
like it hits like a champion right there
love the little baby Kate's was actually
hitting it quite a bit in the last few
nights
over all my pieces tell me yes a really
really um busy week day Friday yeah okay
righty now Hey what is everyone doing
for the Friday Jah yes job of course
John made enough for everyone so when
you feel like you're in the fear and
scar City and you feel like that there's
not enough for you that you're not
getting enough definitely remember John
made enough for everyone isn't that for
everyone we can share just sitting
sitting down to press my first eye swag
stabs of the day nice to catch you here
all right well excellent Andrew Lee hits
some 420 bowls with us I'm sure not
everyone is on the west coast
celebrating in the same time and many of
you may be in the 730 range or in the
earlier even later but hey we celebrate
nonetheless this is our 4/20 and we're
happy to celebrate it with you welcome
David Hutchinson is in the house while
Johnny B and myself sit here and just
kind of wind down a nice
nice day of Johnny B came by with a well
3/4 of herbs that we purchased at the
sunrise wellness foundation if you
watched it on the show the other day
welcome Jeff I free Bueller
anyway we he brought them by he kept two
grams out of each one and pressed the
rest and got quite a lovely return about
a 20% return on his twelve twelve grams
that he pressed out he got almost three
grams of rosin so they're a nice return
for him two and three three yeah so that
is the Teflon which is the cherry pie
crust with the Y 543 the o nine cookies
which is the burner cut and the gorilla
cookies which is oh man that one is nice
let me tell you that's pretty much how
this is lined up right now
so this was a really nice squish as you
know I always love the squish and this
was like dude how about my kids art over
your shoulders everyone appreciating my
kids are some pretty amazing all right
let's see that's like you can tell you
can tell he's advanced ah yes you guys
are dabba rific yes you as well Jeff I
free good to see everybody it's nice to
see that you guys come in and share your
vibes with us it's kind of neat this
this face Beck live you know getting a
little notification hey so-and-so just
went live well might as well go see what
those guys are up to I mean [ __ ] they're
probably hitting Jamaican Terps Jamaican
Terps pretty Serbs I'm looking I'm not
gonna lie well that was a 4:20 rip what
do you think we exchanged pipes and we
do just like a 424 rip it's almost for
24 and for 24 let's be honest is a
palindrome and we should always
celebrate palindromes for instance if
those of you that are unfamiliar with
the palindrome check out bail of flex
album UFO tofu UFO tofu being a
palindrome which means it's the same
forward as it is backwards also fish
did a song called the divided sky and
I'm pretty sure it's the equivalent of a
musical palindrome in the sense that all
the music is the reverse half way
through anyway let's have that for 24
Deb Johnny B do you want to hit some D
for 20k or do you want to hit some fresh
press did the Teflon which one says I'm
trying often guerrilla cooks guerrilla
cooks all right I'll hit other cooks
I'll hit your second press don't worry
these are special valves these are
special dams these are Johnny B's
birthday dabs and for those of you out
there in internet land I will have you
know that my good friend Johnny be
tomorrow tomorrow no no Monday Monday
it's Monday isn't it yeah it's Monday
Johnny B turns 45 and it's his birthday
so feel free right now to hit him up
with a happy birthday this this is a
Johnny B Byrne way no don't touch I
didn't I touched your knuckle you know
what a fantastic weekend I won't be
around on Monday of course so I got of
course a surprise birthday party last
bite
and then I showed up here to get some
squishes so I can have some superior
rosin for the weekend or some really
really good fine flavors on my favorites
okay great thanks to some guys
I think they do have some of the goods
that I do appreciate when you were
connected to this oh there's ro welcome
ro welcome David Powell everyone's
giving him a happy birthday Johnny be
happy birthday happy birthday John happy
birthday man happy birthday Johnny B I
like the variation I like it look at
that three happy birthday Johnny B's
actually that was a happy bday J Johnny
being I like the Hat
birthday wishes happy early birthday
from the great state of Michigan
happy birthday dabs up for you Johnny B
trying to be this one's for you thank
everybody for all those birthday wishes
I mean respect and I really appreciate
these are Wallace from Niagara happy
Earth strong JB god bless that's Kenneth
in Jamaica happy soon-to-be birthday bud
Oh should we show them some of the
photos so we show these guys some of the
photos you guys want to see some of
those photos check this out I think I
can do all right so these are the rosin
photos that I took of Johnny B's rosin
today my killer
and that's what I'm coughing to you
right now I'll be telling the flavor it
is so tasty have to dream
that's some fine resin there's a little
tease for you guys of some of what went
down earlier so hopefully we'll get that
and that's why I'm gonna open up my eyes
burn like the last time
okay that's those terpenes they just
thank you Eric Harold Francie says get
out of here cough cough seasoned vets
indeed a chaise in the house christian
bureau yeah indeed i hope you guys
appreciate that cuz that's some good
stuff there's mcmahon he was always kind
enough to allow me to come to his place
and photograph his beautiful plants we
had some good times I will say I like
that you're under the quiver right now
Johnny be I like I'm under the rosin
you're under the bubble hash the pumpkin
is under the dry sift we're all
representing myself Johnny be the
pumpkin
welcome to Stevie Hughes in the house
Oscar Valley era it's nice to see
everyone man I love it thanks for
sharing the link if you did thanks for
coming in and sharing your time with us
either way having some Babs get an array
really hey I'm not the only one that has
beautiful framed trichome shots that sit
on my table right like that's a normal
thing people have this this is like a
thing right you guys have pictures of
trichomes and frames around your house
right that's normal
ready is in the house fry up Friday
happy bday happy birthday in fright herb
Friday love it
well well we're getting dabbed up aren't
we that last dad was not a safe felt
pretty good that's like I mean that's
like some of the amazing flavors that
are coming off of that not sasquatch is
like I saw I had come it's good rosin
really quite quite nice from flowers you
know it was in flowers less than an hour
ago
and here we are hitting the [ __ ] out of
it so pretty sweet oh I hate to hear
that I'm not too sure the answer to that
you should post that in hash Church so
more people can have a shot at answering
it that's always it thanks thanks for
the happy birthdays guys yeah it's going
very quickly so I'm seeing and you know
this guy is getting old now swinging
glasses indeed well why don't we say
goodbye to them and thank them for
coming out we do appreciate it we'll uh
I don't know what we're gonna do now
chill you puff more bowls maybe squash
more hash you know don't we do yeah
we're on it we're on it just like you
guys are on it I feel like more
confident already I feel like really
like now I'm on it I was kind of a
little bit on the brink there for a
second right I'm not really but I just
kind of like ya know if he was we were
like Abbott and Costello who's on first
what's on third that's what I said
anyway there's nothing wrong with Abbott
and Costello that's a compliment right
there I grew up and I used to watch
Abbott and Costello and think those guys
were as funny as funny could be I always
loved to watch an Abbott and Costello
movie so thank you yeah yeah there we go
Ivan Costello hey Johnny B and bubbleman
yeah I wonder which ones which hmm
interesting
thanks for happy birthday Marcie Anna
Mia I see she spoke to the minister
Manitoba thing see it's rich I think I
church this church skipper I don't know
if there's going to be internet for me
it might not be in that access mmm
it happens it happens hey did you want
to take all that acid now actually I'm
taking it oh that's what you meant by
taking the acid ok well that's cool I
guess we'll see you guys later thanks
for tuning in these guys he saw