[Music]
hey good morning bubble man here I just
wanted to talk to you guys today about
the importance of feeding your endoc
canabo system daily for those of you
that don't know what the endoc canab
system is it's a system that works
within your body that actually regulates
all biological function having your
endoc canabo system up to Snuff and in a
line is very important and the only
plant on the planet that produces
cannabinoids for our endocannabinoid
system is the amazing cannabis plant you
can acquire the tpin and the terpenoids
from other plants and fruits but the
cannabinoids are exclusive to cannabis
so remember feed your endoc canabo
system
daily hey good morning uh I just wanted
to express to everybody that at my age
it's very important to feed your endoc
canid system get yourself keep yourself
nice and healthy that's the way to go
good morning I'm not W for brle but I
believe raage is very important at my
age bud is my choice of
[Music]
ruffage here here we are once
more meeting up along this journey
[Music]