[Music]
Welcome to Bubble Man's World and
welcome to filling up your dry sift
quiver. That's the title of the video
today that we're doing. And what I've
got here is I have a whole variety of a
different um sizes and and actual screen
sizes. Both obviously you can see that
these are a much different size screen
in just their actual size, but also the
holes themselves are different as well.
So I'm going to get into talking a
little bit about that. Um I've got three
things that I'm going to cover today.
I'm going to cover um the simple trick
that everyone's been talking about. Um,
two screens are used, a 250 micron as
well as a 180 micron. Uh, that's these
two right here. So, these are u my
mediumsiz screens and they come in a two
and a four screen set. So, I'm not sure
if you noticed when I lifted up the
screen, but I've cut my screen in half
here. So, you can see that with the
fresh heavy screens because we put them
on properly that even a rip from one
piece of the metal to the next, I can
still use this screen. And I'm going to
show you how. Of course, I will
eventually replace it, uh, as using the
best possible tools is always the best
possible idea, but I'm just showing you
that you can actually, um, use these,
uh, screens even once they've been
potentially damaged. So, I guess the
first way we're going to do today, um,
mentioned the three methods. I guess I
could do that right over there,
actually. So, I've got a little bit of
nugget in this screen here. I'm going to
change the camera angle for you guys.
bring it a little closer so you can see
what's going on here. Okay. All right.
So, what I have here is a tiny little
bit of bud that I broke up uh over top
of this screen and to show you this
process really to show you how
absolutely delicate it is. It's really
just a matter of dropping the herb.
That's probably more than I needed to do
right there. Okay. So, we lift up our
first screen and you can see on
it right here, you can see that it's
captured some contaminant. So, if I move
in for you there, you can see that that
is contaminant. It's sitting on top of
the screen and it's very delicate, this
contaminant. Okay, this contaminant can
fall so easily. So, what we really need
to do is we need to lift up the screen
like this, both of them at a time. And
I'm sorry that I don't have this on the
all white part of this screen, but we
can just do this. So that was the sift
wizard technique. I don't usually give
him much of a shout out cuz I find it be
a little bit negative. So this is what
you would call a very high percentage of
heads, possibly um upwards of 80 to 90%.
And that's because I've already run this
material once. So it's it's sort of at
the end knocking over the parchment. And
so another thing you can do with this
process is you can you can kind
of gently mix the the herb across the
screen. This is going to release a lot
of contaminants.
But what you can do with this method is
once you've collected your your your
your higher grade, you can produce a a
secondary grade that is going to be much
more contaminated. I can see already
that the color is is much darker. Keep
in mind this was only about 7 g of
cannabis uh total that I broke up here.
I just wanted to kind of give you guys
an idea of how the sift uh trick works.
And so you can also give this a little
shiggy
shiggy. And what we get here is gentle
gentle contaminants sitting on top of
this screen. And it's best to just keep
those off to the side. And then we can
take this sift. Now this trick can be
used over and over and over again. And
it doesn't just need to be used with
herb. You can actually use this trick
with sift as well. I'll show you how we
can do that real
quick. Just get this guy
out. Put the herb on the screen
here. Okay. Give it a quick
rinse. All right.
So now another way you can use this
trick is I've got my I guess my
colander. Uh this is a 250 micron
screen. I use it uh mostly just to to
get the hash evenly to fall so it's not
in clumps. As you can see here, I've got
a little bit of the barb. It's clumped
up. We can drop it in here gently. Not
going to use a ton because I just want
to show you the process. And I can
gently rub this over the screen, break
these little balls down. You can use my
finger to to break these balls down.
They don't they're not that
tough. Little bit tougher than um than
the brush will allow. Once you've got
these components broken into smaller
little pieces where they'll actually run
through the screen, then it's just a
matter of rinsing and washing with the
brush over and over again to push this
stuff through. And what you'll often be
found with at the end is you'll end up
with a tiny little bit of
contaminant. So, as well as a couple of
balls that just don't want to break.
So give you that little show right
there. So this is a lower grade right
here. It's completely covered in cy with
hairs and captate
stocks. So just from that without doing
anything else, without banging or
touching anything too
harsh, we can see that barely anything
fell through. So we're going to give it
a gentle card.
Just a gentle card to get some of this
resin to come through. This is a little
bit different than the herb
process. But what this will do is it'll
drop these resin heads and these
contaminants
through. And you can see now on my
secondary
screen that I have all of this
contaminant sitting right here on top of
the screen. To the naked eye, it may not
look like contaminant, but when I get my
macro lens out and I show you what's
going on here, you guys will see it as
clear as a
day. All right.
So, gather up a little bit
more. And so, this is from the barb. Get
that one over there cuz it was a little
different. So, here they have some pure
heads from the barb. Now, you can see
that the process is really giving us a
small amount each time. And so, that's
why today I wanted to go over a
multitude of process. All right. So,
back to the distance shot here. I want
to show you with the two screens what
I've done here, which is a fairly
important component. It's on the bottom
side of this screen. What I've added is
I've added four little spacers and I've
glued them to the bottom of the corners.
Now, these spacers came from one of my
Pelican cases. It's simply the foam that
was inside the Pelican case. I pulled
out two little strips for each corner.
Cut them about 2 in long and I glued
them to the bottom of the screen. So the
top screen sits like a dish, right? But
the bottom
screen sits upside down. So the screen
is flush to the frame. So you get the
two like
this. Okay. And this process is great
for having at your office next to you on
your desk, having it set up in your home
somewhere always. So, it's just sitting
there. You've got a nice um sheet of
plexiglass or glass or whatever you have
cut to fit your screens. I use this
little piece of white paper because I'm
constantly moving them around. It seems
to be easiest for me. Uh very easy to
brush off as well. And one of the things
I should mention that the reason this is
all going to work today is because it's
very cold outside. It's extremely cold
outside right now. It must be close to
below zero. Which is why dry sifting uh
a with the properly dried material and b
in the proper setting with the proper
variables i.e. it being cold and dry. We
don't want a lot of humidity in the air.
We want it to be cold and dry. And
that's what it is right now. No doubt
about it.
So, I guess uh I guess we could cart a
little bit of more of this gently
through. Not even carding it because the
hole is so big. I can actually just use
the
brush. And so, gently, gently,
gently. That's going to produce an
enormous amount of
contaminant, but a small small amount of
the goods. I just don't have enough
room. There we go. There we go. It's
always good to set everything up so you
have
room. Okay, get three nice little piles
here. Now, keep in mind, we've used a
very small amount. We used about 7 g of
bud to get these two little piles, which
I've already gotten all the good stuff
from that bud. Unfortunately, I wasn't
able to show you the fresh bud being
crushed up and then being used, but I
kind of want to show you guys you don't
have to have bud. You can use older
material that's trim or or or lar bud
that's been crushed up. Uh you can of
course use beautiful top quality bud,
which I urge you to do. And of course,
you can use sift as well like you saw us
do with this. And you could run it over
and over and over again through these
screens, throwing it down gently,
lifting up the two screens, collecting
the small amount of what's there, and
just putting it onto the side. This is
one technique. This is one method and I
urge you to have it in your hash quiver.
This is a 60 lines per inch as well as a
90 lines per inch, which is 250 micron
for the 60 and 180 micron for the 90.
The numbers are counterintuitive and
don't match up. As you might have
noticed, lines per inch is a much
smaller number to equal a much higher
micron number. So, I guess what we're
going to do is that's enough with that
process. I've shown you pretty clearly
what you can do with that if you need
be.
So now I guess we'll talk a little bit
about the other two screens. Now the
other two screens uh are the 110 lines
per inch and the 200 lines per inch.
This is a 110 right here. And what I
would do with these is is pretty much
the same thing. Uh you don't need the um
the the spacers, but you can put them on
as well. And what I do is I have the top
one right side like this. So it's like a
dish that my material can fit in.
Whether I'm cleaning sift uh whether I'm
cleaning uh cannabis bud or or or dry uh
or or um trim. Regardless of what I'm
cleaning, I always have this one upright
like a dish. We're not going to be using
it because I've already acquired the
secondary material that I want to use.
So, we're going to get right into
carding. And so, a lot of you know the
process of carting. It's uh simply put,
we can take a little bit of
resin, get it
into into
here. Always the bumps want to fall out
first. That's
uh just the way it's going to be.
Oops. Get rid of that
stuff. There we
go. And I would also suggest that you
get a couple of brushes. I clean mine
all the time, but it's nice to have one
brush that you can use for plant matter
and another brush or two that you can
use to scoop up your resins. Even when
you're dealing with um the cleaned resin
that you've already cleaned, it's nice
to have a separate brush for the
contaminant as opposed to for the the
pure heads.
So, we'll take
this. We'll run it through the colander
real
quick.
Right. And this just gets it even. This
is just like taking your flour and
milling it. We do this because um it's
going to remove a tiny bit of
contaminant, which I will show you in
the corner here again.
Yeah, that's just
nasty, nasty,
nasty. All right. And then carding. So,
standard carting that I've been showing
for quite a few years now, which is just
to take the resin and gently card it
back and forth on the screen. Okay. So,
what this is doing is a multitude of
things. It's going to push the resin
that is non-resin, i.e. the contaminant,
the plant matter contaminant, which can
be
capac hairs and a variety of things that
are
indeed appear to be glandular to the
naked eye and have a very golden color.
And you'll notice I'm able to card this
fairly
fast. Well, that's because I'm working
in a very cold environment and I can
feel that it's it's a slow process. I
can feel that there's a lot of
contaminants and very few heads.
But this process what it'll do is it'll
push those capitate stocks, those cy
hairs and any of those other non-glular
components. It'll push them through the
70 micron 110 lines per inch screen. And
what you'll end up doing, this is a this
is a process that definitely takes time.
Um, what you'll end up doing eventually
is pushing so much through that the
percentage of heads that you have on the
top starts to really unveil the quality
that you have. Once you can acquire that
purity, you'll really start to unveil
the the the quality. So, I'm not going
to show you this for an hour, but this
is a very slow process, the carding
process. And the next tip that we're
going to show you is actually the
carding process improved. And
so, just to see if even that worked to
the
slightest, let's see what we've got
here. Oh, yeah. Yep. Get rid of that
herbs that fell
through. Just to show you just from a
small amount of carding, a very small
amount of carding cuz this this was
clean before I even
started. You can
see that I've
cleaned probably close to a half a gram
to a gram of contaminant. So, that is
the contaminant that I pushed through on
the screen.
And uh it's it's I'll photograph it for
you guys. I'm guaranteeing it's going to
be an enormous amount of cy hairs and
capitate stocks and some heads that are
smaller than 70 micron. So um that's the
carding process you've seen. Um I hope
that you guys aren't going to be
disappointed that I'm not spending 20
minutes on each process. These are
really simple and what I really want to
inspire in you is questions. So if you
have questions about this particular
video, I will make a second video um and
I'll of each process specifically to um
reply to your questions that you have
because maybe I forgot things. I know I
went over the two screen trick really
quick and I'll explain you. One of the
things that's happening in that
two-creen trick is you have these two
micron screens very close together with
a little space in the middle, but you're
using screens that are much larger than
we normally use when it comes to dry
sifting. And that's where the trick
comes in. When you drop the material
onto the screen, the heads are going to
fall like rocks. They're going to go
straight down like this. The contaminant
is going to fall more like feathers. And
what they happen to do is they stick
into the secondary screen. Even though
the hole is very big and under normal
situations, if you were thrashing or
tumbling, everything would go straight
through. In this situation, the
contaminant is falling like a feather
and then getting stuck in the bottom of
the secondary screen. So that is why
that process works. This process works
because the screens are so tight on the
secondary screen. the 70 micron if you
can imagine the carding is going to
break up the non-glandular material and
that's why the cold is important and
that's why dry is important any moisture
any heat any humidity are going to work
against you in this process so you
really want to make sure you have a cold
environment and really really dry
material and then you'll see things like
carding really have an effect because
you're running this material over a
screen back and forth and on a
microscopic level what's happening is
the small contaminant the system hairs
and the capitate stocks over time are
breaking up and disintegrating into
smaller parts much like the way the
ocean will break down uh you know large
rocks into smaller pieces and eventually
into sand. So what we're going to do now
for our third process and this is the
newest trick that I've come across um
via online and through my friends. Um I
saw a gentleman do this some months ago
now and he was taking a DVD cover. I
actually have a Wii game, Scribble
Knots, one of my kids games. And he was
using parchment paper. So, we will pull
out a little parchment paper and we will
wrap this movie. And I guess what he was
doing, what I really like, uh, because I
played around with the static a little
bit myself. But one of the things I
really liked about this was that I
wonder if there's going to be anything
to rip this
with. I don't think there is. All right.
Well, let's see what we can do here.
All right.
So, get this parchment paper. Now, I
guess this works on a principle of like
static, but it's also working really on
the principle of what I'm seeing is it's
extending the size of the card that
we're using to push through
contaminants. And so, that's one of the
things that I was really interested
about. Um, I've only tried this process
a few times. Uh, D420K was really
excited about it the last time I talked
about it. He said that it helped him uh
clean up his carding game, you know,
tenfold. So, I thought, you know what,
I've got the audience. It's probably
very important for me to share this
because I want everyone to share uh to
to pick up their game of Tenfold. I
don't want people to be carding for 20
hours if they can be carting for a
shorter period of time. So, we wrap the
DVD in
parchment and then we push it through.
And you can see right off the
bat there's some heads that stuck to
it. Right off the bat, little bit of
pure headies
[Music]
here. All right. So definitely a very
cool
process. The fact that there's a little
bit of heads sticking to the parchment
each time and it's a very pure pure pure
uh form of heads. I think that this is
something that people could really learn
to use as an advantage to their dry
sifting method. We're getting that tiny
little bit of of pure heads stuck right
to the to the edge of the uh parchment
paper. And I have to say I like it. So
this is one more way. This is why we
have a quiver and this is why we got to
stop uh fighting with one another about
what the best process is when we really
what we should really be doing is we
should be discussing with one
another how we can move this forward.
And I'm definitely liking this large
sort of movie theater sort of parchment
paper movie DVD game whatever you use.
It's not too shabby at all. You can see
here I've got a nice little pile right
here, which
is much faster than the two screen
method. It's
probably get this taped probably next
time. All
right. So, we're just working it,
working it, working it. And you can see
that what we're doing is we're not only
picking up, but more importantly, what
we're doing is we're pushing through.
We're pushing through the contaminants.
And you can see that the material that
has been left on this particular screen
here is of a lower quality than when we
started. And you can see straight up
that what I've done is I've removed a
much lighter uh head from the darker
heads. So, what I'm going to do right
now is I'm going to get my macro lens
out and I'm going to photograph the
varieties that I did with the dry sift
tech with the two screens, the 60 and
the 90 LPI. Then I will show you a
little bit of the contaminant that I
pushed through with the carding
technique. And then we're going to move
right into macro photographs of this
process. I want to be able to show you
what I carded, what I took off the
parchment paper, and even what was under
the the screen of the 70 micron. So, I
hope you guys have learned something in
this quick little tutorial. I know that
the real thing that will open up our
minds is the macro uh photographs. So,
I'm going to go do that right away. I'm
going to take a dab of that, go do the
macro photographs, and I'll get back to
you guys with a little sort of finish up
um discussing what we've done
here. Okay, so I've been playing around
and um I took a few macro shots. I just
want to show you guys what's going on
here. I got the DVD, right? Here's the
three kinds from the DVD. I got in the
middle um three different kinds from um
carding on the three piles on the white.
Um the connect sign are from the two
screen trick, the 60 and the 90 LP. And
then I added these three on the corner
here, which is um a different kind of
hash that I did the DVD trick to. So we
got these over here. here. And you can
see probably out of everything, I'd have
to say the nicest material was this. It
was a I think it was a chemo material
that I had, chemo hashplant. It turned
out really nice. You can really see how
it pulled out an almost redlike head
compared to the contaminant, which is
very green and and powdery. Also, in the
middle here, you've got a very green
contaminant that came out of these two
much lighter components. And you see it
as well on the DVD. So, what I'll
actually
do, I'll give you guys a little bit of a
better show here rather than holding it
up at a weird angle. So, we'll show you
our DVD kinds. Boom. Boom. Boom. So,
this was um what what did we have here?
We had uh this was our best. This was
our second best and this was our swag.
And so, we've got it as well here. We've
got uh the best, second best swag, and
then we have the best, second best swag.
And then these three I have a hard time
figuring out cuz if you go closer to
them, you can kind of see a golden
material underneath. Like it got a
little hard. It got worked. So, this
resin could be potentially cleaned as
well. So, there you have it. All the
different processes right there. We can
show you what a raw sift looks like as
well on there just to give you that
color
effect. Quite dark, a little bit green.
Not the cleanest of sift. You can see
when I go into sift like this, how you
could see this come out of it. This one
right here is definitely what has
happened from Matt um over spinning his
material, which is no problem because
with the ability of cleaning it, you
can't really ever overspin it. From a
hashm perspective, you know, we like
gentler. It's definitely the way we want
to go. But if you want to make sure you
get every last little bit of that resin
off of your plants, I totally understand
it and I support it. So, I will be
putting in the macro photographs both
throughout as I'm taking the as I'm
talking about the resins. I'll show them
right at that point, but I'll also put a
little slideshow in at the end of the
video so you can see all the macro
photographs that we got. So, thank you
for watching Bubble Man's World. I hope
that you guys learned something from f
about filling your dry sift quiver. If
you guys have any tips or tricks that
you've acquired on your own and you want
to share them in the comments, please do
so. That would be wonderful. And if you
guys have any questions in regards to
things that I've shown here today that
wasn't clear or that you didn't quite
catch on, please ask the question. I
will make a point of surfing through all
the trollish comments to find the valid
comments and answer them for you. So,
right on guys, keep puffing that full
melt 99% dry sift. Like I
say, I bring
[Music]
back
Royal Bank.
[Music]
We
get
again on a
earth. Yeah. Oh yes. You're looking at
me so red
because why you so humble? I don't
smoke. That's why I don't
remember and I
burn. Oh yeah.
Oh
[Music]
sh must be burned like must be clean
raol certify the tree and he is the
wisest man
to
prop the soal leaders deceive my lovely
to glorify and teach. Get out.
[Music]
IS
marijuana just get a
friend of the
highest just from the
high of the
Give me the
[Music]
[Applause]
eyebrow. When you're sipping on your
tumble
down your
fun how come one little
make so
many streets my people still by gun man
say you resources and turning of your
yearly budget
but
herbs you know Oh yes, back royalty.