[Music]
it's just us yeah it's just
us oh let's puff the whole time okay all
right let's do
that hey guys welcome to Bubble man's
world I am over here with my good buddy
flab 421 how everybody yeah good to see
you always ridiculous glass in the very
near vicinity when Flav is in the house
or even better when you're in Flav house
yes the options are more for the last
little bit yes it's cool you're uh
you're making the move yes I'm leaving
the Lower Mainland so you know you
pretty much born here yeah born and
raised in Vancouver for the first time
in a very long in my entire life Rarity
yeah not many people in Vancouver are
born in Vancouver it's true and now I am
no longer in Vancouver so I'm moving out
to the country that's awesome dude yeah
getting my my 4 acres and a horse
Perfect Dude well here we are in Flav's
house the glass is Flowing the hash is
Flowing the rosin is flowing and uh we
figured we'd share a little dialogue
with you guys shoot the [ __ ] while yeah
you guys are visiting yeah we were just
talking about going to Jamaica with our
families and how fabulous that will be
yes for the Cannabis get that going yeah
pretty excited about that actually I
really want to get that happening so I'm
going to do a little backup rip once
you're done
that just got the one denail plugged in
but I figured you know what I think
we'll manage three pieces one denail two
heads let's get this party started we'll
make it work somehow I like
it
just dude I think I might
uh yeah let me go like this this is the
one that I want to really hit is this
going to come out nicely y yeah no very
well comes out always very nicely when
it's warm so I like that all right so
tell me about this little cup piece that
one is the team Japan cup from treating
myself don't ask me what year I don't
know I think 2012 2015 something like
that years ago cup piece it was the it
was the first team Japan collab that
they did together in a slop cup other
than the
um um practice cup that they did that uh
Marco Rena had that I think he actually
no longer has but anymore but did have
and um it was the one that was the
competition piece that was made it was
uh dke and uh Rose uh
condo and
um Rose roads kajima um and they were up
against Carlson and I think delene and
Aaron serson oh yeah and Team Canada was
uh Stratus and Corey and JT glass I
think the detail on that is so insane
yes it's so the dot work is ridiculous
yes like ridiculous
wish you guys could see oh wait I can
take pictures and you can yes and
actually you know what actually I'm
going to go off camera for half a second
so I'm just going to go and get the
accessories that came with this cuz yeah
they're pretty [ __ ] oh yeah you got to
see the accessories for certain I'll
tell you one thing I haven't hit a ton
of these uh cups but I really love the
way truly you're holding a cup in your
hand and you're sucking out of a straw
yes whether it's made of glass or not
the feeling of holding a cup and a straw
is so common and you're so used to it
that it's really quite a neat effect to
be getting a rip while doing that and I
got to I got to give it up to these guys
they definitely did the most ridiculous
I was at this event and uh I walked by I
took some photos of these guys blowing
uh different components of the pieces if
I can find them I'll share them on this
video it's always a bit of a pain in the
butt uh but yeah here we go we got what
do you have the stamp okay well it's uh
the Dabber a
Dabber I I call this is this is the
perfect rosin press cuz if we literally
squeeze like a 100 G of rosin out right
now you could pick it up with this flat
part so good it's a paper weight and it
has two go up nice and close and then
put your hand behind your other hand so
it focuses in on it like go close close
close block out the whole screen and
then the camera will grab it once I get
out of the way do it grab There It
Is God that is beautiful
dude show them the stamp part yeah and
then the FP side and you can go pretty
close to that
lens oh yeah right up there yeah that's
nice cool yeah and so that's the paper
weight or rosin
stamp
this is the Dabber
Z also just beautiful thank you for
doing that actually those are the things
that I always have to do and it's so
nice to be able to just sit here and
puff a bowl while my bro does it yeah
and the the
Dome and yeah I really really like this
piece here you want to give them an up
close of
that they're going to be like what is
bubble man
puffing W this is like one of the only
pieces you shouldn't here get rid of me
and before you it's you really have to
like block out almost
everything there you go almost
that looks cool no it's not clear
though now it's clear yeah
boom might be able to take your hand
away
now all right well I'm going to hit some
of that rosin right there little OG
rosin I think I still have some almost
thought I got my
head just in case you need more
[Music]
I really like that yeah I love that
piece you know there's so many times
that you'll see a beautiful piece and
then you'll take a hit out of it and be
utterly and completely
disappointed I'm not going to name names
or name pieces that's not my my my
mission uh but I really do appreciate a
piece that comes together as much in the
function as it does in the artistic ver
uh totally agree
and that's what I love about Mothership
actually is that the function like the
scientific um function of the pipes are
as on par as what you know people like
to think about the well you know what
it's exactly true they turned Proto into
art yeah they people are like that's
just a Proto piece it's like yeah say
that about any Fab egg it is just a
Proto piece but really anytime you saw
that for the first time really your jaw
hit the floor and you were like that is
beautiful how did they come up with that
what Brilliance did that come out of so
you really can't deny that the function
is so great that even without the
artistic the function is the art yes
when function becomes art M yeah yeah
and it's taken like the whole scientific
thing to another level like I mean there
were the the to certain Tauros that are
unique and like one off ones sort of and
you know ones that are more work than
others and this that and the next thing
but but um with Mothership it's really
it's taken it to to the very next level
where even the most basic production
piece is also so artistic mhm yeah and
that one that that uh bubs just grabbed
is the um the Dosa uh condo it's
the recently made recently acquired it
has a Dosa marble in the bottom condo oh
condo yeah sorry everything everything
else
yes EX in fact IED I posted the three
pictures of this on Instagram and people
are like what did condo do I'm like cuz
I never took I never took a picture of
the marble it was kind of a little bit
weak of me hilarious yeah sorry guys
yeah but there there's a condo marel
fused in the bottom yeah I know right
what happens when you start filming like
3 hours after you start
puffing but hey it's okay it's all good
I haven't seen you in a while no it's
true it's been a busy summer busy sum so
this one's for you oh thank you so
you're only going to need this I'll take
this out of your way
yeah ftk in ftk in dude it's called the
fkt
what I know right yeah I know that was
you know what I don't see that so much
anymore but it was kind of happening a
little bit and whatever that is I don't
know if that's passive aggressive or if
it's just Ridiculousness I had kids
calling me out on my own feed and I
would like post it being like ftk and
they're like actually it's the fkt it's
the
Fab Clin tus not the the but you know
you know what actually though actually
since this is the Taurus piece and this
is the clein piece and that's the Fab
it's the Fab Taurus clim H technically
speaking just you know people being
[ __ ] you know liking the one at the I
think it's the Taurus Fab Klein dude
it's the
TFK dude this thing has a dish for a for
a base like there's literally it's you
could put water in here and it would
stay in there and it's quite you know
deeper than it looks for as small as the
plate is really piece of that's the uh
the September shot for their month's uh
this month's uh
calendar yeah that's why I've been
puffing on it cuz someone tagged me into
their photo of um some mentioned it yeah
and um yeah and I was like oh [ __ ] I
haven't hit you in a while let's get you
back the thing is ridiculous it is like
it's like it's more than you expect it's
it would be like driving a a superar and
then you get in and you give it gas and
you're like holy [ __ ] that went way
faster than I had
anticipated exactly that's it right
there so I guess I should probably uh
rip this better yo [ __ ]
yeah always
ripping great way to exchange nails with
that drop down the drop down if it was
only for that it would be a good idea
the drop Down's a necessity to life uh
it really is you know they're just like
enail I I love enails I think they're
fantastically convenient devices the
only thing that's ever sort of sketched
me out is the extra weight you know like
I mean like a unit like this is really
nice cuz there's it doesn't add an extra
amount of weight the drop down keeps the
heat Source away from from the piece yep
um although I usually personally I find
that this is a little bit like asking
for it I'll usually have my drop down
pieces turned in almost as much as
possible and much closer to my piece I
just feel I do that with my Taurus I
bring it really into especially with
this particular nail cuz it's really a
beast it's a beast true oh yeah she gets
the job done we're talking about of
course the uh silicon carbide uh hybrid
titanium nail from denail wonderful
little unit I actually I actually
ordered one two weeks ago this is my own
little creation this is from enrio
sublimator oh yeah and this is the piece
that actually fits this oh go so they
denil had a very tiny tiny little tube
and it would get hot especially if you
wanted a real nice slow dab and leave
that thing on there for for a bit so
super small gauge I just took Enrico's
piece and put it on the little guy works
perfect there you go maybe I'll hit a
little bubs this time yeah yeah that's
some nice yeah that's some pretty nice
That's a Some 90 little 90 Micron
actually it's a 73 day do you have any
73 I'm joking yeah in that one nice yeah
of course he does of course he
does so are we going to end up seeing
each other in Jamaica for the Cannabis
Cup I really hope so I think I mean like
the plan is for that to happen um it all
comes down to for for me to go on this
uh wonderful little trip I got to bring
the whole fam damers why wouldn't you
with me so um it's just a matter of
making it all work like with the move
and all but you know like I'd give it a
good 80% possibility awesome yeah which
would be super awesome I like it super
awesome yeah we'll just rent a little
house in a grill or something like that
yeah dude N Grill with all my friends
yeah kind of tripping and then all the
Cannabis Cup people as well it is going
to be going be wild super wild it is are
you going to do a Legends dinner this
time somebody was asking me that the
other I think about four or five days
ago and I obviously had no answer for it
them I said I don't know you know I
couldn't imagine not okay there you go
you heard it here
first so bring your
resins
Beautiful b u T full hitting some dabs
loving the glass as always such a
pleasure to hit such beautiful pieces I
really am not sure that I've ever hit
that cup if I have I'm barely
remembering it's a rarity to bring it
out um I only I think I brought it out
three times in the last since I acquired
it wow yeah so um and and the first uh
possessor of it the other half of a high
integrity class art um he never brought
it out really like like twice maybe M oh
you know what this this exactly I
photographed it at his place once yes
like a year and a half ago or something
like that maybe less I'm trying to think
it's like you guys have so much glass
yes and it's hard to uh remember but I
definitely remember him putting this in
my hands and being like the DI so that
guy what it's definitely the chip on the
back I forgot to show the chip on the
back and like yeah like cool yeah like
the D alone has like more work on it
than Star of David es very much so yeah
yeah totally right yeah DA's like I like
this I like it yeah there you go but
this like this this da has more work
than like like a lot of a lot of pipes
dude a lot of pieces like full pieces
there just work on this absolutely
beautiful yeah they did a really
outstanding job but I mean those team
Japan guys they're top quality oh [ __ ]
yeah yeah I mean the quality of their
work's amazing the quality of their
people of their who they are is even
greater I've never met them it's
unfortunate that I've never really got
to hang in a room with them but I
suspected I I let things like that just
occur oh yeah it'll happen I'm sure I
mean I'm sure Yoshi will come back back
to Vancouver at some point in time yeah
was he the one visiting roow for a bit
yeah yeah yeah he told me he was like oh
I want to bring Yoshi and his son over
but it never ended up happening yeah
yeah I think you were in whis I think
that's what happened yeah I love
Whistler it's hard not to be in Whistler
in fact I think I'm gearing up to plan
this Winter's Whistler festivities oh
yeah New Year's again yeah something
like that which was pretty [ __ ]
fabulous last year if you guys didn't
see it go check it out after this video
it's uh I don't even know what that
video was called like what would you
just Bubble Man Whistler yeah Whistler
fun with friends I think yeah fun with
friends maybe it's like great Garder was
there DNA with Aaron with wife and child
was there Flav was there with uh wife
and children I was there with uh wife
and children and we had an absolute
blast we rented a beautiful house uh
well you know what go check out the
video you'll see there's actually like
five or six videos snowmobiling
snowmobiling was a video the the Lou
though no the the Bob the B that I
recommend to anybody that wants to have
how fast were we going over 100 km yeah
they were saying it was like 4GS yeah it
was insane cuz and and they said that if
if that we had started farther up the
track it it had accelerated a five they
don't even let you people were being
conscious it was pretty funny it was too
dangerous for the general public it's so
fast and so incredible that you can come
to Whistler so yeah I don't know it's
going to be fun we're going to plan a
Whistler trip we can't control who's in
Whistler if you guys happen to be in
Whistler and you bump into us we might
avoid you no I'm just
joking we will turn the other way we
will run away no idea totally joking uh
man I'm super baked I'm happy with that
oh yeah hard to to know which one to hit
again probably the one that's going yeah
I'm going to have this uh little bit of
uh bubble has here on the ftk or the fkt
or the ktf or the whatever holy [ __ ]
right Yep this is the one you had in
Amsterdam where we we would have
breakfast at the crno PO Ste on the
table it was the daily driver we're just
King around with it you know what I'm
going to miss the Cannabis Cup in
Amsterdam I'm not going to lie I've been
going there for 20 years and uh it's
it's it's been a lot of cannabis cups
from the from the old days at the Pack's
party house to you know the other when
we ended up at that Arena uh when we
ended up at that that old hotel that was
like Hotel was it a hotel Arena the one
that was like an ex it used to be a
pycho that was only one year they had
the cup there but I but still the one
that was across the water no that was
different no that was another one yeah
no there was so many different ones we
had the Cambodian cup the year it was
was right across from the milk vag and
you they only had one lift to lift
everyone up to the third floor and it
took like hours to get everyone up there
and then simultaneously everyone wanted
to leave and it took hours to leave
hours awesome hours waiting it was
hilarious I've only been to eight cups
in my life so I I can't claim to have
have been to them all but no me neither
there was like 26 or 27 of them and I've
been to like 17 or 18 which are still
pretty [ __ ] good oh yeah yeah yeah
skunkman Sam and Rob they've been to all
of them yep all Amsterdam ones they'll
miss it more than anyone and are they go
to Jamaica I can imagine that they'll be
there I'd have a hard time if they
weren't it would be insane if they
didn't make they have to judge the the
Legends absolutely you know and
unfortunately this year who knows maybe
Michael Rich our longtime friend uh who
passed away recently in Amsterdam uh and
one of the founders of Legends uh of
hash uh maybe we'll be celebrating him
this year in Jamaica that would be
[ __ ] cool you know cuz I remember
someone said it a couple years ago you
know it won't be long before you guys
are celebrating us old guys once we
start passing away so I even remember
when I heard them say that I I felt a
weird feeling like ah cuz you know it's
true it's not a mystery you know so sure
you might yeah people die and the older
they get uh the more likely it
becomes it's just sort of the equation
that you can't sort of avoid yeah it's
crazy man death in taxes death in
taxes man super fun coming and chilling
and seeing [ __ ] glass with you and
puffing beautiful hash nice to have some
varieties of bubble hash love the
different colors that you've got there
with your your light and your much
darker very greasy on this one very
tasty on both of them and a little bit
of rosin I brought for the game little
uh uh hash rosin squeezing out the hash
rosin with the denail Press which I will
be getting one I know I can't believe I
didn't bring it in I have it out in my
car maybe we still might who knows maybe
I'll bring it in and Dave will get
pressing while I go grab myself a
dynamite roll from Browns we'll see
what's going to happen here soon but uh
yeah let's call it a day thanks for uh
filming with me as always brother and uh
I got to take it out on this oh yeah for
sure got to take it out peace out
[Music]
everybody there we go
mango this rosin's so damn stable you
can just yeah it's like just chip it off
still a pull snap though it's nice yeah
it's quite nice
oops that was a little jump there wasn't
it it's such a big dish it's funny to
miss like it's
[Music]
huge that's the one thanks for watching
guys peace