Hey guys, welcome to Bubble Man's World.
It is another beautiful day here in
British Columbia. We got Monday morning.
It's about 11:00 a.m. and I just got off
the deck. I'm going to see my good
friend Flav 421. Apparently, he's got
some new mother ships in the house that
I need to go see. So, we're going to go
down there and have a little mothership
session. And then, more importantly than
that, I've got this. It looks like just
a bag that I picked up at the Bob Marley
Museum in Kingston, Jamaica. But in
fact, in fact, what it truly is is an
unbelievable collection of genetics that
could take some a lifetime. Well, Flav's
going to get them all in a day. So,
let's see what we're giving Flav today.
We've got from the good guys at True
Genetics, Phil. We got the sweatb band,
the F1. Got to share when you get
wonderful things. Of course, I'm going
to give Dave the sweatb band. It's
special. the work that's gone into it uh
means a lot and uh he's a good friend so
I want him to have it. Tried and true
Astro Boy. Got to give him the Astro
Boy. It's one of my favorites. The
smell, the taste, the It's just so
unbelievable. I I don't know if you guys
even saw this uh Astro Boy bud that I
just chopped
down. There we
go. Let's see what we got there.
It's dank, I'll tell you that
much. Smells [ __ ] awesome. 100%
deliciousness. So, got that just curing
away in a in a drawer with a bunch of
dry sip. So, the Astro Boy going to be
giving Flav the Harmony. Now, this came
via Doc Atomic from Reefer Man. So,
that's a Reefer Man strain, the Harmony.
And I threw a couple of little um uh
kixes that were on the plant. The plant
was stressed and I guess went into a bit
of flour before Doc gave it to me. It
just had these kixes with with resin on
them. I threw those in there just to
give Flav a little taste of what this
actual nug uh tastes like. Um oh, great
gardener Matt the Barbara. I mean, come
on. That's a favorite. The resin
production on this thing, I don't care
what else you have in the room. This
starts producing resin first and it
continues to produce resin last. So the
barb is essential to have in the room.
Some great gardener
genetics. Haven't given this one out
yet. Remo gave this one to me when I
went there last time and gave him sweet
skunk congo and astro boy. He gave me
the UBC chemo kush. So that's from Remo
and that's going to flower 421.
Ah, this was a gift again from Phil from
the guys at True Genetics, I believe,
from his new partner. I'm not sure if
that's where it came from, but old
school Ortega. I remember this strain
from the '9s, and I got to tell you, I'm
pretty damn excited. It's also in the
Astro Boy, the Apollo uh 13 crossed,
smacked the um Ortega C99 cross. So,
there's the pure Ortega right there
going to
Flav. What else we got? Well, Doc
Atomic. Can't just give a reefer man
strain away via Doc. We got to give
Doc's strain away. So that's the
Northern Lights. The one that he picked
out for me. I asked him for his most
special one and I got to say this one
reeks lemons. Major lemons. So that's
the
Docatomic. We
got the always. Oh, what would we call
this one? This one is This one causes
trouble when you share it. I'm not too
sure why. It's no more special than any
of the ones I just went by. Although it
is special and we do love it, it's the
Congolese. So, I got a couple of
Congalles cuts uh going to Flab 421
because unlike some uh we believe that
it is uh a strain that that should be
shared as all the strains are. I don't
really understand the whole rule thing
on strains. I should reiterate that the
strain was given to me 100%. I was able
to have this strain and I was even told
by Raina Ginga that she didn't mind if I
had this strain. And I was never given
any rules in regards to this strain. So,
I just want to reiterate that I'm not
one to go [ __ ] around and cause problems
in the world. I just believe that a
special strain like that should be
available to people who are in need of
it. So, Flab 421, it's coming your way.
Last, but certainly not least, and this
one I'm going to have to go out on a
limb as saying it's the rarest of all
that I just went through because this is
the 20-year-old lamb's bread that I craw
uh that I popped just a couple of months
ago. And this guy right here, um,
there's three of them. One is rooted and
two were freshly cut. This is going to
be very exciting to see what happens.
I'm really quite excited to to to see
what we get produced out of uh out of
that lamb's spread. I have some other
Jamaican strains going, but this one is
the only one I have that's 20 years old,
and I'm very excited to get it over the
flabs. So, I guess all that is left is
to take a nice big
rip and
uh actually and make our way uh down to
to C Flav and check out these mother
ships. pretty excited. I got to tell
you, when Flav calls me and says, "You
got to come by and we got to do a video
on these new pipes I got." I'm like,
"All right, I I hear
that." So, hitting the tie nail with the
ceramic insert. You probably can't
really see it there,
but I assure you it's there. Keeping the
dabber
clean. And I think we better do one more
before we head out there. I know it's
going to be tough puffing over there, so
we might as well start it out
right. Always excited to go to Flabs and
hit sick glass. Sick glass. I mean, the
guy just has the most ridiculous
collection.
Delicious. All right. Well, let's go
deliver us some strains to Flav, shall
we?
Well, guys, I made it to Flabs. I'm here
with Flab 421. And man, you got a nice
little selection of glass out on the
table. Thought I'd bring out a couple
pieces that we hadn't hit in a while.
And I think a few of these aren't even
on film. I think this Marcel's not on
film. I think this Punty, the Alice
tube,
uh the custom Man United uh Punty tube.
This beautiful new Jake C, which is
honestly it's one of my faves right now.
Yeah, that's a nice piece. We hit that
on your birthday. It is nice. It is.
Definitely down to rip that up. And then
this, which is one of my favorites. It's
my wife's piece, but this Marcel tube
that was done for um the other part of
High Integrity Glass Art Mhm. and was
gifted to me a little later on. But this
Marcel piece is just spectacular. Yeah,
that's a beauty, man. Really unique
stuff that you don't see on a Marcel
pipe all the time. No, definitely. The
the
[Music]
huge circled sections with the ready
lines. M I'll do a nice uh we'll set it
up in the sunlight and I'll make sure to
go through it and and show each piece. I
think uh I obviously brought you some
gifts. So I would like for us to each
have a rip. I'm definitely ripping this.
Okay, I'm ripping this. The FTK. Ah,
very good. Very good. So we have some
beline. Oh, we do. We got to split it
into two, but we have some hash.
Nice. I brought out some of the
seedsman's haze that I did. and some of
the older um MK dry stuff that you
cleaned from. I did some Astro Boy that
I Oh, lovely. wafered out. Nice. Nice.
So, why don't you hit that and maybe
I'll hit some of your MK Ultra.
Wonderful. This is it right here. Yep.
Wow. Yeah, that was the 99 cleaned
heads. Oh, wow. Yeah, that's unique.
Got some beline. Oh, wow. Look at
that. Boy, this is going to get me right
little. Right
little beautiful piece, man. Yeah, those
older Marcel Bubs are just one some of
my faves. Yeah, some of the styles, some
of the guys like Marcel and Jason Lee
and Clinton Roman. I mean, the art, the
sculpture work, the just the lines, the
color choices, everything. It's so
they're they're just so perfect in every
way. Yeah. Well, cheers, brother.
Cheers.
Oh, that puddle to perfection.
Lovely.
We should uh also note that
uh you have a bloody World Cup trophy
here. Yeah. And this thing weighs
serious. It's a lifesize. Like Wait, is
this 30 lb? Yeah, probably something
like that. Wow. I just thought that was
hilarious. Yes. I had to have it on the
table. Flav collecting the World Cup
trophy. Only English fan to actually
hold the World Cup for €150,000. It
could be yours.
But don't tell the Germans cuz they're
still looking for it. Yeah. Don't tell
the Germans. You don't want the Germans
after No, the Germans are coming. Oh no.
So, got this bag at the Bob Marley
Museum on my last trip to Kingston. And
I thought, what better way to bring you
these treats. Oh, more gifts. So, we
start gifts. with the Jamaican lamb's
bread. This is a fully rooted one. Okay.
Like with about 8 in of roots hanging
off of it and then two fresh nice cuts.
Thank you, sir. So, those are
yours. Ah, the ever elusive
congalles. Two fresh cuts of the
congalles for you, my friend. Thank you.
Um, well, this will be a nice thing for
you to have come at you. I know you're
friends with the Doc. Doc dropped these
off the NL a couple months, maybe a
month and a bit ago. So, this is a his
pick, the NL, the Doc atomic NL. I took
two nice cuts. All these cuts are very
clean. You know, I looked after Doc's uh
some of Doc's plants. I remember that.
Yeah. For a while when he was on holiday
out searching for some some new land
races and whatnot out in Thailand. Very
nice. Yeah, I Yeah, that's right. He
ended up finding them in Cambodia. Yeah.
Um, Ortega from uh, True Genetics from
Phil Pearson. Those guys seem to be
doing some really nice work. Yeah, you
know, they have the right foundation.
Yep. So, that's a special one. As is
this, maybe. All of these are special
ones. Here's a couple from Remo, the UBC
chemo kush. Very nice, dude. He says,
"Vegee it longer and you will get bigger
buds." Like substantially bigger. Thank
you, Remo. Thank you, Bubble Mat. And
right from Remo, we go to Matt the great
gardener. The Barbara bud. Two fresh
cuts of the Barbara. Lovely.
Now, those ones were on a mother that
have been outside quite a bit. I dipped
them. I didn't see anything, but some of
the leaves looked a little funky to me.
This is the only one you might have to
quarantine. Okay. All of these are as
clean as a whistle. Uh, this came via
Doc Atomic
um from Reefer Man and it's the Harmony
and I actually put a couple of
little This is fun cuz I wanted to do
this. All right.
So, put those in your hand for a sec and
give those a squeeze and smell those.
Oh,
dude. Harmony.
Yeah, I could sing without harmony.
Isn't that ridiculous, though? That is.
Yeah. I literally was like searching the
plan. I was like, I got to find one
more. Cuz I accidentally ripped one off
and then I I smelt my fingers. I was
like, you got to be kidding. Wow. Is
that not dank?
little smell of that thing, dude.
That has such a nice sweetness to it.
Yeah, that's going to be something to uh
enjoy. Yeah. And so, right behind that,
TGA Genetics, the Astro Boy. Come on,
dude. Of course, I'm going to give you
the Astro Boy. What a kickown head here,
eh? We're not done. We got an F1 of Phil
Pearson's True Genetics sweatb band. Oh,
the sweatb band.
So there it is, dude. This this is this
is the nine days of Hanukkah. Yeah. Did
I give you nine? Yeah. Awesome.
Thank you so much. Absolutely. Sharing
is caring. Uh yeah, it's never a bad
thing to share your genetics. Uh
especially if you know the people that
you're sharing them with are righteous
people who are looking to also get the
genetics out there or just grow the
genetics and uh use it as a medicine.
So, there's those. I'm sure you might
want to put them in your fridge. I will.
For the time being or whatnot. They'll
definitely be good in there for a bit.
Yeah. And then we're going to get to I
think we should puff sampling the wares.
Yes. So, that's what's happening. On
from sampling the strains to sampling
the boro. Hell yeah.
We'll get it
going. So, after an epic genetic
giveaway or an epic genetic give, re
reception, we need to puff. Oh, yes. You
know, so I'm feeling that.
Oh, yeah. Can I borrow a flame? By all
means. So nice.
Yeah. The Alice piece by Panty. Ponty.
That was done when he was still at the
mother ship. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Now
that was the season. Yeah, that was very
nice.
Very nice. That's incredible.
Like come on. Yeah, he's not shabby.
It's incredible. I'll show you guys.
This This one is my personal favorite
hunting piece, but only because I'm such
a giant United supporter. Glory. Glory.
Here's two things you've never seen
together. Yeah. I don't even know. Have
they ever won? Well, that's this is for
nations. This is for just a club. Yeah.
So, England has won the World Cup in
1966, but they pick a bunch of people
from their favorite. Oh, yeah. There's a
United players on the team, but um most
I don't know. I don't No, I know. No, I
know you're not a big footie fan. No, I
know for sure. But um but I respect the
fact that you are. Yes. You're
Manchester United. That is I remember
even when you got this how stoked you
were. Oh, yes, I do. In in life, my most
cherished things on this planet are
family, United, and then everything
else. Nice. Damn. Yeah, I'm under
United.
Sorry. It's cool. Uh, well, my love for
myself is even under my love for United.
Should pack it up with a little bit of
dry stuff that I made. Oh, yeah.
Wonderful.
Oh, it's like an apple a day.
An apple a day will feed your
endockinabonoid system and keep the
doctor away.
Cuz you got to keep that system fully
fed, fully charged. Absolutely. I had
quite a few people talk to me in the
last couple of days with loved ones that
have uh that are just being told that
they have uh fairly harsh cancers and I
mean I tell people to go to the Facebook
page the endockinabonoid system. It
seems to me to be a very good source of
as much of that information as possible.
Yeah, it is. And then without even, you
know, I tell people also that just to
consume it, to eat cannabis to get it
into your body, whether it's the extract
or the oil or the hash or the bud,
that's a good start right there. You you
need to consume it. I mean, yeah, what
we're doing is is more of a euphoric
enjoyed feeling. Um, it opens our minds
to the fact that we do also need to
consume it. I consume a little bit of it
every day and coconut oil infused hash
and I put creams on my my arm and my
back where I have pain from broken bones
with me in the fence. Yeah, CBD and CBC.
That's a good thing to do. Yeah. And so
many other ways too, right? It's
definitely um Yeah, it's a good thing to
feed your endockinabonoid system and in
more ways than just combustion. In more
ways than just combustion. My god. If
you're going to do it with combustion,
you might as well do it this way. We
certainly picked the most beautiful,
ridiculous pieces. Let's go on this guy
now. That's what I was looking at. This
This Marcel here, I'll I'll you can hold
you can to I'll pack and I'll light cuz
this one's just more enjoyable to hold
and have others do the work for you. Oh,
what do you want? Dry
sift. Some of this sift. Some of this
bubble. Some of your bubble. Let's try a
little bit of this. Ooh, the Astro.
Yeah, I love
it. Just put a little a little patty in
there. Look at this thing. Arms length.
How does your wife use this pipe?
Um, she handles it like a champ. Nice.
I know that there's a big rage, you
know, for all the smaller tubes and
smaller pieces, but there's just
something about a large piece like this
that's just I could imagine being so
much harder to keep from cracking in the
kiln. The size of the kil you're going
to need. Oh, yes. from big to
tiny little chip work uh mini Carlson
Shirley. Yeah, that's unreal. Yeah, the
constru uh the the the way he put this
together, the constriction points are
very good for a big bong. It does not
feel like a huge bong. No, it really
feels like it's tight and it's small in
there. not this huge open cuz as you
know as we start to smoke less of the
herb or none of the herb in my case and
all concentrates the better the
concentrate shop the better the
concentrates are I just seem to
appreciate them more through a smaller
piece yes I I actually do agree with you
and although this is a big piece it's
not really that big you know you feel it
the restrict the restriction in it yeah
it's got a it's got a nice chug to it
yeah the restriction is good yeah it is
very good considering there's like a
half liter of water in the base of it
Wow. Yeah. Well, that's probably the key
right there. Not leaving that. You bring
that right up to the top here. I noticed
there it is. Got to love visiting Flav.
Hitting glass like this. And this little
guy, as you can see,
put your hand behind it and then hold it
up close to the camera and it'll grab it
real nice.
It's very small. Mhm. We can show it in
the sunlight as well. It's a pretty damn
nice little piece.
doing it
up. Such beautiful
pieces. Like they really are just
beautiful, beautiful artistic pieces.
Yeah. Marcel's just obviously, you know,
OG. He's just OG and he's just in a
sense the same way Mothership is on
another level, I find Marcel to be on
another level. Agreed. He's my favorite.
They're just uh completely on different
levels from the majority. Oh my god. I
love that. Jake, see is the water's in
there. Yeah. That it's open. Yeah,
that's the best. The marble on the back
is hollow and it's shows the water line
of the pipe.
How is the water right now? It's just um
in the disc. All of it?
Put a little more. Yeah.
But yeah, these this JC amazing the work
that the mothership crew is doing now is
man that little Carlson. Holy
Christ.
Pretty
cool. Always such a pleasure to be
around such beautiful glass. Punty
Marcel Marcel fat plan forest from
mothership Manchester
United. And uh he's coming back with
that uh
what do you call that? It's a JC mini
straight fab.
JC Mini straight. Yeah. Made the line
work. So nice. I like the way he's got
this up high. Yeah. Yeah. And just boom.
Everything's attached.
Yeah.
Fixed bucket. Slides. No, everything's
fixed. See, I don't know the lingo. I
like that I'm learning it, though.
Everything's attached. It's called fixed
bubble man. That's cool. I can admit my
ignorance in the regards to
uh to your knowledge in the glass scene.
It's always a pleasure. You keep me
updated. Be kind to my eyes and my ears.
Indeed. Sure is beautiful.
Shall we dab it? Uh yeah. We need some
melty goodness and some heat. And we're
graing. Yeah. The hit on this one
actually is really nice. This is one of
the better hitting pieces that I've
acquired more recently. I like it.
Darn
tootin. We're going to hit a little. You
know, I did forget my my carb cap
downstairs. Ooh, always good. So, I'm
just going to heat this up pretty good
here. I'm just going to give us
reasonable hits so we don't need the
carb cap. Okay. I find when you put a
bigger one in that the carb cap is
extremely necessary. Yeah, we're just
hitting nice little one bangers. Be
good. It's right on the bottom there.
Yeah.
[Applause]
This is a banger. Yeah, I can hear it up
a little more. I think actually I think
it did okay though. It worked.
You know your pipe. Yeah.
Booya. Oh
wow. That one open up.
Oh yeah. Oh, that is [ __ ] tasty.
Booyah. Shine indeed. Yeah, that Homa.
His afghan. That's the one I wished I
would have brought you. The Afghany. Oh
yeah. Next time. Next time. Got to leave
something for next time. I love that
Afghany. It's soon becoming one of my
favorites in the in the garden. It just
res both the Afghani and the barb. I
mean the barb obviously has the Afghany
in it. It's
um they're nice. They really they they
they thicken up faster. They produce
resin quicker. Other than Astro Boy.
Astro Boy produces resin very early on.
Astro Boy makes I mean it's all about
the the resin farming, right? So I mean
the ones that create the the great
resin, the Astro Boy has always been
great for that. It's always made such
good hash. Oh my gosh. As it ever. Yeah.
So yeah, you have a pretty healthy
collection. Thank you. To add to the
show. I look forward to seeing what you
do with it. Yeah.
Well, there is certainly plans in the in
the works.
We have uh a little bit of the star
dog. It sure has a nice bouquet on it.
Hey, it does. Yeah. Yeah. It's kind of
hard for me to
pinpoint. Exactly.
That's you. Um you know, it's it's kind
it's kind of hard to pinpoint. I It's
like It's kind of caramelly, but
like like
like evergreen. Yeah, there's it's
smooth though and caramelly. It is
smooth. It definitely smells like like
burnt sugars. Smells flushed if that
makes any sense. Yeah.
How long of a flush did you do on that?
Long like 3 weeks, four weeks. Four and
a half. Awesome. That's the way to do
it. Yeah. This was this was this is all
from leftovers from a plant that was in
a big 20 g. Yeah. I can't wait to uh I
have this going from the clone you gave
me. Nice. I managed to keep it alive
while I was away in Jamaica. My wife
kept it alive, so that was wonderful. I
um it's rooted and transplanted and
growing. So, should start producing into
a little plant here soon. I've got a
couple of other tents that are blooming.
seem to be a little bit slow on the
blooming. They're they're they're
blooming, but they're they're sativas.
So, yeah, they're at two weeks or or 3
weeks, and they look like they're at one
week, two weeks. Another 10 to go. Yeah.
I mean, some of them have a good two and
a half months left. Totally. Another 10
weeks, even longer, depending on. So, I
do have in the other in the other tent,
one's just pure sativa. It's East Coast
sour Diesel, it's Congalles, and it's um
Sweet skunk. Nice. The other one I have
a variety. I have John's My Little Pony
in there. I have I I have a Jamaican.
The first one that I'm blooming with the
Jamaican that I'm awesomely excited.
Yeah. Exactly. Right. I know. It's not
the most amazing looking plant. No. But
just because like from the history of
it, from the seed to like how long it
was sitting, whether whether or not
we're going to keep it, you know,
whether or not all the people I gave
that cut to were going to be like, "Oh,
I was just excited to see it cuz you're
the first one to have flowers from it."
Yeah. Exactly. I will be. Absolutely.
So, I'm pretty excited about that. And
there's a couple other strains in in
with those as well. I have some other
things. I can't remember off the top of
my head, but I think an Afghany and a
barb. Yeah. It's always nice to have one
of those in each. You won't believe it.
For hasht
Yeah, that that that uh that barb really
produces resin like you wouldn't
believe, man. That's nice.
Well, I think we're going to continue on
and puff uh puff some bowls. We might uh
I'll I'll I'll I'll show you a nice uh
sort of lineup of all the pipes in the
sun with the video camera so you get a
real nice breakdown. And uh dude, as
always, it's a pleasure, man. Thanks for
having me over, man. Boom. Peace out,
everyone.
Beautiful. So, now really the last
Heat. Heat.
[Music]