welcome back to Bubble man's world here
we are again Deja Vu except John's gone
and Flav's in the house dude good to see
you man to see it's been like a month
yeah it's good to see her back here from
uh Spain yeah I haven't seen you since
uh since before we left for Barcelona so
had the VAP L last time that is correct
is this what we were hitting too that is
the mini one yes oh yeah so we were
hitting this little mini guy here I see
you've brought the larger of the two
that you have yes the medium Joe Peters
uh banjo honey Queen goddess with the
recycling
back with the recycling back and with
the Dosa Mothership honey bucket female
female jeez that's a mouthful it is why
don't you say all that in one
quick it's like in one stumbling
sentence yes
just it all out so yeah these are
unbelievable pieces for those of you
that haven't seen them before um they're
definitely some Next Level [ __ ] the the
um even the um just the quality of the
hands and the digits the fingers all the
glass work the bees the thickness the
Amber the it's just all really quite
incredible and it it always uh never
ceases to amaze me no the two real Gods
yeah I mean banjo for his his figures
and his sculpting I mean he's just so
awesome yeah I mean that is damn near
perfection he really is yeah it's
[ __ ]
awesome unbelievable well enough talk
about this uh we're going to talk soon
about what Flav is here for but in the
meantime I'm going to uh I'm going to
rip up a bowl of some of this dry sip
that's in the house little Afghani from
the great Gardener very does that look
just like cream it does actually
yeah I'll take a triple triple of that I
think you should have a triple triple of
that I'm uh
all right get you the there no worries
doer Shan we get it away from the
screen not that I doubt your heating
abilities whatsoever but wow wouldn't
that make for a great video go to dry
sift and the screens have a giant hole
in
them so yeah that that patties well
pattied out very well full Melt from the
great Gardener we're going to make some
full melt ourselves FL brought a couple
hundred G of the Renee a real oldtime
favorite strain of mine that is just now
wreaking up my entire house in the most
beautiful of ways so no complaints on
that all right close her up boom
that was an eye
closer what an incredible
hit I mean uh it's always a pleasure
hanging out with you Flav because
obviously I've always enjoyed glass art
and the he glass pipes MH but I have
become much more obsessed with the resin
and with the quality of the resin and
with that you know I I'm I'm quite happy
with my production glass my little
Hitman baby cakes and my you know
Mothership not that those are low
quality
production pieces no but it's so nice to
hit a piece of this caliber with hash of
this caliber yes you know it's just
really um it is a treat no it's a it's a
it's sort of a symbiotic relationship
would you say with the the concentrates
and the the the hey glass
and yeah yeah both need each other they
sure do oh yeah so we are you should get
yourself a hit of that
Afghani well I'm discussing what's next
up to bat um Flav has not yet seen the
little dry sift trick that actually most
of you haven't even seen because the
video that John and I filmed yesterday
is still uploading onto YouTube right
now but here I am about to film it again
and we're going to show flab this cool
little trick uh this is once again from
uh a Facebook post by a guy by the name
of Dry Wizard not too many shout outs I
will give him the fact that he told me
this technique other than that he's he's
a he's a fairly negative guy and I hope
that he can potentially be more positive
uh on the outset of all things but if
not it is a cool idea and we're going to
share it with you here
today one second
yep uh the torch the easier the
one-hander yes there you go that's a big
one for the little guy hey yeah with
Dome or without uh with Dome be pretty
hard to hit that
yeah but I want to have this uh there's
such a small amount of water and this
hash is so [ __ ] tasty I want to have
almost no filtration M all right that's
a nice little piece
mhm so cool so yeah we've got the four
screens here we've got the two that I've
been using for years the um uh 150
Micron and the 70 Micron which are known
as 100 LPI and 200 LPI
and then we've got the new screens the
ones that you've never seen before no
this is the first and this is a 60 LPI
and a 90 LPI so these sizes are larger
than what we're used to this top screen
is a 250 and the bottom screen is a 180
so basically the lower the
LPI the higher exactly you exactly
although they meet in the middle okay
you know what I'm saying when you get to
around 120 lines per in it's close to
120 they they meet and then they cross
and go it's strange okay so let's drop
some Renee buds on here yeah and Crush
her up yeah I mean at first we're going
to be real gentle we won't be crushing
these ones up on this screen this is a
more of a gentle process where we
literally um just gently
bounce and try to keep all the herb on
the inside
although it wants to bounce around was
it's definitely easier when you're using
powder these are full bone dry
nuggets and so the purpose of this
process is because the holes are so big
tons falls through on the second screen
the majority of the contaminant somehow
gets caught up in the second screen
either by piercing it or literally just
laying flat it seems like the balls
falling this short little distance seem
to make it through whereas not a lot
else does H interesting yeah so we'll
see what Renee is saying here we'll try
it with the buds and if we see a nice
return we'll do it a few more times so
it's really not that much of a process
like that literally what I did just
there yeah it should be
enough down gently
and then you can
see all the contaminant just sitting on
top
there that little
back just that gu
Perfect all right
[Music]
now no but a little rip and guaranteed
it'll be pure
heads so yeah let's try it again and
we'll break the herb
up
more let see what we can
find all
right um thinking maybe
go in at her well I like I want to grind
the herb up the right way uh grinder is
ideal yeah let's do that we'll be back
all right so we have ground about half
of that half of it still in Bud and the
other half we've ground up pretty good
mhm might as well give it a little oh
God does it smell great hey oh
yeah just give it a
little shot of
that don't have any glass so going bare
hands one of the things I was just
noticing to flab was that the the bud
although it felt so so dry when uh when
we first touched it and you can it
breaks up quite nice there's still
moisture inside the Nuggets when you
break them up so um with a strain like
Renee which is no slouch for Tarin it's
not going to be losing any extra Tarpin
you could let this literally sit out
like this in powder overnight right out
and yeah dry it out that little extra
bit and uh I think you would have a much
easier time sifting with it it's all
about getting your material to the
perfect texture the perfect place and
dry sifting is definitely not a misnomer
it is to be done
dry that's one of the reasons I don't
really support the dry ice method
they're using fresh material and that
wax membrane is just a little too fresh
all right
so let's see what we've
got okay A little bit of P tamut so
he there we go
[Music]
a little
TI for you to have a nice Gap mhm you
ready here this is his other
trick you have the
bounce so that's supposed to give us a
second
grade
[Music]
should interesting hey very so we've got
two very distinct colors one's very
blonde and one's quite dark very green
uh Choose Your Weapon you know I'm going
to hit the I'm going baby cakes baby
cakes for let me put a little water in
there for
you I have a pendant rig from Cory
that's roughly about that size anyway
just with the big side car Arm coming up
there you go sir thank you sir Renee
full melt dry sift oh man I bet you that
tasted good
wow
yeah that tastes spectacular yeah oh
well why don't I I wish you could all
taste
that okay also very sticky on this uh
second grade yeah definitely no
slouch get a
little dabbed up in the one ball that
was an i
that's good you can tell it came out
before you were ready for it to come out
quite excited about that thank you
sir oh man was that nice tasty that's
all it was was just
that was a vapor hit it wasn't even
smoke no yeah totally man excellent well
there's our little trick that gives you
a rip each time you do that little 10 to
15 second trip I think next up we're
going to get rid of the little screens
step up to the big boy screens and uh
make some sift beautiful what do you say
fantastic all right we be back see you
soon
all right so we've got
the
[Music]
Renee powdered
up still a little bit of in nug form
here I think a good idea when you're
working with herb that has a tiny little
bit of moisture in it and your real key
is that you're trying to dry
sift is to spread it out thin on the
screen and go puff
bowls for about a half an hour or so
which we will happily do yeah that's
what we're going to do right now while
this sits here mhm and gets
dry got these fingers in here it is dry
don't get me wrong just the center of
the nugs cuz Renee also is a very tight
strain the flowers do grow very dense
yeah it sure does yeah it's like a
little tiny ball of wetness on how many
weeks did you go with this um these ones
went eight oh okay yeah so and my friend
always took Renee 9 to 10 oh yeah yeah
oh [ __ ] I've even cut it down in seven
sometimes think there might be some
throwing Hermes well that's why people
cut it down and the thing about Renee is
it always Hermes always but it never
seeds but people cut it thinking when it
Hermes that they can and keep the seaing
from
happening and I swear you should do the
experiment next time grow The Strain a
couple more weeks really yeah
really so don't worry about the hermit
no they won't produce seeds they're not
viable hermies I've never seen like ever
and and I saw a lot of Renee yeah yeah
yeah
totally lots of
Renee such a fragrant plant it really is
it's just a great great great
smell all right we're going to go puff
this is going to sit here and we will
see you
soon like real soon like in a quarter of
a second I'll edit the video and it'll
just be like we'll be back and we'll
just be sitting and be like hey how's it
going guys good to see you again anyway
you get the
point all right well we have got
ourselves some chairs we've switched
spots if you noticed I was standing
there and flab was standing here it's
not a mirror anyway grabbed um I grabbed
the hos the Pacquiao G cross the number
four oo nice as well as the Kush two and
three from John I've got your MK Ultra
that we cleaned that was a month or two
ago and then I've Got The Afghani the
heom and I
believe the Barb so I've got the Barb
and the H that's Barb
that's
[Music]
haom yes Shish
Berry excellent all right well we've got
some flavors uh let's say I'm ready to
hit that
one and I think I'm going to do a little
mix I love the color on this afan this
afan you can't really see it it's like
caramel cream
it's so
nice not sure how well that worked but
I'll make sure I give a little pan and
show you the uh quality of
that um actually this real
quick here's a little piece of it right
here ready for a dab this is
the all right
well that is just a pleasure to
hit quality hash Quality Glass I mean
it's even kind of above and beyond yeah
both yeah you know and the way the
recycling tube comes up with this in the
Melt With The Honey drip this is the
recycling tube and it comes up and goes
back into the the back of the queen yeah
and it's sitting there with water in it
yeah yeah just a little bit right before
it drops
in yeah that's very cool yeah well what
do you would you like me to um the Barb
actually please it's a bob yeah that is
fabulous stuff that's the one yeah that
is what are you heating up on um I'll
use the same
yeah can't [ __ ] with the with the Honey
Buckets they're just too
good well that's a nice dab by anyone's
standards
a nice dab of the
Bob that is a beautiful it's like
smoking a whole joint to the head in 30
seconds oh the smell of this
Renee I love a situation where a good
buddy comes over with epic glass
beautiful cannibis and says let's sit
around and
puff and dry sift we'll film it all for
your YouTube channel which reminds me
we're going to get him a YouTube channel
coming up here um Flav 421 will be the
YouTube channel and uh we're actually
going to film his first video tonight in
the office later so I think you will uh
I think you'll get the idea of what he's
going to be doing for his channel it'll
definitely be a channel that you guys
want to check out so that'll be flab
421 how was that barb that was
scrumptious that was scrumptious he oh
delicious yeah yeah I love that [ __ ] I
tell you I hit that Afghani and I am
just zooted yeah oh that is delici it's
such unique color differences yeah on
these he and even since it's really
pretty it's the same screen size same
method same everything
so the I love the caramel cream look of
that Afghani yeah scy has the crazy
color oh yeah it's like cremma on the
top of an espresso it's
crazy yeah it really is it really is
it's funny how it's so much more
appealing than the almost greenish
tinges of the hom and the Barb mhm
although they're full melt beautiful
tasty delicious resin tot that color
just adds a
certain it makes all the other ones
really I mean if I took these away if I
took this away these would look less
green but you put that next to any of
them yeah no like even these ones down
here look more green with that
absolutely sitting there yeah yeah it's
true that's crazy uh interesting all the
differences of the uh hashes I'm pretty
sure that the colors are the essential
oils the tpin and terpenoids MH at
different um Cycles in their life
whether they're new or old or mature uh
they tend to get darker they tend to
create different use different colors
and it's definitely um it's definitely
interesting thing I've found over the
years uh particularly photographing with
the macro
L wow this has a great texture to it
yeah it's like sand soft sand
yeah Johnny be I think it's time for
another rip some of the Johnny
Be H the johnnyb I think
so which one shall we do let's go for
this one right here
here a little
press and then a finger people often ask
me is it
dabbable well you tell
me that's pretty quick actually yep
certainly dabbable
dabble all right hit
man
here she still holds her own even
amongst the
professionals
yum yeah
get back in there
you
veryable I find the
smaller a piece is MHM somehow the more
enjoyable it
is for hash sming device oh I for me I
mean with everything it's about the
certain hit the perk the amount of water
the amount of filtration that's coming
but I I always like
a faster sharper hit less water
filtration mhm yeah well all these
pieces are quite small in that sense
yeah there's I mean in this one there's
next to no water at all there's like
literally
drops that one's also you know there's
like less than an ounce of liquid in
there y same same with this one too
actually oh yeah that looks like a shot
yeah shot proba just yeah they probably
just like an ounce in there give a nice
little push down on there s
here
yeah puffing Wild the herb is a
drying been loving this dry sifting
lately uh soon I'm going to be getting
real heavy back
into wet washing nice I've got these
different levels of bubble bags out
right now and I'm really sort of gearing
up to I've been gearing up all winter
actually to get out to the ice caps to
do this ice
cave bubble session yep and I'm hoping
that will be the beginning of a good you
know intense spring and
summer uh you know mad bubble washing
lots of wet washing will you go up to
the ice caps all all through the summer
time um you know I I'm looking forward
just for that really being a sort of an
event a a twod day one night you know
where we stay overnight film the whole
thing make a bunch of bubs I'm not sure
I'll be going back too many times I
guess it it's it'll depend on how Beyond
blown away and inspired we are by The
Experience cuz you got to admit it
sounds like a pretty good experience
going to a you know milliony old ice
cave on a glacier that you have to go
for 45 minutes on a snowmobile just to
get to yes it's uh sounds like an
amazing experience yeah exactly so I'm
really looking forward to that and I've
just uh yeah I've got a lot of friends
with a lot of herb that needs washing
and um it seems like a good thing to get
the bags out and
reestablish with
people just some the basics you know so
many people have been experimenting and
coming up with different ideas and I
think it's important to go back to the
foundation that will assure Purity mhm
will assure a full melt product if you
have the quality Y and then from there
go off and experiment and as long as
your quality you know doesn't go down
all sor not your quality but your I
guess quantity really it's all about
purity at that point you can't make the
bubble any better than it is uh with the
bags but you can make sure that you're
getting the right you know Purity Y and
the right yields
yep all
right one more rip for Flav cuz we
haven't just been taking 20 rips each
off
camera all right so
we balance that around a little bit not
too much just
basically gently kind of doing this sort
of
thing much like what a tumbler would do
to it as it was tumbling
around you don't want to grind it into
the screen really too
hard dropping is always a
nice nice way to get it done
and
I'd always suggest too when you're done
dry sifting like this um to clean your
screen don't let it sit around
dirty um whether you have a brush or um
you can just take them outside and kind
of drop them bang them on the side and
they they will release but um it's
definitely a good idea to do something
rather than to just leave it with uh
resin on it like this uh you're asking
for trouble hold on so put this one
here
okay a fresh card over there sir
Flav all right let's see what we got
here it's fluffy
we get some this
[Music]
time
P very
Greening
looks W in there
yeah you are aren't
you so we do a little bit caring with
this resin
[Music]
little pieces the
side so yeah generally will'll card this
up for a little bit it's not a ton
there's maybe a half a gram to 3/4 of a
gram here but we'll card it up and we'll
clean it into a nice little pile of full
pure heads 99% anyway and we'll dab it
up and then we'll smoke it and then
we'll smoke it and possibly do it all
over again so hope you learned a few
things from watching and hope you
enjoyed yourself Flav and I are going to
get to to cting this up we'll end it
with a few macro shots of what we ended
up getting this was the Renee remember
dry sift and uh thanks for watching have
a good night peace all right so we've
cleaned the Renee up and we have
our last and final third
grade our second
grade and our first grade
this will be the
dabble so we didn't get a ton but there
it is broken up into three three
[Music]
bits oh W you were sleeping
is reing
for
in
in and while you were
resting we are
blazing
[Music]
for 60 year old graduate from school
protecting Fe the line rehap them G for
for
in
in I know the
way can't give up out the Lord of
[Music]
love very
translate our dreams Real by the
me you
turn love