[Music]
alright here we are
we got flat 41 in the house he's got the
buck Marcel angler we've got the banger
what's that get the tiger
oh yeah good call god this pipe is so
ridiculous bro I know and to be hitting
Dobbs out of it - I've never actually
done it
I've only smoked coals out of this pipe
so this is actually
I'm pretty excited about this
I don't know what I was thinking about
thinking about selling it for real I
don't either I was shocked and shocked
and dismayed oh yeah here we go oh yeah
I get that that's important
little carb cap oh it's cool with the
brakes guy behind you the angler you
heat it up more cool cut some nice low
temps
it's so good
Jeffie right behind you boom alright
well this is an exciting moment on my
deck hitting the Marcel Buck angler from
flat-4 to one who's on the camera right
now and I've only ever hit bowls of hash
with a beeline in this out of the Marcel
push Bowl this is the first time I put a
banger on it so we're gonna heat this up
and have a nice little dab alright
god I love the weight of this piece in
my hand the size of the can and the way
it feels so planted and then of course
sitting up against my shoulder right now
as well as right on my body I can feel
three points of contact with this pipe
and for me three points of contact for a
pipe like this is definitely what I eat
wad all right I think we're gonna go
what are you safe laughs oh yeah I think
you're probably okay
[Music]
it's like hitting a little double can
it's like saying hi to an old friends I
mean how special is that sun's beating
down the oceans blue and puff in the
buck marcel angler give thanks love
[Music]
look at such a beautiful splitter though
there may be a tiny bit more left in
that most of it rapid butter that we got
out of that yeah like crystallized right
away the color is just so beautiful move
to macro photograph it we have to
[Music]
original indigenous beer back
original indigenous dear kanga
[Music]