[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world I'm
sitting here with Flav 421 in the house
hello all it up Budd see you again good
to see you dude good to see you always
as always You' bought some uh some nice
treats for us to enjoy I guess we're
just we were just really having a puff
session really yes we're just hanging
out we're hanging out we're having a
session and we figured hey we should
film a little uh for the bubble man's
world audience I know that I've been
waiting to hit this piece for quite some
time yes and I wasn't sure who I was
going to hit it through I wasn't sure if
it was going to happen through high
integrity glass art or if you were going
to bring it over one day just in your
own personal collection yes which no
well I mean for the the the company had
it for a while and I uh recently just
uh acquired it personally right off off
high integrity glass art yeah um so tell
everyone about this this cup all right
well um it's one of the it's the first
team Japan cup what you would consider
team Japan which is um the original
Incarnation is D gay from slop which is
the design of the cup the designers of
the cup
um excuse me sorry Rose roads
um and condo yoshinori condo and the dot
stacking is by condo the
uh dot flips the dot filif flips are
done by Rose rhs and the uh construction
of the piece itself is done by dice Gade
um it was done um at treating yourself
Toronto I think I think three years ago
can't remember now yeah two or three
years ago I was there yeah when they had
um they had the second um incarnation of
the um flame off at treating yourself
and this one the competition was the
three Japanese artists as well as Marcel
and no no it wasn't Marcel no it was
Carlson and serson and Peralta but
Marcel was there running it yeah he was
the one running it yeah he was running
it exactly and um the Canadian team
consisted of uh Cory cottam Stratos
Patrick Stratus Stratosphere glass and
um JT glass very nice yeah Jared toner
so a good year for the glass blowers
wasn't yeah it was a lot of fun I mean
sitting and watching these guys um do
this cuz you know I mean they'd never
been that and I personally and most of
the people there i' never seen them ever
do any of their and they were just there
it was just kind of like oh there they
were right there yeah just just watching
you know I mean and it was it was
fabulous so I mean to have been able to
acquire it myself is is very nice um it
was very good of of high integrity glass
art to be able to uh to get this for me
so it's awesome dude yeah I'm going to
write uh Light It Up yeah please
do cuz you've already got the dabbers
loaded bro I
do we're pre-planning pl's pl's is
exactly we're not pre-rolled we don't
pre-load we pre or we don't pre-roll we
pre-load I like that
little
dad beautiful sunny day dude it is a
beautiful sunny day for dabbing on the
cup this ridiculous with the Congo
between us oh
lovely little outdoor action
yeah so nice
see your other lovelies sitting over
there soaking up the sun yeah these ones
just you know they were uh they were the
last of my indoor crop um I got a little
bit of um bugs and and Milo from Friends
passing clones on and what I finally did
was I just sort of I got rid of
everything these were the last few and
instead of just like killing them
completely I was like I'll put them in
my backyard and let them they're looking
nice now I'll let them s out well you
know what they say about a plant you put
it outside and it usually gets better
pretty fast you know for sure I mean
even more so you plant them right in the
ground mhm but these guys are yeah I
could do that without one right there
planting in between the Roses yeah and
the
poppies you want to hit that
oh love to of course nice little
Ripper yeah these the slot cups actually
hit real well M um the function on them
is really really
good yeah definitely they have a nice
feel to them as well but I haven't hit a
ton of them but the few that I've hit
I've enjoyed for sure I'm a bit of a
snob when it comes to hitting uh hitting
the nicest thing that you can possibly
hit I love obviously the mother ships
I've hit so many of your beautiful pipes
as well as uh higher ends Rose from high
integrity glass
art between you two
guys and I guess the relationship I've
had with glass blowers for the last 15
or 20 years Big Time managed to hit some
nice pipes in my day when I was a when I
was young like like later teenage years
I would come to your shop to check out
what was going on cuz I mean there were
other stores around but there was
nowhere that had quality glass made by
the guys in Bellingham when everybody
was there like Marcel and when Slinger
was in town you know oh way ahead of his
time Slinger lived here at the time like
I mean Slinger and hippo were like
household favorites mhm yeah they were
they were doing their thing it was
really nice it was a unique time I
actually found
recently melting point footage from the
original degenerate art show oh slick
and this footage in my opinion and that
art show really spawned the degenerate
art documentary that Slinger went on to
do uh at the time I guess I talked to
him recently a little while ago I asked
him hey why didn't you ever use that
footage and he said I just didn't have
it so we weren't really talking much at
that time or he could have probably
gotten in touch with me and I would have
made sure that he got it but uh I'm
going to put that footage up um the
interviews with all the different Glass
artists and some of the footage of the
pipes that were in the show uh back in '
04 cuz' 04 we did degenerate art and
then in ' 05 we did regenerate art so
those were two shows in a row they were
both great shows and they were both real
fun to be a part of and I definitely uh
I can't wait to share the footage of
these
blowers 10 plus years ago doing
interviews at my shop totally and for
this art show yeah it's like Marcel
right and yep who else was there oh
Amber pel andrini was there uh um max we
had there ease surf was there um yeah of
course Brian and hippo and
Slinger um Chris oh nice mroy mroy came
um Jason Lee showed up absolutely uh or
he showed up for the second one his he
was in both of them I just can't
remember if he himself showed up I
believe also bearclaw it was his coming
out like becoming like he had never been
in a show before was his first show to
be in and uh many more than that I'm
forgetting for sure I'll have to go
through the video to see their faces and
to hear them doing the interviews to it
be great to see them so much younger too
back in the day absolutely you want to
load me up the da there oh I suppose
that can be accomplished awesome but we
figur we'd hit a few out of out of the
qus Banger here out of the cup and then
we've got a few pipes on the sideline a
couple of ships that we've got filled
with different um things to hit off of
rather than quartz we have the silicon
carbide which of course if you follow
Tony vora's Instagram or Facebook
accounts you can see that he's really
enjoying his silicon carbide uh Bowl
says it's by far the tastiest hit he's
taken really you and I can test taste
that out today that's a good idea and
then I've also got the new dab Master
sublimator plugged into the atomizer and
and plugged into the mothership straight
Fab that I got from you y and we'll see
if we can't uh maybe hit some uh Vapor
rips and maybe even some double deckers
dabbing on top of the and see if we can
feel that difference that Enrico's
talking about when you hit that dab and
pull it through the bed of weed and have
that all sublimate at once there's I
think there's something to be said for
it so dab on the through the top Dabber
part with the with the flowers on the
inside
chamber
intriguing I love a quiver my friend I
love a quiver yeah I love the options
that was a real nice hit that was great
I let that sit for the perfect amount of
time to just get the just nice and turpy
yeah but also like I did get a
substantial hit that didn't let me leave
me feeling less than oh yeah totally you
know that's the one thing that I found
incredible when I was first got the
sublimator and I was getting these big
rips but it was kind of he there was
problems at the time it was it was
breaking and this it was in the early
days so it's uh I'm definitely not
calling out sublimator it was a brand
new product he's increased the quality
of it it hasn't had any breaks on me
since I've reacquired it in the last
week but the old one it just sort of
what happened was eventually it stopped
working enough for me and then it was a
pain in the ass so then I do the
electric nail but the electric nail
always felt like I wasn't quite getting
the hit that I was getting from the sub
now after not using the electric nail
for sometime or sorry the sublimator I
found that the um the the the nail was
perfect it was fine but I stopped a
vaporizing herb so one of the things I'm
really stoked about getting that this
back is getting away from this mentality
where one has to be the best or I have
to choose one over I want them all I
want to be able to hit quartz with a
torch I want to be able to hit a
sublimator with my herb I want to be
able to carry my denail with the three
units and pull out these are all things
that I want in my quiver and as I get
older I'm learning that it's not
necessarily A you don't have to choose
one you can be happy with a combination
do it all yeah exactly smart don't fair
enough I mean a combination you know we
were talking about earlier you know ego
gets in the way of things you know and
it's true it's very true and I agree
that like to have an open mind to all
the different things I mean everybody
has a personal preference absolutely you
know but in all reality until you've
actually experienced all the different
varieties how can you know what your
preference is right true enough you can
know what you think your preference is
this is true but that's quite different
than knowing what your preference
is anyway we're going to rip away on
this cup for a little bit but when we
come back we're going to have the
silicon carbide nail on the table and
we're going to have the dab Master
suppor on the table wonderful be back in
a
bit all right so we've got uh the dab
Master sublimator on your right on our
left right here plugged into the
straight Fab and then we have the
Silicon carbide hybrid titanium nail
from denail in the Cory cotum drop down
in the mothership Fab Egg and I
guess I don't even know if we're so much
comparing
things as much as I mean this this has
been the the one of the best hits I've
had taste wise yeah actually I do agree
having used it with you before I I agree
that that that is a very nice tote it's
definitely very tasty but um it'd be
interesting to tell test it up against
the dab
Master just to see taste wise cuz the
sublimator is doing something different
other than being titanium this this is a
silicon carbide nail and that's what
they focused on and then it goes down
into your pipe but the sublimator as as
this might not look like much to people
this atomizer this this metal Bowl
titanium Bowl but it truly to my in my
opinion it's something about it makes it
the game changer because of the way it
just holds that heat in um the closest
thing I've seen to it actually was
denail puking beagles deep dish Banger
or S the dog the dog house the one that
you and I've said before I I actually
quite like that thing yeah that dog
house was amazing that thing was [ __ ]
cool I pretty much missed that yeah I
and I actually don't understand why they
didn't continue with that sort of
thought process in that line next time
you talk to them you should tell them
that mhm true enough yeah cuz that was
cool there was something going on there
for sure yeah so I don't know what do
you say a little Vapor hit sure always
but we you do to ground up I ground up
the harmony o nice I have not tried your
Harmony yet yeah nice small little
pinch yeah with the atomizer the right
temperature you smell the vapor
instantly just when it's touching the
side of the
walls There You Go sir thank you thank
you
we can just lift this even oh there you
go
boom it's very tasty nice taste that's a
very nice taste better sure off you got
another good one in
there booo yeah holy Snapples dude that
was a good
rip yeah got me jealous
I need one of those that one just sort
of just jumped up at me well the crazy
thing too is is that you just hit herb
yes it's not like you just took a a five
star dab of of the the super melt or
something you know what I mean like you
just if we rosined that it probably
would have been just a medium to small
size dab instead of like a third of a
small joint whatever it felt like when
you just exhaled those two big rips
either way so I'm definitely a fan on
that you you produced like some really
nice the
goo and it smells great what do they
call it it's not they don't call it
reclaim what do they call it no they
call it sublimate sublimate and it truly
what it is is it's a distillate it's
like what Horatio did with this he took
his DH he took his dmon yep and
he roved it till it evaporated and then
recondensed and everything that was left
in the rotovap was that nasty get rid of
yeah and all that's is the the
recondensation the vapor from the but
the smell of that is so good it doesn't
smell like anything's been burnt or
anything bad has occurred in the process
whereas and The Taste actually doesn't
have like I've never been a fan of
vaporizing cannabis it's just not like
flowers it's just not something R yeah
and the taste it has the weird funky
like burnt popcorn sort of a taste well
because I say what we just did there so
much isn't vaping cannabis as much as
what we really did did was we just
vaporized hash that happened to be
diluted on can we we stripped the can
it's like we we extracted it with heat
as in this flash way almost the same way
rosin works the way you get this
pressure and this heat and the oil comes
out at the perfect temperature well
somehow he's figured it out that when
you get that herb in there and I mean
we'll do it after we hit the silicon
carbide um we'll do a double decker hit
and then we'll well that's what we'll
finish it off we get the D lemoning and
the bubble hash with weed in there put
the we'll put the herb in the bowl put
the hash on top of the herb in the bowl
and then double decker the delemon down
be fun it'll be good yeah so I'll let
that heat up a really important thing
for the sublimator to work properly is
to always keep the atomizer hot hot hot
it's got to be the temperature that the
wand is the real job of the wand is to
heat the atomizer I you have to keep
that in for the most part it always keep
it in and the same thing with the carb
cap he said always leave it on if you
let this cool down and it cools down
just a few degrees when you put it over
and you suck that cooler temperature
through it's going to steal some of that
magic that only occurs at a certain
temperature for a certain amount of time
which is yeah it's interesting
interesting okay so I guess I'm ready
for a little
Harmony kind of excited here this is
really tasty actually yeah well I love
VAP and flavors man it's been a while
since I Vaped any herb a lot of people
were shocked because they said Bubble
man's you know they they they were
shocked you don't smoke weed man what
are you doing smoking weed listen I'm
not smoking weed I'm actually vaporizing
the hash off of the weed that's what I'm
doing I mean you can't deny like there's
just a certain reality to things you
know and you can't deny the flavor that
comes through
I mean I personally don't know if I
would be putting that into any of my any
of my pieces but in in the ability to
use it with you you can't deny the
things that are claimed are 100% true I
love this Mothership for it totally yeah
big be pipe holds it careful I never
feel like it's going to tip no it's got
one of the really nice put it in the egg
no yeah no no it's got the widest base
it's seen a wider B in fact that's the
widest base mother I've ever personally
held out of all the ones that have come
through as well and I mean he's got a
bunch of different pipes that you can
put this thing in that he's um carrying
now but one thing I don't like about it
is the plastic like sorry I'm not you
know I'm just giving an opinion and it
has nothing to do with the quality of of
of anything it's just I don't
like
using anything that has plastic on it at
all and I really don't and and the whole
metal thing just sort of feels like I
understand understand that it's a
necessity to
the
helicopters they're going they're going
to get the grass from the ski and
thieves yes but yeah so anyway the metal
just feels a little strange to me you
know being like a I don't want to say
glass snob but you know that's how you
feel some days yes truly I hear that but
yet otherwise you have to admit if it
didn't have the rip that it had you
wouldn't even consider no hitting it no
no I would not you're hitting actually
function the way it says that it
actually would function exact I wouldn't
I would pass it off as nothing that's
correct but it does they have they
definitely have something there with the
way they we just hit what I would call a
medium to small size joint between the
two of us oh totally way what a great
pie it literally cut through the hash
that we smoked already not in the sense
that I'm higher just different it it's
it took it to the this direction a
little bit you know well it makes it in
in the way it vaporizes it makes it a
little more cerebral it does absolutely
you know as as opposed
to I would agree with that it almost
sativ sa
sativ if that's a word thin thin thin
Leaf drug variet yes yes the the narrow
drug cultivar the nld the nld the nld no
truly it does have some sort of uh
difference to it so how about silicon
carbide I think we should we need to try
now so silicon carbide y all right and
then I think we should even go back to
the quartz just to finish it off again I
mean I wouldn't say no no silicone
carbide is at temperature got her at
about 700° you have a dab right there
already got a dab right here
wonderful got a nice
big carb cap here which will come in
handy for this monstrous surface that
this is okay
interesting very
interesting great tasting rip
it went deep mhm like deep y it's not in
my throat at all it's like deep in my
chest the silicone carbide definitely
has this I've mentioned it before
preserved taste yeah there's something
preserved that doesn't get preserved on
most other surfaces and I've tested it
against titanium Sapphire ceramic quartz
and Titan uh I went back the same one
are you Stone there mark
Stone and titanium and quartz and
titanium and quartz and
titanium so there you go here's your
carb cap as well very
nice give me a little bit of an itchy
nose too on the exhale which is always a
good sign a little bit of
spice you definitely need a big carb cap
for a silicon carbide nail yeah you
[ __ ] do for sure yeah that's you know
that's actually the sublimator carb cap
he uses for his um torch nail that he's
got going on y but
uh I pulled it out to use with this cuz
I love the the nice uh neck on it I love
no no this is good yeah this is a good
little Dabber yeah you know or a good
little uh cap good little carb cap for
sure for
sure well feeling pretty Ivory after you
know cup rips okay that is the the
flavor
is substantially better than any
tie oh yeah yeah it's not even I I only
really compare it to quartz quartz you
really can only compare it to quartz
it's tastier than quartz the only is the
sapphire bit that you have a lot that's
pretty much my favorite it is eh yeah
but it's a pain to carry it around the
sapphire because it's porous it seems to
absorb the material into it so it'll
take it'll be a nice off- whitish color
or clearish opaque and then it'll it'll
absorb the liquid and literally now
unless you want to torch it which you're
not supposed to do you have to leave it
on the nail for quite some time let it
clean to clean off oh that's pain in the
ass so it is a bit of a pain in the ass
I hit it I hit too often to want to do
that so I get you know agree I end up
pulling out one of these units I usually
have two or three D Nails going and now
with the sublimator back in the quiver
it's uh well it's really opened up the
ability to vaporize herb but get a hit
that's more on on par cuz I would say
the hits that we're getting out of this
that are vapor hits they're pretty
[ __ ] good they're on par with the
hits that we're taking that are hash
yeah no I was surprised at how choked I
got like I was just and not choked like
it hurt my throat it was too hot just a
huge tooke you got all the res it's a
efficient huge [ __ ] to it's efficient
that's for sure and you could tell how
huge of a to you got because when I
pulled it out there was oil condensed
all on the outside of the down stab
which wasn't there prior that's from
from from how it's recondensing super
quickly exactly
yeah good fun yeah it is love sunny day
you know waiting for friends to come up
yeah we got some buddies coming up we'll
probably be doing more filming this
could be a show on its own or this could
be the intro to a big long 3-day show we
have no idea what's going to happen here
no maybe many parts but it'll be fun to
see it turn out it should be fun it
should be fun sounds like someone's here
now never know
well shall we uh go back to quartz or
try one of the
uh I think it's time for a double decker
oh well yes that's what I think I'm
going to clear my glass off the table
because it's time for double deckers
okay and we'll get this in the
middle we've got it on
temperature we get you a little dab of
the L and I mean a little one I don't uh
think we need to go
overboard here is this for me to start
or you uh you can go first if you want
to put hash in let's do this we'll take
this yep and put this in that yep yeah
put
Noise
Okay and then the L on the top yes and
then we'll put a little dab of the L
right onto the top a little one don't
need a big one of this you really don't
that's uh more than enough okay
that is very little it is so I just find
when you put yeah when you put too much
on it's not as uh it's it just seems to
be more of a medicinal thing than a than
a recreational
thing thank you want there
a little double decker rip for flab
421 see that's a sketchy thing when you
pull it out and if you don't want to
pull it too hard you pulled it out
sketchy you pulled it out by this handle
oh do it together well I don't even do
that I just do this to be honest I just
go like this okay yeah I just go give it
a quick little kind
of oh yeah okay instead of actually
pulling out the base hey still get a
good rip I still get that sort of I got
a hit cuz I see it clear and whatnot but
yeah I would never pull it out just by
this especially right now if you
notice this can be much tighter it's
gotten loose what if you pull it on so
now there's no wiggle to it at all this
is tight so yeah I have to admit I don't
generally pull it out yeah that was
super tasty and I got the end of yours
so I'm going to actually pull this out
clean it
and take another one some hash in there
yeah oh
absolutely just a little piece y so then
what I'll do is I'll actually put the
bowl back in and put that back in just
for a minute just to ensure that that's
at the temperature that I want it to be
at because literally you can forget this
up here and that can cool down so much
that it just it turns your 10 into a 7.8
it's like a convection of them it is
really when you get to that perfect
temperature it's all
exactly it's more of the science of the
cooking what's happening at a certain
temperature water goes from not boiling
to Boiling so there's there are these
sort of intriguing Innovations able to
happen in those little zones where the
magic hides yep and I truly believe
somehow some way that enrio figured out
some of
that all right oh there's the hash in
there too nice nice very nice
good flavor on that grass too like
really yeah well it was like I said
grown with just water barely any food
given so it had like a 7 or whatever
yeah it was uh it's crystally I'll tell
you I put the microscope under it and I
was like oh yeah well I've tasted worse
weed by people that have put a hell of a
lot more effort into it so yeah well
that's the problem people put too much
effort
sometimes trying so hard to spend to to
make money that they've already
spent and I'm not doing any of
that I just I just want to grow a little
medicine it's real nice to have four
five or six different bags of of your
own herb you
know oh that was a real light bit rip
nice
awesome I mean that's a bell ringer dude
MH
bell
ringer it's like a triple do sandwich so
good you get the itis afterwards I
didn't even do the l r oh you didn't do
all I did was was the hash and weed oh
there you go you didn't even get the
Triple Decker so there it is I just did
a double decker just a clubhous
completely forgetting about completely
forgetting about potentially the
strongest part of the rip and I got to
say that was a
ripper so
good well we're going to continue to um
abuse ourselves with various forms of uh
fto canabo inhalation
devices mostly canabo systems but uh
we'll get back to you guys this could be
the end but this could be the beginning
so for at least one more second
[Music]