[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and I want you guys to give a warm
welcome to flab 421 who's in the house
with obviously uh nothing less than epic
glass some more glass good to see you
dude welcome
welcome so uh a few of these I recognize
well this is the um Marcel Spirit
bubbler from smoke Volume 2 that we had
out on the boat last time yeah this one
doesn't make it out too often this is a
roller ghaster on Instagram or ghost
glass it's an electroform sculpted the
the face doesn't
really me to hold that just take it out
it doesn't really like represent
anything necessarily but it does look
like like I've been told at least the
cyborg guys from Star Trek one of the
Star Trek shows which I not necessarily
watch but um it's a true beautiful piece
for sculpting I mean and more than just
electric formed like literally like
metallic Parts yeah yeah there's well
there's he has little diodes like this
is a like AC adapter that he's cut off
and electroformed right into the to the
borrow um this is like like a you can
see how the bolt is screwed on and then
the nut is this one looks like it had a
pin through it yep and then each each
one like I mean they're different like
Plumbing pieces trippy it made me feel
like it was wet and dirty and it is not
either no yeah it's just just the the
patino and the electr form that's trippy
yeah so it's got like some nice green
patina well we definitely got to figure
out a bowl on that to take a big rip of
yeah totally we find an 18 I have an 18
Bowl we'll just have to throw a screen
on it it's good and and have a a puff
but for now we can uh we can start with
the this little amazing Mothership Dosa
yeah let's talk about that for a second
ridiculous so this is OG Moss which is
an extinct color so I mean there is
tubing around of it which is the green
the Sun the green you guys yeah it does
to look at it close up it looks surreal
yeah it's got a really nice uh full
Globe opal right there nice little white
fire one with some
uh crushed opal with rainbow double
layer tubic I it's beautiful isn't it
yeah John's such a I mean you know like
he is a young artist in the grand scheme
of things but man it's he's he's just
coming along so good I love hitting his
pieces and looking at his art well I'm
stoked for that I've uh got this
beautiful sweet skunk dry SI that I've
been ripping like crazy what do you say
about that that's no than the pipes no
wait you were talking about the CBD
Renee I was I I don't have much of the
CBD Renee but take tiny little bit I'll
take a little tiny guy and I'll give you
a nice
little little uh oh we'll give you a
nice rip don't I got to say it's always
nice coming back on your
show some of the more enjoyable times oh
dude you're going to love this wait
until you get a load of that taste that
is a big
Ripper a big old Ripper and that is the
Renee CBD from Matt The House of the
great Gardener and I'll tell you when he
comes up from it he's going to talk
about the candy uh flavor that's left
over he's going to talk about the
intensity of the fruity Dash candy of
the flavor it's so intense that when
you're finally done with it exactly it's
a it's a oh oh my gosh oh my gosh like
it's just it's it's all the
wonderfulness of Renee and then leaving
behind a bit of the funk and some of the
other strange undertones that come from
The Strain it's left all that behind and
then the canonic has inspired more of
this fruity sweet sort of big time it's
like candy it is like Cy
literally it's like those old dipsticks
that you would dip into the sugar well
you tell them about it while I load
myself up that is delicious no yeah it's
it's it's got a lot of uh floral tones
to it like and really really really
fruity
wow good job bro I'm tell you really
good job just get which we'll be seeing
you in Holland I'm sure over
here make a little more the over the
under all right so I'm excited now
actually to hit this the quartz bowl
that I've never hit I think this is
called directed injection this
particular
Bowl yeah really looking forward to see
all the Matt stuff over in Holland this
year kicking some ass for the Canadian
team well he sure got great
stuff yeah it's tasty like come on
really tasty you finally exhale that
last little bit of smoke there about a 1
second delay and then the flavor
literally explodes in the back of my
throat all the way up and eventually I
start licking my lips and I can actually
taste it on there as well that
is really strong it is and the high CBD
like you can feel it like I have I have
uh oste arrus in my shoulder and so I
can really feel it when when there's a
really good body effect when when the
the pain management as far as the
physical pain management is is in effect
well Rene always I was always like that
you know I always felt Renee was very
body oriented and very strong pain
relief and sort of uh you know however
he worked that cross it worked out great
for him and uh yeah that's pretty
exciting it is very exciting so let's uh
we got to find a bowl for this guy
that's what I want to do I'm going to
find a bowl for that I want you to take
a rip out of this and tell them what you
think of the sweet skunk okay if I must
I will be back in a Flash it's a hard
life we live sir
all right so let's try some of this
sweet
skunk also I believe by
Matt oh sweet skunk's always been one of
my favorit
the spiciness and the
earthiness literally like I don't
personally know the heritage of the
strain I don't know where the strain
originates from but it always reminds me
of being somewhere in like the poonian
or like tropical yet humid with a lot of
good spicy food around it's just so
delicious options Oh either are
wonderful you know what um
Slinger Slinger all right has even
though there's a bit of an angle to it
well you know you know what I do with
this particular Bowl how I really like
this bowl you take the pipe off I'm
just we get that over
there and all of these pieces you guys
I'll have with me in Holland this year
at the Cannabis Cup so you know that's
almost perfect just like that so I hit
it kind of like
this beautiful you want to hit it like
that you keep it like it really however
you want I've always hit it sort of
sideways like this totally
well I mean like that it gets the
perfect you know what I do got to do I
just got to quickly run and gra some
water yeah
sure you know what screens fitted well
so oh look at this he he ran and got
some water so yeah this is an old
Slinger bowl from probably around
2000 maybe 2001 this was at a time when
I was trying to explain to rure that the
open Bowl wasn't really the concept that
they should be looking at for the
concentrate user the hash smoker we're
more into these pushed bowls with either
a single hole or a multi-hole so you can
use the herb iron or a product like that
totally butth this was sort of Slinger's
response and I think it was honestly one
of his first like okay well let's uh
let's see what we
got
so did you try the the sweet SC I did
yeah that was lovely I gave a nice
little review for the for the folks at
home well let us know what you feel off
of a a a a flame hit I guess I'm going
to actually have to go get um line some
[Music]
beine yes look at that how's that for
for
professionalism well you know without
disturbing the to using the Dabber to
remove a hair did it somehow got
attached to the screen almost look like
a
fiber fiber hair was were you're dealing
with professionals here
folks there is one actual thing that I
should mention that uh this this marble
here which I'm sure uh Mark will be uh
taking some photographs of is one of the
few pieces that's not actually done by
ghost on the piece it's a freak brain
marble and the Fume Tech in these brain
marbles is really Second To None I mean
it's a really really really cool design
it's a really really really cool feature
that freak was doing doesn't haven't
seen a lot of them done recently but um
it's you know one of the it's it really
helps make the piece in all honesty this
this I was just talking to the to the
screen about this brain marble by freak
it's the one of the attachments it's not
done isn't that just awesome theing on
super incredible
yeah I went and your wife gave me a
beine hemp light beautiful I was like so
it's got the beine on there through the
tube um I don't know who makes these but
I picked them up um I can't even
remember where I picked them up but I
just threw a bunch of the beine that I
got from on it's totally F it's a it's a
pretty cool pretty cool we'll enjoy the
sweet skunk with the flame
rip oh
yeah good flamework good
flamework beine is definitely the
product of an experienced user if you
suck too hard you suck the beine out and
you'll get the smoke from the beine
there nothing you want to contaminate
your bowl with um if you don't suck hard
enough the flame doesn't grow properly
and it ends up going out it's really
quite a tricky sort of thing to just
simply light a bowl and then each bowl
is different how hard it pulls how hard
it chugs depending on the pipe that it's
on totally how much the indent goes it's
ridiculous so I were to compare the the
flame to to to to the low temp dab you
know more of the spiciness comes out in
the flame to whereas a lot more of the
like
um earthy tones come out in in in the
low temp da but it's funny because like
sweet skunk is such an amazing strain
just no matter like whether you're
smoking the flowers whether you're
consuming the concentrates no matter
what it is it's just truly one of those
strains this is where it's so tasty
unbelievable isn't it cool it's really a
pipe that you could would almost like
not many people could hold this pipe
yeah it's aw in the sense that yeah it's
very awkward you wouldn't want to grab
it the wrong way you could break a piece
off you know what I mean especially
these like SP pie oh yeah
man and the wind comes up right at the
wrong
time but where're
sucess Ah that's a nice big crazy tube
that's a Halloween piece right there
dude y well I mean I'm bringing a few of
these pieces to Holland because as I'm
doing um an art display with the ding
Gallery excellent while we're there
that's cool and um so I thought that I'd
bring out some pieces that that maybe
weren't as publicly appreciated but
pieces that I personally thought just
have really cool artistic values to them
and different texts that were utilized
and used you know cuz a lot of these
there's not a lot of people that are
doing like electroforming as much as was
like 3 four years ago you know and ghost
ghost Brandon Martin like those guys
they really do exceptionally
cool
mhm work I mean like I've seen so I've
seen so many pieces where the electro
forming almost ruins the piece you know
like I love the borrow I love the like I
love all the different tax and stuff
like that but it's it's almost like a
Gody expenditure like you know when
you're hanging out in New York and you
see some like Rich lady walking down the
street and she's just way overdone sort
of how I feel about some Electra form
Bor pieces and I think that like the
subtleties and the and the Styles and
times in which it's applied particularly
in Ghost and Brandon Martin like I was
saying I really think that their Texs
are awesome so I thought maybe you know
I'd bring them out and some of the guys
that are going to be hanging with us in
Holland will be able to experience this
killer all right well that's uh quite an
interesting piece for sure I like it
with the Slinger Bowl on there yeah you
know doesn't the color scheme actually
quite match cuz even the yellowing and
the paing under here and stuff totally
oh yeah jeez I had the method seven
glasses on and I didn't realize uh the
color difference was uh substantial
these things really seriously
cut I'm just too much squinting
otherwise so thanks guys for method 7
and damn before I forget rkm seeds Okay
thank these guys from Spain sent out the
care package and uh jeez what did we
[Applause]
get oh goodies Let's see we got a pack
of the Negra
44 so I'm I'm guessing there's two packs
of each one so let's find the other
Negra there's the negtive 44 the black
44 there's the uh rkm which I guess is
their main yeah that one in the icer is
the one I heard about the most which is
right here icer couple of packs of the
ice
and last but not least two packs of the
portella so that's interesting very cool
brother looks like they're feminized
seeds too I read at the back these
aren't these are male and female but
look all the rest of these are feminized
I wanted to thank you guys for sending
out those beans that's super kind I'll
make sure that all my friends get access
to the um results that come from the
seeds the top picked fenos if you have
any hints for us uh let us know love to
know what the uh what I should be
looking for in any of these packs and
thank you for the kindness it will be uh
reciprocated throughout the medical
community here in Canada so that's kind
of cool no that's super cool yeah that's
a really nice care package right yeah
all right so now um let me see
here give you
that that's have a really nice care
package ient the RO it's a very nice
care package and we definitely
appreciate it I've seen nothing but good
good stuff come from the these guys
their seed company goes back to the '90s
1998 is when they were founded so
they're no new no new kid on the Block I
was reading the back of one I don't I'm
not the best on Spanish but you but like
what I got out of it is that they're um
it's a haze dominant sativa grown in the
Blue Mountains in Jamaica that's
the
E Jama so a male Jamaican nice sum
donoso mucho like lots of dense resin
production L bre chosen from the
selection of lambs
bread blue so yeah like they're picking
from Lambs bread fenos to pick this male
and that's what they use to make their
icer so very cool that just made me
excited I uh I'm always happy to throw
some more genetics in the garden
especially if they have Jamaican lineage
uh I
absolutely love resin um grown
particularly in Jamaica but I also love
Jamaican strains that have been shared
out of Jamaica that we can now grow you
know here in our own country so I have
one right around the corner there
growing with the Congo always nice to
have a couple of those out on the deck
and uh yeah I don't know I guess we're
just waiting on Flav to get back with uh
the mar cell Phoenix he's just putting a
whack of water in it and we're going to
load it up so I think we'll load that up
with this particular batch I have two
batches of sweet skunk first
pass I like to call it not to be
confused with first
bounce and yeah first pass time
okay so here we
go all right so yeah you have shown back
up with the Marcel full of water and
I've pulled aside the two first passes
that I was mentioning the first pass uh
being what I would call the first
quality of um of dry sift that I'm able
to make this is the pure of the pure MH
and it's a nice you know beautiful pure
unadulterated heads so I think you is
the best thing to [ __ ] be toen on
yeah I think so do you have a preference
there that you'd like to um no honestly
pick just whichever whichever is clever
I have a bit of a a I can't stick a
dirty Dabber into clean dry sift so no I
always just give it a swipe on the
denail and then clean it that way with
my fingers and then you're rubbing
you're actually getting that medicine
into your skin still affecting your
endoc cannaboid
system much like in the same way Rick
Simpson
oilwood so here we go nice big fresh
heady hit like look at this
yeah look at the Crystal on
that nothing like killing unicorns and
smoking
diamonds unicorn
tears a tiny little bit of unicorn tears
tried to escape I think not you will die
too I think
not
awesome what a beautiful thing a dry
that melts on that level just turning to
nothing almost zero Ash just a nice
light Ash it liquifies yeah just
straight liquid isn't that great that is
and that is so tasty holy [ __ ] super
tasty oh my all right I'm up next all
right I'm excited for that actually want
to move that guy over and we'll give
this one the uh Center Stage that she so
deserves yes this piece it's it's I I've
actually found it quite amusing how
often it uh comes back into the rotation
these days when we're puffing cuz it was
one of those pieces that when I acquired
it like it was a piece that I always
wanted it since I saw it in the release
of smoke Volume
2 um never thought I would um so I kind
of never thought that I'd bring it out I
never thought that it would be a piece
that i' I'd puff on regularly you know I
thought maybe the octopus would have
some fragility to it but you know the
way Marcel does his pieces the way
they're tacked together right in here
and back here and over here and over
here there I have to say it it's
reminiscent of my old Marcel pieces and
I'm super comfortable around this piece
I don't mind you know going boating with
it I don't mind carrying it or walking
with it it's it's my Marcel pieces I
used to take everywhere MH and not even
with any Pelican case or anything like
for years I had that thing in like a box
with peanuts and stuff I just feel like
put it on the front seat be like yeah
I'm going to take this down to like
Grassroots on Commercial Drive we're
going to Puff it for a bunch of hours so
that's how we did it and it worked out
rather well
all right Mr Phoenix this is such a
great
piece really put your back into picking
this Beast up with one
hand I want a bigger flame yeah big tube
like this build up your flame boys big
bowl of hash like that
well that's old school right
there like real old school yeah 20 years
ago but I mean the the the rachell like
the the r aello Line work which has
always been some of my favorite the line
work is ridiculous but with the air
trapped bubbles true yes it becomes like
absurd yeah and how perfect the the
trapping is on this one absolutely like
and to have this have this much like
imagine how much [ __ ] pain was used
you know no to make this piece and to
have the trapping like so octopus on oh
yeah I know and all that di
room it's really great I appreciate it
all so how wonderful is this you guys
come to Amsterdam during the 22nd to the
28th around the that time is the Canvas
Cup I think it's the 23rd to the 27th
but we'll be there it's good to give
yourself a day before and a day after at
least
and you can go by The Damp cran gallery
and you can see some of uh these
beautiful pieces some of them will or
potentially one of them will be entered
into the Cannabis Cup so that'll be on
display at the venue and you're welcome
to come by my booth if you want to talk
to myself or flab that's where we'll be
I'll be at the fresh H's Booth I'll be
sharing a booth with hemp hoodlum as
always my Dutch Distributors as I am
their Canadian distributor so if you
have any interest in picking up a hemp
coat or you want to come check us out
for hash tools or just talk to us
puff a dab with us out of a sick piece I
definitely implore you to come on by and
say hello even if we look busy just
interrupt we're not so busy that we
can't be interrupted and uh yeah just
want to thank everyone for uh like uh
rkm for sending these wonderful seeds
thank flab for coming by with the Epic
pieces and than for the hash oh
absolutely brother thank the great
Gardener for the hash true yeah thank
you Matt for that and uh yeah if if it
all works out and I end up getting some
of these uh fancy pipes photographed
we'll uh we might have some of those
photos in the art show as well so stay
tuned keep watching Bubble man's world
and uh we'll see you next time see you
in Amsterdam
peace
hey Timber feel good
[Music]
me one man Home Grown
purpose of the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose after we gave by this
expression the purpose have to we let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time God
is not here to trick the
M it is only here to do its purpose of
dying been tring to kingst mil hours
sing on like fres vegetation with
[Music]
trees give me one Bigg and if
bigger me me
[Music]
I make
pass pass and
[Music]
then up the now
before cuz LS off and pass that pass
that pass that
now purpose of the we that keeps me
going the purpose of the weed that to
the
Mind purpose of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the mind
it is only here to do its purpose of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying will I imagine don't the road be
some cops setting
up TRS man man we tell me off and upon
the SE inter in my bra that and behind
your scene me and my team have another
25 and we smoke it
clean ass now
[Music]