[Music]
hey guys welcome back to Bubble man's
world I'm happy to say I'm with my good
buddy Flav always uh we've come over uh
today for a for a good reason uh the
passing of genetics definitely the
sharing of genetics the sharing of
genetics exactly so um you want to pass
that over to me again just like we did
originally the sour diesel East Coast
Sour
Diesel a very well-known cut super stok
to have acquired this uh cut it
definitely for any of you guys out there
that uh know the sour these it's uh it's
got the funk it has a a familiar Funk
actually that Renee oh it's boy Collins
the funk yeah it is seriously boy
Collins the fun so I'm really happy
about that um just super thanks for
passing this on and it's of course going
to be shared with uh with
many and now let's get to the buck
Marcel angler I'm I'm always so stoked
to be able to hit this thing so St it's
just ridiculous yeah this is always
going to be one of the highlights of my
collection no matter what I'll take
get Barb are in taste oh Barb's right
here oh so wait until you smell bar
you'll be like never confus the two
again that's the fun this one's got that
Jack
cleaner sort of
seeds I haven't had any AR since we
were yeah it's not a strain you see here
in DC that
often there we go look at that sir oh no
that's you well I got your light hair I
have lighter I have bline yes yes this
is always just such a pleasure to hit
the glass shout out to Bach and shout
out to Marcel shout out to high
integrity glass Ark collector exactly
shout out to those guys as well and
really just a shout out to all glass
blowers pushing the boundaries taking it
to the next level and that's all of you
guys whether you're the guy who's
learning who has literally learned one
technique from a friend and you're just
kind of copying that technique over and
over and over again that potential
copying that experience will lead you to
mistakes will lead you to um Revelations
and will lead you potentially to create
something like this um I'm going to hit
the the NES or the
Arian the Arian
Haze I believe I'm not sure what number
this was but aran's number three I was
in this grow when he had all the mothers
and I think there's four or five of them
um the number three was uh had a
Neville's cut in it it had the super
silver hair ha which was um uh worked on
by Shany Baba and then it had another
some other create a la sativa so really
quite a beautiful selection of genetics
to put
into yeah absolutely hazes are my
favorites yeah I agree and then puffing
the pure sift out of you know the buck
angler the Marcel Buck angler and of
course Bubble Man style one handing that
thing you know you know how I
do
small it sounds like it's in a giant
chamber
yeah the bubbling and the percolating
[Applause]
Y and now that 15% is a piece of glass
is% of the UK
Market one of my favorite pieces to
truly um you know every time I come here
flabs super easy going about his glass
any piece I request he'll pull out and I
rarely request pieces but when he asked
me in my head I pictured this piece and
I was just like oh that and then he he
looks at me and he says the buck angler
Buck angler
fish cuz true art needs to be
appreciated and to be appreciated it
needs to be held and hit I mean it's one
thing to sit on a shelf all day long but
well and it's also one thing to have a
pipe like this and fill it with anything
it's another thing to fill it with full
Mount dry and highest of quality yeah
just such great
qualities so this is
Barb get your little bar Bud
out
easy well I think I'm going to give you
a heroic
hit I have faith in
you of course I'm here to back you up if
you need in case in case I'm I'm I'm
down in the trenches and I always there
for my
friends really excited about the the
sour Dees today my Jamaican seed
sprouted as well so it's just genetics
all over around in bubble man's Garden
happening with uh Afghani and barber bud
congales and sweet skunk uh Astro Boy
the My Little Pony the hos the Romulan
cross with the OG number two the MK
Ultra My Little Pony two fenos superer
indeed that was Rockstar by the way want
to congratulate on that oh you did well
he did very well that hit would have
killed most elephants and uh FL just
took it until he exploded and that's
that's that's a poia coming on proper
yeah yeah one thing you may may not
notice uh in these videos we tend to get
fairly
cooked yes well we tend to medicate
appropriately well that's a better way
of saying it that for me you the
man
[Music]
[Applause]
barara yeah that's stuff really tasty
shout out to the great Gardener yeah
yeah definitely sh
great that's got a good Funk to it too
man deep really grabs you yeah
completely different resins this
uh the Barb and the uh Arian T mhm
totally
well full m dry
six beautiful
genetics glass an epic
glass thanks again FL brother always a
pleasure thanks for watching guys we'll
see you soon on Bubble man's world have
a great
[Music]
day