[Music]
do
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world i
am here at my good friend merlin's place
and we are going to be heading up to
squamish today
check out a little grow and hopefully
pick some edible mushrooms i guess this
is puff wednesday without johnny b i was
waiting for him to show up but i still
haven't heard from him today so i doubt
john's gonna be there but we'll see
we're going to a pretty popular place up
in squamish that people pick for edible
mushrooms we're not really looking for
psychedelics today
but we should find
some edibles hopefully
it's usually a pretty hot spot for
chanterelles
and a couple other different varieties
cauliflowers and whatnot so
fingers crossed we're going to jump in
the vehicle right here right away and
head up because it's already
almost 11 o'clock and i'm sure a lot of
people will be out there already
i'll give you a little quick shot of the
view here at my buddy's house and then
we're gonna head out
so yeah there it is
beautiful lions bay
you ready to get this party started
he's ready
all right guys
let's go jump in the truck head up to
squamish
hey coming with us buddy
are you coming with us
yeah dude yeah you're coming with us
aren't you
so this is brixton he's a brand new
little dude and he's gonna come mushroom
picking with us today
yeah
yes
little dude
he's got his little unit on he's ready
to rip dude
ready to rip let's rock and roll
all right we've made it we're up in
squamish i'm with merlin and brixton
ruxin's in the house
little dude
he's so cute
merlin and i uh our neighbors uh and
friends and we also kind of work
together he's uh part of kanmart i'm
part of embark and we've just kind of uh
worked out a little deal together so
you'll see more embark kenmart uh
synergies i guess collaborations
collaborations if you will
but in the meantime today we're just
puff wednesday we were waiting for
johnny b but there's no johnny b for
today's puff wednesday so what we
thought we would do we're not sure how
successful we'll be
we came to squamish to walk through and
pick some edible mushrooms in this
forest just over to our left before we
do that merle's gonna roll a joint i'm
going to take a dab
and then we'll get ourselves uh well
we'll get him finally running around
before he pukes in the truck before he
pukes in the truck are you gonna puke in
this truck yeah yeah not yet
yeah give it a chance you know probably
puke on the way home
so yeah just puffing on a little of the
cookies and cream let's
give you guys a little show on that
oh yeah super good quality there super
good quality there
i'm just smoking some tom ford
some tom ford yeah the smell
interesting all right well let's make
this happen
let's see what i got here i got my temp
tech
which will be fairly important
absolutely loving this jp toro banger
i feel like i have to say thank you
every time i hit it
a little bit of smoke coming off of it
it's always so hard to clean
like i'm not gonna lie it was hard last
night you spent a while cleaning that
dude i'm telling you i was giving you
guys dabs out of the chest banger
i wasn't even like do you know what i
mean if you noticed i had a different
banger for everyone else i did see that
i'm high
it will get right we'll get that right
out of your face bricks and there's no
need for you to have
bubble smoke in your face
he's young though i don't need to be
i'll give him a nice clear there we go
window down smoke gone
all right
nice to have a dab before you get into
the forest
a lot of it is just walking takes a
while when you're foraging mushrooms
first of all anyone that is being
inspired by this video i'll tell you
right now
try to find a local amateur mycologist
in your area a group of mycologists some
information online there's all sorts of
great things anything that has paul
stamet's name on it
because picking mushrooms is something
you should be careful these guys have
two big full bags of mushrooms right
there whatever mushroom you find if
you're not two hundred percent sure
don't yeah when in doubt throw it out uh
people ask is it edible every single
mushroom is edible one time
uh you wanna stay away from the ones
that are only edible one time because
those are poisonous and they generally
kill you
so be careful out there when you're
picking mushrooms
i'm gonna clean my banger and we're
gonna get into the forest
all right so we're just heading into the
forest here
in squamish
you know you can tell right away right
off the street this is just an epic
forest i mean it's like fairytale land
really
so yeah let's head right
we'll head to the back of the woodlot
here
it's so beautiful in here isn't it
what a blessing look at this conch
it's trying to grow right here that's a
red belted polypore it looks like it's
probably been broken off or cut off
what else we got over here
[Applause]
got some more little guys
more over here
another guy right there oh yeah
it's mushrooms
hey brixton what's up buddy do you feel
good
are you feeling better
yes you are
yes you are he's like bro i was gonna
puke in your truck so hard
at one point i didn't know if i wanted
to [ __ ] myself or puke
that's what he was saying to himself i
could see it on his face and i know you
could see it on his face
you look nervous for the last 10 minutes
of the ride
[Laughter]
dude you know it would have been fine if
he barfed in the truck though
yeah i mean you've done in mine a few
times but i'm not tripping
i don't really care
[Applause]
another red belted polypore
it's just so sweet in here
no
they have those only in whistler
supposedly
have you heard of them
um not up in whistler i haven't but
that's interesting push play
i wasn't recording that whole thing
just did a whole nice intro talking
about bringing you guys on this
adventure
i'm not gonna repeat myself but um yeah
continue to show you guys a little bit
of mushrooms that we find in here
hopefully we find some edibles that we
recognize
like i said before when you don't
recognize them it's best to just
probably not even pick them
uh and it's definitely best
to not eat them
all right we're gonna film this weird
we're gonna film this weird mushroom
that marilyn found
a weirdy
oh there's some witches brew
ah there's some witches brew
we've been walking around for about what
half an hour
it's been pretty chill
unless there's a huge flush
i usually walk around for about a half
an hour plus before i kind of get to my
zone and start
pulling things up out we'll see how it
goes for us we might be a little early
we might not be
i'm kind of hoping that we're not
some really big mushrooms popping out of
the forest floor here
just not necessarily the ones
we're looking for also this is a very
popular spot so a lot of people do pick
in and around here
what's up braxton
yeah they sure did
they sure did
i wonder if deeper down
well that's way over there
back this way
what's wrong
on what the knife
oh my goodness
i thought you were stung
i'm not gonna recording
all right i'll get these little yellows
it's always good to just cut them
i'm not confident in that one
that little guy
and then we'll head back over here
pull this
another nice flush these are actually i
didn't actually see this flush i'm
seeing it for the first time but look
how big these ones are
oh brixton you
silly little dog
you know some yellows
really nice color on these things
make sure we don't get all this
nice little golds hey
oh wow look at this guy
isn't that cool
we were like we just walked by these
ones man
they're hard to see
the beautiful colors and look at them
they just once you start there's more
and more and more no problem it's always
best to make sure it's a nice one yeah
that was a nice one
i'm excited for you to cook with these
i made a really nice soup with like a
huge bag full of these
it was so creamy here
these are small but they weren't perfect
this is the first one
all right well let's keep let's get
going yeah that's it
all right merle's uh picking up some
more yellow foots
just getting little babies but uh one
thing you may or may not know about
merlin is that he is an exceptional chef
and he'll make something very nice and
fancy and delicious out of these yellow
foots
and he'll figure out a way to pull that
flavor out of them
even though they're still quite small
that's fun looking for them
we just found this little purple
mushroom looking pretty crazy so we
figured we'd share
[Applause]
we got another
maybe just don't pick the rotten one
there
this guy right here oh it's not even a
mushroom
so if you've got golds there they're
everywhere they're going to be all
around us we're in a patch right now see
them over by the tree i see a big one
standing out right there another patch
behind right there
it's funny how it happens hey yeah it's
when you're not looking for them yeah
here's another little flush right here
they're popping out right here
nice one
boop
more here
by brixton right here
i guess these are indicators this is the
first time i found them next to these
big ones
really yeah
i was in the middle of saying these
aren't really indicators and then i lit
then you walked right by that little
patch of chandra yeah just sticking
right out nicely
it's kind of cool
yeah picking mushrooms is a trip
we've got our friend who's coming to
meet us here and we're in a pretty big
chunk
of land so his phone died and that's why
merlin is screaming his name every few
minutes
so he can find us
oh
come to papa
come to papa not a whole whole bunch but
a nice little oh nice one nice little
bunch well they're all over here yeah
exactly they'll go all around this whole
stone so i found this little guy and it
kind of goes around this
but as i was sitting merlin could see
underneath me
were more chanterelles
and there's a line of chanterelles that
heads in this direction
and it probably crosses the path and
heads over there
um
let's pick these ones merle yes
sir i'm glad we went mushroom picking
today dude what uh
don't you just find it meditative and
medicinal somewhat the woods are the
best place to calm down yes
super relaxed the better parts of
picking mushrooms you get to just chill
in the woods and find treasures
dinner
yeah exactly
forging with a chef and you are a chef
self-proclaimed that's okay
i'm uh
i'm proclaiming it as well
look at that flush though dude this is
like pretty much
a blessing
this little flush of goldies
are yellow sorry
wow these are gorgeous
aren't they nice mushrooms yeah yellows
so as you can see we're having a pretty
good time there is a level of relaxation
that occurs
when you're picking when you're picking
mushrooms and uh
i just sort of saw this over here i
thought i'd come and share
this is a like a boulder right here
covered in moss
and what's growing out of the boulder
but a tiny little mushroom a little p
look at that
look at that little guy you want the
attention i know
i know brixton i know oh you broke it
off
you broke it off let's look at it oh boy
oh my god i think that's a bowlette
little bowlette right there
i don't recognize this one
for sure so i'll be leaving it but i
honestly think that that's what that was
like i said when in doubt
just uh leave it be
leave it be
[Music]
so yeah we walked right through here
with no visual whatsoever and then
suddenly
it was uh yellow foots kind of
everywhere
you got him i got him do you want to
grab like these ones
it's just this whole other patch right
there
it's beautiful
some more nicees
let's
show these guys or some chanterelles
that color is absolutely gorgeous
they're gonna be all over in here i have
a feeling right next to the stump again
they're definitely
over here didn't we see them when we
came over here or was it over here
oh over here
here we are
do you have my knife
your knife is in the ground over there i
think actually no way it's right there i
know where it is here i can just stay
here so that i don't lose i left it in
the ground
that's awesome
merlin
your knife is uh over in the ground
this is what happens when you're a total
bubble head
picking mushrooms what's that i thought
that you had picked it up no i'm filming
like an idiot
good call
thanks merle
oh man you're the man here you can see
the flush here
all of these are
yellow foot chanterelles
nice little flush here
all up here there's a nice little flush
these are just starting to pop out some
of these are decent
okay we found some decent ones
these are some decent sized chanterelles
much bigger than the babies we've been
picking but uh
like i said i've been here before and
you want to pick these out
oh don't do that
here look at this
beauty
this is a really nice chanterelle
flush
these are some big ones
this guy in particular is huge
holy crap what's the pigeons
like alice in wonderland yeah
he pulled me in
it's incredible that the forest just
gives these gifts
you know
like little treasures is right cut it
all down
what's that how can we cut it all down
oh you're stepping on them
yeah you just stepped on a little small
flush
just a little small flush
another
goldie here
well
unless we find something different i
think we're gonna finish up here and
we're gonna head over to a little grow
have a dab check out some plants
and uh kind of move on
thanks for joining us at this part of
the adventure and uh
we'll see you guys soon
all right yeah this looks like they're
past
that's a bowlette right there admiral
bullet look at that
look at that
too bad they're first bullets that we
found today but they're a little past
due
i found some big ones up
oh yeah i found some pretty good sized
ones as well
up near white lake
not too far from cyprus
exactly yeah not so dark on the stem
either
look at that
yeah exactly so now we're into a gold
flush that's what i mean man like and
the first time i ever came here i saw
like
like hundreds of times this
that's why it didn't matter how many
people were around
i like how brixton walks right through
so we just found a big yeah this is an
amazing flower those almost look like
psilocybin
but we are in the yellow flush i'm not
sure if you guys caught that or if my
camera broke but um
there are a ton
of yellow foots
all in around this tree on both sides
huge flushes
like really a lot we could we could be
here for hours picking
so
we're gonna pick a bunch of these i'll
talk to you soon all right merlin you
found something chanterelles the big
ones oh the bigger shawn trails okay
wavy sides tight ribs
another one right here
wonder careful brixton
well that is like stone
a little a little root that it was
attached to there we go
excellent well maybe we should keep an
eye out for some of those
in this little zone
that you found
mushrooms are such a hoot
[Music]
they are such an absolute trend
no
we're kind of well because we also said
let's go now yeah we're like let's go
let's do we're good
come in here and then what always
happens when you're good
because you start finding more things
now we're heading out anyway if we see
anything else of interest
we will be sure
to share with the audience like this big
red belted polypore conch
how cool is that
i love the red belted polypores
that was great
picked some lovely
yellow foots got a couple golds
a little stress
after half an hour walking and not
seeing anything though it's funny how
you feel right
but mushrooms sometimes require a little
bit of a commitment
every time i give up when i find them
you get off your phone you focus on the
forest floor
and then you give up that's right
oh i think i might have found something
i don't think it's what we want
no it's like what you picked earlier
so
i just realized that look at how
close i parked
to some amanitas now they've been
nibbled on and there's some new ones
coming out
that goes to show you the power of the
mushroom i drove down this street and
just randomly pulled over right here
and there's amanita muscaria mushrooms
so that is pretty cool we're gonna head
over to the grow now
so let's uh keep this adventure going
all right first things first apologies
for the red light method seven has even
gifted me
the clips that go over my camera and
i've totally spaced them i didn't bring
the right shade so everything's going to
be in orange and green unfortunately but
uh take us through your little grow here
merle there we go
these are some pinkies got some tom ford
pink fish growing here and we read four
events about to flip over in 12 12. all
right
over here we're testing out a few new
strings
we got some hulk right here bruce banner
we got some
london dough seeds
those are hulk as well these are
boscotti right here which is a gelato
and then we have banana runs right here
oh it's a banana runs it's funny how
like they look almost like stretchy yeah
with her the name runs they want to grow
this one here seems like the better
pinot noir smell dude
wow you can pick up a bit of that banana
oh you really can eh right
holy [ __ ] this one seems like the
strongest female in the really tightest
notes i'm phenomenal hunting right now
so i'm gonna pick out which one is the
best all here these short bushy london
dosey pie
we got
the uh cookies what was the kind that
you gave me animal cookies animal
cookies right here awesome
we got uh
what's the other one that you gave me uh
black colombian crossed with cookies
right here that's the black columbia oh
[ __ ] and we got uh
some house trained right here
i got some pure michigan over here do
you have a lot of different things here
for how even and nice this canopy looks
it does not look like you're growing
like a [ __ ] ton of strings yeah well
we're really trying to pull them all
down with these nets and ensure that
there's a head in every single square
cool
that's really been the key oh i wish i
could get rid of this orange light i'm
sorry everybody
and i'm sorry especially because method
seven has gifted me the clip that goes
over the
we go over camera it's probably going to
be a no-no i'll have some people talking
[ __ ] oh let them talk [ __ ]
we want to see the flowers man
here hold on i'm going to get to the
other side and they'll turn the actual
buds
these buds look great dude yeah these
guys are looking really really good
okay so i'm going to need my flashlight
to kind of let this look how [ __ ]
monstrous these things all right oh
[Music]
there's so yeah cops in here that
they're just like toppling onto each
other
these are nice nice nice nuggets dude
look at this bad boy right here
terrible light right here beautiful like
oh when the light is on you can see how
great they are fat stacks we could come
back at night if you want to do the
video for it before i cut it
oh it looks great what is this all it's
called
oh yeah it looks like a big fat kush
pinky
they're all starting to go nice and
purple now too
these donkey dinks hanging off the
[ __ ]
they're all pointing down bro
all right give that lens a little bit of
a wipe it's
not the best light in here i do
apologize but uh
looks nice man
better to show than not right yeah
okay dude
fun to grow
we should uh go hit a dab that's a great
idea
[Music]
they're like pumping out on the engines
here i love it when it does that oh yeah
they're fat yeah golf ballers turning
into
and this has really been our technique
of holding them apart with the frogs and
getting like a lot of them have like 10
14 heads on them
it's got a nice crystal content like it
is crystalline oh yeah
it's got resin
oh yeah
it's funny like in the beginning i
started playing with those straws and
this was the first section i did and i
don't know if you can see how many
clocks are in that section that's
ridiculous
it is ridiculous
like some of them have like 16 monster
heads on
i gotta say this is probably the first
grow i've ever toured with like my
flashlight on my camera it's pretty fun
really nice crystally content
super fun day picking mushrooms with
merlin
checking out his grow
he is going to end up producing a really
nice meal with those mushrooms and i'm
hoping i can be there so we can finish
off the video
with actually the food that we prepare
with these mushrooms
um but i think we're at the point where
we need to dab this is inspiring me to
dab
your trichome forest has inspired me
let's get dabbed let's do it let's dab
it up
dab a doodle
[Music]
oh yeah look at that
when you open the door
spinning
yeah the canopy is pretty nice leaving
right now right
yeah yeah it really is
good job sean
all right we've gotten we've picked the
mushrooms
we've walked through the woods walked
through the woods we've checked out the
grow
i think it's time for a dab
and a joint and a joint yes i love that
you're always rolling a joint while i'm
uh
making a dab that's actually perfect
so hope you guys enjoyed this little
squamish adventure that we've been on
here
we're probably doing some more of these
mushroom picking adventures
i like the idea of foraging and then
having merlin make a really nice meal i
mean that meal give give them a low down
on what that meal was yesterday
five quart five course dinner yeah the
five course dinner so first course first
course was uh
it was a bruschetta with uh balsamic
reduction with maple then we did uh
beat tartar with avocados and roasted
pineapple that beet tartar was
ridiculous you also had a toasted
sourdough with the beef toasted
sourdough that's true and then we did uh
we did pan seared scallops with a
butternut squash celery root puree with
a bar barbarian and then we did that
[ __ ] was so good micro greens with it as
well yep that was incredible and then we
did a wild mushroom chanterelle mushroom
risotto with oysters as well with
roasted trumpets on the puree one didn't
you have like uh
pomegranates oh yeah we did have
pomegranates pomegranate seeds as well
so the beautiful thing about this is
which you probably noticed by now is as
we were talking about it i took photos
of all that stuff yesterday so i just
edited them into the video and you've
just seen these beautiful pictures so
you can see the caliber of what we're
working with here so
i accept i expect nothing less from the
chanterelles
oh they'll be good i got some good ideas
awesome
what's up brixton
what are you doing dude what's up
he's like what
what
all right shout out to uh concentrated x
for the
strawberry banana hash rose and shout
out to dna for the genetics
shout out to jp for the carb cap and the
terp slurper banger shout out to dustin
revere for the water droplet
pipe
and jeez you could just shout out a lot
of people just to take a dab couldn't
you
oh i'm excited shout out to dnail for
the daimodium pearl in the bottom of my
banger here
that should smell so good oh my god
that [ __ ] was so good
almost like a cold start
it'll give a little bit more juice
wow
just so tasty it's a whole different
experience
it's a nice cap off to the day big fan
of the terp slurper
i feel like right around now my music's
going to be chiming in
but it's not
because i really want to make sure that
i catch a little bit of what he makes
with those mushrooms so this is kind of
the end of the video but in reality you
should see one more final scene if we
have our [ __ ] together where you'll see
some of these mushrooms prepared so
thanks for uh tuning in everybody thanks
for having me
[Music]
baby
you