[Music]
hey guys welcome to bow man's world I'm
here today on my 42nd earth strong my
son was playing piano in the background
but he's now stopped you can keep
playing but it sounded good
I'm I figured I would share a bowl with
you guys you know I feel like I share so
much with you guys as it is it made
sense that on my birthday I would come
and share a nice Bowl a nice rib for you
maybe even mention a little bit of this
this exosphere ball rig that high
integrity glass art is selling with the
ofz but never existed before if you guys
have the mothership calendar you've seen
this piece it's a it's on March this
month actually but the one thing the
calendar pictures missing is the ofz the
optimized flavor zone so that was just
completed recently and it made the whole
piece just really you know finish so
there it is right there if you guys have
an interest in picking up such a
beautiful piece
PM me send me a message bubble man at
bubble bag dot-com this piece is for
sale 33 opal crazy exosphere ball rig
and this is a bit of a roller so I'm
gonna go and put that right back on top
there when I suspect we better have a
nice little rip while we're sitting here
how about something bluesy
well for a little blues while we're
hitting this full melt sweet skunk dry
soaked now it's true I haven't been
rosin 'never ething I still do hit full
Mel bubble and full melt dry sift really
enjoy it there we go there's my blues
[Music]
lovely rip of the dry cept getting used
to this
cooking be courts carb cap as well
really like that little guy not a big
fan of this aspect of it I always use a
different dapper than the dabber that
comes on my carb cap but I definitely
like this part of it that little part
right there is just a choice a
choice little unit
man how bad you guys want me to just
light this baby up I do too but I'm not
sure that I got $25,000 to put into it
just yet so if you think you might have
$25,000 to put into it
send me a message
oh
[Music]
yeah
today it might be a birthday video I may
just make the video this little short
introduction and that could be it but
depending on who comes by who shares
different hashes with me I might have to
make that a video as well I know Johnny
B's gonna try and come over he was
telling me earlier that he is crushing
some full Kongo plants over the screens
probably right now as I say this so that
would be exciting and then I've invited
some other people from the community and
so hopefully we'll see some of them as
well
and please do yourself a favor every
time I take a rip you take a read it's
my birthday it's my request thanks for
watching bubble man's world I'll see you
guys in a bit hey guys so I am just over
in my backyard now and working most of
the morning editing videos for you guys
for the channel still trying to catch up
on the Barcelona shots my neighbor must
hear that I'm outside about to film he's
decided to turn his bandsaw on which is
pretty much what he's done every time in
the last two years since I've been out
here but that's ok you guys a pretty
cool audience you don't mind a little
band song a little circular song a
little jig song I figured I was gonna
take a little rip I got the new banger
there from DC glass so I'm pretty stoked
on that
give it a little go go
all right
there we go birthday rips in the pock
it's probably gonna do a dunk
real thick glass on this on these DC
pieces there I don't know if they're
three millimeters and what it is the
thickness but they're very thick and
they're definitely a little bit tricky
the first time you heat them up because
you don't know how hot it is it doesn't
really turn orange the first several
times that you turn it up
right time for a dunk through the fab
egg
[Music]
nice taste maybe it maybe just a little
bit hot but
still pretty darn nice
[Music]