[Music]
welcome to Bubble man's world pretty
exciting again here today uh with new
genetics um I was going through my seed
collection the other day as I was going
to pop these seeds that subcool sent me
recently and I was peeling through all
these old collections in the fridge and
I got down to the bottom and I found
these two particular things now I found
an enormous amount of things in there
from the last 20 to 25 years that I've
been uh smoking cannabis and collecting
the seeds smoking hashish I should say
now it's been for the last 12 to 13
years I collected these particular seeds
um I have eight seeds here they're a
white seed very very light light colored
tan almost and I collected them in 1995
in Negril Orange Hill Jamaica West
Morland the furthest part of of uh of uh
the West Morland area Orange Hill for
any of you that are familiar
unbelievable ganja and this particular
ganja back then I remember when I was
smoking it it had made my mouth numb
with how much resin was seeping out of
the joint of course it was sungrown
tropical sungrown resin so it was it was
excellent quality but
basically the gentleman who had passed
it to me said that his friend from uh
Eugene Oregon had brought some really
nice seeds and they had uh bred them
with the local um Lamb's bread style
strain so it is indeed a lamb's bread
hybrid uh super excited to crack these
so we've got these little eight seeds
and I'm going to open this container I
haven't opened this little plastic
container for almost 20 years so I'm
just opening it right now and Out Come
the the seeds onto the plate they still
look like they're in growable shape now
um also I found from not quite as old
but around 96 97 there was a strain that
used to be quite prevalent back in
British Columbia in Vancouver here
called the hash plant when it was grown
to Perfection they often called it the
champagne hash plant and this was that
La style lime green Bud that sold itself
perfect you never saw any other grade
other than Perfection out of this strain
it was apparently clone only there was
never seeds available but out of all of
it that I ever saw I remember pulling
two seeds out of out of a bud and these
two seeds are right here with me now so
I just wanted to take you through my
method of uh cracking seeds and we're
going to see if it works for 20-year-old
seeds so I had called a couple of
different friends I talked to Matt the
great Gardener and he told me about a
trick that s had told him about about
putting putting it into a glass of water
which I had heard about uh myself as
well and letting the seeds float and uh
I guess once they sink you pull them out
and you plant them and that means the
seals cracked and that they're ready to
grow I personally am just more
comfortable for whatever reason with
doing what I always did and I always
just did the old paper the old paper
towel and plate moisten the paper towels
open it up throw the seeds inside and
then put this in a nice uh uh dark place
and hope for germination so that's what
we're going to do today here the seeds
look completely different so there's
really no worries on on mixing them up
uh show you with the lens there that
some of these seeds are
literally White and the couple of hash
plant ones are uh quite quite a bit
darker so we're going to put these all
in their little place you know give them
a little bit of space there there is an
excellent thing I found on on
seed uh germination and I'll put the
link in the
comments um I was really impressed with
this uh this particular post that I
found on seed uh germinating and it
really told a lot of the different
stresses that can help increase your
numbers of males which generally isn't
something you want so he's giving a list
of things to avoid uh simple things like
uh you know obviously don't uh crack
your seeds and allow them to get a
quarter of an inch to an inch long
before you plant them that shocks them
and that can produce males temperature
variances can produce males um uh the
lack of uh light he says that you want
your light right above your soil your
t5s when those seeds come out it's good
for them to have that light right there
uh if they have to stretch any amounts
if they're falling over this is another
thing that can produce males so I'll go
over a couple of these things in the
upcoming videos that I do about these
particular seeds and uh we'll let you
know what kind of female ratio we we get
because we've just cracked 3 four 5 yeah
so there's eight and two so we're going
to have 10 seeds total not a high number
of seeds by any by any
means you'd think we should get a
solid five uh five plus females so
they've got their place on the on the
paper towel I'm going to close that
paper towel up and we're going to mist
it get it nice and
moist and of course keep it moist don't
let it dry out that's a good way to uh
affect your seeds in a very negative
way so we just want to get this nice and
wet through and through not soften by
any means but still nice and wet and if
I open it up in the middle it's still
completely dry in here so we're going to
give some moisture in there
too
20-year-old
seeds let's see what you got for
us so feel free to you know add your
comments and your tips I know everyone's
got a way of doing this and I'm not
really promoting this as the only way to
do this by any means but it is the way
that I'm the most comfortable doing it
moisten this the paper towel uh I've got
a nice coal uh not Cal but you know not
warm at the same time either space for
this to be in the dark and just allow
for those seeds to uh to tap into that
natural mechanism of sprouting once we
produce the um conditions that it
requires really excited Jamaican Lamb's
bread hybrid and hash plant stay tuned
keep watching Bubble man's world and uh
have a great
day
hey
that's