[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
uh today just simply put we're going to
keep it simple we're going to do a
little wet washing we're going to run a
set of the Bubble Bag Originals I've got
some fresh ice I've got some chilled
water down here and I have two fresh
frozen oh a little piece of ice kind of
trip me out there for a second I think
we'll just keep that ice smells good so
we got some fresh Frozen uh Astro Boy
and I will come up and show you what it
is we're dealing with
here oh let's see if we can get this to
focus on that camera for you good really
really nice nuggets I can hear jibs
telling me break those down a little bit
more bubble man don't worry Jibber I'm
breaking these down brother so this is
extremely Frozen material it's been in
the freezer
for jeez I want to say a couple weeks
now it's
cracky and uh it's a good amount you
know this is actually a couple of plants
this time so could be anywhere from 50
to 60 gram of dry plant matter nothing
nothing monstrous I'm just growing small
plants but it should be a nice amount to
run for a batch of bubble there's
actually some substantial amount of
nuggets
here so just a matter of pulling out a
bag ah going to grab the bags
so just a matter of pulling out the bag
that we're going to mix in of course
last time you may have seen that I have
the standard Barrel shaped which was a
design we came up with quite some time
ago uh in conjunction or not conjunction
but in sort
of after the pyramid design which was
designed by Acme my manufacturer uh he
came up with along with our help uh the
design of two uh other bags so I think
we're going to go with this one today
can't believe how sticky my fingers are
from touching this Bud right
here
so let us jeez part of me wants to use
the barrel shaped as well let's
go let's just do it let's throw a bunch
of this butt in
here get this washed this is just like
top grade butt like as good as the
material gets this is it right here
perfect size material couple of the buds
are a little bit big and once I get them
all in here if I don't drop them all on
the floor
prior ni save I will uh get back into
this and break up some of those flowers
that are a little bit larger than they
need to
be be
careful to not let this I am kind of
insane you know I do this so you guys
can see I do it so you can uh enjoy the
view but ideally you don't have to be
doing this out in the sun it's why I'm
rushing it's why I'm working very fast
if I was in a cooler environment in a
lab setting um I could have by lab I
mean a hash lab by no means is that on
par with an analytical
lab oh yeah nice big nuggets in here
getting broken down into popcorn size
they're rock hard nugs this is part of
the the real enjoyment here is feeling
how hard these nugs are even in the
Sun and although they are getting a
little bit sticky now just on my
fingers this will be a real joy to run
so we
will the ice cubes never a shortage of
ice cubes when you're running bubble
please use as much as you can don't
Sprint out ice is important this is a
mixture of homemade ice and a little bit
of store bought ice but the homemade ice
is gnarly solid sharp little pieces that
I jaggedly cut with a knife there's an
enormous amounts of these pieces of uh
ice cubes these are very effective ice
cubes when it comes to fresh frozen I
find I love the density of any type of
dark ice that is opaque and you can't
really see through it
not quite clear but more
cloudy all
right get that done
up sit that there and we will load up
our bubble now with some chilled water
move this out of the
way put our bucket down
all right so nice chilled
water this water is probably a solid 4°
it's extremely cold I mean
cold and so we'll drop that in top of
there all right and top that up a little
bit okay
simply
put that's really all she wrote guys it
is that easy make sure when you're
starting that your nozzle your drain is
attached I mean you want to make sure
that even before you pour the water in
obviously um I'm going to go for
probably a 6 Minute run on this
batch and we'll be back to pull this in
6 minutes
all right guys the bubble now literally
just finished mixing it mixed for about
6 minutes and uh no time like the
present to get the resin out of the
water and how do we do that we start by
draining the resin into the bags I've
got the bag sitting down here below it's
a gravity fed unit so gravity works in
your favor here once again uh it is the
gravity that's helping you separate the
resin glands from the rest of the
material by the resin being so dense
that it's still affected by gravity and
in the water while everything else of
course is not it's buoyant it floats
this is part of the magic of water
extraction
so not only am I going to filter that
material through but I'll also use just
a little bit more water I've still got a
little bit of cooled water here but I'll
fill this up it's never a bad
idea get a little bit of water in the
face it's all par partial
and parcel for the gain here we go a
little bit
more another little
rinse never a bad idea to give it a
little rinse very cold in here so we can
kind of drain that water off into the
corner we will of course do a second
batch and uh what I'll be doing almost
ASAP is taking this material getting it
into the
freezer so that's done oh a little bit
more
little bit more all
right get this guy in the
freezer pass this on to my
assistant all right so we can get the
bubble now off the
table get it into the
shade cuz we will be running it
again it's ideal if it's not sitting in
the sun I'll prob probably run the
second patch ASAP
so move these plants out a little bit
there we
go get this guy up
here I'm going to do one bag at a time
got my tools in a bunch of ice here
keeping it nice and cool for when we get
to
the micro planing or the Dr uh seing I
should say all right lots of contaminant
in this bag leaf and such that managed
to get through
oh it holds the bag
well
so pull out my
spoon just sitting here completely
covered in ice how awesome is that you
know your spoon is cold
when
awesome p that back
up
and not using the spray bottle today
could have I suppose but
just going to do a real real
quick extraction today here we're not
messing around usually John and I are
giving you guys full explanations on
everything sirens in the background hope
it's not for
me perfect way to clean your
tools make sure you get these bags is
very very clean it's an important part
of the process you don't want to scrimp
out on the
bags getting
clean and properly
dried this is the first thing that will
wreak havoc to your bags putting them
away
dirty all right a very small amount of
wasn't expecting I probably
ran a total of
60 G
um through the bags in that fro in that
Frozen Bud that you saw there just two
plants my plants aren't huge they don't
average much over
30 all
right bag
90 you see in the pattern
here all
right you can keep the resin
cold and get it collected before it
heats up on the screen it picks up just
perfectly
perfect to help with the bucket is I
can't say enough about it to have this
little sort of bubble bucket thing as
your tool to help you is definitely
going to come in
handy no out about
it all right let's start getting into
some smokables
here yes nice nice to see a little bit
of
120 nice little pile of
headies it's nice to have that little
bit of water in there it really allows
the resin to come off properly without
uh grinding it into the
screen there we go this resin is savable
we will wash the resin on this bag the
120 into the
90 o that water's so cold you know you
got it good when you get the water that
cold hose water is of course not that
cold nice that it's such a hot day that
this is enjoyable to have the
water all right the 90 I always like to
see a little bit come out of this bag oo
and I like the way it's holding the
water unlike the other
bags never a bad sign anyone that's made
a lot of water has knows that when you
pull that bag and it doesn't release
that's generally a better sign than
not of course we're using just baby
amounts here I want to show you the
amounts I don't want to deceive you and
and show you these huge pulls which I
can do with 20- gall bags no problem but
I'm trying to show you guys what it
looks like if you run a small plant from
your
crop and what it looks
like is that
there we go beautiful 90 Micron just a
little pile you know really probably no
more than a
gram but the quality of this
gram or
two will be extremely
good in fact this
one I will choose to se almost
immediately
the other ones are still W wet and
watery so that's good I don't want to
let this resin deceive you it will stick
like you would not believe particularly
if you get it warm right now it's very
cold in this bucket so it comes off real
nice if I sat this bag out for any
amount of time in this
heat to give you an idea it's not an
extremely hot day it's about maybe 75°
80° maybe at the peak of the day just
getting past that
now all right that's holding pretty good
it's pretty greasy I've got it in the
shade it's a little bit
cold spread it out a little bit we'll do
the 73 and then we'll we'll sip them
both at the same time see them both at
the same time
s ni little quick upper so I can get
that off there even
quicker and once again we're left with a
nice little
pile just blowing the foam off of it so
you guys can see what we got there nice
little pile of
73 and the water present really makes it
easy to scoop it
off and to place
it back on the
screen all right so rinse that in there
rinse this in
here make sure that 73 bucket is rinsed
so easy to make the mistake on getting
over excited and wanting to process that
bubble that you forget about your dirty
bag to me that's not acceptable you got
to clean your
bags okay so we're going to take the
bubble that we've taken so far that
we've pulled we're going to bring it in
ins side with you guys and we're going
to show the uh seing process we'll come
out and pull the last two bags and then
we'll do the seing on that and we'll be
done one more video on how to make your
own water extracted resin okay so I've
got my pizza boxes all set up my 190
through 160 my 120 my 90 my 73 and my 45
and my 25 I'm usually able to make do
with these size boxes because I'm
running smaller batches the resin's
still nice and wet so I'm not not overly
worried about it the um
strainer the strainer is sitting in ice
a nice big amount of ice to sit the
strainer in so that when we get to that
it's cold I'm going to grab the spoon
and we're going to start
straining okay so we are going to scoop
out the 70 or the 90 I should
say it's uh just that perfect liness
right
now comes off on the spoon
nice we get our strainer
out and then we will
start straining this gummy
goopy
resin through
here well that's definitely not
working that gummed up worse than
anything I've ever seen
all right so we had a major upset the
resin gummed up worse than we thought so
what we're going to do is when this
happens I guess it was a little
deceiving we will still collect the
resin nothing is
lost but we will let this dry by
microplaning it and this is a great
thing about microplaning and how it can
sort of back you up so we will freeze
the resin we so far have
all right so we're going for the freezer
method you can see I basically pushed
half a gram of that resin into the
strainer no loss this resin will dry
perfectly I will allow it to spread
throughout the the screen
and it'll just crack off once I've
heated once I've uh warmed it up so no
worries on that it won't be lost but uh
definitely I'm sure many people have
seen this sort of thing and thought Oh
my God I [ __ ] myself you did not it's
a little bit of an unfortunate move but
uh it'll come off it'll dry and it'll
crack right off beautifully so nothing
lost we'll be back in a bit once we've
got this ready
to microplane
all right so that stuff was a little
stickier than I anticipated it's going
to
uh require a microplane of course I'm in
too hot of an environment too so these
are the little bit of mistakes that
you'll come up with if you're working
too hot in an environment so it's great
to show you guys this cuz I know
sometimes people are completely baffled
and Confused how these things can happen
to them um here we go nice big 45 pull
on that Astro Boy covered up the screen
real
nice so more gooey gooey gooey resin you
know what we got to do with this we get
it off we collect
it coming off real nice and then get it
frozen for micr planting really nice
pile of 45 Micron I'd
say easily 3
G just on
that so it's good I'm sure you know last
time I was getting four four to five
grams off my yields and I think because
I used twice the amount this time that
we're going to see twice the
return always easier to get the resin
off when it's a bit wet
and particularly if it's cold as
well always have your your most
reasonable time with your resin when
it's a little wet as that moisture gets
out of it and it starts drying and
spreading
out then you can run into problems so
you want to keep it off your
fingers keep it moist keep it wet even
if you got to dip your hand in the water
every once in a while
excellent
excellent all right nice pile of 45
clean that 45 bag real
quick ask for a nicer setup for
cleaning perfect
all right final bag Mr 25
micron this one's always slow to
drain so we do this people tell me it
takes them hours to drain their 25
micron bag and I have to shake my head a
little bit at that I mean I'm sure if
you stood here like this it would take
hours
but why would you do
that using the air to force the screen
you don't squeeze the screen don't
bruise the
fruit can't remember who used to say
that but for some reason I think it's
someone it's negative so I won't bring
any more of that up 25 micron is
decent also covering the screen much
like the
45 never quite as Blonde never quite as
clean looking but this is pretty nice
looking
25 Spoonful and a half
anyway I guess that's what they meant by
a l Spoonful I mean isn't that a l
Spoonful right
there all right well
Okay so we've got our tpine Rich water
and that's something I'd really like to
talk a little bit about how do we get
these tpin out of this water how do we
do it without heating up the water which
will affect the actual tpin and produce
what is called an artifact over a true
molecule I want to recapture these Turin
and I want to hear what you guys have to
say about that uh I know they have
different machines at Eden Labs that you
can use for these sort of different
processes that are done to essential
oils I don't know much about it but I'd
love to hear from you people that do
know a lot about it um i' you know
something that's not distillation I
don't want to heat up the water too much
I'm not sure I want to evaporate the
water there's got to be a way to trap
these Tarpin that are in this water and
rebr bring them back out I think there's
a future in that and uh it's something
that I'm putting my focuses on so I
wanted to share it with you guys this
bubble needs to get into the freezer
ASAP as it's sitting out right now just
looking awesome
and the birds want it can you hear them
they're like give me that bubble man
give me that
bubble anyway I'm going to get this into
the freezer we're going to come back in
a little bit and microplan the whole
batch it's going to be a tough one cuz
it is sticky icky but we'll get it done
we'll see you in a
minute all right guys it is the next day
my planer has been in the freezer I've
got a little piece of a 120 here and
we're just going to we're just going to
shave her
down there's tiny little pieces but with
this planner that I've got I have to say
it's called the micr planer that's it
just straight name it's got a very very
small bump it doesn't have very harsh
holes on it and because of it you can
actually plane without planing your
finger off it's actually quite
nice all right
so little bit of Chunk here
but
120 breaking up just starting to get
sticky on my
fingers uh the next upep we
have 12073 we have 90
so we're going to have to grab that box
or 73 I should said I'd already done the
90 that's
right
73 so we'll go grab the 73 and we go
microplan
it all right nice little piece of
73 we're just going to grab Ry that down
on the old microp
planer it's going to get gumming so we
got to work
fast The Joy about this
is especially with the metal microp
planer that you can release all that
sticky resin this one's releasing quite
nicely due to the fact that it's got a
little bit of moisture I'm going to put
this back in the freezer we're going to
come back here and we're going to do
this last little
chunk all right so we got the last
little bit of
this Frozen
bubble I almost
need a new planer cuz mine is guming up
good coming up with that that 90 Micron
love and what a great problem to have
right a little bit
of a little bit of gummy bubble
little bit
of oh
yeah little bit on the bottom you can
hear it
just hitting that parchment paper
nicely
awesome you can just bang hang it hang
it through with the one hand and then
flick it off with the scissors so there
are a little bit of chunks here but
because it's so fresh um what I'll be
doing with those chunks is I'll just be
giving them a small amount of time um
probably less than 6
hours and then they will get um uh they
will get reapplied broken up a little
more uh for now I got a pretty nice uh
even texture on that 90 mic run there's
none left
so what we do is we shut the box and
this is one of the great things about
the pizza box people have been laughing
about them for years you know you get
certain guys thinking it's fail Tech I
say that it's not fail Tech at all I say
that once you've lined the box with your
parchment paper you're covered with
worrying about any type of fibers that
you could possibly get from the box um
plus you get the box closing it closes
right over the hash so you uh can avoid
paper uh you can so you can avoid uh
dust and debris and animal hairs
basically keep your hash nice and clean
so easy to transport to once you got
that you can just kind of take it right
over I've got my 120 and my
73 uh we're going to do up the 40 45
next so also if you get yourself some
hash on your fingers like
this right real nice easy way to take it
off is with a Dabber
now the trick
is if you want to get it off that
clean is to heat up the Dabber just a
tiny little
bit with your torch or with a
lighter and basically you'll get those
fingers clean as a
whistle and you'll get your
bubble ready to smoke
and you'll get your bubble off your
hands just another tip from the bubble
man all right so I let a little bit of
time pass I've left the 45 and the 25
frozen in the
freezer they're right here freshly out
you can
hear how completely Frozen that is and
I'm going to be using a
different plane this is more of a
greater here's my plane here I've gotten
it quite dirty and so I'm planning on
using this this time around so I'll let
you know how that works in about a
second oh
nice really
nice wow just pling super
nice breaking it down into pieces that
first little bit was going real nice
we have to break these little chunks off
later
[Music]
[Laughter]
here shaving
nicely this is exceptional
quality no doubt about it
so getting quite a bit of chunks but I
can break it down
[Music]
further these off to the side a little
bit come back at
them probably a good half gram or
gram of larger pieces
there o I got away lucky I think with
that that is a
nice nice
plane able to sort of push this through
the
holes it's actually planning quite
nicely right now this is actually
usually a cheese grater it's the first
time I've ever used this
particular style but the holes are sharp
enough that it's it's giving me a
decent a decent plane on it I mean
really the the whole purpose is to break
your your hash up and get that surface
area that's really what you're looking
for not leaving it in
chunks it's always easier I'm not going
to lie you know once again even this
could be made easier if I were simp
simply in a colder environment even the
warmth from this environment right now
and it's not that warm it's probably
around
70° just warm enough to um cause more of
a problem than than create a
help so that's
perfect wet wash and this was the 45
Micron so that's
done what I like to do once I'm done is
I like to shut that up you can see it
cat just jumped into the view here
there's cat hair there's dog hair
there's kids there's other people
there's debris and Dust In the Airs that
just float around so I like to cover my
[ __ ] up and so that's why the box
so that one's
done last one on
the that's 25
kind of gently rub it off the pressing
screen
here
excellent this one I usually um is the
one that I'll usually break up often by
hand the 25 micron um I find mostly
because it's a
met um also that because the heads are
so small I find it's the one that seems
to be able to
dry properly without the help of being
uh completely powderized every single
time and it's sort of one of the reasons
sometimes people wonder well you know
like they they see the 25 micron dry and
they figure well they should it all it
should all be able to dry like that and
unfortunately it's not like that I think
the 25 micron dries like that because of
the smaller heads and if you put a lot
of small balls in a bowl for example the
smaller they are the less um space
there'll be between them and the larger
they are the more space there'll be
between them so the way I look at it is
the larger uh heads are allowing more
water to get trapped in there taking a
longer time to dry and the smaller heads
are leaving less so there's the 25
micron boom two boxes done got my 120
and my 90 already microplaned and drying
so that's the 120 the 90 the
73 and the 45 and the 25 so that's it
Astro Boy Fresh Frozen I'll finish it
off with some macro photographs of each
one I hope you enjoyed the run and uh
next up I'm
thinking My Little Pony see you then
[Music]
he
[Applause]
[Music]