[Music]
all right check out the
Barbara excellent look at
this screens are out more importantly
started with the house of the great
[Music]
Gardener very nicely that's all canonic
that's the high CBD beautiful well done
dry racks down at the
end oh yeah went
through and what kind of temperature and
humidities are you looking for in
here uh because it's open on either end
it's tough to control mhm uh it doesn't
feel muggy in here at all it definitely
no no that if it gets too hot we have
fans that we I'm more concerned with the
air blowing down and just keeping a
constant air flow on them uh still
takes 7 to 10 days for them to dry here
and then they'll go into bins and then
from there World treat them flip them
get the moisture out and then from them
destock them and then back into
bins okay so good process all the all
the shake is put on screens now that's
what I'm talking about right there this
is what I want people to see this is how
you do it people you don't have to go
and buy uh expensive racks from
restaurants you can build your own this
is perfect he's got them dated
and named this is really nice to see
this is just so much resin lost when not
done this has been sitting on here since
December
13th wow it's ready it's ready no we
it's ready for the ready to be and do
you have a you have catch trays on the
bottoms or the very bottom we have a
little trays that clip onto here M so it
Clips onto here and then you pull it out
uh and then you flip it beautiful and
then you move it down and then you pull
the next one out flip it only ever it
gets flipped once uh and that's it cuz
then from there it's scooped up
and excellent either put through the
Tumblers through the Tumblers to the to
the and then to the Bakers hash then to
the Bakers tumblr's bags and
Bakers yeah this still has you can see
see it's it's sort of dry to the touch
but if you squeeze it in the middle yeah
so it still a couple more days to
[Music]
go this is a bar Bud seed room look how
Frosty that is just change that up a bit
here so these have been that's very
frosty fan leaves fan leaves removed but
it's you know a lot of the fan
leaves
uh we
crystally well there's a
cake and this is why you do this over
screens cuz he just literally knocked
off
83,000 gland heads when he did that and
we're catching and we're catching them
all
absolutely but everything they wouldn't
be caught without those
screens so you can see if I if I just if
I just bang these a little bit you can
see the seed oh yeah do you have a seed
separator that you guys use or um just
do it a couple sort of again homemade
machines that you know just run them
through holes no not even I use I use
more sort of gravity and and air flow
you've seen those laser perforated hole
sheets though those are pretty good with
a little vibrator I've seen a few I've
seen the one with the um blows the air
up and blows the Sha up right yeah
that's nice through the tube or whatever
yeah those are pretty impressive
too
Ingenuity nothing beats these seeds I
love eating them so basically the work
here is to deed these uh destock them
uh and because it's C you don't really
have to do this stage but because of the
fact that we we we want
to uh capture the tric Combs right
always want to keep the surface in front
of you clean cuz when you cut it off it
hits the screen thousands of tricomb
have just fallen off that butt we
collect that so you sit here you know
it's you know it's dry when I could sit
here and use my fingers
don't even need the fiskers don't need I
don't need these scissors I I I can I
can operate this whole thing with just
using my scissors but but this butt
itself is still if you squeezed
it it's it's good so we'll sit here
and do a little debing do a little
debting I'm going to take a few macro
shots of that resin to show people the
quality that you're working with and
then once you have a little pile in
front of you just slly push it forward
you always want to make sure that the
bud falls directly on the
screen be
like just kind of do a one far shot and
then good
[Music]
guess I could have helped you
there all right
so yeah those go
downstairs
gosts
thanks oh I guess uh yeah a second
[Music]
he could always tell where a workstation
was look at that yeah that one was
definitely well worked
[Music]
nice pile of
sift got the other
car he's got some here for
you so will you keep these four separate
or just mix them all yeah they're all
the same y
[Music]
I almost have to put my shades
on glad you did that work on screens
Quick Test throw it here throw it in
your
[Music]
hand squeeze it for a
second
come
[Music]
gumy oh
anomic that's a word is that a word
close aromatic aromatic arom arom
[Music]
aric quick quick
aroic oh yeah
[Music]
so time to make some dry sift
or Y so now we
oh that sh Berry smell is
unreal they stoed it collected the KE
that fell off of that oh those are nice
that's a nice knock and now because it's
a seed
crop
yeah if you dump it too fast I won't
dump it all
just slow
M we'll uh throw the whole batch in the
tumbler
and we're going to do it for 30
seconds 10
minutes and then we'll do a 1 hour
run at which point we'll take it and
then go and then go get the seed out of
it and then after we got the seed out of
it we'll bring it back and we'll bring
it back for a 24-hour
run uh and then we'll put it in for a 24
to 48 hour run and then we put it in
for like two days 48 to 72 hours of run
wow uh making sure you getting it
all nice probably put this
[Music]
so what did we just dump in there 15 lb
of herb 10 lb of herb 5 lb of herb got
to be 10 five yeah probably five five
it's
fluffy it's that high
well within my storage limits of my mm
license yeah mine
too so put it in
[Music]
here it starts getting on the outside
smell that's
crazy that is a nice smell
not so much on the outside but after the
24-hour
run so this and
take and you saw that when it was Bugg
when we put it in that would have broken
it all
up
mhm does a lot of work for you
especially over
[Music]
seeds sorry Kirk yeah good good time
to that the pile got so deep
you can see the
screen where the screen was hitting
at that looks like some hundreds of
grams you might want to get
some e
[Music]
let's
see that's a good
amount it's a good amount of weight
right there for sure and it is dense
you're right it's uh it looks denser
than you think or it is denser than you
think it's denser than it
looks good
color all right so you've gotten to the
point where Barbara's been well sifted
we sifted it for an hour and those big
fluffy buds we had are now just sort of
like this but you got to get the seed
out so what we do
is we take put it onto this screen so
all the seed and everything that's will
already fall
through and then this a small grinding
breaks up all the bud and get in
particular it gets out all the seat so I
usually do this with gloves
but all that loose stuff all the seed
that's over harvested
see
just all the loose stuff let it fall
through
and then after you after you do it
all you end
up end up sort of with
that and then from in
there you get the seed
out try to get
them but they're in
there let separate those further using
SC SE screen separators or pull them out
by hand yeah no we have a couple other
wind machines that'll blow the blow the
chaff
away and then uh one more after that one
more uh system after that that uses the
Angles and lets the seeds roll down
perfect and then you put a fan on there
blows off the CH so good amount of sift
came off of that
uh off of that barber it looks pretty
good so that's the 1H hour r run so then
after we get the seed out we'll actually
put this back in back in the sifter and
do a 24hour run okay the last little bit
and then a 24h hour to 48h hour run and
that stuff will go to Edibles tinctures
and things like that awesome awesome