[Music]
apologies Rasta fireworks them for
swallow these I am a cosmology my omona
traded under surveillance preload
Babylon and pollen is now
Marshall er my shop them to refill your
diamonds every nerve in our you're
brilliant are you will do my snapper
from clear no one but yourself your
people it does help me to see
[Music]
it would be made would be mathematics is
through metaphysics I bet our civics
damn near poverty that we could up the
shock intelligence bubble on above all
life that demands to get [ __ ] the box
with no 44 elements etiologic on earth
like the co-president them Nawaf anova
bernard am president under system was
set forth a german once again the
knowledge on you will be from it the
wise one will know the truth game seek
lesson and you will be blessing love can
ever be over
[Music]