[Applause]
[Music]
my strike lightning as the morning break
my open wi the sun was up in my face the
wisdom of the W keep my head straight
with I canot
[Music]
try to Perfection smoke synic I love
the found we get the
fulling I love
the I when the rest consum the
meditation to CB1 and
CB2 can receptors in the brain and
happiness for
horiz man herbalist The canab
Specialist
[Music]
herbaliz over and you search the
a pull it up and give it a sniff
turn I say yes and I also got
hash full m edes all that dry make you
cool and relax and if you get some you
must come
back
her man her canot be special
original
indigenous we
[Music]
just
indigenous cre them from the
in be care and turn you TR in
[Music]
Ander
sexing
orous
indigenous can just
[Music]
some phone out Yes Man
[Applause]
[Music]
full full full full
full with
[Music]
yes