[Music]
only here to do it purpose of
time ganja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying we I've been traveling to Kingston
about 20 M hour sing
on trees
[Music]
make pass pass
pass
and
that that
now purpose of the weed that keeps me
going the purpose of the we that's to
the
Mind purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time weed is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of time
ganja is not here to trick the
M it is only here to do its purpose of
D well I imagine the road there be some
cops setting
up all traps
man we
me in my bra St that K and behind your
scene me and my team have another 25
me smoke it up
[Music]
clean my eyes
now pass pass pass