[Music]
Nails not plugged into the truck hey
guys welcome to Bubble man's world for a
city parking lot truck sesh yep with the
West Coast concentrate boys in the house
we just had a delicious meal at cardos
scooted into the underground parking lot
here and of course uh like we always do
when we don't have a torch uh we
couldn't get the Dil to work we couldn't
even get their Chinese version to work
off of this little piece of [ __ ] 100
watt [ __ ] inverter that I have
wouldn't work so we were like do we need
to get a torch what do we need to do so
Bret got out and he walked around and he
was like I found um a place that we can
plug in that we can get get this [ __ ]
done and so here we are we're definitely
on camera uh under the parking lot
there's one literally right here but
then there's also another one right over
there on the wall so we're we're in well
V we're in good I didn't see that one
camera view so we'll see how this goes
we're uh we just finished a great meal
so we're going to smoke some beautiful
hash and I kind of wanted to have a
conversation with these guys today about
hash making and uh you know a lot of
people ask me all the time how do you
get into this how do you how do you
become a good hash maker do you have any
advice for me and I thought what better
way than to have a conversation with
Adam and Brett they're fairly fresh new
hash makers on the scene you guys have
been making hash for like the last year
yep last year and uh a beautiful job
they've been doing thanks to uh the West
Coast concentrate crew most definitely
helping everyone out along the way Phil
doing a great job and passing on the
knowledge that I shared with him and uh
I guess we've got the Fab egg all ready
to go with the Cory cotum drop down and
the Beagle uh Bowl we've cleaned the
Dabber so I think it's time to Puff here
Gentlemen let's do let's say we do this
what do we got we got some uh some gcg
full spe full spec and PC full spec all
right well I'm down I'm down this looks
quite nice quite lovely actually give
them a little view of
that it's amazing how nice it looks he
yeah like just in front of the camera
right there beautiful with us here we'll
lower it hey there's Adam and now he's
gone hey there he is and now he's
gone great job guys blacked out by the
hash I mean man I could push that right
up against the lens and it just keeps
looking better and better and
better so we can talk a little bit um
about how we got into making hash that'd
be perfect dude because that's kind of
what I wanted to ask you guys from a
perspective of like fresh on the game
well I would say it first off started um
with me and Adam being inspired by
seeing full melt resin that we couldn't
purchase um couldn't go out and buy so
we decided we were going to take it upon
ourselves to try and make it um mind you
that that was a a long road to where we
are now not that long I mean not long in
time but long long in um um actually
practicing you know and making a lot of
hash and it wouldn't be possible without
you know the help of our our Collective
and our crew behind us um because that
really gave us opportunity to uh you
know hone in on our skills guys like
Phil in knowledge uh coming in to the
crew uh definitely helped um and and
your videos really um got some water in
there yes there's definitely water in
there beautiful well I'll hit this while
you continue to tell the story of uh how
you guys got into this yeah so basically
we just started making hash for
ourselves and um yeah we met up with the
West Coast Collective guys they seem to
like the hash and uh wanted to offer a
solventless product in their Collective
so we came in and um started doing that
for them and then um we started with
Rosen dryft um when Phil came in he
really helped us hone in on the bubble
scales so now you see um some beautiful
bubble like that oh yeah it's not it's
not really a long story we basically
were inspired we went out and try and
did something we accomplished it and we
try and just redo that day after day
after day well I think it's going to be
an inspiration for people to listen to
because they all want to be doing it yep
and so I mean really I think from my
perspective the the tip I always give
people is is hone in on the best quality
possible yeah because that's where you
want to pay your attentions to yes
that's all that matters if you find
something that someone thinks is the
bomb but it's not you're kind of wasting
your time in that sense of like why is
my product not melting why you know why
am I getting such shitty yields why I'm
personally bummed when I run a bat and
it's just not yeah it's not what you're
what you're expecting yeah for sure or
or when somebody um you know the whole
uh trash to stash it's like you're only
going to get as good as good as melt as
the uh you know the product that the the
resin comes from um it's hard to turn
real trash into six-star full melt um a
lot of the time damn near impossible
it's damn like you go and shake the
Grower's hand when you're done fire in
fire out always what always say fire in
fire out I'd say that's the most
important thing to remember this is some
great uh tasty bubble of course uh I'll
show some macro photographs so you guys
can see this is the GS the go The Green
Green Crack godd Green Crack God Bud the
G
CG There It
Is I've been smoking enough of it you
think I'd know the name by
[Music]
now
oh we should have filmed us walking
around the parking lot looking for we
should really show this real quick yeah
it's a good it's a good
time right you see that right on the
pillar this is how we do that's a tech
This Is How We
Do all right so yeah we've been trying
to film this uh sequence most of the day
we met up earlier we had a little
session we went and ate and the day just
kind of like did that not just disappear
onest I can't flew by yeah what the hell
hash we hung out for a few hours in a
parking lot just smoking this truck out
like fiends right now I really like it I
guess I could uh oh but it'll be loud
true we're okay we're okay we're smoking
it out so yeah I think I'll have one
more little dab a doodle here while
we're try the other stuff here let's do
it
the
PC we're going to do a little uh
Periscope after this too so I want to
keep this video short and sweet kind of
the inspirational video of like young
fresh new hash makers that want to make
their Mark you know this is a video that
I want to be able to sort of answer a
few questions to people like that which
is you know where do you start quality y
That's pretty key and then the
information I guess when you're someone
that doesn't know how do you know what
information is real and what information
is not experimentation yeah yeah really
R&amp;D because there's so many things out
there and you may you may think
something works and then you try it and
you you quickly come to the realization
that it doesn't um we all have those
ideas and you know after you make it for
a year um you start realizing what works
what doesn't uh in the end fire in fire
out um is is the main not to mention
when you say something like I've been
making hash for a year that can mean a
lot of different things depending on
where you're coming from like oh I made
like three batches in the last year
that's what I mean or we make like 5 to
10 batches a day 365 days a year so
those are two different sort of
spectrums mind you I wouldn't say we're
making hash 10 batches a day 365 days a
year but we definitely get to make hash
every week um if we aren't making hash
we're making Ros and we're trying to
understand um more about the plant we
all love awesome really right on guys
and what uh when people ask me locally
where can they pick up West Coast
concentrate solventless well the go I
was just going to say the only place you
can get uh our solventless products
right now is at THC it's on Main Street
um and yeah they're great guys in there
they just did a pickup of uh some of our
purple candy uh full spectrum it was a
really nice drop and I think the guys
over there grabbed a couple GRS for
there so definitely uh get that quick um
if not DM the West Coast Collective um
especially if you're a MM mmpr patient
um or have your dispensary card in the
Lower Mainland um DM the West Coast
Collective um uh Collective with no e on
the end of it and then I guess another
option is they can always just whip by
the cchq on Davey on Wednesday Wednesday
we're always there Wednesdays um yeah
scope up the product there come and see
us we have product for you to try free
full m yeah free full m free free full
melt that's what we've been doing here
it's been a wonderful experience full
Friday full melt Fridays are in effect
and uh I think that's a r guys we'll uh
obviously we're going to do a periscope
now but let's say goodbye to these guys
cheers next time happy Friday