foreign
[Music]
bubble man here today is Gaper Day on
the mountain it's May 22nd it's the last
day of the mountain so it'll be full
Mayhem up there lots of people wearing
jeans and costumes and furry costumes
and all sorts of wild [ __ ]
I'm going up with my buddy Craig I just
saw Andrew from Whistler Technologies
probably see a bunch of people up there
today we're going to bump into Ryan good
friend of mine as well and uh sporting
my unicorn cup back freshly from the
visit with antidote and Che making hash
in the Kootenays at antidote and uh yeah
I'll be telling you guys about the
Unicorn cup a bunch more go check it out
Google unicorn cup in the Kootenays on
Rosebud Lake uh if you want to hang out
with me see me and any of the people
that I'm hanging out with on the regular
that's where we'll be August 11th to
14th and in the meantime well I think I
see some guy behind me putting on a tutu
back there oh it's on it will be
happening I'm gonna film as much as I
can today it's just on my phone we'll
see how it all splices together
let's do this
all right halfway here
Craig's got the pink on today
Pinky Tuscadero I'll be calling him all
day
with the Aruba shirt look at these two
looking good there dinos
I'm good
that's awesome oh [ __ ] look at this
I just walked through the muddy mutts
the muddy muds
all right well here we go for the
accelerator all right a couple of pond
dippers
well that's a mad delay
for the chair oh yeah think about that
gay per day baby
all right look at this fog
in the clouds
it's time to make some of our own clouds
I love this [ __ ] dude
oh man look at that hey I don't see
glacier moving
I don't even see Jersey cream moving
dude
[ __ ]
foreign
[Music]
thank you
oh yeah
are you most welcome
that tastes really good yummy
hi Fidelity rosin
platinum OG
Craig just reminded me I made a mistake
it's rainbow driver it's the Platinum
line live rosin it's the Platinum line
there it is
good catch Craig
still acting like my QA
[Music]
you're all right
yeah yeah here's some yahoos
[Music]
the hot dogs are a choice
yeah
a couple of dogs
[Music]
do that Ryan
so this is uh the this is your costume
Jesus Christ you win we'll find a spot
driving through a line all right let's
do it
just ripping on the snow skate
the police
skateboard with a single ski
harder than it looks
especially to control it
I went down today if I go too far
forward
dude I went down so hard today in the
slush
foreign
all right Captain vaginas on the
mountain
let's do this
[Music]
we gotta make it back
[ __ ] yeah
right here
neither
I have zero [ __ ] left to give actually
spent them all so we're going to that
little shitty Pond up there yeah it
seems like the pond and then we'll go
down to the next Pond and do that
no we weren't staying up there May the
force be with you
yes
May the force be with you these guys
know how to do it
that's awesome
that's what's up all right
hey
foreign
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
[Laughter]
holy Christ
[Applause]
tomorrow
[Music]
[Applause]
oh [ __ ]
[Music]
wow
[Applause]
[Music]
here we go
[Applause]
[Music]
you buy your shoes
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
again
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
that's a wrap okay for days over Greg
and I are heading our separate ways that
was pretty cool crazy dude people were
oh you guys saw you guys saw some of it
so uh yeah
the wrap
[Music]
thank you