[Music]
garden
sage at
that right on bro good by tumble now
good to see you man good to see you
right on good to make it thanks Ron
right all all right see guys this thing
going right
away oh I tumbled uh a lot nice up here
I tumbled a lot that's what I love to
hear up here I pushed the
dry a picture of these buds on all right
so you you tumbled about 20 o about that
like I like it was It's All trim like
okay I've got this machine called The
Mean Green trimming machine
for triming dry so so I hang the
material and then I trim it dry and uh
so basically it's all the trim right uh
that I've been saving up uh for quite a
while and uh so so it's like you know
it's not pure bud but it's really nice
Leaf yeah yeah well looks like there's
some Hees in there we just got to clean
them out
awesome garden sage
approved poros beautiful all right yeah
just drop that right in the mo of the
nail there like right here yeah right
not in the middle of the hole but the
moat you know the the thing around the
center hole okay just the thing around
the center hole and and just hold it
there yeah just drop it right in it'll
melt and then take your hit right my
goodness yeah take your hit and then
just sort of hold that in there move it
around a little bit and then yeah you're
getting and suck of course that's the
key
booah garden sage knows how to do it
it's fun to be dabbing out with people
that have never hit the denail and just
kind of letting people wow I have never
seen that before isn't that
nice it's always on that was amazing
stream so yeah Dave Dave was saying that
he he didn't he didn't really understand
what I was when I put this in his hand
he was kind of like cuz I just showed
him the bubble it's bone dry powder so
it's not it doesn't look like this
doesn't look like that so he was just
mentioning that so now I'm going to take
a dab on that
note the garden sage has asked this
bubble here
just became that gooey little disc that
you had that was actually stuck on this
lid so we're going to take a little
piece like maybe that
much and just with our
fingers we're going to turn that into
what we just
had just the body heat alone yeah I'm
giving it pretty good pressure
too
that is amazing that is the most
beautiful gooey stuff I've ever freaking
seen yeah dude
wow it's what we all love about cannabis
it is this is truly it that's it that's
why I laugh at this whole Health Canada
thing when they're like no you can't
have derivatives it's like listen then
don't call it derivatives figure it out
just figure out that this is marijuana
if that's what you want to call it cuz
that's what the medicine is Purity
Purity right there yeah I like to call
it the
unadulterated cannaboid High
wow that's
amazing I up pict you don't really see
cannabis laid out that
nice you're if you're going to store it
for a long time you might as well though
right yeah oh for sure that way doesn't
have to be handled you know and the care
just the care and attention hey they
pile firewood so so that they breathe
right yeah man so do the same with hey
no listen you're talking to the choir
here we love what you've done here
absolutely and and when you see that
kind of care like it just it translates
to like it's clear that you would have
shown care throughout the entire process
yes right down to this end right here
right here this gummy resin I just wish
I grown better than PK now I'm grown God
and but I begged on one of Mark's videos
the the skunk man Sam or whoever you are
come out and bring us that skunk po
again you know that real you know from
the 9s yes real stuff that smells like a
skunks in your neighborhood yeah and we
out of it because we didn't want how it
burns and all right uh ready for me to
rock dab
AO yeah you're good well nice to have
you here David nice of you to Mark to be
here oh it's great to be
here
stop me
nice
oh a there we go all right so what the
garden sage is doing here is he is
looking at three grades of dry sift um
the first screen which was this stuff
what it looked like the one he's looking
at right now which was uh oh no s story
um this red one on the far left was the
one I cleaned from this one and then
this one I cleaned from this one so this
was eventually in here both of these
were in here I took first this out and
then out of this I took this and you can
see the difference uh with the
microscope can't you
absolutely it's amazing difference a
little
off there you go
so what would you say is the difference
in the for contamination levels of this
first one although when you first looked
at it you did think it looked beautiful
didn't you cuz it's glandular and in a
sense it is beautiful there's still
heads that are smaller than 70 Micron so
we've got 69 down to 25 micron in there
but now that I look at it there's a lot
of the stock because you've looked at
the good one now if I only ever showed
you this one you could leave here
thinking this guy just showed me the
most beautiful amazing thing yeah and
it's it's neat that way so yeah a little
little dry SI and I think we're going to
try and put some actually if you want to
maybe scoop a little onto this onto you
want to push some one with your the
other one there sure yeah we'll just get
you a
little there we
go pass this over your way
all right let's see
okay here try to put your hat on
backwards so it doesn't steal the light
off the
screen let's see what we get
here oh it doesn't want to
drop would have been nice to watch it
bubble in mouth but it denied
us
how's the taste on that so smooth it's
like a vapor like vaporization basically
exactly wow that's
nice dry sift
goodness
nice yeah that's
Sublime
amazing yes all right a little bit of uh
uh single
sift single screen sift here from the
tumble
now
all right let's see if we can get this
clear so here's some of here's the dryft
that was in the tumble
now um these ones are basically all top
screens that have been cleaned at
separate times and this one
here is the 90 I'd say about 95% gland
heads and I'll show some macro
photographs of that it melts and bubbles
into a liquid so yeah quite happy with
that a garden sage it's awesome thank
you bubble man hell
yeah