foreign
[Music]
I'm here with Dan we're over here at
Embark and we're going to be using the
gamma cert today we had some uh listen I
should say right away we're just playing
with this thing we don't need all the
comments of people saying it's a scam it
doesn't work it's not this we're going
to be testing black cherry punch today
we do have an hplc COA for this flower
that we're going to be testing it
against and we're just checking it out
we're just having fun we just want to
see what kind of numbers we get so we're
going to jump in here we're gonna log
into the to the
to the page are you going to use your
fingerprint yeah because it has your uh
all your logins perfect so there we go
we're going to log in I need inbox
internet and we're gonna get the
password going here soon all right just
giving the unit a little wipe down here
as it
um what's it doing right now it's right
now it's just warming up so the unit's
got to warm up to temperature before
it'll actually let me calibrate it right
then it calibrates then enter the
calibrate and then we can start playing
with the putting this stuff into it and
then we'll check out what kind of uh
what kind of action we have with the
black cherry punch it looks like really
nice bud and it smells great we've been
making really beautiful bubble from it
so I suspect it's all going to go quite
nice
we'll see what happens
all right so the unit's warming up and
getting soon to be calibrated and now
Dan has just placed the flower on the
little pin and it will show you what
this does in a second
it heads on to here this is using light
and a reflective surface and it's
basically
um I mean how would you explain it Dan
it's basically it's using the reflection
of light off the trichome to measure how
many how much you're like cannibal
content is and then goes to a database
to test against already tested hplc
numbers yes and so it's not like going
to be exactly accurate but I have heard
some people I think when it's not
accurate there are so many ways if you
bump the table if there's vibration in
the room if there's too much anything
the door opens yeah there's an air that
air moves you can you can it can affect
your results and so I see a lot of
people saying these things don't work
they're a scam I prefer to get my own
first-hand information I've talked to
the people at Gamma cert they're really
cool they've explained it to us I'd
rather Dan and I go through use this
thing test 20 or 30 batches test it
against hplc this material has been
tested against hplc I believe it was
21.2 percent
THC when it came back from the hplc test
and so we'll see what we'll get we're
going to test the bud and then we're
going to do a ground test and test it as
powder and we'll see uh we'll see how we
go we're almost done warming up here so
we've changed over to calibration now so
we're just calibrating
being very careful when you're using
this I would say some of the most
important factors of using this unit is
to not bump the table it's not to open
the door it's not to have blaring music
going it's to really make sure
that in no way shape or form do you bump
or bang this unit while it's calibrating
or while it's testing and that generally
can cause a lot of problems and I think
it's probably the number one factor in
Wi-Fi where there's so many people on
our last post that we're saying these
don't work they're not effective you
have to have extremely good Sops and
Hyper awareness
of not
um banging the unit I don't think it's
conducive to take this units to events
and have a table with people standing in
front of your table and testing with it
I think it's much better to have in the
lab we're not using it in any way shape
or form is the word of God but if we can
get this thing going and calibrated
properly where we can test our hash and
some of our flour without having to send
it off right away and have an idea of
where that sits it doesn't have to be
the word of God for us we're certainly
testing everything in our facility
through hplc at third party Labs that do
all of our testing for us but I think
it's a cool technology I'm glad there's
companies like gamma sir trying to put
this technology out and if it's not for
you no problem don't buy one don't use
it if it is something that you think
might fit into your lab space while
we're doing these videos for educational
purposes to let people know you know how
we found that it worked so that's what
this video is for today okay so we're
going to the next part of this on the
unit here it'll basically give you your
run through of what to do so it's
telling us to lift the drawer up and
then hit okay so what we're going to do
is we're going to lift this drawer nice
and light and nice to be gentle this
machine is
it's a scientific machine so gentle and
everything and says hit Okay so we're
going to hit OK
now what it's going to do is it's going
to calibrate with the drawer open
so we'll take a couple more seconds do
its calibration here
and then once that's done it's going to
tell me to put the bud in the drawer
and close it down beautiful there it is
so there we are we're calibrated so now
we're going to touch analyze please
insert flower sample so now that I have
this on this on the pin already what I'm
going to do is I'm going to look for the
frostier side that doesn't have a whole
bunch of leaf and doesn't have any stem
sticking out so I'm going to choose this
side here and this stuff's pretty Frosty
and pretty well trimmed and it goes
upside down into this machine so
little magnetic eye
that's pretty cool
so there's a yellow dot on the side of
this machine
yeah this yellow dot is supposed to be
lined up Center on our Bud that we're
wanting to test yeah I don't think we
want to be moving this unit at all so
what we're going to want to do is we're
going to want to drop this down
just a littlest bit
and that'll get it into that halfway
point and then rotate it I was going to
say it looked like it turned around on
you there we go we have
okay
now anything that's Fallen debris wise
can brush out you got your brush
pull that debris out of there
and off the machine
I feel beautiful
and from there what they want us to do
is we're going to touch this picture
here
and you're going to take a picture and
that goes into the final
um
results the scan results everything that
we get for our numbers will be attached
in the account that we have with that
photo so it's a good frame of reference
to know what you're testing rather than
I often look at coas and there's no
picture of the flower or whatsoever I
think that's kind of this little white
spot you see my finger not coming close
to but pointing at that's your
calibration screen never touch that
don't try to clean it off don't try to
do anything with it leave it alone okay
so now we're going to drop this drawer
nice and slow and lightly and make sure
that we're not dropping it at the very
bottom because we're dropping it onto a
little robot that's going to be rolling
around the little spectrometer light
that's going to be doing that reading
for us totally so from there we're going
to hit percentage
analyze and it's going to hit the Allies
all right so this will go for about
three to four minutes
and we'll come back and we'll show you
what we got
all right so Marcus just stepped out of
the room so I'm gonna get this before it
shuts down
we got the unit saying it's done it's
actually seeing a little bit of lower
water activity on there so it's going to
measure that too what we're going to do
is we're gonna hit okay
we're gonna pull our drawer up ever so
slightly
nice and light once we get to this spot
here we can get our results we can't get
our results until this drawer has
actually been lifted
so what we're going to do from here
is we're going to tap onto the result
button
and there we go that's almost exactly
what it is I think it's like less than
one percent off it's point nine percent
off it was 21.2 percent the total THC
so I gotta say
this is some of our most accurate that
we've found so far
because we were doing it in a very loud
room people banging the table uh the
other day at the collector's cup we were
getting numbers in the 13 14 15 16 and
17 range this compared to an hplc
I can show the COA for this it was 21.2
percent and what we got is 20.3 so it's
less than one percent off which I have
to say is pretty impressive I'm I'm
extremely impressed with that yeah and
we're testing against this COA from an
hplc so this is uh on a non-ground cloud
on a non-ground flower so we'll probably
do another test with this where we grind
the flour
but um yeah that's pretty darn cool from
here we're gonna take the same bud and
we're gonna do a ground test so we're
gonna go into mode
I already clicked on the ground so you
click your ground
and then you go back now we're going to
have to do is we're going to calibrate
the unit
for the ground piece so this is what
they would use you put all your ground
up bud into this little show them how to
open it
so you're gonna
spin it
nice glass wall in there
a little the white edges are always
going to be your zero for the
spectrometer and then we're gonna take
that
slide it into the machine nice thing
about this machine you don't gotta worry
it's magnetic just pulls it right in all
right I like that a lot and so then what
we're going to do is we're going to
slide this drawer down nice and light
again
and we're gonna can we put it right here
thank you that's even a little more
obviously
but that's okay all right perfect and
we're gonna hit calibrate
perfect so calibrate it up calibrate to
ground make sure it's saying ground
there is no ground in there right now
but it's got to calibrate down to that
first some white screens on there
perfect so it's already warm it's
already at 47 so it's gonna go directly
into calibrating okay perfect and then
we're gonna grind up some flour do you
want to grind up the exact same bud I'm
going to grind the exact same bud
beautiful
and then we'll take these Buds and go
throw them into the reactor
so I'm going to pull out as much of this
stem as I can while I'm doing this so
that we're not getting
stem reading off of it
more than enough right oh yeah
all right and perfect timing as we're
done the grind
it's done the calibration for the
downside so what we're going to do is
we're going to lift the drawer
I'm gonna hit OK
now it's going to calibrate drawer open
all right then we'll come back and throw
that ground flour and
all right so we're done calibrating it's
gone back to this normal mode we're
gonna take the unit out
and push down on these two black green
tabs downwards and then it'll rotate up
nicely
cover that little window
and now what we're gonna do
is you want to make sure you're putting
it on a soft surface you're not
scratching that glass on the outside
because that will affect your reading
and now we're going to do is we're going
to fill up
the glass any over spillage or anything
you're just going to push it back down
onto the glass anyway so you don't have
to be too crazy careful
but make sure you're getting
all those look at all that Christy
sitting on the bottom of that buster
yeah so you want to make sure too that
you're getting
all this kind of stuff mixed in
otherwise you're not going to get a
proper test
right you need a proper emulsion
from here what I would do
is I would take something
like a stem or something that's not
going to scratch your screen
and actually mix the butt up a little
bit
because you can tell how many crystals
are sitting on the top
and lightly pack it all down
put our brush out and we're going to get
our brush out to clean up and do a
little
perfect
I mean I like to take the back of the
brush
is kinda
make things a little even in here
and then you're going to take your
little screen your little white
make sure white down
and it will lock into place
what that's going to do
show you here it's going to press all of
it up against the side but you're not
going to only flour up against there
take this unit
again it's magnetic so it'll Place
itself into place
and then we go
analyze
please insert ground flour and take your
picture so we're going to take our
picture
okay we're going to insert our drawer
and we're going to hit the analyze
button
and we'll be back with the numbers
we got the results in but to get the
results you've got to lift the drawer
gotta lift the drawer so we're gonna
take the drawer up
foreign
looks
looks like ground weed right and now
we're gonna hit the result
look at that 20.3 every number is
exactly the same
from ground to the bud
so there we go that was an accurate uh
uh number today I gotta say I'm pretty
happy with those results we tested the
flower twice and what we did this time
is we were OCD we came to a room that no
one's in we removed the table from the
wall because there was vibration on the
wall it's on a concrete floor so there's
no motion we've eliminated the door
opening and blowing wind into the room
there's no music playing we're not
touching the table in any way shape or
form and for the first time I feel like
we're getting accurate numbers 100 so
there it is den and bubble man coming at
you from Embark Health Inc
hope you guys enjoyed this and uh we'll
continue
um to bring you more tests with the
gamma cert uh as we get more flour to uh
to test so thanks a lot everybody peace
out
[Music]