[Music]
boom
all right we're up on the business
Lounge what was your name again
Tim that's right and yeah Dennis and
Dennis so I bumped into Tim and Dennis
yesterday they wanted to show me some
rosin Dennis grew it he washed it he
pressed it and so we're gonna check it
out here real quick
do you want to open that up for me
cheers
and which one is this now this is the
rainbow cake the rainbow cake
beautiful and this is the one I didn't
smell
it
all right and this one is
go see though
nice well we're going to try them out in
the puffco just got the brand new puffco
Peak Pro from the good Folks at puffco
and uh time for a little dab
all right here we go I will need my
Dabber
[Music]
time to try the uh The Works you want to
grab a seat here yeah then you can be in
the video with me uh okay so we wanted
to try the RC this is RC oh yeah oh I
have the lid under here I'm using it
yeah you know the difference so yeah no
problem
yeah
oh my goodness this one still has a dab
in it that didn't get hit
I left uh the Yaki in there from the
full moon session party yesterday so not
very often that I open up my pupco or my
Carta and it's dirty I'm very obsessed
with keeping it extremely clean so let's
hope I brought
my uh
she gets so much stuff in my bag it's
insane ah here we go these will come in
hand did it vibrate
let's see it's too long
okay there we go
yeah once it vibrates you can hit it I
think we both be hitting it to be honest
because I put a lot of them
[Music]
yeah
wow that's nice
it smells like uh almost like Romulan
oh wow
I'm gonna have to hit that too
[Music]
um
Yaki
no no then we'll hit this one I don't
I'd have to ask Lorenzo I bumped into
him earlier but uh
thank you very nice
what a nice event with the outdoor and
the beach area and the pool if you see
me outdoor pool over there yeah
there were lots of people swimming
actually I was surprised yeah
so where are you guys from
in Orlando
[Music]
so that was some
hash from Lorenzo now we're going to try
Dennis's
rainbow King keep forgetting it
I love the rainbow belt those the
rainbow drivers yeah wedding cakes this
should be it should be good where'd you
locate the seeds from just order them
online
[Music]
that's the right spot right
right here we go
this is lovely Dude
Love
three
grown washed and pressed that's the hat
trick the triple threat it's amazing
when you can do all of it you learn so
much about you know how many variables
you have just to grow the Cannabis which
is the most absolutely then you want to
make sure when you wash it you do
everything right and you get everything
off because you don't want to leave
anything behind
and then the pricing you want to make
sure you're not blowing bags you're not
too hot of a temperature you're not
there's so many things to kind of worry
about
that was nice man thank you man yeah
thanks for that track thanks for
tracking me down and just giving me
adapt hey man yeah yeah it's a big big
honor well it's gonna be on Bubble man's
world yeah so it'll be uh it won't just
be a memory you'll be like any time you
want to hear the honor you can be like
let's check out what bubble man said
about my product everything it's good
product every time I feel like that I
watch the video yeah yeah absolutely
it's good to be inspired it's good for
us to inspire one another absolutely
yes you know it's such an enjoyable
thing making growing weed making hash
sharing genetics
smoking with people it's all just gravy
yeah it's awesome
all right well
see you next time
[Music]
thank you