[Music]
boom
hey welcome to Bubble man's world I am
in Berlin Germany today for the Mary
Jane Expo I was here yesterday I was
just so exhausted after the jet lag I
wasn't really able to film but I'm gonna
film as much as I can for you guys today
and uh just a beautiful day it was also
raining really badly yesterday in Berlin
so today it's a much nicer day and we're
gonna get to walking around the Mary
Jane Expo checking out a bunch of
different booths there's really great
people really nice environment there's
also the full moon session going on
which I was at yesterday
um really fun time really beautiful
dinner shout out to Igor and the whole
team at Full Moon session for putting it
together bringing me out to be a judge
for the event and then of course later
on in the week we're going to be doing
the ICBC conference so I'll try to film
as much as I can in the meantime I got a
bolt showing up which is the German
equivalent of uber and uh we're gonna be
rocking and rolling so see you down at
the festival
[Music]
thank you
all right I have hooked up with Mr Dave
auger uh you guys have probably seen
Dave in the videos in the past a friend
from Alberta Calgary Alberta and
actually a partner we're working on a
project in Arizona with the Arizona
malletts we're going to be making bubble
and live hash rosins and all that good
stuff
and Dave's got mushroom licenses he's
got big league genetics he does export
to Germany and some other countries so
he's doing all sorts of things we're
here in Berlin Germany we're on our way
down to the Mary Jane Expo we have
these funky little scooters that we're
riding hey trust these Deeds little
little limers on the trusty steeds
actually Dave is also on a panel with me
at the ICBC conference in about a week
on genetics yeah genetics so that'll be
fun too
um I'm probably not going to be able to
film The Ride on the way to the Mary
Jane Expo but it would be fun if I could
because uh Berlin is a beautiful city
with beautiful buildings you know some
old some new a real mix of architecture
and uh we're all ripped up and bubbled
up it's gonna be great so we're gonna
continue on and we'll see you throughout
the day peace out
[Music]
yes
that's why I don't grab them
[Music]
back
[Applause]
[Music]
and he is
I've already toured the entire place but
I'm now at the business boat here
and uh just gonna go check that out so
if you guys want to join me
mushrooms
the sessions
um
thank you
foreign
yes
thank you
they cry
[Music]
thank you
nice to meet you
complexities
[Music]
in the playlist foreign
try it
again
[Laughter]
signs
[Music]
oh my God
thank you
um
[Music]
exactly
in this countries
[Music]
thank you
yes mate yeah
[Music]
conversations
thank you
[Music]
just a monster event here in Berlin
Germany
thank you
four different buildings indoors
Outdoors people flowing in like hot
cakes
and who do I bump into but my boy Alex
Rogers from ICBC this is two old school
fools you know Ivory White Tower looking
over [ __ ] right now to tell us how sick
the ICBC is in Berlin it's it's sick you
know Mary Jane's amazing it's a it's
great that they both can happen at the
same time because they serve two
different purposes agreed and this is
super like bringing the culture and you
know I and I we support uh cannabis
culture and healing of the nation
culture cool and what ICPC does that too
but we just do it on this like a little
bit next next level totally and we bring
people from about 80 different countries
from all around the world to really
really really really really really get
down in terms of business policy and
activism it definitely looks from the
outside like it's a much more corporate
event but I can say from someone who's
been a lot it's really a nice mix of the
corporate and the culture the Legacy
culture that that kind of just combines
this really nice sort of uber
professional like you're not wasting
your time at an ICBC conference if
you're there to do business you're there
to say export cannabis from Canada
you're going to find people to do that
with if you're looking to sell equipment
for extraction you're going to find
people to do that if you're a consultant
you know whether it's from lighting or
growing or processing you're going to
find people to connect to so uh this is
my first ICBC in Berlin I have been to
Vancouver ones and Barcelona ones and
always had a great time but I'm super
pumped on Berlin dude I ca I came out
really for ICBC
that's an honor bubble you're a [ __ ]
Legend and those are first aid the words
man and you know I probably couldn't
have said it more eloquently myself
that's the work well we're going to get
back to this conference and or this Expo
and we'll see you later on
peace out
[Music]