boom
[Music]
okay we're back at the business Lounge
day three of the Mary Jane Expo I'm here
with my new friend Tim and Dennis and
you remember Dennis was the guy that
grew his own crop washed it in the
bubble bags pressed it in the rosin
press and we smoked it the other day
there was like a dosey doe and there was
uh oh what was the other one RC
which one rainbow cake rainbow cake I
don't know why I can't remember that
name but it seems to be uh so anyway let
me uh go over what we got here these are
the entries for today one through 17
although 16 is missing
and uh let's just do a quick little view
of that with the jars Oak flavors no
exactly you know
number one
number two
number three
number four
number five
number six
number seven
number eight
coming down to number nine
number ten
number eleven
number twelve
thirteen fourteen
[Music]
fifteen
and then number 17 but I guess it's
number 16 so
[Music]
there it is
in a nutshell one two three four five
six seven eight and nine ten eleven
twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen
16.
let the judging begin
[Music]
here we go
i've smoked about seven to eight of the
different kinds I just realized my
camera's dying I don't know if I left it
on or it didn't turn off accidentally
but my battery on this is done so I'll
have to figure this out and hopefully we
get more footage for you guys maybe on
the iPhone so continued