[Music]
do
all right so you guys are in luck you're
gonna get
that last scene that i spoke about
uh just headed over to merlin's
of course brixton's here as well hello
hello
hello yes look you're a star look at you
look at you okay
back to the food so tell me uh what
you're prepping here bud i'm gonna make
some tagatella homemade homemade wider
noodles with uh
some wild mushrooms and sage butter from
the garden oh my god he's got his pasta
maker out he's got his fresh ball of
pasta here ready to go yeah dude it's a
nice silky pasta
that looks beautiful yeah a little mix
of semolina flour and regular double
zero flour
that's the ticket
lots of flour so it doesn't stick
together i love it sorry
move over here
boom
and you got some other prep over here
done
onions and garlic onions and garlic and
farm and shrooms dude how fun was that
picking shrooms amazing and all this
fresh sage from the garden too
oh fresh sage
harm like you said
i brought a flat bread with a ball of
fresh mozzarella cheese and i don't know
if you have sauce but i actually brought
some sauce too i figured we could do a
little starter flatbread
yeah in the oven some
some of the mushrooms some mozzarella
you know a little bit of garlic a little
bit of sauce
well i think what we're going to do is
we'll fry all these mushrooms with the
onion and the garlic keep them on the
side and then mix it with all the pasta
with the sage butter is ready i love it
i'm thinking a similar thing for the
pizza like i think i would fry i think
that's what we're gonna do fry the
mushrooms up with some garlic and butter
this and this all together we'll
separate some a little bit of that can
go on top of the pizza even in the last
like two minutes of baking it yeah let
it melt into the cheese it's so good
yeah i'm excited good lunch
oh my god
all right
this is great
just chilling out making pasta we should
do some dabs we are going to do some
dabs you ready for me to serve you up a
dab now that you're home yeah let's do
it all right
eating all my rigs this morning dude oh
nice i clean mine every single time i
take a dab i have a disease
[Laughter]
we love it though making a big meal is
great but what happens is you rush to
get timing for everything ready at the
exact same time
and then everyone stuffs themselves for
15 minutes and dinner's over
so the courses are nice aren't they i
like it it adds to a dinner like when
you're with friends you know you spend a
few hours eating and drinking instead of
just eating clean done
oh it's so nice man
i'm getting hungry just looking at it
nice portions too how many portions are
making uh i think it'll be enough for
the three of us beautiful
is that kim yeah awesome
maybe we'll give the ac guy some of his
nice
all right merlin just came down to grab
some thyme
boom that's awesome
you gotta love having a little herb
garden don't you that's too stepping
into that
hey brixton
need brixton
i'm brixton want to play wanna jump i
want to play want to
yeah jump okay let's go do food come on
let's go food food you'll learn
nothing's more important than food
little guy
he still thinks fun's more important
than food yeah not yet
all right the chef has spoken he said
dabs it is
and today he he's hitting gaps yeah i
like that you were smoking joints the
other day that was kind of nice
it's a lot of a responsibility even now
i'll be honest it's nice that you have
your own rig there's a big
responsibility that goes into dabbing
out all your friends totally and to me
it's not about dabbing the beautiful
hard to get hash it's the rig and
cleaning it all work into it
all day long the other night you sat
there cleaning the bong for like an hour
four people were puffing yeah
all right well
you're going in for some cold starts
he's got some strawberry banana in there
i'll get some strawberry banana going
too
that's the other way to get it off to
stick to the dabber oh that's a good
idea
just right breaking this all up look at
what a mess i'm making this stuff is
like
hard
oh man that tastes good
oh man
i'll get you prepped i'll be your sous
chef today
just tell me what to do oh yeah
we're cleaning dishes
serving
[Music]
yeah exactly
that's pretty nice of them
it was
i'm always shouting out everyone for all
of this stuff
gets a little crazy
you want to find out what temperature
you brought that too yeah you're sitting
at 500 right now which is a pretty good
cold
like cool
temp
oh about to get litty lit
well this could possibly be the first of
many shows we're gonna try it out see
how you guys like it see how much you
like
cooking with merlin cooking and dabbing
dabbing yeah because if you do
we've got more than a few episodes of
our sleeves
oops
oh my goodness
just tasty tasty goodness
kobet friendly
puffin our own rigs
that being said we're also in the same
circle yeah
no
here
that'll help with that if you heat it up
a bit first with the torch yeah and then
pour that in it'll melt it and pull it
off but it's going to put it all on the
sides of the wall so i usually just have
one of these that i just sit right there
as it's doing it
like you don't know how to clean the
banger
giving him a mansplaining to merlin how
to clean the banger
see
men do it to each other too oh it's our
oh my goodness this is not something we
just do to females my apologies to all
the females i've ever done it too
it's a disease i'm trying to break
myself of it i just told my girl that
she had to clean the banger properly
you were mansplaining yet i was
kim's cool
kim would never take that the wrong way
no
all right
tasty tasty treats
you know dabs are similar to a
multi-course meal you know instead of
having what would really be a session
where you're smoking joints and haunted
stuff afterwards yeah yeah yeah you have
like a dab yeah and then you're like no
we'll try this one for a little bit yeah
please do
that will come onto the uh come off onto
your dabber really nicely it's still got
a nice uh texture it's gonna butter out
soon though
oh yeah that's a nice texture yeah it'll
pull out nice that's for sure
kind of pulling snappy
okay
excellent another little cold start for
you yeah
here i'll get the rest off for you
joint smoker
you got some in there yeah i did
i don't like to do big dabs anyway
well
i like your style
a bunch of small dab is better than one
big one that hurts your legs forever
yeah i'm pretty consistent i don't know
if what i i don't know if what i hit is
small because most i certainly don't
think this is big either but it's not
something i give to people that don't
dab a lot
you know because even what you put in
there it was a very very little bit but
look how much it turned into when it
when it expanded
exactly and it i just like little puffs
like that that just tastes super good
i'd rather do it that's not like sheer
terps yeah
with the carb cap on the cold start it
really stays all those volatile stains
oh yeah well you're getting first just
the volatiles you're getting tur pits
and then you're kind of finishing it off
towards the end it won't have near the
flavor but that's where all the strength
will lie
i like cold starting but i do prefer
just hitting it from the start to finish
if i can get it in one or two small
poles
that being said
i mean there's nothing tastier than just
hitting the turf
starving you know what i mean yeah it's
always that first hit that's like that
person off the joint oh my god i always
called it the king's hit or the queen's
hit
you know because that was like man could
you imagine if the only hits you took
were those always tasted like you're
just like i'm the queen king of england
england
i'm smoking only first starts
essentially that's how dabs are though
compared to joints you know like a joint
for the in comparison the amount of
totes that you get you get that first
two or three tasty ones and then after
that it's like it's good but dude and i
can even still hear people like arguing
with us in the comments right now
because i do remember when i was younger
at least thinking
that some of that [ __ ] tasted good right
down until it was burning my fingers but
you were lying to yourself i might have
been yeah i might i must have been i've
said that's interesting cognitive
dissonance is definitely interesting and
how it creates in
our reality the one we experience at
least remember the guy in high school
that was always like i like the taste of
roaches
i had a roach collection that was like
several pounds towards the end and i
remember i gave it away through a friend
that ended up giving it
i can't remember who got it but they
said that those roaches lasted them and
the person who got it was
you know someone who loved cannabis but
didn't have a lot of money to spend on
cannabis
and because i was going to throw it away
no they were huge fat crazy hazes and
all like special like
they might have looked like garbage to
most people but that person
really appreciated it and i remember
them saying like i got two christmases
out of it
it's like celebration like they were
celebrating like bubble beds all men's
roads yeah well and that's from the day
exactly it was like 97 98 and then by 99
hit
i was just puffing only bubble yeah once
i could make this stuff i was like are
you kidding me i've met you probably
about four four years five years ago now
something like that four years ago yeah
and i haven't seen you smokey joint ever
we'll smoke a hazel yeah there you go
i made a funny um meme of myself on the
guy's body that leads the interesting
life you know the coors guy or whatever
he's like i may not always
i was like i don't always smoke joints
but when i do they're pure hats
you know that is a good it's the same or
whatever like the world's most
interesting the world's most interesting
man thank you i knew you knew
you know
all right well listen i'm appropriately
baked i might have one more rip here in
a second but uh we're gonna go make this
food because really this whole video
has been about the inspiration of the
last scene of putting the plates down
and showing you what can be done
and you can see how we did it it was
very fun we got to take brixton for a
walk we got to explore the forest we got
to discover new mushrooms
um and now we're going to eat eat them
and enjoy them so
satisfying would you catch yeah let's do
it the vegetarian way to eat what you
catch yeah
forage all right so merlin has prepared
pretty much everything here he's just
kind of doing some finishing touches and
he's kind of gonna walk us through how
he's gonna prepare
this dish and i'm just going to be the
cameraman and the voice behind the
camera there you go
cast iron pan
hot
preheat it nice start with the onions
get them caramelized a little
a little olive oil there
you just want to make them translucent
[Music]
nice
so the other day we were driving and you
told me your favorite line from the
sopranos that you finally kind of got it
yeah the best the best line is from in
sopranos is tony when he says
christopher you'll understand the
importance of good produce and when you
get older and it's the best line out of
the entire
series in my opinion
that's awesome
pepper up those efforts yeah
all right those are getting close
now next step is we'll turn our water on
get our pasta boiling we've got our
tagatelli there
and then our pizza as well what's that
he's feeling we're filming
come say hi
don't be sorry
so now we'll get the mushrooms
oh yeah
about uh
60 dollars worth of mushrooms
that's awesome
you have one other kind right here too
these are the yellow mushrooms all right
all right so we'll just slice these ones
up
what's that
uh i film with this uh panasonic
this little 4k unit
here
[Music]
yeah we're filming for the channel right
now we're just uh merlin's walking us
through uh the homemade pasta with the
mushroom
how beautiful sauce looks yeah it looks
really nice
now once the mushrooms are in you don't
want to move them much you want to get
the water to
to stay inside the mushroom rather than
get the whole pan super soggy
and put your garlic on after
so once they're mixed in don't move them
for until they sear in
all right
there's a time
oh no you're running out of time
he's like don't worry i'm growing it in
a plant out back
you got one of those time plants
let that sit
this is coming along salt your water
that tastes like the seed
we'll do this bread too we'll create a
bit of cheese for it
i'm gonna make a mushroom sauce for this
flatbread yeah and then this is
mozzarella
at this point you can see the water kind
of bubbling out of there you really want
to get all that moisture out of the
mushrooms so that they can caramelize
yeah it's steaming nicely look it's
steamed at the front of the camera it's
awesome
did i clean it well not really and then
for the towel i guess we'll just get
that um
yeah you got the water boiling got a
little salt in there oh yeah lots of
salt it tastes like the sea
i'm gonna get the tagatell in there
this is gonna be super quick and then
we'll cool it down to stop it from
cooking
what's super quick like three four
minutes yeah at the moment
two three yeah
you're one really nice heat and not
really move them you want them to stay
like that it's definitely steaming less
yeah well you can see it bubbling out
here
and that's just the flavor getting back
into the mushrooms
you almost want to see like onions
starting to caramelize
before you start turning it
all right she's going oh i'm steaming
her up again
trying to get this food
so here we go pasta just came out of the
pot that was about three minutes
yeah
and these are still going hard
and the onions are starting to
caramelize and there's a lot well
there's almost no more water um
bubbling but definitely certainly there
is moisture coming off of the mushrooms
you really want to cool these noodle
boxes yeah
oh yeah so they're not still cooking in
themselves exactly
now you're ready to take that around
well you know as much as i saw that as a
first turn it really looked like a
second or a third time
first turns now we hit a little bit of
pepper
pepidepa
this is all looking quite well
mm-hmm
chop up a bit of garlic
this one for the pizza
a bit of ricotta
well you've got some ricotta
some garlic
that's great
bit of parm
parmesan
we're doing this up well by we i mean
you
at a time
[Music]
boom salt and pepper
so you put parm in there
garlic thyme olive oil
and little bit of salt and pepper
okay okay
just get that all in there nice
that's going to be our sauce yeah
[Music]
those delicious mushrooms
now our mushrooms are almost ready here
oh yeah
now they've got some nice caramel on
them
[Music]
these are pretty much done
here we go
[Music]
we'll take all the flavor that's from in
this pan and we'll start making our safe
butter sauce for the pasta ah
and there'll be a lot of that flavor in
the pan won't there
[Music]
that's pretty much why you like cast
iron
yeah and it's also consistency of heat
is the key to it
since it's kind of like a sage butter
tangerine some gin has a little piney
flavor
get all that flavor up from the
mushrooms
[Music]
well maybe we'll let this uh
melt up
just mix up with all that flavor on the
bottom
like the gin and the
butter and the mushroom
remnants
like heat on here
that smells so good it looks good
and it's only got like two sage leaves
in it
well then once we put all these in what
happens is these are going to pull out
all the
all that incredible flavor
but they also crisp up and turn into
sage leaf chips which are all right i
love them
the best yeah
candied sage leaf buttered
buttered to perfection
so i'm just gonna let this go
what's that
a pizza it's a flapper that looks really
nice
yeah we've got some pizza cheese on
there
not too much cheese
less is better
on pizzas it's not that
it's not dominoes
there we go
um we'll heat up the pan too
best practices
making pizza
in an oven
preheat your pan
and we get crispy dough
very good advice yeah
500 degrees get in there for a good 5-10
minutes heat it up and then just slide
your pizza in on some parchment paper
a little garlic in there as
well this is looking pretty nice you
threw a clove of garlic in there oh yeah
a little extra flavor
oh yeah did you break that or anything
yeah just crushed it okay yeah i figured
now we're almost turning this to
clarified butter as you can see all that
foam coming off that's all the lactose
essentially if you cook butter down
enough and keep taping taking that foam
off it becomes ghee yes
but flavor is starting to happen you
want your butter to be like a brown
butter right
[Music]
we call it a
iron bar noise that's beautiful no barn
was that how bomb was that
in a fancy place barbell and some places
too like it's nice
and noise because it always it gets a
little hazelnut flavor when you burn
another
the pizza
a little nice amount of little olive oil
on the side crisp it up
concentrates the heat on those tips and
gives them a little darkening huh yeah
it gets nice and crispy too
drizzles
[Music]
a little bit of salt and pepper
and that's hot enough
here we go
watch you a little thanks if you can the
key don't lose heat in that oven making
pizza yeah
that's about done huh pretty close
one a little crispier
i want to take the sage out
it's delicate at this point i'm guessing
yeah it's pretty much chips
so
[Music]
oh they're just hiding in there aren't
they
if you can see the color of the butter
it's nice and brown
that's perfect leave those nice chunks
of garlic here it'll be a little extra
you're gonna dose the pasta with that
now we take our pasta
get it right in there
[Music]
the butter
the sage
the garlic
that's all getting up in there
oh man you can smell those terps yeah
pine turf say hardcore
[Music]
i think that's why i like sage so much
as it's piming and so strong it like
almost like wakes you up
like taking a bite out of a pine tree
now we'll let those fry up for a second
warm up
[Music]
get our shrooms in there
oh
yeah
now bring up the sage piney buttery
sage flavor
into all of this
it's the flavor of the woods i still
didn't think of it
it is the flavor of the woods
[Music]
very blessed very good
save a few on the side for plating
and everything else
jeez louise does that smell good
you know i'm most impressed at
how much
you're keeping in the pan
you're like over filling that pan but
you're you have a good control good food
control
[Music]
two times not spilling stuff it helps
for sure the palm added on to the
pasta
i like how you want to evenly distribute
and homogenize each ingredient
yeah it's the way i'm cooking them
separately to keep their flavors intact
like you never want to
mix up mushrooms with everything so you
lose the flavor
that's the key
now
to do a plating did you say it yeah
a little bit of parsley to finish this
whole thing off
nice plates yeah they're gorgeous though
yeah
i feel like stone almost it's ceramic
actually
wow it's a great uh texture
all right so you create a little
parsley
a little dressing keep that for the
garnish a little garnish
oh my goodness i was like i don't
remember you cutting any that were that
long
[Laughter]
that was ridiculous
wow
nice very nice nice sized serving you
know yeah
like more
this is the mushrooms plate
after all it is isn't it
oh that was nice the way the mushrooms
dropped into the bottom for you
[Music]
it was like the chef's plate right
there you go
[Music]
i want to pick the shrooms out from the
bottom
[Music]
because they're also good yes
a couple of nice plates right there
yeah
oh my god did that thing unload
all the
the shrooms shrubs
let's go look at those under the uh
sunlight
yeah wait we're gonna hit it with a bit
of parmesan oh nice
of course we are
as in you are
the
parsley
wiping the bowl up a little bit
[Music]
there you go
and also the last thing i'm
sorry some more fresh puppy
one last little pepe or something
oh dude i'm in the way there we go
that is absolutely stunning bro
let's eat it let's do it
okay so we kind of forgot about the
pizza
but you know what i don't think it's too
bad i'm going to try some
i want to try something
that was funny
all right we're just about to sit down
the beautiful pasta
was just spectacular i can't believe
what a great job he did on that wow
we're we're gonna take our first bites
on camera and then we're gonna leave you
uh and here's the flatbread as well
that came out looking just perfect
really nice mushrooms melted right in
there
[Music]
let's see chef's first bites
roll those noodles
roll them up
tasty tasty
i'll do the same thing take my first
bite on camera it looks absolutely
beautiful man
like this is some some some styley pasta
hmm
really nice
that parmesan is um
nice and salty
[Music]
there are so many flavors going off on
that
coating my lips that that sage butter
wow
[Music]
i hope this video was inspirational i
want to thank merlin for the exceptional
work
let's do more of these bud mm-hmm
another time for sure we'll do something
else
awesome all right we'll see say goodbye
to everyone and pull us out of this show
thanks for watching
peace
[Music]
[Applause]
my
me
[Music]
[Applause]
ah
[Music]
you