[Music]
all right
i'm in you're in everyone's in
welcome to bubble man's world everybody
we got a big crew to introduce you today
for our cooking with merlin episode six
episode six episode six so i'll get
right to it we got some folks in from my
hometown you guys are winnipeggers right
yes i am uh
introduce yourselves guys to the
audience i mean i'm sure
the cannabis community probably knows
you and your battle that you've got
going on right now but yeah give a
little introduction
you want to start simon or should i lead
her oh you go ahead all right hey
everybody this is the overgrown team we
got the tech wizard camera wizard
control wizard um
we've been launched uh we launched a
lawsuit against the manitoba government
a year and a half ago
[Applause]
that's a standing ovation
can you say that one more time oh it's
just it's so nice to say we launched we
launched a lawsuit against the manitoba
government a year and a half ago
beautiful we uh we also got joe asked to
join the quebec lawsuit so we're
fighting uh two provincial governments
at once
and uh these are my these are my boys
who are helping out in the background
and doing a big difference so aaron yeah
so i've done a lot of the photos and
videos and different marketing
strategies and stuff like that and
lately we've been making lots of videos
just like hilarious [ __ ] try to get
comedic with it so awesome lighting the
vibe right yeah man that's exactly it
and simon i know you we go back a little
ways not super far but yeah you're doing
your i'm just helping them on the tech
side of it right i don't know what i can
and can so i'm just he's
he's understating his health yeah
[Laughter]
that's awesome
well cool i'm super glad to have you
guys all in here i saw you guys were uh
raging with remo the other day that must
have been fun
that was intense yeah i think all three
of us were the highest we've ever ever
yeah i think i'll play with you yes
last week cooking was was an episode
he couldn't smoke the joints fast enough
so we also just raged hard with with
ramo so it was great to see you guys in
that zone i was like oh we're going to
have all sorts of things to talk about
just in regards to
the raging that we all did with with
ramo and for those of you that obviously
haven't hung out with rainbow but have
watched his videos you still know
rima loves to go hard he is a true
cannabis warrior i would say
you know a true cannabis warrior a
cannabis aficionado a true lover of the
plant on every level and i'm pretty
stoked that uh these guys brought me the
mega stoner super high album
which is ramos new
i guess kind of metal yeah battle band
this is his new metal band briston's
aren't all over you hey
yeah
just so everyone knows there's a little
velociraptor
come here
chewing on you guys
it's so cute that's awesome
well yeah we're going to cook some food
today you guys want to tell them you
want to tell them merlin what to do
well it's a rainy day so i thought we'd
do a soup we're going to do some spring
rolls and some ramen beautiful yeah
that's awesome
on a cold rainy day and the
winter is coming it's dumping up and
whistling so oh yeah major dumping it's
been raining here like crazy in fact
i did get my drone resorted it was kind
of down the battery died on my um
phantom 4.
um so i've got that battery replaced and
every day that we filmed this for the
last like two or three cooking with
merlin's i've thought if the rain ends
i'll shoot the drone out for a little
visual because
part of this episode in my opinion
that's the magic is is the view and
today it's not really there you can't
even see the mountains it's just some
trees and some
some fog but it is pretty beautiful uh
when you can see it so eventually we're
gonna get that drone up there and we'll
get some drone footage cut into these
videos but in the meantime
quick little sessions smoke some joints
light some bowls um get iri and then get
into the kitchen today merlin has a lot
of sous chefs you're going to be on the
camera
right um i can cook something i'm going
to be doing no i mean for your own like
okay we'll get some stuff yeah and then
so you guys are probably going to be in
sous chef position from uh although i'm
guessing rome's probably gonna need one
of you to do to serve him dabs and
joints yeah so probably one of them will
get that job right that's simon's normal
job but he's in my table as well he put
remo to work the other day and it took
him only about 10 minutes to realize
maybe i should get rimo to be rolling
joints
yeah
it really was a good idea it was a good
move he was doing great
it was definitely not a shot against
remo he did great in the work that he
was doing but when he said that what was
his quote i can burn water
when he said that i i felt a little bit
of the confidence uh he wrote out
his soul
so we put him on joy switch this guy out
when i'm sitting beside merlin that i do
the best i can to stay out of his way
right it moves on fire yeah it moves
like fire did you try holding a camera
on the guy you couldn't imagine but i'm
telling you the wide lens helps because
if i had the normal camera lens that
this camera has i'd have to like stand
in the back corner uh over by the
skateboard deck that some of you have
noticed maybe people see if any of you
others notice the skateboard deck this
episode in the meantime it's time for a
dab
if anyone can see this stuff is
ridiculous what is this marcus that is
some forum cut
cookies from ethos it is white and it's
actually was produced and grown by
concentrated x in ontario so shout out
to concentrated x
for keeping me in stash
hopefully with the work that i've signed
up for with merlin and his company
hopefully this year we're going to get
that bubble man brand out to you guys
and we'll have some products that are
deserving to be on the brand such a
difficult thing to create exceptional
quality products
in the regulatory framework it really is
a challenge a lot of work a lot of
hurdles but we're there we're gonna do
it it still beats having a gun put in
your face and having your kids taken
away in your dog shot in my opinion it's
not much stress to be honest comparing
the
in the space no
exactly
about it yeah he brexit is give
everybody excited about it
thank you sir
film or rising film evaporators nope
no well this is kind of what that's
based on it's based on pulling the resin
up into this part of the not letting the
dab just be taken on the pan but getting
it pulled into this little tube that's
also heated up
and then the little marble inside is
just moving it around to make sure that
it's painting and touching as much of
that surface area as possible this is to
reduce uh oxygen as well as this so it
makes it that tighter little pull yeah
you know shout out to nephilim glass
because basically i'm not a dad i've
never done that
you can pull it off
and the turf slurper really only works
with these three components so
i kind of needed to get that and luckily
for me the
nephilim glass lined me up
did you get one
oh my goodness
full
dunk let's taste this is this something
you passed around
hey watch out for pickle wreck
that is a pickle rick uh carburetor cap
i'm not gonna
i'm not gonna lie
what temperature did you hit that at or
do you not know just cold started it was
a cold start yeah i love to know my
temperature wow so i have a little
thermometer that gives me an accurate
readout on how hot my banger is i could
imagine it would be oh was it
it's now it's like 350.
i had it pretty low though i did like
eight seconds
that's i think that's like the fourth
time in my life the next time you do
this
well it sounds like you got a good one
it tasted wonderful yeah
awesome lemony
wow
well i'm one and done
you guys want one yes please
love your dog he loves you
look at that it's boiling let's just
check it out yeah where's it at
320 398 400 degrees
you know it seems ridiculous but if you
dab a lot knowing the temperature of the
banger
and the amount of time that you heat it
up you ready to see some groupings it
changes from banger to banger depending
on the thickness the type of material
that it's made out of so what's the what
type of what are we aiming for well
everyone's different okay so like for
instance people that really like
if you want to take the rocket ship to
the moon a warmer or hotter temperature
will get you there
um anyone that's accidentally taking a
hot dab knows that
exactly but that didn't seem too hot
no that was a low time no i just i'm
just we're just total rookies well or
here's the question
do you smoke cigarettes
do you smoke cigarettes i haven't i
haven't i have you recently that's what
i mean
i normally have stopped today yeah
yeah cigarettes can have an effect on
your lungs for certain right all right
okay that makes sense because um
i mean soaking a good dab
they can get you coughing whether you're
super hot oh my god dude
oh
all right well we're gonna get in here
as you can see we're all baked and uh
off on our own tangent so we're gonna
get into the kitchen make some food and
uh
enjoy this high yeah and then eat the
food right awesome
all right we're here with merlin let's
see if he's gonna his intro will be as
stoney as the last episode yeah it was
we were pretty baked last time i don't
think that we can top that one but uh
today we'll try and put together some we
can top it the next time we have remo we
definitely can
so we got the guys from toba grown here
as well awesome
chef with us absolutely
we're gonna make some ramen and some
spring rolls with a peanut butter sauce
so
jesse you're going to help me out here
we'll do the sprinkles i'll do the first
one and then show you exactly what to do
and then you can roll the rest i get
some gloves off yeah sure it's like kind
of like rolling duties to be honest
it's kind of like rolling deepies it is
are you saying you don't have good dewy
rolls
skills i'll try to put it into a
vaporizer and you'll go with that oh
nice is that how you hit more often than
not so the rice paper or so now okay
just put it into a plate with some water
oh [ __ ] rice paper into a plate with
some water totally just lettuce just let
it soak for a second all right
and then we'll get yours going once you
get your gloves on we have everything
prepared pretty much here already we got
some cilantro some sprouts some red
pepper cucumber
some cooked uh tofu with ginger and
soy sauce and garlic
that's gonna be good with the carrots
and a bit of uh
avocado some chives
so you don't want to go too long or
these things get uh
some backstory merlin and i used to work
together i actually lived in this house
for about four or five nights right when
i moved in yeah right when you moved in
it's true and there's lots of weed smoke
then too at the same time we'll get it
going for the ramen will you get the
onions with the
onion yeah
look at these these creeps over here get
them in the shot hey what's going on
over here guys
what's going on
[Music]
he's got good art right now checking all
the decks out yeah yeah yeah did you
check that one out up there
way back when you come back so cool you
want to put another one in there yeah
i'm on it
and then i'll show you how to do this so
you're just hydrating these
rice paper hydrating a little bit then
we get a little bit of carrot in there
that's just subway style subway style
exactly
a little bit of avocado
you taking this down jesse or what yeah
mentally a little bit of onions
simon knows how good i roll
a little bit there you go
a little bit of cucumber in there
sides there to wrap it up it's the name
of my uh contracting
and just
tuck it in just like your doobies
tuck it in just like your two pieces
there you go
oh
prepare to be missed
perfect spring roll
you try one there too prepare to be
amazed you know this stuff you got some
eggs over here you got some yummies yeah
we got all the noodles ready
some tofu will reheat i had already done
and while we're doing that let's get
this broth going this is the most
important part of the ramen
oh yes the ramen broth exactly
favorite ramen spot in vancouver
gingerbread junior oh jinya's baller
yeah a little bit of grapeseed oil in
there big fan of the uh
[Music]
some ginger to start it out this is
awesome
strong strong start in the background
there just keep the camera over there
what's happening over there we're good
we're good that's going good
all right let's put a ginger oh yeah
it'll
flavor up that oil really nice the
grapeseed oil
smells so good oh my goodness yeah
big fan of the ginger myself so you got
a little garlic in there too
yeah it's like a mix vapor rub when you
put the ginger in there right oh yeah
oh the onions come too let's turn that
heat up
we're gonna we're gonna do onions and
mushrooms for inside the
ramen soup
yeah
almond soup
oh my gosh yes perfection
so uh tobogram was started in april 2020
so this april will be two years
it's a
lawsuit against the manitoba
government's ban on homegrown cannabis
i remember when the ban first came into
place in 2018
i was working for with merlin at the
time
and
really really annoyed me but i wasn't at
the time personally affected by it
because i didn't have a place where i
could grow and was traveling for work
but when kovid came around
and our governments instructed us to
find
[Music]
creative and constructive
projects to work on during lockdown
i
started researching how i could launch
this lawsuit and
went shopping for lawyers and
launched the initial lawsuit in august
after about
four and a half months of diligence and
um
shopping through lawyers
which was a lot of fun in itself and do
you want to tell us who you ended up
with yeah we started with mlt aikens
they
they're massive firm across western
canada and
they
built a very strong foundation and a lot
of research in what we were doing i then
transitioned to
daniel trenipinsky which is a smaller
single lawyer just to control the the
legal bills because obviously the big
firm you pay more it was just us
initially uh funding this
and yeah it's um
it's been a learning curve and a half
and i'm really happy with the amount of
community support we have behind it
dude talk about being a local hero when
that lawsuit goes through and you win
the rights for all manitoba's manitobans
to grow
in their plans yeah that's going to be
different dude that's a right that we
all earned here that it should have
happened in legalization and you're you
know it's the last bit of activism left
onto the cannabis market i'd say the
last fight and the the premier who is
recently
appointed in manitoba is actually the
one who wrote the ban and she's publicly
stated she will defend it so
looking like it'll be a fight till the
end which probably is a year and a half
from now until oh my god she's so on the
wrong side of history and she doesn't
even know it your next fight should be
to not tax us to death
manitoba is actually the best tax in
canada as far as excise but the rest of
the country we get slaughtered
damn well that's crazy man that's great
to hear and so where can people go and
read about this and support this
so simon actually he met earlier he's
built an awesome website like
toborgrown.ca.com
uh we're on all the social media
platform forums under toba grown until
the groan aaron's done some amazing uh
footage for us you see a lot of the
funny videos and high quality stuff next
to that guy right there that's awesome
and we got some team members who aren't
here but who are drooling over the
footage watching us eat this delicious
food
and full disclosure i'm 11 out of 10
baked right now uh
cooking cooking foods that's how it's
cheap
that's what's up that's how we do it
here on uh getting baked with merlin i
mean getting cooked with merlin i mean
cooking with merlin i mean merlin's
cooked i like we should switch it to
getting cooked with merlin
yeah that might have to be it you are
you are there's there goes the mushrooms
we put some shiitake mushrooms in there
oh yeah we're just gonna level them out
let them grill get that water out make
sure it seals in
beautiful see only on cooking with
merlin can you go from like a full-blown
federal lawsuit to why we put the
mushrooms in with the onions and how
they're going to affect the broth
that's uh a little bit of that soup
and we're back to federal lawsuit
exactly
well man everyone i mean marcus you're
from you're from manitoba and like did
you tell me you were start you started
the first activism for hemp in manitoba
well we were we were the yeah in
manitoba we were probably the first and
it was just like it was like martin and
alex and neil and john
these guys were all kind of the core
group but then there were other people
from the university of manitoba who
started a hemp group that were a part of
it and other activists that came into
play like you know paul de feliz and and
alan middlemess from nelson from the
kootenays the holy smokes guys
so lots of people were a part of it for
sure but yeah
i feel lucky enough to be able to say
that we got that license for that first
five acre experimental field in 1995 and
driving my volkswagen van through that
hemp field
was uh
in a way it was the first cannabis
activism in manitoba really
yeah i mean i don't know there might
have been people in the 70s and the 60s
because that i would have missed that
boat and not been you know like i
remember the rock shop used to sell
pipes and kind of like different kind of
weed positive things which i guess in a
sense during prohibition that would
still be part of it kind of a bit of
activism you know where you're like hey
you know we're selling stuff to slow
cannabis but exactly
exactly what i'm putting in here is some
red miso paste oh beautiful organic miso
yeah it's delicious red type i love this
stuff beautiful we're
[Music]
i'll remember to add the recipe for last
week's too as well i'm also going to add
in a little bit of dashi paste that i
got dashi paste yeah
oh you guys are on a mission i was going
to give you a job
i'm totally joking i was totally joking
i heard you guys conversations
go get your coronas but not the
corona the coronas
so it's similar to miso
it is miso actually it's just another
one
looks good looks good
[Music]
oh there's like these you mean they're
not rice aren't carrots oh oh we'll have
to grate up some more how many you got
done there you have four done i'll have
four done okay
i guess we'll have to straight up some
more carrots here
grate them up as this heats up
this should start to
kind of turn into a broth a little bit
can you guess which one is not mine
you know what no they all look pretty
darn good man
[Laughter]
i know you know what i bet you you did
it better than i could have let's find
out
why you want me to roll that one don't
uh
roll the next one
okay oh i forgot
i forgot the most important part
just think of this as your lawsuit
yeah you're rolling up yourself
you just have to focus on it and make
sure you execute
and then everyone can smoke weed
everywhere that they grew in their
backyard
dude and winnipeggers will
[Music]
yeah they do it anyway of course quebec
did that
that's that one's for you simon
i mean they may have turned the law
around in quebec but quebecers act like
it's still it's still in place right
like four planets is still loud of
course it is of course it is
right how could it not be i've been
doing it since 1976 exactly i mean it's
400 not four but
that's the good old quebecois mentality
someone else want to help me out simon's
jumping in look at this guy he's got it
in he's ready to go yeah okay i need you
to cry i almost took his shirt off crack
the eggs crack the eggs yeah you want to
get the skins up all right
i like my eggs with shells right looks
good
i just like my eggshells without egg
can you uh can you do that just use egg
shells for just egg shells on yours
that'd be delicious
and then i guess we'll make the peanut
sauce while we're waiting for these to
finish you gonna do a little uh dash of
uh cilantro
a little dash cilantro bay
yeah sure and you can you'll have to
wash them off after anyway so
[Music]
for the peanut sauce we will do peanut
butter of course
yes just two petals
a couple spoons of that in there
yep that looks pretty good
yeah that looks good
and then some coconut milk
oh [ __ ] voila
now we're going to put a little bit of
soy sauce in there have the soy sauce in
there
a little bit of sriracha
give it a little bite
a little bit of garlic
now a little bit of lime juice
looking good yeah and then
we're gonna put a little bit of this as
well and which one's that now a little
bit of sesame oil just a little shot of
a little cesare of miso as well can be
pretty tasty in there
while we're doing it all right
yeah
almost held back almost held back i
thought twice about it because miso is
super salty but i'm not going to put any
salt in here i'm just going to place it
with the music i think it'll kind of fit
with the dish
a little ginge
with the spoon tack again
spoon tech
just
line that up with the sauce as well or
what yeah exactly we're going to lime in
here as well yeah we put a little bit of
lime already in there yeah
[Laughter]
i think we need a vitamix sponsor
i'll hit him up
those are good units
oh yeah
looking good looking good
it's really yummy it is tasty huh oh
it's yummy
peanut butter ginger goodness spring
rolls right
oh my gosh
mushrooms are looking proper proper
mushrooms your miso broth is looking
proper too also it's coming so now let's
spice up this miso broth i'm going to
put a little bit of ponzu sauce in there
beautiful
a little bit of
which is pretty much soy sauce
salty goodness salty deliciousness
a little bit of rice wine vinegar oh
rice wine vinegar not too much
and then a little bit of sesame oil in
here
oh this thing's coming out
nice
dash of that a lot of flavor
[Music]
vegan on this soup with a little bit of
pea
pea powered milk all right give it the
creaminess right mm-hmm
clean it up a little bit yeah
how'd that have the egg mission go
perfect we're ready to go on that so as
soon as this uh broth is up and boiling
we'll put all the parts together and
we'll get it done
all right making some uh
some portions yeah some portions out of
the bottles for the ramen noodle
beautiful
make sure simon gets that one simon gets
that which one yes and then
we'll just heat these up heat them up
real quick i had already pre-fried them
before let's just get a little extra a
little bit crisp on them before and then
my noodles here that are tofu noodles
oh the tofu noodles
for the gluten-free people out there for
the gluten-free people
very considerate we're pretty much good
there let's do
the uh get the broccoli in the in the
broth
it's boiling your broccoli in the broth
so that they cook into the broth and
soak up all the flavor
[Music]
and then we'll pour the hot broth into
the cooked noodles after [ __ ] yeah
i'm going to do the buck toy in there
too
i wouldn't be against it yeah broccoli
and bok choy it's going to make more
flakes it's going to make more
flavor whole
it already looks better i'll be honest
there you go
it's going to be delicious so good yeah
all these are heating right here
how did your your spring roll mission go
went good
let's
plate the spring rolls while this is
cooking real quick here this shouldn't
take too long you know you kind of want
to keep the crisp
this is going here
uh you can put it in the fridge if you
like
time to plate
these plates sprinkles
every good kitchen there's some good
knives
oh yeah these are looking good yeah
this one's pretty bad at us too
oh yeah
i need to get rid of it
that was a good save that was a really
good save because that is what happens
in a stoner kitchen
these are not the tightest roll joints
over here jesse i have to admit yeah
yeah yeah dog's like yeah lunch
i'm all about air pockets good flow good
flow
these have incredible flow
incredible flow you could actually call
these air pockets that would be really
good for you that might be probably like
the product name if we sold them in
grocery stores
[Music]
so jesse when do you when do you plan on
closing out uh tobogram when do you
think that you're gonna get a resolution
so you gotta think of
law cases in three stages
so quebec for example 2019 they had
their first stage then there was an
appeal which is stage two and supreme
court is stage three quebec supreme
supreme court stage three will be a year
and a half from now
in manitoba we're gonna have our stage
one court proceedings in february march
yeah
and then uh roughly
six
to eight months after that will be in
the appeal court
so
all in all for quebec and manitoba to
start growing weed is probably
a year and a half to two years away if
the governments continue to fight really
so it's a long ways away before anyone's
gonna be able to grow their stuff at
their house legally at least and
hundreds of thousands in legal bills
and thousands
and on their side it's taxpayers paying
for it
wow and how are you raising the funds
we've been selling t-shirts people have
been buying them like crazy it's so
funny seeing them all around winnipeg uh
people walking in grocery stores and
whatnot we have a gofundme that's really
bumping right now thank you green planet
for your latest
uh donation
and uh we have a big surprise for early
january that i'm working on merlin with
to help really bolster our legal bill
fund there you go
more to come on that awesome
well these look amazing yeah these are
pretty much ready right here they're
nice and poached full of flavor from
this broth
pulling out the bok choy and the
broccoli so these are out we'll keep
these to the side and we'll start
filling our bowls over there
looks good
it looks spectacular
as it always does
good soup on a on a cold rainy day right
who doesn't want that right dude this is
my point right now though
yeah i think you're really i i've never
cooked this for you before marcus no oh
man
i think
dishes
this is actually thanks to my girlfriend
kim this is her recipe right here
actually i have to admit
yeah
thank you
she
makes ramen
i think she has a ramen tattoo that's
how much she loves raw dude
that's ramen commitment that's ramen
commitment right there
do you want to put a little bit of
broccoli a little bit of broth in each
one of these
oh yeah
i think he's doing a fine fine job of
that
[Applause]
so yeah we can do this real fast i like
your style
a little type a action in there yeah
it's like we're gonna speed through this
let's do this
all right so now
first step is done everything's going
there
let's start to build our dish we'll
start with our bug joy
get a few little black toys on the side
there
you got tofuse going in too just fried
tofu with some nice oil and a little
salt and pepper sometimes it's super
tasty like that
[Music]
just
they got mushrooms going in
yes
we can't have an episode without
mushrooms
seems like the right thing to do
this looks awesome dude
[Music]
now let's get a little bit of these
onions in here oh wait not yet let's get
the
i forgot so what do you guys sprouts a
little bit earlier
spaced in the oven baked in the oven
with a little bit of sesame oil and
sriracha okay so this is all going into
the ramen all going
damn bro
this is over the top
she looks like something
i don't know if anyone wants it but
you guys like a little chunk of butter i
suggest as usual
goes in this ramen as well you just put
a little chunk of butter in each one
just gives it a nice little creaminess
as it melts
just so everyone knows this is a razor
sharp knife so i'll try not to cut
myself yeah try to not cut yourself that
would suck
take your time
use your skill
all right now those are all cut and then
off with the gloves it looks great let's
put a little bit of
sesame seeds on here
jesus just keep making it look better
this is the shallot onion
and you can also do it and then also
just a few of these little bean sprouts
in the middle there
now some people like to fry the greens
bean sprouts i like them crunchy
so i put them in right at the end okay
a little bit
and there we have it ramen super five
plus some spring rolls well let's get it
on the table buddy
crazy you like my asian dishes because i
love all your dishes
from every culture that you pulled out
from they've all been like great
there's no complaints there
so yeah we merlin just crushed that out
the rest of us sort of stood around you
did a pretty good job actually i gotta
give you problems
they're staying together yeah i just
held the camera as always but um i was
much appreciated you provided the dabs
dude
watching you create this was
inspirational the noodles and then the
bok choy but then like some broccoli and
then some you know some mushrooms and
then the tofu and then you pull these
brussels sprouts out of the oven and
then there's an egg going in there with
sesame
and then sprouts yeah it was like a
seven thing addition yeah you gotta have
it there that's what's good and don't
forget the butter too yeah and then you
finished it with the butter see the
butter is now melting into the creamy
goodness yeah so i guess as always we
will take the first few bites let you
know what we think let's do it and then
uh yeah exactly wow
i don't have six
uh chopsticks so i got the i got the
four okay
i'll start with the spring roll
i was thinking about myself
okay dog
you are awesome
[Music]
before he's back
this meal does perfectly match the
weather outside exactly
right
i like that
what's that soup season's year-round
definitely
i like that i always push for the
sundaes too with different vegetarian
stuff coming up every week see this is
absolutely delicious as always
very fresh right
very fresh
with the salty peanut butter sauce
i think people would eat more vegetables
if they could make them taste like this
that is so on point
got so quiet all of a sudden that was
good exactly that's a good sign these
videos always end up
why
well
well thank our guests for visiting uh
this week thank you guys for making an
appearance hopefully we can do another
one with you sooner than later
thank you braxton for all the
entertainment thank you for joining us
for choosing my shoe dude
exactly and thank mark thanks uh merlin
as always for uh for cooking the
delicious food and serving it up as
always bro
thank you for having us yeah absolutely
guys
[Music]
we got this
all right
[Music]
smash it