[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world i
am back
with merlin hey guys and this is cooking
with merlin
and we're going to be cooking hell yeah
with merlin as usual some good food some
good dabs and some good weeds we start
off by rolling some joints you got a
couple of big nuggets there hey
i always like to show the camera so they
know what's going down
a little little fatty kush nugget yeah
oh it's gassy it is
so i like the smoke
i think a lot of people don't know what
gas is i think some people smell sativas
and terpenoline and they call it gas
that ain't gas it's not gas gasoline is
kush smoked knock you out right it's
that smell right there this is gas yeah
that's the definition of gas i mean it
literally
has a gas smell yeah
i did bring my my banger here today
got a buddy that's going to be showing
up another friend of mine actually uh
who's also very good friends with patty
who you guys met last week on cooking
with merlin when they produced those
ridiculous
[ __ ] bomb men
those were so good bro yeah i meant to
make them again this weekend oh
my girl was asking me man those were
good so yeah patty and mike who's going
to be coming in a little bit i don't
know if mike's going to be want to be on
camera i suspect he probably won't care
and he will join us but it's kind of
neat you know doing these cooking with
merlin shows and bringing in a new
individual merlin's going to bring some
guests in eventually as well uh here in
the next couple of weeks that we'll be
able to have and i guess in the meantime
vivo gets stoned yeah i like that idea
people get stoned why am i using the
german accent because we're going to be
cooking a german specialty today que
spetzla otherwise known as mac and
cheese but a little bit fancied up it's
a old-timey dish i've been having since
i'm a little kid that's awesome like
from mom and grandma exactly that was
like all i wanted from when i was a kid
when grandma came to come and see us it
was make questions you know i love the
aspect of food um
how it connects generations
you know and how we like everyone's got
grandma's recipe of course no one being
able to do grandma's recipe or a recipe
similar to it something that merlin's
got a history with
it just makes it that much more cool i
love mac and cheese connects it with a
memory too which is which is crazy
there's almost nothing else that can do
that like a certain smell or a taste
that connects you to a memory of yours
that's pretty cool truly as you light
that cush joint i'm like flooding with
crushed memories
of the good days
awesome well we're gonna hit the ewok
classic have you been up how many years
since you smoked a joint
um okay well i usually say about 20 but
then there's always people i try you
light a joint it's like okay yes someone
did come up to me like four years ago
with the karma cup and they had a
canadar
and they were like oh would you mind you
know lighting this it was like an honor
thing right it was it was mostly it was
tons of hash it was like 80 hash but
then it was wrapped in some leaves and
there might have been some weeds so i
said you know what sure i'll light it
for you i lit it passed it on didn't
really smoke it you know and that was
true and now people are like you smoked
joy and i saw you i was like well i lit
the can of garbage the last time i
smoked a joint for sure was 20 years ago
we tricked people on the last one too
with that hashtag it looked totally like
a choice i love it too because some guy
from humboldt was like that's not a
unique one-hitter we've been smoking out
of those for 20 years yeah but not like
paper ones yeah they're the glass ones
exactly the glass and the ceramic and
they conduct heat and they're just very
different they're not going to be as
convenient and ease of use as you know
being able to pick up and it's not like
the problem is the glass ones
unfortunately because of like other
drugs that made it they look bad right
you pull out a glass pipe like that
people are thinking you're not smoking
cannabis right so i like those paper
ones it looks more like a cigarette it's
almost like when i'm drinking my water
and everyone thinks i'm drinking vodka
we were talking about that off camera
before but i'm sure you guys have seen
my memo bottles these very flat bottles
this is the one that looks the least
like an alcohol container yet it still
does have a little bit what kind of
vodka you got there okay it's like i got
the h2o
version
berry flavor
you've got the dabber or did you put
that away already
oh thanks brother
so yeah super excited with these series
you guys seem to be very um
receiving them very well it seems like
uh
positive um
yeah positive comments and positive
feedback from everyone that's been
watching the cooking with merlin's
merlin series
uh he's close we're good friends it's
kind of easy and so we're gonna try and
keep pumping these out on the weekly on
the sundays and just
i know a few of you have said oh it
would be great if he used measuring cups
well it's not how we do you have to
follow the recipe you just gotta throw
stuff in maybe what we could do is add
the recipes at the end of it there you
go exactly
yeah i like the idea you know but i do
love the fact that you don't measure
things
you do it it's all to taste yes it's
amazing dude it's awesome yeah we'll
also try today because my girlfriend's
brand relax we'll have some of these
edibles nice
dried banana chips infused
let's start with this
very unique and novel product that you
can find here in canada probably the
only edible that's a fruit
that i know of and the only edible with
natural fats found in it
[Applause]
chill delicious to you
no candice flavor whatsoever no i'm just
done with straight disciplines although
there is none excellent but the bio
availability is really there because of
bobby
because of the natural fats so it really
helps right yeah
awesome i love it all right you can
check that out
r-i-l-a-x-e
sold across canada
pretty cool little idea you know he's
got like apricots
cherries cherries
bananas and mangoes and mangos that's
right
all good fruit in my opinion
let's get ourselves dabbed up yes sir i
don't know what i'm gonna hit here i
think i'm gonna yeah i think i'm gonna
go for a little strawberry banana
oh merlin also went picking the other
day he went and picked a ton of
chanterelles at the spot that we were at
the other day
so we're probably going to incorporate
the chanterelles we meaning
him
into the mac and cheese or into the
cage
cheese spatula
yeah cass is it case yes i just always
called it cass it's spelled i'm sure
people right they are going to call me
out on my misspelling i speak fabish
germans but is is it spelled k-a-a-s
because i remember i feel like i've seen
yeah like because listen
yeah i'm not a total vegetarian but i'm
close to so when i'm in germany you can
imagine i'm eating a fair amount of
casts or kids you got nothing else to
eat
it's like meat sticks and
sticks of meat and like more and more
cheese and meat oh my god right at the
gas station and potatoes and and you
know sour potatoes and cheese i've been
going there i've probably done you know
10 20 trips to germany
i'm probably right along at 10 to 20 as
well i started going to dortmund
originally in the late 90s
for the can of business
and i would go to that quite a bit
and then i became really good friends
with martin from roar
and he's in franken paul
really like little like one of those
neighborhoods where you really like this
is germany totally you're not in a big
city
all the streets are like without gps
forget about it forget about it you
could get locked into dead ends like
every it's like a maze no it is and it's
because it's so old too right it used to
be horse carriage
definitely not designed
for like mercedes 500 sls no so my my
cousin actually lives in uh in this
little town called bibarak which is your
classic tiny little german town oh yeah
they've been he's been in the packaging
business for i don't know 30 years they
do most of the food packaging across
across europe and they just recently it
was a super conservative and i asked my
mom about cannabis packaging since
that's what we do pretty much all day is
i make sure that i can bring products
like yours to the market as cheap as
possible with good packaging right so i
don't know if we've mentioned it before
but
merlin works with canmart formerly
namaste technologies yeah
he's kind of been a
i've been involved since he kind of went
over there and he's grown himself into a
nice strong position and in fact
you know my company embark and kanmar
have recently
kind of created a little synergy and
we'll we'll tell you more about that in
the future as we announce yeah so it's
really fun and we get to work together
as well so it's even even more fun right
it's awesome dude get some good hash
products that you know that's what's
really lacking in the canadian market
right now i think is like good products
people don't understand what good
products is
they're just listening to what other
people are saying well and let's get
into the real conversation because
you know we know the very people who are
you know basically mocking and
belittling the canadian regulatory
framework and i i can understand where
they're coming from it's it's it's
difficult and it's it gets to me
sometimes but
trying to bring great products to market
in a regulated
environment it's not the same
it's not the same
and so it's almost like we're rewinding
and starting back over with like okay
now all of these new people who have
you know and i think the thing about
cannabis is that it was so
removed from everything for so long and
now that group of people
as much as they may have thought they
wanted it open for everyone i think
they're having a hard time with it yeah
and it's like oh who the [ __ ] is this
guy who does he think he is he's like
he's everyone dude like we wanted
cannabis to be for everyone not locked
in well that's what i think about this
micro program is gate is but the problem
is is that those very regulations we
talk about are holding back these micros
if you look at anyone's business plan
this do a micro based on the square
footage and the amount of investment
especially here in bc you're looking at
a four to five year runway before you
start seeing a penny that you have to
have a complete passion and have bank in
the
in the pocket yeah they put the right
steps in place i think with farmgate and
all of that but what they're missing is
that the regulations for these small
guys just don't make sense they don't
have to bankroll to lose the money to do
it and that's what we need to be honest
they don't make much sense for even some
of the
medium and bigger players yeah like the
regulations
it's not just crushing small companies
and i get that yeah like let's protect
the most vulnerable players but there's
a lot of people in the middle of the
board who really need protecting too
yeah like they're just as likely to get
eaten but the reason that i say that the
small that fight for the small guys is
because the big guys have such big rooms
that they can't show enough love to
their cannabis and grow good product and
for the products that you and me want to
see in market it takes the smaller guy
that's this is his life if he doesn't
have this crop come through as nice as
possible yeah he's not going to be able
to keep surviving but they they can't be
growing bad cannabis on purpose you know
that they're not so that's what i'm
saying and they have people like
there are people like that know how to
grow cannabis that are involved with
these companies like these companies
have you know like i mean dna was
involved with canopy why can't canopy
because growing
herb that good on that
it's a big difference between 20 lights
and 400.
it probably should have been grown
pragmatically small like everyone starts
out as a micro
and the ones that gain milestones and
success can apply and become maybe
bigger
i don't pretend to know the the cure for
it i think no matter what you suggest
someone would have a big [ __ ] problem
with it
like they always do and so i just try to
navigate it the best that i can from a
hashmaker's perspective
it's really difficult good and good it's
got to be the recipe for you to ask yeah
right of course but trying to find great
material i'll be i'll be honest some of
the first material we found
like it was maybe our second or third
batch it was tropicana cookies and that
[ __ ] was like cookies it came back like
wow like one of the microns we tested
all the microns the 25 micron that
people are like oh that's just food
grade throw it away but the question is
70 did the supplier have to have another
batch for you the next time that wasn't
really the question no no not in this
instance and so it was regulations that
have has kept and still
is keeping
that hash from market and it's not ours
we uh we told it yeah but it's
unbelievable it's been over a year and
it's still not released no
i no say it's at least a five-star
bubble oh man i remember seeing pictures
it was purple on the
picture that you took it was a little
bit chop cookies is definitely in my
like i love cushions but if i want to
taste something fruity i love chocolate
stuff yeah really nice tastes like
smoking oranges it's true yeah it's just
lovely and in the concentrates it's even
it's like the best yeah that's true yeah
i love that calio you know the first
real orange flavored cannabis for me was
calio and when i saw calio
everything since tangerine and the vel
what any orangey flavor yeah it reminds
me it always is first
it's got that calio in it yeah
those were a big fluffy orange yeah that
was good stuff yeah really nice and the
nicest girl i've ever been in in my life
it belonged to shanti baba uh scott
blakey and it was in switzerland in
belzona and it probably would have been
like 2000 or 2001.
[Music]
and i i drove down to bellenzono with
bushy older grower
and gypsy nirvana
and we drove down to bellenzona and we
met
shanti baba and he walked us through a
greenhouse
of six foot tall
one or two days away from finishing
monsters
for like an acre like it was a huge
greenhouse or a half an acre i don't
know it was really big for real
um nicest smell that i never smelled and
it was neat that i got to share that
with a bushy older grower and gypsy
nirvana wow that's a great story
oh dude and i asked him i said
how did you do this like how
who's growing this and he said
rose farmers i don't hire smokers he's
like i don't hire people
from the cannabis it's
rose farmers rose farmers he's like they
are like
disciplined
meticulous aware
and it was their first crop of cannabis
and he said the only difference
was instead of getting poked
don't get the resin in your eyes that's
the only real thing they had to consider
after that it was just like botany learn
about the plant i mean i think what
happened to a licensed producer world is
that it was
how many grams can you produce per
square foot and that was your evaluation
in the public markets and it just ruined
everything instead of how much quality
can you pull out a square foot right
instead of these guys what did they say
i saw an article the other day 18 of
total cannabis grown since legalization
has been sold like that means there's a
ridiculous amount of crap that's being
written down destroyed or used for god
knows what oh my god those horrible
tasting pre-rolls that some people face
there should be a a
like a
you know
a facility that's like
you know not for profit but that takes
all of that
and just processes it into cannabinoids
as just
ingredient
and then not affect the market but just
like allow whoever has the best overview
probably the government health canada to
figure out where this should go but not
ever allow it to be destroyed because
it's too high of a value i think i think
what happens is for companies it
probably ends up being cheaper to
destroy it than right down to the loss
of profit
unfortunately
but you should be able to like instead
of destroying you should be able to
choose to donate where it gets donated
it would be so good
that's a good change like wouldn't it be
amazing and then just be like i don't
know like if you're worried like make it
free
to people who don't have access to it at
all like homeless put it for the
medicine the most vulnerable yeah just
make it like if you don't want to profit
off of it
and you're making companies destruction
should go to health canada labs to make
it permanent free medicine for the world
let someone benefit from god
imagine
all right we went a little bit deep if
we did and that's okay we were talking
about maybe doing this
um i think it's time to make some uh
goosebumps
let's do it
kitchen bound all right
all right so serious so uh we should
introduce our next friend
mike's here hey what's up dude
all right so i think the first step is
to add
onions to a hot pan
[Music]
which is not hot
really
yeah
it looks pretty red underneath yeah
and then we're gonna have to caramelize
these
[Music]
yeah there's uh we're going to go
through that cheese for sure because
there's like four or five different ones
get a little saltine
man don't sweat the onions bro
this guy's always sweating the onions at
least they're white
yeah they deserve it they do
soon to be
caramelized and delicious
all right here's our cheese collection
we got fontina
uh
carlsberg aged parmesan
truffle gouda
[Music]
just some cheese huh
when you're lazy you use the machine
yeah last week we were here with patty
who's who's cooking with us okay
at once turning into a cooking channel
yeah all the cheeses at once
well as much as we can fit i like it
makes it easier faster on high
damn just like that
this [ __ ] doesn't really mess
around
it's just like
no fair warning or nothing
just like fully homogenized five
different cheeses
that's the way to do it
we'll go for the pasta next
so
two cups of flour
you recognize you can stir this now you
want to let them just sweat a little a
little bit more stir in the second one
if you don't mind it'll be great
crack four eggs in this thing
is that first you know especially with a
cast iron that first like caramelization
that gets made on the pan
[Music]
and um
that's what you let it say yeah exactly
so four eggs in
here real quick
we're going to add in a half a cup of
milk
[Music]
you could use a vegetable based milk too
or if you wanted to do this i don't know
you can maybe use linseed
you didn't see the water that replaced
the egg have you ever tried that no it's
like a vegan egg oh okay
that's nice and stirred up
put it into the two cups make a little
well in there
[Music]
just a little well
and then we can start mixing this
and
made pasta right
yeah these are really cool it's really
different from most pastas it's like a
special german pass so these they're
super light and airy and fluffy you'll
see it's a
special machine
you can get to make it
interesting so now i'm intrigued i think
we'll add in here now a little bit of
salt
[Music]
the real secret to this pasta to get a
lot of flavor
is nutmeg
that's the touch right there
exactly what i said
[Music]
just a couple little scrapes in
there pretty yummy
a little nutmeg
you want this dough to be a little bit
runny actually so if it's not runny
enough would you mind grabbing me some
milk out of the fridge
it should be in the door
right here
perfect thank you just add like a little
another dash of milk
get it a little
moisture just a dash
because you'll see when it has to go
through the pasta machine you almost
want it like a wet
wet dough gotcha i feel like that's a
very old statement a dash
like how long have people been saying
just a dash
it might have been replaced by just a
dab it's the dab that's the 2021 version
we do our dabs before our dashes yeah
that's the order a dash of a dab
there's a lot of similarities here with
hashmaking actually of you absolutely
just your preparation the sop
you know the awareness and the
cleanliness
i know i do feel that as well the pasta
is done and mixed
we're just gonna let that rest for like
15 minutes 10-15 minutes awesome
add some butter in there ooh
butter makes everything more delicious
these onions are a big part of it you
don't want to go too hot and you want to
get them all nice and
caramelized
i just like the sound and the look of
things cooking
the asmr aspect of it
the asmr is picking up didn't burger
king just do one for the sizzle with
asmr oh i'm sure i feel like they've
done they started doing that a long time
like i i can't i haven't had cable since
98.
they were definitely doing it in
commercials before that
this you know just those sounds you want
to know what one of the greatest sounds
would be is the damage you should do an
asmr of just the damage totally the
sucking of the
bomb yep we'll turn our heat on for this
as well
and this is the contraption believe it
or not this is what we're making pasta
with yeah exactly it's pretty simple
interesting
um
let's try some mushrooms to put on top
of this oh i like that idea
want to fry some mushrooms bricks then
it's probably smelling my dog
get this pan done
your mushroom cooking
butter
what's that your mushroom cooking butter
got a cookie with butter and then you
can put a little grapeseed oil on it
and it goes for a higher heat
so patty was saying oh no it was shawn
my friend sean who was saying um you'll
get a lot more mushroom flavor if you
don't uh fry it with uh garlic
the garlic overpowers the mushroom
flavor like the mushrooms
but garlic is so good i don't know i
think the mix of them both is good oh
i'll take it that way that's for sure
i guess it's a neat way to say if you
wanted to prepare a dish to have a more
earthy
fungus based flavor yeah you could you
could do it like that you know what
actually we're going to cancel this
brown right here oh yeah and we're going
to cook the mushrooms in this pan to get
the flavor of the onions in there as he
spoke like that i think that's a great
idea perfect
so that's the garlic yeah a little bit
of extra garlic in there
with the butter the onion smells so good
did you walked into it bro he had me at
gruyere
yeah
the truffle gouda is the one that smells
the strongest smell the smell this is
cheese it smells so good
you can smell the truffle right away
that's awesome
we got the water going there we're gonna
want to put some salt in water too
salt that [ __ ] like the sea
shell
start that [ __ ] like to see huh
these come along
pretty good
ready
onions are pretty much ready
they look great
i'm gonna put them in the bowl yeah
let's just put them off to the side for
right now while we cook the noodles
because you want everything hot at once
so it melts all the cheese
ah yes of course
and
like you were saying with all the flavor
that we have left in this pan from the
onions
we'll cook our chanterelles
okay a little bit of onion in there get
them
fried up a bit so
it just went in
yes sir
all these beautiful chanterelles
i'd love to see the chanterelles
look at that one yeah this is a this is
a yellow i think i don't know it's not
no that's a yellow
a giant yellow yeah it could be a very
small gold
so
you don't want them to move too much
oh that's the sound
[Music]
i think i'm just gonna have these on the
side just because they're so amazing
flavor and i'll do a i'll do them with
whiskey this time yeah
instead of gin
instead of gin we will do whiskey
um
[Music]
so getting the water out of these
mushrooms and onions
really it's coming from the mushrooms
you know what actually though we should
do the salad first because
i have time once the noodles are ready
we gotta like put everything together so
all right start with the salad
and mike you want to go in the drawer
right here
second one down and there's a cheese
grater
that would be amazing
a little bit of cucumber on there as
well
this one right here thank you very much
thank you
a little cucumber on there
my favorite carrot
condominium of salad good stuff and
carrots insides
carrots on there
well that's going to make a quick salad
dressing
do i want to give these a stir
sure yeah
yeah i'll give you that
mike actually knows how to handle the
camera everyone will be like why did the
camera get so much better after the
bubble man leave the
camera this bubble man sucks
these look great man
you want them to spread out again evenly
yeah that'd be perfect
a little dressing up of the salad a
little olive oil
[Music]
olive oil
some white balsamic
some classic balsamic
and then the secret to every canadians
oh yes pantry is maple syrup right oh
yeah
who doesn't want maple syrup
we had some of sean's uh
a little bit of
and salt
a bunch of maple syrup is good in there
it really cuts the acid right
i don't like when it's too
too acidic a salad dressing but a bunch
of maple syrup or any really sugar will
make it a lot softer it balances the
acid
and then
a little bit of dijon mustard or a nice
amount as an emulsifier
and that'll be our salad dressing
so that's on the side let's start our
mushrooms
this is the whiskey portion now they're
nice and fried
so we'll put a little bit of that in
there a little bit of tamari
for the saltiness
you can see there's a whole bunch of
flavor left on the bottom of that pan
from the onions
from
from this and smell that tamari right
[Music]
let it boil a sec
then go
puts a nice little crisp on them
not for the paint for the faint of heart
yeah be careful
do it a few times before you know it's
very nice do it with a high ceiling if
you're gonna do it anywhere right
not condoning
that was a one time one try
you know
and now that puts a nice caramelization
on these things and delicious yeah they
look beautiful
that now our water is boiling
making pasta
so one last spin let's see the
consistency in here that is nice and
runny
you want to make sure that there's no
lumps and that your pack the gluten is
really binded you can see now that the
gluten's binded together and that's why
you want to wait and let it rest did you
put extra gluten in there for me extra
gluten just for you my friend thanks all
right let's
switch places here
[Music]
you're just gonna
scoop a bunch in there so now we slap
this on top of here so that's nice and
straight
now this is where it gets kind of crazy
because it's boiling water and the pasta
is cooking while you're putting it in
but we'll do our best on this
oh my goodness
manual madness
as you can see it's very very sticky
it looks very sticky
now you kind of want to just get that in
there
would you mind sliding those mushrooms
off uh slide it off the heat slide
and then as we get in there this is
where you want to start sliding this
thing back and forth and if you can see
in the pot look at those nice noodles
being made filled with air
so they're super fluffy
jesus
yeah and then now we load in some more
that's crazy
this is a trip dude
and make while i'm doing this would you
be able to uh
grab this and put those mushrooms in
there so we don't overcook them though
so they go in and then they like form
with like bubbles in them so they're all
fluffy yeah
so they're hollow on the inside like i'm
like a macaroni a little bit almost
right wow
it's almost like they're hollow it's
like they're very very fluffy because
it's an egg noodle right yeah yeah
and then that last bit of dough always
gives you a hard time
to do the best you can get it all off
there
not at the expense of wasting your other
noodles
because you don't want them overcooked
okay
but look how beautiful those things are
yeah those are some nice little
they're actually really long this time
they're usually uh shorter than this i
did a
we did a stellar job here and they're
like actual pasta noodles
usually they come out a little bit
shorter
i appreciate the wii merlin but we did
it man i don't know what i did
you like uh maestro that [ __ ]
it was like some mastery and i was like
this is jean-luc
french kitchen
all right those are pretty much cooked
because noodles don't take long
especially fresh ones
strainer here
[Music]
here we go
and now i know a lot of people
like to run it with cold water to kind
of get those starches out but you want
to keep as much heat as possible because
that's going to be expense
essential to make it
melt all your cheeses
next stage here
that was quick too
yeah
super easy pasta to make
so now we get our nice pot here
get our pasta in there
get our onions in there
with all that butter and onion
deliciousness
this is gonna be the best mac and cheese
you guys have ever had yeah i was coming
over for mac and cheese i heard you know
this happened
so we're gonna mix in those onions get
all that flavor and butter distributed
in there
now it's some delicious oniony noodles
now we start with the cheese
get it in there
can smell right away the terps of those
cheeses coming off especially that
truffle cheese cheese
cheese terps
it's probably the first terps when
people started fermenting stuff
oh man
oh yeah
that's insane that little more cheesy
but you gotta get that cheesy
over the top
let's put another cup of this in but
which one was that last one mozzarella
is just to have the stringy i think that
we're gonna should we mix that in ah you
know what i think so i think the way you
just did that with everything was like
let's get this let's make this next
level special for the bubble for bubble
man's world
it's a mushroom special
mushroom special just for bubble man's
world food that you hand-picked the
mushrooms for
us and we hand-made the noodles for
this one's all done special
look at the cheesy goodness in there
just smell you can see you can hear it
oh yeah yeah look at it it could just
get like
goopy
and now it's gonna melt this is the key
why you wanted to keep the heat straight
out is because this next few minutes
turns it into a sauce kind of then we
want to hit it up
a bunch of pepper peppers delicious
we're gonna have our own food network
marcus
cooking with merlin yeah
whole bunch of water
damn
a bunch of salt
oh yeah
we're gonna go gluttonous right
i think we're well on our way maybe
we've passed gluttonous like three
milestones back
we don't have string half a pound occur
uh half a pound of cheese back we passed
uh
that there we go
and then we're gonna do some of this
a little bit of chopped parsley for the
top of that
now we'll grab some tongs here
let's mix our salad
dressing we made earlier
tongs are the best for salad
[Music]
you know let's make them
awesome
there we go all right let's uh get you
another place
all right wow that was uh quite a
production yeah it just looks like it's
gonna be pretty damn good
it's a great sunday sunday tradition i
feel like you should start us off let's
do it
[Music]
but thank you sir
that's ridiculous
thank you sir
i agree with the top hat i guess we'll
just go back for seconds yeah exactly
i'm definitely gonna be
crushing some circles oh the aroma is
so good it's so good man yeah
i feel like i just my mouth is just
watery
like hard yeah as always merlin
let us take the first few bites
let them know what we think
mike's here he can give us his uh
the mushrooms added to it for sure
dude the onions the mushroom wow
the nutmeg those noodles
the five cheeses that you put in
[Music]
it's elevated in a big way
so
you'd expect them to be a little bit
more subdued but
the texture of the mushroom is nice it's
so nice too the noodles are very unique
it tastes so fluffy yeah
definitely creates i'm not saying
anybody
straight into the boiling water as you
shredded
me neither i can honestly say i've never
seen that that thing
whatever you call it special maker
y'all remember that
is
loads and loads all right i've never had
mac and cheese like this the onions are
just
perfect you weren't kidding like how
they're camouflaged yeah it's so good
this is like i've been having this dish
for my grandma since i'm a kid it's only
time to make it
super easy we'll put the recipe in the
bottom of this yeah we'll start putting
the recipe in the bottom because merle's
not really measuring anything out he
just does it by feel and whatnot
but um yeah thanks for joining us
while we eat the special
this has been a special occasion that's
what we did stolen from mike
peace out everybody see you later thank
you
[Music]