[Music]
do
all right this is where it gets good
boys
all right first i usually have to start
by saying welcome to bubble man's world
uh we're back here at merlin's cooking
with merlin and i brought another good
buddy that you guys may recognize from
some of the whistler riding videos pate
is in the house
welcome both you guys
yeah patty and i just spent the day with
our families up in squamish picking more
mushrooms at the same place that merlin
and i were at last week so we brought
some of those mushrooms but uh i guess
what we're gonna do is have a couple of
beers and have a couple of puffs
and then these guys are gonna prepare
another meal what what what was what was
the meal preparation today the meal
today we're gonna do some uh bon me
sandwiches uh
vegetarian style just for yourself my
friend okay and uh with some coleslaw
pretty good
sounds good and a couple joints during
excellent i think it's probably a good
idea did you break you didn't bring your
herb i did
oh you did i did i didn't know what
you wanted to press something but uh
i don't really have time so
we're gonna do a mini squish i got it
one of those mini yeah
one hitter
see how it works
it's been burned for a long time
that was melty hash
actually melted and bubbled a little bit
oh you do have a little press for sure
you gotta there you go that's amazing
put that thing on the table it's
hilarious
a joint at a time look at this thing
that's so awesome
does it work okay yeah it sounds like
for what
right
exactly that's awesome dude let's see
i thought you were gonna pull out a flat
iron i'm not lying i was waiting for a
hair crimper it pulls it you know what i
mean like that thing but the flat
version that's actually pretty
impressive
just hash
quite lovely i'm always looking for new
ways to ingest and consume hash
right hey why not
do why not do i not always have
something you've always got something
unique something that's going on one way
to get it in there well today i forgot
my rig so i forgot my entire packed up
all my dabs my my the entire thing torch
temp attack pipe everything uh and so
what i did find was a couple of these
one hitters and i thought well [ __ ]
that's probably enough to sit uh back
with the boys and have a couple of pups
looks like
merle already rolled a nice dube
little can on exactly
brixton's raging around with the rising
full power with the lamb
yeah
it's a beautiful sunday here in british
columbia why don't i give you guys a
little
little show of the view real quick here
there we go
this beautiful
lions bay bc
a japanese maple is
red out there
and it actually stopped raining
i can't believe it stopped raining
dude how about shannon falls dude i said
to char i don't think i've ever seen
shannon falls raging that wow she looked
angry yeah for those of you that are in
and around the vancouver area shannon
falls is absolutely
going off right now that would be uh not
a bad place to go in the next few days i
wouldn't climb up and go anywhere near
the actual waterfall but i would enjoy
it from under you know the bottom
there's a shower at the bottom from a
distance you know in the summer i go in
it when it's like dribbling but the way
it is right now
you wouldn't want to go in there
two summers ago didn't some guys fall
off yeah some uh some youtubers they
were going up there into the top pools
yeah and i guess the girl i think it was
the girl lost control and you know was
sliding over and then the guy went to
jump and grab her and he went over too
it was really a nightmare yeah
everyone's trying to get those views
that's some stellar views for
exactly that's insane yeah i don't think
you'd be enjoying that that's not the
way you want him he wouldn't be enjoying
it though in his
those last 30 seconds that's uh some
hindu
some older high school
yeah it's interesting huh yeah
i don't actually know where i got that
but it's pretty satisfying
yeah it's got a [ __ ] nose too that's
for sure
you guys have a lot in common in the
sense that patty also just loves to cook
and make food and he's always just
busting out things with
that's what stoner's like today i said
yeah right i sent him the videos
i can hang out with your buddy
let's do it people ask me they're like
do do you cook for professionals like no
i just smoked a lot of weed
you know that's kind of where it goes
yeah it does indeed
and once you eat really good food it's
hard to go back
true
you know nice husky
yeah that's pretty cool yeah that is
really cool i've never noticed that on
this pipe before it goes straight like
milly husky oh yeah that's awesome
well when they sold it they said it was
the lone wolf
the lone wolf yeah here i got to show it
to the camera i'm just gonna say well
we're talking about it i probably should
show it to you
the wolf the lone wolf
there we go
should we do some cooking and starving i
think so yeah why don't uh let's do it
we clean this up real quick and
get to what's important
the cooking
and i'm gonna do it with uh
we'll do like a yogurt dill sauce yeah
it'll be [ __ ] delicious
you missed the guys but
literally patty just was saying how he'd
never made these types of sandwiches but
he was just like last week googling the
sauce for this
he's like why am i not making paumy
sandwich
what are you saying brixton why am i
buying them why don't i just make them
what are you saying buddy
what are you saying
all right well we got some uh we got the
wild brine
i think we'll start with the tofu
kimchi
get some garlic
i'll get you set up too you want to
start cutting up some uh for the salon
cabbage yeah some cabbage
all right
oh it's about to go off in here
to prepare some food
now is there any tape which one you want
all right i would say slice it thin yeah
that's what i would do but you don't
want to are you particularly going to
head this way or make it easier
okay
will i use an animal
nope
all right
gotcha
just quarter it
i did a bit of both eh yeah exactly
do be hanging out of the mouth that's
how i like to do it
last time i kind of held back and didn't
have a joint line out the whole time but
it's like how much i always cook oh
there you go beer in your hand
smoke in the mouth you look like a real
quebecois
yeah the spoon is kills it on instead of
the knife right
that's interesting a little trick yeah
yeah instead of like tearing into the
ginger with a knife and losing a whole
bunch yeah you're not losing any no it
just really takes the skin right off
that's awesome
these two guys are going for it
fresh up some garlic after he cuts up
the ginger you just slice the ginger
into fairly big chunks yeah we're going
to grind it into the
blender anyway
it's so much easier to put to build
sauces than these just got the
slivery slug ready to go ready to go
ginger and garlic in there
ah okay you got the bullet a little bit
of onion
put some yeah in there
damn just right there huh
that's ridiculous
[Music]
lemon in there opens this cupboard pulls
out a handheld lemon juicer
he's like two inches away from his hip
okay a little soy
sauce a little parmesan oh yeah lemon
ponzi
little ponzu
that's the goods
a little bit of sesame oil
[Music]
and to be canadian we'll put some maple
syrup
oh yeah a little maple syrup
to be canadian yeah
beautiful
go
you know what actually i think i'm even
going to go back and put a little bit of
tahini
a little tahini yeah
just a moldy way kind of you know okay
just a little tahini
didn't see that one coming
there it is
this emulsifier this is looking
sweet
yeah it's making a mess you know fractal
coated
a vicious racket with its arms around
your children
the truth about marijuana
degradation sin vice insanity debauchery
the smoke of hell
so for those of you that are wondering
where that came from it came from here
reaper madness
and you can thank uh like the william
randolph hearst and those [ __ ]
i think they're still responsible
we're gonna build that up a little bit a
little relaxed
[Music]
i mean i can but
i don't want to
oh yeah the fruits of the small fruits
of our labor this was a big chanterelle
for a yellow foot
you know what maybe for yourself this
will be easier yellow bigger
beautiful
and i'm telling you there was a lot of
chanterelles out there today yeah
yeah these yellow foots are the winter
chanterelles
that's what they call them the yellow
foots
yeah once you hit a patch do they come
all year
until like december january i think
we'll see let's keep let's try picking
them all here yeah seriously
make a new meal every week for like
three months
slice up our tofu
okay a little tofu
squeeze that water out
i used to always think it was some sort
of solution but it's literally just
water okay
like what are they putting in to make it
better it's like oh it's water it's like
that's the tofu solution
i don't know about that in a sense it is
a solution because without it it'll dry
out
yeah i guess you're right
just not the solution you were thinking
it's a double entendre
yeah
so tasty
probably not the best food
what's that
soy is probably not the best for you but
it tastes delicious
well we're going to eat some today
oh
[Applause]
it's got that nice creaminess from the
tahini
instantaneously appetizing
yeah definitely that's the beauty of
tofu taste whatever you want right
it's really like a nice base element
salad from patty okay we'll let that
marinade
soften it up with a bit of lemon juice
[Music]
so what do you did it marinade and you
saw the tofu right in the marinade yeah
yeah so as you're tossing that salad is
anyone else here thinking about that
joke
or am i the only five-year-old
yeah like the minute he started doing
that did it come to your minds because
i'm like a five-year-old i'm like as
soon as you said we are building so i
heard you chuckle
but i just don't think you thought of it
before i said it no so i'm more twisted
than you okay as soon as you said cause
in the sun
they immediately went there
we're not in prison boys
we don't have to be anymore this is
legal
as of today isn't it yeah today's the
anniversary
october 17th
[Music]
from the back to the front right
all right
i'm out again
uh i'm going to shred this too yeah
please you can shave it and shred it
here
shave it and shred
it was giving me
attention
kimchi
probiotic man we're all gluten-free
vegans
wow
i got all the
popular terms for selling food these
days totally
i think he's one of those
items now right
it's always just been super healthy and
awesome it's like it's like uh kale
yeah yeah exactly
we're doing kale dirty
next time we should go pick kale at my
buddy's garden these are the monster
[ __ ] dinosaur kale let's do it and i
got the best enchiladas oh let's do it
and i want to go get those evergreen
huckleberries as well
and then do something with those
the foraging yeah let's just expand our
ability to forage and find as many
things as we can and then make cool
things out of the things we find i like
it it's awesome
i was just thinking the sea grapes yeah
the sea grapes so that yeah the seas
berries will kill us too
they just look cool too right yeah
there is a few broccoli and radish ones
there too if you want
oh right
yeah we're going to definitely put those
on
i'll bring them over here you can just
dig
you wanna oh i guess we should put some
carrot in there too maybe we should
grate another one because we want some
for the sandwiches too okay
i like the idea of putting it in the
in the coleslaw though yeah it'll
brighten it up a bit right with the
orange yeah and i have some fresh
cilantro growing downstairs
i usually do like uh cabbage carrot
cilantro i do garlic and mayo yeah a
little bit of mustard vinegar and salt
but i'm down do it up something like
that
yogurt for the dill sauce
what's that mango flavored
[Music]
could you imagine just pouring in this
super fruity yogurt this is going to be
delicious
i think not as he puts in a bunch of
fruit citrus
you gotta put citrus juice
for the dill
sauce oh [ __ ] i'm gonna put my secret
ingredient
oh yeah we can turn the camera on
it's nice to have secrets
it's not much of a secret it's just hard
to find
straight from where from germany is it's
like us
and sauces and everything because like
what is it it's like vegetable salt oh
yeah okay okay it's delicious
it's like good and everything it makes
everything like that
it's kind of like uh it's just 98
msg definitely
organic no no i know
but could you imagine someone's like i
know the stuff that you put in there
look they have these two you would love
these marcus actually
they're they're vegetarian this one's a
mushroom one as well you can only get
them once a year in germany from this
company you have to pre-order it
champignon
these pates are just absolutely
delicious try this it looks like cat
food
but let's try it
you'll see i'll give it a shot
carrots are going in
once a year i'll get my grandmother to
send me oh my goodness from germany is
that delicious or what
wow
that's rich
like all vegetables all organic small
drops from this like organic company in
germany it's nice
almost got like a smoky flavor yeah
that's the mushrooms it's uh steinkill
so uh schneidenthalt would be king king
mushroom king
really yeah
these are king bowlets
we saw some beautiful bullets in the uh
in the forest today
yeah it's awesome did you guys get any
good ones
no we're going to pick them yeah i could
have i left them yeah yeah i didn't uh
have any way to really prepare it
here i'll show a picture of it right now
i didn't pick it up
it's a nice one it's nice right those
are good and fried it was three and a
half feet tall oh i'm just joking
just the way i shot it though
cutting up more look if you would have
tosh and then me and then the mushroom
in front oh my god
that's awesome
oh i got a present for your kid after
yeah yeah okay
amazing
my kids love presents
it's a bunch of toys
um what's next here we go put the dill
in here
he's pulsing his salad again since the
salad
i like the tosser salad german salad
tossing
already put lemon in there if you want
to do uh the dressing that you said
before would be great okay sure really
nice that looks like fall now yeah look
at that just cause you're crushing it
over here you got bay dill over here oh
yeah
this is for the uh
this is for the veggie sauce for the
bond me oh yeah
man this is what's up guys
a little bit of pepper
nice
that's gonna turn nice and green oh yeah
old school style huh
[Music]
old school
14 minutes of preparation so far not bad
too bad we do it fast
i think let's get used to the thickening
yogurt
i think we're going to put a bit of mayo
a bit of mail yeah
i'll thicken it up
this guy over here is like crushing the
garlic rushing
oh yeah oh yeah salt just drives it up
like so
right into here huh
i actually need a good toss now yeah
a saddle need a good toss
toss away
thickening over here
tossing over here um spoons
ah right there
oh man does that smell good
a lot of nice flavors in the air oh yeah
that's good to me
[Music]
the cilantro we'll grab the cilantro in
a second it's downstairs we'll do the
tofu right now
tofu is going in
we'll go this way after some quick uh
salad tossing
i wanted to see that get all homogenized
that looks delicious it sure does and
then we'll come over here
for mr joint smoking tofu cooker
[Music]
we got the oil just like preheated over
here
grapeseed oil for high heat
oh what kind of food are we looking at
it's pretty hot i don't know
medium high yeah
and this will all get marinated right in
there
[Music]
there's a lot of sauce now but it'll all
absorb into it
it looks amazing
we need to bring a small plate home for
our wives gotcha you can do that
this was requested it was requested it
was requested how did charlotte you know
where the noodles left she loved it yeah
she thought they were great what's that
patty i thought that's what the video
was where logan bring home the video
yeah yeah exactly here we go we brought
it so good this is what we had oh my
goodness
and this is what you have sir divorce
divorce no i always think of my woman i
love her so much uh last time i brought
her food home for sure
she thinks of me the same way so it's
reciprocal
yeah it's nice
32 years i've been with my uh my
beautiful wife wow
how many years
32 wow
yeah
married for like 26. that's impressive
can't buy that at walmart no
no sir
we'll cut this brother go
i think we should butter them
this is the buns
butter the buns
people are going to be commenting on
this video
not for children
you know what i if i can't film a video
of hanging out with my buddies and
shooting the [ __ ] and puffing dudes
while you guys have a beer and make a
video then i i don't want to live in
that world if i can't do that that's
true who does and it's not a fun world
no we need to be able to have fun we
need to be able to live this is actually
very chill
yeah super chill
that's how it's got to be this is just
looking good
[Music]
[Applause]
as the water disappears the tofu grows
a little butter in there a little bird
in the
meatball
25 seconds let's preheat this
so i just noticed that this stuff is
basically the same color as my sweater
he made a sauce to match my sweater
how cool is that
matches shout out to seti for the
psychedelic research
hoodie
oh yeah look at that
giving them a turn
they're just like perfectly french
toasted yeah they do like their french
things they really do
little french toasts
if you told someone this was french
toast and then put syrup on it they'd be
surprised
you just tell them they don't know the
syrup's already in there
infused like mcdonald's in the griddle
exactly i don't know what that means but
we had like a wicked yeah well is that
what it was i don't know i don't know
butter in the buns
and so we're doing this why
just so they crisps up and gets nice and
golden brown and we put it in the oven
okay that's the key right yeah we'll
we'll remember these
butter makes everything better
yes
i go through a ridiculous amount of
butter on the weekly i bet you do
putting it on the inside the outside
you're like i'll be boiling using butter
and frying them in butter we could poach
the tofu and butter next time
awesome that's what you want on the
bunny though right the nice crisp exact
crunch when you're biting into it
totally
booyah
boom
oh [ __ ]
this is just ridiculous at this point
it smells so good it really does
it's a nice
tofu meal
i can't mess around with good tofu
there's definitely a lot of bad tofu out
there
yeah i i find for i don't really like
soft tofu as much i like frying paste
yeah
soft tofu is really weird actually it
just kind of feels like pudding it's
like solid pudding
i'm out hard to get that stuff crispy it
just kind of turns into scrambled rum my
baby in there i feel like i need my
beverage because these guys are slipping
their beverage and
although they're drinking beers i am
drinking water
even though it looks like it's vodka
this was vodka and i did this
isn't that the trailer park boys trick
with the
the dad
oh my god
yeah right mr leahy that was a lot of
vodka
that was a lot of not vodka
feel the way that [ __ ] clings to the air
right yeah
oh the trailer park boys
r.i.p mr leahy yeah
i met him once i met him with uh
who is he with he was with randy of
course
in whistler no it was in vancouver at a
at a at a like health event
yeah they were randy was walking around
without a shirt and he was like he's
like mr lee
i really need a cheeseburger
and that's what i heard
and i was like what the heck and then i
found out later it was my friend mark
who actually had brought them he was he
had some cannabis cup that he was doing
and he brought you know he brought snoop
dogg one year and he brought
he brought charlie murphy one year nice
yeah charlie murphy came and did a
comedy show he was like come see charlie
murphy come see charlie murphy i'm like
i don't think i'm gonna be able to make
it he's like if you can get here for
like 11 30 i got a surprise for you so i
get there me and shar end up going down
it's like on hastings it's like the
bamboo room or something and we're in
the back little green room or whatever
and we're sitting at a table
and i hear everyone clapping we're we're
backstage and and then he comes out with
his bodyguard charlie murphy with his
bodyguard and sits at our table and for
the next hour and a half we proceeded to
tell like true life charlie murphy
stories
and i got to tell him some of my own
crazy life stories
it was the greatest experience dude
i gotta shout out mark for that because
that was uh it really was unbelievable
rest in peace to charlie murphy as well
sucked down there
pretty much ready
let's get them on sorry patty i don't
know i'm just leggings me too
that's some good tongan you got there
you go buddy
tongue ninja grilled ginger for the side
yeah a little grilled ginger for the
side
i can't say no to that
bun's in the oven look at that yeah it's
just butter from yesterday for his
finishing what's that that was from the
marathon that he did yesterday he came
to tenth place
feels sweaty
and he touches the do you guys want to
hear the funniest part of the whole
thing he finishes a 50k marathon in the
rain like dying finishes the race like
yay i lost my car keys
so he lost him in the bathroom so he had
to walk home
he calls me panicked he's like oh what
do i do
lost him in the bathroom apparently
somehow speaks to someone from the town
they find his keys he tells me he's like
you know i gotta tell you i'm wrong he's
like
finding my keys felt better than winning
the 50
that is [ __ ] awesome
imagine you're soaking wet you just
finished 50k you can't get in your car
yeah you can barely stand that is just a
brutal just a kick in the neck so you've
heated this oven up already till about
350 or something
375 there 375. a few minutes and all
right i'm trying to think of what else
we need here that's good it's pretty
simple left over we have the carrots the
tofu
we're putting this down on the table
over there or something yeah i think so
okay here maybe we should make the table
and get some of this over there yeah
all right
some shit's got to be convenient yeah
that's starting to look good i got three
minutes on this battery so i'm going to
put the other one in
extra battery as always
so we're back again oh [ __ ]
that's awesome
so we're cutting up the avi
yeah see avocado
and then we're gonna dress everything
once he's got it all set up right here
he's got the sauce the kimchi the
cucumber the carrots the tofu ginger up
the salad and a variety of sprouts what
are your sprouts patty those are
broccoli and radish micro greens okay
hey patty you want to chop up those uh
those
tomatoes you brought sure
oh yeah a little hit a hash here over
here in the intermediate
there we go a little uh you want them
for the side you want to dice how do you
i think we should put them in the
sandwich why not okay so small pieces
they're big things those slices is good
with the equator
[Laughter]
that's awesome let me tell you dude
always like this and i'm like man
you just you just i love you but you
just [ __ ] up watch yourselves rickson
left us a little oh yeah sweetie oh yeah
yeah
oh brixton
he's pulling
this guy's from quebec you don't have to
tell him how to smoke cash he'll figure
it out no matter what it is it could be
on a [ __ ] pin it could be in a bottle
it could be on the end of a
a traditional fashion when you learn how
to smoke hash is the old hot knife i can
think like 25 years ago when you're on
the
yeah yeah yeah of course
or the coal or the flipped knife right
the double
you know
two knives on there and you you grab it
and then push them together
oh yeah we used to do that hot knives
that was classic we did we did
everything as well that was actually
really good hash that i put in there i
won't i won't lie
i believe it yeah that's why it's
bubbling and melting
people like you can't actually put melty
hash in a one hitter why not i'm like
are you sure
do you remember when i had the ball with
finger hatch oh yeah and i brought it up
the mountain oh yeah so i thought it was
kind of funny
and i was being
kind of silly
and you know we were feeding the whiskey
jacks and everything and i gave him a
little morsel of food on top of the hash
ball and didn't really think about it
he grabbed it he grabbed it he ate it he
flew off but i just
i didn't think about it at the time
right but later on the day and i'm like
man
that poor little [ __ ] is either having
the best time of his life or he's
sleeping it off hopefully i don't know
jesus
the whiskey jacks they'll take it off
you man they're the coolest little birds
don't let them steal your dabs it was
like a quarter pound finger hatchball
let's put some of this on here so that
it doesn't turn brown
good idea
and now let's assemble these things
let's assemble them over here
i want to grab those
oh this is looking
beautiful
i gotta say it really does
oh we're plating now are we we are
so now we gotta like be stylie
we'll try it's upon me so it's not it's
not a super styling but i think it's
going to be i feel like you've elevated
it a little bit between
it's going to be pretty uh colorful i'll
give it that that's for sure it looks
beautiful
yeah even just
just this zombie i mean i ate a small
bowl of chowder before i came so i
wouldn't be starving the entire time and
i did get like starving when you put the
tofu into the pan that's when my mouth
started watering yeah and now my
stomach's actually like
like okay guys like how long is this
going to take
dude
for dinner last night and they told me
when they see my house they get hungry
awesome
yeah this this right here
this is preparation yeah take a couple
of nice shots i just want to picture the
whole zone
here with a bit of this
oh yeah that's nice green sauce man
just suck up on one side
no
tofu
i know i was like damn how many
you can put three on there maybe
it's gotta be three yeah three isn't
three i'm good with a three i'm with
three two i thought you're just gonna do
two
oh what are we gonna do for the oh i
gotta
wash the hands off
next we'll hit it with
some of the carrots
oh yeah
it's like when he says he's putting
carrots on your sandwich
he's gonna put some carrots on yourself
i love carrots yeah the carrots sugar
carrots are so good oh my goodness
a little bit of a cucumber
this is going to be a massive sandwich
just you guys know it's already massive
you smoke a lot of weed you think with
your eyes not with your stomach
right
i think it's good
i think there's nothing wrong with that
oh yeah
okay
let's get some of this tomato on there
did you grow these fatty yep nice
yeah at the cabin it's pretty cold and i
had them in the greenhouse and they took
over the greenhouse and then a lot of
them it froze
so they didn't uh a lot of them weren't
ripening on the planet now you got some
green tomatoes that's delicious well i
actually took a whole bunch of off and i
round paper bagged them and then they
started ripening
okay let's set some kimchi on here
crushing it good luck good luck at that
you know we still got avocados and like
dude i'm just gonna eat it
dude don't worry about that
oh don't worry about that i just like
a little bit of kimchi it looks like
ridiculous
at this point
it's pretty you'll see what the kimchi
gives it a nice sour
taste kimchi
he's just dosing it
if we're gonna do a cooking series we
might as well make some
outlandish food
yeah like healthy outlandish food
exactly it's all vegetarian everything
we've done so far good food
inspiring people so bubble man eats i
got i got inspired last night with the
with the sage there you go oh yeah it's
like a late night pasta and i'm like man
i'm doing some brown butter some sage in
there sage butter after watching the
video or what yeah well because i had
sage i had sage on hand that's awesome
a little bit avocado in there yeah just
a little bit
there's not a little bit of anything on
any of these
only a lot of everything he starts
rocking four tofus
i was like this [ __ ] guy let's get
some of those micro greens in there
oh my goodness
this is really
quite something
these are from your garden too right
yeah i grow this yep
got a little micro greens business on
the side nothing tastes better than from
the garden right
now let's hit it with the dill sauce
i just gotta go to my friend's place for
a quick sandwich
for a quick
look
it's ridiculous keep them open so we can
put them on the table all nice sure
let's see
you want to keep them open yeah yeah
keep them open i want to photograph them
yeah and in the other light this is poor
light over here the light coming in from
your window will be really nice oh and
then the coals off yeah you gotta have a
lot of cool sloths too there's a giant
thing of it that's what will bring the
wife's back this is what we ate
i'm surprised he's not putting it on the
sandwich
it's like well we gotta have a sauce
there's one thing that we forgot for
this whole thing what's that but i have
it and i will grab it yeah
two seconds merle went and grabbed his
cilantro
getting a little cilantroy
you have to on the with the bind me it's
part of it oh yeah
it's all about like the clash of the of
the fresh herbs with the
the spice yep yeah that tiny little bit
that's what i want yeah you want that
one yep exactly like just rip it out
there you go perfect
all right let's bring them perfect
absolutely ridiculous
holy [ __ ] that is beautiful
that is a beautiful thing merle
you guys saw it here
we're now going to consume it
looks amazing dude
like last time we'll take our first few
bites on uh camera and then we're gonna
turn the camera off because uh i mean
holy crap there'll be no talking right
there'll be no talking it's a good meal
if no one's talking wow cheers cheers
yeah thanks guys thank you nice dudes
good
i think this is the technique you got to
take
right
like this
and just close it
just like that and then you can take
your knife and kind of stack it all in
like this
my
god
look i got it me too
that was my
wow
another winner
i would say
maybe
if you're inspired you could follow
along and make your own
cheers
[Music]
that is so good
you're not missing meat with that eh
everything about it is on point dude
ridiculous
well
cooking with merlin and patty
we're signing off boys
peace