[Music]
hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world i'm here with uh
brixton
brixton's in the house and of course uh
the chef merlin it's been a while yes
getting cooked with merlin is about to
begin we figured uh first things first
some dabs get cooked i see you've
already got your dab pre-loaded
pre-loaded
[ __ ]
i like your
so yeah we're going to do a little
cooking here but we figured we'd start
with a dab
we're actually going to do a dessert
today
oh i'm excited man yeah i am a slick
dessert you can make in like 15 minutes
when you're baked at 10 o'clock at night
15 minutes yeah
that's a good amount of time for a
dessert
absolutely
[Music]
i thought he was asking for
quick little dab it's tasty
oh yeah it's got a super great taste
shout out to concentrated x for the
strawberry banana hash rosin that we're
puffing on right now
that was a pretty small one i put in
there
i'll laid a joint
gorgeous day out here gorgeous day the
orcas are out in the water i've already
had multiple friends in the village here
texting me
telling me that the pot of orca killer
whales are
out in the house sounds such a beautiful
beautiful area that we are in here it's
truly um
it's special there's no doubt about it
got the orcas got the dolphins sea lions
and seals and the mountains right now
the snow is great oh yeah it's really
riding pretty often this is insane
yeah i mean i've been trying to get up
to cyprus the which is our much more
local mountain for for merle and i just
20 minutes really from here to the
parking lot in cyprus wouldn't you say
that's what it takes it takes longer
from the highway up to the parking lot
than it does from here to the exit yeah
exactly true depending on how busy it is
yeah
but uh yeah i have been getting up to
whistler and uh definitely taking lots
of sweet shots up there and uh just just
vibing out in the mountains it's my
favorite thing to do really both in the
summer and
the winter yeah like in the summer i'm
up there on dirt bikes
in the winter it's like sleds and
snowboards
and during the week you're making hash
and i'm helping this
sell it yes exactly exactly so merlin
and i are working together he's over at
lifeson leifest
it's kanmar really i know it's canmart
but we want to get this right so they
just changed their name to lyfist
they're working with us over at embark
we just had our sale go through with
bevcana which now they're called naturo
how can you keep up with all this stuff
i'm a lifer so it really doesn't matter
what the banner is that i do these
things under um i'm just always doing
them so
yeah i'm pretty excited to get some of
these products going yeah me too man
absolutely it's uh you know to be able
to get the bubble man brand out there
with the actual hash that i want and the
rosin that i want that is a dream come
true
it's gonna be it's it should be good i
mean we know it's a small group but
they're a group that recognizes quality
when they see it so that's really who
that will be for and
try to make it affordable it's not a
hundred dollars a gram i don't know i'd
love to see it be closer to
like 40 percent less than that yeah
definitely
and it'll be good to have some legal
stuff to dab sometimes because right now
there's not too much yeah it's true it's
true not enough anyway although i did
hit some of that afghan kush that we
made a while ago and sold under the hank
brand it was lacking in terpenes didn't
have a great flavor but i cannot deny
how strong that hash is
close to 70 percent but even know if
it's the number that means anything it's
just it's really strong whatever that
the terpene whatever's modulating it
because it's not just thc a whatever is
modulating it just makes it really like
like heavy
still to this day it's the best hash i
have for going to bed
like if i just if i'm all amped up and
i'm like i just
hit it up yeah
i've been smoking a lot of these like
just smearing like i was saying on these
guys
here in live resin on the joint i'm like
that's a good night joint i have to say
not bad and it burns pretty good what
kind of flower you got in there uh i
have some
what is this
this is wedding cake with uh
with girl scout cookie live bread
so not a lightweight you know
it's a pretty hardcore tv actually as
you can see it burning like you were
saying yeah yeah it's nice but it's
actually not so
and it has a light ash yeah i haven't
smoked a joint a very very very very
very
very long time
well i'm excited to get to watching you
make this okay what are you gonna do
you're gonna make something in 15
minutes it's it's a dessert are we
surprising them we're making a chocolate
raspberry lava cake
and uh yeah it's the best for late at
night and it's actually gluten-free
of course it is yeah right because you
of course just had this discovery yeah
totally so that's good to have to get
pretty experimental in cooking
i think you've already always kind of
been pretty experimental with cooking i
think it's just a shift on the
experiments that you're doing
but i think that's much easier to do
than say go from
a regular person that just cooks kind of
blandly and doesn't experiment a lot to
just trying to experiment yeah you you
experiment dude
we try that's for sure you're like
opening up the book hey look at this man
that looks so good we should we're gonna
make that today like have you ever made
it before he's like no no no we can make
it
i'm like okay this recipe here we i do
it all the time because it's just so
easy it's like nine o'clock at night
munchies nothing to eat oh yeah make
your own nice so let's go do it all
right i'm excited
well
here we are
got cooked getting cooked doing some
cooking start with some tea let's get it
oh thank you amigo that's very nice
you're getting a little mint tea oh
that'd be lovely that'd be lovely
cheers brother cheers dude let's cook
some lava cake beautiful
all right this one's gonna make for four
people
pretty simple ingredients you need
four eggs
five ounces of
chocolate
two
one and a half tablespoons of
gluten-free flour
some raspberry jam
some sugar a bit of vanilla and four
tablespoons of butter
just toss the butter in with the
chocolate put it in the microwave
then she goes do it for one minute and
30 seconds at 50 power and then just
toss it after
i feel like they missed out on seeing
that so i wanted to
give them the best
not so good view but while that's going
[Applause]
get your little ramekins good
when you want to do it is you want to
push it up like this
so that it rises properly
it's just a bit of butter
up we go
[Music]
then put the sugar in there
just toss that around
and you want to just coat the whole
thing and this just makes sure that the
cake doesn't stick to the sides when it
rises
a little bit more
and just make sure that it's coated all
on the sides
here we go the rest of the trash
no more chocolate
chocolate dash butter
chocolate slash butter starts to melt
it's very similar
mix all that together you probably have
to put it back in the microwave for a
little bit
i'm surprised
it feels pretty good otherwise you can
do a double boiler but
yeah
that takes a while it does
kind of gotta pay attention to that
thing too exactly
yeah it's not really a walk away and dab
situation this you can do at your house
super fast at night
first we'll start with the eggs
eggs in there
then two egg yolks
this will make it super creamy
it's good enough there we go
let the chocolate sit for a second we'll
lift these up
you want to beat it so that it's nice
and consistent get a bit of vanilla in
there
you want to get a little bit of salt in
there as well
it's nice to salt with the chocolate
that's next
now you got your chocolate
get it nice and consistent
it smells chocolatey it doesn't it
really does
oh sorry
now
we'll mix the chocolate in with the eggs
this all mixed nice
[Applause]
you want it whip nice so that
it rises well in the mannequins
now get a bit of flour in there
you don't need very much flour
i actually have done this and forgotten
the flour before and it still worked
yeah almost like a souffle
okay
by the way the oven's on at 475. okay
that's a really key point to when you
start this whole thing start the oven at
475. yeah
now we'll pour these things in
try not to drip any on the
sides
now we want to keep just a little bit
left in here
so that we can cover up
the jam
yeah
so let me just take a little bit of jam
here
just kind of push it down in there
scoop it over
cover that little jammy eh yeah
that way it becomes part of the lava
i can kind of just smooth them over just
to make sure there's no jam exposed
these are all good
now toss them on the pan so that the
heat gets distributed evenly
in the oven you go and they go
for eight minutes
oh really
now we can do dabs and make whipped
cream ah very good very good
now we can have our dab that we're all
cleaned up here
i need my torch ah torchy maybe we'll
show them out the window
on such a beautiful day in lions bay
just a beautiful day
in lions bay this is where the orcas
were out here today they were actually
out
over
here
and had we been here with the camera we
probably would have been seeing them
right now they were swimming around
north of that island right there so
just great view
at this spot
band of windows
i hear the sound
beckoning the eye
oh
that was pretty low down by guys
you could use my temp tech if you wanted
or just heat it up again
oh hey hey
hey
[Music]
the plan is to make some whipped cream
yes sir
a little vanilla a little bit of vanilla
oh yeah
here we go
some cane sugar here
a little sugar sugar
and what machine is this oh it's like a
little blender
a little cream whipper
cream
seems like such a ridiculous thing to
just pull out of the drawer
but there it is folks
if you're baked you've been enjoying
some fine cannabis or extracts or
edibles or
whatever
you can make this cake real bad this is
a real fast one we'll put the
ingredients list in the description
and um
yeah
merlin said this is the one he tried to
get it down to 10 minutes he said 13 14
was about as close as he got
um
we're doing more rushing yeah we're
doing a slower version for you guys here
but still i don't think it'll be much
more than 15 minutes
nope there is one minute and 30 seconds
left and we got pretty much everything
set here
our whipped cream is there we got some
strawberry powder too little strawberry
powder
strawberry powder huh
yeah this is just an extract a
strawberry fruit powder
that's what it is it's pretty tasty
should be ready any second here sounds
good
then just take a knife
gently go around
so it can get out huh yeah
that's why you put the sugar too it
helps it to not stick yeah you can
definitely see that the sugar's doing
that
we didn't add any sugar besides the
semi-sweet chocolate that we did
water recipes will tell you to add sugar
but i don't think he needs it
four to go there you go
all right now this is where it gets a
little trickier
because you're not just gonna serve them
in those little cups you're going to try
to flip them upside down be very fast if
you are going to touch them
be careful grabbing them if you are
going to grab them
be very fast
now
give them a little
oh that was like harder and louder than
i would have anticipated
waiting for one of those things to break
these are pretty tough i bet
oh this one not as green
the lava popped first
look at that little guy
[Music]
no one's perfect they come out [ __ ] up
sometimes too but they still taste just
as good
this one definitely looks perfect
then we're gonna add a little this
now to make it
just for our show here
a little wheat leaf
a little strawberry powder
that's so sweet dude
at first i was like what is it he is
doing here
i was like that's a lot to put on there
merlin
getting cooked with merlin
it's always fun a little imprint and
sometimes artistic
sometimes he does art
boom that one didn't work out as good
but
it's still going to taste good i think
so good man
and that's that
dude
killer
that's what's up
all right here we are with our teas oh
yes sir
very good very good this is just picture
perfect
as you guys can see
the cool weed leaf insignia there that
he put on there gotta like
that all right let's take our
opening hit
oh man oh my goodness oh my goodness
look at that
yeah this one look at this oh my god
i better show
this is the best munchy trip ever just
exploded
into the cake i'm gonna give it a shot
gluten free don't say
wow
that is insane
[Music]
okay not just glasses that's over the
top i don't really eat treats too much
these days so that was like a
sugar blast really nice
not too sweet guys no not too sweet
i guess we're going to go and crush this
out
always a joy to uh
film you making awesome delicious
preparations i know i should appreciate
it i know they do
we'll be back when we're back
peace out everybody
[Music]
you