[Music]
hey guys welcome to bubble man's world
uh episode four here cooking with merlin
we've got a new friend would you like to
introduce our new friend marlon this is
my buddy paul we go from way back he's
been working in the cannabis space
alongside me and probably one of the
true head reps out there that smokes
more weed than the rest
trying to keep the culture alive
yeah yeah absolutely he had dabs from a
good friend of mine so that was a good
sign right off the bat it's got this
beautiful little piece here who's this
piece by jt glass jt glass
the opal scope got it from drip glass in
edmonton
all right yeah shove those guys up
they're saying you always get good deals
from good deals from drip glass folks
that's awesome yeah all right so you're
twisting one up and we also made some
halloween gourd dab rigs
oh halloween halloween gourd dabrick so
this is the pickle rick blender gourm
gourd dab rig oh i like how you shave
the bottom off so they're not uh gonna
break yeah exactly attention to detail
is key
dude you guys are hilarious paul came
over we were going to get the food and
he's like i'm gonna make a dab break out
of a pumpkin
lo and behold they're sold out of
pumpkins oh my god
so we went for the next optional
butternut squash and it gave us
inspiration for one of our dishes as
well all right we're gonna make a
butternut squash soup butternut squash
soup is the first
course of today's meal
and that's awesome well i'm down with uh
maybe taking a little dab yeah here you
go
what uh do you do this thing for like 15
20 seconds and let it cool for 30 or 40
or generally do cold starts it's just
cold starts yeah that's what i'll get
cold yeah keeps it nice and simple and
that way you can guarantee you're gonna
have a great time okay i like your style
normally marcus is the most prepared man
ever today he forgot all of his
equipment it's happened already twice
now though out of two times
if you think of it oh it's true
well that's what they say right a friend
with weed is a friend indeed
that's the truth
uh okay well cold starts here we go yeah
yeah nice little jump in there
a little cold start action
sometimes i like to heat up the part
that's away from where it's sitting
q-tips
shout out to jameson for i think this is
one of his treats oh nice yes it is
james is the best
definitely a must visit in calgary yeah
you got a nice little crew in calgary
it's yeah well you're part of the
jameson's crew you got that
dave
yeah dave
those guys are doing some great work at
big league they they're bringing fire to
the market and that's what we need up
here right yeah they're doing great
things in both cannabis and the mushroom
space right now for sure oh yeah i'm
definitely stoked to always pay
attention what they're doing shout out
to chris and jordan and my fungi
it smells pretty good too
very nice a little orangey flavor to her
wow the rosin world really opened things
up i'll be honest you know before rosin
all my friends that were of the
persuasion of bho which i know you
appreciate some nice bho
my friends that spoke bho
they just never we never had like they
would smoke my hash i was just like i
don't smoke bho but now what i find is
that most people that have an
appreciation for bho will also have
rosin in their stash oh for sure
it's all about having a diverse offering
that's nice i think it's hilarious
you just ripped it yeah
pickle rick blended
that's awesome well i figured you
probably blended the soup too didn't you
yeah i'm gonna be doing some double
blending oh yeah so merlin did a little
bit of preparation today because it
would have been literally an hour or
more of time to prepare what he did so
once we get into the kitchen he'll kind
of go over a little introduction and
what he's already done and we'll make
sure that when we give you guys the
recipe if you want to try and um you
know recreate these dishes for your own
selves and families and friends
uh he'll we'll get the recipes put up
the best that we can yeah i'll try and
put the best directions i can on the
recipes and if you have any questions
just hit it in the comments and we'll be
sure to answer you if it's nice yeah
this guy's just like
how much is this doing oh just something
see
salt salt and water into the ocean
and i think the number one question is
going to be do you do birthday party
right
exactly
special appearance from marcus and
merlin to cook some cook some food and
smoke some meat oh yeah
that'd be a fun little lip section yeah
definitely that would be a fun little
lip session it's nice this is so far so
good four episodes i'm excited to see
what we do today roland's got his
sights set high in regards to the levels
of elevation
are we announcing what we're going to do
yet yeah i mean so far we've been doing
a lot of comfort food and today we're
going to kind of elevate it a little bit
so we're gonna do three courses so we're
gonna start with uh
with the butternut squash soup and then
we're gonna go to
beet tartar and then we're gonna finish
with scallops creamed corn and uh barb
lamb
so for those of you that think you heard
beef tartar he did say beet with a tea
as in the root vegetable yeah the beet
tartar i remember the first time he told
me we're having beef tartare i was like
i'll just skip that
he like served it up and i was like you
were there yeah it was delicious on that
avocado bed that was looking like yeah
paul's a regular at our at our dinner
table as well we like to get the homies
together and have dinners on a regular
basis yeah like i was i was saying
earlier generally kind of a picky eater
uh you know stick to heavy meat and
potatoes but
i will eat anything merlin puts in front
of me i mean that'd just be silly not to
lie near horizons
i feel the same way i'm not as much of a
picky eater i think now as i've gotten
older i'm pretty willing to
try anything at least that's within the
scope of my diet
which i don't really have a
title for you know i eat some fish i eat
some seafood
i don't generally i don't eat birds and
red meats but um
no i can keep it pretty [ __ ] i was
brought up a vegetarian my parents are
eating my boys you're awesome actually
they've been to your house hopefully one
day they can do an episode yes they're
actually uh coming out here in december
so that's the episode you should film an
episode of your parents yeah the old
nash guy my dad has worked on hash farms
in the 70s uh in afghanistan and
pakistan nice it's crazy stories before
this yeah he's gonna tell us
some stories well you're cooking you're
dead i was just telling paul about like
my dad's old stories about uh double
zero hash oh yeah 100 kilos for one kilo
that's the true double zero right
totally
yeah and then there's the true skunk man
sam dry sip
99.9999 heads
and that was like
10 grams
per kilo
wow
10 grams per kilo
holy crap yeah one percent
yeah that's uh that's for the five
triple zero
i don't know it was definitely the
strongest product i've ever consumed and
what is that that was in amsterdam first
time yeah
yeah i left cross-eyed
i used to hear people tell stories of
leaving his house cross-eyed and like
uh and then i smoked his hash like a lot
of it because he kept just keeping me
bombing after bombing up after longer
like i'm certain that night he hit 50 or
60 bombers wow i'm certain i hit
probably around 20.
and that was like a lot and i remember
leaving there just being like
trying to kind of get my way home from
the area of amsterdam that he lived in
bikes flying everywhere yeah
oh my god just driving trying to like
not get my tires stuck in a tram track
fall into the canal
falling into the canal was never a
problem but the tram tracks are
deceiving and if you don't pay attention
to them and you you don't cross them
properly and you go like one's going the
same way as you and you go into it
[Music]
it's uh it can get ugly fast how many
years did you live there
i didn't live there for any years but i
traveled there like 40 or 50 times for
sure since 95. lots of trips to
amsterdam yeah it's a great place for
sure i've only been twice but both
memorable oh yeah i mean i'm sure i
probably spent almost a year in
amsterdam if i added come back yeah if i
added up all my time maybe maybe more i
don't know
it's a
definitely a cool city i've never had
the pleasure oh well one day soon here
man
i'm
the world will open up again one day
soon and one can only hope and when it
does
traveling will be afoot
traveling is there but just these
vaccine passports there
yeah but that's not really opening it up
i just mean once it's opened back up
yeah for everyone just yeah
especially not live like um
like under
a medical emergency or a health yeah go
back to normal
yeah or someone that's going to be kind
of normal maybe maybe even normal can be
a bit different because a lot of the
systems we're currently operating on are
like faulty broken
and just need replacing
there's always room for improvement
right yeah
there is i like the way uh greta would
say about the system she's like well if
the system
is not working
you replace the system yeah try to fix
the system just replace it yeah yeah
i'm ready to do some replacing i mean
that's it i mean what it's done for the
workplace as well like you shouldn't
have to go to do a nine-to-five job
anymore unless you're you know unless
you're working a physical physical labor
job most of the jobs that was just
taking admissions for nothing but people
driving to work
too right i mean think about these
commutes right some people spend an hour
in an hour out of the city that's two
more hours of work yeah yeah we're
dabbing what's your point
i like how you think dude
well let's uh maybe think about getting
into the kitchen and starting this
little uh cooking video i like it i'm
excited
awesome
all right we're doing it merle just
called paul in to be the sous chef as
always i will be behind the camera
giggling away and enjoying myself let's
uh let's get to it boys all right
we've already done a little bit of prep
for today i saw you just fill the pepper
yeah filled up the peppermill because we
use pepper and pretty much everything
gotta get that beta carry often that's
right
it's so good anyway so we have a pot
heating up we'll start with the the soup
put a little bit of olive oil in there
and while
i you didn't see it but on on camera but
earlier i made
some butternut with some curry with some
cayenne pepper
with uh or not curry sorry with cumin
powder
and uh with a little bit of salt pepper
olive oil garlic and ginger and then
roasted it all in the oven at 420
degrees 420 degrees yeah that's what's
up and it's pretty much ready right now
so we got a nice little crisp roast
flavor to the butternut squash
that looks like perfect
so we got the butternut squash then we
got the hot pan we got the onions in
there
[Music]
you want to get a little bit of
translucent get some flavor stuck to the
bottom of the pan there
a bit of salt
a bit of pepper
and you can see in here they're kind of
hidden because
they kind of took on the color but
there's like roasted garlic in here
there's roasted pieces of ginger in here
and all that flavor is like trapped
inside and it's all gone
[Music]
once these are
flavor trapper flavor trapping exactly
dude tell me about that uh speaking of
flavor trapping
tell me about your mustache bro yeah
my girl loves the mustache and it's also
movember so you know we'll put a little
bit of support i've actually had a few
friends with prostate cancer so
better off to support if not oh yeah you
look like a dirty porn star so yeah
that's [ __ ] slick or like a plumber
or a cop or something
do you find it's better for the
do you find it's better for sniffing
turps it can it gets stuck in there and
you kind of like you know airs out and
then you get the right smell
flavor filter all right paul you want to
start by putting those into the blender
right over there cool
here these are the beets
once or twice
move it around
scrape the walls off so you can get a
nice consistent beet
i'd rather eat this than the beef tart
oh my god you just ground up
the color of the sun shining through it
too is just like so good man look at
that you'll see it'll be a super vibrant
dish when it's all done how about
you want to stir the onions over there
for me yes sir
do some onion stirring
so now we have these ground up
yeah now that we have these ground up
we'll get them into this pot right here
[Music]
wow
there we go
now
we're gonna hit it with a little bit of
lemon
a little bit of olive oil
it'll give it a really nice shine if you
can see
could you drop it down a bit into the
sun
there you go
really nice makes it a nice shine on it
yeah it really does
you can use all sorts of different oils
i've done it with pistachio oil a little
pinch of salt
a little pinch of pepper
now this is where the real flavor from
this part comes in
with a few capers
you're really preparing food for all of
the senses even beyond the palate
yeah i mean i it's nice to have
different textures and flavors that kind
of bind together it makes the dish
better
once you kind of understand that
everything kind of flows right
so chop up your capers a little bit
how are those onions coming paul they're
coming up great
get nice and brown nice let's just
reduce the heat a little bit on there
let's get our capers in there you want
to get this to
marinate a little bit that's why i'm
getting this one done first
get the capers in and then this is the
part that really adds a little nice kick
to it
is some horseradish a little horseradish
little house and peppa exactly
get all that mixed in there
we're so close to having the sun shining
in it but it's just not quite there i
think we're right here
color is great it's worth doing for
honestly because it was just in the
shade and it didn't have that yeah it's
so vibrant red super vibrant dude yeah
beautiful yeah so now that that's
marinating i'll just let that sit
you want to try it
i'll make sure that you're the taste
tester here cheers man cheers
i was after a flavor explosion
that's very very good
now we'll get these squashes up here
butternut
all grilled up and mashed ready to go
it's about uh
15 to 20 minutes at 420 degrees in the
oven
and it gets nice and soft and then what
did you put on there you said you put
ginger you put garlic whole ginger whole
garlic i put cumin
i put a little bit of cayenne pepper
a little bit of olive oil all of it so
now you can see where it's going to get
a nice coating in the bottom there
you know
[Music]
you want to like burn it to the bottom
almost
it's getting there
stir that all up and boil that out
[Music]
just absorb them
then we'll get a little bit of veggie
stock in here i like to take the stuff
with no salt so that you can adjust it
yourself after
get that going
now we'll turn up the heat on here to
get it boiling
one little extra thing
this is like cooking with
splashes and all yeah dude it's awesome
a little bay leaf in there just remember
to take the bay leaf out before you
blend it
because we're gonna blend this i just
want these flavors we'll make sure we
mention that again sit together exactly
yeah it's definitely very very important
you don't want to eat
sharp bay leaf so usually when we make a
bunch of courses like we're about to do
we serve them one after another today
it's all going to be about timing so
soup's going i think the next part we're
going to do
is the bar grass sauce because it takes
about 15 minutes to mix
we want to get a bit of time so a little
pot on there medium heat
we're going to get some
olive oil right here
so what is a
blah blah sauce
it's a barb language with mean white
butter sauce
not like on fish a lot of the time
you'll see you'll see like a yellowish
white sauce yep i mean it's really gonna
go well and you're calling it bar blanc
bar blend
bar blah yeah
i'm eating white butter
it's a classic french sauce and it's
gonna go really good with the corn and
with the scallops it's gonna be
delicious cool yeah so we'll just let
that heat up a second
um while that's happening
we'll make the avocado mix here
so um
what we're gonna do i cut up these
avocados already yeah i put a little bit
of lemon on them so that it would
preserve it and it stays the color
yeah you squeezed like half a lemon
under them right exactly it just
preserves the with the acid it contains
it right well it kept them from browning
out completely yeah exactly
i'll just scrape that nice green color
[Music]
we're gonna go two full there's two full
avocados here
for four people i would suggest about
two full
maybe put a little bit more
lemon the avocado adds an amazing
texture to the dish it sure does yeah
and this time i'm going to go with a
little bit of dill extra in there as
well
use your people put cilantro but i like
dylan
because it's
super powerful like an herb
what's the terpene on dill
i'm not sure
the top of my head
i'm sure it's got a nice variety of them
for sure is it so pungent yeah
put a little bit of that in there
[Music]
a little bit of salt and pepper super
simple for the avocado
simple is better with mexican food
i don't know if i'd consider this
mexican but
this bottom part of the semi-glock
definitely
shine and you want to get it mashed a
little bit because when we're going to
put it into the molds after
it'll just be
easier to work with
that's why you're not mashing it
completely yeah i won't still want big
chunks yeah but i want it like mashed
enough that it's kind of like emulsified
yeah we'll let that just sit there for
right now well this is hot now
get our shallots in here
[Music]
did you have just a bit of oil in there
yeah just a little bit of olive oil
[Music]
there's not your shallots going
now we're gonna add a little bit once
this these get a little
[Music]
a little translucent of salt as well
just so everyone knows that it looks
like i'm putting a lot of salt it's
kosher salt i'm always using it's a lot
more granular a little less salty a lot
easier to salt stuff
pretty
um much
a little bit of salt i'll sweat those
onions out a bit
or shallots i should say
then
a little bit crazy with this one
i'm gonna put some white wine
we're gonna put some white wine vinegar
and we're gonna let that boil down
i just want this to be super hot and
kind of get some flavor stuck to the
bottom of the pan
before you throw in the alcohol exactly
and then we'll really let these reduce
then it would finish it with some good
butter it would be delicious
these shallots are getting
nice and translucent and super cooked
you can see they're like melting lemons
now we're gonna hit it with a little bit
of white wine about a quarter cup to a
half a cup
let's get the boil out there
kind of hoping for a little more boil
but i think it'll be good and then we're
also gonna put
a little bit of red white wine vinegar
in there as well
now we're just going to let this boil
out and kind of reduce
and then we'll add the rest of the
ingredients beautiful
this is going good all those flavors are
coming together let's just turn it down
and let it simmer
looks great yeah it's gonna be great
at the end we put a little bit of
coconut milk and it really brings that
creamy flavor to it it's delicious
so let this boil down i'm gonna turn
this up a little bit next is prep the
corn
it's gonna be for the scallops that
we're gonna do okay so what's your
favorite dish to cook
i don't really have one i like to cook
something new pretty much every time i
eat
it's pretty good i like to do all those
tiny things if i like something i'll
make it again and again until i perfect
it and then kind of forget about it like
pull it out so it's about the journey
not the destination yeah exactly i like
to always eat it
i don't know it's fun
for me it's like a decompression from
the super stressful work environment see
that's what growing always was for me
that's it was always you know watering
the plants getting in there training
them it was always very cathartic
totally
so this corn has already been boiled
it's pretty hard to find fresh corn at
this time of year unfortunately this
one's from
i think it's from mexico or southern
southern us
it's nice to have pressure corn you can
do it with uh canned corn as well look
at it
frozen corn i should say
a little bit
now we're ready to go with that
we're going to fry that into a pan so
all this is going here
did you say you're going to fry the corn
in a pan
yeah we're gonna fry it in a pot and
cream it with a little bit of cream and
a little bit of parmesan it's gonna be
delicious
i think what i'm gonna do here is turn
this one on in the back
this is where the butter comes into play
we're also going to prep butter for our
barbed sauce if you can look over here
yeah it's starting to
starting to reduce down sure turning
into like more of a sticker goop with
the shallots
so what we want to be prepped for is to
have cold butter
to add in there in increments so you
want
it's a decent amount of butter in yours
it's not for the faint heart i think
butter is good for you
we should put a little rosin in there
with it
oh my god
new floor just
gonna go back
and go to sleep yeah for two days
for two days
yeah i'll get the one piece that it all
was sitting on
i just put a gram in yeah i think i ate
about a gram yeah cannabis that can
eating cannabis can get you
yeah i think that it's a nice one
i enjoy it great sleep
i sleep great all the time yeah oh
absolutely yeah i'm a hash smoker man
house smokers don't not sleep great
because you're not you're not doing a
cannabis smoker
for sleep well i think that when i
smoked cannabis it was different from
when i started smoking hash for sure
yeah it was just yeah for sure i used to
like cough and have like phlegm in my
throat and like cough up little things
sometimes definitely it's more i've
never had that for 20 years of just
smoking hash wow i've never had anything
like that
and i remember that was 20 years ago i
was only like 28.
so i was thinking i was like
i shouldn't be like coughing up like
flam and stuff caught that but i was
smoking
major joints dude like a couple of zips
worth of weed a day big three four five
gram wheat joints you know
silly amounts plus the ceiling was no
bueno for me so oh man
well you made a good decision you're on
the concentrate healthier i think i'm
i'm addicted to just having a joint i
appreciate you having your joints some
of my friends speaking of which
some of my buddies call me the smoking
chef
the smoking chef girl's got a joint in
my
mouth all right this is getting pretty
good here you can see it's very very
syrupy now
now we're going to reduce the heat down
on here
we're going to add in
a bit of a bit of cream
you want to get the heat way down
because you do not want to boil your
cream so take it off for a sec
get your cream in there
about a third of a cup in there good job
not boiling it
stir that down
here i'll get this shot of like you
stirring the pot with a joint in your
other hand that'll be our thumbnail for
this video there you go
a little bit butter is going here
for the butter we're gonna just wait a
little bit and get it a little bit brown
it's called a bar noisette it just kind
of has a little extra flavor it'll add
to the corn and then we'll cream it and
we'll put some cream in there it will
still it'll still be a bit junky too
so now you can see this is turning into
a nice medley right here
a little bit of salt to it
you just want to keep this constantly
stirring
and then as the heat is low we're going
to just stir in
cold chunks of butter a bit at a time
and it'll become like a bechamel kind of
consistency
we'll start with our first one right
here
and you really just want to slowly melt
it in
each chunk at a time
kind of whipping it in almost if you can
see melting it and whipping it and
adding air
we're going to do this a few times
until this sauce thickens up
and then we'll just put it on the side
and wait for our scallops
cube number two
all three of us actually i i guess
we all eat fairly healthy although paul
did have the the record this summer i've
never seen anything quite like it
we spent a lot of time on this on the
road together this summer visiting
dispensaries across this great country
and we had a we had a blast we bumped
into each other twice yeah
from different provinces
yeah and uh we
yeah we ate some pretty good food but
paul ate how many 72 pizzas about that i
touched about 72 different pizzas across
the you know one road trip if you're
gonna he was having like pizza anxiety
like i need to get pizza you'd get pizza
i was sweating marinara sauce man i was
sweating
it was some serious how long was your
trip it was 65 days
okay
73 different cities and we have 421
stores if you can imagine in the 70s of
pizza that means you had pizza almost
every single day of your trip no problem
oh yeah
i was thinking it was like a two-week
trip and this [ __ ] was eating
like six or seven [ __ ] eight pizzas
ten pizzas a day or something goes in
the next butter i was like whoa how many
pizzas did he eat
yeah it's starting to you see it kind of
thicken up and getting kind of shiny on
us definitely
up at the same time we don't want to
forget see we're starting to get a
little bit of a hazelnut color into the
butter we're almost there yeah we're
building flavor on the bottom too as you
can see we're gonna
soak all that up
so this soup is coming along quite nice
as well it's getting bigger this is only
like one
one meal we're gonna have a three chorus
all at once which is hard to do usually
but i think i think i can time it right
for us
if there's anybody that can it's mad
merlin the magic
oh [ __ ] that's why i don't wear white
shirts when i cook anymore
i
had good clothes on last week and i
cooked just melted butter everywhere
unbelievable turmeric pancakes
gluten-free wheat freezers it was with
rice flour corn flour
and turmeric and uh and coconut milk and
it makes these crazy pancakes that's ben
i can't even pronounce it b-a-n-x-o it's
a vietnamese dish and i had all these
chives but then i finished the dinner
and my i was i had like nice clothes on
and my girl was like you ruined all of
your clothes
i did i i did ruin all my clothes
taking care of her all the stuff
but i had turmeric everywhere pretty
much ruined different that's why you
need a good dry cleaner yeah
we're getting nice and browned here
it's time to hit it with our
corn into the
[Music]
a lot of flavor in there
now just to pick up the juices
you will add
a bit of oh wait that's the wrong
this guy's collecting broth like
i love cooking vegetarian food but
during the week i i do cook uh meat as
well
in in
very good moderation though i try not to
eat it all the
i time brought up a vegetarian so i know
what it is we're going to add a little
bit of uh vegetable stock here
and kind of clear off all that stuff
that's on the bottom
get a little bit of liquidity to it
keep that heat moderately low because
we're going to put a little bit of cream
in there as well
to cream in the corn creamed corn
exactly
now we're gonna hit it with a bit of
salt and pepper
you know just let that simmer a little
bit while it heats and then we'll just
hit it with the emulsifiers
we'll be able to do the soup at the same
time
okay how's our barbed wine coming you
can see it's starting to thicken up on
us a little bit here
as we add butter bit at a time
this sauce is going to be delicious
hard not to be with uh it's mostly
butter
exactly well the shallots the vinegar
and the wine really give a nice acidity
to the to it as well so it makes it cool
and it's just going to be we're going to
just have a few little dots on the side
of it with the
scallop and with the corn i think
they're all going to really melt
together as flavors
emulsification to it and you don't want
to go too much because we still want
those beautiful kernels of the
[Music]
corn nicer if you can get it deeper
this show should be in 3d
shit's flipping everywhere if you didn't
notice on the camera there is stuff's
going everywhere oh nice we're getting a
nice thickness here now
yeah that looks great
let's get one more stick of butter in
there one more stick of butter keep it
going
and when it cools it gets really thick
because of all the butter as well right
oh we're gonna strain out those uh
well you know what they say right a
stick of butter keeps the doctor away
now exactly
i'm pretty sure that's what it is yeah
that sounds like a quebec motto
um okay while this is clean let's put it
in the back here let it heat up and kind
of go together
and we'll take care of this um where's
my toms
from there
we're gonna not forget our bay leaves
before we emulsify this
shake the bay leaves out very important
they're not poisonous or anything but
they're super brutal texture
digestion bay leaves
chunks in your meals
we're back at it
all right this thing is thickening up
pretty good for the barbell sauce let's
straight up the shallots
have a little saucy here
for oh filtering it right through here
look at this
it's great you are not joking about how
how smooth that silky that sauce is
going to be oh yeah
and when it cools just a little bit it's
going to get really thick
i wonder if i have a little bit of
truffle oil pad in there to be pretty
good too
truffle oil right yeah
so do you use a spoon sometimes to mesh
that out a little bit
just sort of squeeze you can tell it is
drier than you think right yeah
gravity does most of it for you
totally
oh wow
little veloute sauce there huh yeah
really nice all right
lions bay
lion's bay water
fresh from the mountains
right off the mountain yeah
okay
i will emulsify this thing
catch you
[Music]
looks awesome
when you roast the garlic and you roast
the ginger together it really works well
um i'm just gonna turn that down a
little bit
we've got a pretty good consistency here
oh it looks amazing man
now we're going to add a little bit of
coconut milk to it
i like this brand the argument
a roy d i don't know it always tastes
pretty good did you know in the future
what we'll have to do is we'll have to
get um
our guests and this the sous chefs like
my like short training seminar before we
film
because there's all sorts of things he
could be doing
right yeah right but it's the timing
right you're doing you i just you only
know when you need it exactly so that's
the tricky part
so that whole canon in there goes in
there it's gonna get extremely creamy
just diluted the color so nice yeah
that's like the color of spring
or fall i should say sorry
the color of fall butternut squash is
like a very fall time
yeah it's one of our favorites at home
you've never had one before you've never
had a butternut squash soup
you don't eat much vegetables yeah like
most things you cook i have not eaten it
before
yeah
yeah this is a good one man
i'm gonna put butter in the soup pick it
up no it just makes it a nice silkiness
right
you'll see it gets a nice shine to it
you know this can use a little bit of
that
truffle oil
oh a little bit of the soup that we
talked about last time oh yeah a tiny
little bit of herb spicy
[Music]
there we go
i would say a little bit of salt as well
but you can really taste the ginger in
the soup it's delicious
season it all up you want to grab a
spoon there paul for
good marcus try you want to try a
two-pole grab another spoon here no
slice do it dude that is on point yeah
are you kidding me that's great oh that
is delicious
great
and we didn't really do that much icing
besides the initial one when we played
if he spiced it slightly different it
would be a dough
it tastes like a buttermilk dumpling
it's not too far off it's not too far
off and i think the lentils
exactly exactly well use
in here i put a little salt slice them
on an angle put a little bit of olive
oil a little bit of salt a little bit of
pepper now we're going to put them in
the oven at our favorite number 420 420
degrees in the go
while that happens i think that this is
ready that's ready let's get the pan hot
for the scallops
let's get the pan hot for the scallops
[Music]
where they're
okay so that's heating we've got to prep
the scallops at the same time which uh
i'll show you guys how to do
[Music]
find where i put them
i think they're up to the left above
your tomatoes
and above the tomatoes yeah nice all
right so uh it's really important to
prep your scallops
and everybody knows this but there's a
little membrane
around
a scallop like a little muscle that you
have to take off when you get them
because that little muscle is super
chewy
man i wonder if that muscle in that
little creature ever thought
there would be a group of beings that
would classify that muscle
as chewy yeah
that's a real existential crisis yeah
man i got these two muscles
sure
if only scallops like evolved to have
more of that muscle maybe humans would
leave them the [ __ ] alone
they're just all around you so if you
want to see out thinking like that we
can thank for delicious tasty weed
there you go for real
okay so you know what i don't know this
one does no
so this sometimes they have it sometimes
they don't luckily on this nice beauty
one we don't have it so okay here's a
perfect example
if you can see right here there's an
extra muscle that you can see that's
attached here oh yeah and you kind of
just peel that guy
right off
and then you have your scallop so this
one's good right that one's good exactly
so you want to put them on a nice dry
towel because you want them padded dry
that one has a technique that we're
going to be doing well that's true i
kind of feel like i'm peeling off the uh
iono ribeye
it is kind of that way
that last one has one too
yeah before i realized this every time i
made scallops and especially when you
make like a ceviche or something you can
cook properly yeah and when you make a
ceviche you know that chewy part of this
scallop
and everyone is like ugh what is this
that's awesome
i'm just gonna wash my hands again
a favor here and we'll drain out the
beet mix that we had here and then we've
kind of let it sit together and as you
can see there's a lot of juice left in
the bottom of here
it'll spill out all over the plate so
what i like to do
here
grab a little strainer
and then just put all that bead in there
and then press it down so that we can
get all the liquid out of there
we'll build our plates for our beet
tartare dish
okay
and i got a little mold here
so i like to do it with a round mold
let's start with oh okay get your little
mold there exactly
and then we're gonna start with the
avocado
kind of push it down to the bottom there
really nice distribution
[Music]
now we're going to grab our beat mix
here paul you're going a little too
crazy over here all right so is this
stuff already strained is what you're
what that is yup okay perfect
you don't have to go too hardcore i just
want to get a little bit of the juice
out so it didn't go all over the place i
wasn't sure what kind of pressure you
wanted at the plates no stress brother i
love it so here now we're gonna add some
beet in
there um
yeah i'm pretty baked
sweet this is the best time yeah we
definitely will hit a rip before
hey paul you want to know what is my
favorite sous chef to do is line lineup
dabs while i'm cooking is the best thing
ever gourd dabs gourd dabs it is okay so
now that one's ready
we're going to slide this off
holy christ dude that looks so good
great colors just
you've got it right in the sun you
couldn't have had it in a better place
to share with everyone
you know yeah the reveal was really good
and then wall sorry what did you say
well that's well these are i'm making
these i'm gonna have a
rip dude look at that mustache happy
halloween folks
that's gold we're also going to roast a
few pine nuts here okay
so this is always tricky you don't want
to burn those yeah
roasting pine nuts and burning them to a
crisp is a fine line it's a very fine
line have you would you say that
something i learned this week though is
that a dry roast is much easier to
to handle so we're gonna have no oil and
we're just gonna dry roast in a cool pan
in a cool pan we're going to put it at a
low heat it's not going to take very
long but
it'll be just gravy and they're not
going to burn before that nutty flavor
kind of comes out perfect so we'll just
finish these up real
dude that quick looks so nice with the
sun on it now i'm blocking the sun but
we've had about a month of rain
and it's nice to have a few days of sun
that's so nice
the two colors
are a banger just alone yeah totally
well then then you add the textures
and the flavors it's a triple threat
totally hey paul would you mind checking
on the croutons in the oven
hard and then it pulls out nice and
straight there
and number three
you just want to make sure when you do
with the beats that you push it down
really hard otherwise
it well not really hard but like with a
bit of pressure
that way the mold comes out nice and
easy and you don't get beads all over
you i see you tapping the edges too yeah
exactly you want to really push that
down
make a nice flat surface on the inside i
don't think you messed it up
okay now we got our three
dishes there
just pulled out the croutons just pulled
out the croutons they're nice and brown
they look great now we can just let
these rest a little bit while we get the
rest of the meal ready you kind of smell
a little bit the pine nutty flavor
coming out they're getting a little
rounded see they're dry roasting yeah
yeah dry roasting a little pine nut
flavor
it takes you know you really get the
flavor out of here before burning them
if you put oil they'll burn before you
get the flavor out okay okay we got a
little preparation going on here this is
a little behind-the-scenes b-roll it may
make it into the show it may not
the old b-roll set up
yeah dude
dude how about that let's give him a
little shot of the glacier across the
way
yes seriously
winter is here in the mountains
i gotta get my drone we would have done
a drone video
i did let everyone know that the drone
is gonna be back
it's coming back the battery's ordered
it's the top of anvil island that we're
looking at right now
i went to squamish the other day
and there is faces that you can ride
right now oh yeah whistler has like
three meters of snow
i was in squamish the other day too yeah
all right let's see if we have enough
time to do another quick little
dabaroo here
see watching merlin get a dab made me
want to take a dab
nice
another little
start now
this is not the best dabber
for dropping cold starts in but
i didn't bring any of my gear
so i'm blessed to have access to what i
have
let's give it a cold start
this
that
was tasty
wow
three perfect low temp dabs right there
well perfect abs
get ready for some perfect meals i love
that you guys have both been in the
background of this little
clip we can come back here
well i'm gonna clean this
it's all nice set up oh yeah all right
well i'll come set up the camera over
there
let's clean the banger
get the tripod here
probably have to go get my other battery
because this one looks like it's almost
done
oh yeah
the nuts are almost roasted here the
nuts are roasted look at that dry roast
nice
brown color on them looks amazing
looks amazing can we just grab these
nuts and put them on there now it's
great oh yeah
so how am i going to set this camera up
you want to finish the cook first
oh sure absolutely that's a good idea
all right we got our pine nuts cooling
over next to our tartare now the next
step here is get our pan super hot for
the scallops which is the final part of
our dish everything's warm everything's
ready
prepped plates are made
i think we're getting to good heat here
we're going to add a little bit of grape
seed oil
it's a lot higher temperature
and one of these not too too much but
just to coat it right
wait a second
get a little out
yeah just want to get the coat there
okay
now we're getting out there let's get
our scallops that we prepped earlier
that are super nice from the market down
the road here
you want a nice padded
dry a little bit of paper towel on there
that way we get a really good sear
you can kind of round them out so now we
got this high temp here
yeah i think that's gonna be good so
when you put them down this is the most
crucial part for the good sear is you
want to get them down and really place
them and push them down firm so that it
gets a nice crust on it okay
i like to do the widest side down first
it's a nice
presentation
now for me i know that my pan is hottest
over here so i concentrate mine right
now
with a gas grill you wouldn't really
feel that same
hot spot well i imagine there's hot
spots on on gas problem would be
different for that yeah
that's very good comes in
distributed
but even then there's still a hot spot
in that pan for sure definitely cast
iron is the way to help on that
let those things dry out now the whole
key to this thing is you want this first
sear
at the high heat with oil
and once those are seared when you flip
them you essentially want to start
hitting it with butter and basting it as
you go okay now that i think about it
just so it's a little bit better
we're gonna add garlic
into the bottom of that pan as well it's
going to make it super tasty butter
that's going on top
out
we'll keep those sitting on the side
right here
along with our cubes of butter
now these you can tell underneath it's
starting to get a pretty good little
browning sear on there
hey paul while we do that you want to
just help them you can
[Music]
chef ocd
it doesn't make all the difference in
the world if you drop a drop on the side
of the board
you you eat with your eyes now look at
this that's like that's just what you
wanted to look like
now we got a nice sear on all of these
oh look at that
and you'll see they kind of like stick
in place when you flip them back over
this is when we hit our garlic down in
the corner start hitting it with a bit
of butter
really a lot
you're getting a little bit of flavor in
there now we want to just
tilt your pan up like this as they're
frying
and just literally spoon butter garlicky
butter
all over those scallops for them to
finish
[Music]
get that garlic right up in there
you really want to do this at very high
heats
so that it really gets that good sear
when you go down you can get a little
more heat going
back to it and then you can pull it back
up you don't want to do this too long
about two minutes aside probably at the
moment
you can see all that lactose foaming up
but it smells so garlicky good
and the butter pretty much bastes and
cooks the scallop itself right
okay
these are getting pretty close to ready
for two seconds in that pan and let them
finish off i grab something
to hold them in
while we wait to plate we want a little
bit of paper towel
we have our nice barbed sauce that is
really kind of reduced down and it's
super nice
um at the same time we will set up
planking over here as well
for a scallop so why three plating areas
if you guys can see right now we're
going crazy today yeah you do and yeah
you are and yeah you did
okay here we go these are all ready to
go
okay now it's going to be plating time
so let's start with our we'll start with
the scallops paul's wonderfully done
here wonderful didn't mess up at all
good job
we're going to start with the corn for
the for the scallop so we'll put a
little
dollop on each one here
i like to make little piles first to
kind of measure
exactly how much corn we have each
you want to be nice and generous on the
corn it's delicious
you can see that like burnt butter or
browned butter i should say
color of it
and we'll just give it a quick little
swipe down
okay
just make two nice little dollops there
on the side
this is when it comes in handy to be
baked to do this you kind of take your
time
totally
and then we'll grab our scallops
you missed the public okay these look oh
that looks spectacular
just in that butter white butter sauce
it really has thickened up as it cool
down
yeah it's going to be delicious and then
for the smell of color
get a little bit of parsley on there
as well over here we're gonna put
parsley on all of our soups
i think i got a little more left here
i like to throw it around all right now
let's finish our
let's finish these put a little bit of
pine nut roasted pine nuts on the top of
them
and then we're gonna grab a little bit
of these alfalfa sprouts
just build a tiny little nest there
tiny little nest there
now we'll grab a little bit of olive oil
this is infused with garlic
12 year old vinegar
12 year old vinegar right yeah
there's not very much left so it's okay
you're still getting it yeah
just for a little touch it's super sweet
it's delicious and just add some toasts
to here
for scooping
exactly finely baked
finely baked like us
exactly
there you go so
get good going
what's the one extra
you know what i think we're gonna put
this up front i like it
so ridiculous dude
there we go let's set up the chairs here
oh my goodness dude
like honestly sure this is so
ridiculously gnarly
i don't even like it
i guess you know what you should start
by announcing what each dish is and then
just gobble it up so we got a pan-seared
scallops with a barbell and a creamed
corn with a barn rosette
and then we have
our butternut
squash roasted soup with garlic and
ginger yep then our beet tartar with
roasted pine nuts avocado
and
some sprouts and vinegar and oil
well that's just absurd and ridiculous
on all levels but why don't we take a
bite of each
thing here and
as we do we'll let you know what we
think i think you know what we're going
to think but
oh my goodness
they just fall apart
just fell apart
the trick is to get up another car oh
yeah
that barble is amazing
i think it's really quite incredible
the contrast plays really well together
this is definitely loud
that was spectacular i could have
crushed that like
non-stop
soup it's hard to put it away right now
isn't it yeah
well the soup is just
delicious even like the way the
aftertaste that that plays with this
yeah it kind of works so good
just the creaminess of this
yeah the texture of it is absolutely
silky
[Music]
garlic
that's really nice these are all
ridiculous yeah
this is such a sweet looking dish as
well as
clearly being delicious with the 12 year
vinegar
croutons as your
kind of pork i guess yeah exactly
again that contrasting texture is just
impeccable
seems to be a really good theme working
through today
two thumbs up for me
everything's awesome dude
would you give it six stars
definitely give it six stars there you
go
that's a 90 micron full mount meal right
there right there
looks like full mountain clear double in
that clear dome right there just try it
try try uh try going that film yeah
exactly
purity excellence achieved
wow
that's a great way for people
who have a hard time with avocado
to go into it to get past it yeah
really
really yeah it's really a different dish
with the horseradish gets a little
pungent
yeah it's like a spring dish for sure
and the capers give it a salty
well knocked it out of the park once
again i feel like you pulled the cape
around my taste buds
super pleasure
oh it was an absolute honor i say with
the amount of time and energy
that merlin put into this we owe it to
him now to focus our attentions on this
meal
thanks everybody for watching the recipe
will be in the description
and
i'll see you next week
[Music]
dude