[Music]
boom
ers
[Music]
thank you
all right Merlin and I are joining
forces here at the Saint Joseph La
boqueria the the market off the ramblast
ramblast behind us this is the craziest
busiest [ __ ] Market ever to meet a
person at it's probably not the best
idea if you're not from Barcelona to
meet your friends at the market but
let's go [ __ ] pick some food for
getting cooked with Merlin
yes yes
excuse me
do you have any idea do you want to lead
the way or are we making Ceviche tonight
yeah
it's right here even look at all this
crazy [ __ ]
let's do this ridiculous oh my gosh
it's pretty crazy isn't it
this is amazing fresh cut fruit
we're gonna try and find the fish
[Music]
some artichokes we'll have to do a
couple of a couple of rounds a lot of
places selling the same stuff eh
God is it look it smells so good that
fruit
gosh
[Music]
first whatever you like man whatever you
like
what's up
some cheese
can I get like um
what do you suggest I'd like like three
different cheeses something low
oh [ __ ]
oh it's fun and those TVs
one this way and one the other yeah
[Music]
there's some langostinos
forgot to film it Merle you're buying
stuff for the dinner are we getting
cooked with Merlin we're getting cooked
we're already cooked that's what's up
64 jars deep look at these things
[Music]
you have the olive store here dude
oh my God how about these uh artichokes
that's already chips
she's finishing these people up
[Music]
foreign
some nice veggies
[Music]
oh here's where we were earlier yeah
I'm gonna go this way yeah
totally
over there
oh look at this Merle Merle Merlin
this was the woman that let you wash
your hands of your sink and look at
herself this is all salt nice so is this
Barcelona original salt
[Music]
all right
babe
[Music]
so you've gotten back from the market
Merlin you got the bread
the tuna the cheese
the artichokes these [ __ ] mangoes are
ridiculous
some of these plums lemons potatoes
oranges aubergine olives olive oil
heirloom tomatoes big old artichoke
morels
[Music]
see asparagus and a bunch of microgreens
flowers this is just ridiculous I'm
excited I have not been hitting many
dabs on camera which I apologize for I'm
going to try to do more of well just
took the most beautiful dab number 17
smells like [ __ ] bananas
beautiful
really tasty
and of course Merlin
is prepping the Foodies
dude this is like deja vu
cooked with Merlin and Barcelona yeah
dude I'm gonna come join you in a minute
here all right so I haven't been filming
Merlin's been busting ass over here he's
already got the egg per the aubergines
opened up and salted is that what you
did yeah okay and then you got some
water boiling over here
okay slice it and fry it crunch that
[ __ ] up and we got some leeks
right here oh you're frying leeks
[Music]
throw me off a bit should we go to choco
okay I gotta keep going on I think I
have something
I'll twist you up a fatty if you have
some
[Music]
there you go
thank you sir
thank you
cooked with Merlin
oh [ __ ] dude this looks beautiful yeah
[Music]
flowers little edible flowers good
this just looks great
up s
[Music]
oh yeah the last touch
you got that charcoal salt chocolate
Salt
oh dark charcoal sea salt
on a real mixed dish
looks delicious
Mediterranean ingredients
with Merlin's zest
for cooking
[Music]
walking away and I'm walking away
just need some bee footage of this [ __ ]
[Music]
five thousand square meter Greenhouse so
like that's great 5000 square meters but
we have it you have a 300 foot like
square foot like you know I want to hear
more about your about that thing that
you were talking about that patent you
got not my trans trouble yeah ah okay
I'll give you the full pinch then so I
might is it is it Alex right yes I
remember I got your name right
no yeah the transdermal pan it's uh it's
quite something man
just waiting
um
no that's that's dry that's the that's
the stuff
dude you're still going over here huh a
little eggplant you know yeah but a
Spanish eggplant eggplant
the Cajun dressing foreign
here
balcony
this looks like a sauna nice little
balcony though right yeah it was awesome
I love it
what do you got going on now some pasta
pasta potatoes
oh that looks nice dude
some potato
mushrooms
my shit's fogging up bro
there you go
I think you said it was Cactus though
Cactus you know
that looks yummy all right getting
cooked with Merlin pasta is in the House
pass it clams and mushrooms let me see
those longest dinos
[Music]
Jesus
yeah okay
[Music]
that looks amazing man
black salting it up
nice sound
so you want me to take two of these do
it yeah
[Music]
I was ready to go
Amigos that's a lot of food I know you
don't have to finish at all don't feel
that way
I go this is gonna be yummy
it's called great gas great gas
cultivated by a friend of mine
um his name is Zach and he grows like uh
in living soil living soil indoors oh I
like that yeah the living soil indoors
yes a bunch of rounds in the same bed
and his product is just stunning like
everything from his garden
as you all know I didn't do much I just
separated the heads but it's very
beautiful
Mr that's the rose we started doing um
oh absolutely it's kind of a cold cure
hash we played with the texture here a
little bit yeah
we never whip Edge when we decided to
whip a little bit this one
yeah I was like Wow Let's try it out
yeah it's kind of fun
yeah Bravo Merlin yeah
[Applause]
we're finishing it off with some of
these what are they the garbages
remember the name all right yes what is
it
what is it like
uh it's not the mental you know it's
like aluminum or whatever it is it's
like like
yeah and you squeeze it so like it's
like your hair so yeah yeah
oh yeah
oh
[Music]
my God
my life is open why the sun was up in my
face
[Music]