[Music]
hey listen welcome to bubble man's world
we are here for episode five of cooking
with merlin and we have men and who
brought remo hey how's it going
rainbow's in the house we got we had it
well we had a request for you in fact
last week someone was like man you guys
got to get ramo on there cooking with
merlin all right we were here i was like
all right let's let's make it happen so
really good to see you dude it's been
way too long first of all yeah like
really
seriously i haven't seen it since the
trailer
that's what just killed it there's been
no shows there's been no events and
i usually see um not in our country but
like in spain or in some foreign country
i hang out with bubble man not
[Music]
we live far away from each other but i
still i've made i've made the trek out
to your area a few times and it was
really nice to hear that you guys were
going to be able to make the trek out
here to merlin's place and uh he's got a
really nice meal planned for us here
today
tacos yeah he's got a whole whole bunch
of uh tacos
i'll do what i can do whatever you need
me to do it's not gonna be very hard got
a light set for you i'm going to get mrs
grower to drive that because it's
medicated
that smells amazing oh my god dude
that's strawberry banana living gold
it's the living gold is that from dna
dude this is from dna that's the doctor
that you just quoted
you just quoted the doctor yeah dude
that's amazing so let's talk about that
for a little bit because when you said
it i was like
for just a split second i was like how
does he know about the living gold but
then i remembered
we linked up in jamaica many years ago
and we traveled up to my buddy's grow
it wasn't a hike it was a straight wall
climb
it was like a no we were climbing a wall
like it was a ladder and i remember when
we got up there and he had like 55
gallon buckets and stuff and i was like
how did you get this up here and he was
like
on my head
like he climbed up this wall with these
huge things on his head
you know the other crazy thing about
this is we got to the top and uh
myself we're just like sweating oh my
god we're dying and there's not one
droplet of sweat i know
you remember he also he also climbed
that mountain
with shoes that had no shoelaces and the
tongues of his shoes were flipped out in
front of his shoe yeah and i remember
just being like looking at me in remo we
got like you know like the proper shoes
all tied up good and like i'm looking at
the doctor and he's just like are you
okay
you know kind of just like i don't know
it's a full-on jamaican experience but
the only the weird thing about that trip
is that when we sat um
in his little hut and we're smoking the
living gold he kind of gave me
some foreshadowing of what the next few
years my life was going to be like
because he
i don't know i had this captured on on
video where he starts telling me that
don't worry cannabis is going to take
care of you it's going to give you food
it's
since right no this was in western
he's doing really good man i mean he's
still got eight foot long dreadlocks and
yeah mikey was his name and they called
him geronimo because he used to drive so
fast
it was like geronimo
like he would just rip by like it was
kind of funny because he was the super
chill dude but he would drive like an
utter maniac and i remember all the
stash spots that he used to have on his
car and i was just like dude like
these stash spots are not good and you
are the ultimate heat score like he's
got his joint was like four times the
size of that like no he used to roll
these giant like
15 gram joints that were only like that
long but like that wide and he just he
would just have it hanging out of his
mouth all the time
he was uh definitely a character he
crushed sugar cane for us and made like
passion fruit sugar cane some other
juice when we were up on top of the
drinking amount of gourds dude it was so
good
a really jamaican experience authentic
yeah that was authentic for sure
shout out to mikey the good doctor
geronimo if you were making that uh
bubble hatch we made that big
i absolutely remember the ocean uh
i remember was like crashing against the
wall and you could hear the ocean around
there i was staying there yeah yeah
beautiful setting to make out that was
unbelievable it was the nicest place
i've ever made hash in my life you've
seen it there must be videos of that to
be honest i'm just certain that we
filmed that and we just documented the
whole thing we put it up i'm not sure
where it is now because we made it well
what we wanted to do today was film this
intro
do the cooking but i brought the rosin
press and i've got that turned on and i
thought maybe you could capture the
rosin pressing for your channel we can
kind of cross
it yeah okay give you the money shots
sure so we got the camera we got the
sasquatch m1 i saw you brought the
camera that's a nice humor quick awesome
well i'm going to hit this dab real
quick shout out to concentrated x
and everyone else that is going to make
this dab happen
yeah
sounds like it's going to take off
it feels like it's going to take off
like when i'm when i'm hitting it i feel
like it's just going to go
shoo like a spit a fidget spinner or
something
so i've gotten away from my wasteful
ways of q-tips and now i'm in the
wasteful isopropanol phase
no no this is actually good it's an
efficient way your bangers are always
going to be clean
beyond
and actually if you're dabbing on the go
that's awesome because you can just like
dab a hot dab throw it in there cools it
yeah and you can go it's nice that it
doesn't chas the banger you know these
bangers are like 400 us dollars
yeah yeah so once you've heated them up
too much and you don't clean the little
bit of resin that's there and then you
heat it up again for the next ab it just
starts darkening darkening and then you
have to torch it to get it off and it
kind of creates a foggy glass which i
love the fact that he frosted this glass
already right i think that's a good idea
to you know poor johnny b he's told me
he's gone through like he doesn't buy
these ones he buys the the chinese ones
that are like
20 to 30 to 40 dollars but yeah he was
like
he was telling me the other day he went
through like a dozen of them or
something like because he just he keeps
chasing them
you should do clothes first you gotta
you understand using cannabis for pain
yes cold starts are not the best for
using cannabis for pain they truly
aren't like john likes hot gaps for
preserving the turks yeah that's the way
to go you get all the trips absolutely
absolutely but have you ever hit one
that's just too hot and then you're like
whoa
i am way higher than i normally am yeah
i think we can all agree when you when
you hit a 900 degree dab you're just
like your lungs are on fire your lungs
are on fire and your throat hurts
it's not good it's not i agree but i
definitely don't know i'm a grandparent
and
i want to live forever dude
i'm a level three now i'm almost uh you
know you know a jedi ground here you
know
yeah almost there so i could lift my
grandkids if i go with cold starts like
a little longer probably
i go with the temperature i go with the
temp oh yeah and then it tells me
exactly like that that rip i just hit
was at
575 degrees fahrenheit nice nice to be
in control right well i i appreciate it
that's for sure
so what do we say should we um
yeah i better check on to make sure i
started ahead so
check check check we'll see what we're
gonna do we'll see what order we're
gonna do things
um definitely you're gonna wanna go
check out ramos channel um because the
rosin pressing that we're gonna do and
he brought what was the cultivar again
uh well i got the frosted fruit cakes
which is uh my green base for everything
right now
i wish i could put the smell up it
reminded me of like engaged television
it smells like
fruit or something it does that's what
it smells like no kidding like it's not
dude like it smells exactly like fruit
loops it even has the the
like it has the flavor profile of like
the fruity smell but then it even has
that background flavor of like the
mildly stale whatever the cereal is made
out of
that is amazing dude it tastes like
something
too that's crazy
that she just brought me oh you're
puffing it too yeah damn all right well
i'm down with making some raws and uh
taking a dab or two of that because that
sounds ridiculous then i brought another
one this is the new one it's called
assay berry gelato okay i think uh and
this is another edition from ripper
siege oh it's a ripper
really good producer actually it's the
best thing in my room right now that's
really nice as well i'll have to take
some pictures so um i always like
it's not good light right now for me to
go and
bring this up close but i could take a
couple of pictures of the bags
well you know what i think that's fine i
think uh there's a couple good buds in
there we can pick out and it's a little
joyous
please i also like hash too you know
don't get wrong i love hash
every wednesday i celebrate hash on uh
you're not prejudice hash wednesday you
know i do for the catholics right did
you have to pass me a joint a couple of
times during this video so i can go like
this and then 400 people can write in
the comments
but nobody's expecting it
but you know what
you've taken it before and oh yeah [ __ ]
here you go i don't do this i just did
it ten minutes ago all right yeah every
once in a while i don't mind i don't
mind you know what i think the way to
beat it is actually
a salted hash joint like those hazel
hashtags
now you're on it there we go all right
well we're going to get to cooking and
we're probably going to get depressing
rosin to check out the rosin video
you'll have to check uh go head over to
remo's channel
and uh
you want to tell them that channel urban
rainbow on youtube
youtube.com backslash urban rainbow yeah
that's us awesome
um yeah we're gonna press some raws and
i'll try to get some pictures i'll try
to get some footage um but it will end
up over on his channel so make sure you
go there to check it out right now
awesome
let's do it welcome to sunday's cooking
we got remo as our guest roland joins us
thanks for having me and i'm getting
cooked while i'm here dude time out how
big did we get oh we did some dabs and
you can check that out my channel and we
got mangled
fully mangled
this is pretty quick this is the most
baked we've gotten to do cooking with
merlin so uh have have patience with us
people watching but we're gonna have
some delicious mexican food too dude
you've done an exceptional job preparing
this already i'll say that about it i
look great remote's gonna be my sous
chef today yes and i have no cooking
experience there you go i can burn water
right no stress today we're gonna make
some some good hummus actually she's
really made that before
it should be pretty easy never made it
before lined up for you here
so what's that made with chickpeas or
something yeah exactly we're going to
eat it with uh we have some cauliflower
and that's going to be our side and then
we're going to have three different
tacos we have
shrimp tacos
argentina shrimp those are uncooked even
though they look cooked it's just from
argentina how they are beautiful and
then we have some uh
halibut
uh deep fried health that's been
marinating in buttermilk and uh spices
it's gonna be delicious that looks that
looks awesome yeah it's kind of jeez
so uh isn't there isn't there
fruit here too we had this earlier yeah
that thing was crazy pomelo we're gonna
use this for the ceviche actually that
we're gonna do too
on the side since we had a bit of it
left over so i thought we'd do it i'm
going to put it in here you can try it
right here it's like a dry grapefruit i
will try it it's super tasty little if i
just pick a piece out of this or go for
it it's just they're huge if you can see
that here check it out the thick skin
there's pink ones and yellow ones
actually
i think they're super tasty crunchy add
a little crunch to it there's a third
taco is there not there is a third taco
there's also a sweet potato taco which
is pretty much
coming to a finish right here in the
oven we got kale
and uh sweet potatoes in there
and then we're deep frying the other
stuff and we got some pickled onions
that we just made before too that are
going to be super nice nice
yeah it should be pretty tasty so
preparation
for the ceviche i guess
i like to soak it with the lime for a
good like hour half hour to an hour
prior and then add all the extra goodies
stuff so i'm gonna put some mango
and put some red pepper
see i find cooking so much easier when
all the stuff's normal
it makes it a lot easier like that way
more of this roll like this right and
then some jalapeno
oh it is nice yeah like you've just got
it all super properly prepped and then a
bit of cilantro in there as well a
little bit eh yeah
it's gonna taste good and we got a lot
of lime in there mix all of that up
ceviche
[Music]
i like the tapas i also like the paella
oh yeah yeah
we'll hit that with a little bit of
that's real spanish food
for real
you got that doobie going you know it'd
be really good in here too i think we
have a bit of mint
a little bit of mint
he's got his device he's puffing dudes
what are we doing
i did get mangled off those dabs oh yeah
definitely
mangled
put the garlic in there okay put the
garlic in
showing the garlic
and then it goes
we're all in no
that is tahini so it's like oh yeah
organic fair trade tahini yeah it's like
a garlic uh or a sesame paste
okay
two of those
loaded up with a bunch of olive oil in
here as well
more of these
yeah
there you go
and then to make the nice color we're
going to put these beads
i boiled for about an hour and then took
the skin off
damn
i'm just gonna just turn this red
and then you want to hit it with a bunch
of peppermint oh yeah
pepper it up
pop it up
clean the window the ceiling
the skateboard
on that yeah it's like insane actually
that's pretty nice huh i've never seen
i mean i grew up i was vegetarian
because
probably 13 or 14 before i
started eating meat my parents are like
super big hippies so
cool we lived off the garden pretty much
that's awesome yeah
dude we're gonna have your dad on the
show one of these days robert plant
he's like an old uh
he was like an old smuggler back way way
back in the day in the 70s and like
afghanistan and pakistan like he had a
red hair so they called him a
hat you know once in your life you have
to go to like mecca and you can dye your
beard red right but he had a natural red
beard so they just let him everywhere
and i was like perfect yeah working in
hash farms all over the place over there
hash farms
got some eggs in there
and whip it up looking good
a little shrimp first i guess
yeah whatever you think man i guess
because they have less the shrimp yeah
exactly we'll do those next but uh we'll
see
egg and bread those things are there
for this one
yeah yeah wait a second smoke that joint
dude okay i can do that i'm good at that
yeah smoke that joint i do have
something we can do
okay
i'm gonna get him to scoop out the
avocado yeah exactly
and he's already put the lemon juice on
there too
like it just fell out that was
awesome
that's how you want your avocados for
sure
and this it's like a bit of corn starch
flour and some uh baking powder to make
it kind of rise a little bit okay you
want to coat it so that it seals for the
oil
and then we'll get it in the egg and
we'll get it in some panko avocado for a
room in the bowl
and then you'll put some of these
ingredients in sure
there we go
same size dash for the red
good onion of red onion
another dash
that's up two dashes two dabs two dashes
a little bit that's good
okay a little bit of salt and pepper in
there so
we got the pepper jar
i'll take care of the salt
oh look at you guys go this is really
this is cooking with merlin right now
there you go oh yeah
and we'll get a little bit of lime juice
in there
hope you like pepper that should be good
like that okay
oh hey is it supposed to be a red circle
or a green pause on the camera here
i'm totally joking i'm gonna do that all
over again i've been recording the whole
time but i just thought i'd you know
i think we're baked enough for such a
joke to go over decent
you know what i remember a few years ago
i was filming something uh we were
judging um
one event i can't remember what event it
was and we spent hours and hours and
hours filming and judging this stuff and
then we realized the microphone was
awesome there was no audio whatsoever so
we redid the whole thing oh my god
yeah see always check
to make sure your microphone's on um
that's why my microphone and my camera
are just one in the same and you can
never do it over the same
oh god no
okay so that was right it would have
been fun though if you guys just over
dubbed it watching it oh yeah that would
have been math yeah it would have been
hilarious
just been like oh i remember this i
remember this
no you don't
see bread and those shrimp up very
literally up here remove you wanna you
wanna wash your hands real quick sure
and then you can
put
take these and put them into there and
flip them around
all right
or am i making you work too much i'm
just surprised you don't have a joint
going yeah i know that is one thing see
that's the problem when you put remo on
like making all this food you know what
you're back on joint dude don't get
joints wash your hands
yeah that would be amazing i could do
this you can do this that's what paul
did paul rolled up with the uh with the
dab rig yeah while you were cooking
last night
he's like i got you
okay i've got all my equipment you're
gonna sneak behind here okay
thank you frosted fruitcakes
i'm on it and i'll get on doing this
halibut here all right so now you got
remy rolling joints
that's that's probably that's a
privilege right there it's a good thing
the highest that's been doing yeah and
probably people that are watching this
video that are like they haven't smoked
that much at all you'll have to go to
remo's channel
urban remo
youtube channel to check out the rosin
pressing we did with his frosted
fruitcake
um
cultivar we made some really nice rosin
took some dabs and that video was filmed
on his camera and it's going up on his
channel so go check it out
over yonder
and it resulted we'll finish that we got
the last piece there yeah
boom and what did you put in here again
there's uh buttermilk paprika like uh
cajun spicing um
some chili flakes okay some salt nice
yeah so maybe it's not good too grinding
weed where your food is
awesome hey what do you got there in
your grinder bud yeah it's like this
joint doesn't taste the same
it's like garlic bud i think it was
some garlic in there right you know what
his turtles
it's not going to go in the joint anyway
oh my gosh yeah
i would be like this doesn't taste funny
you were knowing something was up right
all right that's funny okay we're back
our oil is at
165. let's start with the
halibut filets the halibut fillets
the first two are all testers
they're still wet
is your testers yeah you want to make
sure that the oil is
[Music]
i got a fire here too oh my god the
classic remo lighter holder
it's a remo lighter the lighter leash
thank you sir increase your lighter
retention by a hundred percent because
dude a hundred percent
increase
increase your lighter retention
now the worst thing is being a stoner
with a joint with no lighter
terrible
it's true
it's unacceptable actually this is going
to make a big
[Music]
yeah this is so awesome
well said remo
no one else heard you say it because i
hadn't pushed record yet but i heard you
say it no it's awesome all right again
yeah you did
[Music]
oh that's some purple paste right there
sure you want to spike these things like
this i'll show you for the first one
[Music]
just post that skin right off of it
is that a green tomato yeah it's a
tomatillo
just like that
not like any food cooked for them
for like creme brulee
[Music]
that's gotta be the best job ever to get
get to be given i've never seen anyone
cooking food give this job to anyone
hey you want a torch for mentos
there you go
what are they called it's a fun job
right i gotta torque that avocado too
here's your uh avocado mix that you made
that's looking good this fish is looking
spectacular buddy let's get these shrimp
in
i'm gonna put some shrimps on the bottom
this guy's crack probably snapping over
here
what are you doing
he said i wanted to dab give it up oh
yeah yeah this is your dab right here
we'll stick that in the room
terps
so heat those up leave them so they're
nice and retaining their heat yeah
we're going to make a duka here a duka
almonds some sliced
walnuts
some
sesame seeds pumpkin seeds
we have uh
sunflower seeds oh yeah sunflowers just
notice them oh and what are the small
ones the chia seeds or
the small ones are sunflower seeds oh no
those are
sesame seasonal some hemp seeds
a little bit of this coriander seed
[Music]
coriander
little cumin seed
i have a golden brown yeah that's
perfect just awesome
[Music]
oh yeah
golden golden the living gold oh not
quite no not quite
that's a big fatty
that's a good
[Music]
it's gonna be for the cauliflower
it's like the people who designed
kitchens
did they really think we only needed
those people seem to have like i don't
know five six seven different plugged
items not to mention the electricians
never put it in the enough power for
that yeah if you get two toasters going
at once on the same circuit you're sure
to blow it up for sure with the
microwave running at the very back oh my
goodness okay so that's one got one down
one down ceviche is looking good yes the
beach is flavoring up there we'll put
these tomatillos in here
i'm gonna grind those up yeah
oh well this is where we put a bit of
avocado so it thickens it okay otherwise
it just turns to like straight liquid
i'm also gonna jam some olive oil in
there
a little olive oil
a little cilantro a little bit of
cilantro
some onion some onion
also a bit of jalapeno
a bit of garlic
garlic and jalapeno yeah
damn merlin
and then we're gonna add in more lime if
we can
looks like you can
[Music]
that looks so nice
nice
this one's fatter than the last one
you roll more joints over there and it's
got 100 less onion in it regardless
this onion tastes better oh
all right we're almost you know what
actually no is that my joint maybe i put
it down i got this one still too i don't
know here's the pressure right here
bam
that's it
let's see that one
that's a movember that's a movember one
right there me and remo are matching
this november split
strength in numbers right there you go
buddy
okay these are almost
right on the oven
the lighter just said hey
he's over here
waiting to move some stuff nope
you want to come over here yes
there
let me get some of this on there as well
and this is
this is the kizu oh the pizzeria
all right the first one
we add this one to your little crunch to
it
some of this all the seed
damn dude
that's one down these wonderful things
here
oh yeah these are great
we'll take our tiles out
okay now we'll grab these
do our first floor with these
so that's the sweet potato and leeks and
some kale
this i think i wrote a fresh joint i
don't feel like you missed much just him
putting these in but that's what i made
that's a nice bat
fate la
[Music]
oh yeah that's for real that's the one
taco supreme man
a little bit of this tomatillo sauce
well lady looks insane
it does
yeah man that's what i'm talking about
a whole lot of tomatillo sauce exactly
those are the things you toasted up
oh yeah you just ground them into that
that is awesome
tomatoes and fresh tomatoes and then a
bit of cilantro on there
and then we have some i just pickled
some onions as well
you know
got to pickle some onions
yeah free tacos dude yeah exactly like
what if you made tacos and you didn't
have the pickled onions that would be
good
right clearly be [ __ ] up that'd be
absurd i don't know life's too stressful
these days to have tacos without pickled
onions homemade pickles
okay that one's pretty much good to go
now our next one we've got some sriracha
mayo mixed up here with a little bit of
lime juice
we're just going to put a little dabble
on there a dab
oh yeah
that's what i'm talking about
that me up good
have you good
buddy
you like that this is this is what for
the halibut now or the shrimp this is
for the shrimp oh buddy
oh my gosh look at that
that's full-on
what is this
merlin
oh wait that's not he doesn't wear a
wizard's hat but it makes him no less
wizard nice remote
avocado nick's here with the mango
that's going on the shrimp
dude
this is
so on point
you gotta eat good food when you smoke a
lot of good weed oh yeah no yes i agree
bro it's like the best part his buddy
paul was like
i've never eaten any of the meals that
merlin makes i just eat them because
merlin makes them
cool
i just eat like meat and potatoes it
looks magical
it really does
and then we still have the halibut one
to go yeah exactly the whole way geez
louise a little bit of cilantro in these
as well
just for good measure you know yeah yeah
cilantro it up
there we go
and then the last one is the halibut
which i put right here
you did
those pieces of halibut look so nice
this is kind of what kind of sauce can
you put on those ones beautiful
beautiful fillet
uh these ones we are gonna go with a bit
of this as well oh yeah that's what i'm
saying i'm gonna sauce it up sauce it up
buddy
you gotta have a fish a fish taco with a
good uh
with a good spicy sauce it's almost
tasty oh [ __ ] look how tender they are
it just fell apart in my hand beautiful
looking pretty awesome
it's looking ridiculous
boom
then we're gonna mix this up with a
little bit of
a little coleslaw we got a little
coleslaw with a little bit of vinegar
and vinegar in the coleslaw
a little bit of vinegar a little bit of
mayo
just tossing it in at this point yeah
you gotta have coleslaw with your fish
taco dude you really do it doesn't make
sense without it
the baja
exactly
dude i love your your um
your helpings
healthy scoops don't you have an
appreciation for his
you know when you see nice food you're
like oh i hope we get a nice chunk of
that and this guy's just like scoop
there we go holy [ __ ] i'm gonna finish
those ones off with more of this
tomatillo salsa here
finish it off with some green
it's always good to finish with green
um i can't believe how good it looks
dude it's all over right
okay and then last up is the ceviche to
get plated and we're good to eat all
right there you go
well that's a good car to have on the
west coast of british columbia in
november yeah well you know when it
snows i don't drive right yeah no i try
not to so well i have a truck so i can
drive
but if it snows too much i'd prefer not
to yeah snow in the mountains is
different than snow in the prairies
this is not the same people from
winnipeg like all those people in
vancouver they don't know how to drive
when it snows it's like no we just have
[ __ ] mountains it's it's like you
don't know how to drive within the
mountains with snow that's a whole
different deal it's a totally different
watch highway through hell it's a deal
breaker yeah oh that's nice the way
you're preparing this yeah little bites
you [ __ ] kidding me
i'm not i guess you know that
this is so choice bro
there we go
let's see yeah there we go
is it red light there red circles red
circling
it's all good dude we're in so what an
absolute feast you've created once again
here merlin do you want to go through
quickly what you've got here yeah
surprisingly we pulled it off
rima helped a lot as well actually i
tried he was my first kid
yes in this show that we've done so
thank you for that no problem my
pleasure yeah it turned out amazing we
got a
fish tacos with uh with coleslaw and
green tomatillo salsa we have um
vegetarian sweet potato tacos with leeks
and onions and kale
and with some pickled red onions some
cilantro and a bit of tomatillo sauce as
well and then we have some deep fried
shrimp with a avocado mango salsa with
cilantro and a bit of
spicy aioli in there and then we also
have
some roasted cauliflower
with
beet hummus
dukkha and a bit of pisu which is like
ground up uh
green vegetables it's kind of like a
pesto dude it's very colorful and then
we also for the rest of the halibut we
were able to make a mango
ceviche as well
so yeah let's eat pull them in yeah
let's do it i guess we just take one of
these full trays or something like that
you guys want to start with one of these
yeah no you just serve it the way we
shop treasure first yeah appetizer first
that looks amazing and we actually also
have some vanilla i might note it was
pretty pretty significant this ashtray
was empty when we were not here
show that to the camera yeah
that's for real
there we go all right let's check this
out cheers guys ceviche
cheers let's hope it's salted good
thanks for inviting me
wow
fresh olive oil that's that was
medicated right
definitely yeah
you're not going to get it ready
that's why i got mrs grover here there
you go dude that was so tasty delicious
holy christ
yeah i can't say that was bad good good
heat in there what's the heat the heat
is jalapeno jalapenos that's nice and
then the pressure in the end it bites
your right fresh from the pomelo with
the citrus and the lime that's like that
great texture too it's crunchy all right
so it's up to you guys how about we each
try a different one yeah
that's a great idea yeah all right i'm
going to go for the first one in front
of me which is the fish taco the fish
taco you go for the shrimp and you go
for the veggie but not normally would he
go for the goal for the veggie do you
want to go for the shrimp i volunteer
for the shrimp all right well i'll take
it i'll take the veggie one that sounds
good to me you know i'm not you know
against vegetables
no but i love them i'm nominated
thanks very much cheers cheers
awesome guys
this fish is so tender
a lot of flavor in these veggies too man
that is really nice this is gonna put
taco bell out of business
they're done
wow
well i'm not disappointed with my first
bite
no thank you that's once again wonderful
and then we're going to eat this topper
was delicious here before i clean my
forehead
the perfect hummus the beet hummus
it's so vibrant eh
dude i'm telling you there was some
zingers of flavor in this my mouth is
still kind of zinging from the from the
ceviche yeah this ceviche is super fresh
very acidic
oh put that thing down
it looks really nice too
oh yeah didn't taste like what i thought
it would taste like no no
it's really good though
not bad for your first time producing
this meal creating this meal
this this one is first time i've ever
done it wow i've done different
variations of this one i haven't done
exactly these ones probably but i always
just play around and try and do
something different well listen i want
nothing more than to just go crush this
hard and there's some other people who
are going to be enjoying as well
so we're going to wrap it up cooking
with merlin episode 5
with ramo
visiting and hanging out with us that
was awesome dude thanks for having me
and thanks for inviting me over for all
these problems no no no no no no no no
no no no no no no no no no no no no no
no no no no wait kill her fair share
this video
too dude exactly so once again go check
over at his channel on youtube urban
ramo to check out the rosin pressing
that we did and uh we're going to finish
up the way we should be finishing up by
respecting the chef and eating the food
that he just created thanks a lot for
joining peace out
all right
my compliments
[Music]
you