[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and welcome back to high integrity glass
art with Mr row good to see you buddy it
was a pleasure yes I'm always exced this
is like a kid in a candy store when I
come here I see you've got the uh ball
rig out on the table as well as I don't
even know what Ballo ball EXO with major
opal awesomeness so I got a call today
and it's a really wonderful day because
I'm getting to a um take care of a good
buddy of mine and I'm also able to pick
up something that I've been dying to get
for quite some time so why don't we just
get right to
it
boom TUS
so this is the one tell me about the
Taurus St de's version of the
recycler
okay Scott Dee's version of the recycler
but I've heard from quite a few people
that smoke a lot of mother ships I think
it was even both you and Flav who just
mentioned that the Taurus has a a
special hit for sure it's the recycler
you know what I mean yeah it's
the more
flavorful I'm not even sure I've ever
hit the Taurus
I know I've hit the ball and I know I've
hit about the ftk and the straight Fab
and the Egg Integrity glass
unfortunately uh unfortunately let go of
the our Taurus so that's probably why we
haven't let you oh right you used to
have a SI on or what yeah Punchy oh gosh
FL of
Life a nice one I'm so SL to open this
up they
going wrapp them really good I don't
mind that at all I mean really don't you
want them to wrap it really
good eventually it's all going to come
off
nice there we go one level all right as
you get down you can just start feeling
the solidity of it you know how like
completely awesome it is man this is
exciting
oh sh nope we have to go do the third
layer yeah we going to do the third
layer they really wrap them
good who doesn't love opening
things but wing power GL
wow that's a beauty right
there look at that yeah I've definitely
never hit one of these before because
I've never seen
this sort of I guess that's how he's
created the recycler by the two of
posing holes that is
unbelievable and then the what is it
called seed of life
yep well that's pretty damn sweet dude
man
yeah hat off to the Mother Ship now I
say we might as well open up the egg
because it's going into the Pelican case
to go to its new
home probably the best way to ship an
egg wouldn't you say
let say so too any any real high-end
glass it just makes sense to get it in
that get it in that Pelican case or
Turtle case or whatever kind of case
that you uh you can find oh that's a
nice sweet little bowl really little
bowl
the eggs feel so
great such a big fan I only really got
into motherships in the last year
but I'm uh I'm
addicted this is how I got I got mine I
pulled this right off my egg when I got
it these are wrapped a little bit a
little bit better there we
go oh yeah
T man look at that
beautiful real nice that one won't be
getting
hitting and I
guess is this one go with this one
actually and this one go with
this did you say or vice
versa I think they're all tiny
interchangeable
yeah those are I haven't actually seen
those cool you want to check it out nice
teeny Stu yeah there's another one real
teeny right well I'm super stoked to get
this Taurus in action I've got the deep
dish Banger here from uh denail it's
going to go right in but
do get this into
position turn it a little bit angle
there there we go always good to make
sure this isn't hot I think I'm going to
put it the other way
there we
go click and what are we puffing on here
you probably already told me twice uh
Kimo 90 chemo 90 well I'm going to be
hitting some chemo 90 here really stoked
on this
little she's
a yeah I like that instead of going up
she's just doing
circles it's really nice and so that's
about the right amount of water right
there
uh each teach their own some people like
it with a little bit more that feels
pretty good to me yeah it's got a good
train too oh my God does that look
unbelievable when it drains that's a
macro movie waiting to happen you guys
are going to love that telling
you good thanks well super stoked that
you guys are taking care of uh I guess
what do you got you got right to center
of Canada or what do you got British
Columbia and Alberta yeah it's pretty
good two provinces that would otherwise
potentially not have motherships these
things are D too Winnipeg yeah okay cool
are there any motherships in Winnipeg
don't think so not yet well come on
Winnipeg get on it he just said he's
taking care of Winnipeg you can give him
a call you can get in touch with him
through Facebook or Instagram and our
website will have a shop up the next uh
two weeks oh very good very good dude
I'm telling you spreezy did I not tell
you about spreezy you could be
photographing one of is right now and
selling it I'm telling you it would be
like that
fast I was very impressed PR breezy.com
so anyway we're up to uh temperature
here to about
600 I guess we got about 661 you're
sitting at a solid 730 how do you love
the uh like the ready coil I love it
yeah it's pretty good little unit see
with the heat it looks pretty beefy the
components look good I like the big
strong thick cable and it's got a
titanium nail on it yeah oh
yeah well I can't wait another
minute nice no need to wait see you guys
a
little
boom dabs
up all
right deep dish Banger Dabs out of the
Taurus you only get to hit your pipe for
the first time once so thank you once
again
[Music]
Dam that's really nice with the carb cap
it just shuts it right down almost
completely it's got HS on the
bottom it has a hole right on the bottom
but I I don't there's a dish so I think
that hole has something to do with the
the way the cartz like right at the
bottom of the dish there's a hole and
then it's just like a little space that
goes up to the flat dish I figured it
was something to do to keep the glass
from exploding I mean or the the crystal
the quartz because I maybe if you seal
it
completely you can run into uh some
issues I figured everything about these
guys uh puking bee beagle and the denail
guys they don't do anything just because
every single thing they do is like
majorly been designed thought of
utilized and gone through like a long
process of actually getting to the point
where okay this is actually a working
model man is that
beautiful I'm so happy I want to come
back every week and get
one oh yeah well I'm going to load one
more up I think what else we got here we
got some Congo chemo yeah chemo Congo
d420 K is in the house as always D got
to thank you once again man I mean what
a generous gift that was to kick down
that sort of amount of dry sift I've
been puffing it with everyone everyone I
puff it with I talk about you and your
kindness and uh I give you shout out so
thanks brother really appreciate it ooh
yeah bring the fire what's that diesel
it's nice isn't it so we're talking
about that d420 K diesel that's
reminiscent of of a jell Bean or an
agent orange or a Calo or a Tangi which
one orange velvet orange
velvet God I love the small compactness
of this piece it's uh it's it's
substantially smaller than the egg
you don't even get a drop of water in
your mouth on this
pipe I mean I probably sound like a
total Noob I'm not a big recycler guy
true um I have hit quite a few pipes
though and I just have to tell you
there's a I mean this pipe just gets to
a certain point and it's just the
water's spinning so hard at the top that
when you stop pulling it drops into this
perfect funnel and actually starts
dropping beadlets of water through the
tube I'll give you guys a macro uh show
of the nice clean pipe um but later when
I get time uh for now I'm going to
continue puffing bowls out of this new
piece giving much homage to uh row here
at higher end glass uh sorry high
integrity glass I got so many names art
in my head you guys can check them out
on Facebook and Instagram Instagram is
one word high integrity glass art
Facebook same
thing Facebook same thing so go check
them out for your Mothership needs and
uh thank you dude I really appreciate it
really cool peace out St kind of real
cloudy like I say CU I bring back this
[Music]
music Roy alongside one SP
s
againest looking at
me find head people always ask me say
why you so humble I don't smoke that's
why I don't
gr s
me must burn like must be cleaned rather
vital for Spiritual a king Salomon
certify the
and he is the wisest man to we so propa
preach never true speech so meanwhile
the song called leaders deceive man
obligated to clarify and teach you now
[Music]