[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
and uh well gez today I feel like I'm uh
Mr DNA over here I got my new hat and my
new shirt from uh Kim and Aaron I want
to thank you guys once again I did do a
little uh video that I'll be uploading
here soon in regards to the stuff that
you sent we really appreciate the schwag
I can't even call it schwag cuz really
it should be called Full melt full melt
outerwear by
DNA super stoked on uh on the work that
you guys are doing unity in the
community so I thought I would just uh
do a short little uh uh video here with
you guys I've got some unbelievably
beautiful dry sifts um it really has
paid off sharing all this information
with my friends from d420 K to Johnny
Burell to Horatio Delbert between those
three guys they are basically um my dry
sift ambassadors right now they're
really taking it to the next level of
course Horatio will always be the LH guy
but he's a smart enough cookie to know
that if he's going to really know what
he's dealing with from the start to the
finish that it's important that he
acquires an unadulterated canabo profile
and what better way to do that than
through the wonderful uh mechanical
separations of screen sifting so what
I've got here is I've got the Jamaican
the Lamb's bread from Johnny B that
we're going to start it out with thank
you so much Johnny B you made such a
small amount and you gave it to me and I
just uh it just goes to show you're such
a a super super human being I'm lucky to
call you my friend and for those of you
out there that don't know about Johnny B
go check them out 420 weedmas on
Instagram John H Bell on Facebook and
John Bell on YouTube so check him out
we're going to hit the Jamaican Lamb's
bread that I brought back in 1995 after
being married in Jamaica give thanks
Jamaica give thanks Johnny
B
nice and creamy on that get some of
these glass pieces out of the way my new
quartz Banger from dabinator and my new
mil nail as well as a a male to male so
it can fit the female on my piece and
then uh what do we got we have the
Jamaican that was so delicious can't
even really Express how different of a
flavor that Jamaican is it's
really
it's difficult um I'm going to have to
pay a little bit more attention to that
one I don't have a ton of it but it
seems like one that would take a couple
of weeks to really get used to the
subtle differences of uh of the flavors
and the highs I've also wondered because
it doesn't taste exactly what it tasted
like in Jamaica and I have a feeling
that it's that tropical sungrown sativa
that hasn't been able to produce the
same tarpine profile grown under lights
although I will say John did an
exceptional job uh the resin is really
really nice damn
white so we're going to go we've hit the
quartz pooking B bowl with the denail
now we've got the denail whip with their
brand new sick uh which is the silicon
carbide nail and I've got it in my
Straight Fab and it's actually plugged
into the new nail the dabinator
so I think what we're going to try on
this one is some of Horatio's new live
sift all right you seen this guys live
sift you seen it here first this is dry
sift that he has added Tarpin to so I've
got a quite a photo of this I might not
show it in this in this particular video
but it will get shown um really
interesting it almost looks like GID
Up's live resin it looks like it's wet
almost or
crystallized um buttery it looks very
buttery but I'll tell you the taste on
it especially off the silicon carbide
nail is absolutely tremendous so here we
go with a little I guess uh Seven Star
as Horatio calls it I like to call it
the uh sift the turp sift which is what
we called it in um Amsterdam when Tony
and I made the first batch ever but
Horatio's got his own his own Vibes and
he's really thinking that the seven star
is going to be the name so Props to you
Horatio I respect your name # sstar
going down right
here
now the flavor on that is absolutely
unbelievable how
strong and
deep and plant Mattery not in a bad way
Plant Mattery but in a good way
talking about it with ratio the other
day the taste that I get is almost fresh
squeezed carrots and that's just the the
background of the flavor and I I suspect
that's the intensity of the added
Tarpin producing a a a taste that would
otherwise not be that strong might not
pick up the carrots uh smell but I'll
tell you when you get it that
concentrated you can really taste it
it's almost like cannabis carrots really
really lovely got to uh got to love guys
like Tony and and Horatio
who really put their thoughts into
things they really put their minds
forward and they love to Pioneer things
and I don't think it's an accident that
all of us have come together here in the
last year so let's see we've got the
straight Fab we've got the Fab egg now
what number three are we going to hit we
got to represent d420 k d420
k probably the most generous dryft kick
down I've ever had in my life had some
pretty nice ones nothing compared to to
what D brought me the last time that he
was here it was a lot of hard work to
make this sift a lot of value once you
get it and to just be to just give it
away the way d420 K did just want to
thank you for being such a great friend
dude and uh I appreciate you man you're
the dry sift General and uh you're
moving things forward you're a big part
of the team and uh you know go follow
d420 k at
on Facebook D
fur t w n t
y k d420 k but he spells it the four and
the 20 out between the D and the K you
can check him out at
d420 K on Instagram and you can check
him out at d420 K on YouTube so go give
him some subscriptions and some follows
he's a kickass guy all of my friends are
Kick-Ass guys I really just can't say
enough good about John Horatio d420 K
and then I got to kick it down to Flav
and row for hooking me up with the
amazing glass that they've hooked me up
over the uh over the course of the last
year and of course shout out to the guys
at denail um you guys have been an
absolute pleasure to work with I
couldn't do what I do without you guys
and I want you guys to realize I'm not
just promoting denail because I think
that it's a product that everyone should
use I promote it because I love it I use
it I can't imagine not having it and now
with the gift of the dabinator from Max
thank you so much dude ridiculously kind
Germany representing I've got a unit now
that I can take with a cord to Europe
and not worry about blowing it I've got
my North American units thank you guys
everyone I'm going to finish it off with
a d420 K dry sift full melt New York
City Diesel super orange flavor we're
going to hit that right off the pooking
bee quartz
Bowl
thanks for watching Bubble man's
[Laughter]
world