hey what's going on everybody bubble man
Here I am at the trial golf resorts
cruising around this cool little golf
cart and I tried to go live I wanted to
do a live video but it wasn't letting me
and I thought you know what I'm going to
at least still do an actual video so
that we can you know have a little fun
show you this cool little area gonna
have to turn my phone around because of
the way I'm doing the video it doesn't
allow me to switch my cameras from angle
to angle
front to back
just in this really cool little
neighborhood up top called Barnes Hill
and I'm actually heading down to the
beach right now and we're gonna go
through a little tunnel go underneath
the main highway should be pretty cool
yeah
all right so yeah beautiful places up
here fairly exclusive I suspect this is
a neighborhood of very wealthy people
because the homes are definitely the
nicest I've ever seen in Jamaica you
know there's the driveway to one right
there really really sweet looking spots
some on the beach some up on the hill I
wish it was alive I really do
I really wish this was a live video and
we'd just be showing everything live but
this one's just gonna be a short little
get uploaded
head straight down
the magic spot
and you just like that we're on the
other side of the highway in the beach
side
[Music]
[Applause]
all right we are parched let's turn that
off grab this and continue on the
adventure this is basically where the
golf club is and the main restaurant I
don't even know what it's called but I
was here yesterday I can kind of see the
walk up is quite beautiful I did some
footage of this that you'll end up
seeing on the channel later but I like
to be able to share a little snippets
and clips
what better way see how long this video
is in total to get us
right just over five minutes and right
from the place your paradise on the
Caribbean Sea so I just came through the
restaurant yesterday obviously if you
haven't come to Jamaica before you're
into cannabis you're into great food
great music today today first of all I
know it's a bit windy right now but
everybody