[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
today we're going to be doing a little
review on a quite a wonderful little
unit that I've been excited to get for
quite some time now it's called the
Grasshopper Vaporizer now they make them
both in stainless steel as well as
titanium this unit is 100% titanium uh
the titanium unit as it will and it was
um passed along to me this year in Spain
in Barcelona at the spannabis and I
wanted to give a shout out to vape fiend
you can check his website out he's got
his card in here let me just pull out
all the little utensils and such and so
Vape fiend yes George Alexander is the
CEO and the founder and you guys you can
hook him up with him at www.
vape.co do if you're in Europe um
vaporizer wizard is great to hook up
with if you are in Canada and of course
you can always check out uh Grasshopper
Vaporizer decom uh and go right to the
source got a cool little grasshopper
sticker here and the thing comes basic
um I'm not sure if it actually comes
with this or if he kicked me down a
little extra he gave me two extra
batteries rechargeable uh uh lee ion 3.7
volt 750 Mah this is the model GHB 1 and
it's also says Hopper labs and has the
little grasshopper logo on there so I
got one with the unit itself as well as
the two extras so that's very nice to
have and one of the really cool things
about this unit that I thought was was
pretty interesting was how it charged
it's got the classic USB charger uh but
but it's got this little guy here and I
wanted to kind of show you up close how
kind of cool this is you got this little
guy and
basically it's that simple you just
attach it it's magnetic and that's how
you charge the unit so I really thought
that was cool kind of futuristic much
like these new Apple iPhones and such
with their um easy to charge just place
it down and it's
magnetic um the unit itself is is very
very simple uh the top goes
uh switches here you can you can twist
the entire top to open up the unit and
uh remove the battery so there's one of
the batteries right there and it's just
a real simple unit titanium pop that
battery in there turn this little guy to
spin
it the threads grab real nice and easy
on all of it that's one of the things I
like about it and then there's five
settings so at the top here you have a
little pen clicker you've got your basic
setting and then you go to two to three
to four and to five and of course each
person is going to enjoy their vapor at
a different level it's also got this
cool little uh silicon piece that I
guess originally I thought was for a
mouthpiece but then I realized if I just
gently put it into my down stem uh or
sorry my drop down I could actually take
rips through my pipe as well so we'll be
doing that here in a little bit now this
is a vaporizer for flowers for herbs I
do not believe it's a very uh
a unit that you would use concentrates
for I've been told just to use flowers
and it's real simple you unscrew the top
it's got a very small three little
threaded piece inside this stain uh
sorry inside this titanium piece you've
got a little screen inside so that when
you're inhaling you're not uh inhaling
the dust or the small particulate of the
of the Cannabis and then inside here
it's got as well another perforated
laser screen with three tiny holes in
the side and uh why don't we just just
get going right here I've grown a little
bit of my own little
Jamaican pop that in there you guys a
little give you guys a little see here
there's a little bud there it's kind of
going out of the out of the Sun so I
don't want to take it too close to the
camera but that's some of my Jamaican
from 1995 and I guess simply enough
we'll just crush a little nugget of it
into this
unit it's uh I've only used the unit
once myself so far and it was quite nice
I did a little review on Periscope
yesterday unfortunately Periscope was a
little bit glitchy so I thought you know
I think this vaporizer deserves a full
review on my YouTube channel and I
wanted to give that shout out to vape
fiend for hooking it up and vaporizer
wizard in Canada they've sent some units
in the past so I thought I'd pass their
address on as well and of course
Grasshopper Vaporizer who is the one
that put this unit together so there we
go we got it nice and stuffed we'll take
a few different varieties of hits
here this is one of my favorite Parts
about the pen now I'm going to set it on
four you click it down you get these
little red lights that come on one two
that's it it was about 4 seconds blue
it's up to temperature and you can
already start
vaping
nice light Vapor coming out right at the
start real nice tasty tasty flavors on
those first few rips coming through
exactly like the flavor of the herb this
was an outdoor grown herb that I growed
on my deck so I can taste that outdoor
Sun grown quality to it
very nice indeed why don't we try a few
rips through the mother ship and see how
that
goes twists in real nice doesn't feel
janky or loose at
all wow that was a surprising huge rip
that I got off there completely
different from hitting it on the unit by
itself the water created this incredible
suction not bad at
all give that a little click
off a little empty
empty sometimes when it doesn't empty
right away that means that you've got a
little bit of resin still left in there
and you could probably take a few more
hits um very small amount sure if you
guys can see this but uh I got a little
picture to show you I'd say it's less
than a quarter of a
gram the unit cleans really nice and
easy though I'm quite impressed with
that so let's try a little bit of the
Astro Boy that I've had curing for well
over a year now this stuff hits just
beautifully great turpine profile on the
Astro Boy uh you can just smell and
taste that unique flavor not saying that
the Jamaican didn't have a very nice
unique flavor as well the Astro Boy is
just much more fruity and really gives
that sort of fruity
rip so I'm just kind of holding my
finger over the top and blowing out the
um where the thread is that way you
don't get a buildup of resin in those
threads I'm sure that it could happen
clean that out a little bit as well give
it a quick click and we'll count this
time one 2 3 4 and it's done I think
we're going to go for first a clean rip
right out of the right out of the
unit oh God is that tasty we got to go
right into the bong
now
that is a pretty incredible little unit
for the size and for the efficiency and
for how um fast it heats up how easy it
is to clean how easy it is to roll with
it in the
pocket
really nice indeed tasty treats I don't
get to enjoy flowers very
often as I'm mainly a hash smoker and
even though now people could argue that
I'm hitting flowers really what I'm
doing is I'm hot air extracting the hash
off of the flowers and of course the
flowers are being left over uh nicely uh
dric combed completely removed and uh
yeah I'm impressed with this little unit
I got to say
one two three
done can't believe the taste right down
to the end as well really just
continually hitting a nice flavorful rip
now I'd love to tell you how long the
battery lasts that's something I'm going
to have to get back to you on I haven't
killed one yet I was using it yesterday
and I used it
today now I'm by no means hitting it
like a fiend I hit maybe four or five
bowls and ideally it'd be nice to know
exactly how many full Chambers you can
hit with a single
battery but I guess that's why they give
you a second battery
too uh for that very reason and it's
easy to just click on and off and get it
back up to temperature if it's cooling
down on
you excellent excellent little unit so
this will maybe be a two-parter I want
to get back to you guys and let you know
how durable it is you know how I'm very
hard on these units uh I travel with
them and I Ru with them in a way that I
I definitely don't treat them like
they're eggs um I treat them like
they're a unit and that they're going to
last I treat them very much like the way
I would treat my bubble bags keep them
clean uh and put them away all the time
but at the same time by no means do I
baby them when it's work time it's work
time and uh this unit right here being
100% titanium really gives me the feel
that uh that it's to last even the
Silicon uh mouthpiece which I regularly
really don't like these very much it's
not your average one it's a much it's
like a silicon wrapped around a silicon
tip so it's very thick up here and very
thin down here much like those cheap
ones that you get with all the pens that
you can just put on top of there this is
more like a two-part unit so uh I like
that as
well give it another
click for it to be able to turn on that
fast is incredible one two
3 3
seconds
good old Vapor cough happening there
coming out of the end of the cold and
that little bit of uh that real nice
little hit that it gives you just
uh grabs you by the throat anyway I want
to give a shout out to the Grasshopper
Vaporizer crew I want to give a shout
out to vape fiend for hooking me up with
this in Barcelona I do apologize that it
took so long I was sick for almost three
weeks there but here I am reviewing the
unit and I got to say it's a great
little unit I love the way it looks like
a pen super nondescript does not look
like your regular vapor pens in any way
shape or form it actually looks like a
pen so shout out to those guys for doing
such a great job uh having such a
successful
Kickstarter and uh yeah I think I'm
going to be a fan I like the idea of
bringing around a little bit of crushed
up herb and this is something that might
be important to you if you want to use
vaporizers like this and the reason I'm
getting the rips that I'm getting uh is
because I've dried the herb this herb
has actually been dried for months
and it was really going to be used for
dry sifting so it's probably even just a
little
bit just past dry uh but the rips that
you get out of it because of it are
these really responsive it's the
difference between hitting a fresh plant
and hitting properly dried material and
this is a good lesson for you
bubbleheads and dry sifters out there as
well um fresh frozen is going to be
twice as hard to dry properly than cured
properly cured Bud that is then washed
and with dry sifting you are not dry
sifting if you haven't dried the
material properly and so this is
properly dried material it hits perfect
in a vaporizer it's completely
responsive to um vaporizing the second
the heat gets there and the heat doesn't
have to work its way through a uh you
know moist wax membrane to get to the
medicine so I guess uh nothing left to
do but thank you guys for watching and
uh we'll get back to you here soon on
Bubble man's world with some more great
reviews some more great videos and
hopefully some hash makinging here in
the very near future so thanks a lot
Grasshopper Vaporizer thank you George
from Vape fiends see you next time on
Bubble man's
[Music]
world