welcome cannabis enthusiasts to a brand
new episode of grow weed at home with
Kyle kushman I'm thrilled to bring you
an incredible installment that promises
to take your knowledge and appreciation
of the Cannabis world to new heights
today we have something truly special in
store for you we're honored to be joined
by a distinguished guest the one and
only Marcus Richardson renowned bubble
has expert and The Mastermind behind
bubble man's world get ready to embark
on a mesmerizing journey into the world
world of bubble hash making throughout
this episode we'll be diving deep into
the art and science behind creating the
best bubble has in the world from the
selection of top quality starting
material to the meticulous extraction
techniques the bubble man will share his
Decades of expertise and guide us
through the secrets of crafting premium
bubble hash whether you're a seasoned
grower or just starting your cannabis
Journey this episode promises to leave
you inspired enlightened and eager to
elevate your own hash making skills so
sit back relax and prepare to be
enthralled by the knowledge and passion
of Marcus let's learn let's grow and
let's embark on this extraordinary
Adventure into the world of bubble hash
together all right everybody so today
here we are as promised we have a
fantastic guest it's Marcus bubbleman
Richardson thanks for coming on my bubba
dude thanks for having me on I mean
listen uh I'll be straight up honest I
read out to you yes it did that was an
honor that was such an honor made me I
Matt did I not like immediately like
glow and be like oh my God that would be
so great yes yeah definitely gave you a
chubby well dude that's that's kind of
like uh it's not the beginning of our
story but it's certainly I'll never
forget the day you got the sort of like
you got to have a show at the Cannabis
cop and High Times was sort of giving
you a chance to move into a new field
you know you were already writing for
them and you had done the whole Adam's
garden and all of that awesome stuff but
then it was like you would you had this
opportunity and I remember you were
taking it pretty seriously and I was one
of your first guests yeah they they but
you know they didn't give me like an
opportunity basically it was like it was
okay you're going to Amsterdam again
you're going to do the same old thing
you know you're going to do a grow
seminar and I'd been there two times
before and I'm like I want to do
something different and they were like
what I said I'm going to put on a show
like what kind of show I said I don't
know I'll come up with something and so
literally I went and had cards printed
like the Jerry Springer like blue cards
that said The Grow Show on the back and
uh and and and this is true story it's
so funny you brought this up because I
didn't think of this I was going to
start the show with another story I
showed up in Amsterdam without any plan
I figured I can you know I didn't I
forgot how hectic it was and literally
the night before I stayed up with Steve
Bloom we wrote the outline for the show
and the morning of I woke up early and
went to what's the name of that Pancake
House it's right in the D plots there
hul um the it's it's a tourist place
right and so we sat there and ate and
Cosmo wrote out the chicken scratch of
all the notes that I had written for the
show that you couldn't read onto my Grow
Show Cards so that I could actually do
the show and yeah and that led to uh a
historic uh controversy didn't it yes
yes it absolutely did that was uh it was
a whole wild experience the way it
actually played out because of course
you know it it played back to S and S
who was we you know friends with both of
us at that time and Som you know was
also friends with Mila and Mila was of
course not overly excited that I was
doing my own bags and I was doing it
from a different perspective than she
chose to do it from and so I was having
some pretty good success and obviously
you doing the article in High Times
prior to your Grow Show um was a big
help it was a big exposure I had been
already sort of popularized on overgrow
and cannabis world and cannabis
culture.com but High Times was like a
whole different level you're like yeah
I'm gonna write an article about you
dude after we met in in Switzerland and
I guess instead of getting some photos
from me you were like I'll get some
photos from s and you're like hey hooked
me up with some bubble has photos and he
gave you some really beautiful ones but
the problem was was that you know and
the reason it got taken out on you was
that s knew to deflect that energy by
telling when I was over at his house he
had bubble bags out on his thing right
he's like I love these bags there's more
control there's instead of just two bags
I can make higher quality resin but if
Mila went over to his house he would
take the Bubble Bags off the the little
hanger and he'd put isolator bags on so
she was under the full assumption with
you know and you could you kind of can't
blame her that those photos were
isolator hash not bubble
hash and that's what she was that's
that's what she ended up blowing up on
you in front like at your show like it
was like literally during the filming of
your
show yeah I literally I put on a whole
show right I had I had the bong babes
rolling joints and I told the audience
if if they clapped really loud that
they'd throw a lot of joints out into
the audience we're having a good time
rocker T came on and did a song and
closed the show and it was really I
couldn't believe it it actually was
coming on really well and so I'm out in
the audience like Jerry Springer and
there's a there's a time between between
skits where I'm taking questions I
interviewed you and then I'm out there
and I'm taking questions and this woman
comes up to me and I honestly didn't
even know who she was wasn't until after
the show that somebody told me who that
was and I didn't even know who it was
when it was
happening so we're both learning we're
both learning new things about this
story isn't this great and so I'm up
there just in the show like really I
mean like I'm like in another whole
world I'm for the first time I'm putting
on a show like a show in front of people
and I'm concerned with what I'm doing
and and I asked she asked the question
it was something
about do you realize that I made the
first bubble bags and I I didn't know I
had no idea and I basically brushed her
off and but to finish this in context I
actually spoke because I had done a
story about you Mila called me at the
offices in High Times just a couple of
weeks before I went to Amsterdam right
and she had mentioned to me she she
brought me up to speed that you know I
came out with these isolator bags a long
time ago and it would be nice if you
gave me some some press too right and I
made this Pro I said oh absolutely I
promise but I didn't know what she I'd
never seen a picture of her I didn't the
only thing I talked to her on the
telephone so even after that promise of
what I was going to do and and then she
came up and I had no idea how to handle
it and I was like thank you very much
thank you very much cuz I I didn't even
know it was her so I couldn't even
legitimately follow through on the it
was just it was really funny and I I had
left I wasn't even in the room anymore
right like after you interviewed me I
bounced I I should have stuck around for
the uh for the hilarity to ensue but uh
I did not that was fun I was going to
start off the show with uh Switzerland
when we met in can you can you remember
what year that
was I want to say it was
2001 and the reason I want to say I want
to say that because
Steve breeder Steve myself and Scott
Blakey I.E Shanti Baba who were all in
Lugano at the time uh had all just had
baby daughters born that year uh really
all within like uh 20 20 days of of one
another like his daughter was born on
the 31st of March I know that because
that's my birthday my daughter was born
on the 13th of April and then I I can't
remember which one Shanti baba but so
that was kind of this weird sort of
coincidence that was occurring and and
of course it was sort of Steve that
brought me out to Switzerland he was
like you know come make a bunch of hash
um he had owed me some money too that I
was going to sort of collect on it made
sense and then you know bumping into you
guys was just uh
serendipitous yeah and and no
coincidence that was my the first time
that I ever
saw bubblehash do you remember remember
you made a batch and then before we went
to dinner you in your hands you made a
chunk of hash that looked like a little
piece of bid honey you remember those
old candies bid honey and and and I'd
never seen that before that was that was
the very first time and it was
fresh and we weren't going to try it
until we let it dry or cure at least
some or something or and and then we
came back from dinner and that when we
indulged and uh and went on with a a
very amazing trip to uh to Switzerland
that was NE nonetheless it was
definitely 25 years ago yeah yeah no it
was yeah it was literally 2001 because
our daughters had just been born Steve
uh wasn't out there really long at all
prior
to prior to his daughter being born so
yeah that was uh that was a long time
ago for sure and good times man that
that was uh that was a super trip like
Switzerland's an amazing country it's so
small it's so beautiful it's like German
in the north and Italian in the South
and then you get this whole French
Quarter that's completely French it's uh
it's very unique little country that's
uh and from be being from British
Columbia being from the West Coast it's
very West coastes you know it's got
these just epic mountains and beautiful
skiing and snowboarding and creeks and
just it's it's beautiful you come you
you absolutely in my opinion you come
from one of the most beautiful parts of
the globe without a doubt yeah there's
no doubt that you've stayed there for so
long and so well everybody's gotten a
little bit of history that we've we've
known each other since we were like in
our 20s and
uh that's almost high
school yeah it really is so let me let
me ask a few question actual be a little
interviewer here so you know
um a few questions that maybe people
have been following you that that you
haven't been asked so you're native to
British Columbia correct you born and
raised I wish I actually was born north
of North Dakota in the Bible Belt of
Canada Winnipeg Manitoba right in the
center like the god- Forbidden anuse of
Canada I love it you said that yeah I
did not know that I probably probably
told me that a while back but that's
really interesting and and then how old
were you when you uh
migrated uh I believe I was about
23 years old so it was your
decision yeah we were just like of
course both my wife and I were like
let's go out there let's start a life
out there in fact how it happened was I
had my mentor Ron hickey who's just an
absolute Savage Maniac this is an
amazing man who's just will he'll bend
over backwards to teach anyone how to
grow cannabis he had one of the first uh
hydroponic stores in Winnipeg and he
taught an enormous amount of people he
developed that 32 pipe system that
you've probably seen since the 80s it
white pipes with the black plugs on yes
with the yeah yeah so he designed that
system the waterfall Reservoir like 25
to 30 years ago uh like unequivocally
that was him so he did all sorts of wild
stuff like that and he um
he I rented a a house in a fairly
affluent part of Manitoba and I was
pretty young with his help and he was
like look we're going to build you it
had a huge basement he's like we're
going to go down there and build some
false walls and we'll get you like a
nice thousand square foot grow down
there and he like had guys come in and
build it it had a secret door to get
into Under the Staircase I love those
and literally dude this grow was so
beautiful I think it was like 14 lights
and uh like four veg split into a two
2/3 and a thir and it was all wired
beautifully and it had the big parabolic
you know HPS bulbs hux bulbs and
uh a week after they finished grow
building it the landlord called and said
oh I just want to have someone to come
in and do some
uh oh I can't remember what she called
it it was like some sort of like um
basically where they come in and measure
the [ __ ]
house and so the guy's in the basement
he's going like he's like dude a huge
section of your basement is missing and
I had to basically get all the lights
out of the grow room put a couple of
trees like way in the back with my two
iguanas and try to convince this guy
this is my iguana room with the Secret
Door Under the Staircase that I had to
bring him under so he told the landlord
and the landlord was like yeah you're
evicted so after we built this
incredible
room I wasn't expecting that well this
is how I ended up moving to British
Columbia I was so pissed off I was like
okay you know what [ __ ] this this is so
ridiculous I'm you know it's time for us
to go to BC and so it really was the big
push putting all that time and energy in
a you know two months of buildout into
finally just being told you you know it
was a beautiful house and it was
comfortable and it was off the beaten
path it was just perfect and so did you
did you move out did did did you have
contacts or did you just move out into
you know another country on your own
just well another
Province well been another country it
was super trippy dude trust me like for
all these years I've known you I haven't
been able to get into Canada I I had a c
I had a company for 10 years that made
my that my nutrients that were made in
Canada and I still couldn't get into
Canada yeah it's bizarre the whole
Canadian American relationship with
trying to keep each other out you know
it is look I look with the way things
are now you know you guys are kind of
lucky because you have the this awesome
border right you have you have the
Arctic Circle and then you have us so
you know it's like uh we you can control
that it's like we got we got we got
idiot to a degree but if you look at our
country 90% of the country lives like
right at the US border within like an
hour to two hours all of our cities are
like right down there so if if anything
ever goes down that's really serious in
America like we'll be yeah of course
like we'll have to go wait we'll have
don't get me wrong we'll have a lot of
space to go north but there's nothing up
there but until then you have Healthcare
and we
don't kind of it's gotten worse and
worse here I I won't get into the
politics of the country but it was it
was the Canada your thinking about
definitely existed like 20 to 25 years
ago and since we got this sort of new
prime minister it's gotten a lot
different yeah but isn't it relative to
how much worse that the US has gotten
too I mean we're just living in l i feel
I wake up and I feel like I'm living in
a Mel Brooks movie like he did Space
Balls part two the United States you
know yeah I know it's wild it definitely
is I mean and we're not too far off to
be honest it's like we're not too far
off we're we're your your your brothers
from the north kind of thing you know
like when people are like Canadians
always want to like disassociate
themselves with Americans but like the
whole thing that makes Canada Canada is
that we have
you you guys are a huge influence on
every aspect of our culture it would be
like I mean not only that like you're a
Hu you guys are a huge influence on
every aspect of everyone's culture
nobody exports culture the way the US
does that's interesting but because
because I I the America does United
States doesn't really have any culture
we don't have any we don't have you're
the storytellers you have Hollywood
you're the storytellers and those
stories are the culture that you're
exporting we have entertainment and we
have Silicon Valley that's what we do
better or as good as anybody in the
world but we don't have tradition or um
we don't have a holiday that's
distinctly the United States that we P
well okay we do let's right I'm G to get
off of that I'm G to ask you so you're
in CA Canada now you've been there
forever and you know what you know it's
it's it it's hard to deny that um you've
become a luminary in our community um
and to me I'll Define that a little bit
you know it uh a luminary it it doesn't
happen by accident it happens by
deliberate um intention and the
intention that you had was to uh make a
mark in this world and you certainly
have with uh bubble has and uh hash
church and Whistler Tech and um you know
I don't know how many other uh
successful companies you've got going on
but I want you to tell me a little bit
about that so we can get caught up about
the the shop talk what's going on with
uh your new tech these
days well all sorts of things in that
sense I mean I've definitely been
working with Whistler Technologies for
you know building out sort of an
industrial commercial equipment that
doesn't sacrifice the Purity and the
quality that's there for the scaling up
because generally people are always
afraid to scale especially in the can
industry you've already said it all
because and and and that and because
there's nothing like that here you you
know that right
so nobody thinks like that you cannot
get anybody with millions of dollars to
invest to think like that so go on
please yeah so we're just uh you know
pushing the boundaries and the sort of
innovating in regards to that equipment
we've got some pretty awesome Engineers
that are really just like engineers at
their core and they've been getting into
hash and cannabis more and more and more
over the years as they develop this
equipment with the help of you know hey
hash makers like myself and we've got a
sales guy by the name of Tyler and one
of the engineers Andrew is also uh uh
into the heady culture so that always
helps when you're building this kind of
equipment there's a lot of people doing
the equipment on the commercial side now
but they come from manufacturing and
Fabrication which is great you need that
side of the puzzle uh but you also need
the grower the hash maker you know the
guy who's going to be putting the
product into these pieces of equipment
who will understand the pain points much
differently than the person it's just
like anything in cannabis right you've
got all these sort of big money guys
that came in and sort of they have this
corporate culture uh and they didn't
really respect the people who were from
the Legacy and vice versa the Legacy
people were like oh these corporate
douchebags we don't but if they
understand that you need each other to
sort of operate in that corporate
landscape but still bring in that actual
culture of the grower hash maker the
heady culture you always need those two
I've always said it like both sides
always think that they're kind of the
best kind of like Mick Jagger and Keith
Richards but really alone they suck
balls but when you put them together and
you create that third little entity in
the middle the the Rolling Stones that's
the that's the magic right where you can
create that Synergy so and it isn't even
just the ideas it has to be the right
people right because I've gotten in and
out of you know you got to have the
right people at the right time in their
lives everybody's got to have the right
amount of ego the right amount of
self-confidence but the right amount of
lack of ego too right totally man it's
not an easy it's literally like like
winning a lottery if you can if you can
nail it but uh it's what entrepreneurs
love and it's fun and I'm having fun
with the company I would was uh you know
pretty exclusive for The Last 5 Years my
contract with them just just ended my
exclusive contract so now I'm able in my
consulting which I'm doing a lot of
these
days able to access different calibers
of equipment because there's no doubt
about it that Whistler technology is at
the very very top beautiful I've seen it
I I I've looked I've studied it as much
as you can you know online and stuff and
absolutely beautiful and yeah it's
completely like it's really for eug GMP
and gpp like be more so than like trap
Labs not that I don't have utter and
complete respect for trap Labs but you
don't need to over engineer the
equipment to that level for that kind of
lab if you're not you know highly
regulated so this equipment is highly
regulated the way it's designed is for
highly regulated markets I dare say that
you have not smoked any particulate
matter in 30
years it's been at least 24 to 25 you're
not wrong on that sense that means leaf
for you neop fites out there that that
basically means leaf leaf or stem or or
uh uh cellulose or I'm not I'm not going
to go on because I'm not that
smart but you're not wrong thank
you so man um so in fact let me say one
thing on that point before you go on I
would love to design in my brand I have
the bubble man brand and it's
operational in some states I would love
to create the product where I do an
extract and it's in the jar and then I
take the flour that I extracted it from
and I dry that out and I create
cardboard boxes out of
it the resin itself goes into the budm
made box which is basically cellulose
and fiber which is exactly what
cardboard is cellulose and fiber so
flower isn't too far off it it would be
very easy to turn buds into a cardboard
is this is this the first time you've
spit that that that little idea or have
cuz manifestation I believe in
wholeheartedly so I'm already I already
think you're GNA have it done
somehow yeah I've mentioned it just a
few times to sort of friends in passing
I don't think I've ever mentioned it on
a podcast or anything so this will be
the uh this will be the test I think it
would just be amazing to get that Tech
down take all your dried your wet flour
and dry it out and get it pressed and
card F and C printed on like how sick
would that be if you probably could
manage to get a little scratch and sniff
on the back too it's basically like
resin
deconstructed that's awesome man um so
you know um I got a you know I do have a
few questions here that I did want to
make sure because I want this to be
informative to people not just
entertaining I think I'm having a great
time usually if I'm having a good time
then everybody else is too so since
we're on the the the the the subject of
bubble hash um you know usually I ask
like people what's give me a couple of
tips on you know growing at home what I
want you to do is give me a couple of
piece of advice for you know uh
home bubblers we'll call them home
bubblers well I will say this you know
everyone how deep do you have to get
right cuz I know you know you can get
freezers for this you can work in a
freeze room you can get really really
deep but we're going to we're going to
lay it out here for the home guy couple
of tips that are above all GNA improve
his General work well I mean number one
tip is that the bags are the word of God
when it comes to the quality of your
resin and although cognitive dissonance
will allow you to delude yourself into
thinking you have better quality flour
than you may have and we've all been
subject to that me
included um the resin will not allow
that it's very difficult for the resin
to allow that so and what I mean by that
is they're they're the word of God when
you countless people when I release
these bags would message me and say Hey
how do I get my hash to melt like yours
is melting and I'm like oo now that's
not actually a technique in the hash
making that is actually something to do
with a the caliber of genetics that
you're running so that basically means
what are the gene synthes that are
present in those in that genetic code
and which ones are on Gene synthes so
that's like you know if you have a th a
cbda gene synthes that plant can produce
cbda if it doesn't have the gene synthes
in its genetic code it's it's unable to
to produce that so this is where
breeders will figure out what's present
in a plant even if it's not dominant and
then they can be like oh this thing has
some it has the thcv a gene synthes we
can use that is breeding stock to bump
those numbers up and then I won't get
into you know breeding is that what we
would just call
dumpers well I mean if if they were the
gene syntheses of of resin and they they
could be dumpers and then if they were
also the gene synthesis of volatile
organic compounds they could also be
like super flavorful and tasty dumpers
right it all depends on what Gene
syntheses are present and so that's the
genetics right what genetics are there
then it comes down to are you able to
create an environment that allows that
plant to sequester the components that
it requires when it requires where it
requires and how it requires you know
which I'm always you know when people
say what's the what's the best way to
get great resin I'm a big proponent of
living soils it doesn't mean it's the
only way and I've smoked
incredible material resins from
non-living soils that have that have
blown me away completely so I'm not
saying it's the be all end all I'm
saying that the intelligence that the
fungi has the micro rizosphere that is
coding your root system in a living soil
uh environment is an intelligence that
we cannot quite understand it has a
direct link of communication with the
plant where it's like I need some of
this boom it gets it it sequesters it It
prepares it and then it delivers it
right to where it needs to be in a way
that I mean sure there's probably some
phds out there that are very intelligent
and have somewhat of an understanding
but I can almost unequivocally say that
until we have like some super level of
sentient AI Singularity type [ __ ] um
nothing is going to be stronger or
smarter than so I'm going to take you
forward so we we've got the material
okay and give us a give me a little bit
in the technique of how to handle it
that's what people need to
know well I mean I like hash never
touched as a macro photographer I prefer
that the plants don't don't get touched
I don't want people rubbing up against
them with t-shirts or hoodies because
then these big fibers stick in there um
it's the same from the hash perspective
when I start macro photographing resin
and I see when there's buds just leaning
over that people are brushing as they
walk by and I get under my re my my
macroscope and I realize the resin
glands have been torn off they've been
stretched and pulled and contaminated
and I'm like uh don't do that so I like
never touched I love I I I I don't mind
running dry material or fresh Frozen um
the best of the best materials even
dried out will produce incredible
quality hashes now the fresh frozen
pathway really became a thing for people
to have more of a chance of acquiring
full melt so whereas old school Growers
like yourself and people that we know
have been curing these monot Turpin
these very costic rough sort of tpin out
of the plant that's what that's why we
cure flour we get rid of that harsh
stuff well in the world of fresh frozen
both BHO and wet wash we're trapping all
of those monot Turpin now as you raise
the turpine profile
percentage you increase the likeliness
of a of a shimmering melty glow as you
hit that hash that's not necessarily the
same thing as a perfectly grown resin
gland that will melt into a liquid and
boil upon Heat Going near it those are
those are different things pick up what
you're laying down I I am picking up
what you're laying down well there
there's even another way so not only
will they use fresh frozen for that
they'll then take the hash afterwards
and this is you know with with water
hash even for home guys listen the
recipe is super simple if you follow the
very simple recipe of mixing and
settling and pulling you end up getting
what is there very effective
the only very difficult part that enjo
involves subtle nuances is the drying of
the hash that's the trick that's the
trick drying it no I have I have
questions before then so so Step One is
dry your
flour and cure it with the with the with
the Sugar Leaf with with the sugar leaf
on it right whole plant dry it and cure
it and then and so you're going to dry
it you're going to Buck it down you're
going to put it in containers and cure
it the way an expert or or the way the
best but and that would be the before
you would prefer taking away all the
other Perfections and
Imperfections you're in your home you
grow it in your closet you grew a really
great batch you're going to dry it
slowly you're going to Buck and you're
not you're going to leave all the sugar
leaf on it and then you're going to Buck
it down and you're going to cure it is
is this what I'm taking from you well
this is what you're taking from you but
the guy next to you could have said so
what you're saying is you want me to cut
it down all fresh freeze it flash freeze
it and then run it fresh what I would
suggest is both to find out what you
like and you'll see that the old school
guys prefer the cured resin and the
younger guys they're more now like
addicted to that just that crazy grab by
the neck so good answer fresh is what's
most popular right now good answer so
now okay so I'm going to I'm going to
I'm going to hang it whole and I'm going
to put it into jars and I'm going to
cure it for a couple of weeks and then
I'm going to trim those I'm going to put
them in jars Loosely and then I'm going
to trim off all the sugar and that's
what I'm going to make no wait there's
no trimming anymore we're using the
whole buds so you're going to clean that
off of all the stem correct you're going
to really break it down small now that
you got cured
Buds and this is where I'm going to
start my process okay anybody can do
this at home we haven't we haven't we
haven't broken anything made anything
too heady right like that that is non
understanding so am I is this is this a
good am I am I you with me so
far yeah yeah okay so now so now I got
my my five or my 10 or my 20 gallon
bubble bags and of course you don't want
to use top water because water is a
source of contaminants
correct it absolutely can be now keep in
mind from the perspective of the home
User it's not the end of the world you
know from the perspective of the
commercial producer well there's
regulations to follow and you want to
just make sure your product if if you
follow me I'm just following a simple
path I'm still a simple man I'm
domesticated I don't have a factory I
don't have a growroom I have a grow tent
so it's real simple for me so I'm just
bringing it along at a real simple pace
but from the man who's done it all so so
now we got our we got our bubble bags
and so I'm going to use either filtered
water or I'm going to go out and buy
some purified water I mean that's worth
the money right yeah yeah it's not too
difficult to do for sure okay same thing
with the ice right so you know I've
exactly soce with the water that you got
exactly back in the day I started buying
clean ice but what you couldn't just buy
it anywhere you wanted to buy filtered
clean ice so now you've got clean water
in most ice what's that do you know
what's in most ice water fluoride fluide
water water water is in all ice
exclusively fluide is only in some ice
but yeah you buy it and you're like why
the [ __ ] are these [ __ ] putting
fluide in this this is not even sensible
and they don't even have to list
it yeah it's often LED though so so
we're so so look I'm just hammering the
basics really quick so you got your
material that's how you do it you got
clean water clean ice and so now to me
the next important step
is cold water you got to be patient in
between the steps right you got to you
got to be patient in between the steps
you you got to put the ice in the water
and let it sit for a certain amount of
time you got to be patient you're not
wrong um this is one of the things that
the fresh frozen people will say when
you freeze the flour putting the flour
into the water allows you to use less
ice because the flow is so cold it
reduces the heat of the water you're
just proving it's all about expedience
and or uh expense what I'm talking about
is simple and pragmatic so so uh um so
again bubble man says I'm not wrong so
you're going to sit and you're going to
wait good 10 15 20 minutes maybe 30
minutes be patient to get your water as
cold nearly as cold as the ice right
before you take your material out of the
freezer and put it into the
bucket well also there's a second part
to that that you want to pay attention
to which is even the more important part
which
is first of all you want the temperature
to be basically you know 32 degrees
Fahrenheit 0 degrees CS um you want to
make sure that when you're putting dry
material in that you allow it to absorb
water and that's going to take at least
15 minutes because if you just start
mixing some bone dry material that goes
in there it'll start breaking off pieces
of contaminant and the the magic of
water hash is that everything floats in
the water while the resin glands which
are still affected by gravity uh due to
their density they sink in the water and
that's why the whole process works um if
you break the material up too small and
it loses its surface area size there's a
a threshold where small particulate will
will will sink yes see I'm bringing them
I'm bringing you down to the really the
really silly small granular stuff yeah
and that that was the next thing I was
going to say is after patience for
allowing the water to get cold then when
you do introduce the material to the
water you need patience again correct
because you have to let the material not
only get saturated but you want to make
sure the material now comes down in
temperature to the same temperature as
the water before you start
mixing yep yeah exactly and it's fun
it's like you can geek out on this when
you're at home I mean really the the the
process is fairly simple I know it's
scary especially for people that have
never done it before to just put you
know water and ice over their flowers or
their trim but um when you see what
comes out you'll just never look back
it's just this beautiful Sandy material
you can press it the whole Rosen world
we haven't even really gotten into that
but that's that's huge you know when I
first released Bubble Bags all all those
people that ask me hey how do you I get
my hash to melt like yours and you know
when you hear the answer it's like well
you have two options you can go down a
20-year rabbit hole and learn about the
symbiotic relationships of plants and
micro risos speres and all of the things
that they require when they require them
and how they require them you can learn
about light spectrums you can learn
about green houses and literally like a
multi-decade pathway or you could just
Jam that weed into a PVC pipe and get a
can of mutane and just like blast that
[ __ ] into a golden honey and it'll dab
perfectly and so unfortunately 98% of
people took that pathway and I was
scared for those people because a lot of
them blew up and burnt themselves and
whatnot so when I saw rosin come out I
saw that it was the same same like most
people's rosin is made from mediocre
bubble like if you get full melt bubble
there's almost no reason to press it
into rosin because you're going to get
like a 95% return or mediocre weed
you're pressing mediocre well that's it
you know like I don't know too many
people that do flower rosin anymore but
I know that a lot of the live hash rosin
it's very little of it is made from the
most exceptional hash and that's why the
people who have it will never have the
hash that they pressed the rosin from
and the rosin can look Triple A but if
you know it was pressed into rosin it
the hash probably wasn't uh I'm not
saying there's not anomalies but
um I just I love the fact that rosin
exists and now instead of people you
know like imagine being a young guy in
high school and just buying like a
little bag of weed and with a hair
straightener you could access dabs like
solventless dabs that you could just
drop into a little like that is huge man
it is you you can carry around a little
thing in your pocket now they actually
work that'll tell you the potency of the
weed you know you can bring it you know
it's really amazing and and and and bubs
may I call you cuz we're old friends
bubs you you you um you exist at a level
of cannabis um production and
consumption that all of us I don't know
how to liken it to anything else um
without demeaning it because you know I
have I do have an ultimate respect for
cannabis and it's really
unlike anything else more than it's like
and what what I'm trying to say is that
uh the discussions are
um they're very heady and uh uh I I
admire how far you've taken something
that like you said you know you just you
know even before pressing and resin you
know you just what was the old uh uh you
know if it don't if it don't it ain't
worth the trouble if it don't bubble if
it don't bubble it ain't worth the
trouble
and that was listen that was Rob Clark
who I first ever heard that from and
that's literally how I met skunkman Sam
by using that logo I got to give props
to Sam because it really was Sam's sort
of quote that he had
said well it was pre the wizard that was
my guy right the bubble bag guy but so
when I started the Bubble Bag Company
because Hillary black had introduced me
to Rob Clark I had met him in 95 at the
Cannabis Cup in Amsterdam maybe 98 too
but I bumped into him I don't know if
you remember that Thai food restaurant
behind uh aran's Greenhouse off the dam
rack it was all like the katoy
waitresses like it was all it all lady
boys who were the waitress it was hard
to forget this place because it was
pretty trippy back then um but they
allowed you to Puff they were super
open-minded they so I remember walking
up the stairs to get into that place and
it was like John Conroy was there and
Rob Clark had the rure and he laid me
out out with a a hit of the most
spectacular bubbly hash and he he looked
me right in the eye he lit it and then
he looked at me and he said if it don't
bubble it ain't worth the trouble and I
was just like that's stuck with me for
the rest of the cup you know I was like
I'll tell you you got to give Amsterdam
and High Times a mad shout out because
uh that really was the birth of of our I
mean listen of course this has been
going on for a thousand plus years and
there's been people that have been
involved in the prohibition and the
fight for you know cannabis versus evil
for a long long time but for our scene
that whole Cannabis Cup uh you know 1989
to whatever it went till was really
profound everybody
everybody that anybody thinks of as a
founder or a Trailblazer in our
community was on the cover of High Times
you know Dennis Peron Jack Herer um
Arian uh uh uh help me out you know I
mean every
body all of them um Keith stra um uh you
know uh Tommy Chong and Jack Jack and so
yeah without a doubt and come on there's
no way I would be sitting here talking
to you because Kyle wouldn't have been
invented and I never would have gotten
sent to
Switzerland and uh you know and you know
it really is uh worth a shout back to uh
all those people and I still keep in
touch
you know like I said I spoke to Andre
this morning who wished you well and um
remember when we raced up the mountain
to try and get the sun to raise so Andre
could get the picture of my wife for the
cover of High Times magazine yes I do on
on the top of uh over over across the
river from uh
Italy yeah yeah campon exactly it was L
Lugano yes I do remember how frantic he
had to get this picture yes it was it
was great I just remember the sun was
going down and then we were driving
around this mountain so fast that the
sun was going up tell me you still have
that
picture I don't know I if I ever got
that picture to be
honest yeah I have to I'll have to see
if Andre still has that
2001 Lugano Switzerland I'll have to ask
him so what else we got here I mean you
know uh uh everybody not most people
know about hash church that you brought
back after uh Hiatus and now you're I
don't know you got you got a how many
hundred episodes Have You Done of hash
Church oh geez I don't know it's been a
while since I did one but they're always
just right there now I've done so many I
will say that it was 167 without a break
without missing in like seven or eight
different countries like I just never
missed if it was a 9:00 a.m. on Sunday
West Coast time I made it I mean I
traveled through a blizzard in Brampton
Ontario with two Rastafarians after
landing from King Kingston Jamaica while
they were driving in the blizzard to get
me to this house so I could turn on and
and make the 9:00 a.m. hash Church um
you know host it was absolutely mental I
don't know what was driving me to be
honest um but I still do it now and then
and I've got some good friends that I
would like to bring forward I I forget
about the importance of that
conversation and then it wasn't it
wasn't a business it wasn't um to
compete with anything it was something
that was Standalone on it on its own we
never took sponsors we never you know we
never monetized the the the content
because I was
afraid um that it would affect the
Integrity of the content and so we just
never monetized it but oh man did I turn
down a lot of sponsorship offers for as
you know even though you know we are
obviously I'm here because of homegrown
and I've been working with homegrown
cannabis Co now for eight years eight
plus years
and um but uh I just think it's all
about perspective and I just try to
bring on people that have unique
perspectives you know something that has
to do with cannabis of course you know
or or or our community and and then we
just chitchat and uh you know um
sometimes people have products that they
like to talk about you know companies
that they've made they're entrepreneurs
and sometimes they're not um but like
you said it's it's it's unfiltered as
far as um nobody's brought on for the
sole re for for the main reason of
presenting a product no and I'm I'm
coming around a lot more I mean listen
you remember my party back in the day
Legends of hashish that was very much
the same thing I've refused to monetize
it I gave away any money that we made
from ticket sales over the cost of
throwing the party I would give it to
like the Cannabis college or the
Cannabis Compassion Club and Amsterdam
or whoever was wherever the country was
we were throwing it we would donate that
money away I was somehow like oh I just
can't monetize this Legends was always
about celebrating hash not talking
business not not like you know promoting
oneself or one's products and now
because it's it's a different world you
know back then we had Smugglers and
people that were under the the radar of
Johnny law that didn't want to be
photographed so there was no cameras you
know now
Legends yeah now it's like there's
multiple film Crews filming everything
recording everything like there's drone
shots there's you know full sponsorships
there's the young guys you know that's
that's you know you know the young guys
don't need me to teach them how to grow
anymore there's so many good Growers out
there man and certainly I can't I can't
keep up on my Instagram with all the
production value everybody's got
learning how to press the buttons and
make it look like they have all these
videographers but it's about perspective
and unique perspectives are still
valuable um and uh you know so that's
why we're here and I'm enjoying this
little chat with you and you know I
really hope that someday the last time
we saw each other was in Jamaica at my
wedding where you ended up in the bar
after hours where I decided to have my
after hours party you didn't even know
and we just we partied for three four
multiple hours together and uh I smoked
a that was the last time that I smoked
any quantity of really good good hash
was that like
that was 2014 yeah exactly yeah that was
when we got married yeah that's the year
that was the Year my son was born so we
had a baby with us that year yes yes
yeah I think my buddy Kimbo I think my
buddy Kimbo invited us all onto his big
51 foot yacht and we had like a a part
yeah yeah Kimo just passed away pour a
little out for Kimbo he just died of
cancer recently but he a he was a great
dude man yeah he just he just offered
that he's like hey if you want to bring
any of your friends on my boat man like
just put the invite out so I remember
you know you and Susie were there and
Ramo and Sandra were there and my both
my sons my my older son who was around
11 or 12 then and my youngest son who
was like two months old they were both
there yeah I that was a great trip and
um man I just I I keep thinking how I
can find a way to uh to bring us
together again for a uh a reunion who
knows how that'll happen um it's a must
I would enjoy that a great deal I would
I would as well um you know uh I have a
I have a I have a well-worded question
here I think is worth asking it says as
a respected figure in the Cannabis
Community what industry issues or Trends
do you feel are important for us to
address
or discuss what's on your
mind well I guess you know right off the
bat the industry is happening in a lot
of different places simultaneously so I
guess I could speak to both kind of
Canada and the US obviously the big
issue in the in the US is that it's not
fair to Brands and companies to have to
operate in every single state uh when
with the amount of states that are
allowing cannabis now at this point
federal law should pretty much kick in
so that uh you know the US can
can export their product around the
world potentially I would love to see
the US Hopscotch right to the top of the
game again by literally allowing the
importation of hash from other countries
and flower from other countries to bring
that sort of old school Vibe back but
also to create their own Federal you
know but not overregulation like the
Canadian one but created something where
it's like you know kind of of between
where we're at and where we came from
because I know a lot of people think
it's the old days were the dream days
but that was monetizing Prohibition the
the money was based on people doing jail
time and there's a karmic debt that
comes with that and that's why you
always saw these amazing like just kind
beautiful families Growers like just
awesome people getting robbed and then
getting busted and then getting just
like one thing after another there's
always this sort of karmic debt what do
you think about selling
what do you think about um you know the
uh the Psychedelic Community more
specific like the the psilocybin the
musroom mushroom Community is trying to
approach it um where uh they've learned
from Cannabis and you know they don't
want uh uh decriminalization or or
anything like that I mean do do you see
anything positive in in that do you have
any uh reach or friends in that
Community oh absolutely I was just with
actually Dennis McKenna uh in uh
Vancouver I was with my youngest son and
I bumped into Dennis at um this mushroom
event I think it was like the 43rd
annual van duen mushroom uh event which
was just spectacular and they did he
they did a whole talk on psychedelic
mushrooms and so at the core at least of
the psychedelic mushroom Community it's
um it's always been an incredible core
of people and I've been going to those
sort of psychedelic Gatherings for 20
plus years where you could go and meet
you know Ralph mner and Jonathan a and
Paul stamitz and and Terren and sort of
all of these guys that were writing
these books about these these compounds
back in the day that's sort of my
psychedelic Community you know now
there's a newer group that will expand I
always do welcome the newer group and
focus on the good of that but also
realize that there will be some wolves
and sheep's clothing uh that make their
way into the psych delc Community as
they always have you know even if you
look at rainbow gatherings uh there's
always been these sort of small percent
seeing as you you you you are kind of
plugged in you know to the that kind of
do you think that there is any chance
you know specifically in the states here
that there'll be a
um uh a recollection of the experiences
and the the actual relative danger as
opposed to the benefits and that
legalization will look more like you
know it should or is it going to get
wound up
in something red Bure bureaucratic do is
there a chance that they're going to
find a different
route I mean I surely hope so I always
have faith you know keep in mind it's
always the people [ __ ] this [ __ ] up
not the plant medicines themselves
they're good to go um it's the people
who think that they know what's best if
we just listen to these plants and you
know I I'm not for instance I'm not
against there being some
regulations for producing a medicine
like cannabis I I think it's fine to
have regulations now don't make them
insane and
impossible but definitely like have
levels that you won't accept for heavy
metals and pesticides and anything like
that molds yeast mildew like these are
important things to know what the what
the potency of the product is can't sell
to Children can't have a dispensary on
the corner behind a school
blah blah
blah yeah I mean there's some crazy ones
in Canada where you couldn't even see
inside they made you cover up the
windows which made it very dangerous for
the people who work there for people
that would want to go in and Rob the
place because you could just go in lock
the door and then be like Rob the place
and no one from outside could see you
that was just Chang you made me think of
something do you think that uh uh do you
think it would make a big difference if
the Le the people are trying to legalize
mushrooms for personal use if we simply
separated any type of commercial
activity from first just legalizing it
for personal use without any
restrictions in other words you hurt
somebody you you then you there are laws
if you hurt somebody generally you're
allowed to hurt yourself if you're at
home and you chop your finger off you
don't get charged with mutilating
another person you did it by accident
you chopped your finger off so you know
what I'm
saying I mean do you think that we'll
that that would be a good idea to just
simply try to legalize without the idea
of giving anybody the right listen in a
sense it is so that's where mushrooms
are at least here they're you know it's
only in once you dry them that it
somehow becomes an issue and I wouldn't
say there's a police force in British
Columbia actively enforcing is that your
distinction that you've come up
with no no here in Canada they're
they're they're they're illegal once
they're dried and I guess it's because
when they're fresh
they're so diluted of their drug
compound that it's it's just I don't
know what the numbers are but it might
even be that way in some of the states I
don't know but it's definitely that way
I I understand it it's pretty silly but
it's kind of like I pick them every year
I I picked a bunch of psilocybin
mushrooms this year cyan essin and aly's
and maybe some stunes I think the big
ones out here in La which are like
replacing all the housewives uh
anti-depressants are uh albino Avery
yeah so those are potent staria cubensis
cultivar and everybody's doing them in
gummies and micro doing and I do I do
now and then you know I even I I I tried
to find out if it would be a good thing
for me to do on a
regular
and I you know without uh stereotyping
it or without even putting in a negative
I just I couldn't find a regular dose
from me that was helpful there was
always some kind of a cown so it's a
regular it's it's an irregular use thing
for me how much where you're like
because generally a micro do of cocy and
you shouldn't even feel it it's so
subtle sure sure but uh what I found was
that after you
know if I even got up to 150 mics that
at the end of that day it was still
there was still some kind of a cown and
that's my own physiology and so yeah you
were feeling it I couldn't find a
neutrality where I only got that you
know where you take it you forget you
took it and three four hours later you
that's why I had such a good time that's
what it was that's a great thing that I
would love to be able to do and take
every day really depends on your
definition of the micro do because there
there are definitely different def
definitions of micro do and some people
they'll be like oh I take like a third
of a gram or a half a gram I'm like whoa
that's like really like to like what I
talk about as a micro do is an is a true
micro do it's such a small amount
there's no psychedelic effect to it it
doesn't affect like your appetite or
your it's just this super super slight
nudging of your overall being and how
you feel and it's very subtle uh that's
how I like it myself which is very very
very small amounts um I don't have a way
to test my psilocybin so I don't know
exactly what I'm taking but I know with
the dry mushroom that if I eat like a
stem and they're very thin stems a
little thicker than semin catas these
are the wavy caps the cyan Essence um
one small little stem is a perfect micro
do where maybe I might feel something
for five minutes like a little bit like
oh I feel like I took a dab or something
uh but it'll just dissipate in five
minutes I like to keep it below the
threshold of feeling it and then I can
do it every day and after like 20 or 30
days of that it's uh it's a it builds up
the effects of how good you
feel
interesting interesting I'm so glad we
got into that it's a crushing depression
actually it's an important um thing
nowadays for just people to have options
other than going to the to the doctor of
course yeah man absolutely and
particularly the psychiatric and mental
health problems those types of medicines
are you know ssris and whatnot they're
fairly harsh so to at least have
something else on the table I'm not
saying that every single person
shouldn't take those drugs because maybe
some people get helped by them but
there's a lot of people that don't and
when you take a drug for depression or
suicidal ideations and the top um side
effect is may cause suicidal
ideation that does not line up to me
that's insane no and they and they they
can get away with saying it right on the
television you listen you're not paying
attention the TV's running in the
background and you hear may cause
death I know what the [ __ ] kind of side
effect is that that's a seriously har
side effect actually because but because
they LIF listed it it they're no longer
liable and America runs on liability so
that's all you got to worry about God
Bless America God Bless America we love
it here you know so uh other than us uh
getting together we talked about the the
bubble has and we talked about how we
met and we talked about how much we want
to see each other again and uh we gave
respect to the old days of high times
and I think before we before we signed
on we we gave a little respect to some
of our missing soldiers you know we miss
uh we're not going to name we can't name
everybody but we we miss we miss
Frenchie and we miss subcool and we miss
Eddie Franco and Jack and yeah all these
people you know that uh were taken from
us and but we remember them and we smoke
in their honor and we mention their
names often and we we we recite the
stories and the things that they taught
us and um that's what it is being a uh
an OG an Oldtimer old school
industry an old school C uh culture type
person you know it was like like you
said you know sure there's plenty of
people that came before us we didn't
invent cannabis culture but boy was it
rocking when we when we were early and
High Times was still an icon of America
and every stoner in the world bought it
or or stole it off the news
rack back when the Dutch were still
open-minded right before they went
right-wing holy [ __ ] just like closing
down the red light trying to shut down
like making you know the Dutch
experiment where it's like 10 coffee
shops and 10 companies that will
represent and produce all the flour and
the hash for each of those C coffee
shops it's uh they want to lose the
value which is the importation right and
I get it they want that that coin for
themselves but if they were smart they
would go to those countries and say look
we pretty much [ __ ] your country over
uh for a long time especially back in
the day because the Dutch were the the
original Sailors they taught the
Russians how to sail and Russia damn
near took over the world so like the
Dutch they were out there sailing before
many and they um yeah they they they
could go to these countries and make
deals where if they legalized it you
could import it into it would just be a
special thing when you don't try to
control it and you still in my opinion
the perfect world will be when cannabis
is legal everywhere but I can get
Lebanese hash or California OG kush or
you know whatever you you need to be
able to get it from that spot where
Monsanto Lebanese
hash right
exactly hey brother you
know you
know a lot of people don't have a pallet
a lot of people can't taste the
difference between a McDonald's
hamburger a lot of people don't have a
pallet for cannabis or Hash A lot of
people don't have a pallet for
culture but it's important for people to
get together and just pay a little
reverence tell a few old stories
remember what the old times were and
pass it on to the young ones who weren't
born when you and I met and smoked our
first bowl of bubble
hash totally dude that's what's up I
love it I do love it so hey man I just
want to thank you for being on this was
a total blessing and you are a uh you
are a Chieftain among
Chiefs in my in my in my heart and uh if
you ever have any anything of
consequence or humor or of any type of
entertainment value that you want to
share with us again you just call us up
again and we'll do this
again that's what's up man I appreciate
it I really uh enjoyed hanging and
talking to you on a Sunday afternoon
here it's uh just a beautiful day blue
sky and just seeing your smiley face and
hearing your voice was uh indeed a
pleasure I look forward to uh to seeing
it going uh live me too man uplifting is
what I'm talking it was definitely
uplifting so uh with that we're going to
sign off and uh you have yourself a
great day and I would say stay green but
uh that doesn't apply to
you no it doesn't last thing I want is
green hash you can you can tell me to
Stay Gold Stay Gold my brother well now
that was enlightening Marcus bubbleman
Richardson is not just an expert on
Bubble hash and Entrepreneurship but he
is genuinely an extraordinary gentleman
I want to thank you all for being here
for another episode of growe at home
with Kyle kushman and please tune in for
the next extraordinary episode of Gua gu