[Music]
hey guys welcome to Bubble man's world
happy to have you here with me on this
beautiful almost fall morning it's uh
really sort of Switched here in British
Columbia in the last couple of days and
we went from our epic beautiful weather
to bur cold weather but that's cool um
this morning I wanted to tell you about
a cool product called grung off now
grung off is a friend of mine's company
Richard uh he owns this down in
California and uh it is quite a cleaning
technology um options for cleaning our
bongs our dirty bongs we know that we
after smoking for a little while
especially with the D Nails you get this
reclaim melting down the stem it's it
can be quite difficult to get off you
get quite a bit of uh I mean this is
just a hash bong so it's not going to
look as dirty as some of the herb bongs
that you guys might be used to
seeing so what I've done is I've taken
the mother ship and I've soaked it in
the grunge off okay when you first buy
grung off it's going to be a much Golder
color one of the great things of Oak
grung off is that you can use it uh for
a multitude of uses you don't need to
just use it once or twice but you can
use it literally like a 100 or 500 times
and so this particular grung off that
I've been using uh it's been used quite
often and it's there therefore the color
of the resin has mixed into the grung
off so from what I know about grung off
it is a enzyme uh from a soybean
something extracted from the soybean I
know that you can purchase this product
at Home Depot or or um some of those
type of shops uh it's a cleaning oil so
what Richard's done is he's taken it and
he's um marketed it to the Cannabis
world made it real easy nice small box
uh uh bottles nice small bottle that you
get you buy them in I bought it in a
case personally so I'll give you an idea
here I'm going to clean out this
particular unit and I'm going to pour it
into this unit you never got to see how
dirty this one was so what I figured I
would do is we would pour grung off into
this one I would let it settle for a
while the the cool thing about grunge
off is it doesn't doesn't clean like ISO
and rock salt where you want it clean
and you're going to shake shake shake
shake shake and get it real clean it's
more like an end of the night thing you
fill your bong with the grunge off you
wake up the next morning and
simply let's see what we got here we'll
pour this into
this from the mother ship to the Swiss
perk being very gentle when touching all
right so that's just coming right out a
lot more
room in the Mother Ship than in the
Swiss and then we'll just rinse this
little guy you can see he's still got
darkness and there's still spots where
he's been dirty now we're just going to
rinse him with some warm
water rinse off that too one thing you
notice when you start playing with the
grunge off is is that it's very slippery
stuff so please hold on to your pipe uh
I would hate to hear a story that
someone was grung off their piece and uh
lost it to the sink
Gods I give it a tiny little bit of a
shape but not much for the most part the
majority of the work's going to have
been done over
night and then I use nice hot water as
well when I'm doing this
part you can see right off the bat and
it's 90% cleaned there's a little bit
more resin in the stem that I'll
probably be be able to take off with a
sharp Skillet tool but if you clean it
often if you clean your pipe often you
won't have
to um do secondary and and third
tertiary cleans because literally the
first one will do the
job all right
so give you a little wipy and show you
what we got
here just tiny little bit of specks
still in the in the can I can see and a
few nice
marks of resin right where the nail sits
but for the most part that's a pretty
good clean right
there that Grunge off so normally now
what I would do is I would either um
using a toothpick or using a small piece
I would pick away uh these little pieces
these are only here because I waited so
long to clean my piece I certainly
didn't didn't have to wait uh the 3 days
that I waited usually one day is enough
but uh yeah just getting the toothpick
out and you can see once the bong is
real nice and warm and you've grunged
off the majority of it that resin just
comes off real easy on a
toothpick which it'll almost never just
rinse off with water so this little bit
of help is going to be key if you want
to get those last little drops of res
off off of the
pipe can see that I'm working
that and turned a multitude of times to
get that last little bit of
resin out of the
pipe boom Oh got quite a bit of it you
can tell there's see there's just the
tiniest little bit left here so
depending on how OCD you want your bong
it's just just a matter of uh giving it
a little bit more rinse I also noticed
that from my bong putting it down
there's a lot of hash on the outside
here so will also give that a little bit
of a
clean which
uh yeah nice big base on this Mothership
it catches hash sometimes that's that
doesn't make it into the bowl or other
times it's just hash that's on the
ground either way there's a nice clean
Mothership I'm going to get back to you
guys I'm going to let this guy sit for
about maybe an hour or two which isn't
quite the amount of time I like to let
it sit overnight is great but I'm going
to let it sit for an hour or two and
then I'm going to come back and we're
going to show you and that will be our
grunge off segment and you can pick up
grunge off at Fresh heads.com we sell it
on our website there and uh yeah if you
guys have any questions please put them
in the comment sections even if it's
just a comment or a critique throw it
down I'll read it and uh yeah hopefully
we'll will see a bunch of you guys next
Sunday I'm going to be doing hash Church
episode 2 it'll be a live stream so
please be good if you come into the chat
on video and understand that you can't
have a TV or a radio or any music
playing because we are streaming live uh
but we'd love to hear from you we'd love
to see you okay so I let the grunge off
soak for a couple of hours not as long
as I normally would but uh I think it's
safe to say we can take this grunge off
and place it back into the
bottle
do a quick Water
[Music]
Rinse all right
so that was just a 2hour
soak and we pretty much got everything
from a distance it probably looks like a
fairly nice clean
piece up close you can see there's still
some marks where the water was and
there's still a little reclaim in the
down stem and a little piece of hash
that I have stuck on the outside here
but not a bad job for the grunge off if
I would have left it overnight it would
be even better and once again I to clean
off that easy enough with a toothpick
particularly after I've already uh
heated it up and and used the uh grunge
off as well it just softens it up real
good it still has stick so you have to
actually physically remove it
but anyway there you go grunge
off
heyo
B Timber
[Music]
feel one man HR man
real me
going the purpose after we that to the
mind
purpose after weed gave by this
expression the purpose after weed let I
view the
time it is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
time gja is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do its purpose
of
dying will I've been traveling to
Kingston about 20 M hours sing on J like
the clock to Fresh vegetation with trees
and with flowers off
[Music]
stop me and if
bigger pass
[Music]
pass I make
pass pass
[Music]
pass pause that
now purp up the weed that keep me
going the purpose of the we to the
Mind purpose of the weed gave by this
expression the purpose of the weed let I
view the
time we is not here to trick the
mind it is only here to do it purpose of
time inis ganja is not here to trick the
mind
it is only here to do its purpose of
dying well I imagine on the road there
be some
cops upon your scene inter in my bra
that and behind your SC me and my team
another 25 come in and we smoke it half
[Music]
clean my ass
now I'm pass I'm
[Music]
pass
that