[Music]
all right well welcome back everyone uh
something I don't often do is go up into
the forest I have like acreage behind my
house and it's just trees for for Miles
literally you can walk over my house and
you can end up in Cypress bowl and I've
got hammocks strung up here two of them
here it's a little bit harder to get to
but me and John managed yeah and you
know it's a nice little drop here and
looks yeah it's like a 50ft drop or
whatever I'm used to those we should be
fine yeah you could do this drop on your
head John oh [ __ ] you know I've been
there I'm I'm a little bit more uh I got
a little bit more structure oh [ __ ] so
we got the little baby cakes Hitman and
I brought some of John's uh wonderful
dry sift that we made together recently
it's pretty wild to see bugs up here uh
uh in the shade isn't it yeah I was
going to say I got mosquitoes happening
yeah I just had one land on me and tried
to bite me actually I'm getting bit
they're big though they're big they're
big and slow they're big and slow
they're a little bit stunted from the
cold
weather there's a torch for you I'm
going to heat this up for you because
you're definitely doing the first D here
yeah so like we've mentioned in this
video today is my 41st birthday
stoked totally stoked feeling blessed in
in life feeling very uh just feeling
good always happy to make these videos
and share it with all of you guys John
and I were just talking with my friend
Bata downstairs and she was like what
are you guys doing and like this is we
just do this we make these videos and
it's it's kind of neat you know what're
we're educating you guys showing you
that you know what this is this is a
medicine just showing our own scene you
know I don't even know how much I guess
it is education in a sense well yeah
they're learning things but I learn
things too nice get him did you like
that I liked it although you didn't get
him like I was trying he got away from
me pretty good oh he got away again okay
so I'm going to go after mosquitoes and
here's your rip oh give
thanks worked out tasty and great was
beautiful nice mosquitoes left they're
high yeah they're done here let you take
a hit and I will heat up the baby cake
for you it's a great little pipe you got
there yeah well you know it seemed like
we needed it in uh Barcelona after the
denail died the the the mothership to me
it seemed like the pipe to pull out with
the
denail but we needed something that was
quicker and easier than that case each
time and the amount of you know how fast
things were traveling for us one scene
to a next one interview to a next it was
getting pretty crazy HEC it was pretty
crazy you know lot of fun so I've heated
it up right on the right where it says
hot the hot right in front of you there
yeah oo nice dunk now that was
professional you probably couldn't see
it from there but he dunked a huge
monster dab on there and it this little
10 mil Bowl it's not very um it's not
very forgiving if you make any mistakes
so a little bit of my hit actually went
down the center but John hit that with
accuracy not like the last one that's
okay man what a beautiful day it is so
this is the house sound out here that
you're looking at the Pacific Ocean and
there are killer whales and dolphins sea
lions and seals the whole nine yards one
of jao's favorite dive spots right out
there you go check it out one day if
you're ever in BC and uh I think we're
just going to finish up a few more dabs
and we will meet you guys out on the
back deck where we'll get this fresh
Frozen going fresh frozen fresh frozen
fresh frozen yeah peace
you're going to be okay John get that
man some
dabs or P dabs dabs dabs dude dabs
you're going to be okay John you're
going to be okay oh Jesus Christ
[Music]