hey guys uh welcome to bubble man's
world a little bit of a new video today
i'm trying out i'm going to do one of my
first reaction videos and so i've been
watching all sorts of these different
reaction
characters online
mostly for harry mack which is what i'm
going to be doing today
um i guess the first guy i got turned on
to was mr video he was pretty hilarious
he'd smoke joints and and react to
different uh you know songs that he had
never heard before i thought that was a
pretty cool concept and it kind of grew
and grew and grew and i've been watching
uh
you know i think there's cliff beets
who's like a ghost writer for the rap
industry and he does reactions that i i
kind of like and i watch um
oh no life shack is another one that's
pretty good and then uh recently oh my
goodness i hope i can remember his name
he's the po he's the poet gentleman
and so ah jeez
i'll i'll remember and i'll put it in
the comments because he's really good um
he does great harry mack reactions i
don't pretend to you know that i'm gonna
be doing amazing harry mack
reactions i don't know all the different
lingo and and whatnot in regards to his
you know skills and his ability to
freestyle and his ability to just
absolutely off the top create entire
songs that make full sense and have
depth and intellectualism and uh you
know lyricism that is just absolutely
next level so i wanted to do a reaction
video i don't even know how to really
edit these right now so this is just
kind of my first shot uh the one that
i'm gonna do is uh rap coltrane harry
mack rap coltrane where he took it's a
very wu-tang s beat going on in the
background he just absolutely crushes
this
i may end up doing all three songs that
he did as most of the reaction videos i
see are like that but i may just also to
get this one out and try and you know
get my first one done under the belt i
may just do the first track on this so
uh i guess without further ado
um
yeah let's watch fairy mack
[Music]
okay
h
[Music]
this is just the [ __ ] i'm into getting
loose over instrumentals people
recognize i'm influential slice you like
against you blades i just want to get
paid i'm giving rappers to fade cause my
flow is a great top in the class check
the way i'm rocking your ass i hear the
beat then i drop
so i don't know how many of you caught
that but that was some pretty incredible
double entendres going on there in
regards to i'll make you shake your ass
if you go back and listen to that one
and another one right before that after
influential just next level serious
beats and just you can just tell he's
about to murder this this beat even for
the first few seconds
breaking out the cage and [ __ ] when i
spit i'll be on some outrageous [ __ ]
amaze you quick you're bugging but you
see for me it's nothing [ __ ] if
they judging i'm the one they never
touch and they never busted quite to
this degree hey yo i kill [ __ ] in the
cypher like history no mystery and all
flow is fully evolved i'm way too hairy
i'm way too [ __ ] worried for y'all
i'm just myself damaging your health i
ain't on your radar system cause my [ __ ]
is stealth i be underground letting the
[ __ ] thunder pound i only come around
when it's time to hit you with the
blunted sound but i no longer smoke weed
cause that [ __ ] had me tripping it's
what i really don't need when i'm out
here ripping i had to keep my focus now
for rabbits it's hopeless i'm working
magic like hocus pocus i hope that you
know this neck is coming i got these wet
cats running i checked away my skills
getting summoned i'm bubbling like kids
that's playing outside in the summer
time and when they come to the lyrics i
don't ever kick no bummer rhymes and
every time they write it's where they
got they fighting one of mine so i'm
about to show em number one we're
slowing i'm going up i can't hold back
i'm crazy real my flow is better than
some navy seals i'm well trained i go to
war to injure rappers i pull out ninja
stars and throw them in the form of
vicious ass bars yeah
[Music]
you can hear that wu tang in there and
the way he's like delaying the the rhyme
with you know i throw some ninja
stars and goes in at you know in the
form of vicious ass bars it's just so
impressive and the cadence and how he
can change it up and how he can just
come up with this right off the top
is uh absolutely incredible let's get
back
to ninja rappers i pull out ninja stars
and throw them in the form of vicious as
bars yeah i spit it too fast for most to
comprehend and that's the reason i might
push you off the cliff my friend i get
you high just like a spliff again i got
you tripping in a whole nother state of
being the way i'm freeing is something
different keep your distance cause in
this instance i grow you in reverse to a
nymph in my video trending on the
internet been a threat ever since i was
young jabba rhyming off the tip it is we
getting it done making it sound like a
record but better our last forever i'm
the one that puts a wet rapper on the
stretcher i'm the one that gets his name
etched up in the stone tablets i be on
my own rap [ __ ] y'all should know mackin
i'm about to throw back into the session
something brand new they like we don't
even understand dude it's hard to
comprehend this level uh y'all know that
i stay on this dependence level yeah i
have always been a rebel guess it's just
embedded in my genes now i get lose with
the free style hear me rhyming they say
he's wild type of rapper that these kids
will take could be now i get props and
hip hop get views on tic toc every time
they step to mac they
cats got me pissed off ready for liftoff
hoping you are understanding the gist
boss uh and if not don't have to break
it down king with no crown they know i
got sacred sounds yeah my [ __ ] is holy
none can control me the one and only i
told you i'm hairy than rolling
something like woogie over bees i bring
heat i'm sweet as a cookie fresh out the
oven delivering the flavors they loving
we are not related not even the most
distant cousins so do not act that way
i'm here to rap for days i'm known for
spitting the abstract ass phrase that be
something like pablo picasso later in
life when it comes to ripping mics i'm
the major is type and my flavor is hype
pulling out the lightsaber tonight
slicing rappers with enticing lyrics i'm
slicing and dicing you catching the
little itty bits and nothingness really
unpredictable so shout to the wolf for
inspiring all the flows that i be
kicking someone called a [ __ ] fight
yeah you heard it right there shout to
the woo for the flows that i'm inspiring
somebody call the firemen that was
awesome it's also probably an important
time to take a dab got a bit of a dirty
rig today i do apologize for my
dirtiness on my rig but i'll get that
cleaned sooner than later in the
meantime it is bubble man's world we are
doing a hairy mac reaction i'm going to
give you a whole list of hairy mac
videos to go check out but if this works
out and people enjoy it i'll probably do
some more reaction videos not the same
as you know the reaction videos you see
out there right now because people are
seeing this stuff for the first time
i've watched this video like 15 times
already i'm absolutely addicted to it
that being said every friday harry
releases something new and i don't mind
doing a small little video to do a
reaction uh
for you guys if it interests you
[Music]
all right let's get back to that flow
think you on my level homie try again
i'm the rapper everyone admire you're in
that there is called the spazz improvise
i be john cole train with jazz improvise
i be bill evans sonny rollins rappers
broke with their styles like money
problems i'm back again wreaking like
manual underground sounds pound for the
[ __ ] sewer
absolutely incredible i'm uh i'm just
blown away like i said i've seen it 15
times
if you're a fan of hip-hop if you have
any appreciation for hip-hop whatsoever
you absolutely have to give this guy
massive props i mean here's a guy that's
just been completely influenced by the
culture he just is the most humble dude
he's absolutely
100 percent in it he's been practicing
for what i hear is about 18 years
uh and he's he's you know near mastering
his craft and every time he does
freestyles
he gets better and better and better and
you can actually watch him evolve
through his youtube content so
listen everybody thanks for watching
hopefully you enjoyed it
drop a comment down there give a like to
the video if it's something that you
appreciate if you want to see more of it
i'll do some more reaction videos here
in the future
[Music]
you