oh okay I guess that's it hey everybody
welcome to hash Church 3.0 episode 5 and
this is a weird house church because we
can't we haven't been able to go live I
haven't been able to get the stream from
zoom to go live on YouTube so
unfortunately currently we we aren't
live so we're gonna record this I got a
great group of people that that got up
for this today all over the countries so
we're gonna do it we're just gonna have
a chat and we won't have our live
audience like we normally do so that'll
be a little bit weird but we can still
record the show and throw it up on the
channel afterwards so I guess welcome
all you happy faces out there and in
Cannell and I have nothing on from the
waist down I'm just wearing a shirt
actually fuzzy pajamas only hey we got
Brian in from bestfriend farms to I
don't think you guys have ever maybe met
him he was in episode how you doing good
yeah of course thanks for coming out
I've been enjoying reposting all that
fire melty he'd been making yeah thanks
I just Sharon and it all comes through
the good old bubble bags
good good five gallon kit you are a
bubble ambassador I'll tell you there's
we are for sure getting there that's
awesome yeah good stuff and you get your
over in Maine yeah I mean it's starting
to get into spring everything's melting
and snow's disappearing and things the
garlic's starting to grow so we have
some new growth coming in and signs of
life
absolutely yeah you know it's it's so
wild to kind of
a situation where the winter is over and
people are kind of like getting ready to
you know do all this stuff plant those
seeds get the crops going
we got farmer Tom in the house I'm sure
he's been preparing yes sir
you've been on a cool little well I
guess you're probably not traveling
anymore but you were traveling for a
while cruising around teaching the good
word of hemp yeah it's been going pretty
well I've been doing these a hemp 101
the good the bad and the ugly we learned
a lot last year what to do what not to
do where the bottlenecks were and you
know people get solid information right
now I'm in Puerto Rico working with some
farmers down here to help them in some
different you know pet projects so and
working with the local medical growers
down here they got a pretty robust
medical system down here in Puerto Rico
and they really embraced the day up you
know all the doctors are recommending
cannabis to patients not just certain
doctors and it's good to see the
enthusiasm down here about a medical
program and they're so excited about it
and you know kind of reminds me of the
good old days you know I mean first in
Washington and what's legalization came
the toe went sour and so what's going on
so what we're seeing and then Oregon was
all fired up so I spent a lot of time
there but they're kind of getting sour
and so puerto rico's everybody's still
fired up it's keeping me fired up and as
far as the farm goes you know we've got
all of our seeds secured for the next
two years
we've got enough potting mix and seed
starter mix to get us through the next
couple of years and I just got my
ingredients from concentrates Northwest
in Portland secured those on Friday so
I'm feeling really comfortable about
what's coming on and I'm looking forward
to the future both on my farm and down
here in Puerto Rico well I love that
you're out there doing that man I feel
like a lot of farmers especially in the
u.s. right now need to know what not to
do almost as much as they need to know
what to do I feel bad that people are
getting scammed out of shitty seed that
they're growing and ending up
fitting into the regulations or it's
just not the seed that was said that
they were supposed to grow and just sort
of all this you know this pipe dream
vibe that just needs to be kind of put
into context and hey listen this is this
is hard work it can be done if you do it
right but you just see so many people
you know potentially losing their shirts
making last year in southern or again a
lot of these investors left once they
found out about the weather and
everything they left a bunch of these
farmers to fend for themselves so a lot
of stuff rotted in the field and you
know and they had a lot of mold down
there of course it was the worst season
we've had and I don't know how long
hopefully this year it looks like to be
a better year and I just don't like to
see people ripped off either you know
what we really teach is how to vet these
guys out how to do your due diligence
how to ask the right questions how to
contact other farmers who have used
these guys you want three C of A's for
C's to show they've done the proper
beating practices and done their due
diligence so there's not hermaphrodites
and doesn't cost all these issues you
know the only good thing about last year
is it really kind of thinned out the
riffraff you know what I mean it was a
horrible year nobody's doing well with
it and it kind of got the people R in it
just for the money out of the game and
it kind of you know real farmers were
prepared and we take the precaution we
don't pack our fields we allow for
ventilation we allow all these things
they're key components to having a
successful crop and farmers just are no
strangers to devastation like the way
money people are money money people hit
devastation and they are gone farmers
hit devastation and they start planting
for next year exactly you know you've
already done your due diligence in your
field you prepared for the worst like we
do every year and well you know we're
and being a cannabis farmers and
cannabis people in general I've been
talking about this a lot lately we're
used to adversity we're like Gumby like
man we can contort each way we'll figure
out a way you know and our model is man
there's always work around for
everything out there so that's the
message I'm putting out there for
everybody
think outside the box look outside the
bubble see how you can do it differently
and you'll get it
cannabis and hemp farmers were literally
bred for this
I mean farmers in their own right have
that aspect of you know understanding
weather and terroir and and all of these
things but then there's cannabis farmers
who also have had to deal with
prohibition the police a lifetime of
prison having your children taken away
having your dog shot having your friends
rat you out you know all of these
different things that are just like yeah
you have no idea regular farmer guy what
cannabis farmer guy has been going
through for the last like I don't even
know how many years but too long to
count along to count before your beard
was long and gray exactly before I had a
beard well I keep trying just because
I'm such a tenacious person I thought I
would try to stream this live on
Facebook as well but it is also not
working that's okay because we're
recording this and it's still gonna go
up and it's sure better than nothing and
I know that the people in chat right now
are a little bit bummed out that we're
unable to they're unable to watch but
hey at least we are able to gather and
talk about this wonderful plant that we
love and for those of you that don't
know I've got a t-shirt on of some
Lebanese women and they are making dry
set so how about that for a nice sunny
picture I want to be these mug I just
want to be wearing this outfit and I
want to be sifting in Lebanon with with
these people that's from the book
hashish right suomi Laval yeah I love
that book suomi laughs I want to say one
more thing please
you know while everybody's at home we
got an online school called hemp farming
Academy we've got a really good
community there where we have over 45
video courses plus we have a private
Facebook group that you can ask
questions in and I'll always pick up the
phone and if anybody out there wants to
talk to me about what I have going on or
the school or everything my phone number
is out
I'm the guy who always answers the phone
so thanks so much Marcus for inviting me
onto the show I know it's been a while
I've been super busy you know we've been
in Santa Fe New Mexico in Salt Lake City
and I've been hosted by the Chamber of
Commerce here in Puerto Rico and you
know I just been super busy and all this
other stuff has kind of caught me off
guard but you know we're farmers were
prepared for what's coming on down the
road and thanks so much for having me on
the show again of course we're happy to
have you Tom absolutely
Jesus I just had a good thought I was
gonna mention and I kind of lost it
darn Abbot well I guess SD 420k would
say oh wait there's people we need to
get in my bad look
hemp guy mark scaled own MC West I
forget sometimes that I have to get
permission to let people in so sorry
about that guys you were stuck in the in
the outside room there and but Dee 420k
is not in the house I kind of was hoping
that he was gonna scream the bong rip
but someone else screamed it so let's
let's do that because get a bomb in it
boys girls love that yes yes we've only
have two we're gonna invite a lot every
week I've invited Alice and I've invited
Maria and I've invited dr. Natasha who
else did I invite I invited Chloe
Villano
from from the college there I definitely
constantly have people telling me hey
why don't you invite more women on your
show and I'm like listen I'm inviting a
lot of women they're just not always
showing up what's with you guys that
you're always available just to roll in
and and and you know is our the wound I
know they're smarter but are they also
busier looks like
sometimes most likely did anyone catch
the subtle Grateful Dead reference there
I know Debbie and Mark probably did yeah
as long as you say is it that a Jimmy
Cliff song originally maybe yeah man
SWAT man smart women smarter yeah yeah
yeah song it's definitely a reggae team
they didn't write it no but they sure
played it they sure did it's a Harry
Belafonte song oh thank you that wisdom
and we all learn Harry Belafonte how you
doing hemp guy mister stunk man Sam mr.
Amsterdam I'm doing fine except for the
microphone is or the speaker's coming
out of my computer instead of my TV oh I
hate that
technical difficulties that happens well
we've got a good group in here twelve
thirteen of us did this start a half an
hour ago or you just well we have I've
been I've been recording for I don't
know maybe 25 minutes but we have not
been able to go live on YouTube
unfortunately so what I'm gonna do is
I'm just gonna post it so people can
watch it hey Sam how's your non THC CBD
variety going I don't have a mount ehe
CBD variety I thought you were playing
with one now my Corona cure is THC P of
which you've patented and it's now
available to us right all right several
years ago before they discovered THC P
it's kind of what I figured I could I I
didn't think it would take you long to
have a kilo of it you know I
heads I wouldn't expect him and his team
not to you know Patel I thought the
other day of a cool show idea would be I
mean I don't know how it would work you
you almost have to get Rick over there
or something but you have such an
incredible collection of cannabis museum
type things that it would be cool to go
through just a small amount of it one
day like things that you wanted to share
you know and just have someone like Rick
on camera being like oh and this is you
know you in the background explaining it
cuz for anyone that's ever been to Sam's
house emini he inevitably will always
disappear off to this little back room
and then come back something cool and it
could just be anything it could be a
silly DEA patch you know for a
particular year against cannabis growers
or it could be you know two thousand six
hundred year old cannabis seeds from a
grave site and in near some old tomb or
something but it's just neat stuff and
he has an enormous amount of it and he
has a really great knowledge on on what
it all is be I think it would be a cool
show Sam's Museum I could totally see it
yeah I mean really if you could if you
could afford it you'd get that little
you know your little puppet there
actually turned into a puppet and he
could do the whole show but that might
be too much investment of time and
energy
I can't believe on his way on his patch
collection alone that oh yeah
entertaining yeah yeah for real I only
have twelve hundred and fifty different
ones so if I spent one minute on each
one that take like half a day or
something it would be long I tuned in
absolutely yeah I actually the one I
really like are the my favorite of your
whole collection is the old like like
the what the hell are they I guess
they're like he's got like the beaver
land dams they're all like you know peak
artist apart those aren't patches though
no marijuana labels labels the Lee
those are my favorite underground labels
from illegal marijuana bouncers yeah
those are amazing dude the show in show
going so that's really beautiful
we don't want you to incriminate
yourself and tell it's active or not Wow
come on we can't really sign a non
active bladder sheet of blotter sheet
for 10 bucks I'm cherry wood it must be
some anniversary right now of owlsley of
bear because they keep seeing all these
bear stories coming up every well
there's Lee or whatever but is it like
an anniversary of his birth or death or
some other crazy ship that he did
recently cuz I've seen more on him in
the last like three or four days than I
have in the last year just an amazing
cat I mean yeah I got to run into him
oddly enough at a Debbie had us work one
of the Grateful Dead shows backward
gathering signatures for Jack back I
think in 95 no no 94 and yeah just
working the booth and up comes this cat
and he's like you want to play a buckle
he questioned me breath rebrand exactly
thousand dollars to you you know I'd
sell a little more but you know you're
with you know you're gathering
signatures so and and I say crazy I'm
Barry I know who you are you should ask
for the vial in his pocket yeah I was we
were way too bit again we were gathering
signatures that's when we're working out
in the lot we did that but when we're
inside we were serious about what we
were doing and you know we had serious
business
oh yeah yeah we ended up with a whole
big big jar of that here in Vancouver
for a lot I bet either still a few left
like that and that was like 25 plus
years ago it was just this big old
bottle of orange sunshine and it was it
was you know from that was that the
granulated was that the granulated well
the look kind of like looked like little
was a tiny little tab a tiny tiny tiny
little micro dot well they used to have
a friend of mine back when I originally
started with kin back in 93 was this cat
in Berkeley and he moved into a
abandoned house that house turned out to
be the old printing house for all the
old posters and they left all the old
plates and he started trading the
original last-gasp plates and all that
for actual art and one of the things he
got at one time was a time capsule of
orange sunshine and Purple Haze and we
actually got to do that and try the real
stuff which was actually it was
granulated you could crush it in between
quarters and snort it and it would onset
within 15 minutes and it was probably
the most amazing LSD I've ever had in my
life hands down people made that the
first time I had any Osley acid was
purple Asli but they were sweet little
flatter tabs and it was in the mid
sixties that's what these were they were
yeah they he bought that it was probably
a time capsule from back then that was
saved and he traded it for original dead
art yeah and the sunshine was put out by
the brotherhood sands group and that was
yeah I I still remember being at
Altamont this the free stones concert
and some guys were standing on top of a
big School Bus well psychedelic school
bus and
they had a huge brown paper bag like
from a grocery store
completely filled to the top with orange
Sunshine's and they were reaching in and
the guy's arms were completely coated
with orange to the audience handful
after handful after handful after
handful the day the day the day the
Summer of Love died no Altamont damn
that was heavy vibes did you feel the
heavy vibes Sam or were you just trippin
balls
I was so tripped out I didn't know that
anything was bad happening until after
we got home and people started telling
me holy [ __ ] I was so high I didn't know
it was a bummer until somebody told me
you could tell how much of a bummer it
was by just listening to the interview
with Jerry Garcia right before like you
could be like well I I noticed that the
music kept stopping the stones are
playing and they kept stopping and I
would hear me say things like now stop
that stop that or whatever I guess that
was when the angels were murdering the
black guy yeah I think they put like a
they had some type of a hit on Mick
Jagger for a little wild anything
weren't they kind of upset with him
about that
yeah him and Keith Wow
well I'm I can't you know what Sam it's
just kind of blows my mind that you were
just everywhere like I just like of
course we're at Altamont of course I
still AM everywhere oh my goodness it's
true isn't that the truth you're here
right now on hash Church that is quite a
story you know we got we got lucky too
up here because Nick obviously I don't
know if he got in trouble down in the
state sands but he did end up here in
Vancouver he did he did end up getting
in trouble up here him and his partner
Peter built a very big lab that was
producing DMT of MDMA and LSD crystal
and the whole nine yards it was it was
pretty crazy in the 90s the lab that was
produced in Vancouver it was it made our
city extremely psychedelic and I will
say that it's chick it changed
drastically when that lab got closed it
it took a few years but that whole you
know that lab was the production of
psychedelics for Canada and it was the
epicenter of Vancouver and it was
incredible I mean you could just buy
grams of crystal LSD for like you know
eight eight thousand bucks or whatever
and get yourself like I don't know
whatever I think it was ten thousand or
hits or something but um pretty crazy
that those guys just did that and I I
thank them for it because it was a lot
less alcohol people were consuming and
it was a very different frequency and
vibration that people were experiencing
thanks to the to the psychedelics that
that lab produced and they meant
business those guys they took [ __ ]
seriously they did not put out bad drugs
if it was LSD it was LSD if it was MDMA
it was actually MDMA I remember because
MDMA when they made it was a four hour
experience and when that lab closed and
people started doing it with other
molecules that were more accessible with
easier precursors or whatever it was it
was like ten hours long and people were
you know like just on it was bad drugs
it was just not the same thing as as
what those guys were doing so props not
not the same as good drugs as what well
I mean just accurate drugs I guess good
drugs from a chem extreme a chemist
standpoint is purity and accuracy like
is this the molecule he put a little
methamphetamine speed in with them to
pick you up oh yeah well I was
absolutely true so I'm sure orange
sunshine barrels had a little bit of
speed in them no they didn't know true
which ones not it they were Asli acid
not the sunshine banded brother
it was obviously acid because he somehow
for some reason thought that it made it
better you know he was one of the people
kind of like you Sam you and Osley are
the two similarities when I started
bubble bags
I had to somewhat abrasive characters
contact me via email at first I was just
like I knew who you were right away
because you were like you wrote me like
this short email that was like if it
don't bubble a date with the trouble do
you know whose first said that something
like that and I was just like this is
the night I can't remember what your
email was at the time it might have even
been snow wasn't skunk man some other I
was like is this [ __ ] so is this who
I think it is and and owlsley was
another character who hit me up he was
like yeah bubble bags hey like I like
butter better I like putting my resin
into butter and then he's like I started
a dialogue with him over bubble bags I
ended up sending him a set when he was
living I guess in Australia is that
where he finished his life is that some
right was he in Australia yeah so it's
correct yeah so that was that was like
the late 90s early 2000s that I sent him
some bags and he just couldn't
acknowledge that it was he was kind of
like yeah you know it's okay but I just
took it all and put it into butter I'm
like butter like his in fact like animal
fat you took that hash that you made and
you put it into animals I was like bro I
wish you could have just puffed a bowl
of it before you did that to each
they're not big on the meat diet right
like he was huge on the meat diet dude
it was like all the way have I ever told
the story about like when I met when I
met there I don't think so okay I
thought maybe I said that I had shirts
er yes crazy when you remember so I
defended my PhD dissertation on a
Wednesday afternoon it was March the
18th 1992 and March the 20th
a day and a half later we were in
Hamilton Ontario at the Grateful Dead
show and so a friend of mine was
actually having an affair with bear at
the time and she came up to me during
darkstar so I remember correctly
Darkstar it went into space and and
Starck star I was really high was just
really not in the mood to interact with
anybody and she said come with me you're
gonna we're gonna go meet bear and I'm
like oh okay
you know so I was led through a crowd of
people and she had a laminate so she was
able to get me back backstage and I was
literally on the side of the arena and
the band walk right in front of me like
Jerry was like right there like right in
front of me like as close as I am to my
computer you know I'm just like
starstruck I didn't know what to say and
bear was over in the side stage and he
had his belt buckle thing and a
flashlight and he was shining his
flashlight on belt buckles trying to
talk somebody into buying it and so
eventually I went over there and was
sort of his next person to talk to and
so this was during the drums portion now
because the drummers were just on stage
and the first thing he said when I
walked up to him is he grabbed me in the
gut and he said you need to go to the
gym pal he grabbed my beer belly and
pinched my gut and then my friend Sharon
introduced us and said this is my friend
mark he just got his PhD in chemistry
you should talk with there and so it was
cool because my first discussion of
chemistry outside of my PhD dissertation
defense because I slept the entire next
day Thursday then Friday we drove the
Hamilton was with Barre backstage at a
Grateful Dead show and we talked from
the drums portion through the end of the
show through everybody leaving the arena
I think we were the last two people in
the arena and just still talking about
chemistry and acid and just talking
about all kinds of things and he was
just an amazing dude and just yeah I had
basically about
two or three our conversation with him
at a Grateful Dead backstage and we were
the only two people in the building by
the end of the conversation and it's
crazy it was just it was just such a
wild conversation I if I could only had
a recorder and record like what we
talked about what we talked about
everything having to do with chemistry
about having to do with psychedelics
about having to do with extraction
chemical modification the early days he
would reference to other people I think
he may be talked about Nick I'm not sure
exactly it's I have to put thing and
again I was super super hot it's a time
so said that once before in hash Church
but yeah that's like I noticed might
create my first interaction with
chemistry as a PhD this was bigger
couldn't be any better come on that's
beyond epic dawg is that so cool is like
total circle because again I was just a
spun out kid on Grateful Dead tour in
the 80s you know like most kids just you
know wow this band is like it again I
had said this before on has Church you
can go to like a new young show or an
Allman Brothers show and you get hassled
if you had a one-hitter at a dead show
you could just blatantly just blaze out
in the open and it was just it was so
cool because again like if my friend G
chem dog who tells a story for most of
us who lived in the Northeast United
States we really didn't have access to
really kind bud like he'd go into
Manhattan and you get this little manila
envelope full of mostly seeds and stems
and it was like 40 bucks you know from
the same guy you get eight ball coke
from you know but you know that's like
the extent of of weed in Manhattan in
like the you know mid to late 80s so
when the dead came to town they just
brought great genetics from NorCal and
just tons of just great weed and so so
it was kind of like the cannabis smell
was the Grateful Dead show smelled to me
you know to me like it just it became
like it was so just conditioned to me
like really good weed oh yeah that
smells like a dead show like skunky weed
and we that smells like dog poo right
right hey Kevin how you doing what are
you doing
I begin you're out of purgatory well you
know what here's the thing we actually
aren't live right now we're recording
the show but I couldn't get zoom to work
because I'm guessing the entire world is
doing zoom doodles right those were
great Grateful Dead stories man I'll
tell you you definitely if you want to
see the most cannabis smoke you've ever
seen at a concert for me it was and I
was there with skunk man Sam and his
wife it was in Negril Jamaica at one of
Bob Marley's birthday bash concerts and
it was I have video footage of it the
audience legitimately looks like they're
on fire
there's just billows of smoke coming you
keep in mind to like when people smoke
in Jamaica they don't pass joints
everyone has their own joint so we're
you might have three or four people
together at a fish or a Dead concert
sharing a joint at a at a at a reggae
concert in Jamaica the joint is four
times bigger and nobody's sharing
anything it's just your own joint it was
you remember that Sam absolutely it was
impressive hey enjoy Jamaica concert
yard concerts mom yeah yard concerts
exactly just good vibes I know a lot of
musicians have been playing free
concerts lately including Neil Young if
you're not a part of it you can go to
Neil Young archives com cost about 20
bucks I got on there for the presale
tickets that he gives you when he does a
concert he'll let you buy them like a
about a week before and you get some
really great seats but also all of
Neil's entire catalog of music
is on Neil Young archives calm and it's
all of the highest caliber quality music
it's not some funk [ __ ] mp3s Neil's
obsessed with quality and with with
proper music but him and his wife have
been doing these fireside concert series
and he started it out in his like the
backyard of his ranch with his guitar
and his harmonica then he ends up inside
sitting next to the fireplace and he
does you know some harmonica some guitar
some piano just short concerts 20 to 30
minutes long but absolutely incredible
and very unique to be able to see that
with Neil Clinton Fearon the bassist
from the gladiators who's been doing his
own music for 25 plus years he did one
the other day that I posted as well and
I'm sure there's a lot more that you
guys probably know of as well but have
been doing these live concerts during
art self-isolation time I think ray
anastasiya has been doing some corn
tunes as well I've seen them not live
but I've definitely seen a lot of them
in his living room that's great at least
like two songs yeah just playing
treatment Mike Mike's been doing some
bass lessons and some Theory lessons on
his channel as well so if any you guys
are our fans of his bass playing you can
check that that out and hey learning the
covert virus in cannabis I shared this
link with Sam and with Marcus
unnourished I'm gonna put it in the chat
obviously not now but when you guys get
a chance check out this YouTube video
from this guy over Ebru University who
talks about the recovery phase from
kovat and out cannabis indica
quote-unquote can be useful I know let's
talk about that mark yeah I mean I again
I I was actually in the middle of
watching this when the episode started
so I want to give this guy a full listen
to before I completely discount what
he's saying but do you know the state at
all Kevin I don't I haven't seen the
paper yet but I have been digging
through their literature and it's the
the lung fibrosis seems to be very
interesting
where it maybe reducing lung fibrosis
maybe in recovery I don't know the vibe
the viral load stuffs kind of all over
the map there's some positive results
although they're in very small studies
with HCV but it doesn't work with HPV
and then I think someone published a
paper showing that in THC and mice it
can make it worse so yeah it's kind of
uh it's murky it's murky information but
I don't know that there's reason to
suggest people get off their
cannabinoids right now it seems to be a
little bit premature and could be risky
depending on people's condition yeah
absolutely because in general doesn't it
just sort of boost your your you know
your immune system in general because of
its cb2 activity and just sort of act as
sort of like a peripheral
anti-inflammatory agent that would help
with fever or any other symptoms that
could come along with getting anybody
nice I'm not a physician I've been told
to say that a lot when it comes to this
stuff but what I've read is it's an
immune modulator so if your immune
systems down it brings it up if it's
cytokine in the vacants in a cytokine
storm brings it down that's probably the
most important feature because the
cytokine storms were killing people with
Kove it you know the viral loads are
going down and the storms are going up
which is a sign that your immune systems
already dealing with that but the
dragonfly risk medicine family and
bubbleman hosted a webinar a couple of
days ago with a few doctors on board
talking about this very issue it's very
informative and very upbeat there's a
couple of out there moments but it's
worth checking out I don't know the link
on it I don't know if Josh and Kelly are
still on but it's bubbleman you would
know how to steer people towards that
show yeah I put it on about this that
was all dragonfly earth medicine all I
did was host and listen so the props
goes to them and all the people they
organized and brought on that was
amazing I really liked it I thought
Ethan's presentation was really solid
I liked Terry a lot he was just like I
was just
like am I gonna go hang out with this
guy when this when the self-isolation
things over cuz he just was like he's
wrong yeah he's just the mushroom man I
love I love that guy actually believes
what you started self-oscillation
you know Todd's got his that's the one
minute to mention about you know the
thing about cannabis is that it brings
balance and stasis because it's an
adaptogen yes this is true eating it or
smoking so okay yeah I mean especially
if you have it in your chest they're
telling you not to smoke at all that it
all should be ingested if your
respiratory distress smoking cannabis is
not what you want to be doing you don't
I don't even know if vaping it is safe
but you know your lungs are trying to
recover and your lungs you're trying I
don't think that it's it's more just to
give your lungs a break from all the you
know stress that just smoking puts on it
what about dads like 450 you know I
don't think the research is is out there
I mean maybe we should do the research
I'll be the subject I'm set up right now
at 450 degrees okay well first get
infected with the virus and well I mean
again a double-blind study you would
have to actually have patients with
viral load I mean it's just I don't even
know how you but the mechanism for
putting health workers in harm's way and
how that whole thing plays out you know
I think it's long as you give my dad
first they'll go with it yeah well we're
well that was weird
Oh a little bit 18 what'd you say I said
we're just following CDC guidelines and
proper six foot spacing we've also got
authorization to do curbside delivery so
things that we're limiting as best as we
can patients access yeah I mean check
out this for irony so Pennsylvania as
you know has state-run liquor stores
well those are all closed but they
deemed cannabis as being medically
necessary
so the cannabis stores in Pennsylvania
are open but the liquor stores are
closed we're living in the upside-down
times for sure no go ahead Tim okay I
just wanted to mention that the highest
I ever got on acid was not oddly acid it
was a nix acid orange sunshine and I ate
between fifty and a hundred of them I
didn't know my friend ed dosed his bond
Oh of orange juice with a hundred hits
and I was so thirsty they walked up to
right if I could add some orange juice
because yeah and he's soaked like the
kind then he watch me with really big
eyes is a great half the bottle or more
oh my god Sam that's dr. Seuss character
my wife was there so she did her VW Bug
and we went back to more candy that I
was able to sleep that right because
when I discovered with acid is once you
take more than 500 or a thousand bikes
you don't you might have a slightly
stronger experience but it doesn't
really last longer or you know it's
okay four months as opposed to five
minutes pretty safe stuff I'm like I
know guys the dead very small amounts
and just never came back the same they
just had it they just went to a
different place Syd Barrett
cough cough Syd Barrett yeah I mean I
didn't know him personally but that's
definitely a good example but I don't we
all have our own Syd Barrett's like I
remember we had our own Syd Barrett we
called him microwave well I never really
had bad trips and I I took the acid more
than 500 times blue has taken a trip
during quarantine already no thanks I
yeah
I know my psyche and all that and yet
not the time probably yeah no not time I
stress about it it's not a very high
dose if you don't feel like sharing if
it's not very intense and you don't
think about coronavirus that much and
that word is ending I'm kidding but yeah
it is a nice it is it is a nice thing
and helps out I feel like well welcome
Alison walk sauce thank you guys thanks
for showing up how how was Spain
congratulations on a near win there I'm
you're snacking thank you guys
actually it was kind of crazy we're
quarantined together now since we came
back from Spain I'm not an American
citizen so it was pretty stressful the
returned I really thought I wasn't
coming back I actually entered United
States one hour before they closed the
doors for like any outsider you know any
any person that it's not an American
citizen so it was very stressful
experience but we're here safe in his
house there's a huge garden I'm
inspiring I'm getting a lot inspired and
attempt your family right now so I'm
using this quarantine time to plan a
garden and to prep the garden
chase what I think everyone should do so
everyone that has a garden should do
that so now it's this time all of my
free time will be towards that and Spain
didn't happen much Genovese was canceled
some cups happen happily the ego clash
had happened
this guy here got first first first in
water hash the theory I got sick and it
was very nice everyone congrats course
take it home with the bubble bags or
maybe not I don't know I don't want to
overstep my boundaries use according to
watch to look at resin he was nice but
what's short cut short yeah yeah I was
surprised how many people went I was
supposed to go to Italy on the 24th to
see this different form of extraction I
was going to do a tour and then I was
kind of like oh geez I don't know like
it sounds like Italy is not doing too
well with this like maybe they're gonna
quarantine people I don't want to get
caught up in a quarantine and that was
like weeks before Barcelona like at
least two and a half weeks or something
and then people were all like oh I'm
going to Barcelona I'm like what like I
just kind of saw the writing on the wall
I was so surprised at how many of my
friends were like yeah yeah I'm going I
was just like wow alright let me know
how it goes
because spannabis I think this been
abyss as an event was very irresponsible
and they're still being very responsible
because they posted something online
that they were not going to cancel the
event like 500 right and then and then
the government made them shut down there
not maybe event not happen and now have
a new date guys we don't know what the
[ __ ] going on the work and now they
have a new date on September well what I
heard was that they did not have
insurance to cover like you know
cancelling it because of some virus but
if the city cancelled it then they might
be insured so they had to wait for the
city to cancel the event and the city
cancelled the event like on an hour
after everyone showed up to
now everyone showed up everyone everyone
everyone dropped the gardener before
like one week before sometimes you know
like so it's it's a it's very
responsible especially when you're
dealing with people that I mean work
with cannabis I feel like it well I
guess go ahead think about it
spannabis and all these big smoking
events half the people I know get sick
when they go to them oh yeah no deny
that that's just a cold truth I was
thinking man if everybody goes there and
Corona had some Jesus Christ oh it's a
huge vector like nobody can deny the
vector that is fifty thousand cannabis
smokers getting together and it's in a
city where everyone that doesn't smoke
cannabis smokes cigarettes and just
smoking smoking smoking smoking I mean
it's the sickest I've ever gotten in my
life has been expand abyss and it was no
joke I was sick for four weeks hard like
bedridden like thought I was but my wife
ended up in the hospital I know and we
stayed at the same place so what your
wife got was what I got like we all were
under the same roof that trip
you me Diana and Tony it's crazy to see
you that you got sick to Marco's because
I know you don't share things with other
people I know you don't share your
devices you know smoke joints I feel
like in a moment like this we always
have to think about all this harm
reduction strategies that we already
know for like drug consumption but way
more you know like when we were there I
was I was kind of paranoid with bacteria
and everybody expanded his chairs joints
and chairs pipes it shares bongs way
viruses word viruses are completely
different you know they're not like
bacteria like if you have strep you
should be taking an antibiotic but
actually if you have a virus taking an
antibiotic is actually
not the really the best thing you can do
for your house and and the thing is is
like well the way viruses viruses were
just like bundles of RNA and DNA that
get into your cell and infect yourselves
and so it just it works completely
different than then then bugs it's just
it's it's not like a it's not like a
bacteria and so and so when you were
saying like yeah well it's kind of like
the kid who ate dirt as a child is
healthier because his immune system was
challenged with not like the complete
viruses but just like a piece of the
virus I'm not exactly sure how the body
uses like its immune challenges early in
your lifetime to develop an immune
response and so like some people may get
the corona virus and it may just be like
influenza virus to make it a sore throat
it may be you know again go through
their system in like a week or two but
others are gonna be really susceptible
and I guess it hits the lungs and before
you find out if you don't do the testing
you know in a reasonable period of time
it could be too late and that's when you
need to respirator and that's where put
strain on the medical system but there
is no real you can't really you can
attack viruses with a prophylactic
antiviral like they're talking about
this chloro quinine and all this other
stuff but they really don't have things
that are specific that fight these
viruses that's why HIV was such a
challenge to develop specific antiviral
therapies to treat it I faith in our
immune systems it's the ultimate
laboratory where that is done
pharmaceutical company right and so and
and so on that aspect I think you know
Ethan hit on this the other day which is
I think keeping your endocannabinoids
sister from nourished can only help
right because
you're basically you're gonna get your
immune system as good as it could
possibly be to you know fight off what
it can't and what it can do ultimately I
think if you do get a virus whatever
virus whether it's a rhinovirus
it's a common cold or just some other
you know viral infection the best thing
you can do is yes sleep push the fluids
get your kidneys working you know and
just you know try to you know stay away
from things like antibiotics the thing
with antibiotics if you dude you take an
antibiotic you should be taking you know
live yogurt cultures after that to help
reestablish again what these guys were
talking about in the talk the other day
which is your bio yeah unfortunately you
know if you're taking antibiotics well
first thing I wanted to say is that a
lot of the science and everything behind
this is all funded by pharmaceutical
companies so let's not forget you know
them up with solutions for you that help
profit them so that really is bypassing
a lot of the money and the research
being put into the natural immune system
which continues to be you know bypassed
because they don't want our natural
immune system to be first and foremost
because it's free and it's also because
we can make those things or we can grow
those things in our garden so I think
that you know also one thing we got to
cut out on before but cannabis is a is a
stasis it creates stasis in the body and
the reason why it creates stasis is
because it's an adaptogen so I think
that it's really important for us to
continue to look for natural adaptogens
and continue to have faith in our immune
system and every time that we take
antibiotics it's not just the upper
tract of our digestive tract that gets
washed out it's also our lower digestive
tract as well as different
microorganisms that are inside of our
blood so unfortunately just like
balancing with yogurt or a pre or
probiotic afterward is not truly gonna
help you we keep going back to soil
microbiology as well as you know birth
so many people now around the world are
being
via c-section and completely losing a
massive amount of the microbiome that
happens during birth coming through the
birth canal which sets us up for life
it's such a tone that we have for ever
and ever and nothing really can
necessarily penetrate that but
unfortunately you know this this virus
is is is is is telling us something we
as a human species right now are not
very healthy so that's the reason why
it's impacting humanity so much we need
to look to our immune system continue to
boost our happiness levels because when
we're depressed and we don't feel good
we produce cortisol and that's just a
bummer so that's all you know really
work on being happy and I just think
that and building our immune systems is
crucial like Mark was saying and you
know we drink medicinal mushrooms every
single day because we know there's
toxicity out there and viruses out there
all the time and medicinal mushrooms
give you killer T cells and cells that
go in it attack viruses that come into
our body and that's what makes us
healthy even out of the Black Plague
which killed millions of people that
people have lived through the Black
Plague all the sudden lived to 70 and 80
years old so in order for us as a human
race to get stronger and live longer we
have to look at our ultimate health and
it's not coming from the medical
industry it's coming from our food and
it's kind of beautiful that the
coronavirus is happening in the spring
right now it's the best time to start a
garden and a start of food all of the
videos that we're seeing from
supermarkets with people you know is
lined up for aisles trying to get food
when you know it's a wake-up call to
start producing some of your own food at
home and then you can start making your
own seed which you're gonna continue
growing but when you eat food from your
own garden it gives you endophytes and
it gives you special compounds from the
soil that help you fight off disease and
just like our microbiome right now
as a human species it's totally out of
balance so is our like faith and and and
feelings about science we're completely
out of balance with it we'll continue to
look towards science and away from
Mother Nature when she's the one that
has all of the answers we are people of
Earth I just wanted to make that
transplant patient did not want a strong
immune system it'll cause rejection of
their organs
they got there to begin with they're
having transplants above a bodily part
because already their microbiome was
already problematic so we have to look
at the root and not just say oh well
let's take you know point five percent
point zero zero five percent of the
whole population and use that bizarre as
our you know basis oh it's not that I'm
using them as an example it's that you
that there are groups of people who
cannot make their immune system as
strong responsible it'll kill ya you
lost their immune system already to
begin with their new system is gone and
then they don't patients and they have
to deal with bring that all together
this the drug that's showing so much
promise right now is actually initially
found in the bark of a tree so it's
quinine quinine is basically that's not
chloro quinine right there two different
Quinn has a chlorine group added to it
to slow the metabolism of it but it's
believed to have the same mode of action
but just last longer and then hydroxy
chloroquine has another hydroxyl group
hanging off of it somewhere yeah makes a
little bit safer but isn't that like a
metabolite or something like that yeah
is it that a metabolite or something or
something oh you can't you can try to
mimic it with their metabolized by 3 or
4 or so CBD slows that
grapefruit juice slows it down so some
folks are just taking quinine and
grapefruit juice to try and stretch the
quinine a little bit further you can get
quinine and tonic water but it's only at
80 like 83 Meg's per liter so people are
using this at like 400 to 500 Meg's in
some of the Kovac patient's sometimes
twice a day so I don't know if you get
there with quinine but you might be able
to get a prophylactic dose because I'm
assuming the prophylactic doses don't
need to be as high as the doses required
to treat people that have like millions
of viral particles per microliter right
if you're looking if you look at the
qPCR data in coma there's a the viral
load and the tissues is outrageous it's
really really high and there's they're
managing to reduce that with chloroquine
and hydroxychloroquine so I would
imagine if you're at an early infectious
stage and your viral load is really low
you probably don't need the full dose to
push it off and for it to be
preventative but I don't know it's so
it's all conjecture right now but I find
it somewhat reassuring that you know
this is this is a drug that actually
like most drugs we found in nature and
then modified and so it's uh hopefully
we'll be able to get it to the entire
world my fear about you know chloroquine
and Hydra Corp and I mean they all of
them have long QT issues you have to if
you have a fib I've got a fib so I can't
take it or I got to take very small
amounts of it because it can it can
trigger a fib patients to go into long
QT so it's gotta be monitored with like
in a live core and Apple watch or
something but there's gonna be rationing
issues I think the pharmaceutical comes
already donating millions of doses which
is a nice of them but I don't know that
it's gonna gets all 7 billion people
maybe it doesn't need to maybe the virus
doesn't spread that far but but quinine
is something that probably could like
that's an over-the-counter tonic water
right yeah yeah zinc is a there's
another good study on if you if you co
administer it with zinc it's believed
the motive action is still in debate
even though it's been around for 70
years but one mode of action that's been
proposed is that it's a zinc ionophore
so transfer zinc into the cell and zinc
is something that stalls the RNA
polymerase so the virus can't replicate
but human polymerase is seem to be able
to handle zinc just fine if you know it
competes for magnesium
I think in the in the polymerase is
class so what's the effective dose to be
able to control symptom ology in a
patient that's got advanced symptoms you
know like yeah the famous French paper
that came out from Ralph's lab was using
a combination of hydroxychloroquine and
I think an antibiotic surprisingly to
your point about antibiotics I don't
understand the mechanism of that but
that antibiotic is if from ice and I
think has some activity in a bola
and I don't I don't know why but
typically you're right markets they
don't touch viruses but this this one
particular antibiotic seems to be
helping and it may also be helping with
any sepsis or pneumonia based infections
that are going on so they're kind of
giving them yeah there's probably all
kinds of secondary [ __ ] that happens
yeah it's like throw a monkey wrench in
that's a really important point you know
everything that we do we really have to
think about it as you know like dropping
that stone in a puddle of water and you
know you don't look at the first ripple
you've got a look at the fiftieth ripple
and when we're dealing with our you know
health and well-being that's important
so well I've had a lot of experience
with chloroquine after the tsunami I was
over in the odd-shaped province in
Indonesia I was working with the w-h-o
you know going down the deep dark holes
of malaria because there was lots of
problems after the tsunami bad water I
saw a lot of very you know moderately
healthy people who were testing positive
with malaria
go on chloroquine and then become
incredibly sick so I don't necessarily
feel like you know on a personal level
you know I hear what other people are
saying out there in the world but I've
personally you know prescribed you know
hundreds of people chloroquine and felt
like that was a really bad road to go
down
what was your I'm curious what the side
effects people should look out for are
on it I mean I've read about the long QT
stuff but I haven't heard of any you
know a lot of people feebleness you know
people becoming very weak not only just
weak in their body but also sort of weak
in the mind and you're sort of sitting
there and talking to them
even after two days of using it and
their mind can't stick with like the
same train of thought or you know of
course I was dealing in at every big
disaster area you know there was a lot
of people that died I was there for a
long time and I know that you know they
had you know sadness and depression and
things on their mind at that time but it
still was like we called it the nine
yards stairs you know like somebody
looking off into the distance sort of
nine yards just just not really checked
into their body and it was almost like
you know the more that they were on the
chloroquine the more that you know they
were sort of leaving their body which is
also like the strength of their weird
dreams on it that's one that's one side
effect I read about but yeah
you know the doses for malaria do they
use more or less of it than they're
thinking about using for for kovat you
know I don't know I don't know what what
they're saying about it I feel like
quinine you know is an awesome idea and
you know we can go down that road and
talk about it because it's from nature
but then again you know just like Mark
was say and when you start to sympathize
synthesize things it really changes how
the body up takes it it understands that
though you know unfortunately I'm not
having a whole lot of faith in
chloroquine right now but that's my own
personal opinion you know something else
might come out that you know might be
awesome but I saw a lot of people have
depleted immune systems and depleted you
know vibrational energy from it okay and
I asked three questions I just have
three questions they could be answered
in the whole can we ever show cher
joints again can we clean the glassware
in between uses so it's safe that we can
use the same rig if we clean it and
three will our cannabis gatherings ever
be safe if we're not sharing but other
people are and then there's sloughing
virus everywhere
select the questions I would be buyers I
have to be able to fire
your break it out yeah break up they
brought way in while he's rezoning in as
I think there's gonna be a resistant
population because we see that and
almost all viral infections in any of
the models right now all the models you
have have this exponential curve with an
R nought of two which is very similar to
a PCR curve pre CR has an R nought of
two it doubles every cycle right so but
all of the all the projections are going
exponential to the moon they don't have
an S curve in them and everything in
nature typically has an S curve and that
S curve is a combination of social
distancing of natural immunity of
education and what have you so I I I'm I
guess I optimism is healthy for my
mental state right now I'm looking at
the graphs and thinking it's not gonna
be as doom and gloom Zombieland as we're
seeing out there and so III think we'll
soon have an immunity to this thing like
like other cold viruses that come
through our population that we deal with
yeah you you made me think of another
fish lyric Kevin right before was we
were treating the symptom and not the
cause now expanding exponentially like
summer eater like summer Harris you
gotta just drive up and play it cold
turkey like you no one knows you're
doing it forward thinking and again just
plant and good food around us
I'm also you know one quick thought to
what you were saying Debbie is if you're
gonna pass a pipe you can always light
it with your lighter on the end of the
pipe for a little while I learned that
from Bob Snodgrass you know it's a great
way to burn out anything but you know
not necessarily during this Tobit time
by any means but I think that you know
that could be helpful in a social
situation but also you know we have to
be into what you know type of
environment that's been given us and
also the fact that it's spring right now
the the shoots that are coming out on
the trees are extremely powerful
they're really high in vitamin C and and
Terry Willard brought up the alter
catkins and finding alder trees and and
the buds that are coming off on and
making medicine out of the buds you know
like our it's really powerful medicine
even the pine pollen and different
pollens that are coming out are
extremely useful to our immune systems
so the the beautiful new growth of life
that's happening in the spring we can
utilize in our immune systems right now
so it's again good timing if we want to
look towards nature towards some up for
some of our tears even birch bark you
can boil and drink birch bark and get
the betcha linic acid that's coming from
the cambium layer which is why Chagas so
important because chaga has the most
antioxidants of any herb or plant on
earth and the chaga tree you can also
tap right now a whole lot of people our
territory birch trees don't attack the
birch tree right now and that's
something that you can use directly into
an IV so you know that's just really
interesting how tree water and tree
blood is almost identical to you know
the same pH and the same sugars and and
nutrient value that our blood is pretty
awesome how nature provides at the same
time for me Birds polypore is a known
antiviral antifungal poly Porter that
was one of the three mushrooms found on
the ice man in Italy which is very
interesting the three mushrooms that
were found where the chaga the birch
polypore and the ama do go ahead and and
the birch polypore what we know about as
far as what nature produces it's
absolutely the strongest anti
environment the strongest anti defector
thing that the forest grows and it's
incredibly bitter but what's interesting
about it is when it grows on the chaga
tree or when it grows in nature it grows
on other things than birch but it's
white and it stays this gorgeous like
beautiful white color meaning like
nothing in the forest will attack it so
that's just we've actually used that as
a foliar spray on
ants that have any kind of mildew leaf
eating mildew or any plants that are
showing rust fungi it's been
unbelievable we've been able to drink it
I've given it to children who have had
wands and they've been able to determine
themselves within like a week
it's an unbelievable medicine there's a
really good there's a really good book
called The Cure ISM of forest and I
encourage people to get the book the
cure is in the forest and I think the
bark is an underutilized medicine by
people bark tree tips even even tree the
buck read the leaves its are the branch
itself is the very end is very useful to
it so I think it's yeah and people the
ability right now go on a walk let's get
outside go on walks of course your
social distancing but right now nature
just explode a spring and such a
wonderful opportunity to out there and
you know be the new Frazier thank lactic
acid bacteria and cover yourself in dirt
and wash it and face and compost and
smoke hashish okay I I've seen you know
I've been we've been because we've been
inside and we've been following this go
into the CDC's web site and trying to
get the latest and greatest instructions
on what we're to do if we are quarantine
my family here in my house is quarantine
we just want to make sure that we're
doing the right thing and we're you know
and I've heard mixed things some people
say that you should go outside and in
other people I had seen two posts and it
looked like it was from reputable
sources where they had a bunch of
activities and they said please remain
indoors is there a situation where if
the virus gets so widespread in your
community that actually staying indoors
is what is is more beneficial for the
collective good of society as opposed to
going outside as anyone now
well it's passed by droplets that we
know so the CDC you know made a decision
a few days ago they were trying to say
that it was airborne it's not it's
droplets so being out in nature only
gives you vitamin D which is absolutely
imperative to our immune system make
sure that when you are outside you're
not totally bundled up you know get
outside breathe the clean air I think
that it's really important I don't think
that we're gonna be you know nature is
not passing on the virus human beings
are passing on the virus so if you look
at the viral load of the area that you
live and if you live in New York or New
York City it would be really hard to go
outside and get that type of thing which
really points to the fact that people
living in the country or having that
country home is extremely beneficial
right now and that is how we've gotten
through the past sicknesses so going out
if you live near the country going
outside and covering yourself in dirt
breathing that air is going to be your
ultimate health I feel blessed to have a
forest in my backyard things grows
almost all the mushrooms you guys just
mentioned like mark all right behind the
house yeah I've been taking walks on the
beach and in trying to get out a good
bit here I'm in Massachusetts and you
know I have a lot of family in New York
in New York State in New York City and
you know I've been a resident of New
York City and I really feel for them
right now it's geographically it's not a
safe space so you know if you can get
outside do could you get our pen city if
there's a higher propensity of infected
patients by definition there could be a
higher propensity of infected services
so like you could just be walking I
guess to the store or something put your
hand on the wrong stair railing and get
affected that way
versus you know I live kind of like in a
suburb
I guess I'd call it you know I mean
there is a population density we lived
there's an houses around us and stuff
and certainly like when we go to our
there's a grocery store where most of we
mostly shop at
it's kind of like unlimited services
right now and it's kind of like I've
never seen it like this I don't remember
it being like this after 9/11 this is
like a whole new reality it really it
really really is yeah I don't know like
large cities like Los Angeles and New
York I mean it would you think again
again I understand this whole flattening
of the curve but man you need a certain
fraction of the population to do those
absolutely essential it's a big fraction
to if you a really good example is in
1918 when the Spanish flu hit I think it
was somewhere in Pennsylvania that you
guys threw this huge parade with like
two hundred thousand people yeah so then
like 4,500 people died and massive
casualties into the hospitals over the
course of the next seven days at the
exact same time in st. Louis they closed
schools churches gatherings of 50 or
more people like everything they just
closed everything and the end rare curve
was like this long flat like barely like
totally non comparable to what went down
in Philadelphia so that's kind of a good
sort of historical context of looking
Philadelphia they have done this before
like social isolation starving out the
virus definitely seemed to work at least
but then man conspiracy folks are just
going nuts right now like there is some
crazy shot listen I've always had an
appreciation for the bizarre the nut bar
that you know like back in the day I
read every single David Icke book I read
you know started with Robert Anton
Wilson got into Terrance but then
Terrance led into David Icke and all
that madness Cathy O'Brien
transformation of America just the
craziest [ __ ] you could possibly imagine
and I feel like it's just dangerous to
Terrance told me something a long time
mom didn't tell me but through the tapes
he said the anchor of mankind is belief
too fervently believe anything is the
anchor of free thought and when you
believe something you automatically
cannot believe it's opposite so what
I've tried to do in all of
is just kind of keep an open mind kind
of like I look at at least my government
here in Canada I don't think they're out
to get us they're like hey can you guys
like please just like socially isolate
like it doesn't seem like the same vibe
when I talked to my buddy in New York
who's like we're trying to take our guns
they're trying to make us stay in our
homes and I'm just like well like what a
total difference in the two countries
it's like our government's like can you
please just stay inside
Canadians are like I guess so like
probably what we should do like seems
like a smart thing to do but then from a
conspiracy stand part I think years
later since 1918 we still have a
hospital bed problem right I think you
can maybe blame on government but I
don't know about everything else I'm
they're saying that you know I think
it's important to note that it's not
that people just carry the virus from
one person to another there's cells
inside of healthy bodies that attack
viruses and kill viruses and they're
talking about using people's people that
get through the virus have natural
antibodies in their blood and in their
bodies that they they're talking about
you know being able to utilize to create
cures for it so it's very important for
people to realize you know how important
it is to be able to process a virus it
happens and it's essential to the
evolution of humanity how cool it is
because like two years ago we're felons
you know probably say it to the
responsibility of staying open like this
is pretty overwhelming yeah and you
actually just got a letter from the
Department of Ag in Oregon that states
because we are an agricultural company
and we have a lot of agricultural
licenses that were allowed to go on
about our business as long as we keep
social distance so
for us it's really awesome we're gonna
you know be responsible I don't know if
other people are necessarily responsible
out there but it it's pretty funny
Debbie you know you're you're saying
that you know we used to be you know on
the outs and now they're pretty much
they sent us a license in the mail
saying go ahead continue to deliver your
CBD to people so that's what we're doing
we're just going to continue to be able
to get the medicine out there so I was
really thankful to get a letter from the
Department of Ag saying go on about your
business but I do hear that that's does
that extend to all your like
subcontractors and all the people who
supply you I mean that's that's where it
seems like he gets a little foggy we
have we have to have already had a lot
of our product cuz it's really difficult
right now to get you know supplies yeah
it doesn't it doesn't pass over to our
suppliers by any means but what it does
do is it helps it keep it keep it open
so that if they shut down certain postal
services to certain businesses or areas
that they that we will continue to get
mail you know as long as they continue
to stay open but it's specific to just
our company and as far as supplies the
lucky thing is we've chosen to live near
a wilderness so we have endless supplies
of medicinal mushrooms that we will be
able to continue to have medicine no
matter what happens so I'd love to hear
from Jack and hear about what's going on
with the most vulnerable because you
know the people that are like blessed
enough to own properties and have
forests in their backyard and have all
this clean water and not be worried
about like how are the vulnerable people
of the streets feeling right now during
all of this Jack they look like this
like how I look right now
ah it's terrible man like I like you
said I feel very privileged because I'm
looking out at a forest in front of me
because I bailed out the reason I bailed
out is because they closed all of the
shelter areas which you know
legitimately if you have rooms that have
hundreds of people on mats right beside
each other they they can't be open but
those people are all on the main
corridor streets of downtown like
usually on the main blocks where there's
maybe 20 to 50 people during the day
there was probably 200-300 on each block
like so there's almost a thousand people
like in the main Aires all dragging
their tents and their [ __ ] behind them I
like don't want to be all panicky you
know but I talked to the bureaucrats and
the language that they speak in without
actually saying the words or one time
saying the words when all the services
are shut down they ask me how many
outreach workers can I supply because
what they think they're gonna do or try
to do is you know how we have military
bases and stuff they want to corral
everybody so they can figure out who's
sick and who's not sick isolate the sick
people from the not sick people and then
have all of my staff who generally like
work inside of a building where people
consume drugs and that's where they
watch them to keep them safe that
they'll be going out and watching people
in the community and having people like
the drug users and people who who live
in those SROs helping one another in
these communities that they'll build
that will keep the sick people isolated
from the not sick people it it honestly
and as you can imagine like if you had a
500 dollar drug habit a day which you
had to do many crimes for yeah but what
are you gonna do like when they say hey
man you have to go self isolate so again
I had some pretty high level of doctors
call me like last Monday from the
province and say they're not from the
province from a housing place and they
said what would we
what will we have to do to get people to
go in their rooms for two weeks and
selves isolate and I said you already
know what the answer to that is lots of
drugs yeah and so they said okay so if
we offered morphine or hydro Mars
tablets and dexedrine to the people who
used methamphetamines what else do you
think we would have to give them and
could your outreach workers go out and
try to make it happen yeah yeah yeah
like get buy-in from people because we
know that we won't get buy-in because
the tenants don't trust us you know what
I mean we're the landlord so that didn't
happen all last week I thought that
would happen right away as a way to get
people to go in their rooms but it seems
like they're trying to have some kind of
bar cuz you can imagine that if you
started giving somebody tablets to stay
in their room for a thing like this why
would you want to take them away at the
end of the two weeks they're gonna go
back to committing street crimes at
great cost to themselves in society you
can take the tablets away from them that
you give them right now so I imagine
they're having some larger philosophical
and structural things trying to figure
out how that they would keep it going at
the U this is something that's long
gonna be long term like a year year and
a half so it may only really help for
somebody like myself whose job is to
fight for D Krim and clean access to
drugs and [ __ ] like that because this
crisis may force them to just give drugs
to drug addicts in order to keep them
isolated you know and you know me and my
kids were both sick before this whole
[ __ ] started so I just decided like this
is just too confusing and stressful so
and I was lucky enough to be able to
bail out and come to the country where
we could figure out a couple weeks if
you know that we're good
it's uh it makes my anxiety levels go up
for those people to be honest like it's
one point yeah you know family and home
and all that mark
Marcus man you know what we have I think
my last member count like two weeks ago
is 1700s
and so for example with the giveaways to
keep people we follow BC CDC protocols
so they don't want people close to each
other so anybody who comes for just a a
giveaway we give the joints away in the
street now we just have people standing
on our block we're like here you go here
you go keep going you know what I mean
like don't don't come in the store and
they about reach office unless you need
a narcan kid don't come to the cost
recovery service unless you're using it
and and even in the street population
people are panicking them like you can
tell with the numbers that they're
stocking up with the idea that one one
day that they'll force us to close our
doors so that's the impression like what
going on for the people in the community
and them yeah I think man what if one of
the members had it yeah I don't want to
be all dark
you know what I mean like all sir but it
is it is it is dark it is stress
provoking to think about like though
with the what the what ifs right and my
my partner she like she's the kind of
the BA the boss of a lot of frontline
services so I know that talking to her
and the other managers they're
definitely taking steps to make sure
that everybody has all the information
about trying to protect themselves and
all that but it definitely does seem
pretty pretty scary and I think that
we'll see like some pretty modified work
protocols for a long time that I'll
actually probably change some of the
course of drug policies you know doesn't
leave everybody prescriptions medically
in an emergency time then that will
change the way they when we look at
change in laws later oh yeah we cooler
people are able to look inward I mean
I'll tell you yesterday at like seven
o'clock at night in Vancouver people
hung out their apartment windows and
clapped for the health work care workers
in in Vancouver oh wow like it was like
you could hear people just like clapping
all throughout the city and that was
like
Vancouver's never done that that's
they've never shown any any type of
respect like that so you know that
people are paying attention to this and
they're looking inward and it gives us
an opportunity as humanity to be human
you know to choose humanity the thing
that we are over this sort of reptilian
sort of emotional list non empathetic
non compassionate mentality of just like
capitalism or whatever and hopefully you
know that's that's a good thing I think
that people are kind of being a little
more conscious like okay like maybe this
is better if we help each other maybe
this is better if we support each other
rather than it's all for one and one for
all so much small learner all of a
sudden were realizing yes I definitely
hear what you're saying Jack you know it
is definitely gonna be a socio-economic
thing people that are struggling have a
higher chance of you know maybe
contracting the virus because of health
issues also because they don't have a
safe environment necessarily to go to
and also this is not a sides thing this
is not a oh this country against this
country and I can choose a side like
we're all vulnerable to this we all now
have this ability to connect on such a
beautiful human level that we can look
at people like you are just saying
Marcus that they're doing the same thing
all over Europe hanging out their
windows at a certain time and they're
clapping at the same time and it's like
hey we are all together I've been I more
than ever I've actually felt during this
whole thing like this beautiful global
community the people that are reaching
out to us are from all over the world I
get emails and and messages on my DM
from our Instagram that's just so
beautiful and connecting so I mean
something is opening up there it's
creating some kind of an opening for us
to be able to have success on another
level it's an opportunity we have to be
able to look at the [ __ ] that's been
given us in this horrible pandemic and
find some
kind of opportunity in it so that we can
grow and and really align ourselves with
a higher vibration because I don't think
that humanity really has the issue it
has the ability to go to a higher
vibration unless we're faced with things
that are painful nothing makes us work
harder than things that are painful so
I'm really encouraging everybody out
there to just like have a look at it and
let's go deeper and let's try to reach
this vibration that were that we all
need to be able to get rid of this virus
and Marcus does you know in Canada
instead of the scare mongers there's the
care mongers so you know see what you
can do in your communities to be awesome
my question is very simple
howdy how do you roll drinks without
touching the paper or licking at going
to glue it take dab no forgiving joints
away he means I guess you could exactly
you could roll them with machines the
rock tones the rock cones you just you
don't have to glue or stick anything you
just stuff it in there and you could
twist the end with gloved hands I guess
I would cover my hands and dirt first
and then roll the joint out I haven't
smoked a joint in so many years it's
just not even funny but well I did smoke
a pure hash joint but not like joint
joint I miss joints I miss I missed that
I ruined joints for myself I smoked foam
elf hash for for like two and a half
years every single day just had an
incredible collection it was like Rene
and he's a sweet skunk and wish to bury
all these great hash plants all these
great things and then after two and a
half years I realized oh my god I got to
smoke a joint and when I lit the joint
and tried to smoke it it tasted like
like a camel's [ __ ] I don't know it
was just terrible it was burnt just
nasty I could I never could go
I totally roomed joints for myself us I
usually love joints again I used to live
in a cloud of smoke you had the world's
best hash - let's put it you know maybe
there's more gray - a joint would taste
pretty good I think so yeah if I ran out
of it for a long time you know that's
the thing because I used to get into
these debates online where people would
be like I'll always smoke doing
something like have you ever had full
melt hash in your stash for like five
years straight Wow know what I'm like
I'll get back to me when you do hello
jack I have a question which is how did
the joints get robbed that you gave away
I mean did you touch them where they
lived no no I used to like babe way way
way back in the day we we had to hand
roll but no other I used somebody add
another dispensaries future role of
machines and then when they went to a
white bar company we just bought our own
machines so I have only one he will have
one human doing production who himself
lives in a fairly isolated scenario
doesn't member a lot of contact with
other people and since we are like I do
run Health Canada sites I follow all of
the protocols as best we can to try to
keep people away from each other you
know and no no licking no don't lick the
joint that was another thing I could
just never get over you know or also
getting past the like super wet Joey
it's like here man here man here you go
just like my dad bring hey
here I'll show you I don't like I don't
have the quality control there of what
you guys do cuz but Marcus here like
here's the here's something that
somebody gave me yesterday that that I
thought looked fairly nice I don't know
if you can see is it rosin or a Saul
extract I'm I think well I think it's a
live resin this guy I've met seems to
make most of his like and this that I
think this is chatter oh wow looks yeah
I like I hear wow that looks nice here's
the shadow from the same guy I'm sorry
it's bad I would like everyone to show
the camera what they're smoking right
now how would that would that be a nice
screen shot oh it's so nice when the
camera gets like goes and focuses
properly on your behind smiling own ice
cream waits got the the sheesh their
little stone of hash and markers make
sure you get a screenshot of this right
yeah well we can make one cuz I'm
recording it okay this is great for sure
I think almost everyone had a stash out
there I got your bad times triangle Kush
beautiful so here's the thing I saw
everyone hold up their jars are you guys
familiar with the Telex containers no
dude I love these containers my quest
turned me on to these containers he met
this guy Jake who works with calyx down
and I just in the u.s. somewhere they
stacked really nice on top of one
another if you know this it's got this
little piece here and it's stacks it's
it's a square container you can open it
with one hand all you do is really
squeeze on the on the lid and what I
like about it also is it's a good amount
of extract for sure add some bubble hash
some some wedding cake that I got from
my agent rated X but it also has a
little turf skirt about this a little
PTF terpene protecting cover from
consuming your plastic lid PTFE PTFE
yeah sorry
same thing we used when we did the
terpenes inside the terpene lids because
some of those companies weren't using
those and it was crazy how the Terps
were just consuming the inside of the
container it would make this weird
plasticky sticky mass so I gotta give
these guys up to MVP that's a what fep
liner oh there you go thank you Mike
Mike would know he turned me on join
people set what's the f EP he's unmuting
it's similar to it's similar but it's
not as reactive to terpenes that's one
of the things that they're saying that I
suppose fpp makes better of that cleat
it's essentially a clear transparent
liner but anti-state jerking proof
moisture oxygen blocking barrier and
it's got a Oh ringing in it mm-hmm I
like them I really do
I like the jars man have you noticed
that it keeps your stash better longer
question mark um you know I smoke my
stash pretty quick I'll just be honest
oh but it I just like the access that I
have I like the size of it I like the
way they stack in my Pelican case and I
like that they're just a me they need my
Ron bases and recycled glass or hemp
flat those are my only two complaints
because I like I do like I've been clear
bothers you can show off your oil but
that clear bottoms gonna let in UV light
alternatively if you have a like my Ron
or some sort of cobalt in code for Amber
glass that's gonna reduce the amount of
UV degradation it does have a seal in it
though so I'm impressed with the shelf
stability of the smell especially in
higher I'm just not a fan of these ones
you gotta push down and open I don't
think they're quite as good of a jar
they just don't seem to we kind of have
to carry that we have to carry those in
California unfortunately due to the you
know the
controls here - here tonight yeah
because it causes a major problem for a
lot of people who will get older to have
arthritis and it's a major problem with
these concentrates is there not one
everything is printed so small that's a
problem too then people who suffer from
any type of hand debilitation it
definitely has a very difficult time
getting into them so that's something
we're working with the state on that we
have to do better as well as especially
environmentally-sound because they're
still ungodly amount of over packaging
and plastics for small amount of
concentrates it's it's obnoxious and
we're not even talking the pans so it's
just what we have to carry carry in for
the product to get it out the door what
we're loading on to the consumer is
still overbearing and outrageous for
what they're they're buying really yeah
factories Corona does anybody know if
the majority of patients who have corona
if they got it from droplets from people
coughing or from their hands from
touching contaminated surface
does anybody know he said this is this
is colony I I have two people that are
close to me that have it in New York
City and one of them got turned away
from the hospital yesterday and they
believe they got it from touching
surface areas that's the only way that
they they weren't around people that
they remember sneezing or some things
they don't have the symptoms like some
people carry it without the symptoms so
it's you ever know if you touch the
surface or if you inhaled it in the air
or if you yeah yes that's what's scary
about it as soon as we get stolen Sam
that was he was trying to ask me a
question a while back but I keep getting
a kid kept interrupting me it was just
about the joints oh right thank you
sorry distracted by children we heard
regarding droplets we had everybody
especially says it could survive on
paper since we handle cash as well as
plastic cards we had everybody
immediately go to gloves a couple of
weeks ago so that's something once we
heard about immediately we implemented
before and during the CDs so the same
thing as I have the guys wearing gloves
because of physical money that's the
best thing that I can do right here in
Holland the majority of businesses no
longer take cash you have to pay with
the with the big card that's what I came
across here trying to implement a
cashless society research I've done that
I can show you guys it's to promote the
false round globe theory I'm just joking
yeah we don't get that Debbie and I can
attest we don't get that love here in
California we definitely have to have
access to cash or even ATMs on site
because everybody rolls around in a very
much cashless society and that's just
the reality of what they're trying to do
but the reality that we deal with that
we have to pay our taxes in cash and all
that we still have to deal with heavily
in cash so we always stay or to try to
stay up-to-date on things such as this
so that we can you know respond and
react accordingly because you can always
launder your cash you know with maybe
you VC or something like there's UVC
bulbs that we should do a whole show on
that Kevin Thomas financials you guys
know those guys they do this very high
level scrutiny to FinCEN standards and
then somehow hook you up with a bank
that's FDIC approved so we've been
officially formally lelee banking for
about two weeks now after we got kicked
out of our 10-year law
credit union finally was like you guys
are gone so can you drop that link for
me please I 38 banks and I mean we have
support we have a credit union compliant
credit unions seaport that I worked with
for a year it's wonderful yeah
Massachusetts has has just a few but
it's it's been ok here but if there's if
there's you know information to be
shared I would I'd love to read on it
and better understand it guys Debbie Ann
Etienne what when you guys get kicked
out of the bank what were they what
reason do they give you what did they
say what what's the offense that they're
kicking you out
what's marijuana being federally illegal
kicked out of all the finest large banks
and small banks the latest one ten years
ago they weren't so nervous so original
operators of magnolia walked and talked
to the president told him what they were
doing they said fine ten years later
they revile you ated their stand on
things and just sent a note saying we're
closing your accounts on this day it was
like three weeks I I called my phone
that's not fair really you know it's not
enough time for me to get things going
they gave me an extra week and that was
that but I give us any reason when they
closed our bank accounts up here yeah
it's run the whole gambit from day
before payroll getting a call saying the
checks in the mail you're done oh that's
that's lovely
as well as it's usually just the same
it's just the it's federally illegal or
there was an audit done from some and we
were contacted by the feds that we can't
do with your cannabis account and blah
blah blah blah so since like I said 38
so they're each one's been different but
all of them mostly the same usually
checks on the way expect it you're done
with us so we always investigate and
have
a couple in our back pocket in
preparation yeah because you have to do
that that's the reality
I just want to act normal that's all we
want to do is be normal businesses
because we are normal retail businesses
but the frustration is none of us can
use proper banks or when we do you have
a limited time only yeah ain't that the
truth well one trip I can give one tip I
can give for Canadians I was in Colombia
I don't know if it was six months ago or
something and I was standing in line to
to get checked in onto the plane and it
was another woman just one woman and she
was a Canadian woman who was like
working with the banks in Colombia
Canadian bank but doing you know
building everything up and I told her
you know I've had as a cannabis company
I've had some problems with with the
banks in Canada and she's like oh that's
strange so we started talking about it
and she finally started asking me
questions and she said she said you
don't have American accounts do you and
I said well yeah of course and she said
oh that's that's where it's half and I'm
like what do you mean and she's like
well if you were operational with a bank
for 15 plus years and then overnight
they hit you up and said they were
closing your accounts I can guarantee
you from working at banks but that would
have come from America because they know
if you have American money in your bank
account like they know they they like to
know where their money is they can
investigate American accounts and if
they just did a little research on yours
and decided they didn't like what you
were doing they could have they have the
power to absolutely call the bank and
because the relationships are the
Canadian banks are terrified of
upsetting the big American banks because
everything goes through the big American
banks like you can't do money transfers
without going through Chase Manhattan
you can't do any of this stuff even in
Canada without those big American banks
so a lot of that if you're in the
cannabis industry and you're having
problems with banks it's a little bit of
a bummer to lose that exchange each time
but that could be the difference between
having your accounts closed up here and
and not having them at close what do you
think and again I'm just thinking out
loud here that
could just be a matter of like the whole
federal I'm not the federal regulation
but just this this w-h-o thing or this
United Nations stupid thing that as soon
as that thing just triggers that
there'll be some bank like Bank of
America or one of these large big banks
who say you know what half of our [ __ ]
workforce are cannabis patients it's
okay to do business with the cannabis
industry and completely open the
industry with welcomed arms in fact have
like marketing deals marketing towards
the 80s and the Debbie's and trying to
get all of this money I mean it to me
it's like it's an untapped opportunity
we already know that the market is there
right so the fact is is that ATMs
business needs financial services they
need point-of-sale transactions they
need to be able to pay their paychecks
do other expenses through all their
taxes and all that stuff that any
business needs right why is the cannabis
industry still being penalized it's
because there's 280 [ __ ] or this
[ __ ] federal and this international
[ __ ] stupid treaty that all the money
is somehow kind of I always think that
you know who is the executive in the
bank that just closed down
Debbie's account who is the guy who
basically signed off yeah it's okay
let's just close down again they'll
bounce to some other bank it's like his
business is now losing account that's
generating revenue they're gonna just go
to another bank for just another
executive maybe that dudes a weed smoker
and he won't shut him down
I mean it's there's so much illegal
activity happening through banks so many
criminals way more sophisticated and
dangerous than us and just like
everything we're always the low-hanging
fruit for the feds they use us to wedge
into taking away civil liberties locking
up huge populations of people and just
being general you know super jerks
I think the banks are afraid that if
they have us in there we're on every
website in town
no the feds will open the door and see
all the really criminal stuff that the
banks are engaged in so they don't want
us in there you guys see that HBS see
like men in your faction money
laundering suitcases and when they got
bagged they got a fine you got to
understand though there's a great
passion for Debbie Debbie used to come
to work well back when they always work
at BPG and she just called the local DEA
office and just started talking to the
air why you come why do you get
marijuana
why are you totally against it's just
totally wrapped up in this federal case
yeah that's the DEA agent that came to
my door to serve the subpoena he was so
nice like dude like how can you like you
seem nice why are you working for the
DEA this is what he told me I couldn't
even believe it
oh you know I got involved because I
want to stop criminals like serious
people etc etc knows off but until I had
a kid but then I realized those guys had
guns so I asked if I could get switched
over to the marijuana Department where I
could just go after marijuana users like
are you [ __ ] kidding me
coward coward yeah that sounds about
right though it's like hoof low-hanging
fruit versus like work and put your life
on the line exactly but it also but lets
me even to it for us to understand you
know sons do understand know your enemy
better than you know yourself you know
understand what their mindset is you
know I I still watch cops and other
things I just want to understand their
modus operandi what are they actually
doing how are they interacting people
understand their mentality gives you a
better understanding about what you're
dealing with what you're fighting
against because again they're humans too
and eventually we were able to connect
with enough grassroots people and around
that we were able to change laws in
states that we changed that momentum
that went from it's never gonna happen
in your lifetime kid to when's it coming
to my state you know it's I it
understand that for a cop or someone in
law enforcement I don't understand that
for a banker for a banker who's who's
watching the economy go and now what you
see I don't know if you've seen these
numbers 18 but actually cannabis story
revenues are up in California right
because people again they're buying lots
of toilet paper and buying lots of stuff
with the flautist when they go but you
know the point is is that someone in the
bank who's a financial guy not a law
enforcement is saying now we can't do
this we have to keep this client out
it's like but pop do you really think
that they're just making that decision
or do you think there's a memo from the
Defense Department or some other high
ranking government they always say
really sorry you're really cool we had a
great relationship but it's not me it's
come from above 99% of the time okay I
believe it does so do you think that
there's like what like people at the DEA
who drip on these senior executives in
the banks no I don't think the DEA are
involved at all I think it goes with and
they're like over here the banks are
here and whoever is telling the bank's
probably the White House so what
so Marcus what do you think not that it
makes a difference but what was the
kernel that led to Debbie's bank
basically giving them the boot what was
the thing that first started like was
weird you know I don't know I'm just
trying to think like why am I always
thinking I always think this this is a
group of people that have a very very
very different mentality quite possibly
the opposite of the mentality that
cannabis gives you attention and it's
the greatest fear they have is that
while they're trying to continually
brainwash society with their beliefs and
their core values that aren't really
everyone else's beliefs and core values
that they just that nothing cuts through
that [ __ ] better than Erb while
cutting through the [ __ ] of their
pharmaceutical lies while cutting
through the [ __ ]
their justice system while cutting like
it's just it's the ultimate enemy to
this long-term agenda of just you know
whatever it is I don't like to go too
deep down the rabbit hole and think it's
some huge conspiracy I like to call it
an agenda because a conspiracy and and
you know it sort of insinuates that
maybe it's not happening at all it's
just all make-believe but this we know
this is happening the word Pro Spira see
and also you know mark one thing I was
trying to say or thinking about is weird
well but thanks
you know last I heard they've all been
bailed out by the government so who's
really in charge of the bank's you know
like the the mass amount of money that
banks even have to be able to be running
right now it's from somebody up above
them so the banker is not making it yeah
they're all nationalize now I mean
you're just giving notice that they can
do zero reserve lending so they're
lending out money they don't have
they've been doing that for a long time
it's always been levered though they've
always had like a forty to one ratio of
you know what does it call fractional
reserve right they've always says but
they put out a note on Sunday saying
fractional reserve they can loan money
they don't have but this is just like
when money went from gold to not
representing gold anymore to just now
represent a paper that you print this is
just the next version of that which is
terrifying what's the exchange today
between a dollar in a year oh it was
almost unity right I mean right
oh nothing dollar a year maybe a dollar
in the pound am I thinking I haven't
been tracking that particularly currency
pair but we're all printing money like
mad right now so it's it's correct do
comparison so what's the log isn't the
long-term impact is that that's gonna
ultimately devalue the currency and like
the next say hey yeah and full of years
stay from three to five years from now a
bunch of currency today the trick with
the money supply between there you go
between um I think the last crash in
this one 2008 in this one huh however
they didn't train it from helicopters
would give it to people they gave it to
bankers and it didn't necessarily
there's a Kantian effect it didn't
really get into the economy completely
so it we probably haven't seen
widespread inflation we've been seeing
inflation x' and certain arteries that
they're subsidizing but I think what's
gonna happen next is we'll probably see
inflation a little bit more immediately
because they are gonna probably rein it
on everything they can
it seems to be the only trick they have
right now we should grow weeds these
crappy remember when we first got closed
down by Bank of America before that they
loved us they knew what we were doing we
used to go down and the teller would be
like and smell the money be like we love
you guys and they were even talking
about giving us a house loan and then at
that point they told us that there was
some wing of their company that
evaluated these kind of I don't know
sinful I don't know what you would call
them the activities and whenever they
flagged one in their banking system they
would look at it and if they've been
there and been good banking good good
banker you know banking partners or
whatever they just let him roll and they
decided that sort of Berkeley patients
group and some local vise shops you know
like were still they were still letting
us roll but of course shortly after that
uh we did find out that our bank was
being took all the money and booked in
our account negative nine hundred ninety
nine million nine hundred ninety nine
thousand nine hundred ninety nine
dollars me and Etienne were negative
billionaires there for a moment in time
that's when they DEA sees that when I do
an IRC cpg got destroyed in two thousand
seven yeah
Don actually went down to the bank while
they were seizing the account and took
all the money out of the bank account by
the time the lien got on the DEA [ __ ]
you not and that's proof right there
that there there's an agenda like deeply
deeply disturbing agenda
against cannabis to the point where they
would never do that even to a money
launderer to it to a massive drug lord
like the same thing with like when they
arrested Marc Emery and it was like the
the number of pounds they said that his
cannabis seeds grew was exactly the
number that allowed you to charge
someone with the kingpin law which was
like the death penalty which was pretty
intense up here when he was just like.he
people were like oh you can't go down
there like they might kill you and he
was just like no no I'm going I'm going
I can't run away from this sounds like
kind of like the thing you run away from
life like be having your life threatened
seems like no they try to do that to our
friend ed Rosenthal and if I remember
Debbie and I a week we were the two of
the recalcitrant seven because we knew
that we could only give the fifth and
tenth amendment before the federal court
because if they if anybody said yes he
was the boss they were gonna put kingpin
charges on Edie and it was life in jail
so it wasn't a death sentence per se but
it was a death sentence that I would
never see my friend again so thankfully
all of us yeah we all went to first it
was a grand jury we had to go through
then it was the actual federal we had
you had to go up before the actual judge
declare a fifth tenth amendment and
fortunately we were held in contempt and
they let us go home it was weird
they'd never been booked it on our
records Etienne they didn't book on it
in Bochum they actually when we refused
to testify against Edie Rosenthal they
put all of us on trial
Ian Etienne got put on trial for a civil
and criminal contempt of court for
refusing to testify holy [ __ ] you guys
are he scores on trial in federal court
here in the Ninth Circuit and standing
to get on the stand and and mian Etienne
realize they're Atlanta's make little
speeches it was judge Breyer so our
speeches were all like what we're doing
is right we're supporting the will of
the people we don't understand why the
government
as us here the government's actually
wrong in this case and one by one we got
up and said that it was so cool the
judge was like he gave a speech about us
he said something like when people look
at this case and they should they'll see
how you can bring strongly held views
into the federal court in a dignified
manner that gets them heard and and then
he said if if you guys are guilty of
civil contempt of court if going to jail
will make you testify against Edie I'm
gonna send you to jail if it won't make
you testify against Edie I'm gonna send
you home so we really are lawyers were
like get out of here they literally let
us just say like no we're but no matter
what we're not going to testify in the
end and judge Breyer sent us home and
even though he found us guilty he never
booked it on a record so it was really
pretty epic / stressful and all Debbie
it's actually being taught I'm told in
law schools and how to do proper civil
disobedience in federal court crazy
solid very solid you guys and very good
Paula read mother lovers let's do this
sorry I'm late guys
mark sent me a text hey where are you
I'm like like I look at the thing this
morning I'm like oh I got five minutes
I'll just lay my head back down on again
at Brown he's like holy [ __ ] scrabbling
get dressed everything good morning
everyone
playing games late night with that chair
away oh well I wasn't with a ten but I
was video game until about 4:30 this
morning I always [ __ ] do it man
like I get on it you know 9:00 or 10:00
at night I'm playing a little bit then a
few other people come on and we're
chit-chatting from all over the world
we're talking about the virus we're
talking about what's going on where they
are we're talking about
we're bond ripping and playing Red Dead
and shooting [ __ ] everybody
and then it's 4:30 in the [ __ ]
morning and I'm like what the [ __ ]
time for bed bong rip man [ __ ]
bastard sure glad you do this stuff mark
I sure
it's not highlight yeah it's fun it's
good fun you know today we had a little
bit of a technical difficulty we can't
go live so we're just gonna upload it
after we you know still I'm sure still
some thousands of people will see it and
it'll be fun I mean honestly I'm just
happy to gather with you guys and sort
of shoot the [ __ ] and tell some stories
and you know feels feel better feel good
very stressful times out there
yeah the funny thing is that there's
still a bunch of people in the chat I
know I looked earlier there was like 47
people or something okay 27 now still
though yeah delayed you know broadcast
yeah shows you how many people make a
day Matthew Clark says anyone in here
know if after I let my hash dry on
cardboard does it need some time in a
jar to cure seems like the longer it
stays in the jar the more oily and
better it smells yes and yes and yes so
many people like I always ask people
well do you understand what cure it is
cuz cure it isn't like when you make
your hash and it's all brand new like
that's preserved do you want to preserve
your hash and put it and put it in a
freezer or a fridge do you want to cure
your hash well that's a little different
that involves Turk burping and you know
aging your hash in different varieties
of containers and temperatures and
places so it all kind of turns out weird
and different that's for sure my oldest
is is gonna be 10 years old this year
oh I've tasted that so it tastes like
crazy no does this not taste crazy yes
yes like hurt Hume and just rips your
[ __ ] head right off it's so wasn't
traditional Afghani buried for two years
and then actually pressed after it was
saved I guess me Sam might know this
damn it's like what they were really
trying to age it to be honest what they
were doing was just waiting for somebody
to buy it look at the color of that [ __ ]
but they were just storing bangumi they
were just storing it in the bank of the
earth and until buyer came around oh you
guys this strawberry banana cush I guess
it is last one then this one here pepper
[Laughter]
Marcus yeah I got some cool seeds from
Great Lakes Greece friends over there I
got some all kinds of different
watermelons and heirloom tomatoes which
is another hobby of mine so that's a
beautiful seed trade from Andy over
there just just few days ago and all
kinds of unique greens and brassicas so
we did kind of a northern latitude or
northern region trade for pipes that
he's saved by feed-in his own varieties
nice tomato what did you bet like much
my favorite out here I don't grow I grow
sun-grown no cover tomato heirloom here
so I have to have adapted or ones that
do well I try out about 50 plus righties
each year but the pineapple slicer a
West out in Northern California was my
favorite I haven't tried out your yet
Cherokee purple and Brandywine those are
the two liter blue beautiful I love
those you crude those in your greenhouse
didn't you Sam absolutely
we would get easily more than 100 kilos
every year we got a single a dose of
Brandywine that were more than one kilo
did you pull a lot of tomatoes off your
wall in your living room there in your
window
oh yes we also grew but the the
container the little 10 meter pots worth
of in your window
they don't yield certainly no I've even
had 20 liters on the floor with all the
fruit coming over to the to the window
dude I'll still say your tomato vine
that was in your window in your
apartment in Amsterdam was nicer than
like most of the tomato plants I've seen
people grow in their gardens well we
love tomatoes and Dutch tomatoes are the
worst of the world so you the other find
some solution and heirloom tomatoes is
the way to go that's tomatoes are the
equivalent of iceberg lettuce is that
what you're saying no Dutch tomatoes
just I mean they have no smell very
little taste
they look red from the day you buy them
to the when you throw them away they
look like a tomato but they ate looks
like a-alice has got a messy collection
going because these two rides 2pj
tomatoes so if there's anyone in
Northern California
I would seats I can't reseeds because I
don't have seeds it but I would collect
the in the end of the year but I'll
trade donations of seeds I'll go grab it
after I'm quarantined of Spain you know
just to make sure you guys are all safe
I am now I am in Sebastopol like Santa
Rosa area there's a real easy one I
don't know if they're still doing it the
in Sonoma County there's a group the
Sonoma Valley cannabis enthusiast or
something like that that has been doing
for a couple of years regular meetings
every Tuesday I think and they're
teaching people how to grow they have a
campaign called grow six big ones which
in the you know in the California scheme
you can grow you grow six plants
for your personal use yeah and yeah
their whole thing was grow six big ones
outdoors and they're given away a lot of
seeds over there but with the quarantine
thing might be easiest if you could just
reach out to me and I can send you some
of the things I got sitting here because
I have way more seeds than I'm ever
going to sprout and they'd be mostly CBD
and THC things together CBD and stuff
helps but I want also veggies oh yeah I
got a bunch of clones downstairs and
some seeds and pop some seeds to pop
some bio vortex seeds now and also
sunshine stuff like some of the seeds I
collected in her garden some rebel moon
stuff I'm waiting for it to pop can we
and I'm gonna do the six outdoor with
this once and let's check how how
they're gonna be phenol on may be on
that but I really want heirloom tomatoes
like I'm gonna prep like I need Josh and
Kelly I kind of like Nita maybe to call
you guys and show the garden because
it's like from zero I have no idea how
to start like I have a bunch of ideas on
how to like what to do but um how to
start is very hard like start digging I
started digging yesterday checking the
soil we got you girl
let's talk we'll do a little facetiming
in the backyard sounds like a good
series for a show like Alice and wook
doing a garden getting help from Josh
and Kelly now recorded every week or two
I'd like to be involved to please you
know some will get rid of past some all
of the track proper stuff like that's
the stuff that I am totally what you
know another good person for that is is
Sean lost Gardens he's he's cool he had
these little vials of his cannabis seeds
filled with all these other seeds that
are the beneficial plants that he grows
around his cannabis plants in his area
and he likes to give them to people that
live in that similar terroir and they're
always like what
this and he's like well those those are
like the cannabis seeds and then these
other seeds are like a variety of other
plants that are that are gonna help you
out I was like dude now we always do
that that's kind of like we give up big
fat bags of seeds and everybody's really
stoked I'm saying you know you'll find
the cannabis seeds intermixed in there
got a search form also say to for people
to look up peace seedlings and peace
seeds online they're out of Corvallis
Oregon but we've walked their gardens
before and Alan Cap Euler is the the man
who runs it but his kids run the Peace
seedling art so both of them sell seeds
but they grew two hundred varieties of
tomatoes on their property and Alan has
been breeding tomatoes for his whole
life
so there's other dult life yeah a lot of
the reasons why delicious Tomatoes have
hit market is because of Alan and really
cool to check out his varietals
beautiful flower I originally got my
tomato seeds from the Seed Savers
Exchange I'm not sure if you're familiar
with that group but it was started by
Kent Wheatley years ago I've been a
lifetime member for 40 35 40 years so I
imagine you have some good seeds well
I've grown a few that oil of oregano oil
went down the wrong pipe dr. Alec a
pillar he grows wild garden seeds we've
been buying their varieties for years he
does great greens he does an amazing
rainbow kale which is a red Russian
cross with the lacinato that's our top
favorite has a lot of purple in it and
also dog tipping down at us seven seeds
in Williams Oregon he does an amazing
job too we took some breeding classes
down there with me and my wife lived in
in Williams in the early 2000 those guys
all have great good quality seeds down
there and I highly recommended
unbelievable oh thanks for the share Tom
that's great
I you know all this talk of heirloom
tomatoes when I had my gallery the
melting point gallery and I decided hey
you know like I wanted to build this
beautiful gallery with this beautiful
vapor lounge where you know something
that I just hadn't seen in the cannabis
space where it was like let's build
something really beautiful and and no
one even believed it was a cannabis
lounge when they would come in I thought
it was like a jewelry store or something
because I put these beautiful hardwood
floors and these cherry wood floors and
Japanese cherry seeds that we here's
some these are straw flowers this is
just a huge tote we have like three
totes of just pollinate some stuff that
we garden seeds just pollinators
intermix with all of your cannabis and
all of your fruit and your veggies that
are sweet or all marigolds this is all
what we gathered from last year so we're
gonna have you know basically our whole
entire property is going to come alive
with flowers petals everything it's so
incredibly healthy when we're planting
pollinators and it's beautiful - we were
getting species of birds even this
spring so we'd never seen before
well that we just saw last year that
seemed to come into our farm in the
summer and we're just wondering if they
sort of told each other where to come
back to and already we're starting to
see insects so I just want to remind
everyone part of growing a garden is to
save the seeds so the garden is the
source of the seeds for next year yep so
you're acclimating your own seeds yes
you'll really see a difference after one
year of growing seeds on your property
and saving a buck next reel will see a
noticeable difference and also if you
plant the seed in the soil that is on
your land the seed is going to be
stronger the plant is going to be
stronger and you
it'll it'll recognize if it can climate
eyes to your area once it does and it
will build the bacteria and the fungi
within the cells in order for it to
really thrive and provide its medicine
so right now we're being able to benefit
from a winter's worth of soil building
now all the scenes are just gonna just
dig into the soil and create medicine
because the seeds actually have the
microbiome of the soil that it came from
and then when it continues to update
that same microbiome which is the end of
FIDIC system which is the bucket
you know the microbiome of inside of the
plant and just like human beings acumen
acclimates to the same zone you know we
we talked a lot about the microbiome of
the human being but it's also important
to start bringing up the conversation of
the microbiome of the plant because it
also has bacteria and fungi that digests
and helps bring up nutrition so it's
it's sort of cool to think a battery for
for acclamation there's a two kilo bag
of seeds so this has got a hundred
thousand seeds in it and i've got
hundreds of bags like this also today is
a Pisces moon it's a really beautiful
time it's the new moon phase in Pisces
it's a really beautiful time all day
today and tonight you just plant as many
seeds as you can even your microgreens
or your sprouts for your kitchen they'll
be really vigorous if you plant them
today
get them crack and crack a lacking Wow
we've been rocking this for what that's
pretty good went by quick today I didn't
have to deal with the live thing it's
kind of nice to to do the show not live
even though I know a lot of people are
kind of bummed out because it's nice to
have them as well the audience and being
able to somehow help the conversation
along you know often they'll be able to
ask questions and lead the conversation
but that was not the case today so it is
what it is lots of seeds I know where
I'm going to get my seeds if I need
any seeds just gonna be sending a couple
of private messages when you reload this
dude as a premier and then people can
talk and they're as they're in-house
Church as it's going that's how I knew
some of my videos oh yeah scheduler
those are premier and then people can
talk all the way through it for the
couple hour we won't be able to talk to
us but they can talk to each other
need to talk to each other and you can
jump in there too and say hey we're
gonna be in the premiere it's it's
another way of being able to talk to
people well after you like I like and
this is well jump in and say we need a
germ plasm Institute for North America
for our cannabis genetics so that they
can be acclimated so that there are
regional groves that are around the US
and Canada that are growing on certain
longitudes and latitudes because when I
used to order my hemp back in Hungary
and Romania I was actually knew exactly
what the output of this compote a seed
exactly what we were growing had because
they were actually grown and proper
Institute's that were properly
acclimating it so I could maximize you
know the fiber that I was trying to get
out of the actual Hector's okay that's
real projections that I needed to have
and if you don't have proper acclimated
seeds right out the gate you're not
gonna get the reality that you're
searching for you know and that's a
reality that is different from what
we're doing here in America because we
were growing 300 to 400 seed per square
meter which is not how we're doing it
here because we have the machinery in
Eastern Europe to break that hamp down
where we have absolutely none of that
infrastructure or large-scale dunking
tat you know tanks for you know reading
the hemp etc etc so I'm very fascinated
to see as the hemp industry grows
throughout North America actual
investment in the infrastructure that
will be needed but on top of that germ
plasm Institute needs to be there just
for the start of this before any of that
can really take off so people can have
good steady supply because we're gonna
see cross pollenization ruins te crops
because it's going to increase THC and a
half that's just the reality
what we're gonna see as well as we're
gonna see the reverse and you know
people growing outdoors for you know
cannabis for their smoking so these are
real realities we have to you know look
at and face and I understand why a lot
of people are going towards CBD because
it's easier to just you know shake the
flowers as opposed to invest in the
billions of dollars needed for a fiber
factory to cut nice the hemp to make it
into a product that could go to a market
to manufacture a product that consumer
could get today
that's decades away still sure yeah
there there's a group I met from
Saskatchewan I believe and his father
had invented some technology to it had
to do with trees and the and and the
what was inside trees and I can't
remember if it was the length or the
percentages or he had this technology
and then years and he was very
successful with this technology and then
years later he attuned it to cannabis to
hemp for fiber and now they're doing
this big fiber project and I know Martin
merav chief who was one of the founders
of manitoba harvest who spent the last
five years trying to crack the economic
viability of a fiber production in hemp
and I know go ahead oh you're muted I I
could speculate mark on what they're
doing sure yeah so it's probably just
having to removing removing the lignin
efficiently from the cellulose so they
have to do that in wood in wood there's
a lot more lignin than there is an
intent but the same type of process to
basically pulp you know for not sure
that's what it is
it was some of their like tigers no it
was some type of like x-ray or like
photograph of the lumber that they could
he could figure something out and he he
was tuning it to hemp to figure out to
grow these fibers that you can't really
see with the naked eye but when you do
it with this machine you get an idea of
of the quality from the data points of
the photos something like that it
reminded me much of what the guys from
Carnegie Mellon
University were doing the robotics
division the AI division where they had
developed that camera to photograph buds
and they were taking all of these
different data points and they were
trying to basically recognize when the
plant was in peak production of say THC
like a single molecule
well how you R it also depends on what
type of fiber you're gonna come out with
I mean I remember Gardella has a machine
that could actually remove the fiber
from the hamp wet but the problem is
still the lignin in between so in Europe
I mean for hungry we would soak the ham
and these large concrete tubs so that
the natural biological would eat away
the lignin and then we would come away
with a very golden fiber if we laud it
ready right if we feel dreaded it and
just let it lay out in the field it
would turn gray and that's how a lot of
the Polish hemp was it's just the
natural by ultraviolet light correct so
it's just all about what you're trying
to come out with a final fiber so we
wanted a light golden so we had to force
soak it to actually water read it to do
that whereas you know that if ruptures
there and they can actually keep it and
do it currently Hungarian breeders also
bred varieties of hemp which had much
more golden fiber correct we'll have to
get Robin a mirror on here one day
they've got their hemp boutique company
they've done a little doctor well I live
I've lived in hungry off and on I was
deeply involved with the couple T
Research Station which is where Compal
was developed by dr. Ivan bolsa who was
a good friend of mine I told him I
taught him how to breathe cannabis he
taught me how to breathe industrial hemp
surprisingly that doesn't surprise me
yeah because that's what we use the cold
a genetic and because of the golden as
well as its availability after we water
edit it to still maintain through they
know it was a great crop and yeah loved
it he was the world's foremost temp
reader until he died in 97 did you know
go to Morocco from the Institute of bast
fibres Sam what was he in Yugoslavia he
was in the Ukraine in Kiev oh I was with
Zola - no show guys I met him via
telephone
yeah the Vavilov Institute right yeah
exactly
we met go to Morocco because we flew him
from Kiev to Manitoba to our hemp shop
called the hemp exchange in like 91 or
92 or something no no sorry it would
have been 90 no it probably would have
been that that 94 maybe that sounds
right and we brought he brought a couple
of his farmers and they this was the
beginning of us importing the four tons
of Zola tanoshii 11 and 13 into Manitoba
to grow our first experimental Hempfield
in over 73 years don't want to criticize
the Ukrainians but they're notorious Lee
broke oh yeah they couldn't put fuel in
their tractors they tried to sell me
hemp until I sent a rad meter and it
went well we brought seeds over fine and
it you know it started it kick-started a
big part of Canada's you know the whole
grain hemp
rain you know as a food as a as an oil
and as a protein powder all of those
things were really kick-started with
Zola Genosha 18 wins it was at the
Chernobyl strained yeah the og Chernobyl
funny enough that's are too noble that's
how that's how we found out about hemp
as a fighter remediated product in
Canada through those farmers that were
tobacco farmers and that's how that
Chernobyl actual in Chernobyl growing
hemp project got started right but you
got a wonder markets like did all that
oil that oil from those plants make it
into products you know it was
experimental in 94 95 96 97 Canada
didn't changed the law till 98 when it
became commercial and now you could do
stuff with it before that like there was
no squeezing seed or there was just
destruction and so they were tripping
out because they had to test their
tobacco field I guess from the
radium-226 that they spray on tobacco
which is a radioactive nucleotide and
does definitely register on one of those
little Geiger counters their field was
way too low and they had no idea at
first that because it was the first time
they ever grew hemp ever they just I
don't think could believe that the hemp
was that fight or remediate of that it
was that but it could pull that much up
that would make a large noticeable
difference you know kind of freaked
about actually because now they had hemp
it was like you can't just throw it away
there's like rules you have to follow
you heard was Sam I was wondering if you
have heard of anybody I had heard right
after Fukushima that they were gonna try
and do some remediation using in Japan
have you heard anything regarding that
no I heard they did it Ukraine but Abner
Danny think about Japan here here's some
mutant seeds that are as big as peas
they're 12 to 1 gram what kind of
cultivar is that well I'm trying to get
it in my camera well you're not doing
very well I'd say pull it back a little
bit
there you go those are huge yeah but the
average seems like that's like seed is
fifty sixty to one gram these are twelve
to one gram
don't you have like the little ones that
are like a hundred or two hundred or
something
no they're eight hundred eight hundred
those little nepali seeds but not nepali
that i got them in kashmir make better
like hemp oil or a better food product
with the seeds larger do I got better
cutting small let's can see they're
never seen in my life cereal every day
so those would be great those look like
like peanuts oh yeah the big ones yeah
you can shell them and then it's like
opinion of it yeah grow those for a
product or what's the those TFC PDG i
bred them for five years I made him
almost tc3 nice nice
what's the cannabinoid content of it
then CBG huh there's a little bit of tea
CBD and THC B but to be honest what I
did for five years was I bred all
cannabinoids away from it because I
figured if it had the ability to make
any cannabinoids it might also makes the
THC even though the papers were
published until recently that showed
that most CBD synthesis can produce
about a twenty five to one ratio of THC
whether you wanted or not so what about
the terpene profile a little better dirt
beans were really really interesting you
could find individuals that smoke just
like afghan hash and you could find ones
it smelled pretty much like Tommy
yeah some of the type 4 plants have less
leakage because they don't have a CBD
synthase gene so that there's still some
THC but it's usually like a hundred or
two hundred to one presumably coming
from the other residual cannabinoid
genes or so floating around right
I know CBD does it we didn't understand
the exact mechanisms when we bred the
world's first high CBD variety in what
was that late 90s
but the end effect is still saying that
it was coming from someplace and and I
wouldn't be surprised a few the other
ones at CDC can also do similar things
yeah that's with CVG in there or CVG a I
guess well if you've got a real CBD
variety you might be able to stop it all
at CVG but easy way is to find a mutant
for ID that won't even make CBG then the
entire kinetically trading stock that
you've got a true melvoy variety there's
a more economic acid which is the thing
that makes CVG that's what it is is it's
the CBD synthase that is not performing
it's a little like acid cyclase and and
what else isn't them halfway yeah Tod
right it's the geraniol altivec acid
transfer rates
I think ggot right and mixed around the
literature I think there's some debate
over what to call it but yeah some
people call G ot others I think we're
calling a live attack low atomic acid
cyclase but yeah it's a little bit messy
in there but yeah it glues on that g PP
on to live at all right right so Sam if
I'm just wondering it can you back up
the pathway all the way to that like I
know that
I can't believe the varieties that I see
I saw this one guy who's got a variety
now that's got 14% CBG there's about
it's less than a percent of CBD but no
THC at all none twenty years ago
the rest of the world has finally caught
up to you Sam what can we say but so I'm
wondering can you go can you back it up
even a step before that so yes deuces no
CPG yes that does it produce all tava
Casson and maybe the terpene levels are
higher I we haven't
yeah the GPP is competitive in the
terpene synthase pathway so if you knock
out the ability to conjugate GPP to a
limit aaalac acid it's gonna end up
getting used and shunted over in the
terpene pathway particularly I think I
think the monoterpenes are it's it's
usually I think it's a different
I think it's fpp on the on the
sesquiterpene so the monoterpenes are
all sucking up GTP anyway is there any
interest in looking at a limit aaalac
acid as a cannabinoid or not as
cannabinoid but or I guess all tall
because it would decarboxylate right
yeah this is people claim that's uh it's
kind of a rescue man for too much THC I
don't know how true it is really yeah if
you dose people with live at all and
we'll bring down their high but shorting
a stock knows what to avoid right he's
like I've spent my life working in the
other direction live at all is
essentially kryptonite for sippy so much
because they can put
and modulate the effects of THC and
that's what I was looking for I'm really
curious about the friend of yours mark
that has a CVG plan that has residual
CBD and such because I haven't said and
that might have a different genetic
thing that we learn what we typically
see is a little residual THC but but too
much lower than like a CBD line because
the CBD synthase gene has gone in those
plants so that thing can leak on you but
we think like Sam said it might be the
cannabic roaming genes that are still
there leaking some THC and there's some
plants have that that that's a two mega
base region in the plants that is
missing in some plants and present in
others so there's there's probably a way
to breed away the cannabic
the group is a Dortmund they they
originally saw that found this out to a
movie five six seven eight years ago and
they they published about CBD producing
tea tea in in a fixed ratio but they
were only looking at either one of the
synthesis or they were looking at a
particular suite of them so it could be
that some of money to doing it you know
five to one or fifty to one right you
just yeah there's a good paper from zoo
bell on this where they did
site-directed mutagenesis on the enzymes
I should say in the DNA constructor of
the enzymes put them into yeast so there
was only one cannabinoid synthase gene
per yeast and then measured the ratios
and it's a really good paper that shows
like which parts of THC synthase and CBD
synthase like when you mutate them what
artifacts do you see do they did they
have all of the CBD sensations I didn't
need to know people knew there was
exactly there are I think they started
with the canonical one that's an NCBI
has like an ee number on it and then
just mutated from there and a lot of the
variations that they find that do impact
the yield
we've not seen naturally yet in the
sequencing that we've done across those
genes so they're but they do give us an
idea of what parts the enzyme like are
really sensitive to glycosylation
signals or sensitive to you know other
types of shown theoretical basis whereas
yeah they're not representative of
what's in the marketplace it's just kind
of like what areas of this gene can we
break and maybe change the ratio and but
in all cases the enzymes were
promiscuous and that they did not
produce a pure single cannabinoid they
had no THC synthase produced some
background and CBD synthase as used to
have like a twenty three to one ratio of
CBD to THC but maybe there are natural
ones out there that are mutated in such
a way that they actually expand or
compress that ratio and that's something
that I think we got to figure out if
that was done there where they first
found this I contributed I think six or
seven or eight different kinds of CBD so
that they could find more versions of
synthesis oh cool yeah yeah there's
definitely a lot of them we have I think
there's over two hundred and twenty-two
mutations in THC and CBD synthase alone
that are on the snip shift that we're
building and those are just from
naturally derived plants no no
mutagenesis done in them so there's
plenty of variation out there on those
genes we just don't have good
connections to what those variations due
to the chemo type not always getting you
type information so if you guys ever
find something that breaks the 25 to one
rule of CBD to THC coming off of a CBD
dollar plant call us we'll sequence it
instantly and see if we can find
anything in those genes that might be
predictive of usda compliant heme have
have you tried grace the variety GW uses
I don't know that we have access to that
okay well it's a shame because I
strongly suspect he breaks it but I
don't have proof I wish I did yeah Ed's
Ian's probably has that data I would I
would imagine I'm sure he's stated
going deep down the rabbit hole there
boys I appreciate that it's nice it's
good you have the varietals that are CB
g hi c CB g varietals that are high in
terpenes because the ones that around
now yeah absolutely
what's fine in Turkey is like three to
five percent two to three percent like
on a fly yeah I think three five percent
definitely is that the traditional upper
limits whereas of course they can be
bridged with sympathy for like folks out
in a prone step I think they're ten
percent people are reporting even higher
I haven't seen most of the CB g that's
out there now is low low turfs so it's
um you know it's not as good of a
smokable hamp type thing as the as the
high CBD varietals that are high
terpenes actually the best smokeable is
high THC believe me and it's your buddy
varieties coming out whatever leave them
like a one-to-one or though many to many
I like equal parts I will click to enter
full screen mode all right here we go
marks laying it down
yeah I think they it's hi-hi terpenes
DVD is is really evolving and I think
Stevie G's just just slightly behind it
CVG herbs CB d pc g h MP d cv g'v yeah I
can't find the the particular one I'm
looking for but I just looking on his
Facebook this is the dude Mateus and
he's he's a Swiss guy who's in the north
of Italy but he has a seed production
operation somewhere in Oregon now well
he is he connected to Shanti Baba
no not at all no I know these folks and
yeah they have a high CBD variety called
yeah yeah I I tried to buy some of them
but they wanted minimum orders
fairly large amounts yeah well anyway
this is the guy and he does have that
this isn't the data that I remember
seeing this is just again indicative of
the levels that he's seeing here which
is pretty damn high he had a bag on his
on his post fear of CBG a hash I've
never seen CVG a hash before um it
looked really light Sam let me see if I
can pull that the color or big dark yeah
yeah let me stop sharing and let me let
me look let me look for that and see if
I can find it mark and we gonna see
that's incredible
was it clear what's golden oh it was dry
sifted cash not water - hey Mark in
upstate New York with we're making some
CVG try sift and it's coming up pretty
light in color hold on a second more can
have a chromium than THC in these lines
that's that's kind of a that's an
interesting ratio can this is very light
- yeah it looks like white say almost
yeah beautiful you lizard rose and
Turkey no lean yeah - pedaling dude
40% CVG sovereign fields and platonic if
I'm saying photonics 0.3% he might just
be saying
just to her I bet you Sam could get that
forty up to a solid 75 that's nice it's
not the way come on beautiful I'd have
to try I have confidence in you Sam I
put my money on you hey Mark I commented
down here because CBG hash I said
actually see VGA that's awesome that's
like that's the pothead chemists version
of like grammar actually you see me
they're not cool is that
I guess I'll assume that when you heat
up see BGA it decarboxylate just like
THC would so absolutely correct okay so
the CBG have a psychoactive effect that
the cb1 receptor do you know Sam no no
not at all and CPG doesn't get you high
cbc doesn't get you high CBD doesn't get
you high THC B doesn't get you high now
there are people who claim that they
take CBD they get psychoactive effects
well it ain't high it's maybe call me
their lack of paranoia eight it doesn't
get you high the way no the epic well
that's not true CB man we'll get you
loaded and Delta 88 C will also get you
high but I'm not so sure that Delta
eight isn't just an artifact of
lavatories i I've never seen a delegate
synthase and I don't know if some days
so Delta nine is what's made in a plant
and in acid catalyzed isomerization is
what
happens to move it over to Delta aid
yeah that's that's what I'm convinced
but I keep hearing other people tell me
that no we found Lt Col we read miss
EULA's pay permit machine I heard this I
believe you yeah and you've read miss
EULA's papers and I've read mushrooms
papers of what I I can tell you is that
in his discovery work in fact I should
tell everybody this I just wrote an
article for the American Journal of
endocannabinoid medicine which is Jhon
mark heussner journal and they want to
dig deep into the history of cannabinoid
chemistry so I'm gonna write a few more
articles for them but it was really cool
what I found out again is that that
group in Cambridge at the end of the
century in the 1890s were the first ones
to isolate not just cannabinol not just
CBN but the isolated sea as well so with
that extra wood yeah yep yep yep yeah I
would have never get and and check it
out what I recently read in someone
else's paper I didn't include this in my
own but what I would I recently read
there's that paper that's talking about
the conversion of CBD over to CBN and
use an iodine and it was an Italian
group and the first author on the group
was Palestra got it yeah on that paper
check out the acknowledgement to would
Spivey in this Easter field so the
research that they did they found that
both wood and Spivey perished and I
thought I had heard that one had gotten
malaria and that's not true at all one
actually perished in a lab explosion I
think it was Wood who died the lab
explosion they were trying to nitrate
THC to make nitro cannabinol and in that
experiment I think he exploded and then
the other guy so not Easter feel
would spivey and easter so that I think
species the guy who died in the
explosion would died from basically
taking too much of the [ __ ] that they
were making they were making all kinds
of derivatives in their lab and he ended
up poisoning himself Easter field was
the professor that I think they were
working for and he harsh mistress
yeah there was a rumor that he also too
had perished but it turned out now he he
had actually made it out of New Zealand
alive and yeah so it was interesting
what happened to that those those three
people but they published two papers in
the 1890s one in 1896 and one in 1899
and damned if they weren't like the real
true pioneers who first isolated
cannabinoids and and they in their paper
wasn't one of the references they have
is back to some journal of
pharmaceuticals from 1850 something and
I can't find that reference I can't even
find the journal you know I think it was
some German article or something like
that because I think a person both
German Italian other languages I can't
but I can google because they're not
digital they're just scanned the
journals you know this is like this is
like contemporary with the discovery of
the lightbulb these guys isolating THC
in this lab in Cambridge to me just way
ahead of their time I mean this is you
know way before Adams and Khan and so
yeah that so my next article I'm gonna
write about Khan
Robert Sidney Kahn who kind of looked at
the wood spiffy and Easter fieldwork and
said you know what their formula isn't
quite correct and their structure isn't
quite correct and and a robertson econ
kind of got the major elements of what
the correct empirical formula for
cannabinoids and THC and CBD were so he
kind of nailed that and he nailed the
structure and again this is in like 1934
you know way before Adam C Adams was
until later in that decade right so then
then there was Adams and Todd who's
still this is 20 years before Michelle
so it's just I love that history it's
just a wonderful tomorrow that's right
yep I've said it made absolutely yeah
but you know what in researching the
paper that I just wrote what I also kind
of came to the realization was so what
he did is he took cash and he
chromatograph did are the silica gel
column but then what he did was he took
the fractions that contain primarily THC
and he made a crystal and derivative
that he can crystallize to purity and
and thinking back to my academic
training as a chemist one of the classes
you have is the is the identification of
organic compounds and it's fascinating
because back before we had HPLC S&amp;G sees
and and all this analytical and
instrumentation that we have now they
used to make derivatives and crystalline
derivatives were always popular because
you could purify it from all the non
crystalline impurities and so what
moschella made is he made a crystal and
derivative that he could purify to the
henderson with purity and then he
removed the thing that made it a
crystalline derivative and then further
distilled it and so so that way he know
that it was
absolutely pure there's no other
impurities in there and so so yes I'm
assumed used again NMR like you say Sam
to solve where the double bond was the
thing that miffed
Todd and Khan and Adam this was the fact
that again they were using derivatives
ation chemistry to identify what the
structural components of the
cannabinoids were and in that
derivatives a ssin chemistry this goes
back to Kevin's original point they were
ice on rising it over to Delta eight so
if you look at the structures in atoms
this work from the forties you'll see
they're all Delta eight configured
because a lot of times the first thing
they did is well let's hit with acid and
see what happens and that's exactly how
Spivey died they were trying a nitration
with nitric acid and sulfuric acid
that's also the same explosion that
killed Lamont DuPont who was the son of
the VI DuPont the founder of the DuPont
company was killed in a nitration
explosion in the rapado works over in
new jersey so so yeah man I love
chemical history like that it's so
[ __ ] cool and digging into the
cannabinoid chemistry because it was
kind of like this outlaw thing that only
certain labs did like there was
obviously machine who arguably was the
kind of like the Shulkin the Sasha
children of cannabinoid chemistry but
just like Sasha Shogun Michonne stood on
the shoulders of Adams yeah of giants
right all the people who came before and
masoom will humbly like any chemist like
myself will humbly admit that that we
were we're here today because of all of
these people who did this previous work
so these Brits who were distilling THC
back before the turn of the century they
didn't know it but here we are now over
a hundred years later reading their
landmark work
and you know what their boiling point
was spot [ __ ] on I mean it was
exactly the way it should have been
which is the reason why I believe they
didn't just isolate cannabinol they
isolated THC in 1896 and it was really
for many years thought that because they
called it kanaev and all that
oh they isolated CBN but I don't think
they isolated CBN I think they isolated
THC and I think if you go into mushrooms
paper machine has a wide body of papers
and the scientific literature he
references all of this prior work by
Robert Sidney Kahn and Easter field
wooden Spivey
all those people just it's fascinating
to go through the Machine important to
kind of rediscover all of that chemistry
just like in the same way that I
discovered bluegrass music through the
olden in the way record right which
which led me to this portal of Bill
Monroe bluegrass that I had no clue even
existed right I found it through this
portal although no well yeah I was one
of Jerry Garcia's projects but it was
the Jerry Garcia thing that brought me
into it and now I discovered this whole
world of bluegrass Misbah is kind of
like I knew about Missoula and I knew
about his important work but I had no
clue really or no real appreciation for
all the work that was done in the Prima
shulam cannabinoid chemist the Truman is
written very very good reviews so has
illumise it so heavy deep trunk and yet
Roger portray that's right Roger all
three men written fantastic and Missoula
two or three times has has written
histories of it have you guys seen that
work on cannabinol bone that just came
out
yes that's what I'm smoking right now
yeah we we talked about that in fact I
reached out to the guy through chimera
you guys know chimera right yeah yeah
they're in Italy right yeah so I reached
out to the guy through because you would
think Kevin I mean again I'm just
throwing this out there
if Allah all tobik acid is its
biosynthetic precursor wouldn't you
think can a bomb Evonik acid would be
what exhibit should have the acid group
next to the phenolic Oh H right the
other possibility could be that it's
being produced the way THC is produced
by Stevie Dee said bases I'm not saying
that's more likely I just say well
you're just probably underwent
adventitious decarboxylation and if
they're characterizing the extract by GC
obviously it's gonna be carboxylate in
the in the GC and it would be
interesting if they actually are
isolating the the carboxylic acid of
that again I I don't know like like when
people are talking about CBG just go
back to that for a second there seems to
be a lot of emphasis and CBG is this
really for CVG or is it the acid and
like you said Sam it D carboxylates just
like just like THC would so I'm trying
to understand whether or not the acids
are of you know just differential
interest you know got an interesting
five carbon ring as the outside of the
live atomic acid so it's typical six
carbons a ketone right it's got a ketone
on its guy mojito and methyl ketones can
sometimes make a bass with a with a with
a primary amino group and so sometimes
those are like that's a cross-linking
reaction for proteins oh yeah
the chemistry is above me but if it
comes from a planet I'm interested yeah
this one they claim it does I don't
think they mentioned like what
concentration they found it in this is
different from the Italian work that
found
TCP I've got the paper I've had it for a
couple of weeks yeah yeah yeah yeah so
you know they talked about PP r gamma
receptors and but I don't think I
remember correctly this compound was
first found she was 5 or 10 years ago it
was yet hemp you're right hey Kevin
let's talk about TCP just for a second
because I don't think you're on that
hash search when we were talking about
that paper yes so the fact that it's the
two carbon higher homologue of the of
the cannabinoids I said well doesn't
that make sense that like and I guess
the three carbon one is that is the
Varon right you have the Varon and you
have then you have THC then you have THC
P well [ __ ] don't you think maybe like
there's a little bit of line in there
and maybe a little bit of 11 so every
two carbons perhaps yeah so do you think
these group did
Dimitra expose this I care or presented
this I can med this year were they they
took THC synthase cloned it in yeast and
fed at different chain-linked precursors
so they gave it hexanoic acid and got
THC out they gave it ought to know ik
acid and got THC P out I think they use
a butane derivative of some sort to get
the Varens out I didn't I gotta go back
and look at his presentation maybe he
also put a 10 mer in there and and and
and got a longer chain length out as
well that went out to maybe nine but it
was fascinating that the east have no
problem making these things so that so
the THC synthase doesn't care it's
really happening upstream probably at
got or live at all gas at cyclase or
parental transfer I don't know which one
is involved with that but it's it the
this the the the last step of the
synthesis doesn't care a bit about the
chain length so let me ask a question
this is something I speculated on and I
don't know but like if I get a really
good live resin product let's see this
one here if I add up my cannabinoids and
I
my terpene sigh of eighty percent total
cannabinoids and 15% so there's 5%
unknown right 5% other stuff don't you
think like like part of that other stuff
could be team CPE do you see me yeah
just like a whole family of of things
that show I don't know if I'm using the
terminology correctly a lack of well or
promiscuity of the enzymes active site
to act on a spectrum of substrates as
opposed to just the one yeah yeah no I
think so I'm wondering if you can add
them as well like how could you boost
production of hexanoic acid versus oxen
milk acids like is there a way to do
that in a Jasmine pathway or can you
even I don't even know if you could
supplement them or spray them because
they're effectively like alkanes right
they they would effectively melt your
trichomes if you spray too much of that
stuff right yeah well the thing that I
think is that this it's hexanoic come
from glucose which is a c6 so yeah I
have it's got to have a sugar precursor
to it right I mean III don't know this
for sure yeah a lot along the Krebs
cycle but so so the question is is like
like people have been asking oh man that
stuff's 30 times 30 times higher or it
gets you I guess they did a docking
study yeah doctor site and they found
that it had you know 34 more affinities
yeah that's just a delta G measurement
really I mean so so here's the point
here's the long belaboured point I'm
trying to make which is that if you look
at the entourage effect and if you
assume that okay so in that stuff I got
from the dispensary
they know what 80% is cannabinoids 15%
13 there's 5% other stuff right so that
other stuff could have like T it C P
which is could go the whole way yeah
right
part of that entourage effect are these
smaller amounts of like a TCP and who
knows if c9 the c11 whatever you think
that there could be something to that if
they do yeah I mean I guess we got to
figure out what the standards are and
how to measure this stuff on HPLC ease
so that we're not I really disagree
because I don't think the amount of THC
P would amount to diddly spot it's
probably even in the concentrate like to
talk about there's 80 percent THC if
that's what the cannabinoid is and
there's point zero zero one or left
right it's so so so maybe but there
could what are the other phantom
compounds there's some other things in
there that's making up that other 5% CBD
no no no no all the cats of Pennsylvania
they measure all seven I think it's
seven and maybe it's nine let's see yeah
yeah I think they measure nine different
cannabinoids so all those cannabinoids
have been accounted for the terpenes I
mean it's a nice saucy product you saw
my stocks well but nobody was measuring
THC or CBD THC no they were they could
be peek under peak on some on the ground
okay but like I said they weren't
measuring yeah see that's just the point
Sam is is that at last five percent of
stuff that my state doesn't test for is
really the key differentiator ultimately
on why it works so well right it's the
cannabinoids and the terpenes yes and
that's a high but you could also be
presumably murky mark but I think you
make a good point that you know that 5%
in terms of numbers is a lot and and
that's a lot of unknown that you know
it's a you know to bring
all looks good to speak it's like you
know that 5% you know it might not be th
TP but it could be other acid maybe
isn't 30 times better but maybe only
like five or six or seven times better
right and it's only there in a fraction
of a percent and maybe there's two or
three things someone today was asking
online in the chat about flavonoids and
I think a lot of these low-temperature
butane extractions I think a lot of
flavonoids come through I mean I would
see any reason why they wouldn't I think
that's most reason why all the stuffs
colored deactivated 'high from from
smokey but a certain fraction of that 5%
of extractables is flavonoids like if
it's 0.5 or point 2 flavonoids have high
extinction coefficients which mean
they're highly colored so a little bit
of flavonoid can really color it and the
fact that most cannabis extracts are
loose the things that I see are mostly
like you know like this kind of color
this kind of color I mean it terpenes if
you isolate the terpenes are all
colorless yeah cannabinoid should be
colorless the thing that's colored here
I believe is the flavonoids I don't know
that for a fact I just think that the
colorant oxidized cannabinoids and
oxidized terpenes you have gone over
well at least the oxidization color
exits
yeah reddish and yellow colors yeah well
that was pretty deep down the rabbit
hole not too bad I went a little bit
past noon but I loved it it's good just
keep talking if you guys want to talk
I'm not I'm not opposed well I haven't
spoke with Kevin in a while Kevin it's
been a while right where we've both been
on it's like Kevin's been I
and I was traveling one time and I think
I've been on and Kevin takes quarantines
unfortunately yeah hey let me a shout
out the great went post that poster
that's behind you that's that sounds
pretty sick yeah
reminiscing on some of them have you
heard that podcast of theirs now they
talk about the swamp I remember being at
the swamp yeah I can't believe it yeah
yeah I think Marcus was there Marcus
weren't you there
no I was not there I think the biggest
kind of big thing that fish ever put on
that I went to which wasn't a big thing
at all it just ended up being historic
was well I was at the the live one the
tweezer that they put on there in Bangor
Maine but it was 94 Halloween show in
Glens Falls where they did the double
whiteout oh the way though yeah yeah I
was front row Center for that it was
absolutely bonkers so long it was five
and a half hours which 494 was I think
it might have been the longest concert
they'd ever played to date that wasn't
like some specialized New Year's show or
something you know it was long it was
good happy to be there working 1991 EMU
Wow huh and then they played the Hilton
in Eugene and that's and I think they
start their first bouncing ball and the
bouncing around the room the room yeah
but here's the thing how many
Doniak slices do you have my college
stuff I bet I still have some of those
in there wife's actually was gonna
picture farm she's got a bunch of photos
from your Amy's farm days so fishman and
in a wedding dress oh nice yeah Amy's
farm was a big deal that was remember
when we used to play chess yeah audience
versus man right yeah yeah and what else
we got here we got amazingly one at one
time didn't they beat the audience at
one point no it was a draw yeah and they
had a move each night for fall 95
leading up to yeah the run at the garden
is this this is fall this might be that
my first concert was in 1984 and it was
like Iron Maiden that's good Boston more
than feeling but guess who opened up for
Iron Maiden in 1984 any guesses Steve oh
no no it was Twisted Sister you can't
even make that [ __ ] up that is Tiny Tim
well I mean pretty much on some like
crazy
ketamine or something I was gonna say
since you know we're all well
quarantined you know there's there's a
lot of musicians out there that are that
are offering music up now and I think it
now's a good time to support this
artists and to support those musicians
that are you know they're they're forced
home like all of us but this is you know
it's more than as we all know just like
what we do it's it's it's extremely
stressful and it's a hard time for them
so if we can go to band camp and I think
you know a hundred percent of the
proceeds are going the artists right now
if we can you know find your favorite
artist and pitch and I think gonna go a
long way to them speak volumes to to the
fan base out there that still care about
music and deep listen to albums go back
to shows and close your eyes and I'm
getting into it very good idea you've
been some really good time for that you
know it's such a good time to get back
to putting on
record and focusing in on it like a film
or you know and just kind of being in
the moment with it it's you know we were
so distracted with with so much that
it'll it'll you know it gives us a
chance to ground ourselves and bring
ourselves back to you know things we
enjoy the simple things so if any you
guys are out there looking for something
to do I think that's a really great way
to get grounded
well how I'm gonna finish this off
through your inspiration Colin is I'm
gonna share my screen and play one of
the songs from Neil Young's fireside
sessions if you did a couple of days ago
with his wife their own Hannah and so
well thank you all for showing up I'm
gonna do a bunch more hangouts a bunch
more hash churches so of course I'll
invite all of you guys I'm not going to
thank every single person that came in
today because there was literally like
15 of us but thanks going on today as
well like one of these artists who's
doing a online couch tour skunk sessions
check em I know you might be able to
catch some of that this afternoon
awesome
what's that Josh and I think we're gonna
do another session on Thursday with some
more healing strategies and ways that
people can get through and you know
educational series faced way need for
help honey get us connected you know
Jeffrey heard and rather and Stacy and
everything and we're gonna just continue
you know down the path of ways that we
can build our immune system and more
plants that we can Ally with and maybe
ways that we can you know set up some of
the new gardens in order to you know
create some of these healthy things in
the future so thank you today for
everything appreciate you alright
Neil's going live here I'm gonna share
my screen
you guys are welcome to hang out you're
welcome to leave whatever you like but
he's going up now you guys can see it
yes or no all right Neil how [ __ ] cool
is Neil Young just on a side note he
just came to my dispensary a few months
ago him and Daryl their [ __ ] hotel
dude
right through this guy's long rip the
whole time we can't hear them though
really I can you know we can hear you
can't hear them or you can no no we
can't about now they're you know trying
to turn it up it's coming through very
quiet
[Music]
shout out to Puerto Rico who knows how
to handle the crisis thanks a lot guys
[Music]
peace Kevin - Kevin eats everyone I
gotta go
peace everyone
[Music]
[Applause]
these guys have a great Johnny theater
mark you guys doing well I hope
everything's okay in your house I hope
you have a place to eat or you're with
your loved ones all right that's enough
right peace out everybody loose