yes this meeting is being recorded did
you hear
that I did hear that loud and clear that
was kind of trippy I guess they got to
say that now so we're gonna go live
right
now and there we go just like that we
are live welcome everybody hash Church
3.0
episode 24 on June 6th of 2021 I'm just
going to quickly go in and and mute the
link that's live copy it and paste it
into the other YouTube room so everyone
can come and
play and uh welcome dude welcome to
Dustin powers in the house from future
4200 website we're going to talk a
little bit about that today the rest of
the crew is late to the party so it's
just you and I man uh really nice to
meet you finally uh here on uh on hash
church and I'm looking forward to
talking a little bit about your website
and kind of talking about how you
started it and how it all kind of came
to be and just really uh much respect
for for what you've done you know it
seemed like a lot of the
websites I don't want to say fell off
but kind of fell off when cannabis
became more integraded into Twitter
Instagram Facebook and still they like
to play and shut down accounts but you
really pushed through with the chemistry
and kind of brought this group of people
that were still willing to stay together
I just didn't see it on IC mag I just
didn't see it on some of the other
websites that just some of the hardcore
stayed but to me the websites really
crumbled compared to what they once
were yeah absolutely um and you know
none of them had a focus on the Canabis
processing and that was you know those
two things between social media current
social media platforms being a terrible
repository for information you know
unsearchable you you got all this
information in the comments that you'll
never find again which that pushed me
right back into the forum mindset and I
started you know investigating all the
different cannabis forums and I realized
there's a huge gap there's no cannabis
processing form you know icy mag because
I came up up under Greywolf so I knew
all about IC mag but it's got one
subcategory for processing and that's it
there's no you know there's no
organization there there's no detailed
you know like like what we have on
future 4200 right now so I just saw a
giant hole and realized it was something
that we needed to do well it's
interesting that you would say that
because I remember
on overgrow back in the late 90s early
2000s I got on there it was breeder
Steve that was like come on to overgrow
you know I'm in the Shark Tank and I was
kind of like the Shark Tank what's the
Shark Tank little did I know that's
where all the trolls hung out and that
was like where people got into it but I
ended up into the main main room um and
I can't even remember what the main room
was uh welcome Dr Mark just talking
about overgrow right now and thank you
for introducing uh Dustin and bringing
him on to the show today I really
appreciate that
um but yeah overgrow overgrow just had
like a photo gallery and that's where
bog and Gypsy and myself and highgrade
and some other kind of key early people
were just posting these you know what we
did back then was we went and bought two
and $3,000 digital cameras uh they were
Sony cyers shots they were like 2.2
megapixels this was like
1999 and it was the beginning of digital
photography it was the beginning of
being able to actually take a pretty
decent shot it's funny to think that 2.2
megapixels was a big thing I definitely
paid over $2,000 for that camera just in
order to show hash porn and so that's
how I started my company on overgrow and
I would post all these pictures and this
one Forum in in the in on overgrow this
one folder that we all were posting in
was where everyone was and So eventually
shebang who started the website
contacted me and say Hey listen I want
to get you
a hash room and it was certainly it's
just like you were saying like
unsearchable one simple room not really
focusing on processing but keep in mind
this was really the beginning days to
where we would get to with your website
eventually and it was just like it was
kind of a LoveHate relationship I had
with it because I went from going into
this one room that had like 30,000
people in it into a room that nobody
knew existed and I it was up to me to
build up that room and bring other hash
makers it took years but then at the
same time all that great information how
are you going to search it how are you
going to like organize the information
and the data I mean honestly it's very
much like hash church for that matter
because hash church is unsearchable
there's gems on hash church and if ever
there's people that you know maybe have
no lives and just want to sit around and
watch 10,000 hours of hash Church boy is
there a value in picking out the Nuggets
that have been said on this show maybe
we'll learn a little bit about that
today from uh some of the things you
share about uh you know future 4200 how
it kind of came to be and uh you know
where it's where it's at
today yeah absolutely I just wanted to
give a shout out to Dr Mark thank you
for bringing me here and thank you for
all your contributions on the Forum and
everything you've done for for cannabis
so appreciate you yeah you know I'm not
on there enough because I realized the
other day as I was trying to scroll
through and catch up that so behind and
it moves a million miles an hour and
it's just it's so cool I mean yeah
there's a lot of tongue and cheek you
know kind of back and forth but I mean I
think when you weigh through there's
quite a bit of useful information and I
think again you feel an unmet need
that's out there which is and I think
hash church is different though Mark
it's kind like I think of hash church is
kind of like again reporting back in
between weeks of future 4200 which is
constantly happening you know it's kind
of like to me it's like 4200 is part of
the natural Continuum that there there's
this dialogue and dialogue is constantly
happening and it was just like so
fortunate that again that I actually
found a couple conversations there
because I think in my own education in
my own
self-exploration in trying to find out
what are the best methods and processes
you you know if you ever close your mind
to learning you you're you're missing
the ticket you know so just because I
have all those plaques on the the wall
there that doesn't mean that I know
everything and you know I go there all
the time and learn new stuff and you
know you think that oh my God what is
this guy doing on his phone it's mostly
42 hour learning learning catch it up
just catch it up dude I got plaques I
got my
plaqu yeah I mean so there's a whole we
got a whole lot of bases to cover here I
I completely agree with you we have this
it's there's this issue with the
internet right where people can act like
idiots with very little repercussion
and you know I thought we had this
figured out at the beginning but as a a
forum moderator administrator it's
impossible it's impossible to make
everybody happy so we've taken as hands
off an approach as possible possible and
it has its pros and has its cons right
like I spend a lot of time on other
technical forums like whether it be
carpentry or or working on my tractors
or in permaculture Yad ya and a lot more
of them or a lot of them are are a lot
more civil than than our Forum but our
form gets a lot more done a lot quicker
um so it it there's this give and take
and you're right this this form of
communication that we're in right now on
hash Church definitely works well as a
summary also we're looking at each other
face to face so we're much more polite
nobody's calling each other names
nobody's being a troll and that's a
that's a huge important thing um and you
know there's all these different sites
to the internet and I don't think you
can have platform that does it all it's
just not it doesn't work that way so
you're right being able to summarize
after a week of of nonsense with little
gyms in there that's that's golden um so
a and to talk about the formation a
little bit it it came out a necessity
like I said I I wasn't able to search
Instagram and and that came up because I
was working a consult job and the
customer asked me a question that I
didn't quite know but I knew that I had
read like a week or two previous on
Instagram I said give me a sec let me
see if I can find that little gem you
know 10 15 minutes later I gave up I was
like this impossible you can't search
this at all and I had the thought wow we
I wish there was a cannabis processing
Forum couple weeks looking like I said
there wasn't anything and I didn't have
the technical skills to start a forum so
I just kind of let the idea slide I said
well that would be great someday if
somebody did that about two weeks later
I was work in a booth with Cascade
Botanicals um sidco cat invited me she's
one of the original skunk Farmers I had
worked with her and JD and Joe Oaks at
farmold um Joe actually brought me on
board there I was working that Booth
with Cascade Katherine was there and her
son sidco was there and at the end of
the day he said hey man you should start
a forum for cannabis processing and we
hadn't talked or anything I said wow man
if that wasn't meant to be you know I
explained this whole story to him and I
said look don't have the technical
skills but I have a bunch of ideas on
how if you do the technical side we can
get this populated immediately and you
know how you said it took you a couple
years to get your new room rolling I
leveraged the power of Instagram to jump
start the form because we hit the ground
running um we did a couple giveaways I I
was in the process
of downloading every single piece of
scientific literature I could find on
cannabis using Li gen scub uh and then I
would format the titles and then I'd
categorize it and I called it the data
dump and I used the data dump as
incentive for people to come to the
Forum I put up a post I said look if you
repost this if you tag a couple of your
friends I'll give you the link to the
data dump with all of this information
and it just hyperlink people over to the
Forum and that's where we initially
stored it so right off the bat you know
we had multiple thousand members just
hit the ground running and I at the same
time I shared two different large scale
techniques that I had developed one of
them was bucket Tech it was you know if
you got a shed and a and a bunch of mid
to lowquality cannabis can you extract
the cannaboids for cheap and safe in
your backyard and you know at scale and
yeah you definitely can with ethanol and
buckets and a washing machine and uh so
we had the full write up SOP on that and
then at the same time i' had also
developed a technique for remediation of
michol from uh distillate and it was the
timing was such that California changed
its laws and all of a sudden all of the
distillate had to be pesticide free it
was an overnight decision so you had all
these companies with millions of dollars
of inventory laying around I convinced
one of them to let me come in they paid
for all the testing we figured it out
and my deal with them was reciprocos on
uh the IP I said look you can take the
IP do whatever you want I'm going to
take the IP and do whatever we want we
can't hold each other back we can't tell
each other what to do that's the deal
and they were stoked I gave them like
three days Head Start so they were able
to remediate all their stuff and sell it
into a market that was void of disate
and on my end I wrote it all up into an
so and it was the third uh you know
prize for coming to Future 4200 is this
is where the pesticide remediation sop
will be hosted for free forever so that
we can make more clean you know quality
products in you know throughout because
that kind of my underlying goal is what
year was that DUS like what what I'm
just trying to place that on the
calendar when was that you know I should
write these things things down but 2017
2018 I think
2017 yeah maybe 17 18 somewhere around
there okay so it was right when that
California red kicked in right yes
whenever that is yes so there's a hard
set date in the sand right there
whenever they changed that I'm sure you
could look that up right so immediately
you just had this huge audience because
there was this need oh my God I got to
remediate my distill how do I do that I
need an sop bam they go to Google they
find your thing and
they they know that here's a
resource when I have issues around
whatever that I can kind of constantly
go back to yep so that's a great story
man how's it going
Mike what's up Dustin good to see you
again yeah you too you
too hey Mike how are you good yeah no as
Dustin kind of mentioned there was a
couple states that were coming online
with and the requirements to test
pesticides and you know back when back
in many of the states were medical they
would test for the cannabinoids and some
some analytical labs would offered a
test for the terpenoids but very little
regulatory requirements were required by
the medical States so there was a kind
of unregulated industry right
and well the timing was such that some
of these Labs were now getting the mass
spectrometers that had the sensitivity
and the library to say oh my god look
what's in here there's a whole bunch of
crap in here and we could do Mass speec
matches in our library that we
unequivocally know here's this compound
here's this compound and here's this
compound so it was kind of like uh you
know both both things the regulation but
also the sophistication of the
analytical instrumentation and the
testing Labs allow these things to be
found and
Quantified and and so again going back
to to um you know the usefulness of 4200
as a for it's like well if you need to
understand about those techniques
sensitivity those techniques what kind
of techniques are out there I mean if
you know nothing about the field you can
do a deep dive on that form and get all
kinds of information right Dustin oh
yeah absolutely and it's like my fir
people
how on your your you know professional
training on the form go read through as
much of that as you can get through and
you have a huge jump start uh to you
know if you if you don't know anything
to I'm going to be I got a job making
hash in two weeks what do I do uh that
that's a great free resource for
you man isn't that a funny accurate
statement I I got a job making hash next
week and I don't know what to do it's
like well why the [ __ ] apply for the job
if you don't know what you're and it's
crazy to think yeah but you know I I
didn't know how to make pizza when I got
my first pizza making job right like
that most a lot of people don't know
what they're doing when they get their
job that that's that's kind of life
right so and and in a normal World you'd
be able to go and sweep the floor for a
buck an hour and Learn by experience you
know as an apprentice or whatever but in
the real world when a hash yeah and
that's how it should be that that's you
know
look the industry the industry has been
plucked clean I mean let's bit be real
the good on have already paid for
they're taken away so people are going
to fake the funk people are going to lie
what they they have to do but they do
this in everyday jobs all the time you
know early on I didn't know what I was
doing and I had to figure out things
there was no rule books on how to you
know run a dispensary or any of that so
you know we just grabbed it by the seat
of the pants so you know now there's
rules as we used to as we say before we
were building a plane while flying it
now you've got runways you've got
engines you can take off you can do all
these different things so plan it before
you start it and try to do as best as
you can but you know a lot of these
businesses and jobs are new so you know
getting in there and fitting in and
trying to figure it out is is a real
world so you know Dustin's not wrong no
I definitely agree at the same time I
got to say and shout out to all my techs
that we've trained over the last year at
embark these guys came in with very
little knowledge most of them and uh
they have learned to how you know if you
teach people the right way and the the
correct Sops and the the right Pathways
to the results that you're looking for
it's incredible how fast people can uh
can really kind of you know and I'm
talking mostly solventless right now but
I'm sure it will be the same when uh
when Mike starts training people on his
side of the lab so yeah it's uh it's
pretty awesome shout out to the new hash
makers that are coming on I definitely
remember the days where I knew nothing
thank God I got lucky and got to stand
on the shoulders of some pretty amazing
Giants Well people prefer people that
have little to no experience because
those who have experience will want to
do things their own way whereas those
that have Sops they will follow them to
a te which is what you need and have to
do so you know we all we're all about
breaking the rules but know the rules
before you break the rules is all I'm
saying you got to strike a certain
balance you know you have to be able to
do something unique and something
expressive that you could put your own
individual creativity into but you're
you're absolutely right you're probably
going to have to follow a set of Sops
that you may not think is the best way
of doing things but regulation and the
rest of your company requires you to do
it and it it becomes really terrible
when you have belligerent employees that
think that they know how to to do it and
end up either uh wasting a whole bunch
of product or
contaminating a whole bunch of stuff and
then you have to go see that's why you
don't do that yeah that's the worst
yeah hey I want to welcome everyone else
to the room welcome welcome to etan
Fontan who I just spoke over apologies
for that welcome to Johnny [ __ ] B
with the save the turps Hat on crazy
bastard that he is love him love him
welcome to Mike West welcome to Mr
vessel life Colin Palmer's in the house
and uh dude you came in with such a
serious face Colin it's what made me
laugh I was like I looked around Church
you were like I was like I was well I
was looking at something on my screen
really intently I was like what is that
and that's my uh that's my my mind's
churning
look totally I saw it I caught it good
to see you guys how how's everyone doing
nice to see you uh we got future 4200
Dustin what's going on brother nice to
to meet you in the the internet
fashion Mark everyone Johnny B of course
thanks for having me Marcus uh I'm uh
I'm in route to California this week so
if anyone is around I will be there so
am I
nice La first and then San Francisco
second so I'll be there until Friday I'm
going to San Francisco go first and La
second when which day you which day we
yeah which which day are we Crossing uh
Wednesday we're driving
down so la let me ask you guys a
question because I've never been there
but I did watch the movie um The Money
Tree I don't know if any of you have
ever seen the money tree but it's an
incredible movie and Buddy says he says
what's la like and he says oh la is like
a big submarine sandwich when you're
really really hungry uh and you start
eating it you're just starving but then
you realize there's like a big piece of
[ __ ] in the middle of the sandwich but
you're so hungry you just eat around it
is is that what La is
like yeah pretty much I've I've lived in
La you know I've also lived in the good
spots with Todd back when he was in
belir and stuff like that so I'm kind of
biased and having the nice places to
stay but I've been to there's lots of
shitty places around but you know it's
it's like Pockets you know it's like
anywhere elseu
are is surrounded by the bio with the
side and the ocean other there's more
[ __ ] than sandwich for sure oh [ __ ] for
sure I kind of
take all the neighborhoods in New York
City like East New York like the far
reaching corners of the Bronx and you
just put them in the middle of the city
that's kind of the deal with with with
LA and you can't cross the city without
going through those neighborhoods so it
will never ever really change without
that changing as well so then like the
nicer areas the nicer areas in which
atan was talking about I guess there's
more bread there because if you have
more bread in a [ __ ] sandwich you you
eat less [ __ ] is that how it works lots
of condiments lots of in the Bronx so
don't get me wrong
there yeah but you're talking about
Universal City Hollywood Beverly Hills
you're talking about some of the most
affluent
of the United States where they have
more
bread might even have a little cheese
over there you got a little Dough Spread
that [ __ ] a little
thin yeah so yeah it's pretty much [ __ ]
good to avoid San Francisco is also [ __ ]
there's Maps that'll tell you how much
[ __ ] and where it is to avoid it like
literally so it's gotten weird down
there but there's great places too don't
get me wrong it's just you know it's
it's it's it's a megalopolis so you've
got The Good the Bad and the Ugly and
you know there's more bad and ugly than
there are
good well I'm just going to hang out up
here in BC for a little while longer I
guess and uh enjoy my interactions
through the internet uh until uh well it
sounds like people are starting to make
trips it sounds like stuff is uh maybe
we'll be able to hug people here June
21st they said was some date that uh
they're going to make make some
Proclamation on whether or not Americans
can go back to Canada right is that
right June 21st has anyone else heard
that it's like in New York the juneth
where you uh you get the uh the Sun
Lines perfectly up with the Avenue so
you can get this incredible shot all the
way down or
view that's what's up
hinge so they'll let me come back to
Canada as long as I uh identify as
vaccinated right I think the way it goes
is I don't think we're doing that are we
you can't come
backy Canada curently requires a two we
quarantine that's five grand in a in a
hotel but I I believe that the they're
discussing it and if both sides of the
Border are starting to show her immunity
they they'll start looking at opening up
the border the big issue is is obviously
both countries want to minimize the risk
of variant transmission so what we
don't can we only can we only quarantine
in like $300 a night hotels is that what
they're saying
baller yeah I think it's the 14 day
minimum they test you on the first day
and test you on the 10th day but I I
believe if if there's a certain Target
if 70% of the population has their first
shot then they're going to probably
allow vaccinated people to cross the
border but it's you know as with any
anything there's many great plagues
throughout history were spread due to
travel but as long as you're you know
traveling in a Safe and Smart fashion
and not traveling when you're sick you
know there's minimal there's ways to
minimize that
risk and what I just got to show them my
little piece of
paper hopefully probably yeah probably
we'll see let's hope
not let's hope not although that little
piece of paper looks pretty easy to
create you just F why don't you just uh
put that on the uh on the Xerox machine
and uh put Dustin's name on that I'm
ready man I'm
ready that's
aelon spend a weekend with Marcus man
will never be the same and we're just
gonna show up on hash church one day and
it'll just be me and Marcus sitting next
to each other right and Mike too Mike
join you and Mike yeah yeah yeah too
yeah without any oh let me know hey I
got my piece of paper we're good to go
let's go I'm ready you guys got the
papers they got to open up the borders
soon they
gota well they're supposed to open up
California on June 15th but uh OSHA has
made us aware that even though the state
is opening up there will be no new
information for employees until July
31st so it's still masks on uh in the
real world for for you know working it
and doing it unfortunately so Washington
open back up this we open back up I
think the 30th is the day they're going
to get rid of all covid restrictions on
the 30th of this month although they
said they're going to maintain the state
of emergency which gives the governor a
whole bunch of like extra Constitutional
Powers which is strange but currently
they lifted The Mask mandate um and
there's no more restrictions now some of
the denser populated like Seattle people
are still wearing masks and most of the
businesses are requiring masks where I
live out in rural Washington on the
coast no mask no restrictions life is
back to normal not that it ever really
left normal but it's actually like fully
normal the only thing I really want
people to do here is Hash so no masks
but hash you got to do hash man you
can't be coming on to Hash church not
doing hash so come
on we got our pipes here's a pipe
actually I think I might hit this little
crazy Ewok one this is fun right that is
nice little slurper yeah good good good
little slurper you know I've got my OG
slurper from JP and you can really see
the difference yeah in the length this
one really is much more like that uh
what do you call it there Mike the
rising film evaporator Style ah yeah
that's my first thought that the path
there is getting long get yeah that's
what they based it on for sure that
seems to be where they're going with it
you know let's create a longer thinner
tube not a wider shorter tube they need
a they need a vacuum jacket that little
part right there that'd be
sweet get it all jacketed up yeah so you
get your little marbles in there there's
three of them in
there and hit a little six-star looks
like Johnny be's torching up I was going
to ask Dustin just about uh some of the
controversy we hear about Delta 8 what's
going on on on that whole thread 42 man
it's pretty big pretty big and pretty
controversial topic and I just want
throw that out there for discussion okay
yeah I knew this when was coming I've
been thinking about it a lot and and
trying to follow along you know like I
think a lot of people assume that
I I'm like fully aware of everything
that goes on in the Forum impossible no
person that's impossible like I have a
light like I I okay so Delta eight
um we'll just start bunch of people are
making yeah let's start with let's start
with kind of how why people started talk
making it right okay we're gonna start
at the
beginning back in the day we were
running the short path making disl it it
was coming out orange yellow most of our
short paths were like cheap Chinese
glass you got on Amazon cuz nobody was
making it we were just piecing together
chemistry sets people were throwing all
sorts of crazy ideas out there one of
them which uh this is how Photon no
broke into the scene he said look if you
take um you know he sold this as an sop
but it's fully open now if you take an
activated bleaching clay which is just
like clay that's been acid washed or
certain types of silica like filter
Sands um all of these various Medias you
can throw them into the boiling flask
and the diso that comes out that would
be basically water clear not wrong is
great fantastic and this is before you
know we talked earlier about testing and
the ubiquity of testing and and the uh
how advanced these Labs were this is way
before any of that this is when the labs
were yeah testing canav oid content of
flowers May the test canabo content of
your your uh extracts in Washington is a
little better than other states but so
you throw these things in there makes
water clear but one thing we didn't know
because without the testing and when
you're just making a bunch of carts to
send off wherever you're not testing
every single bit what was happening is
you greatly reducing your Delta 9
content and you were also greatly
increasing bunch of other random Peaks
all over you're making like a dirty mess
of this lit um one of those Peaks we've
now realized 8 and this is something
that's been known for a long time but
the labs just finally caught up to what
you know these scientists had back in
the and 70s so we were making Delta
8 on accident making really nice looking
cards move forward quite a few years
we've refined the technique through
analytics back in we got really high
quality
da to get that last little Delta 9 out
and there's a bunch of really shady ways
you can make Delta 8 and and doing it
that way leaves the possibility of
having all sorts of nasties left in your
diset uh anywhere from like the the the
reagent that you used or the Catalyst
that you used is something dangerous or
radioactive or super toxic like and you
might have left that in there or it
could have also caused all sorts of
weird side reactions like we converted
the Delta KN into God knows what one of
those canabo that in the literature says
it killed the rats immediately like who
knows there there's all these weird [ __ ]
that could happen but that didn't stop
anybody and for years they did that and
sold it and as far as we know nobody
like died there's no chronic outbreak of
everybody died from this batch of disl
um now that doesn't mean that it's safe
who knows if those people are going to
get cancer and die in 30 years or not
you know we don't know about smoking
vape pens either like those might give
you cancer and kill you in 30 years too
point
is when a member ion trap said
everything out there is got dangerous
side compound cyclohexanes all these
different toxic things my testing has
showed this this and this and except for
this one lab I found this one random pen
that's safe and it's clean and all the
ones I tested in y y and everybody's
like wow this is crazy bunch of people
jumped on it bunch of people were like
well maybe that's a little
weird roll back a couple years a lab
that got involved with us um
KCA they have been active on the forum
for a long time they're out in Kentucky
they've been always upfront about
everything they're doing they they
sponsor competitions within us they talk
they they improve their procedures based
on what we say they hopped in and said
well that's that's interesting we want
to test a bunch of different samples we
want to see if that that's the case and
then it at the at the same time when
they start they crowdsource this big
funding or this big testing campaign and
they run through it and they get all
these random samples from all over the
place it comes out that ion trap is a
member of that company or works for that
company that was the one clean one and a
bunch of other people start asking
questions and it starts getting it turns
into this thousand long comment thread
of he said she said what's going on here
who's the scammer KCA comes back and
finds none of any of that in multiple
different you know all of them none of
them had those pu in it and they run
another round and same thing so
it it turns out that people are actually
aren't making super dangerous Delta 8
Delta 8 while still most of it is hot
with Delta 9 because it's a very
difficult process to get that last
little Delta 9
out we have yet to find a random sample
that has any of these super toxic
compounds now you can take like a
Palladium conversion um no that's CBN um
PTSA uh a fairly toxic acid um if you
left a bunch of that in there it would
be no bueno it' be pretty easy to
identify but people are not doing that
so you know we are seeing
pretty decent like uh woot grade
chemistry here on this Delta eight thing
um it's it's unfortunate that what's
happening on the regulatory side because
of the implication that it could be
unsafe or you know whatever it is that
our federal government has up its ass
about canabo is coming through on on d8
and not only does that ruin the
potential for d8 for its truly medicinal
value which is that it's strongly
anti-emetic it it's almost absolutely
anti-emetic um and uh that's super
important for children that are getting
chemotherapy right some the way that
people die when they're getting chemo a
lot of time is that they're not able to
feed themselves they're not able to hold
down nutrients and and with delta8 you
can completely eliminate that problem
and then the second problem with the
regulation that's coming about from this
fear campaign basically is that it
starts to affect all the other canabo
that have medicinal benefits we're
looking at now are we going to still be
able to make CBN because of the interim
d8 that perhaps gets made or our
conversion is going to be you know
they're synthetic chemistry of cannabis
and you can't do it anymore it's like so
this d8 thing is is a wild ride for
sure it just killed a bill alone in
Texas because they added Delta 8 to the
hemp Bill and I've Got Friends in Texas
who have been working on it and that
sank that one quicker than anything it
was the fastest torpedo so the
individual cannaboid um firing and
misfiring is going to be a problem it's
going to be a cannaboid whack-a-mole
situation until legalization in
compounds don't you think doctor scal
down yeah I mean I personally I don't
have a problem with the molecule itself
the molecules canono so it's safe
meaning that humans can take a lot of it
it's not going to shut down your
breathing you can't OD by taking Delta
eight but I guess you know whether those
results are real or not what it does
call for is production under some type
of regulated environment because it's no
longer an extract it's no longer well
it's kind of like hash or I no it's not
like extracted anymore it's basically
the the the product of a chemical
reaction and a product of a chemical
reaction yeah as Dustin points out could
depending on how you run that chemical
reaction could have lot of different lot
of different products there uh Marcus
can you let me share my screen so we can
go through some literature I pulled up
here so we can talk about this
absolutely can I can I share my screen
so I do I hit the share screen thing I
think that's about that's it yeah that's
it okay all right okay let's see let's
do
screen and then select which which on
your P yeah youit okay all right okay
all right so what we're going to do is
we're going to go back to the michul and
literature you know this is great Dustin
because this is exactly what I had as a
as a PhD chemist I mean I had not
learned cannaboid chemistry academically
or in my graduate work or my postdoc
work I had to go and totally self
immerse myself into this literature and
here we find a paper from Rafi from uh
oh this is beautiful I think the title
of this paper is
hashish he's got like I think he's got
like four there's a series of like four
of these were just the chemistry of
hashish and look this is from 1966 I'll
bet you half of our viewing audience
wasn't even born yet right so so so look
at what look at what he describes here
so he describes
here this is like the first time that
I'm seeing this in the literature where
he shows the conversion of CBD right
here over into uh well here's Delta 8
he's got an arrow going to Delta eight
but he also has an arrow going to Delta
9 and so I think he recognized right
away is that you can use acid catalyzed
cyclisation chemistry to psych and
here's even something cooler for me look
what he did after he psychoed it he Hy
rated it and made hexahydro canabidol
this I think is one of the first reports
of hexa hydr canaban all here and you
can see it gives a both a mixture of
both up and down so this is from 1966
this is from earlier in the year later
that year when his when his article
published in the Journal of the American
Chemical Society he entitled it uh
concerning the isomerization of Delta 1
to
delta6 uh that's the old nomenclature
that would be Delta 9 to Delta 8 these
days by our by our nomenclature and what
you see here is that yes he does have a
procedure that uses things like sulfonic
acids to basically isomerize this which
is Delta 9 into Delta 8 because Delta 8
is more thermodynamically favored but
it's very interesting here because what
you also see is you can see
isomerization of other cannabinoids in
this case um this here is CBC and CBC
can isomerize over into this uh very
peculiar what's called isot THC and so
where ISO THC rears its ugly head this
is a a paper for much later so this is
from um this is called the chemical
aspects of of CBD I know this paper by
Heart by hanou and um and mulam and in
this paper he
describes what happens when you take CBD
and you treat it with acid yes you can
and mostly make uh Delta 8
THC uh but under certain acidic
conditions you can make other compounds
including this isomer of THC which is
called isot THC and in fact this uh
group of Italians uh last year published
this wonderful uh paper on the uh
conversion canabidol of via acid
catalyzed intermolecular calization to
THC isomers and so what you could see
here is that yes they they talk about
you know conversion to to Delta 9 and
Delta 8 but they also show these two
other ISO isomers right which are are
formed in in in the reaction depending
on the condition so so depending on the
conditions that you use there's two
double bonds and there's two hydroxy
groups uh one pathway pathway a leads to
these ISO products and pathway B leads
to the normal uh products that you find
in the plant which are the THC
configured materials realizing that
Delta 9 is first made and then under
further acidic conditions you just see
isomerization to the more
thermodynamically favored this this is
where the plant ends and the plant is
able to do this chemistry because it's
in a chyro enzymatic environment where
these molecules are being made and
expressed not in a in in a reaction
flask but this gives you an idea so you
start with CBD and again I think Dustin
you pointed out because of the uh glut
of CBD isolate on the market and the
promise that this was going to be some
big opportunity uh people can now take
CBD and convert it into THC and put it
into products that get people really
high uh because they have THC isomer in
it but what you could see here if you
look at this table is that you get a
plethora of different products in this
reaction and even if you take their best
result here their best result here is
right here
93% um Delta 8 THC well my question is
what what the other 7% in fact they
they're quantifying the iso THC isomer
so it's not the iso THC isomers in this
case there's just 7% other stuff so you
have to assume that in that case they're
actually doing some kind of
chromatography to clean it out to turn
that 93 into something like 98 or
99% plus so you only have a very limited
amount of what the unknown material is
at so if people can
make Delta a a canabo that
pure using that that as another as
Marcus would say another arrow in the
quiver of being another canabo that we
can make but look at the reaction
conditions here they're using a LS acid
called TMS triflate that's
trimethyl triflate oh man that's not
only a really nasty Lis acid that you
can't use at larger scale that's
something that's prohibitively expensive
and you would never use this in a
commercial process you would try to get
away with some cheap acid like sulfuric
or some acid that you can just throw
away and not have to recover but you
would and D chloromethane A chlorinated
solvent at minus10 no [ __ ] way right
so when when you look at that you could
find a process by which you can make a
pure canono but the wonderful thing
about this for for researchers like
myself is that they're forced to publish
in peer-reviewed literature where they
have to show their data and let me just
show you one one quick thing so y all Lo
know that I love NMR NMR is nuclear
magnetic resonance and what you're
looking at right here is the proton
Spectrum for
purified um Delta 9 THC so this is
what's great about 4200 and hash church
and the literature is that you know as
cannaboid scientists we do have a
crystal
ball and it's called the literature and
we could look into the literature and
find things like this so this is great
for me because I can look at my Spectra
and I could compare it to this like a
fingerprint and see like how clean
something is or how unclean something is
and what I want to show you here is that
so this is the proton spectrum and this
peak right here this one right here at
about 6.3 corresponds to the vinic
proton that's right here when you
isomerize Delta 9 over into Delta 8 that
proton shifts about uh okay here it is
right here it shifts from 6.3 it was
over here to about
5.5.4 so I can use NMR as a diagnostic
tool to say do I have Delta 8 do I have
Delta 9 just like you can use just like
you can use hlc but what's even more
important is like when you look at hlc
especially if you have the sensitivity
of like a mass spectrometer you could
find all of these Trace compounds and I
want to just point out one more paper
from michul because I love this paper uh
in this paper what he was doing was he
was actually using a a petric oxidation
to make CBN you know a lot of people are
interested in CBN he was using a diano
dichloro quinone which is a really nasty
oxidant reagent to basically convert
Delta 9 THC into CBN but um I love what
he says about the reaction and and you
could just picture rafy saying this
because he's such a such a humble guy
where is it I'm looking for the quote
exactly L but um he basically says that
well you can't you can't use this method
because it's a really it's a really
toxic method and the reason why I wanted
to point that out is because again what
you'll see on 4200 and you'll see on
other forums is that oh there's a
literature method to make this there's a
literature method to make this what they
don't realize is that these literature
methods are not production
processes to make Pharmaceutical typ
compounds for human ingestion these are
to make little amounts of milligrams of
stuff to put it into testing in mice and
other other types of pharmaceutical type
testing before it's actually developed
and I think the good thing about 4200
when I see it is that there are a lot of
people who are chiming in and I could
tell just from Iron
traps what he's what he's posting is
well the guy is really knowledgeable
he's in been in canabo science for a
long time so I like having a dialogue
with someone like that but yeah does he
have a dog in the fight you start
reading through that thread and you're
like well there is a clean compliant way
in fact Dustin am I right that's the
title of the
thread the title of the thread is a
clean compliant way to make Delta eight
so the guy kind of has a dog in a fight
I don't have a dog in this fight so but
you know I do agree with him that it's
bogus that people who are flying below
regulation who aren't regulated in this
industry are basically selling a
chemical reaction product that's no
longer a canabo extract and whose safety
could you know whether those things are
in there and not Dustin I think the
discussion that we're having right now
is more important to make sure that you
don't just say Okay Delta a sucks Delta
8 has to be regulated like Delta 9
unfortunately now if they knock it off
the controlled dangerous substance act I
mean that's one of the biggest problems
with Delta 8 is it's mentioned by name
in the control dangerous substance act
under code 7370 as a Tetra hydroc
canaban and the [ __ ] story it it that
that puts it outside the provisions of
the farm bill in in my non-legal sense
but you know well
the government really just put its foot
in it I'm gonna get a drink of water
I'll be right
back um on that whole deal by P on one
hand they passed off regulation of hemp
over and that set this precedent and
then within that says and all analogues
of uh within the hemp bill says that of
CBD and if since I can get to d8 from
CBD that's why it it's been allowed and
spread so wide because there is a legal
discrepancy in in Delta a up until now
that states are giving specific
exclusions to da um but not not the
federal government though the states are
making these decisions which is within
the rights of of of a state for sure I
isn't it true that that uh people have
been
extracting uh THC and CBD from uh more
hempy type products but then they either
separate the THC or they concentrate it
so that instead of being 3% it's more
like you know three or four or five or
10 or
andal under the Farm
Act no that's absolutely that's illegal
so this this distillate before
remediated had about 4% by weight perc
THC in it now it has no measurable
amount of THC in it because it's gone
through a process called remediation
which is a non-chromatographic process
where they used heat to basically
convert the THC over to CBN and at some
point you know it's so funny not I
wouldn't say it's funny but everyone was
like oh man CBN man like like there's
there there's actually genu genuine
interest in CBN because CBN does have a
lot of interesting properties everyone
always thinks it's the sleep can avonoid
but I could only find there's like one
study in the literature and it's like 20
years old uh yeah so that's Crystal and
CBN so so most of the conventional
knowledge Sam was that CBN was just some
dark tar stuff but no it's the white
crystal and solid as you know
first absolutely right right and and the
uh other thing I yeah so he's showing so
who's making that that isolate right
there
Dustin you're
muted uh we make this one at Future
compounds which is our kind of
compounding lab in
Vegas that's CBN is you you held up
several tubes one was dark colored which
one was that this is this is the CBN
distl um and so this one okay get it yep
so this is like right after the
conversion it's still a diset it has not
been washed yet either we do several
liquid to liquid separations throughout
the process to you know add or extract
various you know the Rea what's the
percentage at that point of CBN Purity
in the
distillate I don't know I couldn't tell
you it's only teared I'm not involved
white stuff is easy to say 98 99% pure I
mean 99 plus yeah white and crystalin
like that do you have
CBC not in B currently um or
cbca definitely not not yet so Sam are
is CBC also a white solid yes you can if
you get it cbca I believe was I don't
remember with
CBC
okay yeah I don't think there is CBC I
it out there is
there I don't think anything
possible he's not wrong have the
genetics caught up yet genetics or
synthesis that's how you're going to get
it right right I mean the cheap way is
with genetics once you've got a variety
that produces CBD if you don't have a
THC problem with it then uh it just gets
mass produced mass produced mass
produced until you know the bubble
pops right well I thought we were
talking about this at last hash Church
there is some tech that talked about
conversion of CBD to
CBC no Mark I think it's CBG over to
CBC
uh uh okay um well you know me I'm just
a simple pla guy but chemistry I leave
smarter folks like you folks
yeah well I mean it's not necessarily uh
smarter but you
know it's it's a little more detailed I
mean the cool thing is again so Dustin
was this some of the literature that you
kind of started with here the michul
stuff or where did you when you started
your your Deep dive where did you begin
oh just in general yeah uh go well so
first Google Scholar and then of course
if you spend any time over there you're
going to come up with a bunch of mhom
and then um I also purchased a book I
was at a bookstore in Seattle and it is
the um it's an annals of the New York
Academy of Sciences volume 191 issue1 uh
marijuana chemistry pharmacology and
patterns of social use uh December 1971
and it was there in it was the last time
that they were going to meet and talk
about uh cannabis they were all shutting
down all of their cannabis research
because the government was no longer you
know that's when everything changed and
they weren't allowed to do you know
research anymore and so it was like just
a dump of everything they had and we're
like look we're we're getting rid of
this we're moving on to other things so
here's everything that we know and what
some of the things that I found really
interesting in there was they had they
had made every single different kind of
canabo they could theoretically come up
with right they were throwing random
[ __ ] at it oh here's all these new ones
we isolated it down and then they were
taking that and feeding it to like dogs
and uh feeding it injecting it smoking
them in a little box dogs and rats and
monkeys and all sorts of stuff and some
of the canabo that they listed in this
book are wild and just killed killed the
animals dead no problem like oh they're
dead you can definitely overdose on that
one so that and at that time we were
doing pretty large scale like this
bucket Tech backyard ethanol and then
doing a crew you know to crude and then
distillation and we just started getting
bons you know throw the bleaching clay
into the boiling flask and it right
there when I read that I was like oh
[ __ ] what if I'm making something that's
going to kill all these dumb
monkeys like uh that's not going to be
good so I I went make it makes sense
because again when you treat these
things with acid I mean THC in the Delta
9 configuration is only metastable and
and converting over to Delta 8 you know
people were always under this
misconception that delta8 is made in the
plant it's not made in a plant the
biosynthetic pathway ends at Delta 9
configur cannaboids and any conversion
over to Delta 8 is just adventitious
from humans [ __ ] with it right so
it's kind of like you you get to the
point where well okay so what that means
is over the Millennia and humans using
cannabis people have consumed Delta 8
Delta 8 is a minor canabo that's part of
that Gish yeah it's a degradation
component but so are all those
hydroxy um uh canabo that El soy keeps
finding on his moldy weed you know
so um so all those degradation
components are they really GNA you know
get you if you look at it actually it's
interesting so if you look at those
those elol Hydrox lated intermediates
they're all
hydroxylated which by the way is a a h
of biological degradation oxidation
they're all hydroxy in and around
that cyclohexane ring right because it's
trying to turn turn The Thing into
biofood or whatever but ultimately all
those things are going to thermally
eliminate to give
CBN so so like you could smoke
University of Mississippi's moldy weed
with those hydroxy things but what
you're going to get when you inhale that
is CBN because at nail temperature those
things are all going to thermally
dehydrate and make CBN so there's I
always I always said that CBN got me
loaded but it didn't get me high yeah
there you go right exactly loaded but
not high that's a good way to describe
it but like Sam when those guys were
discovering these new canabo and saying
oh look at all these it's funny that
those are only found on the canabo or on
the Cannabis that they grow down at the
University of Mississippi so and that
just changed right um that just opened
up they just gave out multiple more
licenses did Dr Sue get one they did I I
I don't know I hadn't been following
that close enough maybe 18 it changed
like a week ago um the guy was on Joe
the the founder of maps was on Joe Rogan
and he was talking about it as well uh
he got his license that they applied for
in like 2001 Dr Sue is is one of those
that that is top of the
list fantastic yeah I mean I think um I
think it was Sue who kind of blew the
whistle on the fact that a lot of that
cannabis was mold she sued them she
she it caused a lot of controversy
because you know uh people thought oh
government weed must be fine but as we
know because I tested it back in what
2010 my point more my my point more more
eloquently made is that even when the
stuff goes moldy those compounds are
just fine and safe for humans
stable yeah who was the guy who got the
can of joints every day or whatever was
his
name was patient one but currently uh
there's one
patient out of Florida right so I mean
there's people who smoke that weed like
it's no tomorrow right and and dude he
was loving it we we had a whole
conversation with him and it actually
made me think a lot because of course
you know this is back when Todd was on
the show we're all like dude we got to
get you better weed we're going to
figure this out like you need better
weed and he was like listen guys this
weed is perfect for me like it's just I
I really quite enjoy it and we were all
just
like I I had a similar discussion with
Robert Randall when he was still alive
and uh I said well you know if marijuana
has all this great you know benefits for
gloma for you then
uh wouldn't hashish be even better and
he he actually looked at me straight in
the face and says hashish doesn't have
medical benefit and uh I was quite
shocked and quite surprised and didn't
really want to argue with him but uh
yeah that was his personal belief you
got to understand they have to sort of
be Representatives since they received
medicine they can't necessarily go out
and uh [ __ ] on it completely you know
what I'm saying I think no I mean Robert
he's the one who stepped no no no Robert
I'm just talking in Irvin Spence because
I've had multiple
conversations specifically I'm not
talking Robert Robert rest in peace but
uh although we we do uh work with Alice
uh she's been assisting US veterans in
all of our different filings and uh
keeping us up to dat so you know uh yeah
his the 20th anniversary of his death
just uh passed on the second so rest in
peace Robert [ __ ] [ __ ] really hit the
fan okay so he got it and I think eight
or 10 or whatever other compassionate uh
programs were available for cannabis uh
from the government but then he showed
the AIDS Community how to apply and
there were like 1,000 applications and
the Government Federal Government
stopped the compassionate program
altogether but it grandmothered those
eight or whatever it was into the
program for life
and now it's down to
one hey Mark um that link I just posted
into the chat is um mesom 68 uh chloral
dehydr or dehydron of cannaboids total
synthesis of canb chrom so it's he did
he did CBC and it looks like I think he
starts it from THC and then he goes from
THC to CBN and then from CBN to CBC I
believe yeah his his his um I I I've
read every one of his papers I'll have
to admit um I've read several of his
papers several times sometimes I go back
and I read them again just read them
again um I I read his paper so much I
could hear him
speaking as he's as he's writing these
things and it's just the connection that
we have with the chemical literature
which is just fantastic and and I think
like what I always sensed from hash
Church like in the early days when when
uh Horatio said hey Mark you gotta come
on
because because Tony was talking
[ __ ] and he wanted me to set Tony
straight you know he's like ah Tony's
talking T beans man will you come on
hash church and get get this guy
grounded on S so yeah I always knew that
there was so much kind of like interest
kind of hunger from the community that
wanted to know all of this stuff like
that michuan did back in the 60s and
then Adams did back in the 30s man I
mean it is just really to me just
fascinating because I think they knew
the importance of the chemistry that
they were doing I think the thing that
really made Adams's chemistry just kind
of go away was was World War II right I
mean he published like 1 papers in less
than three years between 1939 and 1941
then the World War II happened and they
just kind of forgot about it but you
know mulam I think in his movie talks
about this he tried to write offer NIH
funding in the early 60s to study the
chemistry of the Cannabis plan and the
NIH was like go blow then after he
reported Delta 9
isolated they came over and smuggled the
10 GRS that he had made back back to
Bethesda and did all kinds of secret
government work in the NIH on it where
they came up with Axel Rod's patent you
know on on neuro protection and and and
so like there's this whole secret agenda
that the government had on cannabis
while they were locking up hippies
because Richard Nixon thought that
smoking weed was the end of the United
States you know so you
it even goes back further than that back
to the original reer Madness [ __ ]
but um man where we are today think
about where we are today I mean even in
my lifetime I was born in 62 I know
Sam's got me beat by about 10 years but
you know we even go back just even half
a century to where we are now to where
people are doing research to where I I'm
reading I just read this paper about
MDMA
to treat PTSD I mean it's just it's
[ __ ] amazing right where we are today
in the use of yeah
psychedelics and
canono um and just a great great place
where we are right
now thanks to people like Marcus for
putting hash church and you for putting
4200 together to educate the community
because a rising Tide Rises all Bo
I like to share the information I I like
I like all the different discussions
it's you know for quite a while uh
dragonfly Earth medicine was in the chat
kind of going like [ __ ] putting
chemicals on [ __ ] and like don't no
that's the whole plant is better
medicine and I totally get that
perspective and I'm not like I just find
it super interesting all of this
information and taking apart the plant
and learning about it and uh sort of
expanding our knowledge on I do also see
value in it a for the science Alone um
but also for specific sort of patients
like yeah of course listen if you can
get some beautifully living soil organic
you know fed whole plant medicine or a
an extract through water extraction or
something yeah that's that's amazing but
you know the the example I always use is
that that the profiles change and that
they're hard to reformulate if you don't
do things like this and there are you
know like Haley uh Rose Haley's Comet
which John could speak of as well that
sometimes that would work and then
sometimes it wouldn't work and it would
just change the slightest little bit in
in maybe the grow room variable and now
her medicine no longer worked and her
seizures were super or are super serious
they're not lightweight seizures these
are like you know potential um life uh
ending critical style seizures and so to
be able ble to like find exactly what
works for her and then be able to just
take plants apart maybe multiple plants
to put that profile together make it
accurate and be able to give that to her
like to me I see a value in that and I
think um I get where they're coming from
they're very passionate about that side
and I hope they come in later and share
with us uh about that side but you got
to be careful when you're super
passionate about one side that you're
not making a bunch of assumptions in rep
telling the other side what hash church
has taught me is to be more open like am
I going am I dabbing on distillate right
now like no I'm dabbing on six-star
Bubble has and that's okay but you know
we've we've got to allow the
conversation at least amongst
ourselves to be able to to discuss these
things and that that's that's all I'll
say about
it look I like fresh rainwater straight
from the or maybe straight from the
spring it's beautiful but I also like
pickles and I have to take that water
mix it with Pickles do a process to end
up with those pickles both are great
doesn't mean I sometimes don't want
water and sometimes I want pickle juice
but I had to go through the process that
this fermentation or this salting
process this is this is life this is
what humans do we take things and we
play with it we change it and sometimes
we end up with things like Delta eight
that might be beautiful medicine for a
child getting chemo right like there are
high
use like you said you're never going to
get the Delta eight by growing the most
headiest plant you ever grew I'm a
permaculturist 100% I want all of my
weed that I'm going to consume to come
from dragonfly yes that's great but I
might also take some of that and turn a
little bit into d8 if that means we
can't be friends then so be it but
doesn't mean I'm it's going to stop me
from from doing
it for sure well they're going to come
in later they're just really busy right
now so we're excellent yeah yeah they're
good folks they're the they're the
greatest of folks really they're just uh
I could feel his passion I know also
that their souls are absolutely Ely
being crushed right now by the last
2.7% of our rainforest in British
Columbia our our Elder forests uh are
getting uh cut down right now so they
I'm hoping they're kind of going to come
in as well and give an update on that
because it's uh pretty [ __ ] up
situation that's going on here in BC I
want to talk about that too but okay go
ahead
man so I want to C let's Circle back on
the on the trees too because we have the
same thing happening down here in
Washington absolutely there we go okay
so um let me move trying to there taking
off out of the way yeah I gotta get
going boys it was uh everyone was really
nice to to see you all I'll catch you
guys on on the next show um I gotta I
gota get it ready to fly so take care
col have a beautiful beautiful Sunday
everyone out
brother out brother
yeah so we got right here um says canab
CBG canaberal and they label it as
VII goes to De yeah dehydrogenated with
chlorin uh in Benzene which like you
were talking about
yuck um and then you know they Explain
how and why it ends up converting itself
to canab chromin which they've labeled
as V in a pretty decent yield um
especially since we can now Bol grow CVG
in the field and here is the you can
just see the move here's VII so CBG goes
with chloral in that Benzene soup to V
yeah so let's just talk about chloral
for a second so this is a chlorinated
aromatic that basically makes dioxin
type compounds when it's consumed I
mean again if you're going to make this
in a laboratory it's one thing if you're
to make this for human ingestion got to
be something just completely different
you know the other thing I would worry
about with this kind of thing is that so
this the reason why I pointed this out
Dustin is just as an example here's
literature where you could say okay
there's a method out there that's it
that's all I need to know right so a guy
in a warehouse or in a garage would say
well here's a method what equipment do I
need let's piece it together let's
figure this [ __ ] out he did it so we can
do it I guess the other important thing
and again I I know Colin would agree
with me that one of the big issues I
think is not just necessarily the way
that you're making this but being able
to have the intellectual capacity to
understand that you need to develop a
process for
commercialization run it several times
whenever you run a commercial process I
think Marcus she'd probably agree with
me especially when when it comes to
stuff that's related to cannabis so
there's variables in it that sometimes
subtly change we can't tell with our
naked eye or it takes very
sophisticated looking at you know many
many different properties to be able to
reproduce a process time and time again
to make
the for something that's going to go
into into
people right and and so so not only do
you need the analytical controls but you
need to be able to run that process four
and five times look at the data and see
what kind of spread you get so like in a
process like this where it says I don't
know 95% yield well what if you run it
again and next time it's 98 or what if
you run it next time it's 88 so you're G
to have this constantly moving thing
that you need to be able to standardize
and the thing that I really don't like
about using a stochiometric oxidant like
this is it makes stric waste in this
case it's it's it's
chlorinated hogen halogenated
chlorinated waste chlorinated phenols
are the synthetic precursors to dioxins
so these things if they haven't made
dioxins will go to a landfill and make
dioxins in a landfill this is just not
good not practical would never be scaled
up commercially today
sure ab
and um sorry I gotta Echo think sure um
so yeah this is how we got to delta8
right oh well no we got to Delta eight
on accident but once we realize what we
were doing this is how we progressed
Delta we went into the literature saw
that they were doing crazy things with
crazy uh solvents and acids that most of
us can't even get our hands on see that
that's step one most you know most of
these and and that's changing as these
like our future compounds lab we we now
have access to quite a bit of stuff but
we've never sold any of our
intermediates and never would because
it's not safe it needs a lot of cleanup
there's lots of processes and yes we we
obviously want to use the cheapest
safest solvents and uh acids possible
and that's always where we start and
work in hey Dustin Dustin look look what
he says right here on this p on this
paragraph to the right work done by our
group and others has shown that one
which is Delta 9 can be readily
isomerized to Delta 2 in the presence of
paroline sulfonic acid and nearly
quantitive that's it
it it they're Off to the Races they're a
chemist now right Y and made a chemist
out of a bunch of people by listening to
yep that's there's the secret there's
the big giant secret right there that's
made a lot of people a lot of money in
the last couple years yeah yeah anyway
sorry to keep hijacking the conversation
Market this is not at all man I'm
chatting in the chat
room you guys keep going it's
great yeah and you're you're right about
the the waste products because you can
get you can get all of this to a safe
spot now could you do that you know cost
effectively I don't know but you can you
know wash scrub pass through chroma get
it to an isolated compound you know
like like we take the scel that's at 99
.8% or
99.9% in CBN isolate right there could
have been lots of nasty [ __ ] happening
before that that now is not present in
this right I mean it's not
radioactive besides that at this Purity
you know disregarding the idea that
we're throwing away a bunch of nasty
[ __ ] or or in theory we're throwing a
bunch of nasty [ __ ] we got we actually
have a pretty clean process for this CDN
but right
like some of these like and they go
through you know a lot of this they get
to an isolate point and then are
checking it on NMR that they say that at
the beginning of the of this paper
that's how they've confirmed so they're
getting this stuff to some Ultra Purity
right that that CBC that they made with
this nasty process that they got to
Purity would in theory be safe to
consume right yeah but again to use
chromatography on the laboratory scale
where you're just you know putting a
column together with 60 grams of silica
if you had to do that and make know
several hundred kilos of material it it
would be not only cost prohibitive but I
mean that the the process chemistry and
the equipment that you would need uh
takes a substantial investment of course
but now now in let's just compare it to
pharmaceutical there are certain drugs
that are insanely expensive because the
only way that they can get there well
you know politics aside the only way
they can get there is through that
investment that you said it took so much
money to scale up this entire thing that
when we get this 1% of 1% yield that's
the magical medicine now that may have
gone through a nasty process to get
there
right well yeah I mean when you're
discovering a medicine there's usually a
two phases there's a discovery you do a
lot of Discovery and you try to find new
structures and you make a lot of
different compounds basically assembling
Legos in different ways then when you
find your set of
Lego development so so you find out that
that not only has the biological
activity you're looking for but
hopefully some sort of safety assessment
or safety assessment on the
metabolite this is a pill what's going
to happen inside the body and you look
at a lot of different things when it
comes to safety assessment because again
a drug is not a food ingredient uh but
uh again the pharmaceutical Mantra is to
certainly hook you for life and to make
sure that
you have to take this medicine for the
rest of your life you know I I would
assume that again the the discovery
phase can use all kinds of chemistry to
get there to discover the molecule but
then the most important phase is the
development phase which is where you
take that initial molecule or compound
that's been discovered and now think
about how do we actually make a
manufacturing process to make this and
we're not going to necessar use the
laboratory synthesis to make it because
the laboratory synthesis uses all this
toxic expensive crap that we can't use
on the [ __ ] ton scale and to make this
drug we need to make it on a [ __ ] ton
scale and we can't just create a bunch
of you know for every one pound of
product you create 20 pounds of waste
that doesn't so mark on the when they're
doing that process before they go to the
manufacturing scale they've done their
safety testing right well typic
typically you
do uh initial research