boom
[Music]
hey everybody Welcome to Embark Health
this is the bubble man uh we haven't
really brought you guys in here this is
just one room that we're going to be
going into today room 108. uh this is
our water extraction room it's a little
bit of Chaos in there right now we're
just preparing for the day we've got the
machines getting all set up to the pumps
and to the hoses everything's been
cleaned perfectly yesterday so it's all
just sitting there waiting for us we
have hash that's being prepared and
dried in the freeze dryers that will be
sieving later today and we're gonna go
get 6 000 grams of dried cured black
cherry punch flour and throw it into the
Reactor with a bunch of ice and so I'll
take you guys in here real quick little
tag there
all right so here we go so here's our
Whistler equipment you can see that the
SPX pumps all to be [ __ ] up and dialed
in this is our Whistler Technologies
unit that we'll be filling up today we
got our Bubble Bag lights in the corner
we have our two 32 gallon tanks here
that we'll be putting our bags into
we've got our cleaning tub here and then
we've got a recirc tub back here 65
gallons that Craig's setting up right
now to another pump and that allows us
to remove the water from the 300 liter
get it into here and then pump it
through and create a closed loop the
freeze dryers are of course right here
they're working with yesterday's
material and we'll go through those and
do a final dry in a little bit and then
of course
the coal draft ice machine which is
making our beautiful ice
and you can see this ice is absolutely
perfect perfect
ice
all right
[Music]
okay
let's get going
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
so this process is basically calibrating
the scales
we're going to calibrate the scales with
our weights
that are right here
and this lets us uh just know that the
scales are working properly once they're
calibrated they won't be moved for the
rest of the day
so that's what Uli's doing right now
all right so we're gonna head over to
the Vault and grab the flower that we're
going to run today
the vault's just over here
there's another room
this is where we used to one run water
extraction right here
the bfds are still on the wall
and that's where we used to do that
all right so here we are in one of our
vaults
got a nice big deep freezer right here
and that deep freezer has 6 000 grams of
black cherry punch right here
[Music]
there is generally paperwork that you're
going to be wanting to do
um sorry guys I'm zooming in a bit there
is paperwork that you're going to want
to do with this we've got the paperwork
over here and Craig will come in and do
that after me I'm just grabbing the
flower for now so for those of you that
say Hey That's not how you're supposed
to do that yes we are still doing our
paperwork we are compliant
very very very compliant
so
let's keep going here
get this 6 000 grams back to
our room that we're going to be running
the hash in today
foreign
[Music]
we made it back
it's a six kilos of black cherry punch
we're gonna open these bags and get them
into the reactor all right here you can
see the quality of what we're working
with
[Music]
nice Frosty crisply
nugget it's very consistent in every bag
great nose really nice bouquet on this
flower
we're gonna dump it into the reactor
so
six bags of that we usually give them a
little rinse
lots of trichomes stuck in the bag
although I think it turned the water off
go back to that once we look
a little bit got stuck in there
[Music]
[Applause]
to get it even
when the weed is dry especially it's
good to get the ice on top and pushing
it down to soak
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
so the ice and the material has soaked
because it's dry material we let it soak
for a little bit we'll also start the
impeller mixing at a lower rate
fire like up to 25 Maybe
[Music]
a little bit higher
you want to get the ice on the outside
moving it's still not quite moving we're
going out
walls
do you want that
to zero degree
so we're doing a little Reserve here
with Julie and Dan
filtering through the two 190s we've got
the agitator going
pump number two is pumping everything
out of these containers back into the
reactor and the reactor has pump number
one which is fully pump right here and
he's filling up the bags with hash so
the hash will be filtered through the
screens
then the water will come out from the
bottom and go back into the reactor and
that's called a reserve we do this for
well a little bit and then we'll do our
pull really soon here
just pulling the 190 a little patch bag
for catching the contaminants
and so see that I don't want to get too
close to the water okay there's the 190
so that's the lowest grade this is
really just used to catch everything we
don't want yet it will still probably be
around 50 THC so it could still be used
for plant fat extractions or any type of
uh
uh solventless extraction if you so
choose
well we want to rinse and clean out
their hash still too though right so
this is the job we're doing for a
company that wants just the 45 through
160 they don't want the 190 or anything
above 160 and anything below uh 45 so
this is why you're seeing only two bags
get pulled here
and we'll see a nice big pile of 45 here
for sure
[Music]
I'll lift it up a little bit
that's a nice big Vlog in there
there you go there we go
oh that's right there I got this side up
pretty good
all right that's probably good for the
pre-wash there hasn't really I want to
keep as much as we can in this bag okay
and when you're lifting it you just want
it yeah
what I would suggest is like if ULU
pulls it a little higher for you okay
right so Pull It On All directions like
not like that but like this
getting it pulled up the bottom is
coming up and then you want to use this
and just sort of move the hash around
there's a ton of hash in here
and it'll eventually we'll clean this
last little bit up after because if you
keep putting water in see how the the
there you go that's what I want to see I
want to see the the the
sanding there we go turns into the sand
muck this big chunks of hash in here
dude
once I get it you see it how it's like
slowly but surely turning into hash
turning into like an oatmeal on the
water yeah thick oatmeal yeah now you
can do your squeeze
keep it even like don't flip it all the
way over this side like this is a huge
huge ball and just squeeze the [ __ ] out
of it we're gonna get uh
water out of it the more water we get
out the faster our freeze dry time is
yeah just squeeze that ball get that
excess water out a lot of people call
this bruising the fruits
it's just not so resin strong stronger
than you might think even dump this
water
[Music]
you want to go get your tray yeah you
can put that back in there
perfect and then lift it out and we'll
you can scoop the hash onto the tray
form
or you could just pick it up with your
hands
like this maybe you need to slip
it for sure cut it in half with the
spoon
while we're holding it and we'll just
put it boom boom even for one tree are
you sure it's not a little bit well we
can bring it over and you can put half
on another tray but okay in the meantime
let me get another one sure yeah so now
you can use the hose again to get
ourselves nice and adjusted look at this
craggy
have we have we pulled a bowl that big
ever
that is a big hole bro
[Laughter]
and then this part you can pull out a
little wet
you can just agitate it with your spoon
and then stir it together and
yeah turn it so I mean and remember some
of it gets actually and also washed into
uh the next bag so so you don't have to
clean it perfectly we'll rinse this bag
inside the next 45. this is only 145 we
pull
you can see right here the pressure
around the uh gasket is very tight and
that'll get thinner and thinner and
thinner until it disappears
scroll pumps for the wind no oil scroll
pumps for the wing all right pull right
out
nice big fat tray
actually
good
all right
thank you
a dry one
Perfect Two Grands
[Music]
maintaining the balance with Pleasure
and Pain
[Music]
s
your life
[Music]
found the train s