all right let's get ready here for the
live stream says we're streaming now so
I'm going to let in the
folks let's see meeting is now streaming
on YouTube let's invite these people
in boom boom boom and what I'd like to
say is welcome everyone to Hash Church
3.0 live episode oh let me shut my own
mic off
here episode 14 is what I wanted to say
before I got that shut off I just have
to take the live link real
quick uh if my computer wants to let me
I will copy and paste that into the old
link so everyone knows where we are here
we go do a couple of those and wonderful
welcome everybody Welcome Wade and eten
and Mr Skunk Man Sam quick on it this
morning are you good morg I can't hear
is it me can everyone hear it
can you hear me can you hear me now yes
yes yes yes more troubleshooting for the
bubble man oh man all right yeah it's
been a fun morning of it I suspect it's
me so let me just get my video settings
sorted up here and get my audio settings
changed I hear you now a lima charlie
all right lima lima charlie welcome
welcome
guys let's make sure all is well here
it's h it's a lot to do when you're
trying to kind of to do the
troubleshooting welcome everyone into
the room get it recording on YouTube get
it recording on my computer so I can put
it onto a
podcast I'm just happy my computer
keyboard is working because at 8:45 this
morning it was
not so ended up jumping in the car
driving down to the Lion's Bay store and
getting some doublea batteries I think I
probably paid $97 for two of them but
that's okay as long as we're here and
we're up and running so
that's it let's see what we got going on
in the room yeah welcome Wade how are
you doing this morning I'm good I'm good
I had a uh been doing lots of work at
the computer this year already and on uh
Friday and Saturday I made time to go
outside and work on the farm a yeah no
that got my hands dirty got broke a
sweat it was good sure didn't feel like
January though that's what what's up
yeah that's that West Coast living
January doesn't always feel like January
on the west coast
mhm we've been getting a bit of that
ourselves doing pretty good you know
we've uh my company made some pretty
monstrous uh announcements recently we
got a couple of provinces signed up for
embark to order our products so that's
like that's like not a company that's a
province that would be like hooking up a
state like oh I've got I've got you
California now or I've got Washington
now so we we signed up both El and
British Columbia so we're excited about
that and those announcements were made
on all my social
[Music]
medias yes bong rip to bubbleman's
keyboard says Fe raw medic we got over a
100 people in the room right now 166
actually watching at 903 a.m. and I'm
hoping all the email invitation folks
aren't thinking that we're not going
because I did have
um I did have a little bit of troubles
this
morning we'll see if they're all getting
the email to come
in oh yeah I sent it to them for sure
and you would have gotten that email
again as well wait so you're good to go
I did I saw it couple of minutes before
9ine you you're coughing quite a bit
this morning are you all right oh I just
woke up and rolled out of bed and it's
my first joint so uh yeah it's a little
cold here in the Bas so yeah there's a
little congestion in the air it's just a
little bit of normal but uh no no no
just my morning coffee good
deal excellent how you doing Johnny
B arms up Johnny be's got the arms up
I'm always good it's a good
morning excellent get the dab in and I I
got this new little tool called the
terpometer have you seen this
thing I'm going to uh I have yeah Mike
West has been using one of those for a
couple of years I was using one just the
other day in fact I got one for a
Christmas present from the great
neighbors and I got it like I guess of
course the mail came late but I mean
cold starting and then I got this thing
woohoo 642 dude I'm in the other boat
Johnny I've been using temptech pretty
religiously but now I'm just cold
starting because I find that when I
forget my temp teac I'm too annoyed I'm
like oh man I'm not going to get that
perfect dab and this that and the other
thing and they definitely are different
rips to heat your Banger up to like that
900 Degrees let it settle down and drop
that dab in is very different from a
cold start but cold start like you know
anything you can get the skills going
and towards you know I've been doing it
for the last three or four days and uh
I'm sure I'll end up going back to my
Temp Tech eventually but it's nice that
we have these options back and forth we
go back and forth tried the have you
tried the new uh puffco Peak I did try
the new puffco Peak and I was impressed
you're very quiet Again Sam we got to
get you a little bit louder but yeah the
puffco peak the new one I guess it's the
puffco peak Pro is that correct yeah
that thing rips that thing like rips and
and don't get me wrong I also tried the
sort of middle version because you had
the puffco then you had companies create
um a kit for the puffco with a different
um heater a different coil all you know
different pieces that you could put in
that increased the quality of the puffco
but now puffco Pro is released and uh
yeah it's uh I was impressed with it
anyway I don't own one but uh it
surprised
me yeah I I may try i' I burned through
Four puffco Peaks so I kind of gave up
on that instant you know cuz I hear
people all the time I I uh I don't know
if you've heard of Clubhouse but it's a
new social media platform with live
discussions and a lot of people get on
there and they start talking about their
puffco peaks but you know I'll still
stick with my Mothership and my Dil
thanks that actually still works so
well I really like the puffco peak Pro
it's one of my chist I I put this thing
through the paces and tried to find what
could possibly be wrong with it and the
atomizer alone is such an improvement um
and the temperatures like you can
actually use like full melt in this
device and get it to the right
temperature um and then you can actually
hit plus 10 degrees if you start really
really low you can kind of bump up 10
plus degrees at a time um it's really
cool and then I got this little kind of
recycler for it which is really great I
mean it's puffco kind of nailed it with
this one in a way that um I was not
expecting um it's much better build
quality to me the most amazing thing
about the puffco uh Peak Pro was
actually that it with your iPhone or any
other smartphone you can program the
temperature so that a single hit starts
low and end High
exactly yep another great part that's
like a that's like a cold start right
you get you hit hit it a little bit you
get some of those turps you hit it a
little hotter little bit more you
increase the temperature that's uh
that's how the Trinity pen was designed
the Trinity pen was designed that if you
hold that button down for a little bit
you'll get that 500 degree low temp dab
you hold it down like a second full
cycle you're getting up to a 6650 dab
and if you did it four times you could
literally get your Johnny B like 800
fahrenheit hot red nail
RIP
just I was going to say I like I like
the third hit when I do the cold start
and hit it with the the torch again and
heat it up and C of course of course you
do you're
like you're the anomaly Johnny Be you
want that hot
rip I it's what works for me it's and
it's only at certain times because a lot
of times in the morning I really like
that turpy like cold start that's why I
like this tpom meter I like those
flavors in the morning but as the day
progresses I guess that that harder hit
is what hits me harder so the morning
those flavors wakes you up you're
feeling more energetic and as the day
progresses if it got some good pain then
of course I hit it hot and hey I'm right
back at it right there you go hey
welcome uh welcome best friend Farms is
in the
house oh he's just connecting his audio
I'm already like welcoming him when he's
not even like fully in but uh yeah we
got him hanging out I think I'm about to
do a little dab I was a little bit
nervous this morning I haven't felt that
energy for a while where I'm like am I
going to fail at this am I going to like
be not able to do this it was very
strange to not have my keyboard hook up
to my C computer that's never that's
never happened to me before so the joys
of Technology oh bro it's so true it's
so true just ridiculous yet on the same
flip side the joys of Technology the
very thing that allows us to get
together during these times of covid and
share our faces and our sort of
emotional contacts and our our words
together with all these different people
that are watching online I'm sure we
have uh gez I don't even know how many
we got in there right now but I'm sure
it's a couple
hundred hey at least at least it's not
Google meetups
anymore oh my God I know that whole
Google Hangouts thing was like not good
that was fun honly remember being in
India you would have to book a phone
call to a 24 hours 48 hours of Advance
okay then you make your phone call and
it's screechy screechy
screechy oh my God I thought of you this
this week Marcus the Kum kumal uh
your in India has happening right
exactly wow I was there in
1998 so it'll be
um yeah that'll be some years ago now
holy smokes
uh I would advise anyone who wants to go
check out the Kumba in India to go check
it out it's definitely a neat reason to
have you know if you're going to India
it's a it's a good spot to kind of have
On Your Horizon it doesn't really affect
your rest of your traveling you can
obviously continue on from wherever it
is I don't know if it's in alabad jaur
varasi or haridwar but I'm sure it's
going to be in one of those four spots
because it has been uh for the last like
uh I don't know 4,000 years years or
however many thousands of years they've
been doing this
thing pretty cool pretty cool definitely
one of my eye openers amazing experience
for me smoking G uh smoking hash on the
on the ganes with the Babas out of the
Chillum and he would every day he must
have said this I mean honestly this man
was like skunkman Sam in a in a sadu all
he said was one more Chillum we are
making one more Chillum we are making
and that's kind of reminiscent of
hanging out with Sam one more bong load
we are packing one more bong load we are
packing best friend Farms is going to
make another attempt to joining us I
guess he's uh also having maybe some
technical difficulties sometimes it
happens I can see he's trying to connect
his audio now we'll see how it goes
we'll see how it goes so on the news
they uh for the Kumba they uh they had a
sadu that seemed to be rolling in front
of procession the entire oh the rolling
the rolling sadu yeah there was one guy
and I met him at the Maha kumaa he had
rolled from the northern tip of India to
the southern tip of
India he he just rolled and you meet
people like this at the Kumba I met
another guy who was holding his arm up
for 12 years it had turned into a stone
and you could hang like heavy things off
of it because it was not like you you
couldn't bend this guy's arm it had
turned into a stone another guy had held
his hand closed for I don't even know
how long it was but his nails were
growing out the top of his hand from him
holding his hand in a fist he just had
Nails coming out of his hand and there
was a guy standing on one leg as well
and he had been standing on one leg I
want to say for at least a decade uh
just he had this kind of thing set up to
hold his leg up his leg was also a stone
uh it wasn't moving anymore if you
looked at it closely you were like oo
that doesn't look good definitely a trip
to just you know you know do things that
the mind tells you are impossible that's
the one thing I would say I had in
common that kept reoccurring itself with
my trip to India was that um I get I
just kept witnessing the impossible
things that I my North American brain
didn't believe could could happen maybe
also was wondering why you would want
that to happen but at the same time that
sort of you know just doing of this
strange thing to REM almost to remove
your Consciousness from your body cuz
got to imagine the amount of pain that
that would have after a while when that
limb was entropy and just dying and just
slowly you know not working anymore
definitely a trip not something oh what
Mark's Mark's saying he didn't get the
the zoom link
again that is so strange to me he's in
the chat with us and he's everyone else
gets it they all click on the link and
they come in but Mark is not getting the
link and I really don't know why that is
and even more important guess what my
keyboard has disconnected from
my oh no oh yeah oh yeah oh yeah I got a
mouse I got a mouse I might be able to
do it with a mouse let's see let's
see oh look at that I could do it with
the mouse that is funny though that my
keyboard has done that
again might be an update you need to put
in need to do a b might be might be a
new new keyboard for for Mark coming in
here in the near future let's let's hope
we don't disconnect and that the mouse
will do everything that we need because
these are brand new batteries for this
keyboard anyway I just sent the the link
I feel that that's happening lately and
I'm not sure why like how could Mark be
in a group chat with all of us and not
get the link to the show whereas
everyone else clicked on the very same
link I sent to the very same chat room I
don't like that I'll tell you it took me
it took me a couple of minutes to sort
out because there was a thread of emails
and in the initial the first email that
you meant that you sent saying that you
wanted to do a church this morning is
the one that has the link in it and all
the subsequent emails did not have it so
you got to go back to that first one and
open it all the way open and there it is
the Z the zoom link that's what I Marcus
you know you know what it is Marcus it's
the DEA and the dark cannabis web are
trying to Mark away from our knowledge
that's what it is it's the science it's
the anti-science mafia once again just
doing it ah come on hash church we got
to get these anti-h churches you know
what's funny is that 20 years ago we
would have been all over that [ __ ] and
it would have been for sure our belief
and it probably would have been also
true so it's not too far uh of a reality
that we've kind of come out of here but
now we got Dr Mark joining I think my
keyboard's set back up I think
everything is going as it
should must be
a must be a plot it's a
conspiracy uh I don't see him though I
don't see do oh he's trying to join and
what about best friend Farms are you in
the house now are you like here and we
can hear
you he's muted but he's here oh [ __ ]
what up Brian
and see the the dark cannabis
St oh my goodness all right I think
we're dealing with our technical
difficulties we're doing good man I'm
glad glad you made I don't know Mark it
makes no sense I'm sending links to
group chats that you're in and the other
people in the group chat are clicking on
the link and coming in and then you're
like I'm not getting the chat
so there's a couple Mark Sheldon so just
make sure it's me you might be Facebook
friends with the other
right oh that would be weird that's
something there's a mark sheldone
attorney there's a mark sheldone fire
chief a beverage guy a few oh yeah send
invites to all them guys there's another
one that's real
one hey I found another ATN Fontan in
France so it's
possible I got 16 Johnny bees okay 16 if
you punch in Mark Richardson into
Facebook there definitely comes up about
like three or 400 uh black guys and so I
I guess my name is more of a black guy
name than it is a white guy name at
least according to Facebook which uh I'm
pretty good
with and we're all for a maper that's
what I heard that's what I heard that's
what they told
me that's what they told me so yeah just
a nice chill Sunday you know I've been
kind of like regardless of whether or
not we have a plan or a disc
or something really juicy to talk about
I thought you know what people have
really been digging the consistency of
the last two or 3 weeks of us kind of
joining we don't have to commit to four
hours every day but if it comes and it
happens and a natural conversation seems
to uh develop like it usually does um
well then so be it and first off I want
to shout out gez how do I shout out Rob
his his name is like gizer gizer forever
whatever one he's on Instagram he is the
dude that took the I guess Snapple um
advertisement that we've jacked turned
it into the all natural hashish made
from the best stuff on Earth and that is
the avatar for the hash Church show
today so I wanted to give him a shout
out because I had just found it on
Instagram and you know just posted it
and said to anyone hey please if you
know who devel who created this please
uh you know let me know so I can give
them a shout out and it ended up being a
good friend of mine from out east so
shout out to you giz out wherever you
are uh I know you're smoking that hash
he's also responsible for the hre a m um
you know hash rules everything around me
um sort of shirts and and Graphics the
the free I know Brian knows what that's
all about he's definitely like oh yeah I
know that's awesome you know what we
should do sometime we should all find
our person who has our exact same name
and have them all appear in hash church
together all confused
dude epic confusion dude that's some
April 1 [ __ ] right
there I mean my
God so funny people be like what are who
are all these people with like all the
people's
names like who are these people you have
seven black guys instead of you
absolutely dude trust me I've like spoke
to a few of them on Facebook we're good
to go we're lined
up we are lined
up it's funny to bring them in so we're
glad to have you here Mark uh that was a
little bit scary that you weren't going
to make it in we always appreciate your
uh perspective here in hash church and
gez without you talking my goodness
that's uh that's half a show right
there it's great to be back I I always
check in with the chat in the morning
usually over my coffee and dab in the
morning and I'll look to see who's on
chat and you know usually it's John
Maddox and bingo Lombardi yep and 70s
mama will be in there every once in a
while and it's just again this this
thing that happens that's independent to
the show itself but just this Gathering
of people and again just to not go back
to the Grateful Dead thing but it's kind
of like before the conert people sort of
wanding towards the venue it's getting
ready for the show it's these these
people who are in line who are are here
for the show but they're psyched to be
getting ready for the show getting ready
for the show is sometimes more fun than
the show itself well it takes a lot
longer when you're traveling from like
the center of Canada and driving to some
venue on the east coast and you had to
get tickets and you had to cross a
border and you had to like break down
and get pulled over by cops and almost
busted and then you got ripped off but
then you got good weed and then you
ended up at the concert venue but you
had a flat tire but then you found some
grilled cheeses you ate some mushrooms
he ended up in the venue the [ __ ]
show was killer and uh let's do it all
over again tomorrow
yeah you you know I don't know if you
listen Mark but uh every day on The
Grateful Dead XM channel there's uh
today in Grateful Dead history and and
the archist is my friend David Lemieux
who is uh a fellow Canadian from BC in
fact he lives not too far from where
you're at Marcus he's really cool guy he
fishes but he's he's like he's really
into again just keeping the archive of
the Greatful Dead and he's on every day
and so for those of us who listen to the
XM channel we listen to Grateful Dead
stories from him every day and he's
always got that whole you know thing
about how to cross the border how to
navigate the border and go to these you
know Ultra psychedelic crazy events and
still come back to society and
reassimilate back to Canada you know
yeah I've listened to to him as well I
love his stories and uh those those are
they're just yeah they're they're
classic and they're great because we
relate to them you know the easiest I
ever got over the Border here in British
Columbia by far cuz I've been trying and
trying and trying and just constantly
getting denied but when fish came up and
I can't remember if it was like 96 or
seven or eight but one of those years I
was just like I was at the show I was
like kind of tripping and it was just
like everyone was like all right man
we're going you know it's like we got to
go back we got to go Portland's tomorrow
you know like I'm like all right well
you know what I'm [ __ ] coming and I
just got in my car and drove with this
procession of freaks and at the time I
looked really like the least amount of a
freak and I was in a brand new rent a
car so I'm I want to tell you I got
through there so quick every single
person that was at that show that was
wearing patchwor clothes and dreaded out
and like just super flying their freak
flag they were all pulled over when I
drove through I could see them all
getting torn apart by their Vans none of
them cared because they're all Americans
anyway and they can't be denied into
their country but I'm the Canadian and I
can be denied into the country I don't
really care about being denied into
America other than the fact that I
really want to see the show tomorrow in
Portland you know from the actual venue
not from
someone's uh recording like a month
later
so that's what it's up for me
unnecessary the whole [ __ ] border
hold down is just such a bunch of
[ __ ] man it's just it is it's a it's
a bummer for sure it's definitely a
bummer for us to have between our two
countries we were talking about it the
other day how great a country from like
the tip of Alaska you know maybe down to
like Guatemala or Venezuela or something
just have a west coast country we've all
dreamed about it in the past no borders
you know get Elon to build some crazy
tubes that just we can blast down there
in like four hours or whatever going 600
miles an hour that would be pretty sweet
but uh you know we got what got got to
do got to got to do the best we can with
what we have and uh it doesn't stop us
from dreaming because uh had we not been
dreaming all these years I'm certain
that my company wouldn't have been
signing uh contracts with provinces for
hash uh Supply and I'm sure that etan
wouldn't still be doing what he's been
doing for the last uh you know 20 to 30
years and and many others so clearly the
things that we've congratulations on
that markk I know that that's no easy
feat and being able to you know get your
product into the you know uh masses uh
you know or at least having that ability
to grow that market share is just an
unbelievable opportunity but remember
what they always say be careful what you
wish for now a lot of people need your
hash and it's like wow I mean when you
scale up production to say one to say
like multiple kilograms it's one thing
but when you're now doing that at
hundreds of kilograms that is just
yeah that's off to you I mean and a
responsibility like you said it's a
responsibility it's not just about
supplying one time it's about supplying
and then consistently supplying and
making sure that you're taking care of
both your medical patients and your
wreck Market because I do see you know
some difficulties in having both of
those markets I see a lot of companies
kind of go
like just right right to wreck Med can
be difficult you have to deal with
patients there's all these other things
and I feel like I I don't like the idea
of the med patients getting the short
end of the stick on all of that so it's
definitely a discussion and it's
something that we're going to pay
attention to we want to make sure that
uh that everyone has access GMP
compliant Mark like is it is it going to
be GMP compliant if it's not there it
looks GMP compant eventually absolutely
eventually we've got GMP um Consultants
that we speak with on the regular and uh
it's definitely you know gmp's serious
business it's great to get into to that
pharmaceutical market and into you know
markets like Germany and and parts of of
Europe like that but at the same time
you know you want to talk about needing
a Runway to create a GMP facility the
costs are so over the top they're
already over the top with our you know I
don't want to say over regulated
industry but it is it is very regulated
I think we look at it as way over
regulated because of how underregulation
our food and our water and our air tends
to be people are just so it's so easy to
poison either of those three things and
you can profit off that poisoning
substantially and so people in the
Cannabis industry are kind of like why
do we have to be so regulated and it's
kind of like you know what don't worry
about it it's good for the patience on
that sense we don't need to be over
regulated from the perspective of
packaging and all that [ __ ] but when
it comes to the over regulations of
certificate of analysis making sure we
test being extremely extremely sensitive
about what if any pesticides are ondes
are are being allowed and all of that
sort of thing I love the sort of over
regulated uh that side of it I dislike
the over regulated aspect of you know
some of the rest of it that comes into
play where you just get painted into
these corners and you just got to you
know do your best to uh to to to get out
of those corners and uh you know to
create this thing that has not been yet
created it's it's just still scaling up
it's just still happening so I would
like to tip my hat off truly to all the
companies uh both in the US and Canada
that have managed to get products to the
market it really is a long and Winding
Road um but it's worthwhile sticking to
it Marcus could I ask a question so when
you're when you're using all that water
are are you are you recovering anything
from your water because I would assume
Again part of your GMP would be to try
to you know again standardize a process
to make sure that you're getting
everything that you need to get and I
would also just think from a a sanitary
point of view sending hashw water down
the sink may not be the most you know
best you know route for its sanitation
so is what what can you comment on like
the discharge of your water well we're
definitely looking at it you know we're
building a quiver as you know so the
whole purpose of Embark was to build a
quiver so when I when I started the
company with my partners part of me was
wanting to stick with my ego and like
you know what I'm the solventless guy
and that's what we're going to this is
going to be all about bubble and that's
what we're going to do because that's
all I've been doing and I I sort of
thought of these different conversations
I've had I think of my relationship with
Dr Mark I think of my relationship with
Mike West some of my you know chemist
friends that understand that it's just
chemistry and it's just molecules and
chemicals are everywhere and everything
and that sort of helped me to the point
where it was like you know what if we're
going to build this company I don't mind
having a big solventless division but I
really believe the quiver is going to be
important important and it comes into
importance with your question when you
start deciding look how are you going to
recover the say the tpin or the phenols
out of your Waters uh after you've
washed it is there anything that you can
do for that if you've got a solventless
setup that's going to be a little bit
more difficult but if you've got a seven
modalities of extraction you've got CO2
and hydrocarbons and ethanol and dual
solvents and turpine extraction and salt
uh dry sift rosin and bubble hash now
you have these alties that you would
require so we are setting things up so
certain things that happen in the
solventless room that we don't want to
just discharge out can be saved and
eventually go over to that other uh you
know side of things so things like
pressing raws and bags things like you
know not wanting to put the 220 into
your uh final product but it's 40% or
30% you know it's it's contaminated but
it still has resin in it you know the
cut the client doesn't want it mied into
their A or B grade but we don't want to
throw it out so all of these little
things we're definitely thinking
consciously and uh we definitely don't
want to be just tossing things away
unnecessarily because we understand the
value of the plant so we're working on
it is the best answer I can give you and
I'll I'll explain my answers with Embark
um like I did on my live show yesterday
because we're going to go public
eventually because I'm a Founder because
I'm a deep part of this uh company and
because we're so regulated in Canada I
have to be very careful with what I say
and don't say and my problem is I don't
know really what I can't say and so I've
always been so transparent and so open
with everything you know my partners are
like don't like please just like be
careful and so obviously I don't want to
put um my company at risk or my license
at risk but we are making way to become
more and more transparent without
putting our license at risk so that's
all I'll say about that but
congratulations to the whole team at
Embark uh they have been kicking ass
taking names and kicking ass Mar Marcus
a great trick that I have found is you
take a lawyer and then you transplant
them into your hip so that everywhere
you go you have somebody who's making
sure you're safe so I might go for a
lawyer hip transplant for your own
protection for embark is what I'm
suggesting you know dude I know that's
like funny but I'm seriously considering
it
well it is funny but it is side of not
saying anything you know it's difficult
especially when you have an online you
know show like hash church and and you
know people know you as being such a
great resource for information and it's
it's difficult to say no I've had to do
that too Marcus it's like impossible
because because the the the the
community is so hungry for information
you know and and and they'll come you
with such passion and want to know
everything and you can't always divulge
everything because part of the value
you're capturing for for embark is for
yeah a a group of investors who well
that's just it opportunity and you give
away so much that you really create a
level and I mean I've had this happen
with my own friends that where they
become so entitled because I've been
giving them so much that they now
actually expect for me to give them
certain things and it's had it's I've
had difficulties with friendships forget
about like complete and total strangers
with just an entitlement that says you
need to to to show me this or to tell me
this and I'm like listen like please
understand my position like try to have
empathy for me I'm not evil I'm not
trying to keep things from people but my
goodness if you're truly my friend you
would have an understanding of where I'm
coming from and understand that it's not
to keep things you know it's that I'm
I've I've created a situation for myself
myself and now it's my my responsibility
to navigate
it well and know that whatever it is
shared on hash Church uh is patented by
Sam already well that's it he's got the
pen and paper there and he's just
patenting away it's wonderful I did see
recently that next Leaf released a
patent for water extraction and I'm very
excited to see what is going to go on
with that talk about previously
published art there's already been a
patent that's existed for from Reinhardt
Delp from 1997 till 1990 or 2018 I
believe his patent fin number do you
have the patent number you could share
with me um I could find it for you real
soon by just punching in next Leaf so
for everybody out there you know like a
lot of people have been asking me about
patents because I got a couple and you
always have to look at the most the key
thing in the patent always look at claim
number
one claim number one claim number one is
what they're claiming that's usually
like their main thing and if you look
and if you can figure out a way around
claim one well and it's probably not
going to hold up and there's still no
precedent in the United States for uh
cannabis space patents to hold up in an
infringement case against it so there's
still a lot of questions about whether
or not you want to patent anything at
all you know why
would a lawsuit now right between GW
Pharmaceutical and canopy I think right
I think I think I heard about this on
the the biscon thing but if if memory
serves me correctly people have been
using CO2 extraction for Botanicals for
for for a long time so where is the
invention on using it for cannabis I I
don't know well someone patented someone
patented it a long time ago Mike West
was the one telling me about this and he
sold it for
$10 and 1% and canopy bought that patent
by buying a bunch of companies up that
happen to hold that CO2 patent and like
anything I think most people were just
cuz it was patented a while ago it's an
older patent and so I guess you know
people were like well it's there's no
value to that and then canopy bought it
and kind of some lawyer probably saw it
in their portfolio and was like holy
[ __ ] like I let's look into this and
yeah I wish Mike West was around he has
a little bit more information am I
missing something there are companies
that sell CO2 extraction machines I all
kinds of people out there doing CO2
extraction how is well think of think of
how many people to one company think of
how many people were making bub saying
using water to make coffee is
proprietary to Mr coffee or something
agreed I'm 100% in agree and I I felt
like it the first time around when I was
in my lawsuit with Reinhardt Delp and
found myself for 5 years in a lawsuit
because I was selling Bubble Bags
teaching people how to make water hash
and here's this guy saying well I
patented that in
1997 before I showed Mila you know which
I guess Mila maybe didn't know because
she showed the process to Mark Rose and
Elden a couple of days later and they
were sitting there looking at it and
Elden was like two five gallon shaped uh
nylon bags with screen bottoms and
you've got the same thing Mark Rose is
sitting there call going it's the it's
the isolator it's using ice to isolate
it's the ice o lator he named the
product he manufactured the product
Elden invented the product Mila sold the
product and that's really was the
beginning of Reinhardt Delp you know
kind of losing control of his of his
market cap I came along tried to sell
isolator bags it didn't work out so we
made our own with extra bags and extra
screens and that became bubble bags and
that's how I ended up in a nice little
fiveyear lawsuit with Reinhardt Delp
happily paid him figures out which I was
very happy to do because that was the
honest right thing to do Mila was kind
of trying to portray that she was the
one that got screwed in reality it was
Reinhardt Delp who got screwed uh and I
made sure that he got paid for that uh
and that I paid for him for royalties
for the entire time my company was alive
from 1999 right off into the future so I
felt pretty good about that but it is
interesting how the history can be
Rewritten for a very long time nobody
knew Reinhardt was involved whatsoever
they just thought of me as a guy that
came along and stole the isolator idea I
would also like to say that I took care
of Elden by giving him free tickets to
the legends of hash parties and I
also took on Mark Rose as my
manufacturer the very same guy who named
isolator bags and and manufactured them
he ended up hitting me up a couple years
later because I guess Mila decided to
get Turkish immigrants to make the bags
instead of the Nepali people that were
doing it in Nepal with Mark R he felt a
little screwed that pushed him over to
my camp and we've been working happily
ever since for about 20 plus years so
there's a little history of water
extraction for you right there maybe
there'll be new history 20 years from
now with people like next leaf and their
patents I don't know how it plays out
Mark but I'll tell you patent court is
terrifying you think that it's going to
play out one way but it never does and
the judge can lean any way he wants and
you can still end up burning hundreds of
thousands of dollars in the courts you
know with the case over years so my
advice is that companies get together
they work things out uh don't bring
lawyers into it because they are the
ones that will they're the ones that
will take your money and uh they're
they're almost like secret Partners on
both sides of the table they want to be
difficult back and forth because that's
where they make their money
unfortunately also that only only last
for 20 years and then uh you have no
protection exactly well well said Sam
that is a big big big big deal and it's
uh it's something that I don't think a
lot of people pay attention to now I'm
certain there is methodologies maybe Dr
Mark knows where you can extend patents
by filing paperwork and doing certain
things depending on the situation I
could be wrong but yeah yeah so what
what happens is is when you file a
patent sometimes you file very very
broadly and when the patent office gets
it they basically divide it into what
are called divisional patents and those
patents are individually prosecuted and
will grant individually so like for
example like with the hydrogenation they
recognize that there were multiple
inventions there there was the process
there was the composition there was the
you know a a method to control tumor
growth there's various claims that you
could
make and each of those claims in and of
itself can become its own issued patent
and so as certain claims are easy to get
because there's no prior art like
composition of matter hhca for example
there was no hhca until we disclosed it
so that was an easy you know patn to get
it was an easy to get that one but other
things were we had hhca combination with
other canabo well the other canono were
known so now you're talking about having
to evaluate the prior art which is
relevant here versus not relevant in the
other easy to get cases so you're easy
to get cases or they're the first cases
that are going to issue but then what
you do is you file what's called a
continuation in part and the
continuation in part is still the
original patent date when you originally
filed and you're just basically adding
claims onto that patent without changing
the body or the description of the
patent you could add additional claims
and keep on getting those as continued
issued that basically extends the
lifetime because every time you get an
issued patent that's another 20 years 20
years 20 years 20 years 20 years right I
don't know why we don't respect sorry go
ahead no I was just gonna stop by just
saying in the Cannabis industry it's
likely that you know a lot of the you
know sort of secret things that are done
can be can be the form of intellectual
property rather than a patent would be
something called a trade secret so a
trade secret is kind of like the recipe
to make Coca-Cola right the six
ingredients to Coca-Cola are printed on
the side of Coca-Cola can right so
everyone sees what the ingredients are
the whole Magic is is the recipe and how
to make it right so that's usually like
most of like like if you're taking
proprietary genetics and doing some type
of you know either a solventless
extraction or solvent based extraction
but making a particular like a live
resin or a or a particular product that
could be made reproducibly time and time
again and Mark you know the whole
premise of
GMP good manufacturing practices is
being able to do something consistently
time and time again and when I say
consistently again with cannabis things
change so you have to basically set an
error bar or an understand a tolerance
of what your product specifications are
so if it has this much much mercine it
meets specification but if there's not
mercing it doesn't meet specifications
right and it could go on to basically be
another product turn that stuff into
distillate or something but you know GMP
is is again it's in all the other
Industries for food ingredients for the
ingredients that we use in our medicines
for the ingredients we use in the
cosmetics and personal care product
Industries so these are all the adjacent
industries that were basically already
using good manufacturing practices now
this will spill over into the Cannabis
industry and it's just really good to
see because again when you're doing
small scale hash production you could
see the nuances of how this thing could
come out very very different even on a
small scale so imagine now committing
you know hundreds of thousands of grams
or liters now you're talking about you
know a lot of material being processed
at any one
particular time oh trust me I know it
well it's terrifying there's very very
small numbers like if you get a skew
it's got to be between this percentage
of of THC they're not thank God they're
not doing it with Tarpin yet like oh you
don't have enough mercy and that fails
it's like but if you put something into
your skew that falls below or goes above
your THC percentage you know you you
can't sell it under that skew anymore
you'd have to either make a new skew or
you'd have to have another skew you made
that it fits into or and so you have to
do all of these these different things
it's definitely a very complex system
but at the same time this is all we
wanted for the longest time stop
segregating us let us assimilate into
society let cannabis be a part of the
world and a big part of that this is
what comes along with it like of course
if it's going to be a big part of the
world and it's not going to be
segregated into the closet anymore well
then it's going to be like everything
else in the world and it's going to fall
into all of those other sort of you know
modalities which is like yeah we have to
do this properly it has to be like I
know you've been doing this for 30 years
and it's been fine and safe but it's
like we do this for your medicine we do
this for your food and um we're going to
do it with with cannabis as well so
thank goodness that we'll never you know
for me as long as they never take away
the ability for us to grow
recreationally and grow medically so
anyone that wants to put the time and
the energy can still access cannabis and
the resins exactly the way they want but
on the flip side for the other 80 plus
per of the population and it's probably
higher they should be able to go and buy
it like they do their milk and their
pasta and anything else and when they
buy that they should be insured that
it's been created safely and that it's
not going to have a bunch of a bunch of
crap in because you would not believe
the awareness you need to have to set up
a hash facility to make hash to make
sure nothing in that room is shedding
nothing is releasing or chipping or you
know contaminating your final product
and I can't tell you where I've seen
that in different Labs I've seen it in
in things that you could not possibly
imagine you know putting putting your
books down on top of a of a deep freezer
and then the deep freezer slowly
chipping and releasing paint you know uh
box cutters that instead of plastic
bodies have metal bodies that have been
painted yellow and red and black and
every time you put those down they chip
little bits of paint I've seen this in
Labs before so once you become that
crazy person in the lab running the
facility and keeping all of this stuff
from happening you just can't believe
how easy it is for microbials and for
contaminations that shed off of
different things to that you know that
you're trying to keep out you become the
ultimate goal tender you're just trying
to keep this stuff out and it it it
becomes a real challenge the bigger you
get and the the the higher up you scale
yeah I agree Marcus I went through that
um here in the state of Massachusetts
where I got
so wild with it that I I I had to look
at the air filters because I was
finding things that were falling and set
settling and I looked at our hide off
rotovap one day coming in from the
solventless side and I just like wiped
on it and I was like that's in my half
yeah that's it right here you know we've
been scoping this thing for like a while
this is before we even released anything
we just we narrowed everything down and
really cut all the the different nuances
out to really just get the room clean
and I mean I mean as as clean like eat
off the floor clean you know oh yeah
Hospital clean hos exactly Hospital
clean and that's how we that's how I
operate um and I know that's you how you
operate mark because it's you have to be
that in tune with your it's not only
your tools but it's also your
environment it's the things you bring
into your environment the things that
you're wearing during your during the
time in your your environment and they
all play a major role in how the your
end product really comes out because we
don't have these solvents and these
these vessels to to keep this stuff
contained we we very much deal with a
lot of the still what I call the
elements um even when we're inside so um
totally well that that's just when you
see that the company like Marcus's has
made the commitment to gowning every
employee and every employee in there has
got booties on and they're gown from
head to toe and a guy like me fuzzy
beardy guy like me uhuh that's
completely all covered up I'm completely
covered up here you don't want to get
any one bit of contamination into those
rooms and that's it and the thing is is
like when you look at when you look at
GMP facilities you can tell because they
have to be clean from from from floor to
ceiling any horizontal surface that can
collect dust so you could imagine like
some of your Labs you see where they
have like venting coming in or there's
duck work coming in or there's
electrical [ __ ] hanging from the ceiling
uhuh that doesn't work in GMP that's all
got to be enclosed it all has to be
basically stainless steel bleach [ __ ]
clean like it there's no there's no
compromise in any horizontal surface
like if you have like I don't know like
let's say you just have like a cond it
that comes through your lab and
basically there's a you have to have a
procedure on how to clean that surface
and a record of how often that surface
is clean because that surface could be
the source of contamination down below
you're so right and and it's you have to
get that detailed Mark and and that's
unbelievable like Marcus said we all
wanted this for years I mean this is I'm
excited to have these challenges it
makes me better for it and it makes our
process better for it and allows us to
look at different parts of the process
in ways that um we might not otherwise
look at it well let's pass on some value
to our to our viewers right now because
there is one thing I can give you that I
came across that I decided was not going
to happen in my lab and it might it
might surprise a bunch of people because
I see people customizing these I see
people doing this all the time and it's
a conversation I've wanted to bring up
for a while and this is of course the um
the cozies that are placed on the
outside of the the buckets on the
outside of the washers on the outside of
the 65 gallon stainless steel uh tubs
that pure pressure cells these although
can be cleaned unless you have someone
who understands the Sops and Protocols
of a GMP facility they will never get
those things cleaned properly and if you
simply do a swab test on your cozies
that are sitting on the outside of your
buckets you will find the microbial
content is high higher than you want it
to be and absolutely a vector for
potential contamination in your final
product you're folding your bags over
top of that cozy and your bags are
touching that cozy that is continually
soaking TP Rich water in day after day
after day after day if you don't think
that is a breeding ground for microbial
content you have not been thinking
correctly do me a favor rip those cozies
off if you're in a proper lab right now
it's they're necessary they do not keep
your buckets colder you can just put a
little bit of more ice in it really
doesn't make a huge difference when you
pull them off versus the potential of
contaminant that is there to contaminate
your final end product to me that's
something I would get rid of ASAP Marcus
that's such a great suggestion I've
always thought about that that was a
point of contamination do do they start
to smell like after a while like because
if they're absorbing water and they're
like drying out absorbing water dry do
they start to smell after a while they
would absolutely now keep in mind we
were cleaning ours like crazy but it
wasn't enough well with with special
cleaning um uh like detergents that you
could clean we also used ISO on the
outside but it wouldn't soak in they're
very thick so to me I just like the idea
of getting rid of them they don't help
they're not to all they are is a vector
for potential contamination and that's
my opinion but it's a gift to anyone
listening today because you know if you
just want to avoid a potent and if you
don't believe me start doing swab tests
on it you can get swab kits you can swab
your your um everything in your room for
microbial content and you and you should
be doing this and having these things
tested because if you were you would
probably be ripping those cozies off
ASAP so scum man I know that uh you're a
big dry sift I know we're talking water
here but you know we were talking
patents so when does your dry sift
patent expire so that you can share your
dry sift secrets with the rest of
us it is not a patent it's a proprietary
information it's called a trade secret
it's the Coca-Cola recipe but I did tell
a few key people in the universe and I
told them once I'm dead they're free to
do whatever they want with the
information but uh don't hold your
breath because uh I ain't going nowhere
exactly and Sam I can concur you did
absolutely say exactly that to me and I
have held that respect and I've had
people be pissed at me for for being
loyal to a mentor and a friend if you
can imagine which is fine I'm that those
people play their cards early
on I'm
loyal I'm loyal when someone asks and
it's not mine to tell them it's yours
it's yours it's not you didn't give it
to me you showed me and told me that if
when I pass away you can share it until
then keep it keep it to yourself which I
have absolutely done I don't use the
process at my company I've never shown
the process to anyone um but it sure is
um have asked it's an eye opener we have
asked and you were like no and I of
respect it's like actually even further
John I asked you guys not to ask me
anymore is what I actually asked because
I felt like I said this I said do you
really want to trick me out of this do
you really want to get me into a
conversation and trick me out of
something that my that my mentor this
person I have so much respect for that I
that you can't imagine the the joy and
pride I had when he showed that to me
and it wasn't because I was going to be
learning something that nobody knew it
was because that that man decided to
trust me and you think I'm G to let that
go you think I'm G to like let that
trust go what I was there you were like
the happiest man in the world I wanted
to make sure that the information was
available to mankind if I wasn't able to
me mechanical IE it like I would wanted
to I wanted to automate the system but I
I don't know if I'll be able to or not
so uh but one day yeah lots of people
can make pretty damn good dry sip
nowadays
so they're may be not making
99.9 but they're making 95 pretty
the varieties are getting better too so
you know well they sure are do easier to
collect and you know with with that said
do you think Mark and even Sam do you
think utility patents are something that
could uh could hold up because they
nuances of of just processes I mean what
do you think about that Utility Patent
does not last as long as I've held this
Secret
right I agree now now what if you have
what if you're one of those guys like
uh you
know
like try trying to do I think if you're
trying to raise money and you trying to
build perceived value filing patents
could be a way of sort of I mean think
of a patent is like a picket and a
picket fence and a patent in and of
itself he not as valuable as getting a
bunch of patents to kind of like secure
your little intellectual property Island
but like Sam was saying you know the
trade secret in cannabis is really I
mean like there are successful products
out there and they have successful you
know the Genesis of the idea of how
they're made and how they're put
together and the notion that you want to
protect that well if you file again not
a utility but a process patent it
difficult because your competitors
aren't necessarily going to let you into
their facility to know that their
process infringes on your process you
can buy their product in the store and
you could do some type of analysis but
at the end of the day they're extracting
thca or THC or CBD or whatever can
avonoid and and it's in a product okay
well I mean those methods have been
around for a long time so there's
nothing really new about that I guess
the companies who are filing who are
coming out with new extraction processes
or machines that are particular for
their process so in order to run their
process to make that kind of product you
have to buy their machine so of course
they want to patent that machine because
they want to be the only machine
manufacturer that could make that
particular thing but I haven't really
seen that too much in cannabis I mean
mostly a lot of these extracts are you
know is as good as the extraction meth
method and you know a lot of the whether
you're doing solvent based or not you
know
solventless you know the thing that
we've always said here on hash Church
which is you need high quality plant
material that's not contaminated and if
it starts with high quality plant
material and your extraction method is
proper you should get a very proper
extract yeah I can coner with that you
know I've gone through a great deal of
material this past year alone and I've
seen varying sizes of types of quality
and yields and at the end of the day we
have a specific Target to make full melt
and there's things that we need to you
always have to adapt to and it's about
it be does become about your process as
well as the material but there is there
actually like you're saying there is a
there's more sides to it it's not as
black and white as as as you know as
just the material versus the process I
think more people need to focus on
actually growing quality cannabis
because the bottom line is if you
haven't even grown great cannabis the
processes none of these processes are
going to work for you I'd also say that
nothing's faster than large scale water
extraction for isolating 99.99% gland
heads you all have had access to it for
20 plus years so what you just think
you're going to get access to this new
thing and it's going to change your
world trust me the thing that will
change your world is growing better weed
focus on that that is important I agree
Marcus 100
like we were talking last week I mean
having testing that we we can test the
material now and have methods to say
okay what is the impact and you know
when you look at yield and so some of
the work that Johnny B did right here
live on hash Church looking at LED
versus you know high pressure sodium I
mean where these things can actually
have an incremental you know impact on
the quality of the material that's grown
and again venues like hash Church and
other online things by the way Marcus
speaking of online things I saw your um
you're um curious about cannabis podcast
very nice curious about cannabis podcast
that a podcast with Marcus you all
should check it out it was great Marcus
tells his story but um you know there's
so many things that I think that you can
do like you know the dragonfly Earth
medicine school of thought of
regenerative cannabis you know kind of
like what we were talking about with um
with uh the guy from SC Labs I'm
forgetting his name right now Alec right
so having those analytical methods now
not only at the third-party Testing Lab
but at your production facilities
themselves where you could actually
follow the biomass you're getting in the
building you could look at each
individual fraction whether you're
extracting and making distillate or
making some type of solventless product
all these things can be tested now to
look at what the canono and tpine
profiles are and translate that
information into stuff that you can put
on the label that customers can actually
pay attention
to so kind of cool yeah absolutely I
almost forgot about that podcast
actually um I haven't done that many
lately but yeah I did tell the whole
story on that one for sure yeah that was
cool margus you did a great job
congratulations on that that was great
Jason's a nice guy we should get on on
hash Church sometime absolutely anytime
you guys have people you want to invite
on to Hash Church please hit me up you
guys are the core group I invite you all
the time but I love M mixing it up new
energy always creates new dialogue and
new conversation doesn't always work out
uh as good as we'd like it to but I'm
always down uh with taking the chance uh
even if it's just a matter of doing a
sort of a little pre a hash Church video
with people that we're thinking of
bringing on it would be nice to uh to
expand our hash group Core Group here so
yeah we should do
that asked question in the chat here
about Delta 8 you want me to chime in
just for a second about Delta 8 for a
second a lot of interest in that these
days yeah absolutely you guys sick of
listening to me
talk no talk it up bro yeah talk about
so uh yeah um um so remember like when
mulam isolated
Delta 9 THC and the reason why we call
it Delta 9 is because when you look at
the molecular structure of THC right
those thing that looks like chicken wire
there's like three rings right and when
you look at the North ring you'll see
that there's a double bond which is a
carbon each one of those angles is
basically a carbon and and there's a
double bond between two of the carbons
and where that double bond resides is is
is the Delta 9 configuration in the
plant and mul's method was so mild in
isolating it that he didn't isomerize it
but previous researchers were frustrated
because they were using acidic reagents
and other methods that were uh in the
isolation of the active ingredient was
isomerizing the double bond and Confused
the ultimate uh stereochemical
elucidation so what what happens is if
um so think of it like this way so if
you if you're looking
the structure of THC that North Ring The
Ring at the topmost part of the
structure you see the double bond is
pointed towards the phenolic portion of
the molecule which is where the Benzene
ring is right and so that's what's
called the Delta 9 configuration and
Delta 9 would rather be in Delta 8
because when that isomerizes it it moves
it one more carbon away from the rigid
framework of the of the Benzene ring and
when it moves it away it kind of lowers
the energy of the molecule so Delta 8 is
lower by a few kilo calories in energy
than Delta 9 so I've given the
opportunity Delta n which is what the
plant gives us goes to Delta 8 now the
other reason why this is important is
because again because
CBD is a um CBD can be chemically
converted into either Delta 8 or Delta 9
THC right now a lot of hemp producers
because of the price of
CBD has tanked you know CBD isolate is
like you know a year ago it was multiple
thousands of dollars a kilogram now it's
just hundreds of dollars a kilogram so
it's really tanked part of that is just
Supply demand economics there's so much
of it available the FDA has not given
the green light to for food
manufacturers to be able to put this in
into food products so there's a lot of
production there's a lot of it on the
market so that basically puts a downward
pressure on the price of CBD so these
manufacturers are looking to do
something to make some money so they're
converting it over into Delta 8 Now
Delta 8 is less psychoactive than Delta
9 I've seen a couple different papers
where they looked at The Binding
constant to the cv1 receptor but what I
can tell you universally is I've had
some delta8 this lit and it's it's
headyy it gets you high but I've never
been kind of like knocked over bold over
like you do get like I think on on THC I
think you could actually noticeably feel
the difference I don't know if other
people feel that way too but the last
thing I'll say just about Delta 8 is
that unfortunately it falls into the
Tetra hydr
canab all code 7370 of the controlled
dous controlled dangerous substance act
to get that out um which um even though
it was derived from farm bill legal hemp
you're now making an isomer that the da
doesn't give a [ __ ] where they came from
they issued something called an interim
final ruling about six or eight months
ago to try to harmonize the controlled
dangerous substance act with the farm
bill just to let people know that you
know THC and its isomer including Delta
eight are all cut code 7370 covered
under the under control dangerous
substance act and again it's that quasi
legal because you've you've you've made
the hemp and you've made the CBD from
which it's derived legal right so that's
legal and people there's transactions
that are happening where people are
buying and selling CBD hemp biomass and
people are actually smoking flour check
this out people are actually taking CBD
isolate converting it to Delta eight and
then spraying it back on hemp to make
midies yeah it's like the world needs
more midies what you know but it's
interesting because again it's just it's
chemistry that actually mulam described
and you know we were mentioning patents
mulam actually patented this but I think
that this is sort of a gray area right
now Wade I don't really know whether or
not you know the DEA has the muscle and
the the enforcement to basically go
after H manufactures who are flying the
you know Farm Bill flag saying hey we're
processing hemp it's below three in THC
when it comes in the building how we
process it we're we're processing it
we're turning it into products that the
market wants a lot of the regulated
Delta 9 markets those people who have to
pay through the eyeballs to get licenses
and get background checks on everyone
and and do retinal scanners and have
millions of dollars to they don't want
the Delta a industry to happen right
because they're gonna eat the market
share they want these people to go to
the dispensary and buy their licensed
Delta 9 products so there's going to be
some kind of thing that's going to
happen going forward to try to harmonize
these two things but that's where I'll
end my little so if I
could uh
what I'm hearing you say is that uh the
amount of delta8 products that are
starting to show up across the country
at this point it's really either folks
moving CBD into Delta H isomerization or
uh right other aggressive yeah let me
thing way so it's either that or the the
boys over at I think Guild noticeably
The Guild extracts in in California but
people who were using bleaching and
decolorizing Clays first started
noticing Delta H showing up in their
distillates and some of the testing labs
and Alec would be great to comment on
this were like wait a second that's not
Delta 9 that's Delta eight and it was
beautifully clear distillate because the
bleaching Clays there is no bleach
there's no sodium hypochlorite they're
just called bleaching Clays because they
remove color and these are standard
things that remove color in the Essen
oils industry and soybean oil and
vegetable oil all that [ __ ] is
decolorized and typically they use these
type of bleaching Clays which is nothing
more than M marinite clay but these
Clays are acidic enough such that when
they were adding clay to their
distillation pot and then pooping over
what they thought was a Delta 9
distillate uhuh thermodynamics happened
Delta 9 went down to Delta 8 and it
doesn't go back to Delta 9 and so what
they were getting was Delta 8 clear
distillate and they're like oh oh we
meant to make this so then they became
the delta8 company and talked about how
we were making clear Delta a distillate
so I think that that actually predated
people using the acid catalyzed process
to convert CBD into Delta 8 which is now
what you see mostly on the markets I
think are coming from hemp producers out
west yeah the first time I first time I
ran into Delta 8 in a test result was
was um one of our manufacturers was
trying to clean up a batch of cannabis
that had uh I think it was spinosad in
it and he was doing a chlorine bleach
and yeah what we got back it had a bunch
of Delta eight and uh I couldn't find
much science at that point on how Delta
eight affects
patients again you know uh but I'm I
heard you reference earlier that uh you
had seen some papers Rec feels like a
THC wood but it feels less potent it
just it doesn't it doesn't quite do it
for me but I I know some people love it
and certainly like I guess if you're
used to smoking hemp flour and now you
got hemp flour sprayed with Delta 8 it
just took a circuitous way of getting
back to the flower
right thank you Mark Mark did you know
that uh for the last uh few years people
have been marketing High CBD 8
uh
cannabis but the truth of it is as we
both know cannabis does not produce
Delta eight it's a degradation product
yeah I I always thought that that was
the case because if you look at the
biosynthetic pathway the way the
molecule comes together from cbga yeah
it's it's an intermolecular cyclisation
and it makes one particular one
particular um configuration
it would have a a plant uh synthase that
would produce Delta eight but it does it
was really it was really interesting
what we found and I think I gave a talk
on this at American Chemical Society
national meeting a couple years ago
which was we took Delta 9 thca that was
purified and we uh we actually
isolated the um Delta 8
acid by
isomerizing the Delta 9 over to Delta 8
without decarbox it and so we had some
analytical data that supported that so
that was kind of cool because there
wasn't really too many reports of that
so but I I I agree with what you're
saying I think only Delta 9 is what
occurs in the plant from what
I you had Delta 8 a yes t
a yes yeah cool Isn't that cool yeah
it's way harder to find bed Delta eight
yeah so I thought we were the first
people to identify that but actually uh
a came to my talk and pointed out that
there was a a a Roger pery paper from a
number of years ago where he and hus had
actually um spectrally characterized it
so but it's very it's buried in the
middle of a tetraedron letters paper
from the middle of the 80s you would not
necessarily find it by looking for it
but man there's a lot of gems out there
it's really cool I didn't even notice
that Josh and Alec came into the room so
welcome to both of you and sorry for
that for not welcoming you right
away oh please good good morning
everybody happy has
church happy hash Church and blessing to
the family never want to interrupt a
good conversation so that super
interesting hi everybody good morning
happy hash Church good morning Kelly
thank you for breaking up this absolute
sausage party it's uh we got to get more
women in here there's just no doubt
about it we uh we appreciate you we we
appreciate you
awesome can you do me a favor
Kelly yeah tell me that I'm
important you are so important Mark you
don't even know it you know how
important I are me too I that all the
time I just love the way that's
important important but
needy important but
needy that's it oh yeah lots of
mansplaining going on you know I got
into a conversation with my friend the
other day about mansplaining and she was
going off on how she's like oh like men
just constantly mansplaining to women
and I said listen no offense but that's
not a gender thing men mansplain to men
as much as they do it to women it's our
disease but isn't there women
spting I don't know I just think of it
as like the the voice of
reason I just think of it as the voice
of reason
personally but nonetheless I know I
really I really appreciate really
appreciate all of the talk I've been
sort of in the background getting some
stuff done and you know women explain it
differently and I've been really
appreciating the conversation this
morning it's it's definitely got a
tonality of masculinity but I think that
that's really awesome and I appreciate
that week after week so thanks so much
everybody you guys for you know talking
about the plans with such high regards
and love hey I try to say you know there
is a thing called male intuition male
intuition actually exists so you know
you know be intuitive you
know hey Mark I was wondering um have
you ever done any extracting of
endophytic fungi or bacteria from from
Plants I haven't but more people are
asking me about that every day you know
we talked a little bit about this last
week just because there's been more you
know municipalities that
are now making you know fungi you know
or decriminalizing it or making it
available and actually had a
conversation with Alec on whether or not
the analytical labs that are in place
now for the Cannabis
industry are going to start doing the
analytical you know testing for some of
these you know fungal type type products
because as you know I mean having good
analytical methods is really important
for accurate dosing especially if you're
talking about you know medicine for
people who don't want the high of the
Psychedelic experience but perhaps
needed to control depression or or other
things I had an old friend reach out to
me who said you know cannabis just isn't
doing it for my depression anymore and
I'm not well enough vers to understand
where um psychedelics can help but I'm
reading up on it a lot and just finding
a lot of just great work going on right
now actually a lot of government funded
work right now
on both
MDMA and um and
psilocybin for to treat all kinds of
condition the the paper I was just
reading yesterday Josh was really cool
it was talking about stage four cancer
um uh patients getting uh MDMA uh and
having basically a MDMA experience to
kind of help their body understand that
what their medical conditions all about
and and and trying to get their their
mind to think about positive ways of
healing themselves and it's just so just
powerful and just yeah a lot of great
work being done right now man it's so
cool crystal ball right the scientific
literature it's out there for everybody
to look into yeah AB the more I go down
the um the long roads of the microbiome
the more that we're really realizing
that health and well-being on emotional
level physical level spiritual level is
so intricately connected to the
microbiome that you know I feel like
we're just barely scratching the surface
right now of where we really need to get
for Humanity as well as for the health
and well-being of the cannabis plants
you know we're we're having a lot of
these discussions but in five years from
now we're going to be talking about the
endic uh you know reactions that are
going on within the plant and we're
going to be counting bacteria and
different species and that's going to be
the way that we're going to be able to
tell how healthy the plants are as well
as how much medicine um the plant is
providing for patients and also I mean
and to say are you extracting Endo fidic
fungi and bacteria from Plants isn't
really a psychedelic question it's more
there's there's you know 30 to to more
there's different Endo fidic fungi that
the plant pulls out of the soil right P
bacteria and Fung out of the soil to
create its body as it's growing and
those
compounds are often medicinal and just
like I don't know if I if I froze I
couldn't tell but uh just like we and we
may have discussed this on hash Church
before but like taxol right cures cancer
from the UT tree but and they and we
said this before but they took all the
bark off the off the tree you know all
through the 90s and left the tree out in
the woods because they were extracting
taxol from the bark but after further
studies and further scientific studies
they realized it was the endophytic
fungi in the cambium layer that was also
producing taxel and in some cases
producing it more than what was in the
bark so it was possible and this is you
know more into the science realm you
know more than where I'm at you know
where we're at more intuitive nature
lovers but in science you can extract
these comp compounds and the plant is
pulling up bacteria and fungi into the
plant and putting it back into the soil
it's it's
replicating those organisms in its body
and it's putting it back into the soil
those compounds are also capable of
producing secondary
metabolites you know outside of uh I'm
coming down with Rona someone just wrote
me no I'm all good bro just
but um but uh anyway I know the cannabis
plant has these compounds and I don't
and I don't see that we're studying them
yet and it may be that you know there's
a you know a thousand acres of hemp you
know holding endophytic fungi and
bacteria that we don't know about that
we can extract and use for our health
and well-being I feel like it's it's a
new frontier you know there's a few
universities that are studying it you
know and then and then also you know
there's psychedelic fungi and that whole
entire realm of Breaking the Chain and
you know stopping you know not having
the boundaries and the chains that bind
you and that's what I love so the nice
thing about those compounds the nice
thing about those compounds Josh is that
they're water soluable so you know we're
in cannabis everything is oil soluble
not very water soluble you can use
pretty
conventional methods to make a mushroom
tea for example blue juice right
the blue juice oh I've looked at my 300
liter Whistler reactor a few times and
been
like probably whip up a nice batch of
blue juice in that
reactor yeah so Mark is that like a a a
standardized product that you think like
one of these markets like in Oregon
that's legalized psychedelics could
actually you can go and buy your little
shot of blue juice at the convenience
store someday or I well I sure hope so I
mean my goodness listen cannabis has
been amazing for the sort of I mean I
don't want to say it hasn't been amazing
for the mental as well as the physical
but sort of on this plane and now we're
bringing in the psychedelics which is
going to help us in that sort of
spiritual plane in that sort of you know
the mental health plane people are
hurting and people end up taking lithium
and all sorts of drugs that [ __ ] with
your brain chemistry that are created by
companies and sold under the name
pharmaceutical which if you drop the P
it's got the harm right there in the
word h RM like they're not even trying
to hide it I think of that as one of the
biggest things coming in the queue right
now is when people who are seriously
suffering from mental health and mental
illness can go and take these Journeys
with these plant medicines and you know
not have to not have to deal with it for
the rest of their lives it should be an
you know it should be like a trip or two
or three not like 25 years of taking
Lithium you know this is these are
accelerators that don't that don't take
25 years they happen immediately because
once you have been and I take this from
Brian and I can't even pronounce his
last name the book that both Alec and I
spoke about the immortality key he
mentions a woman who was a full-blown
atheist still an atheist even after her
trip but when it's asked about the
mushroom and how she felt and she was
very she had deep deep depression she
took mushrooms only once and and totally
sealed the deal on her depression when
she was asked what would you say the
feeling was she said it felt like I was
being in bathed in God's love and he
said I thought you were an atheist and
she said well I am but that's the only
thing I can put into words that it felt
like and so that's pretty
potent I mean psychedelics has has just
catapulted us to the level where we're
at right now you know I I think that the
entrance of mushrooms allowed Humanity
to think outside of Just The Agrarian
sort of work that they were doing at the
time and allowed them to create
spirituality and now here we are with
psychedelics coming out on a new realm
of course I do believe that cannabis has
opened the door for the psychedelics she
the one that's holding the door wide
open for people to actually recognize
that plant medicine is totally
incredibly powerful and how like here we
are now in this new Great Awakening of
you know psychedelics regular people are
talking about it people are looking
towards plant medicine to heal
themselves more Pharmaceuticals than
ever before and I think that if we just
continue that action and percentage
forward then we're really going to be
catapulted into the next level of
humanity and the next level of existence
it's not going to come from just our own
Collective Consciousness there has to be
some kind of a drop from outside of it
so that our Collective Consciousness can
you know build off of something like
that and I think that you know we owe so
much to plant medicines as to why we are
the human beings that we are and the
collective Consciousness that we
are and on that note everyone grab your
five grams of dried mushrooms where
going to start the consumption part of
the
ritual and that's what we mean by
5G yeah don't be against 5G 5G is
powerful all these people that are
against 5G listen yes it will melt your
brain but in a very good way and when it
precipitates back into a solid you'll be
better for it so just don't be afraid of
5G
please I like the Terrence McKenna 5G
like you know Drake thing that says no
to the 5G Tower and yes to the 5G of
mushrooms 5G
speak the 5 has anyone seen that Jim
Carrey movie Jim Carrey plays ter
Terrence
McKenna did it actually happened I think
it I thought it was fake I looked into
it there was no movie it was just
someone created like a like a an ad for
it but I never actually saw any video of
it yeah I thought it was a movie that
was released in like 2017 or something
like that is that not right I could
never find it all I found was that it
was like someone like a fan-based thing
they took a picture of Jim with a beard
and put it in and then covered him in
mushrooms and plants and made this super
cool advert and it was uh it was fake as
Bingo Lombardi has just confirmed in
chat we all know Bingo's never wrong
about anything so I'll take that as the
word of God bingo today you were right
yeah and Dr Mark was wrong you can write
that down Bingo oh no no no Dr Mark I
was asking about I wanted to you know
we're looking for things to like watch
on Netflix and I I wanted to know if
anyone had seen that or you know hoax
hoax Hox you're spreading false
information Mark fake news no
I no not me not this week deep fake
technology wowy spent some time with
Terence McKenna on the big in Kaya kakua
Bay um you know on the big island was
where Terence McKenna's property is and
that's where uh we we had Dr Allison on
here before and she works with st uh
Leanne sish and you know and there's
people in the in the network that are
taking care of the property and
everything the iasa vines 50 years old
and everything and all the cactus too so
they're taking care of the cactus there
yeah I was super blessed to meet
Terrence um I hung out with him for a
whole weekend a half out on the island
um we kept meeting at 500 a.m. to go see
the dolphins that K alak kakua and I was
just sitting with this guy and talking
with him and having the most incredible
conversations about dolphin magic and
Consciousness and water and spores and
just everything and it it was like on
the third day I started to like
recognize his voice from late night AM
radio so artell it was Art Bell it took
me like then I was like wait a minute
are you Terrence McKenna and he said
yeah you know I am we never really
introduced ourselves so I was really
thankful for those you know ear mid 80s
late 80s uh you know late night am so
that that's how I recognized that it was
Terren and uh we became friends and what
an amazing guy just even spending that
time with him uh you know talk about
catapulting I go back to that
conversation those conversations that we
had quite often it's it's it's awesome
you know he wasn't uh just Terrence
McKenna because it was a happen chance
you know he was he he was born into that
uh for an incredible reason and to sit
in front of that man and and listen to
him you know he he is
unlike a lot of other people so he he
affected me deeply he affected me very
deeply I I got turned on to him almost
as a teenager you know by his from his
tapes from The esam Institute and some
of these other tapes and people in our
community in Winnipeg Manitoba they did
not know who Terrence McKenna was it was
very random that we somehow accidentally
stumbled upon Him absolutely read the
invisible landscape that's an amazing
book read true hallucinations the
archaic revival food of the Gods you
know every article he ever wrote in
every magazine all of his lectures
including the ones with rert sheldrake
and Ralph Abraham I went deep on
Terrence he was probably you know one of
one of the people that affected me a
great great deal when I was younger and
got you know we ordered our spores from
him and his wife cat uh from that that
the big island that you're talking about
that's where those siy spores came from
that him and his brother Dennis
collected in the Amazon back in the late
70s before they wrote the book uh the
mushroom Growers guide on how to grow
psychedelic mushrooms indoors so and
that book was was the book we used with
the spores to actually grow these
mushrooms and so for me I will always
have a huge place in my in my soul for
the information that Terence mcken
Shar yeah I totally agree I feel like
he's given um you know so much to me and
I feel like more than anything he's
given me an incredible sense of humor on
psychedelics like I think of Terence
McKenna when I'm on psychedelics
and for some reason just the hilarity
comes out you know where you're just
like wow this world is [ __ ] hilarious
and I can't believe I was so serious
about it last week he like really has
you know opened up the doors to let go
of uh what we don't laugh at ourselves
about [ __ ] humans are hilarious yeah and
Terence had that gift he had he was
sharp and had the gift gab obviously and
could just could just say things that
just you know would you would erupt into
laughter and I was the same way you know
be tripping balls kind of like like
almost like just uncomfortably high and
then think of Terren and think of all
the words that he prepared I'll tell you
one thing that was the preparation for
largescale mushroom tripping because
that whole Timothy L thing with the Book
of the Dead and rep and like recording
his voice reading it to himself like if
any of you you ever listened to Tim
you'd know that one of his worst trips
ever was listening to the Book of Dead
while he was tripping balls in his voice
his he had recorded it himself because
he couldn't read the book and he thought
well I want to read the book while I'm
high so that was kind of the the the the
the way to lead yourself to a bad trip
whereas the Terren lectures and all of
what he was sharing was just so
inspirational and so you know and and
putting himself out there and shipping
those spores around the world at a time
when holy Christ like they could have
easily hammered down on him and put him
in jail for 10 years but you know he
kept he still was doing it so no no
doubt a huge props to Terence
McKenna and McKenna yeah and and I need
to give props for the bad trips too so
you know absolutely bad trips have given
me the most important lessons of my
entire life and I don't know if bad is
quite the word you know just
like felt yeah the intense trips the
ones that just don't compartmentalize so
easy human beings are such incredible
compartmentalizes that if it doesn't
compute and it doesn't compartmentalize
then maybe if it's an unknown then be
afraid of it and I think that you know
that's that's something that uh
hopefully we're going to be able to
break down with the new entrance of
psychedelics you know that need to
compartmentalize human beings resistance
creates strength and you know if you
don't believe it just lift weights like
if you lift weights that resistance will
create strength in your muscles and it's
really no difference for the resistance
of an intense trip and whether or not
you know it's almost like a psychic
puzzle that you're involved in and
depending on you know not your ego but
allowing your soul to project its true
feeling it's that true like love
experience if you can do that you can
transform and that's what the budha bu
talk about transforming pain and anguish
you transform that when someone passes
on you don't have to cry and be sad
because you were happy they were here
and you know they're not actually gone
they've just transformed it's a
different filter of looking through and
so yeah huge huge
prop and and you know it's like the big
the big questions and the reason why we
have science and the reason why we have
all you know the Buddhists say that the
greatest um disease of humanity is the
need to know why and it's like I think
that more than anything we're all just
really wondering where did we come from
and where are we going I mean really and
truly everything else is noise and fluff
in between everything that we're talking
about is trying to give us little tiny
tidbits of where we're going to go now
that we're here and it's so beautiful
that plant medicine really helped us
align with either a giving us those
answers or B helping us realize that
those answers are not important at all
that we're here and that just being here
is good enough yep and you know helps
open us to those possibilities and big
up Alec Alec was wanting to say and and
my man what's up ganja Gil in the house
today welcome
guys see I just wanted to jump in real
quick with on the Terence mechanic
conversation bless his soul and yeah
Dennis mcken too those dudes are legends
but um yeah just uh it's fascinating how
Terence Mna had um you know selected
identified a choar of banister Opus
Kappy um and brought it out to Hawaii
and they planted the iasa vine out in
Hawaii and since then it's become
essentially an invasive weed like or an
invasive plant in this
way and
so it's it's it's actually to see how
it's growing on Hawaii and uh you know
the the vineet itself it's a it's a
woody lyan which is like a or it's a
lyana which is a woody Vine and uh and
and it grows and stretches to kind of to
to C catch the Sun and over its life i'
I heard some really cool stories about
the plant um over it's you know in the
jungle in in Brazil and the Amazon and
per
Peru the vine will kind of stretch up to
kind of catch the sun it'll it'll um
kind of it'll pull you know as it grows
it'll actually pull trees down out of
the ground to open up the canopy of the
forest so that it can kind of open up
light and then it brings in all kinds of
other life in you know the below canopy
um but but um the vine is is it's F it's
fascinating how much it's kind of uh
kind of spreading on the island of
Hawaii um you know and just similar to
like eucalyptus For Better or For Worse
but as far as it goes on the global kind
of conservation effort to you know plant
more of the vine as consumption and um
and popularity of iasa kind of you know
continues to to grow um you know just
the whole concept of BR cultiv or or
conservation You Know teren M kind of
really has made a major effect in that
you know post uh you know post
humus absolutely well said Alec thanks
for sharing uh Mark Rose my manufacturer
who uh from in Nepal um says he grew the
spores in cat MW back in
1998 and then they went wild in the Rose
Garden in the yard so he just shared
that I just wanted to say one more thing
before we give Gil the floor and let him
uh come in and say hello which was that
imagine if life itself is a
disassociative we're not supposed to
know where we came from and we're not
supposed to know where we're going we
can get little glimpses and little
flashes and this is the whole experience
this is why this is so fun and so
terrifying simultaneously here on planet
Earth but I'm certain that we're not
supposed to know where we came from and
we're not supposed to know where we're
going because if we did it would affect
the experience and the experience is why
we're all here so yeah welcome ganja
Gill good morning everyone thank you
very much for uh having me on as always
uh it's a pleasure to be here with you
guys it's nice to hear your voice I'm
not sure I have too much to contribute
to the conversation at this current
moment but again I'm just stoked to be
here with you all on this morning it's
been warmer in California than it should
be recently it's been real warm still
kind of waiting for winter to come
hopefully it comes but uh feeling good
dude it's another beautiful day I'm just
like to actually sit here and relax this
Sunday morning with you guys and smoke
some hash and listen to the
conversation well if that's not what
it's all about right there in a nutshell
I mean that if we had a mission
statement here at hash Church Gil just
spit it out so there it is welcome
welcome
man oh we got the chat going on go go
ahead Jo what are some of the uh strings
you've been watching in the last uh week
Gil I kind of took a different approach
this year actually and like I grew a lot
from seed um being in California I have
access to a lot of desirable clone only
genetics and uh this past year I grew
pretty much strictly seed I kind of like
go back and forth it's funny you know
like one year you'll like grow all
clones and then I'm like oh that was
boring now I want to do seeds and then
I'll do seeds and then crack like way
more seeds than I need and like end up
getting way more males than I thought I
would or you know the roly pulley will
eat all my seedlings or you know it ends
up being always a lot of work so
sometimes after a SE season I get a
little lit like oh man I'm G to put the
training wheels back on and just get
some clones and keep it easy you know
but uh the seed thing really worked out
really well for me this year um I kind
of it's all mixed pheno washes because
you know I don't have a very large
garden and I chose to grow about 35
different varieties not phenos but
varieties so in a small garden you can
imagine it's all small bat
um but that's kind of what I wanted to
do this year last year I only did like a
handful of like big dumper hash drains
and it was cool but it kind of like lost
its interests after a little while you
know after you wash so many barrels of
the same strain it's kind of like oh I
know what it's going to do you know like
if you press the same strain over and
over again you know what it's going to
do so this past year like I said I grew
like 30 different varieties and it's
been super fun just to do these little
batches and see what they do and uh at
first I was kind of like have mixed
feelings about the mixed feno washes you
know like oh is it kind of generic you
know you should really be selecting the
one and what not but I started to kind
of think about it more and I feel like
you know when you look at like you know
lets be real I cracked mostly 10 packs
of seeds you know just small 12 packs
whatever you know in a 10 pack you'll
probably feel like you know half of them
will lean towards the mom half of them
will lead towards you know the dad and
you know a few come in between and I
started to think about it and I'm like
oh that's kind of a good representation
of the actual the cultivar because it's
like got a little bit of this got a
little bit of that it's pulling from all
of it you know so maybe it's not so much
generic as much as it's like a a pretty
good representation of it and uh it's
been working really well yield wise um
it's definitely interesting to watch the
different quality of resins interact
with one another in the same bag you
know you can definitely see certain
resins kind of starting to dissolve the
other one but uh
it's worked out really good and uh it's
been really fun and uh I've been doing a
lot of papaya crosses papaya is really
popular in California this year so uh
did a lot of papaya stuff um that Kim
Masonic um down in Compton he just dusts
everything with the same maale that
Wilson mail he has Wilson is um papaya
times banana OG cross with Tropicana
cookie F2 and uh just a real solid male
that he hits everything with and I
definitely cracked a bunch of seeds from
him and they all did really well man
they all we tropical island cocktail
fruit pineapple banana turps you know
which I like Funk myself I'm really into
the gas stuff but it seems like my area
California really likes that fruity turp
stuff and I don't know you kind of keep
the people happy and whatnot but uh yeah
just uh this week I wash some chem D
cross with daylow from someone out of uh
Colorado was really really good did
really great then I did the chmd to
Purple OG that one came out purple it
was really cool to see the purple resin
but like didn't really yield well
um uh what else do I got in the freeze
dryer right now I got Wilson zero in
there right now which is original Wilson
from Anie noodles um which is just his
original Wilson the banana OG papaya
Tropicana that's in the freeze dryer
right now looking really good is this a
fish head that's naming these strains
Wilson so that's so funny that you say
that because um it's not believe it or
not I always thought the same thing and
I told them that I'm like you guys know
about the Wilson tune and like most of
them don't um what it is is it's again
banana OG papaya Tropicana cookie so it
smells like a tropical island so I guess
from that that movie Cast Away I never
saw it myself but it's got uh what's his
name Tom Hanks in it wilon ball the
Wilson yeah so
that's yeah that's where the Wilson
comes from supposedly I guess um yeah oh
funny island chirs is that Wilson with
19 L's
Wilson I don't know about that Marcus as
far as I know like I said it's the one
from an noodles oh I was just being
silly um like I said from what oh okay
I'm sorry dude if you ever heard fish
sing the
song there's about 19 L's in
there well there you go now I now I
understand sorry they that way I wanted
to mention in regards to you talking
about mixed cultivars and kind of the
difference and I'm I'm sure Sam will
probably want to T tap in here at one
point because back in the day and I
don't know if this was pre 71 or what
when Sam but was there not like a time
where in Afghanistan they were growing
type one and type two plants you know
having that sort of selection just it
was reminiscent when he started talking
about like mixing all the fenos from a
seed batch in and how I can kind of see
us getting there as we go into this
isolating cultivars isolating resin
gland heads to the point where we may do
a full circle and now it's like you know
what I want to run this whole field into
hash and I want to create a profile you
know probably one that's never going to
be recreated but something that would
still have its place and be considered
special uh by any accounts uh I I would
love to see that happen and as you were
talking about throwing in multiple you
know all the different fenos to really
get an idea yeah full field full field
fresh Frozen full
field
yeah be nice I'm
shifting I'm G to shift argrow outside
next year into uh more strain selection
Fen well just you know many fenos same
thing we're talking about was
interesting to hear Gil talking about it
I could see getting bored with it also
perhaps but I am interested to see whole
bed sets just go to one strain type um
from my breeding with my Sharp for sure
and then some headband Shi that I just
read too are just dropping um amazing
amounts of hash and really good quality
and I just want to lock in more on the
the you know tpping profile to match up
to it you know up to the dump
so yeah I like that you're rocking the
headband
still I mean that's such a beautiful
strain you know over the years
[Music]
and yeah it's Holy Grail like a breeding
Cornerstone for even things like my gas
mask completely lends to that you know
the mac and the kosher don't hurt but it
definitely goes back to the headband
grease that that we pull and then to go
back to the Bubble Bags you know that's
like just pulling this greasy greasy
dank resin we just washed a couple whole
plant from the greenhouse for um cured
resin dry flour wash from sunr and the
the it's air dry but the nug like the 90
to 120 coming off is so goopy that it
has more oxidization on the crust uh you
know outside of the bubble you know
nuggets you can barely do anything if
you look at them they
melt and it was both the diesel band the
headband just dropped it like that the
DB Band came out a lot lighter less
oxidization seemed like a little bit
more quality grow but yeah amazing for a
fuel type in Maine actually into the
greenhouse and it wasn't the prettiest
on the Finish but even just tended well
by hand hand cut dry Barn storage for
two to three months you know controlled
temp humidity in the bin really clean
take down but we do large whole plant
sections we don't take any LEF much Leaf
off after defoliation from you know into
flower where we're opening up sights
getting air we don't take anything off
really thereafter until you know it's
time to trim it by hand dry so great
results whole PL fried flour you know
dry cured resin bubble lately like crazy
I feel if I had I feel like if I had
less of Integrity than I do I'd have
these really cheesy kind of like this
conversation is brought to you by Bubble
Bags you know and have this whole sort
of cheesy advertisement in the middle
but the whole time you were talking I
just felt like man you are definitely a
professional grower and hash maker like
even just the way you explain your
process it's just like damn this guy's
like a lifer he's in
this like iation
oxidization you're adding an extra
syllable in there so just say
oxidation everybody say oxidation
oxidation oxidation thanks Dr Mark
keeping us
smarter uh Brian those photos look
really incredible man uh tiger stripes
gas mask uh is that what you're you're
working with right now yeah got get up
there
and check that out yeah I'd love to
share you know I'd love to share out
some genetics too I've been meaning to
as well I did like some really nice work
from the gas mask out I'm I'm super
impressed with that
shark um kind of like a comic name on it
but it's what it is is it's it hits that
it's a lime cush GMO triangle cush skunk
on on the other end for the sh key so
we've seen that do amazing things for
hash already on its own and it was a
nice dude that went in on it it selected
dude from the crew for that's a swamp
boy seeds
genetic and yeah we got like this lime
to apricot tur on the gas this time with
that one phenotype it's definitely GMO
skunk heavy you know shout out to skunk
skunk man it's got skunk all over it's
kind of like a baby pukey sweet really
really runchy sharp cheddar type
thing and uh we'll see how it washes
haven't washed quite yet what's the
water on on these things like and you
have again same question to you that I
asked Marcus earlier what do you do with
the water is there anything you could do
with it or you just discard it
or we're discarding it we're smaller
batch when we do like Gil when we wash
we're we're not a big setup we're so low
Tech honestly it's it's kind of funny
even but we're you know we're learning
to bump up our volume our water goes to
waste at this point we compost
everything else we just really really
love our compost so I know I could tell
on the farm we we give waste to that but
um yeah haven't I I haven't dabbled into
the water we've talked about the water
like how to isolate it chill it almost
how to serve it if somebody were
interested in wanting to actually drink
some of these things the fruity ones
smell kind of good at some certain scale
and again Marcus I don't know if you
could comment to this but can you you
could almost steam to still that that
Turing I know where you're going
listen this this takes us back okay this
takes us back to about maybe 2014 how
old is Hash church are we like six years
old old right what the hell okay so get
this K from triome Technologies hits me
up one day and he's like working with
Sasha shulan doing TPS and stuff and he
says listen I'm gonna give you a gold no
no he doesn't talk to me dude at all he
won't even reply to me when I hit him up
and say please let's be friends like I'm
so story like he when I partnered up
with Tony that was like the ultimate
slap in his face selling the turps but
listen it gets this is how it starts
this is why and Kenny are pretty close
yeah yeah absolutely I also don't speak
with Todd anymore so neither n nther
there what I wanted to say was
this
so he calls me up he tells me listen I'm
going to give you a gold nugget you need
to figure out a way to get the tpin out
of the bubble water and like put back
into the hash that's it you figure that
out you're laughing and I was kind of
like okay yeah that sounds you know like
not like I haven't thought of that you
know but and realize that I don't have
the tools to get such a thing done so I
phone two people and I tell
Tony and I tell
Horatio and I say Hey listen like you
guys need to figure out how to get the
bubble water the tpin out of the bubble
water you guys got access to labs and
you can do this get her done well this
is only my guess but my guess is that
Tony at the time was at a pretty big lab
visiting in uh Florida and I suspect he
was standing next to a chemist that
worked in that lab and said hey how do
how could I get tpin off of plants and
the guy was probably like you can steam
distill them or hydrovac diffuse them as
long as you use a chiller to precipitate
your uh your um your Vapor it'll
precipitate clear instead of yellow cuz
it's generally in that process that it
goes yellow which I didn't know uh but I
talk to a chemist myself and that's what
they said and I see Mark waving his head
up and down not interrupting me so he it
must be
[Laughter]
correct anyway Tony had like okay yeah
Tony had turps like a week later but
from FL he didn't even bother with the
water maybe it was even two weeks later
but it was like we'd have to go back and
we could look at hash church because
that's how we'll be able to figure f it
out but it was quick and then I called
Horatio one more time and kind of busted
his balls and I was like hey you know
Tony's got the turps what's going on
Horatio and he had them like I don't
know two or three days later and that
started a whole thing which actually
helped both of those guys and I think it
helped the Cannabis world and all of us
to have access to those Tarpin and this
dipping river right Mark it started Blue
River absolutely 100% of course that was
the start of Blue River so it was a
really neat thing that all started here
through through hash church and with Kay
and so you know at that point Kay was
feeling that he I I don't know he said
he had a patent or something on all the
ways you could make tpin with cannabis
and and it just was it it just all went
bad I felt really terrible about it
because now I don't really speak to any
of those guys and I kind of had you know
I had love for all of them I enjoyed
talking with Todd I enjoyed talking with
Tony I enjoyed uh talking with all of
those guys and so Kay especially Kay I'd
known for almost 20 years we wrote for
Redeye magazine together back in the day
when Nick was still alive and and doing
that so sometimes life plays out the way
it does you know you can only help to uh
figure it out and heal so I'm sure
there'll be a time in life where we can
hopefully come to that point where it's
just like because I know I play a part
in it I don't pretend to think that I
don't go ahead Colin you guys will come
back together man you will you guys were
too close
man yeah I was there for it he thought
that somehow in in Indra had gotten
together with um there's a group out in
California that was selling a cold trap
that people were hooking up to their
vacuum ovens because for a long time
people didn't realize that these tpin
are fleeting fleeting meaning that you
pull them with your vacuum they're gone
they're out the exhaust and so if you
cold trap that and I don't know if you
remember this episode Mark there was an
episode of hash Church where Tony was
sitting in the lab for that episode and
he had the cold finger in the back but
he was like really kind of like Hush
Hush about showing exactly how he got
this we see he had a couple vials in
front of him that he was dabbing but he
didn't want to show his Tech when you
know we it was funny because you're
you're absolutely right the way you
recall this timeline was absolutely
correct because I had had several
multiple hourong
discussion where didn't include Canada
but he can call me and talk for
unlimited time so he would call me and
we talk six to eight hours at a time and
I describ you know basically vacuum
distillation and cold traps and all that
and he figured it out and and
um we I shared a lot of this with Tony
because actually my coming on to Hash
church was at Horatio's insistence
because Tony was trying to talk [ __ ] on
this whole turpine isolation thing and
and Horatio was sending me Facebook
messages saying Mark you gotta come on
Tony's talking [ __ ] on half church again
you gota come on and set him straight he
never said that to me he just said oh I
want to invite this this chemist Dr Mark
on and I said all right man it's yeah
that's that's how I came on so how
interesting that all these episodes
later here we are talking about it again
but you know still even at you know best
friend's Farm level I mean I always feel
like you know whenever you I've only
done small scale water hash production
and I always feel like man I I want to
do something with I can't just like what
do I throw this away no there's [ __ ] in
there there's stuff in there that I
want what are the right methods to
isolate it and and use it
okay what's this we're looking at here I
don't really have a comment as far as
isolating the tpin out but from a living
soil situation or perspective I had the
pleasure of working with Steve cwell um
in NADA out of green life Productions in
the beginning of December and he was so
excited to just put it back into his
soil that's what he wanted to do with
the water and totally makes sense too
right organic we loaded it right in you
know yeah you know what I'm saying the
plants the plants respond to it
dragonfly Earth medicine I mean tpes is
just lowly fruit bacteria is all over
that [ __ ] in hours and that stuff is
gone metabolized mineralized call what
you will it ain't tpin anymore as soon
as you add
soil some of the some of the cannaboids
are hydrophobic so I would imagine Mark
that you you know I I've done some
experiments where you you just you
distill some things you distill it down
and try to collect that and then you can
use a little bit of that
material um to go back into have no
problem breaking down hydrophobic [ __ ]
hydrophobic hydrophilic they could break
down everything except carbon bonded
Florine they can't figure that out just
yet you know they'll figure it out after
a few hundred million years so I think
tinctures and and other formulations
that require the water since in my
setting I use all Ro everything's clean
so it's clean in clean out um so you
could you could use it in those those
specific use cases such as different SKS
that have drinks or teas or imagine a
tea you know that that would be
something that you could definitely look
into um there's there's a lot and then
obviously feeding it back into your
system if you um if it checks all the
boxes and you can do that in your
respective
environment but that's what I've seen
but uh yeah I think um if we had someone
develop a system to kind of catch some
of this stuff I think it could be
helpful I would imagine that would have
a limited shelf life like you couldn't
just formulate it into say like a drink
and again just to go back to the GMP
discussion you know trying to
standardize production on basically a
waste product something that's going to
vary from batch to batch have
inconsistent level of tpin because some
things are more tpine Rich to and others
so not only will the tarpine profile of
what's in the water is going to change
but the amount is going to change and
for most Farms it may not be worth it
again just to return it back to the soil
is just a great utilization for it I
just imagine that again if you try to
store it without preserving it it's
gonna foul pretty quickly so that goes
back to it's a c item to cozies around
the cans that get soaked with this
material are probably going to end up
smelling pretty foul unless you clean
them out on a pretty regular basis so
again that would be something that GMP
would want a regular record of how often
does that cozy get taken off that can
how often is it cleaned what's the
procedure how do you know that it's
cleaned and you know so GMP just affects
your production on whole different scale
that you know you don't necessarily
think about when you're just doing small
scale Artisan type production absolutely
yeah I think the the product would have
to be cold chain through and through to
your point otherwise yeah it's going to
ferment there's going to be well not
only that but it Dam straight better be
like fully organic and regenerative and
sustainable and not like poisoned out at
any point in time because that's uh I
wouldn't want to be pouring that into my
plants I wouldn't want to be drinking
that I wouldn't want to you know I mean
definitely it's drinkable like right out
of the thing you can just drink the
water I mean in in a regenerative sense
right like that's the whole thing you're
just like oh my God I just made tea
thank you I'm gonna drink this you know
but you can we've carbonated it before
too and made like beautiful carbonated
hash water out of it and served it up
and gorgeous little champagne
flu it was awesome have you fed it the
animals I'm wondering if
water I
think you broke up on us there did did
you say you
fed I know we put it under the
microscope in Vegas me and Steve and a
Jeff hello no we've been hey is he still
with us go ahead go ahead go
ahead if you can
go you it to animals
yes okay never
mind go ahead
Gil oh no sorry sorry uh I'm still new
to this guys I'm not I'm not used to all
the group conversation on I apologize
to the listeners but uh yeah no Steve
was really excited like I said give it
back to the plants and I'll say one time
we were kind of like lazy about it I'm
not trying to like uh we left it in the
machine overnight you know like and then
cleaned it out the next day and I'll say
the water was drastically different than
when the next time we evacuated it right
away out of the large vessel into a tea
Brewer you know it was still very very
very cold obviously you know we were
using it for ice extraction um and
overnight we brewed it we arated it and
when we came in there was stuff going on
in there it was it was fairly Barren but
like you'd find these little pockets of
these like you know little communities
starting to develop and we definitely
saw you know bailus Rod shaped Backus
some Oculus again not definitely I'll
never say definitely because like I'm
not really great at identifying stuff
you know you got to really stare there
and watch it move around for a while but
you saw some things you know what I mean
and uh to me it was proing and it was
cool um obviously you can't really see
um tpin under the microscope per se you
know you're just seeing the biology but
uh the plants respond to it um instantly
like when uh he foler sprayed it um you
see the plants love it he watered it in
um I thought it was cool he was really
into it to me it's just a way to keep
you know the loop closed def do
something with the water rather than
nothing but uh again I'm sure Mark can
tell us some more stuff or tell me what
I just said was possibly wrong well I I
would I would just add that you know
like depending on the volume of hash the
ear washing and the size of bed or the
size of soil that you're working with
there is a level of residue that kind
comes with having you know this water
you know so we found like if there you
know if you were say doing it every
single day and every watering you were
using was hash water you would start to
see a little residue develop on the top
of the soil and we really find that
that's the overdone part of it we find
that you know for like outdoor sungrown
Gardens and what we're doing is if we're
washing our own hash then we're we're
putting the right amount of hash water
back into the soil if we were to be
taking other people's hash or or other
people's material and turning into hash
water maybe it would be too much but it
seems like in a garden Clos Loop
situation if you're washing your own
plants then absolutely got to put all of
that water back into the soil we've been
like drawing thousand foot 2000 foot
hoses forever from our washing stations
just to make sure that every single
green Greenhouse is hit we do it all
year long even now we'll be gravity feed
ho hoses will just go from our you know
hash station down to the next greenhouse
and whatnot and we're just locking in
you know that water but I do I do agree
this that that water definitely needs to
be used fresh it's like it's like cold
pressed juice you know it's not
something that you you let sit around
because it is it's living especially if
you're using fresh Frozen if you're
using fresh frozen then you're getting a
lot of that bacteria and fungi and
things that are in the plant you know in
the water and and then when you use it
uh I think that would be really smart to
to maybe use keer crystals and do some
kind of a keer water fermentation with
that um another thing I would say is
that we tried to use the leaf afterwards
because it's really easy to put the leaf
back into a compost system or some kind
of you know top dress and a beautiful
thing but then I was like oh we should
try and make bokashi from it um you know
so let's try and ferment it with lactic
acid bacteria so that we can lock in
this green living nutrient you know with
this lactic acid but then we found it
got
really uh sour fast and there was a lot
of water in it so then we said oh let's
take the leaf and let's put it in an
apple press and press all the water out
of it to try and get it as dry as
possible so we making these like Leaf
Pucks in the in the Apple press and then
pulling them out and then erating in it
and it was like oh it was really nice
but then we found we still needed to use
like half organic brand or some kind of
uh sawdust in with the green leaf in
order to
get fermentation because once you
started putting that leaf back into a a
a a closed system some type of bag or
some kind of
and try and ferment itashi for future
fermentations it would just sour off
because too much water it would it would
have an an the Anor robic Anor robes
would come and overtake so you needed
that that dryness and then a little bit
of like either sawdust or some type of
brand some kind of brown material and
then saturate that with some kind of
lactic acid bacteria or em or some kind
of fermenting and that was the way we
had success from turning the Leaf into a
bokashi and bokashi is just any brand or
any Leaf fermented that's just a blanket
term for you know locking lactic acid
bacteria earlier ear you guys were
saying you know how is it that we can
really save these tpin well we feel like
as cultivators the way that we can save
the Tarpin is just give it back to the
soil because we've definitely noticed
you know since we've been doing that for
the last 15 I don't even know we've
always given Back the Water it just
always made sense to us our tpine
profiles and our breeding and everything
is just really well especially in a hug
hugle culture carbon Rich carbon
sequestration bed system you're just
like saturating it's this green turp
water and this green turp water just
wraps around all these rocks and sticks
and stuff you're just like oh hell yeah
that's my system you know what I mean
and it just turns into future crystals I
mean hopefully we have crystals in the
soil to charge up the crystals in the
plant because they're all crystals and
so that's the thing now we're going to
start seeds really soon we should really
think about starting seeds on
crystals feeding it with your hash water
right from the very beginning so right
from the germination a little bit of
hash water because then you get to teach
the plant where it's going to go later
in life why not well you're teaching the
bacteria that's in between these
chemicals and the plant where it's going
right
right so yeah it's like the people who
germinate their seeds by you know
putting them in their mouths first and
letting the Amala enzymes and their
saliva kind of like be the first you
know moisture that actually gets inside
the seed when it germinates people think
that again that's a way of sort of like
personally putting your you know sort of
thing on the plant but you know the
thing that I always like about like what
you guys say is that everything you say
is that what you're you're sort of
feeding this this chemical biome or this
chemom or whatever it is I mean it's
like there's these chemicals and these
nutrients that are being
supplied by the fungi by the bacteria
and fungi again just plays such a huge
enormous role in everything that we do
in this living world fungi are just
everywhere everywhere right and the
bacteria is just everywhere so it's like
they play such a vital important role in
life itself and if we think again that
we could somehow you know use
antimicrobial agents or disinfect
ourselves to be completely clean we're
we're were dreaming and that's just
again a
misnomer of you know people who want to
you know take an antibiotic as soon as
they get a sore throat because they
think that whatever they have it's
something that's going to be cured by
some pill and it's an antibiotics so I
can take it that's no
good anyway I think if we're using the
hash water and the T TP water because we
do it for the turps like Steve cwell um
I think that we're maybe feeding the
ganja terpenome I mean it's a biome you
know but it's a ganja terpenome because
we're just recycling TPS but it's more
than that of course different than a
misnomer a
Tome
maybe and maybe it's a TP
gnome potentially you know on side notes
on a side note I did watch Chile's son
again the other day go through his tpes
language I just like randomly cracked it
open and showed a bunch of people in my
lab and they were just like whoa that is
ridiculous who is that guy classic
Moment In Time classic Moment In Time
classic shout out to the
tpn is
that Chile chil are you talking about
young turp young turp I am yeah yeah no
that's awesome you know what's really
funny about that you know I just cracked
up so much kind of uh you know whenever
that is just going off um but you know
over um over the last many years we've
been uh kind of aggregating all our TP
data and we we've created uh what I've
been joking we referring to as uh
Rosetta Stone to learn how to speak and
teach
terpanes um you know which is a like a
classification system that essentially
sorts tping by primary mono and sasco
tping content you know into the groups
that we see out there it's actually how
the emerald cup
is going to be um judging flow this year
so all all flower entries that are
entered the emerald cup are going to be
um chemotype right tested for Canabis
and turps and pre-sorted um into their
primary turbing groups like all mine
together mine all lmon together limine
all tpine with terpinolene and then
judges are going to get uh entries
anonymized that they're going to be
judging within each class and kind of
choosing Best in Class um so it would be
top one two and three of each tpine
group and then those Advan to the top 20
that essentially would be uh judged
heads up
wow how cool is
that that's pretty [ __ ] cool right
that's super cool I want access yeah
we yeah we're stoked to kind of uh you
know work with em Cup on that because uh
you know we see you know it's you um you
know of the six primary groups you know
once you start seeing how all the data
sorts you start really identifying kind
of what defines what what actually
defines Rarity versus overabundance you
know beyond just the hype strain of the
day name type kind of way that it goes
you know describing things as exotic
this and that but um you know by you
know we're we're hoping that by sorting
it and kind of having judges judge it in
that way you know we're helping to kind
of pay pay tribute to the real diversity
of what the plant has to offer you know
because you see then kind of are able to
give tribute to to these you know Ultra
obscure rare profiles that you know not
only aren't really identified as rare
but they're not even really they're
they're kind of just masked you know in
in kind of the the way that the strain
name name game goes you know all that
certain like aome take on the take on
the popularity of of March Madness you
know how people get all all excited
about about that college basketball
tournament that happens every March [ __ ]
that tournament dude T yeah and you can
almost have like teams rooting for
different Tes you know you have like the
mercing team and the
T I'm on team tpin I don't know about
you guys but that's my team bro that's
my dude give me the gas give me the gas
you can have you want give me the gas
but again Alec again Alec just not to
interrupt this is going to be quick I
literally was thinking osine right
before you said it and I know we had
this happen last uh episode as well so
go go ahead and mention Michael book
yeah
um yeah no I appreciate appreciate the
Mind meld we got going um but yeah o
osine I like calling it aamine um you
know it's it's like a kind of sub
turpine that we see either track with
mirene or we see track with terpinolene
you know and so so usually it's masks
like there'll be like a huge mirr scene
Peak you know and then like a third of
the com third of the profile of the
mirring peak will be awesom me you know
but that profile all of a sudden makes
up super
Gunk mango papaya Dream Queen Green
Crack In the Pines pineapple you know a
lot of that subtropical fruit type
pineapple is what I associate it with
yeah totally totally you know but it's
really rare pineapple whenever I smell
Pine yeah totally and uh and so we but
we see it like less than one% of the
data um um we we'll see aamine as the
primary dominant tpine and there'll
be an absence of mirene you know and so
so so we see certain you know kind of uh
you know recessive fenos isolated from
certain things like in the Pines
pineapple um just like you're describing
that will be yeah awesome and dominant
without mirene um and then we you know
like uh in the emerald cup a few years
ago um green shock farms uh gentleman
named Mark he he won a most unique turp
Award with a stream called tropical
sleigh ride and it was an awesome IND
dominant Peak um but yeah so that
represents you know because we see what
the way we see it all kind of sort and
break down is Mir scene
you know like is the most overabundant
turpine it's like it represents like 43%
of all the profiles of what we see um
you know so a lot of mering in that way
um and then um then we see Cara offing
is about 23% of the data um uh um loning
is about 16 177% of the data but and but
what what you'll notice is lmon and
kopling usually track together so a lot
of the most
popular TRS right now now the gelato
kind of wedding cak TR dessert type Prof
it en lening and Carling but together
those turs are Up Is Down about 37% of
the data um so they're getting close to
me and you know I I speculate that this
year you know because you see it happen
with the name game the way it happens
you know a certain strain like gelato
will get incredibly popular and then a
few years later everybody's growing 10
acres of it you know or I mean in
literally like I guess literally in this
new licensed world
you know and so so
so in this hard you know the market as
that profile you know it better be
really exemplary you know kind to even
be able to be sold you know and so so
you know kind of we're trying to hope
we're hoping that you know the way that
we we're coming to understand the way
Turing sword can help in diversifying a
portfolio to not get stuck in this like
you know narrow game of you know kind of
getting caught up in the floods but yeah
so so anyway so sorry so there's miring
43% of the data kopling lyine together
is about 37% of the data then
terpinolene um is represents 10% of the
data um um Alpha pining so turpening
like the Jack train re Sage Durban you
know uh Super Lemon Haze like the
very a t type
turp um and then P Alpha Pine smell
represents about 6% of the data and
that's really rare oftentimes people
will confuse pining with turpening tpine
kind of smells little piny but you know
all those strains kind of the Jack train
Rec
Sage don't have any pining at all in
them pretty much but but then there's
actually true Pine smell where it's
similar to the aamine it'll be you know
because usually when pining is present
similar to aamine um it's it's in the
ABS or it's it's it's masked by the
amount of Meine so there a lot of Meine
and a little bit of pining and that's
like blue dream and streams like that um
but it's really it's like less than 6%
of the data when it's pining dominant
without miring so we'll see C trains
that'll be like the top three turbin
will be Pine Alpha pining lmon beta
pining you know that's a really
fascinating profile too because pining
when together with THC helps to decrease
the negative memory impairment effects
that THC has in short term um so you
know that's just a rare profile overall
so like six% and then there's the aamine
Prof which is 1% you know when so but
that's you know we we pretty much see
you know from the 160,000 tping tests
that we've done since 2013 2013
um when we sort worked to sort it all
and uh with with some bioin from
mattis's help uh we came to see that
there's yeah six primary tping groups
that really are defined by the mon monot
Turing content um beta care offlin is
the only dominant tping that's a that's
not a monot A tes turpine um but but so
we see six primary groups and each
primary group has like two to three
subgroups but we really see about like
yeah like 13
to archetype profiles pretty much
dominate everything we've ever tested in
California and Oregon you know across
our data
set but
um yeah go ramble on about
that which one is a canabo anot
turpine
um beta yeah yeah beta caropine is
a antagonist but that doesn't mean it's
a I I guess you know again you should
draw the distinction
not based on what biological receptors
molecules bind to but what the
structures are themselves and just
because you know beta copyline has
activity on CB2 doesn't mean it's a
canono it's canono receptor antagonist
but you know yeah yeah it's the only
turpine that's known to bind to an endoc
canabo receptor I think so I think so I
think there's some other analoges that
are related to bet caropine so humulene
I think also has some activity like that
and I think that the other oh uh it's a
kopine
oxide which I think and isn't yeah
totally and isn't isn't
talene like the isomer of beta car did
you just say that yeah hum yeah yeah
humulene and beta kopine are related to
each other in the fact that exactly
right Alec they're isomers of one
another and beta copyline has a very
peculiar four meem ring with a very
large other ring where huming itself
just as one large ring so it's the same
atoms it's same Tinker Toys just
connected at different spots Mark
doesn't it have three uh isoprene units
yeah which makes s yes yeah yeah it's a
it's a it's a CES turpine I think Al
properly said that yeah so SES Turpin
are c15s not c10s right and
what's what's really
fasinating
about from what we see is kind of point
over station's been going you know the
tpes are precious and they they're
fleeting you know kind of depending on
how they're car they're they're cared
for and preserved and you know the most
of the primary attributes that
contribute to the secondary metabolite
expression of the turpine content in the
strain you know are the monot Turpin so
Li so loning Meine pining terpinolene
and aamine and like Len I mean there you
know which are some subt Turpin and
they're they're all monot Turpin and so
those are the quickest to go away at the
lowest temperatures even at room
temperature they
can monoid though right so little rule
is the exception to what you said right
totally thank you I appreciate that
turine because it has a oxygen on it
it's reacted with water so it it's a uh
it's what we call a
turpenoid because you could call it a
tpol alloid t turpo
so geraniol is also another example C
camper yeah um uh uh eucalyptol these
are all alcohols that are derived from
tpin reacting with water and now
incorporating the water molecule into
the structure of the compound to create
a what's called a hydroxy group which is
notably an alcohol right well and and
and and you so so and and
to to kind of wrap that you know so so
you know really you know so we're
testing for like 36 uh tpin um and
terpenoids U um at SC labs and you know
essentially across our entire data set
we really see about five to nine turpins
to find you know
95 percent of the profile of every
turpine test we've ever ran right and so
you know we test for eucalyptol and kind
of geranial and certain things um but
you know um they're
you know tpin you'll signy amounts kind
of that complement the pro profile but
most of these tpin you show up in pretty
much non you know non-detect amounts um
so it's really fascinating to be able to
start to characterize you know kind of
and sort you know kind of everything
we've tested by these you know really
five to nine turpins that Define the
primary and subgroupings and how it
happens but but kind of um just to kind
of wrap the point on how precious tpin
are you know um we see really like from
the time of
harvest you
know
[Music]
through you
know you know kind of harv like from the
time of dry to or harvest to cure you
know so it's like what time of day are
you harvesting you harvesting the middle
of the sun you harvesting in the middle
of the night kind of around the full
moon kind of thing you I think I was
hitting on this before um on uh you know
I think last week maybe um but then but
then what are the conditions that are
being pres that that are taken to
preserve these monot Turpin because
they're the ones that are so fleeting
and um and how they been being extracted
and all that but but but just um I did I
did I mention schwag flag last
week no all right cool right so so so
yeah I didn't want to be very redundant
so so it was fascinating because when we
started aggregating all this turpine
data that we've tested over the past um
you know kind of since 2013 um you know
there was you know everything was
sorting in the primary kind of secondary
groupings that we saw everything you
know kind of very um predictably Sor
into and um and and then we we had like
an outlier Trigger or like or an outlier
flag so if anything if there was a
profile that didn't match kind of these
these very predictable groupings then it
would be flagged for secondary review
and and that's where I was most excited
to kind of really dive into the data
because I was like oh man that's where
the most trippy land race obscure like
turpine profiles are going to be
and and um and like in within that you
know that that that dat that I was um
you know there there was a tiny
percentage of that data that were super
defined aamine or pining Ling
ping type like really rare Pro Data in
there is was the artifact of what we've
come to determine a schwag right and so
so so basically when all the monot
Turpin and cesco Turpin that really
Define the value of the profile have
gone away and volatilized or or degraded
then the only Turpin that remain are
these highest of boiling point turpins
that end in an O so like neurol bisol
guol FAL right so so so we came to
create this like um this this this
uh yeah well so so so basically
whenever I love it the swag I want to
see the swag yeah swag swag flag so so
so yeah so so we so basically um yeah
whenever all the mono and cesco turbines
are gone there's a condition that we see
and it's basically the pro it'll be tot
less than half a percent total tpine
content in the material and the only
tpin that are high or kind of you know
showing in the expression of the tpping
profile are these tping so yeah so
that's just so so but we just thought
that was really fascinating because you
know it just kind of really dug into
just uh
[Music]
discover I mean it's always how precious
the turpins are and how they are really
what Define quality you know the
presence of them with THC and the
cannaboids and the relation the ratio
but whenever the tpin I mean it could
test 35% THC but it could have the swag
flag turpins and guess
what that's like a 90 to1 turpine to
canabo cannaboid turpine ratio that's
like that to me that's what defines
biomass you know like there's no more
value to represent that material in the
market other than than to distill it
right know and so but if it's like THC
but it was like harvested it was if it
was grown in living soil and
regenerative conditions and the
secondary metabolite production doubled
and there's like 5% tpin in the dry
flour because it was you know harvested
around the full moon at night and dried
cured preserved immaculately you know
that's like 5% turps and dried flour so
like 15% that's a 3 to1 canab Turing
ratio right now how how does play a ro
offer and
nothing totally I mean you know they're
definitely having a role in the flavor
um and you know kind of you know the
overall kind of bouquet I I guess like
um for your I guess your you know your
your that type that area of your sensory
system um but we we are starting to
develop some testing for additional tpin
and um some Trace compounds like
flavonoid and th and um but um but yeah
it's it's interesting because you know
we see you know like of everything we've
tested you know we're like we're we're
we're separating and identifying the
primary majority of everything that's
there in the chromatogram you know but
but time you will see these little
unknown kind of tiny Peaks you know in
the chromatograms of these certain
things that we're not testing for you
know because each tpine it each time we
test
tures you know we we we have a runtime
you see Columns of over 90 minutes per
test per sample you know and we do that
so we can get as much separation of each
compound so that we can see all the
trait you know so we have no Co illusion
and then we can make sure that each Peak
and each you know is is what we're
actually testing for but you know from
time to time yeah we do see these little
certain Trace peaks of certain compounds
you know and my my one of my partners
Jeff Gray he kind of it's interesting
because he Likens it to
you know if you if you're making a soup
you know and you have all these
ingredients and spices you know it's
like you c c there all things aren't
created equal because you know you can
take a teaspoon of salt and throw it
into the soup and maybe barely affect
the taste but you could take a teaspoon
of cumin and throw it in the soup and it
just completely changed the overall
profile right you know and so so even
though these certain Trace kind of
[Music]
compounds might not like make up the
profile you know clearly they are having
huge contributions to the overall you
know flavor and Aroma you know certain
things like you know there it's believed
that like the the gas the fu gas skunk
turp are are in fact skunk turps you
know like like thols are skunk T are
Turpin from skunk and so you know
because you could take the OG kush or
gorilla glue or what have you profile
headband profile and you know you could
recreate that you know mixing Botanical
turps or what have you you're not even
getting close the smell of of that gas
fely kind of type Prof
right yeah I've never so it's certain
things maybe you know that are doing
that so it sounds to me like your your
your correlation between Harvest times
uh temperature relative humidity in
which you're you're uh you're drying and
your Cur is um play a major role in all
the different varietal that you're
seeing come through and all the
different test that you're seeing um
across the board through the years it's
now I have a question are are certain
varieties uh historically just speaking
Broad Leaf and narrow Leaf uh are you
seeing the hybrids or certain varieties
that come through um test higher
consistency because I would imagine that
you're seeing many different types of
quote unquote headbands come come
through um and many different types of
test results come through because of all
these said you know points that you
you've brought up such as you know the
medium when you actually Harvest it how
long you know it went for um is there
anything that you you can share that
you've seen um that may point to uh uh a
more hey you should do more of this and
less of
that um well so on the on the expression
side of things of
within the plant you know I mean that's
where kind of I've so much like love and
respect you know for the reality of the
soil food web and Dr laning gam and and
and just how much kind of cannabis
Farmers have really put you know organic
farming potential and how to grow the
how to grow plants optimally by
understanding the soil microbiology it's
like that I mean we I feel like ganing
gums kind of received like Saint status
from you know cannabis Farmers that have
now brought her so much more legitimacy
as
a microbiologist in the world of
microbiology than she's ever had you
know and is helping to elevate the
potential of farming you know and she
shows that through you know when you
find the right fungal bacteria
ratio you know that you're cultivating
the plan under you know then you can I
you know it seems like cannabis is one
to one in that way from the little I
remember you know from kind of you know
how deep I was on it back in the day but
you know she's been showing side by side
by you know with hydroponic kind of or
whatever other type of cultivation
method you know she's been showing and
substantiating the ability of you know
farming to produce um and influence
secondary metabolite production so you
know with tomatoes she's been able to
see like doubling of secondary metab
content from lopine you know whenever
you have this
soil microbiome you know like really
respected and worked out expression is
going to you know the whole conversation
around appalachi of origin you know is
going to it's not just going to come
down to regionality or you know it's
going to come down to the farm
conditions specific and how the plants
are being grown or how the you know soil
conditions are
being created
um it's because there's that side of it
and then you know there's you know then
there's the preservation side of it you
know we're working with certain groups
that are doing live resin live resin
like live rosin uh harvesting right so
they're you know they're they have the
teams and they're going out in the
fields and they're you know harvesting
the plants and prepping them and kind of
getting them in freezers immediately you
know and kind of where you know we've
been worked with them to where they're
harvesting kind of in the middle of the
night or you know early in the morning
right before the sun comes up as opposed
to you know in the middle of the you
know Peak heat of the afternoon and you
know we're you know just from kind of
the return in the extraction process
turn is difference on the Turing content
itself you know whenever there's these
certain considerations around you know
Harvest Time of you know around the moon
cycle around the you know these you know
these what you know just ensuring that
the temperatures that you're exposing
the plant to during time of harvest and
then throughout the process of drying
caring yeah you know ever you know
reaching these certain temperatures
where you're going to be compromising
the
Turks yeah I always see you know you
need to be around 68 relative humidity
55 or you know or or Andor throttling it
really paying attention to the materials
is super super key um there's no Silver
Bullet to dry cure it's all very very
specific to that time and that varietal
or that variety I should say so hey
there was a question for you Sam have
you ever smoked isolated novel phyto
canabo like 331-8358
right I figured I it sounds like it is a
synthetic cannaboid Alec and uh you know
what that [ __ ] scares
me it scares me too kind of I kind of
like certified by Mother
Nature cou with synthetics is people
haven't taken them very long and we
don't know if they're safe maybe they
are maybe they're not but uh yeah I only
have one brain to play with so try to be
as we say by safe go ahead as we say
yeah I mean I think Deno factor is
large what's that
Alec um I was I was just gonna add like
you know in the world of like these like
synthetic compounds or analog compounds
off of the original molecule you know
synthetic canabo do scare the [ __ ] out
of me but it's
fasting you know how something like the
compound of mesculin and then the the
compound of 2 CB you know 2 CB is
incredible incredible medicine and gift
of Alexander shulan
blesses so um you know and you know and
that's you know seems incredibly you
know safe and effective and you know
kind of controlling dose and you know
effect um but but you know it's it's
fascinating how these Endo these
synthetic cannaboids you know that are
largely
untested just they have such rate of
effects that can be half hazardous or
negative to
use I think often with those compounds
they have a potential long-term
degenerative effect if overused in the
case of MDMA and 2cb that their um micro
doing capabilities and they're euphoric
and they're they they're dips into you
know a calm you know meditative placees
as except Ally beneficial and it's
amazing medicine in the in the overuse
of it or say the non you know
pharmaceutical ways that you may get it
can definitely have a degenerative
effect on your neur neurological system
so I think it's always safe to say that
the the the the plant compound itself is
going to be the one that's going to be
healthy for your you know corrective you
know therapy that you're looking for
well apparently the 33 whatever 18b was
isolated by Dr DD Mary Mii from a plant
in technician lab
Israel so it wasn't a synthetic one it's
isolated from a plant it's hermesa ucin
who's in the chat room talking about 140
different conoids been found in the
plant is my understanding Mark probably
has better
number actual but yeah there's all kinds
of different conoids that the cannabis
plant makes and I want to throw out that
I think that uh the real beauty of the
cannabis plant is that it comes with
this whole soup of Tarpin and other
canono and that's where some of the
benefit and magic of the plant really
resides Blessed
Be yeah and things like MD I totally
agree with that you know the other the
other compounds that we were talking
about before the the hallucinogenic
compounds and so like if you're familiar
with Sasha shulan's books so the P book
so the phenethylamines that I have known
and loved and so um the the
phenethylamines are similar to things
like elopa which naturally exist in your
brain and and
epinephrine and related compounds and so
the there are are natural enzymes in the
brain that regulate these these
compounds and you'll know that like
people who are who are diagnosed with
clinical depression will be giving
something that are called MAO inhibitors
and so Mao stands for monoamine oxidase
and monoamine oxidase is an a regulatory
enzyme that exists in the brain to
basically degrade these compounds and to
regulate how much exists in critical
synaptic Junctions that are responsible
for the underlying causes of depression
and so the other thing that you have to
think about like we were talking about
MDMA before and micro doing it's
interesting because micro doing seems to
tap
some different level and function of
these compounds in the brain that's not
quite well understood as opposed to the
guy who goes to the Rave every weekend
and just takes as much ecstasy as he
could possibly swallow I mean at some
point again you're saturating your
body's ability to basically degrade
these compounds and because they look
like compounds that are related to
things that are naturally in the brain
they're metabolized and then reuptake
pratically and so the whole basis of the
whole acid flashback which is where some
somebody just took so much psychedelics
and now pre synaptically they've sort of
reincorporated these compounds which at
one point flooded the synapse is now
coming back and sort of again the basis
of the whole acid flashback is the
reincorporation and utilization of these
molecules that you can definitely alter
your brain chemistry incredibly I mean I
Used to Know kids on on dead tour who
just took way too much
of these things and they just
became like walking vegetables like they
had no like they were more like a meth
head than like somebody who just smoked
weed or did psychedelics they they
became more kind of like of what you
would see for somebody who had a real
methamphetamine addiction as oppos they
got Sid
bared the inability to to have emotion
or show emotion it just became so
vanilla you know very strange yeah I
notic and I think your body begins to
depend on this almost there's a
dependency that um is probably underp
underpins the addiction to them but I I
don't think cannabis I I think cannabis
is kind of like again for that to me is
like the exit drug it's like you can
still get the euphoric feeling that you
get on psychedelics without completely
losing your [ __ ] by just having the
right type of cannabis I think cannabis
product and I know it's a completely
different set of molecules but it's
acting on the same it's a different set
of uh software but it's acting on the
same computer you know it's you're
you're you're not doing things that are
the thing with psychedelics and again
it's so interesting how when you look at
the chemistry of psychedelics how
they're very often these phenethylamine
type derivatives if you look at the if
you look at the structure of LSD itself
you could actually see in in the case of
LSD there's an indle ring which
basically defines the molecule itself
but you could basically map a molecule
of phenethylamine right over the top of
those and you could see where they could
fit in the same same receptors kind of
like as you know puzzles puzzle pieces
fitting together so it's really
cool interesting conversation no doubt
we've got uh we've got 15 minutes left
I've got a hard stop at noon today I'm
going to be hiking up the mountain
behind my house and going and seeing the
Enchanted Forest that's up there we had
uh a little girl in our neighborhood
here some years back now who was hiking
in the forest with a bunch of people and
I guess a boulder shifted and crushed
her and ended her life she was very
young I think seven or eight years old
and so they've created her parents
created a really beautiful Enchanted
Forest Way up in behind the house and
there's all sorts of little mushroom
sculptures and little people go there
and bring little things that they make
uh from memories that they had with
Aaron and the family and so I'm going to
be taking my family up there later today
and honoring Aaron and celebrating her
life as well as just enjoying the forest
with my family so uh 15 more minutes 14
more minutes uh than a hard stop so
whatever you do guys don't get into an
incredibly interesting conversation in
the next 12 minutes please or if you do
wrap it up in those 12 minutes well hey
what what's everybody smoking on today
just keep keep it light and Lively and
for fun and Giggles we haven't done it
in a long time but what are you smoking
on in
chat well let's see what they say it's
gonna happen fast strawberry
guava grapefruit deran
sugar lemon kush mins Georgia pie
with
Somey
Li I've got some dry sift cashis honey
cross with
canesu and it's a kind of a type two
blend that tastes really lovely this
afternoon oh that sounds nice I got some
Mendo breath from the dragonfly Earth
medicine I've got some concentrated X
cookies and cream hash rosin as well as
some full melt bubble strawberry banana
as well as some full melt bubble rosin
from strawberry banana all from
concentrated X I got a little bit of Los
Gardens in the house got a little of
that ka's coffee grown organically and
regeneratively out in the east side of
the country over in Ontario and uh a
little bit of grateful heads I got a
little bit of the yagger so you know
shout out to the uh Eugene family that
Jagger and lot everyone's hitting it's
like icy sweet skunk dream and Diesel
Crazy Train cheese Force zidle breath
dead Orange Dry sift AFU uh cream and
sugar soj Hayes banana OG GMO punch sfv
OG wedding cake chem dog Bean OG I mean
holy [ __ ] straw Nana times triple SE
from stle farms mother's milk crossed
with wook 15 there is some incredible
names blue gelato 41 sticky Barb that's
always a fun question to a ask because
truly there's probably like four three
400 people in the chat room right now
almost 500 actually so that's a lot of
people puffing on a lot of things and I
wonder imagine if we all just puffed a
gram during this church we would have
consumed half a kilo of concentrates
with just our panel and the 500 people
who are watching on the show that's uh
that's pretty cool anyway got some
triangle cush here some uh triangle wav
some lemon cake some Cho cookies I got a
gift here of some flour that I typically
don't have a lot of and this is uh I
believe uh I think this is uh cookies
and cream I
believe but
uh so much good stuff out there super
silver haze crossed with great white
shark old school AK-47 grin spoon
crossed with a Neville's Haze bubblegum
crossed with DEA GMO and STW guava Larry
Bird vanilla frosting mac and cheese
Rosen Kem deaem garlic juice it actually
just puts a smile on my face to read all
this right now has the world not come a
long way Ma and what am I missing here
it's a diversity of gen genetics and
access that people have compared to you
know a decade to go and to see all this
it's amazing I I love it and thank you
all for making it all happen and all
y'all watching it for perpetuating it
y'all are awesome yeah I got this great
little run up here I got lyy OG OG Kush
wedding cake girl scope cookies girl
glue number four and Bubba cush like
that's just a nice little package it's
beautiful not too shabby I will say
Johnny B not too shabby package right
there foot look at that and and I went I
went to local store and I picked up this
OG cam dog and you know
what it's it's OG chem dog it's fire
evergreen's hitting that skunk ran over
by a blueberry truck with a burning tire
how's that that's like I want to I want
to be over at evergreen's house hitting
a little bit of that with just a hint of
burning tire you have to really cut
through the Dead Skunk and the blueberry
truck to get to that burning tire sort
of
off off rubber taste yeah I love the
smok more rubber band the better that's
bad the more rubber band the better
smoking some guava punch I could do a
whole show on Alec talking about the
tpin and the groups that they fit into
man like I'm telling you I'm sure that's
probably I really would love to see you
standing in front of a board one day
with them all written out and circles
and put a book out or something like
make that information available because
it's Priceless and I personally will be
going through everything you said later
and kind of creating my own little graph
with that because there's uh there's
value in
that I'll send you send you some cool uh
cool cool stuff we have a presentation
by um for sure we just yeah we we've
launched this like phofa report so when
you know that's a foundation of a
classification system
cool man very cool hey Alec I know that
they were um Emerald cup is going to do
an indoor certification as well are you
all going to be having intake of that of
not certification indoor competition um
as well are you guys going to be able to
intake with tpine ratios like that
because that would be really phenomenal
to see the differences of tpin from the
sungrown that you're working on and then
move over to an our competition with the
tpin is that in the in the mix coming up
um well so so so we're we're we're tpine
canono testing all flower entries across
categories so and the the ameral compan
is doing indoor this year for the first
time and um and they are also kind of
paying tribute and recognition to third
party certified organic type Farms you
know kind of Uhm
certified all um those others around
and um so it'll be really interesting
you know to kind of analyze and see see
you know both you know from from flower
you know grown
indoor cross but just to kind of compare
some of the around turpine canav
expression compared to the mean across
all the other data um and yes super
stoked to connect and share more about
that I'd love to show you some more on
this Turing
system so I'm super into seeing some
like Alex Gray style sacred G
like meta turine canabo art you know
where we start seeing where the tpine
profile file over fire whoa but anyway
the uh the tpine profile overlapped over
the canabo and how that creates the
effect because it's not just you know a
high terpinolene makes you feel a
certain way because it's mixed with the
canabo so really it's like this total
shamanic fractal medicine that we're
dealing with because like in in Gil's
case for someone who's you know say
growing from all seed you know every one
of those plants are going to have some
fractal epigenetic difference you know
and it would just be really cool to be
able to overlap the two I don't know you
know and then also breed with uh you
know the real putting tpin out front
breeding in accordance with tpin because
I think it's really interesting that
took our two highest lemon SL
terpinolene strains on the property and
it came out like
so not lemony just like aamine really
earthy gassy every single time no matter
what so it would be really awesome to
talk about like the marriage of the tpin
and then what they turn into but maybe
that's the great unknown genetics and
breeding it's the great unknown but it's
also you're kind of creating the Cheta
Stone you know for us to be able to
speak chines you know so we look to you
for guidance yeah thank you for being
there for us Alec we love
you yeah that's
awesome
tpes
um Kelly I I noticed a difference um
from growing a lot of these uh East
Coast you know chem dog sour indoor and
outdoor um a major difference in
profiles from outdoor to indoor um Sour
Diesel might be one of the hardest
varieties to actually grow well
indoors um from growing a lot of it over
a long period of time and I prefer the
outdoor to be honest and Greenhouse
grown um version of it it's um there's
nothing else quite like it to be honest
and I I I stand behind that I have to
try that
then yeah it's it's fascinating but I
see
it I see it well I say it's been a
wonderful show I sure appreciate
everyone for coming in and hanging out
from Gan Gill to etan Fontan to skunkman
Sam and Johnny B to Colin and Brian over
at best friend Farms Dr Mark in the
house Kelly and Josh from dragonfly
Earth medicine Alec from SC Labs
breaking it down for us and of course Mr
Wade laughter one of my favorites just
just being in the room he sets a tone
and I just sure appreciate him as a
human being as I do all of you in fact
uh as well all the people who are in the
chat room hanging out and sharing our
time right now thank you all so much for
hanging out for us P Church 3.0 episode
14 let's do it again next week make it
episode 15
just keep doing it peace out everybody
thanks for coming good love peace
y'all thank
you peace