release I was gonna maybe start with
micah bubbleman you got something you
want to say oh I was just gonna say
there's skunk Mans here as well if you
guys want to hear a quick intro from him
I know a lot of people know a lot about
him but it might be a neat thing to hear
a couple of words from from the man
himself yeah definitely sorry about that
I forgot
[Music]
no problem whatsoever here he is now
howdy howdy howdy everybody in hash
Church yeah my experience with green
houses was I built my own green house
about 40 years ago and then I moved to
the Netherlands where I ran many many
many professional green houses with
computerized darkening computerized
watering and and my favorite way to grow
is greenhouses although there's
but IIIi I've been there I've seen most
of the changes we were one of the very
first in the world to use darkening for
to mature cannabis flowers in the when
we were in the northern environment in
the greenhouse and if anybody has any
questions I'll be happy to step up to
the box but except for that I am what I
am and I think pretty much everybody
knows me Sam I don't know you I would be
interested to hear about your
progression of you know greenhouse
growing and some year maybe your light
deprivation experience yes is it on it's
on howdy howdy
I've been grown in greenhouses ever
since the first year I grew cannabis in
Santa Cruz that was in maybe 70 72 or
something route like that and that was
just a homemade primitive greenhouse
what's and friends of mine were doing
darkening for sexy not for flowering but
for sexy and that was in northern
California but one of the problems with
the sexing was at that time they didn't
really understand what they were doing
so they would darken it for two weeks
until the plant showed sex
whereas well the research that I found
when we were doing the research in
Holland was that most indica varieties
you can darken for one day and then two
weeks later they will show sex they and
they were not staying long and with with
vege with a uh excuse me with sativa
varieties sometimes they need to be
darkened two or three days at the very
most but then two weeks later they show
the sex gist and so it's I mean I had a
friend who produced thousands and
thousands of seedlings and then darkened
them off just for sexing to sell early
known female plants to people and a few
times he because
darken up for two weeks they would not
come back so the customers were rather
irate that they had these little plants
that were you know two feet tall and
flowered off and they would not return
veg can you also tell the story of how
you discovered like greenhouse light
death in greenhouse light depth what
happened was I went into a course anthem
of greenhouse cuz I was interested in
building my own greenhouse or or buying
one or renting one or whatever and so I
saw the chrysanthemum darkened to induce
flowering and I a light went on in my
head and I went Jesus Christ I mean I
had seen people darken plants with a
tarp in the late 70s and early 80s but I
wasn't interested because I I wanted a
greenhouse it was multiple acres and you
you can't hand Arkin multiple acres well
actually you can if you have enough
labor but it's so that's I saw what
darkening could do I instantly
understood what this was for cannabis
and so that was I don't know maybe
eighty six or something like that and
but what once I saw that yeah I never
stepped back for for the Netherlands you
need darkening because you you can you
can grow multiple crops a year or you
can grow one big good heavy crop and
darken it and get it out before the cold
it comes and your heating bills are ten
thousand not what it's a day a week and
can you also comment Sam on earlier Mick
was talking Michael was talking and he
mentioned how he kind of likes to keep
them a little bit smaller which might be
perfect for what he's doing and and
producing super high quality flowers but
you came in as a sort of like oh I'd
like to have really big greenhouses and
maybe just talk to wire that is well the
main reason is is I like big plants love
the work I'm doing is not commercial
production
it's breathing work and for breeding
work I start seeds thousands and
thousands of seeds and then what I do is
I I want to pick the best plants and
2bic the best plant from seed it's very
difficult to do with a little 1 or 2
foot plant you grow at 12 feet tall you
get a really good idea of its positive
and negative qualities and for for a
breeder it's it's really required so I
that's why I had a very high ceiling my
ceiling was well maybe 20 feet or so and
I could grow 15-foot tall plants if I
want get 3 4 or 5 kilos of dried
material let me ask you Sam about the
sexy one more time you know for people
that are you know maybe don't have a lot
of power still in Humboldt or you know
these Kraft farmers if they were to sex
their plants like you were saying how
long if it was it's depending on strain
you would say but if somebody was to do
it would you say to darken it for a day
or two instead of the two weeks like
your yeah and because I experienced the
same thing I've seen plants that didn't
come back out of the veg and it was a
huge pain in the ass could you talk a
little bit more about that like your
recommendation is my mic on okay then
the main thing is that cannabis will
take two weeks to express its sex but
one or two days of darkening is enough
to trip the expression two weeks later
that's the main thing you have to
understand with earlier varieties only
one day if it's a very late late
equatorial variety maybe it takes two or
three days at the very most and then
when you put them back on a long cycle
two weeks later they sex but they don't
stay flowering face are totally veg and
you grow them really really big and then
fly them off and you know what sex they
are that's almost like at the end of
that you should also say you're welcome
because that was a gem right there
absolute GameChanger thank you for drop
that knowledge I think we hope that you
know what I mean like can we can't we
quantify things with lab tests sometimes
because I know that I've talked to a few
lab companies that have said over the
course of time some of the greenhouse
material they've been testing has has
tested higher in the THC CBD and even
the terpene percentages and I know that
the terpene companies bubble man maybe
you might know something about that with
greenhouse material and the terpene
production that you might have heard
about or known yeah okay yeah
you know right through Toni's mouth
almost always the light that the
greenhouse is going to produce like a
way higher level of terpene production
you know not just a smaller amount but
like a substantially larger amount and
not to change the subject completely but
while I have the mic one of the things
Sam was mentioning about greenhouse
triggering flowering as well
particularly in I guess it was in like
close to the equator countries where
they have 12 hours and 12 hours of light
and darkness and often people are trying
to grow with added lights additional
light they'll maybe put it on for
another five or six hours Sam have an
interesting bit of information to share
on that tropical cannabis growing yeah
that's basically what we found is that
we eat in the Netherlands when I would
grow big giant plants at 1012 feet tall
over the winter I could give as little
as I was using these little 60 watt blue
incandescent agricultural balls from
philips and so they were geared towards
but but they were only 60 watts and i
would use one of those for every 10
square meters so that's a hundred square
feet and it absolutely prevented
flowering and not not only that but you
could use as little as just in the
instead of giving them six or eight
hours of flight to keep them veg but you
could do is just in
the middle of the night give them two
hours of light that's all they needed oh
yeah I've been doing this for 30 years
that's a big one for people that have
been especially in countries where you
know he was mentioned like only having
one generator only being able to turn on
enough light in one section of the
greenhouse if you do a quarter here a
quarter there a quarter there and
instead of leaving it on for that I'll
just tell you how severe I've done it
I actually was storing trance under
refrigeration at about plus three four
degrees so they're in a frigerator with
lights and all's I gave them was 15
minutes of light four times a day so
every five hours I'd give them for five
or six hours I give them 15 minutes of
light totally prevented flower and they
stayed veg they also weren't growing
because it was so cold all I was trying
to do was keep the plants alive as the
library did you see that there was any
reduction in actual growth Oh bro
practically they'd under under three
degrees there's practically zero growth
mmm I wasn't trying to grow them I was
trying to maintain them yeah yeah but
Mike I guess my question is is you know
I think some people would argue will
they keep all these lights on because
not only do they want to keep the photo
period going but they're also trying to
have the plant grow at the same time so
I'm just curious if you saw any
difference at any point in your in your
experiences where there you could see
like a difference in growth growth rates
the more lumens and the more hours of
course you're going to get more growth
of course but that wasn't my goal my
goal was to I had big plants in the
ground which I could served in my
greenhouse
I had a small collection on on fo tables
under under halides and just as a
library and I had a third collection in
I had specially made like a refrigerator
with lights built into it which and in
those I
I gave them as little as an hour a day
if broken up in 15 minutes so that they
never received really long periods of
dark at any one time awesome information
yeah I just met a guy in Humboldt a lot
of my research comes from old old-school
growers in Humboldt County and they said
the same thing Sam was saying as far as
keeping the plants and veg the guy came
here recently and did a greenhouse tour
and he goes no I only have my light on
in the middle of the night for one hour
in the wintertime to keep him in veg and
I thought one hour and so yeah to save
on generator and power and all these
things that people deal with they can't
use all this electricity or access to it
maybe in the middle of the night you
know so when he told me that in the veg
period he that he only uses the light
for one hour in the middle of the night
I was just like holy crap and now I'm
starting to hear little bits and pieces
of it and then of course now Sam is kind
of confirming that whole thing too so I
mean I'm gonna try it you know like I
think it's pretty cool I want to try the
sexing stuff and play around with all
those things I like doing experiments
and less time less lumens maybe two
hours to prevent flowering right so keep
that in mind is your sort of recipe as
you get into it well yeah because sorry
so that I'm just want to make sure I'm
hearing you're right so the thought
process is don't don't give him a long
period of no light you're saying just
break it up and you're turning the light
on for 15 minutes every hour yeah I've
heard that and I know Sam was saying
that for his library and part of his
experimentation was to keep these plants
from growing but to keep the library and
so he said he'd dosed him in a couple
times 15 minutes at a time if I heard
you right Sam and then at two hours and
what he were just confirming was the two
hours for a low lumen light right
exactly thing you wanted to share
about talking about lumens but basically
what we found is that absolutely need
lots of the lumens to produce biomass
and vegetation is flowered halfway or
more and pretty much all so it's going
to do then is fill out the flowers and
maybe add a lot of weight from resin and
stuff I found lower light levels I'm
talking about from the Sun or from
artificial lights actually produce
superior product also what I found is
that the high temperatures associated
with flowering really high temperatures
it's not really positive because it has
a tendency to vaporize terpenes right on
the plant so lower temperatures a little
bit lower lumens I found produced
superior product here when we were on
mute that will do you want to mention it
Sam I just wanted to mention that when I
grew the denti-cal clone big small even
in vitro so that the flower doll plant
was only maybe an inch or two tall when
it was completely flowered in agar agar
in vitro in a test tube the resin is
much smaller the resin individual resin
heads on that plant when you grow it to
3 feet tall like you're talking about
four C green or something the the resin
is is quite a big a bit bigger but when
I grew my same clone and it was 12 feet
tall the resin was again a little bit
it's important it's important to me we
we missed that last that last little
part but
well the the last little part was that
if your plant is 12 feet tall and you
flour it off and then you collect the
resin from that it's again a little bit
bigger than the 3 foot plant the each
individual resin head is a little bit
bigger and for hash makers that's
important