hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world welcome to have
Church episode 158 did we miss an
episode of hash Church here recently cuz
it feels like we might have missed the
first ever hashed Church episode last
weekend well we did I was camping I
tried to make it happen
coming back from camping I even tried to
make it happen more it did not happen I
want to apologize to everyone for
missing our first episode but we're back
we're here we're rocking we've got a
Sunday show for you here setup so I am
going to send out the link to the
panelists I will see what they are up to
today I think I had an email open up
here somewhere didn't I didn't I have an
email set up to all my friends yes I did
and it is gone I closed it closed it
like the fool that I am so I will send
out that link again hope everyone's
doing well I want to actually say happy
birthday to my good friend
bingo Lombardi and by a good friend I
mean a random dude that I talked to a
lot in a chatroom he's been a supporter
of the wake-and-bake shows he's been a
supporter of of the hash churches and
he's in chat right now and I figure the
best thing for us to do is maybe puff a
little Bowl for hit oh my god that's oh
it's hard oh that's pretty good mark
well played hey guys doing today we're
doing really good you got like you got
like Jerry Garcia and like a little walk
you got a little walk there like I got a
Wookiee here yeah yeah that'd be enough
fish to her oh yeah that's cool home we
bring in glass and nitrous out a lot
there yeah there he is selling Jerry
Jerry Garcia bootlegs from 78 little
girl Saunders no he's just he's swinging
some glass just trying to make it back
out to the west coast oh [ __ ] he's
swinging glass all right well glass
hasher ass
nobody rides for free at least that's
what they said on the bumper sticker so
how you been there mark missed you a
couple weeks there yeah doing well um
gotta say happy birthday to our friend
bingo right yeah happy birthday bingo
yeah yeah things are going well
beautiful beautiful well I'm gonna take
I'm gonna take a bong rip for bingo
while we wait for the rest of the crew
to uh to make an appearance yeah fish of
course I've announced that they're
playing four shows at the end of the
year in Madison Square Garden
so that means they'll have done 17 shows
in Madison Square Garden in 2017 so
that's kind of cool I tried to get some
tickets me didn't work out what's their
attendance I said I tried to buy some
tickets for the four four four day run
at Madison Square Garden I figured you
know what I just want to be a part of
this in some some way or shape or
another even if I got to buy some
tickets and give them away on my show
how fun will that be but right or they
were you know how's it going Peter long
time no see dude give them away on my
show oh you got a you got a mute the
YouTube show yeah this is the classic I
I even took even today after one hundred
and fifty eight times I was like oh I
gotta mute the YouTube video or my voice
will start sorry that I missed the the
three year I had strep throat man my
kids got me all [ __ ] up with the
organism dude the mic mic dude I thought
you were like am i a I was just like
damn Peter used to show up and now he's
just like am ia must be busy I love
coming and hanging with you and having a
sundae a hash hash joint Justin in honor
of you bro well there you go dude I
appreciate that I'm down to uh I'm
have a little puff let's make it an
honor of bingo Lombardi though cuz it's
his birthday today and well [ __ ] he's
always in the chat room he's always
hanging out with us and I just know that
it makes him happy every time we mention
his name every time we say happy
birthday bingo let's possible for bingo
he's just one of those zany cast of
characters that sits in chat waiting for
church every week and I tell you Marcus
I was like in that group of people who
were really worried about your safety
because when we didn't see an episode go
up for there to have a chat last Sunday
everyone started wondering you know is
there gonna be an episode and I
immediately is like oh I hope Marcus is
okay I hope he didn't like you know
drive off of some you know ravine
somewhere you know he's in stuck
somewhere incommunicado because it's
very unlike you to have the episode
already up there and then as soon as the
episodes up there people start gathering
and started having chat dialogue and
that that is that's where bingo is like
one of the you know one of the cast of
characters that's in that chat every
week with all kinds of interesting stuff
to add and say so ya know it was kind of
crazy dude I mean I I ended up camping I
ended up out away from anything and i DM
was like I'm not gonna be there for the
next two weeks dr. Natasha it was like
I'm gonna be in Europe and I was like I
don't really have anyone that I can get
to even run this show and I woke up
Sunday morning and I was camping with no
Wi-Fi and I was like I don't know how to
pull this off I just I don't know how to
pull this off so here's a bong rip for
hash Church for Miss and Hastert sorry
for everyone that thought I was dead I
guess when you're consistent in this
world and you miss something
people are really thrown off by that
[ __ ] absurd am and she was partying with
me and she didn't even remember you ho
ho how soon were forgotten how soon we
are forgotten in the Catholic Church if
you miss a week you miss
a session it's urge I think it falls
into that bucket of venial sins I don't
really know what mortal says I think you
have to go to a confession booth to get
down on your knees and pray that you
missed an episode so maybe we should all
it's taken me I'd any pray for
forgiveness I guess during the American
anthem you know I even tried to come
home that night I tried to set up an
evening sermon I thought would be a
great idea but my wife had been dealing
with our kids for four days straight by
herself and it was just not the right
thing to do to come home and ignore her
and the kids and go right into another
show when really I needed to pay
attention to my children and I needed to
pay attention to my wife so I chose my
family last Sunday and so I hope that
you guys can all forgive me I do
apologize for not giving anyone a heads
up whatsoever but sometimes that's the
way it goes in the world of hash Church
it's so when I chose wisely yeah let's
go on D 420k mother lobber lovers
everybody today on this fine fall
weekend what are you eating turkey
dinners tonight and all that stuff for
tomorrow or both no we don't have that
only in Canada yeah that's in November
in in America they do it in November
which is why the cannabis cup in
Amsterdam was always on November
Thanksgiving weekend I must have done 20
[ __ ] Thanksgiving US Thanksgivings in
Amsterdam over the years it was it was
always nice I don't know if you ever saw
Sam but Doug would always buy
Thanksgiving meal for four you know the
hoodlum guys the hemp works and and the
sort of bubble crew as we were all kind
of one at our booth and we used to do
the old the Thanksgiving dinners in in
Amsterdam for the cannabis cup yep my
life is to bake a big giant fat turkey
almost every Thanksgiving
here we go what do you think in this
outdoor check to check check check check
check check you guys see this outdoor
yeah it looks respectable all right yes
yes guess how much this outdoor is here
in Canada five hundred two fifty one
dollars five hundred and fifty one
dollars the place is right up here
totally that's Canadian dollars that's
about ten bucks
yeah it's about nine dollars and 53
cents American per pound of this herb no
no joke
six hundred Canadian dollars probably
400 to 450 US dollars for this no but
obviously they got you to buy it so it
works
I didn't buy [ __ ] man people just give
me buzz all right you got me Sam thank
you for laughing that way D that's
exactly how we needed to finish that
particular that was a belly roller that
was like Sam's going hard as [ __ ] oh no
Sam have you even wished bingo Lombardi
a happy birthday yet no but I'll sing it
happy birthday to you mr. president mr.
president that's pretty sad you know
what you don't know right now bingo is
that Sam is wearing the most beautiful
Marilyn Monroe dress while singing that
particular so huh hey welcome Wade from
the House of laughter you are in the
Church of laughter right now we're Bella
rolling over here this morning glad to
hear it
yeah you know it's all good I'm glad
your Internet's working and somehow the
clouds cleared and you're able to visit
us on this beautiful fall afternoon
somewhere not here yet it's 9:00 in the
morning but somewhere it's afternoon
yeah beautiful it started getting cold
the flowers are filling in really
grateful today still alack still a lack
of precipitation down there we had a
light sprinkling of rain that's what
we've had weeks ago but that's about it
yes wait I saw in the news that the
grape growers up in Northern California
it's been so hot and dry recently that
the grapes are all withering up and
getting you know they're having a real
problem with it
yeah we I don't know about the vineyards
but we have some wine grapes here we
don't really make wine with them but
they're turning into raisins on the vine
Wow yeah I saw they were harvested in it
and they were they had machines that
were trying to set the real grapes from
the raisins it's been a hot dry summer
in Northern California after all that
beautiful rain we had this last winter
yeah it's been great for BC I mean all
the people I know that have plants in
the ground still I mean lots of people
have harvested already it's just been
months of beating hot Sun and of course
anyone that grows in the Pacific
Northwest knows well that it's kind of a
throw of the dice whether or not the the
incredible rain you know like basically
powdery mildew just is like what's up
what's up BC here we are boom and just
like people that have beautiful plants
are they just get decimated so quickly
so I know a lot of people are happy
right now just with this endless endless
Sun that we've been getting it's pretty
damn sweet alright well I feel grateful
it's really been beautiful weather hmm
absolutely I feel that I mean man I was
camping last weekend it was like perfect
you know went camping the whole weekend
and it never rained which really liked
it's not like I'm hate the rain but it's
just like fall in the Pacific Northwest
when it starts raining it gets cold
and kind of miserable quick can really
come in and destroy things quickly I
want to share a funny story about myself
this past week on Tuesday morning about
4:30 one of my dogs was making all kinds
of noise in the middle of night and
there was extra noises involved and put
on some clothes grabbed a flashlight
went out to see what was going on and a
fairly good-sized raccoon had taken one
of my dogs into the pond
oh yeah and I had seen earlier in my
life I saw a dog get drowned by a
raccoon
it wasn't my dog but I saw it and it was
horrific and this raccoon was climbing
up on the head of one of my dogs and I'm
here to testify to a couple of things
one it's a really terrible idea to go
into a pond to try and separate dogs and
raccoon oh man because you can get tore
up Jesus but the second thing I'm here
to testify about is cannabis creams tink
creams that are formulated for pain
relief really have remarkable antibiotic
and antifungal properties my the wounds
on my hands are healing up beautifully
and I did a little experiment a couple
of days ago where one of my hands I
slathered in a cream that we make and
the other hand I left it alone because
there was so many bandages but and then
I showed it to my doctor and I and I
told him he knows what I do and we've
talked a lot about it but he can't
recommend anything of course but I asked
him can you tell which hand I've treated
with cannabis since this happened and he
took one look and he said oh yeah that
one and I said you're right because all
of the wounds all the inflammation and
redness around all these bite marks had
disappeared on the hand that I was using
cannabis on and we're still pretty angry
and inflamed on the hand that I hadn't
used it on just a little testimony
compare your body I love your positivity
you come in to tell us
you got attacked by a raccoon and
instead of being like man like who I had
a rough couple of days you like the
wounds the wounds on my hands are
healing beautifully this look man well I
guess the moral that story is if you're
gonna wrestle raccoons have some
cannabis cream on you or or a flat brim
shovel like something or a couple of
[ __ ] dogs yeah raccoons raccoons have
opposable thumbs so they don't really
[ __ ] around you grab a hell I grabbed
ahold of him and he grabbed ahold of me
and that's what scary
went back and forth and they got those
claws yes laws that go down it's like
whoa yeah all the way down my wrists and
tore up both hands I had about five of
them jumped my dog in the backyard and
they they they punctured his throat
fifteen times he had fifteen little
holes as trachea and so he survived it
he survived that he survived getting run
over by a car I survived getting
attacked by coyotes my dog stuff is [ __ ]
your dog's been run over a couple times
hasn't it Wow only once by a car but he
got run over by a little boy when he was
a puppy on a bicycle that's how it all
started it all started with him getting
run over by this bike and then he
started hating things on wheels and it
we you know he'd be attracted to them no
matter how hard I tried to keep him away
like break free and then go you know
[ __ ] with cars go barked at cars so now
I have the invisible fence and he can't
go anywhere and he's alive and healthy
and happy so take care of your pets out
there man especially living in nature
like that's not even bears imagine if
the bear just came down and just like
gobbled my dog but like raccoons and
people and coyotes like it's an endless
they are no joke john vidal they are no
joke we are in their land we've only
been here a short time they've been it
yeah not to mention where we're just
like they can live in the land
and survive and unless we have a lot of
things to take care of us we tend to
perish like we need to store food and
have fire and like have a place that
connection and don't forget Wi-Fi
internet connections so we can Skype
late-night bong rips with my good friend
skunk man Sam oh my god
what a funny episode of hashed Church
today I feel good about it myself I
think it's because I've eaten a pack of
these gummy bears from from the Kennedys
I'm just gobbling down a little bit of
their stuff and puffin on some MKULTRA
that I pressed last night nice did you
uh announce that this was a farewell
episode or well I just you know I I
didn't necessarily announce that it was
a farewell episode I just kind of felt
like I felt a couple of times with
Church you know as much as I love the
gatherings it's sometimes overwhelming
last week was overwhelming I don't know
if anyone can understand what I went
through to miss the first episode in
three years I was like I was literally
having like nervous breakdown stress and
my wife was just kind of like you know
like is it supposed to be about stresses
because it seems like it's kind of
turned into a stressful thing that
you're responsible for these people that
you don't even know but you want to give
them this information that you're not
sure that they even already don't know
like just like what's the deal and I so
I've been thinking about it I I wouldn't
say necessarily that it's the end of
hash but it's definitely like sort of a
a change in a sense maybe some some form
of uh well when you got when you got
meat when you wouldn't I asked you about
it it was um it was interesting because
I miss I kept missing a lot more this
year and you know I'm I wanted to do a
reflection today if you know it's not
like a farewell maybe there'll be more
but like I think that we should we
should reflect today because we don't
have to worry well
Cathedral I am now the Pope well it
definitely I think that I think what
he's saying is that you know there's a
lot of responsibility that falls upon an
individual at 9:00 in the morning on
Sunday I myself am surprised it went 16
plus episodes because if I had a wife
and kids and it was Sunday morning and
it was 9 o'clock in the morning oh I
would never hear the end of it like so I
commend you the fact that you pioneered
through the wife and kids for how many
episodes a hundred and fifty-eight you
gave up a hundred and fifty eight Sunday
mornings to spend information in a row
bro
this morning what my two kids were
opening presents in yeah yeah a hundred
and fifty-eight in a row or all the rest
of the panelists and the rest of us so I
will chime in we'll come in we'll come
and go but like my hats off to you you
know like you went it's a strong run man
I mean another man and a tremendous
amount of information that has gotten
out to the community the industry the
panelists that are here and the
panelists that have come through I mean
it's a wealth of of information over a
hundred and fifty eight episodes I mean
I think there's there's there's been
there's been some pivotal points in some
of the conversations and how it
popularized different movements and and
also for all the patients that have come
on and told their stories some of the
things we've raised attention to when
this thing first started I remember we
were talking about like the whole BHO
craze because it wasn't a huge solvent
list movement and that's how kinda we
started talking with Johnny B and
Horatio and and the core of us we were
saying man you know this whole you know
be a chose taken off live residents take
it off there was like this whole
movement and there was a fear that full
melt or sift was just gonna vanish into
thin air
and there was a little light there you
know like well there's got to be there's
got to be another way to create a
solvent let's extract that that can be
popularized and thus flower rosin -
rosin and everything that followed it
episode 25 episode 25 and 30 were
powerful later I think yeah we can hear
you Johnny be awesome morning guys sir
I think also 30 was a very powerful
episode I believe it was 30 where
Jessica Hawkins came on and told us
about her daughter Naya is that does
that sound right to you guys that it was
episode 30 yeah we all cried on that
episode didn't we
everybody everybody out there yeah and
unless you didn't have a soul I think a
lot of people like that tune in you know
for the first time or even today or
whatever they don't they just see a
bunch of guys coming together smoking a
whole bunch of hash and I would I would
say this that like it's not I don't do
this every day I don't wake up and puff
as hard as I can to get my day started
this was the this was our religion this
was like the once a once a week or like
well that's how Sunday start is like
well I'd really love to wake up and
smoke the different products that I have
and there's different stuff that I've
gotten from people and it was like how
it started was you know we were smoking
whatever solvent less extracts we had
and shooting the [ __ ] and then talking
about information and every morning
well you're retired - he's not even
joking he's not he is not even joking I
wish I had that kind of it's he's he's
he's a religious atheist person the
first thing I do every day first thing I
do it's like I mean I do too but I don't
hit 60 dabs in a row no like that's what
people for like to remember how people
forgot around up
100 like why is that guy hitting dab
after damn after dabbing I was like ah I
thought that's what we're supposed to do
we're supposed to hit it as much as
possible and then there was episodes
where no one smoked anything and I was
the only guy busted in the background
for real
there was episodes there where their
conversations were so deep that nobody
even smoked once really yes wow that's
I guess we'll cry now we each have to do
158 right now well I'm not gonna say no
I'll get busy
that's like a team trip if Gauntlet we
did there hey oh they actually what I
really wanted to talk about was the most
viewed hashed Church episode by almost
like 4 to 5 times and that is in my
opinion episode 33 it is the hashed
Church that D 420k interviewed Jake's
wife what was her name again now
daily I wanted to say Guylaine gayleen
okay I'm on it so yeah and so that is
the most one of the most watched
episodes it's only a three-hour and yeah
it's a hundred and nine thousand people
have watched that episode and you know
she still eats a copious amount of oil
I made her a batch just last week of the
locomotion she does she likes the best
she takes a teaspoon or a tablespoon
sheets as much that would knock any of
us on our [ __ ] ass every day twice a
day morning and night and she's 100
pounds maybe 97 pounds carnie little
lady she is part art on set of
Parkinson's and she gets up and she
shaky and she's a typical human being
that gets up in the morning and looks
after her dogs looks after kids
everybody's growing up everything like
that and herself last if she would get
on the she's starting now to look after
self first take that dose a huge bong
rip of locomotion rosin hewed ste spoon
of the locomotion coconut butter and she
[ __ ] raw
all day at all she doesn't say it gets
her high it makes her normal makes her
like everybody else which is not shaky
it's kind of how I feel when I smoke
lots it just makes me normal you know
that's the best thing about cannabis it
it gives me that that balance that I
need every day and I think that's reason
why a lot of us use it is it's because
it balances it makes us normal thumbs up
definitely for me for sure yeah I broke
my back in my neck and every morning I
get up my back [ __ ] hurts man big
time one rep and I'm yeah completely
it takes it right away I'm sitting there
and all of a sudden like [ __ ] my pain
with my date it's hard to feel bad when
you feel good yep
did you see marks cow domes little uh
Jerry bear did you see that what was
that little thing there first set that
was a little Jerry Garcia with yeah yeah
with the one that was Chewbacca that's
so cool Chewbacca was selling glass
flipping glass on tour apparently the
cops took his case and Spokane and
smashed it over a great I don't know the
whole story but it wasn't good I wish we
all had our own little individual
stuffed animal that we liked resembled
something and we did this whole hash
search thing for 158 episodes through
puppet like Sam yeah
did Sam shoot his chin one time and
people were like started a thread about
it I was wearing a mask don't tell me I
remember that it's all part of the
thread cuz I remember there was a there
was a remember there was a time when uh
God the things been going on a while or
my my my mother had gone through a
divorce and she was living with me for a
little while right and she was listening
to your voice she was like who's this
mr. bubble man what a pleasant voice so
much information he said what's just
going on every Sunday hash shirts
because she was just like trying to
figure it out and one time she like
tuned in secretly on the computer when
she was listening and she was like you
know I get all the information that's
being spread and she's just an outsider
looking in and she's like what's up with
a little what's up with dr. Seuss and I
was like oh who's dr. Seuss
and then she's like yeah the you know
the little stuffed animal and I was like
what do you like what Oh
oh yeah yeah yeah the guy would she's
like why is there a stuffed animal
talking all this information she's like
why is there never a human there and I
was like oh well that person doesn't
want to be known and she's like oh it's
so bizarre you're like all in tuned to
this little dr. Seuss puppet and all
this informations coming out of a little
puppet it was like so funny how she was
describing like the the panel's you know
and she was describing marks marks
countdown you you notice I've got two
little puppets here today
that's because Ryan is the myth of the
rumor is that Ryan will show up any
moment
oh is that Pinocchio there that's
Pinocchio yeah not that Ryan ever has
told any lies ever it's just funny that
you made Ryan Pinocchio though of all
it's all stuffed animals that you have
over there yeah because we know you have
thousands Sam we know you have put it
this way my granddaughter has thousands
that's true
oh yes anyone that has kids knows the
deal on stuffed animals I'll bet she
does never will be so remember we also
did all right what are what are the
other top ten so we had that one you can
you quickly search that and view the top
hits of the top ten or is that hard to
do what about how many hours in the
hundred and fifty someone would have to
count all the hours it's a lot it's not
too bad 158 constellations
it just doesn't break it down very well
the way it shows but I would say our
wise oh it's been good so for I would
say why do you think three and a half
hours average weird something just like
deleted from YouTube that's kind of
scary
a hashed Church video I hope didn't get
removed 553 hours on average of
information scowled owns probably laid a
master course out
over the 553 hours so yeah and there's a
lot of information that has gone on in
those in those hours because thinking
about a course think about how long you
spend in a curriculum course you only
get an hour with the teacher you could
go three times a week for you know a
couple months you know what I just
noticed was episode 37 where Lester
Grinspoon shows up is almost a five-hour
episode yeah I was one of my favorite
episodes by the way then he shows up
again in episode 43 and it's also almost
a five-hour episode how about the wrong
video when it first come out in the
tshirt quick bomb and torch with paper
oh that was pretty cool that was with
soil grown so drugged yeah yeah that was
episode 25 and for whatever reason I'm
kind of in disbelief it only has 27,000
views yeah you had you had a AJ [ __ ]
sour guy you had Pinsky you had jibs
with you you know that day that was I
think even giddyup was there yeah yeah
when I was in Denver yep and then soil
grown dropped a whole lot of knowledge
that's amazing that giddyup was in the
room where's where soil grown like did
the one-inch punch to BHO the Bruce Lee
just like sure yeah it was that moment
for sure where everybody seems like all
right guys he's like so basically I just
got this t-shirt press here I made a few
modifications out of washer I just take
a bunch of blood and crush it up and put
it in here and I press down on it and I
wait and I do this and he like explains
the whole thing and you're like aha
uh-huh and he hope is opened up and
you're like oh damn there's oil there
and you don't think it's a lot but then
he shows you slabs oil that he's
collected you know like all he's a
madman he's just pressing flowers like
crazy ya know it's up there it was up
there with I can't get enough of the
[ __ ] it works it was up there with
bubble hash and the showing people
bubble hash in the in the late 90s was
was very much up there with showing
people rosin
you know being it go ahead Sam Marcus
what was the name of the guy who showed
how to mash it with the big spoon dry
sipped on the side of a silver ball
that's heated that's beautiful
that was Chadwick and Chadwick did that
under the name compassion with a pH
that's right yeah and I tried it it
worked but couldn't make it pure and
clean because you know I wasn't put it
in any kind of a little bag I just don't
think it was the the you know I tried it
also there was just not like his photos
were impeccable but the method just
wasn't easy enough for it to catch on
the way and especially because straight
up the whole that whole pressing you
know buds I think it really really
happened based on how solgryn told the
story was like you know he was doing
this with with hash pressing Ashley
happened because of the way that he did
that but I'm just saying somebody had
tried to do it earlier that's all oh
gosh especially to resin but the actual
flower part I think I think I think he
might have been first yeah because
compassion didn't do it with flowers he
only did it with either dry cept or
water hash ah yeah and that and that
ball things been around awhile because I
mean when I started growing in the 90s
and it was like early 2000 I remember
having I remember having a pot with a
little water turned it on put a silver
bowl on it just put lots of Keefe in it
with a spoon pressed it and it was like
this sweating like yellow hard yolk
because he posted it in like 99 mm yeah
exactly and then I tried it the problem
was which was like very difficult was
once you have it on the bowl was using a
razor on a conk on a curved surface yeah
you were like trying to get all this
like what barely was there out well that
was the problem and the other problem
was you kept getting rezoned rice it
into the stem stuff yeah you would so
yeah so I was like not only was it like
probably a 30%
yield it's basically like it was
basically like if we were talking about
grapes like we always do
I was like throwing grapes in a bowl and
you're smashing them once and then just
taking like 80% of the guts and all the
stuff out just a little bit of the juice
was there and you're trying to like
capture that you know it was like very
hard but it was the next step after what
we called like quizzo or whatever quick
wash where you take the remember that
stuff in the 90s you like quick wash
with ISO and out of like a grate and a
glass tray and let that stuff sit out
but really really cold
ethanol with sonicator for 30 seconds
and it came out beautiful yellow color
oil yeah well you remember quiz remember
quick wash however yes I remember but I
never used it yeah I was I remember like
97 or 98 when I went home for Christmas
I'd made some of that stuff and I've
just I can't remember exactly what it
was but it was like somehow used alcohol
I can't remember exactly what I did was
alcohol and something and it was like I
put it into a glass tray and it was like
evaporated the the alcohol off and then
you collected it with a razor and it was
like a green kind of hash but there was
like it was like this little tech that
people were doing back in the day but I
remember I mean if you smoked it it
really it really really really [ __ ]
you up but I remember that was the first
time I was like any kind of concentrate
at Christmas time
dude I'll tell you 99 the first time
while it was 98 actually but 99 when I
was able to start selling the bags and
showing people this hash that looked
like stained glass windows from a church
was always just like the most people
nobody had it like nobody had it
everyone
just it was an unbelievable time to be
the bubble man because I'll tell you
every person I showed everyone was just
like [ __ ]
that's some [ __ ] crazy [ __ ] right
there when I pulled out that 73 bag
every time the eyebrows
like from this to up here it was just
the full eyebrow rot rays it was like oh
yeah you just saw something that you've
never seen before holy [ __ ] I can't
believe it
just wait dude just wait and it was just
something really I'll never forget it it
was reminiscent a little bit of the
rosin thing you know being at spannabis
and at the booth there with Xavier at
medical seeds and showing like urban the
urban grow or Matt the great gardener
DNA like I'll Crockett like all of these
guys had never seen this process before
and we were showing them with a little
hair straightener right at the booth
that [ __ ] was pretty [ __ ] cool Jeff
Church was there doing demos you called
me
yeah from that experience you're like
bro take that take the 73 or the 95 Star
Plus and press it I'm like why would you
do that you're like just do it
25 and do it and we're doing it with
like other stuff I'm like yeah I don't
know and they're like I remember running
to the lab and and in Denver and doing
it and when I pressed it was like this
it came out like clear and then it dried
white I was like whoa micron drawing
screams I still press what those pieces
that I cut there at the beginning like
yesterday you know I would say one of
the most important things I think that
helped us in this discovery was like we
got became fascinated with with terpenes
in the in those episodes but it's really
interesting to look at them when you're
making a hash rosin or a flat flour
rosin because of you know the nucleation
or like oh why does it go from an oil to
a butter and like your mind just
automatically wonders you know what's
going on there and I think that of
recently like it finally reached kind of
that that the final understanding if you
will where we all kind of we get it you
know we're we're you know there's a
breakout that's happening in that
process to where you know at some point
THC a can be broken out and separated
from its oils and lipids and
and all of its things and so you know
whether you're repressing rosin
a second time like we talked about to
separate the THC and all the oil or if
you let it naturally separate in high
concentration of terpenes that whole
thing was discovered during hash search
like during these these episodes where
we were turning distillate into
crystalline and like conceptually what
terpenes actually do in in the process
so and now there was that recent study I
don't know if you guys talked about it
before when I sent you
yeah what'd you think of that one scale
down that was through proton NMR I
wanted to ask you that there were two
there was a recent study that talked
about using NMR to characterize strains
which I think you know I talked about
doing a few years ago but there's this
other study that looked at the
high-temperature decadence yes of
terpenes is that the one yeah yeah I
tell what before I go there let me go
back to something I just wanted to share
before I forget it which is that I think
whether you know this is like life
imitating church or church imitating
life I don't know which one it was but I
think one of the most important things
that the rosin thing did was it enabled
people to make oil anywhere regardless
of whether or not they have access to it
so like here in Pennsylvania in the
state's out east and everything people
were sweating because again there is no
regulated industry at least there wasn't
until recently that made you know closed
loop butane extracted oil so all the
kids were sweating now how do you get
going on how to get oil and they didn't
realize it and then basically a way that
with their girlfriends hair straightener
and some really good not they could make
oil and that was extremely and abling
for will make boil make oil safely
because people have been making oil for
years prior but we've had an increase in
people blowing up and burning themselves
very badly exactly and I think that like
a lot of people didn't believe it until
the hash Church or other things on
Instagram I mean everyone started
posting you know squishing nugs and
squishing hash and now you look at again
I think what tony was alluding to before
which is sophistication of this method
which can actually be used to purify THC
a itself from extract which is again the
star of the Shiva or a THC a that's what
everyone wants to be I think when it
goes back to like you're saying these
methods on bowls and all these things
were just sort of like ideas on how to
get the oil out what rosin did is it
made it impractical method that anybody
can do you know and you didn't need to
have you know access to good butane or
ya have to worry about residual solvent
because there's no solving issues so it
was just an easy way to make safe oil
and again like kids in the dorm who were
smoking weed those kids got caught and
they got thrown out of the dorms the
kids who were taking that same nut press
in the oil and doing dabs there in the
dorm fine because they weren't there
there's no stink in their room so I
think kids and the whole generation of
people acclimated to doing concentrates
and they needed to have a way and rosin
was that was that way that they can you
know that they can you know and I think
you know whether Church had something to
do that we were part of that wave of
getting the information out and you know
I mean now you there's a hundred
different presses that you can get and
yeah it's still a just a straightener
who works just fine great pressure and
temperature and I don't mean by a bag
and nugget ice cream he's find out what
the oil content is right I showed
everybody I use this hair straightener
clump and I did part TV I did everything
and that the be hom video just cuz I
thought it was just
larious and you know what truly that's a
there was a change in my life props
props to Nick Bradley for coming out
with the DeWalt the waltz yeah because
he he was the one that added the press
remember when you added that press thing
tear oh yeah I used the Gerwin that was
the first thing I did that much yeah but
it was it was Nick who did it with a
Dewalt first so I'm giving props to Nick
Bradley on chromecast Church yeah cuz he
was I don't know one guy got to give him
the others a thing we got another guy
who put it on vices that led to t-shirt
presses that led to the Sasquatch that
led to all different things we got
hammock clamps now there's all kinds of
great claps out there squishes rather
than in company well I think also it
brought a lot of attention to the
growers and and the method of growing
because you know some of the you know
benefits that we talked about when
you're using a solvent and you're going
through that process it's a refinement
and you're trying to decontaminate and
centralize your result like if your goal
is to get all THCA or all THC I mean
that's why you solvents and if you know
what you're doing you can you can have a
little bit more I guess you'd say
forgiveness whereas going through like a
rosin you're smoking everything that was
on that plant so I think what it did
because it remember there's that big
explosion of rosin and then there was
that realization of wait a minute wait a
minute we're pressing all of the
possible oils and everything on that
plant through a little tiny screen and
out comes oil so what about the bug
juice what about this we started joking
about but then it became a real thing
because you're gonna press p.m. you're
gonna press pesticides you're gonna do
you're gonna concentrate everything else
so now put a microscope back on the
growers okay there is this organic
at-home way to to make oil but then
what's the flower ants have to be clean
yeah so I think that Hastert's also
helped there because we brought a lot of
attention to organic growing clean
medicine you know and we were we were
kind of we were talking about that first
we were saying oh well you're right
a lot of BHO makers there's all memes
and all kinds of crazy stuff going back
to forth like if you smoke cross in
you're gay you know it are turns you gay
or something it was all these like back
and forth but at the end of the day they
are cut you know they it did bring a lot
of attention to that so you know when
something becomes easy like that that
you could do at home you just got to be
extremely aware and conscious of the
actual starting material because you're
concentrating whatever that grow or put
on there that's why I still you know
I've always liked just kind of like
washing the plant first or trying to
separate the resin even if you even if
you may it's so like an outdoor even if
you just did everything dry sift you
still could wash the dry sift and just
wash off anything that would be on the
resin so I just want to say that I feel
extremely gay after smoking rosin oh
yeah it just brings my levels up I feel
happy I feel i reaiiy feel gay yeah I
mean that's the point of it it's hard to
feel bad when you feel great resin in
Jamaica they make it with a bat and they
call it batty boy hash oh my god that is
not true that's not true raga Torrey
term Sam has the lowbrow humor that's
that well at least you know at least you
know it's like the ghost it's like in
the movie the Ghostbusters when they
spray you with the pink gel you know of
the goodness and they're like and then
that the guys get you know spray down
and they're just like totally in love
and hey man everything's great you know
that's like the rosin experience you
know that's I'm alright with that
experience at least you're not filled
with hate you know what well that's just
it could you imagine the rosin community
making memes that are like if you smoke
BHO you're gay like think of like that's
like like that's some twelve-year-old
ignorant [ __ ] right there like that's
like that's just very strange to bring
in someone's sexuality and to try and
like wait a minute sell in a new kind of
pot called sex pot for women it's
supposed to make you have more and more
frequent and longer orgasms so that's
the same thing and it
timeout women have orgasms well they do
unless they're married to you I just was
getting a laugh out a couple of the
married guys on the panel it's fine
little laughing little having fun
all right King Justin Hudson that seems
a little off but all right yeah because
I did because I do think there's some
valid information there then let's lead
up to that paper because that paper
there's a part of the discussion that we
completely missed which was another
conversation that hashed Church was very
much involved in and helped propel and
you yourself Tony was a huge part of
which is blue river and the first
cannabis derived terpenes that are
actually made available to people so
they can smell them and try them and
experience them and this was also a huge
huge part of the conversation that I
personally saw grow out of hash Church
and spread like a wildfire so that's you
know leading up to the paper that we're
about to discuss is the conversation
that was I mean keep in mind it's not
like we started this conversation Sam
started this conversation almost twenty
years ago but it goes to show you when
the time is right the time is right
because even K from trichome
technologies was had been on it for I
don't know if it was two years or three
years or if he wants to say 10 or 15
years but the bottom line is nobody was
doing [ __ ] about it until Tony and
Horatio stepped into the ring until they
both decided I'm gonna try my my hand at
making some terpenes boom Tony had
terpenes like [ __ ] two weeks later I
couldn't even believe it I was like what
the [ __ ] dude that's crazy like what do
you like what do you mean you just made
terpenes and then I kind of shamed
Horatio maybe a couple of months later I
was like listen Tony had those Terps
like a week or two later you got to get
on the ball and Horatio had terpenes
like maybe a week or two after that and
for me those were the first two
available terpenes that's great that Sam
was the first he showed me pure you know
fruit based terpenes or plant based
terpenes and the modulating effect that
they can have on cannabinoids
and Kay was one of the first people to
talk to me about cannabis derived
terpenes and terpenoids but tony was the
first person to put that [ __ ] in my hand
to put it under my nose to put it in my
dad Brig
and Horatio was the second so I got to
give both of those guys mad props before
we start this next part of the
conversation because that was a huge
that was as big as rosin in my opinion
making these terpenes become available
and not only that but lighting the you
know it's funny because I remember Kay
being like oh I was a little worried
about kind of wanting to put it out
there I you know he was worried that
people were gonna do it wrong this that
the other thing and there's that's
always the one side of things and then
you have the other side of things which
is well you know why don't we just put
it out into the world and we can let the
world decide and we can all kind
bioassay and go through this together
and that leads us up to where we are
well and I would add to I would say this
that in Johnny beat was there a lot of
the times to when we were in Amsterdam
and did this and there was even and a
lot of people missed this that there was
like when we were doing the steam tech I
was like oh yeah this is basically the
fail tech and there was some the
terpenes were different and and they as
there's not as there wasn't a purity or
stability factor to it or replication
and so Kay called those artifacts you
know barely barely shadows of their
former self right and and the other the
other issues I mean people don't realize
but we had this conversation for eight
months maybe even a year before it
actually got released oh yeah because we
were the whole goal I was trying to
create get these terpenes back into the
t'car of inactivated versions of
piranhas and stuff but these were these
were just like little side texts or like
oh maybe we could smoke this but I
remember was a year of us talking about
it and I had the same issue of releasing
it because there's good and bad that
comes with that a it'll get out there
people try to do it so I'm going to do
it with the you know in a way that may
harm people and looking back I think
that like releasing you know pure form
terpenes without like you know the full
studies always irritated me so I just
want you know want to put it out there I
do feel that like we didn't know you
know and we had these conversations on
hash Church and said what do you think a
safe range is you know how much is
president a flower flowers can have up
to eight nine you know I've seen 10
percent terpene profiles on flowers very
rarely but you know sometimes it's one
two three much higher on a concentrate
made from that same yeah you could try
sit in full mode have hit over ten
percent
terpene profiles so you knew that it was
there we were smoking it but once you
put it into pure forum people start
dipping it the whole dip dip in dabs and
all of that stuff like looking back how
how far terpenes actually go and how and
how far you what the use is now I can
turn one milliliter into a thousand
beverages and yeah you know and like
back then it was like one drop per
beverage it was like when we were just
pouring like those horrible it's like
looking back it's just like a little
juvenile you know so I would admit to
the the fact that like the going that
intense but it's like anything else
you're like you find something new and
you want to see how far you can take it
and at some point you have to know is
just gonna be okay for me as an
individual and if it's not it's okay you
might still do it you just need to know
what the safety the safety is you know
there's just like a jumping off the side
of a building on a bungee cord may save
your mate may work it may not cool up
jumping you know I know everybody showed
you a lot of good stuff with regards to
terpenes but I want to be the first guy
to to show you a turkey and being
created so so this is a strain of
different bacteria actually creating
terpene so that that bloom right there
is is an actual picture of a mature p in
process so I want to be the bacteria
again that shows you that
so explain that a little more so the red
circle is that a cell that's a terpene
that's an actual enduring metabolite
from the the combination of bacteria
creating a smell and actually producing
an exudate essentially or secondary
metabolite which is a 13 blue you know
what that's just like right on par for
the hash church bar that has been said
I'm always glad when you show up Peter
it's pretty cool on the cabbage you a
turkey meat so we'll go all the way back
to the small the small right the
molecular and you guys so much with it
and so so honored to be here with you
guys talking Terps well it is a big a
big part of the conversation as big as
rosin as big as anything else that we've
talked about that's a big big one of the
big conversations that came out of hash
church for sure was just all of this
interesting terpene information and
we're still like it's why you know this
this discussion that we're gonna have
about heating up terpenes and heating up
terpenes too hot the degradation and
what happens it's why exactly when blue
river was started that blue river wasn't
saying this is what you should do you
should take these and take huge giant
dabs and inhale them what we were doing
ourselves was bio a saying that very
thing
I was hitting pure terpenes through the
vapor exhale and to this day I'm
convinced that it was good it was in no
way shape or form did it feel bad but it
was also a very delicate heat it was a
very small amount of terpenes and did we
ever get too much did we ever dip too
much where I was like that's not an
enjoyable hit absolutely in the
beginning Tony was the destroyer this
person was first times in Amsterdam's
word our temperatures remember used to
dab at 750 than 700 then 500 now I'm
like anyone over 550 I'm like
well honestly for me the vape exhale is
one of the only units that does not
degrade the rip in a way like I can hit
pure Terps off the vape exhale in those
little quartz cartridges that you slide
into the tube and it is super enjoyable
you just at any temperature I have a
hard time enjoying it off of any nail
where it hits direct and and and
evaporates it's just violent and now we
have those really long we have those
really long skinny I just put a drop in
it use no heat and you just have you
just thought make it in you just breathe
in yeah well that's also all of these
little cool tops that have been designed
that you can put terpenes into so you
have your little turf cap that you're
hitting fresh terpenes that you're just
not heating up at all but it's going
through the pipe and giving you that
sort of you know it's definitely one of
the things that have attracted us to
canvas so it makes sense that in the
near future that we will take it as far
as it can be taken that much science
will be looked at and that you know we
the the guinea pigs who are using these
things in the next 20 or 30 or 40 years
will be able to clearly show people the
pros and cons yeah one thing to add on
that before Scout dawn goes into this we
once had a conversation about color and
how I got in that argument where
terpenes were seemed to give off some
kind of color because of all this
different stuff that out like if we had
the same base of hash we used different
terpenes we had different quote-unquote
color hash remember that mark mm-hm and
then scale down and then so there's some
things that I would wanted to update on
that because I've gone through a lot of
profiles now and a lot of different ways
of using terpenes whether it's in with
like you know a raw full spectrum with
ta-ta like from from a hash rosin or
live rosin or from flowers or activated
versions what I think it is is so like
so let's look at trippy and allene
versus humulin right so things that are
very high interpreting
so you would get like we've got one
that's like a Dutch treat
Jack Frost would be and they're always
they always produce a oil that's like a
clip like this this particular color
it's never a butter it's never it's it's
it's never a butter it's always an oil
it's always this particular color that
comes out some people would think that
oh yeah it's not a pure white color so
it's like this like it's not as
desirable but it's always got that same
time kind of taste and I think what it
is and you know that what I see is a
limonene data carefully and terpene
alene if those three combinations are
the highest peaks you get a certain
consistency of the oil which makes a
certain reflection or color based on
that that that profile influence and if
you look at something that's very high
in THC a meaning the plant itself and
the resin on the plant itself was was
fresh and didn't really activate much
and you were able to get like an 80%
rosin in THC a form and you didn't have
any terpene allene and you had and you
had more of a the humulin and the
beta-carotene and the pines you would
start to see more of a butter and that
has to do a little bit with the heads
and things but i found that it really
has to do with the profiles and then it
comes down to heat versus no heat and
different semi activation points and
different things so what I thought was
the color wasn't necessarily the color
but was more of the top tier profiles of
these terpenes that have the influence
on the consistency of the actual extract
that makes any sense somewhat makes a
lot of sense to me Tony it seems like
terpenes in some way would be a sort of
lubricant or solvent if you will to help
my internet drop down a little bit these
gotta catch all of what you said can you
go back just and just ask the question
succinctly if
yeah no problem so what I was just a
little bit of what you said yeah I was
just saying back then I thought it was
the color was the terpene thing and I'm
saying later that I don't think it's it
wasn't that at all
in fact what it is is now when I've been
it's like so what we've been doing with
our oil is taking like you know
extensive testing of the flour then the
extract and our final like Trinity oil
you know and when you start to look at
all of the different terpene profiles
because we're taking cannabis drippings
from the same variety and pairing them
with the extracts and they're the same
terpene profile but you get a different
percentage and consistency so as you go
from five to ten fifteen to thirty
percent if the if the trio of those
terpenes if the top one was terpene
alene almost every single time I've seen
the oil come out like this golden SAP
it's never butter and so when you look
at other ones like strawberry banana goo
it's always a white butter no matter
what and so we talked about hydrophilic
or hydrophobic and what they're doing
with the moisture but ultimately the
terpene profile in the in the top three
in the way that it's setting will change
this this consistency or this response
which then appears to change the color
but it's not a color thing it's it's how
the oil is these are all high THC
extracts yeah and then if you take those
butters and let's say try to act double
boil them down and act semi activator
activate obviously the color then also
changes as well but yes if we're
comparing just straight as raw as you
could go on on whether it was a flower
rosin or a hash rosin yeah so different
combinations of terpenes have different
solvating abilities in terms of their
abilities to keep thca in solution right
so certain combinations of terpenes are
can be able to hold t8 ca and solution
as well as other combinations and so
what you're seeing is just a
manifestation of that certainly like
ones that are much more solvating and
the higher-level terpenes that are found
or this desk whatever fiends like
cheerio Faline and which are less
volatile um have different flavor
profiles and sort of seem to be
ubiquitous it's just kind of like your
your trade off on gaining that turn
being profile in in the flower from what
I understand and then bringing that
through and reincorporating that into
some processed purified fraction of THC
a is that that that's what you're doing
yeah what I'm doing what you know what
do and I think I did the way to view
your question again just going back and
viewing the whole terpene thing is I
look like a musical ensemble like an
orchestra is that you have to set the
volume of the orchestra correctly from
where it was set in the plan right you
can turn up the volume really loud but
then yeah you're you're carrying
basically what you're trying to do is
keep the relative in the chirpy he's the
same so the flavor in your in your
consumable remains what it was in the
plan which is a delicate balance
especially when you talk about
thoroughly treating any of these most
sensitive of terpenes and monoterpenes
and as Sam has talked about and we've
talked about a bunch of times on Church
the curing chemistry that happens post
harvesting and curing me being separate
from drying so drying bulk removal of
water but then a process by which there
is chemistry that's happening still on
the plant but the plants no longer alive
but there's sort of terpenes that are
coming to their thermodynamic dead end
before they actually present themselves
and what now is a very very different
flavor than what you would get in a
freshly frozen extract you know so what
I was getting at god yeah what you just
said earlier those really important so
terpene alene is acting like something
more
of a salty solid that's correct right
and and so what you see I mean you know
like the holy water is all those like
high fractions which have a lot of use
EODs are kind of like orange sort of
like a bright orange more orange than a
brownish those are typically high in
Turpan alene Turpin Leah's got got one
of these double bonds that could precess
around the ring and a variety of
different geometric isomers and all of
these are different peaks in the GC and
they all have different you know further
oxidation manifold some of them oxidize
into turkey noids
and you know again some of these
degradation products that you're seeing
i I was really excited when I first saw
this paper come out because from
everything that we've been saying here
on hash Church Tony right that ya
terpenes at room temperature are
different than terpenes when you heat
them up that may have been like one of
the first things I said on his church
right go back to like when Horatio first
dragged me and say hey Mark we're
talking about chemistry we need we need
we need you to help us understand that's
how you gonna brought in it was a
question around beam stability and
whether or not and it was just before
the hash he sheen paper had come out and
I had said look these are reactive
species that we have reactive double
bonds and a lot of these things if you
shine light on them in the presence of
air they form hydro peroxides and then
they start degrading into all kinds of
different looks like methacrylate other
things that yeah you don't want to be
deeply inhaling into your lungs and you
know again when this paper first came
out I was really excited because this
study has to be done but as I read the
paper and I became just a little
disappointed on level of science and
what they did and I think the most
important thing that comes out of a
study like this is not to critique the
level of science which to me I give
about a c-minus tell you
truth I would have had that graduate
student go back and repeat that thing
like 10 more times I would have had them
do a different I would just I would have
done the study differently let's just
say it that way but the most important
thing that comes out of science that's
published like this which is maybe not
the best is is this discussion that
we're having right now on how important
it is to do this and to do this
carefully and notice that they use that
Ammar which I'm excited about
and notice that what they're doing is
they're showing a temperature dependence
and so if you pull data markets if you
could share the that link in the in the
in the chat room so our viewers can yes
we got a chem church again okay so if
you go to if you go to in that link go
to figure one which tells a lot okay and
and what you can see is the temperature
dependence as a function of methacrylate
being measured at the nanogram level
which an anagram is a 10 to minus 9 it's
a very very succeeding least small
amount of material but clearly within
the error bars of the measurement you
can see a temperature dependence on
methacholine being generated as a
function of temperature
now 526 degrees C let's see that's about
that's almost a thousand degrees isn't
it did someone do that conversion for me
it's like nothing hot hot hot it's hot
right so again I think that that's an
important finding from the study but
we've already talked about that before
work so if you go to let's see what's
there next table ok scheme 1 they talked
about some of this the structures of a
combination of merci limonene a little
loool created low temps that's the
problem they are not taking low temp
tabs they're like the cleaning
temperature they're taking glowy's right
is if that
no message that you know that the the
chemistry the degradation chemistry is a
fashion of of the temperature but if you
look now at table one down below where
it says they're measuring both
methacrylate and benzene at the nanogram
per milligram level let's see that's a
that's a part per million so these
numbers are in parts per million in 27
coming out of fire oh gee with limonene
I guess they're just doing this on neat
this is also this is also I think they
clarified it wasn't like a triple
molecular distilled oil it was just this
this was like just BHO extraction yeah
right but I mean I think that that's
valid for the study this numbers yeah so
if you don't have two product
quantification I mean I think these
numbers are important here so it says
because dabbing topography it's talking
about you know being able to assess the
temperatures but what they're seeing is
that with method crowing 185 plus or
minus 11 parts per billion at a
temperature of again 526 which is up
around 900 degrees well [ __ ] don't
[ __ ] tab at 900 degrees and look what
happens when you drop your dad
temperature 22 there undetectable okay
so I think that this does tell the story
of the temperature of the nail being
very very important but I would have
done a more detailed more quantitative
study and again I don't want to be
critical too much I think it's important
how can we get that study happenin
Marcus also everything you said combined
with also hitting it off of different
surfaces hitting it off of time fire
hitting it off of Commerce's conduction
hit it off is sick yeah yeah and also I
mean I think what we've what we've
talked about here on Church I mean this
is obviously one thing that you can
investigate which was that if you take
material and you put it inside a vial
and you put
you know the nail material in there and
now you heat that up well obviously it's
got to be in a few sport silica you
can't do this just a regular glass don't
try this at home kids but if that can
actually be taken up to temperature now
you can actually study by headspace-gc
the different profiles of what you're
getting by examining different different
nail materials and Jeff Raber did a
study for hive nail again some time ago
on this and I think Jeff's method which
I think was published I want to say two
or three years ago was a little more
sound and I think what I'm reading in
this paper in terms of how they
collected their sample here I was
excited about this until I found out
that you needed a cigarette smoking
machine which is how they conducted
their studies and I was like ah [ __ ] how
am I gonna repeat this they have a
cigarette smoking miss you got you know
but what am I gonna do my investors and
say oh I need to buy a cigarette smoking
machine study this don't you have access
to looks just pretty you know you'll
have to admit but they were never
finding this in herbal cannabis which is
smoked it
I believe 451 and if they would have
found it it would have been reported a
long time ago right so I think that were
the trend goes over that these materials
are in there the less likely they're
gonna be pushed beyond the limit of
detection and again simply it totally
makes sense that at the higher
temperatures you're seeing more
degradation that's a that that almost
looks like a first what we call
kinetically a first sort of relationship
which is a typical in inari any a sense
Arrhenius is a guy who figured out the
mathematics for this long time ago that
there's a linear dependency they based
on based on temperature and that's
totally to be expected that's exactly
what it comes down to is that is the
temperature and besides the surface is
but the temperatures is super key and
what I also found was terpenes will
organically degra gate with a rosin and
what I mean by that is if you start with
say a flower rosin that tests eighty
percent it's seventy-six percent THC a
and four percent THC and you take that
and you use the same terpene profile
from that flower and saturate up to say
a 30% and let that sit six months it'll
be fully activated work very close to
being activated which then tells you
that terpenes have this other affective
property that's going on - which is what
I thought was affecting color right
there's an aging mechanism that's
probably at work there and again that
you're right has a lot to do with not
only taking something that starts out as
its life being clear and turning collar
I've seen that color formation up and on
the road of that you're something down
that's you know basically colorless by
the time you get it down it's like
yellowish and it starts to actually turn
almost in front of your eyes because
it's being enclosed - now high
concentrations of oxygen in the plant a
lot of these things are protected
because they live within the waxy
envelope of the plant itself and they're
not being exposed to the levels of
oxygen now that they're being sort of
stripped from their their plant
protective you know for me exposed and
they get off on that it does all almost
without exception have a shelf life in
that they'll either evaporate or they'll
degrade into a mostly yeah yellow darker
colored material than from which they
came and and I said I kept flowers for a
year in the same condition in a vacuum
and even over a year the THC a on the
flowers will convert over to THC not all
the way but it could happen at 25 or 30
percent I kept them for two years
not even in a vacuum just on the Shelf
in the dark ever
temperatures and less than 10% converted
from thca to THC if you have a jar Sam
like the stock down court in a jar they
were in a cardboard box
oh but Eldon can hurt it only converted
10% in two years in two years that's
interesting I was shocked and surprised
yeah that's super interesting what kind
of variety was that Scott
oh well that's why it doesn't yeah I
mean maybe there was a protective
envelope of terpenes stink containing
those buds keeping oxygen after years
THC level was practically the same most
of it was still in the form of THC a but
most of the terpenes were gone Oh
interesting so long story short with
that article though it's so when we were
talking about concentrations of ppm so
think about this if something has like
any kind of solvent left behind or
residual and you hit it at a higher
temperature with a higher concentration
of terpenes moral of the story is it's
probably not so good for you I want to I
want to change the subject for a second
not very far away but something Peter
was shared with us when he first came on
that picture of metabolites that are
terpenes one of the things I've been
exploring is how soil biology changes
what terpenes and how much of them
express in the plants and we were
talking earlier about how purity of the
plant is really important for the purity
of the end product that we're producing
and what I my question is how much
effect really does soil biology or the
biology in the soil and on the plants
have to do with the terpenes that are
going to be expressed by the genetics of
the plant I mean there's going to be a
sort of terpene profile
they're just based on the genetics but I
have a feeling or it's been my
experience I'll say it like that that as
the soil biology has improved in my
garden and in other gardens I've seen
and worked with the terpenes not only
increase in quantity in the plant
material and of course the plants are
more vital but it it occurs to me that
perhaps different species of biology
enhance a plant's ability to produce
more terpenes is that what that picture
was suggestive of yeah and actually if
you like what I can do is actually
quantify exactly what you're talking
about and give you a a pretty
comprehensive overview of exactly what
that does on a biological level so let
me let me share my screen with you
actually I yeah I think that's an
important story yeah okay so this is
this is different strains of bacteria
creating a terpene so what we did with
one of our hemp cultivators is we
quantified the amount of bacteria that
was in a treated and non treated soil to
increase the oil production so so right
here what you'll see is the microbes
that we calculated in one gram of soil
so in in the treated we had 83 billion
colony forming units per gram of soil
tested in the non treated we had 72,000
different microbes and so what ended up
happening was we saw a nitrogen boost
within the leaf tissue analysis of
treated plants so this this study was
conducted by North Carolina Department
of Agriculture so we saw 30% increase in
leaf nitrogen content then we looked at
phosphorus phosphorus is a big one for
biomass and so with an increased amount
of biology the plant is actually getting
the physics that it needs to create
terpenes and so your your
[Music]
micronutrients I'm sorry your
macronutrients are going up here's
potassium so again this isn't a highly
biologically active soil now all these
nutrients are essential for the plant to
have the physics it needs to create the
different types of terpenes to protect
itself in that soil and what we saw at
the end so this was 500 we took 250
treated and then 250 non treated plants
with a highly biologically active soil
you know why people say organic or
growing with bacteria is good and we
found a 42 point 85 percent increase in
the amount of oil that the hemp plant
produced when when you say oil
what do you are you referring to
cannabinoids other things or just
essential oil terpenes yeah this was
just the CBD analysis that the that the
that the laboratory did oil which could
be head size or just oil content in
general of the of the plant that's still
significantly it's not like it was like
a 4% it's 42 percent just be interesting
if the same thing was done to plants
that are producing seeds and if the the
embryo oil the essential amino acid rich
oil the hemp oil was also increased I
would almost have to guarantee it you
would think I guarantee you that growing
living soil rich that's making plants
grow millions of tiny tiny white roots
absolutely does increase smells terpenes
and cannabinoids and resin in general
absolutely that's true but whether or
not it can actually make other terpenes
present i've never seen any proof of
that but i could boot but you feel it
would I mean obviously I've in my
experience I was going to say that
I had this conversation with Brian from
vital a couple days ago when he was like
just kind of checking in on me and I was
just just catching up and I was talking
about Peter and your your product is
like talking about kind of like you know
as a the the probiotic and an essential
in the grow system and keeping it as a
as a key thing moving forward and and
like what he's doing with his soil and
and and and vital system and then I've
seen the guys from pharmacy bras that
have a seven-year soil they have those
what they call pop Paco's and they do
600 gallons and they save the soil and
the 600 gallons and and you know spend
years with the same soil from these type
of growers versus say even not just
indoor but other types of growers that
grow in the same competitive environment
if you will that don't spend a lot of
time or have a lot of education on it
like even you know like wage doing it as
well you know it's like if I take
something from somebody that understands
the soil and understands how to grow
organically every single time the
terpene percentage overall percentage if
you will
aroma flavor oil content is always
boosted cannabinoids and turpentine
don't you know if it's the head size if
you will or there's more heads being
developed or more oil being secreted but
I see it I see it like night and day
between the growers and I'll ever get to
the point where people will take a
vegetative plant grow it as big as they
can so it's just about ready to flower
and then you whack it back halfway like
they do with grapes to produce fewer but
superior grapes are
that'll ever be done with cannabis to
produce fewer heads of cannabis but more
superior or if it would be I'm not sure
yeah I don't know I tend to think that
and it's strange because I find with the
or and this is I mean it's not it's I
don't want to generalize too much but
all of the varieties that I see that are
grown outdoor that are grown correctly
produce a interesting type of resin to
where it's maybe it's not like covered
in trichomes like you see an indoor
where this seems to be like just a lot
more coverage and generally like every
time you see like even organic indoors
just flooded with trichomes just but the
outdoor they get these like juicier
bigger buds you know like it but it's
not like it's not covered in trichomes
you still see it but something
inherently I think that's why that's why
I always said and thought we had this
argument before and I think you were not
sure what side of it you were on at that
time but I always felt like we were
growing really big grapes outdoors like
things were just bigger and there was
just bigger oil and maybe it wasn't so
much on the outside as was as it is
closer to the the surface of the leaf
but the oil content and the terpene
content we're talking like you know
everything's you know a good two percent
plus when people are got a new variety
that I collected from Chernobyl
it grows resin heads the sides of small
size of small melons melons in the dark
so they're really easy to find if you
drop on melons or melanomas and I was
gonna say so to add to you what you're
talking about the soil and things is
that I see that there's a boost in the
heads but then there's this other oil
and it's boosting terpenes within
inherently in the plant and on the
surface of the leaf but it's not just in
the head so I think what happens with
the plant is maybe it expresses and
exceeds its head count and then it if
it's really healthy and really strong it
starts to produce these oils in a
different way
that come out very well in rosin and
they come out very well interpreting
extractions and I see the numbers are
always boosted I mean you know I just
got a variety from verdant that was like
overall 24% cannabinoids there's like
20% CBD and 5% THC and he's all organic
vital you know yes sir one of the things
Tony that we're also seeing is you know
the plant can only hit a certain genetic
expression right it can only produce so
many terpenes so in growers that aren't
getting a lot of terpenes we're seeing
that our bacteria will help them achieve
maybe a level where you guys are already
at but when you guys get to your level
when the plant can only produce so many
terpenes what we're finding is a
diversity of biology will increase more
of the types so instead of seeing like
maybe seven or eight major terpene types
you'll see ten or twelve and so the
flavor and the aroma and the the
comprehensiveness of the Turpan alene
efficacy is just a lot more
comprehensive and where do you think
those oils are being developed either
that's what I don't know I don't know
yet I'm seeing that different type to be
honest if you don't see them in a
regular plant that's not grown that way
and they're not expressed at all even
you know in tiny tiny amounts then do do
they have a synthase to produce that
compound they are being used in macro
doses you know so you'll have your
majors but then you'll see micro doses
of the other terpenes but when you add
our bacteria and those micro doses are
okay that that I could absolutely
believe that that you're making a really
tiny peak grow to a bigger size that's
easy to believe that's that's what's
going so it's a tiny peek and and now
with the introduction of more bacteria
those Peaks are higher you know that
could certainly be I've seen healthier
soil healthier plants healthier roots
definitely creates healthier resin which
is more terpenes
appetites he's working with nature man
that's it Sam well well the key there is
not a gene fixation because the plant
doesn't fix nitrogen but the bacteria
does and so they're able to fix nitrogen
and phases are proteins which are
negative amino acids and amino acids
require nitrogen and so it's those
machines that make their beans beans
just aren't made they're made by like we
said before synthesis and those
synthesis are basically large proteins
that have to be made before you can make
the the those all require nitrogen
nitrogen fixation also they require what
is it your G GPRS
at the time course of evolution to
figure out how to fix nitrogen from the
air so let's just let the bacteria do
yeah
yeah and I'll tell you what you know you
guys over over the years have done such
a good job educating the industry
getting people aware of how important
routines are and so I'm so humbled and
grateful to be a part of you know maybe
helping disclose how terpenes are made
which is from bacteria so on one thing
that we hadn't covered yet which kind of
dawned upon me maybe you guys could
answer this you know the plants going as
as female plant you know sense Amelia
it's going through its ovulation period
and we're talking about the nitrogen
starting early with you know most
growers have this consciousness of hey
we're gonna either foliar feed or just
use low levels of phosphorus and higher
nitrogen when it's vegging and then it's
flipped and we're using higher
phosphorus and much less nitrogen during
the flowering cycle is there and there
but there is an ovulation period of
which it changes like from like day 24
and and day like 36 or something depends
on a variety but there's that ovulation
period is there what is is the change in
the hormone of the plant something else
it's indicative of how the uptake or how
this is working yeah there is so so
that's a great question one of the
things that we have found with
comprehensive biology attached to the
rhizosphere is that the plant is
actually Auto regulating its uptake and
so there's there's a sacred kind of
communication that the root will have
with its its digestive system that that
says hey at this stage of my growth of
my involvement I'm gonna need some some
nitrogen or I'm gonna need some
phosphorus so so what will happen is is
it will enzymatically communicate with
the biodiversity in the rhizosphere to
allow them to act as almost like a
chelating agent for particles such as
phosphorus so for instance if you take
the root and you've got a particle this
size when you put your fertilizer of
phosphorus the plant will enzymatically
communicate with the biofilm of
organisms that are creating assets to to
break down that phosphorus so that as it
hits the root it just kind of it's like
juicing it you know and so the the
higher awareness or communication that
the that the plant will have with its
biology to process nitrogen fixation
phosphorus solubalization all the things
that are so important to have the
physics to create the terpenes is beyond
you know it's it's a naturally occurring
thing that just happens when you have a
biologically active soil well i'm
phosphorus the key is the key element
that holds DNA together right DNA is
basically a polymer that's derived from
a poly phosphate backbone and so the
actual element of DNA itself requires
nitrogen requires phosphorous and so
without phosphorus and nitrogen you're
starving a living system from being able
to proliferate then with a what I'm
saying is that you know and to answer
your question Tony is that once you do
have a comprehensive biologically active
system you
it's gonna kind of take the guesswork
out of your you're fertilizing variances
because it's such a dynamic
comprehensive thing to actually feed
your plants are given the right energy
to grow that there can be so many
methodologies and approaches to properly
fertilizing and so again in
incorporating a healthy digestive system
to your plants is going to kind of take
the guesswork out of that and make your
investment and fertilizer that much more
that much better all right so all right
so these put that these products are and
once again let's see if I'm still yeah
okay so alright so let's say we close my
eyes and I imagine we've got the right
bacteria in the right organic soil and
we've got millions of little tiny hairs
that are coming out of these roots and
now we've got more of these vessels and
way to communicate and uptake that
information through the system in which
you explained and so and knowing what we
know about the plant now with the
nitrogen and phosphorus if there's ways
to take certain types of genetics
maximize their expressions and maybe
target certain types of boosting of
terpene profiles like maybe adding a
certain mineral in that period with that
particular type of genetic instead of
you know is there a way you know do you
think that it's that's what it's going
to come to is that we find this
particular type of genetic we create
this living type of soil that can
maximize and boost the properties in
which we want so that's probably a Sam
question but as far as you know Mike
might just what I feel about that is
absolutely so crossbreeding and it goes
back to biodynamic agriculture for me so
so we're taking a plant that shouldn't
necessarily be cultivated in the
warehouse or even a soil we're deciding
to put it there and so what you guys are
doing with you know crossbreeding and
things like that to express various
genetic
potentiality of the plant in combination
with something that's just been lacking
for so long in this industry which is
the the biology that that these plants
naturally co-evolved with in nature that
they're lacking in the warehouse or in
the soil that they never should have
been planted in in the first place
and so I go in I wonder if I wanted to
jump I'm echoing let me let me mute
myself thank you Peter I think something
you said is really important that if by
having healthy soil a full to use a term
the soil food web if you will and I
think that's some of what you're doing
not to mix labels or anything but the
idea of having healthy soil just to make
it short freeing me from having to make
choices about what I'm going to feed my
plants when so that they can flourish
giving them the opportunity to go
looking for what they want need and
being able to find it in abundance where
they are frees me from the
responsibility of sorting it out for
them it's what I've realized is that the
different genetics they have different
moments in their their growth process
that thing you were talking about where
they go through the hormonal changes of
ovulation and whatnot there's an
awareness if you if I when I was working
indoors I spent a lot of time trying to
understand what my plants needed when
and how to feed them to get them to
express optimally what they were capable
of and working outdoors in healthy soil
what I found is that they take care of
themselves I really all I'm trying to do
is help them have available everything
they need and your product I've not ever
used it but I've read up on what you're
doing and I understand the concept it's
it's evocative of things I've read
before
and I really think you're onto something
where folks are not able to generate
their own inputs but want to invest in
something that will help their soil be
more alive if you will I think it's
important important to educate people
about how to help the colonies that
you're giving them continue to flourish
in their gardens but some of the best
gardens I've been in are far better than
what I've been able to do here and in
every one of them those people have
spent years more than seven usually a
number that someone else mentioned
earlier where over the years they've
just added to the soil added to the soil
added to the soil nutrients and inputs
from their farm or from their neighbors
where they know exactly what they're
doing doing in terms of adding to the
soil to see benefit Indra was speaking
about rabbit manures one of the most
beautiful gardens I've seen this year is
using goat sheep rabbit and chicken
manures over a period of years and his
trees their trees are literally oh my
goodness I don't know I don't want to
exaggerate every but they're really huge
anyway I've gone on a rant but the point
that I'm trying to make to make is that
you that point about you not having me
not having to choose what to feed these
plants like their course of their life
cycle cycle all I do is get water it
kind of takes the guesswork out of it
wait and I'll tell you what I'll send
you a bag of the soil balanced so that
you can try it and if it's okay with
Marcus I loved it since it's you know a
good show I'd love to give away 50 bags
of our of our soil balance to his
audience we can we can put a link to
Nathan's email and then the first maybe
50 people that email Nathan will give
them a free bag of the soil balance so
they so that everybody can see how
important biology is and and how easy it
can it can make call
Automation and that's that's what we're
all about is trying to help cultivators
become more sustainable and utilize
their budgets more effectively and
increase quality so yeah so it actually
if anybody wants to email Nate at soil
balance procom will give 50 bags if
that's cool Marcus like we didn't talk
about it before the show but no you
can't it's great man it's amazing are
you kidding me I think people are
writing that email down right now and
trying to well describe what a bag does
yeah so so 10 grams is what we're gonna
give away we're gonna give away 10 10 10
gram bags so there's 50 bags that we're
gonna give out and 10 grams will create
100 gallons of microbial tea and so each
gallon will will contain six trillion
microorganisms all beneficial
microorganisms and and and and each
gallon will have 62 strains so a 10 gram
bag costs about $29 I think I don't know
what the Canadian but we've set up to
send our product into Canada so so that
will create a hundred gallons of microbe
tea yeah that's a lot that's a lot huge
that's huge actually got really really
happy to learn more about on the really
paying attention and listen to you guys
and stuff but I definitely jumped on
board of that right away for it in my
bag it's in a Canada's about 60 bucks so
ya know it's I'm looking forward to
actually utilizing your products so
thank you yeah no but thank you John
we're so grateful man and we really put
a lot of work we put about ten years
into going around the world and
isolating strains from different
ecosystems like a rainforest in a desert
so we have some strains from deserts
that were specifically to enhance them
and all they need is water to
proliferate through binary fission no
well I have an announcement that I'd
like to make during all this awesomeness
as of about 20 minutes ago my partner my
friend my brother from another mother
Claude Sayers in Jamaica just had his
his girl just gave birth to two Savannah
cannabis sayers so welcome to the world
Savannah cannabis you are you are loved
by many already
congratulations Claude up sent me the
picture I was like when was that he's
like 15 minutes ago like that's amazing
dude we're just doing a stretch and
you're watching kids be born oh my god
Wow well now you can't stop doing hashed
Church now that we've got so many new
members yes little little Savannah
cannabis I like the name Savannah
cannabis it's proper hey Marcus Forrest
stopped by my place the other day
and he brought with him a little silver
pen that said bubbleman on it had some
really beautiful I don't really like
vape pens I don't really use them I've
had I've tried a bunch of them over the
years and that one I liked you know how
you yeah it it tasted like something
there was actual flavor there I don't
know what it was he said but I really
liked the pen I don't know who's doing
it is that Blue River or that is a
collaboration that we're all doing
together myself and Tony
and Gary from up tech so Gary's a lot of
the design and then Tony and I are kind
of R&amp;D with the terpenes on blue
Riverside with the bubbleman brand on my
side and we all kind of came up together
and created this what we're now calling
the Trinity which makes sense because
there are three substantial brands
coming together to produce this one
brand and yes it's been pretty cool dude
it's uh Tony's definitely been you know
got to give him a mad big shout out both
him and Gary have put a ton of time and
energy into this over the last like 14
months so it's pretty [ __ ] awesome
I'm glad you liking it did yeah it was
pretty amazing
like I said never liked really big pens
but that changed my opinion quite a bit
so thank you Tony and thank you Marcus
and thanks to the other person who will
make sure we get you one if he didn't
leave it with you
I as you will yeah no he's loving it he
got one for Forrest yeah and then I'll
get you one I'll make sure you get one
it's uh we learned a lot of what is
wrong with you she wants to be a part of
hastert Wow
she's just having it she's like yeah
there's some things that we learned like
you know with these particular with the
tanks I was talking about with the oil
and THC and there's like a lot of people
trying to make them at home so with
anything new with new technology you try
to you know push through different
things and and you're trying to pioneer
a way to get our organic oils in a
device that's healthy for you that you
can vaporize with that with knowing that
you could reuse it you know and so thank
you one that I would put my name on ie
yeah as well as myself and so you know
it has this like it has a sick element
in it that's like a pumice stone if you
will
and it basically under the under the
tank if you take the tanks he is just
super upset jeez if you take like the
tank itself and if you just if you get
if you're doing fresh frozen material
making a bubble hash and then pressing
it you're keeping it in it's like almost
as raw THCA as you know it's it's rose
form and it's generally gonna have a
high terpene content and so once you
start getting past come on really once
you start getting past ten or fifteen
percent and especially as you get closer
to thirty percent you're getting you're
getting you're getting this breakout and
so not every terpene grouping does a
breakout but say like strawberry banana
goo accelerates this breakout of THC a
and if you reap and when used to look at
any of the post that are taking like the
rosin and the butter and there and
you're repressing it at a hundred and
thirty degrees and you're separating the
oil from the THC a and you're getting
like 97 98 99 percent THC EA you can see
the two separations done mechanically
well that happens inside the tank if
you're not careful and so this is things
that I've learned and next week we're
putting out like a whole comprehensive
video of how to you know use it from the
start to finish there's little tricks
and trades that have done it because
terpenes in a live rosin form and in a
hash and everything being organic and
alive it's what i call an active resin
and it's it's not in its home anymore
and it's it want it's kind of volatile
in a sense where it's like I need to
find a place and so if you mix up
terpenes and you mix of rosin and you
just mix it up right away it's it it
needs time to settle and to kind of
either like market mark scold own said
if the tie-in terpene alene it's gonna
want to eat away at that rosin and it's
still it's going to take some time and
as its doing that there's a little bit
of organic chemistry happening there
that it says hey i need to find my way
give me a minute
I'm showing the pen right now on screen
share Tony where the oil is
crystallizing in the cartridge you can
see the little crystals that I've got on
the screen here so that's THC a yeah
I've got one I've got one that so these
are so this is an it's like you know
it's a beautiful color it's creamy it's
nice and bright but when you look at
this oil guess which one's functioning
better in the tank this one right here
okay and you start to look at we did a
lemon tree one and I did some different
different types of processes to dial
this in but ultimately if you're gonna
use the freshest most raw you know live
rosin sauce if you will and you have a
tank then you put it in and you let it
settle down and you use it right away
but if you let it sit in there this
thing will separate the oil will come
through the center pin like straight
through that center hole which is
different than anything else and I don't
mind talking about this because this is
like we're trying to get of a device
that people can use and understand but
it's amazing because under pressure just
pressure the terpenes are gonna want to
come out that hole
when I hit 15% in the first cards all of
the terpenes came out of this Center us
- yeah a center device and left up here
was THC a there was like well that's a
creep nice magic trick but I just wanted
to smoke the oil that was inside it hi
I'm with you and so what we found is if
you if you mix terpenes and rosin
together and you and i let it sit for
like weeks like I'll do like 20 I'll do
like 35 grams - like - like 3 or 4
milliliters so it's like now we found
the magic numbers about 3 drops and
every drop is 2.25 percent terpenes on
average you should be able to hit 10 11
% and I feel like with a 10 11 % terpene
content and a 77 to 75 percent overall
cannabinoid profile it's the best you
know potency - terpene it's not too
crazy it's not yeah well what if you
took that weird starting to crystallize
there and just heated it gently with
like
was like a hairdryer would would did
with the I mean again when I say he to
get gently left because that's a tip on
our blog on the public and website using
a hairdryer to gently heat it up well
the reason why is he knee and gently
because if it is THC a yeah now star
decarboxylated and it's gonna build up a
little bit of pressure right correct
right correct but but what we don't want
is we don't want our oil to separate
inside the tanks but we what we found is
yes we want to have this like experience
of having the freshest taste that you
can but you also need the function and
so my there's a bunch of people on the
on Instagram I was going to talk about
this today's so if you're mixing
distillate or you're mixing any kind of
extract with terpenes you need to give
it several days to kind of find its way
mix it really well let it sit three to
five days make sure that there's no off
gassing or bubbles or a volatile type of
oil then when you put it into the tank
or if you're mixing it right away and
and you just want to be impatient and
you put it into the tank if you leave it
off if you leave it with the lid off I
have these little trays and if you leave
it with the lid off for 24 hours with
the lid off itself like that sauce you
just saw me put in here I'm waiting for
it to go down if you leave it with the
lid off not like this but if you put it
in here and you leave with the lid off
and you wait 24 hours what happens is
the the sick stone if you will in there
absorbs all of the oil in its in in its
entirety as one unit and and leaves a I
wouldn't say a harder level but it
leaves a nice like kind of custard level
at the top you put your pen on and then
they never leak and then they they hit
perfectly and consistently and they
never separate custard you say custard
so it creates it creates this is like
weeks some custard and it creates a
consistent oil if not just a little bit
of pressure
which led is gonna lead me to like kind
of another idea which is using a device
that creates pressure from terpenes to
do the separations that have an actual
press but if you don't if you don't use
it right away and you let that sit that
could separate on you and so what we
found was if you took what scale Dolan
was saying is if you take the the say if
you you know took a lie Brosnan or you
took a flower rosin and there was a
gentle heat like 105 or 110 degrees to
just gently warm up the extract even if
it was just 10% and a slightly activated
10 or 20% then you get in and then when
you get back into it
you end up getting more of a gel which
kind of looks like maybe of the old co2
days but literally every single thing
will come off this pen this was just
laying sideways but it literally works
perfectly so there's that trade-off this
one was this one was almost halfway
activated but he really works perfectly
so there's that trade-off this one was
this one was almost halfway out damn I
wondered what that was I was like okay
that's weird Tony sounds different now
all of a sudden I was just like not
paying attention for half a second then
Indra came in hello and literally he was
literally in the trichomes I'm just like
what yeah so I long story short you know
terpenes helped break out THC a it helps
break out CBD it helps break out
different elements it also helps me get
high I find it's a very important
component of feeling properly elevated
from the dead not to interrupt you go on
that's all I think it's important to be
honest very much so let's say one thing
about that pen here and right now
and forever do not plug it in with with
with the cart attached to the battery
this is a no now yeah so if anything
with the audience that's listening don't
ever plug it in like this always remove
the tank from the battery exactly it's
an it's a newer type of battery that's a
14 watts of ohm and it will it will heat
up your oil very quickly let's put it
that way and could potentially catch
fire
well that's safe what is the $5,000
right now it's very conscious 60 bucks
it's 62 dollars retail for an empty and
you we were sewn like Gary sellin the
little 10 drop vials with the whole
applicator and everything so people
could make them at home and you know
even for us where we're selling them
with the oil and it and we were trying
to get everything down to like a live
rosin so it's but in that process we
learned you know filling the tanks up
and not letting them kind of sit in
there for a 24 hour period would start
to have them the oils would want to
separate and that's really just a tip
you know if you're at home and you're
gonna use it right away no problem but
if you were gonna if you were going to
try to keep it for I don't know a week
or two weeks you want to let it sit in
the pen before you put the top on for
just a day I changed the subject real
quick I know I'm kind of like a new
friend of the group but one of the
things I was just kind of feeling right
now is you know every time Marcus says
something like I laugh my ass off and
it's usually so well articulated and
insightful and just just joyous to me
man in my in my whole field so since
I've got this this this this a little
bit of space and since there's such a
collective of people I was just
wondering if we could all maybe used
I'm in a church like fashion to kind of
send Marcus some some deep gratitude
some deep appreciation for all that he
has done and given of himself at his
time of his energy of his consciousness
to all of us and just really be so
grateful for that so that that's what
I'm sending to you my friend as a new
friend so thank you give thanks PDA
experiment and so with that being said
I'm gonna go hang out with my kids I
love all you guys I'm so grateful like
deeply humbled to be on such a panel
with with great cultivators and growers
you guys are the stewards and protectors
of our lands you guys are the light
beings that that we supports them so
thank you guys and thank you for having
Pro for kicking down 50 bags for those
of you that haven't sent your email I
think it's Nate now Nate's in the chat
room right now maybe he'll put his email
up again I just saw him in there very
very very generous kick down 50 10 grand
bags of soil bounce Pro just trillions
of bacteria just kicking down the
trillions that's generous when your
generosity gets into the trillions
whatever it is you're dealing with
that's uh I mean come on ridiculous
[Music]
so Marcus I did a little experiment this
weekend which I think may be an interest
you got your head put on a glandular
trichomes body well I I decided to
become a trichrome was the only way I am
so I just gave in and became a trichrome
myself I hang out with dry Chrome's now
and that's it so anyway as far as the
treating of your oil to work in the Pens
a very good way to do it is to take it
in a vacuum oven
set the oven for 130 degrees and run it
for about 38 or 40 hours and your stuff
will run in the pen like water after
that it'll all drain it'll all work
really good we all end off here offering
a pen pal
where the terpenes go it don't go
anywhere cuz you only run it 135 degrees
just stay right here
Oh vacuum and they just stay right there
I was like Indra I just wanted to
mention that I have a patent on my face
on resonance
oh you patented I did ten years ago so
what you're doing is you owe me exactly
twenty three cents at this moment I'll
send it right away
but anyway what I think is a good piece
of notice I took four plants I cut them
down and within ten minutes I put him in
the extractor and I expected them and
the results are truly truly truly
amazing I have never smoked oil this
strong in my life this is the best stuff
I've ever imbibed it's so strong it's
not good it smells like a fresh flower
it tastes like it when you smoke it it
tastes like a brand-new fresh flower
absolutely delicious and it's you can
pull out huge huge huge things with it
it's just the most beautiful oil and I
would say after trying this that maybe
this is a new product I think that
nobody's really making little market
it's absolutely fresh what's that the
oil I BHO did 20 minutes after I cut the
plant down the lines by truly live and I
got some
I've got a drop of it freezing on a drop
of water in the freezer I'm gonna try to
see if I can make a to see if it'll make
a picture or if it'll crystallize out on
the in the thaw out grade I've mentioned
that before with living oils that we
made in the past from many other plants
not hot I didn't try making it apart so
I'm gonna be trying that with it take a
look at this live resident but I have
everybody who's come over nobody has
been able to take more than one good hit
off of it one good hit this plastic like
I believe it it's a lot like my resin
but the terpene count I gotta have it
analyzed the terpenes are so powerful
and you can taste them in your mouth
when you dab it so I'm thinking this
stuff will also work really nicely in
the pan I've got one of those pens right
that's the beauty of the pen you can put
your own [ __ ] in it we didn't want to
pull out a pen that was like locked to
our you know like oh it has to you know
you have to get the oil every time from
those guys it's like no you got to be
able to put your own yeah I'm definitely
with you on that I think being able to
put your own stuff in it that's why I
extracted a very fresh one I wanted to
see if I could get around the long heat
treatment or the long low vacuum
treatment to make it so many more in the
pen most of the oils work in the pen if
you do them in the vacuum of them for 48
hours that are very low heat and not not
a full vacuum you know a gentle vacuum
after that they'll pour no pour into a
pen but this fresh extraction was it's
truly amazing I wish you were across the
border man because I would I love to you
take a toke of this I'll tell ya if I
only had a 5 cents for each time someone
said I wish you could come down to the
US I say it three times a day every day
three times a day or 158 episodes 7 days
a week so we're letting people in who
come and bomb us
shoot us and kill us why can't we let
Marcus in first hey all you wants to do
is stone us
yeah I'll even like I'll be good I'll do
whatever like I'll follow the rules I'm
you know aside from cannabis here's the
funny thing like aside from cannabis I'm
not like a huge rule breaker if my rule
breaking always has to do with cannabis
it's like well I'm gonna grow it and I'm
gonna smoke it and I'm gonna smoke it at
like concerts and indoors and I get a
smoke get leg everywhere I go I just
want to smoke it everywhere I go
and so I don't like it just got the new
waterproof edition so you could smoke it
in the shower what I'm just totally
kidding that would be funny right
underwater and in the shower I was like
come on man into America yes it's hard
to see what you got in your hand Indra
it's a network it's an electric model
and it you're gonna get a cloud of smoke
from this puppy
big enough to get an entire room smoke
this thing it's got a comic tip on it
you gotta you push it one two three four
five there's water in the top bulb cram
it in your local yeah I got a nectar
collector given to me a couple years ago
by D mail it was like the one that you
don't heat up with the torch they had a
coil around it so you just plugged it in
that's what he's got he's got he's got
an electric one a battery-powered model
though and you don't need a plug okay I
chose with you
nice I I hit it a few times I was like
this thing is just like crazy like you
especially because you hit like giant
bowls of a product like he just put that
thing right into your jar of hash and
just be like that's a dangerous game at
least it was for me for the little bit
that I was getting into it go through a
lot of concentrate with one in a day's
time oh yeah a lot so I guess it is
Canadian Thanksgiving today so half
Thanksgiving to all the kanay well
tomorrow this weekend you know Monday
Thanksgiving Sunday many Canadians will
be sitting down for the Thanksgiving
dinner and so yeah I hope everyone has a
good Thanksgiving I hope all the well I
hope that the hash is melty that people
pull out I hope it's like not this like
really bad third-world import swag it's
just like not the best product they
could have made you know what the hell
is Thanksgiving in Canada about I'm
thankful for you know yes this is Rob
Clark okay to let you on your years of
Hafs church bro it's been gone thanks
brother thanks it's we're having a good
time we're just sitting around kind of
laughing and it's actually been a pretty
good conversation today but it has
indeed been three years and that is kind
of crazy
yeah next meal went by awfully quick
that's the thing as you do get older
time goes by so much quicker
it's hardly unfair true it is but that's
okay you know we're we're alive and
we're lucky that's the way I see it
that's that's the lesson I get in life
every time from losing my father at a
young age she was 55 my stepmom was 49
they were killed in an accident and a
motorcycle accident and whatever kind of
being like beats the alternative
you know being dead they're kind of like
oh [ __ ] yeah you're right like it really
does beat the alternative being alive no
matter how old you are you're crushing
it well if you believe in reincarnation
you'll get a nice fresh new young bod
yeah or you come back as a leper on the
streets of India I think that's a bit
terrifying too if you better schmuck you
deserve it
yeah I absolutely do not but no there's
not
do believe deserving he believes in just
desserts
he doesn't have to believe in
reincarnation to believe in that you
know I like coming he's got it patented
he's got a patented absolutely he's got
a patented well I was gonna press up a
bunch of rosin today but I'm not sure if
I'm gonna continue that or not I've been
wanting to make a sh for like a month
and a half so I'm definitely gonna pull
on your bags dude and we're gonna wash
some resin today and we gonna search and
thank you so much for your last 158 Sun
days of your life doing it with you
we've ran across airports to make sure
you've gone from this episode going sped
down rows gone through hotels screeched
and aside things I mean I'm being with
you a long way we hated internet
connections but we didn't have them I
think the best one by far was landing at
the airport Sunday morning Toronto and
then jumping into quads Parker with with
three other Rastafarians and it's a
blizzard and we're driving to Brampton
Ontario and I'm in the back seat and
this you know phobos driving straight
blizzard everywhere I'm like this is
[ __ ] crazy like I've got like 18
minutes to make do they drive the same
way whether there's a blizzard out
listen it was it was exactly the same
way it was insane
psychotic they were all laughing Bobo
was kind of getting mad cuz I was like
dude like do you understand like I need
to do this show and I can't be dead when
I do it I have to be alive and conscious
problem bubble back yeah yeah I'm gonna
get you their blood I'm gonna get you
there I'm like all right well you know
what and in Bobo's defense he absolutely
got me there it was the shortest hashed
church we ever did because the internet
ended up hacking out I think we got 17
minutes that episode of hashed Church
remember the one in the grill where we
could only find one spot on the corner
post the
and people had to share the spot there
was little chairs that were built out of
what is like oh what's this and you're
like well we better sit here early like
what do you mean you're like well sit
down we've got as we got a secure
internet position and we just hold it
down right there in that one one foot by
one foot I took that further I asked a
few people if they wouldn't mind not
going online while we were using the
internet because we were streaming
everything oh yeah I'm trying to explain
hash search in two sentences is tough
yeah it's like what's it what's it for
mine and that one guy you were like well
it's for hashed churches like hashed
Church like a house church is like oh
and there's always that like moment
where they're like I don't they just
doesn't compute well it's two strange
words to put together right it's a once
again I always got a shout out Amir my
good buddy Amir who had a still had a
restaurant across from me at the melting
point called rhyme and that's where we
did the original Church you know and so
after 20 years Oh bye and it's much much
hash and things about hash the stream
had to be making past church so that's
really kind of the birth of hash Church
YouTube letting me stream Amir and my
friends gathering on Sundays for what we
just called Church back then it was
still the Prohibition land so we weren't
gonna call it cannabis Church or weed
Church or anything that made it stand
out that we could be talking about it
and then get ourselves into trouble but
that quickly changed and here we are
hashed church every Sunday for the last
three years and a couple of weeks - one
I was camping it happens you know
hey how about a shout-out to Roger
Waters he's come into town in Vancouver
I don't know where you guys are all from
but if you hear that us and them is
coming to your town I would definitely
not miss it it's definitely gonna be
like a serious serious experience buddy
sets the bar pretty high I would say it
goes beyond just any concert and I'm
quite excited to be going to both nights
in Vancouver on the 28th and 29th of
October this month I never get to go do
anything so as a father of a
three-year-old
teenagers I'm stoked to go out and be at
a concert and just enjoy some Roger
Waters in Floyd vibes that sounds like
amazing I wish I could join you I'm
gonna hit they just started talking
about the obscurity in the show with how
it's relating to Trump in the news if
you haven't noticed member when I went
and I told you I was like hey Bros
you're like oh yeah you want to paint
yeah I'm getting ready to go there and
like afterwards it was like just a
different just a whole different
experience because it's like I wasn't
expecting an entire concert in campaign
to be geared up bashing the president in
a I mean with with shots along the way
like you're like okay cool we're good
this is guy that riddle wrote a whole
album about his mom like he's holding a
grudge oh right bro there's giant filled
with pigs in the air like floating
around I mean the whole their cities
built around it like even when the money
song came on you're like okay a classic
like money is back and forth and like
it's still like has references to the
Kremlin and Trump like it's it's pretty
pretty intense really political it's
political well he's a pretty powerful
political you know voice in that whole
realm and you know what he's saying is
not is not what people want to be
hearing so or at least certain people
and other people want to yes Michael
I I want to just pop on here if it is
the last one I wanted to smoke a bowl on
here I never see anybody smoking a ball
I keep it old-school for the most part
you know I work with all these wonderful
extracts and everything but you know
that's how I started and that's what I
go to when I hate there we go he's got a
ball a ball and a stretch you know I
love the like the way you guys look
perfect like the mic was right in the
middle of the panel you guys both got
the black shirts the bald head the nice
headphones its what Tony hep Tony had me
go get the headphones so we could try
this dual headphones yeah
I've had them for a hundred and fifty
eight episodes and not everyone's oh I
did dual headset with Steve DeAngelo but
it was so loud we didn't get to to use
it but I told him was like man I got the
mic I got the headsets he was like
really I'm like yeah I get the headset
yeah we had Steve DeAngelo and hashed
Church and he never said a word we
watched you guys on mute the whole time
and this is the last one I just saw this
is that this is it tour so this starts
that this is it oh I got you this is the
the latest final tour well this is this
is basic the first final basically what
this is is this has church with no
makeup we might do a whole makeup tour
yeah exactly
this is - Church live on actually he's
gone 158 episodes it's gone on
unbelievably in all locations and
sometimes a man needs a Sunday and you
know they all need Sundays and so what's
he saying
that's it I'm gonna stop the broadcast
on that thanks for coming out everybody
we'll see you next time bye there never
be another time Bobby's yeah ask Church
is breaking down from its sober
foundations and we have to get right
back on the track ball wrap you know
what I wanted to do was I wanted to stop
all this cannabis ridiculousness and
start booze church because let's be
honest booze is the real deal
it's medicinal it's recreational it's
good for the children nobody ever said
that takes my pain away right away takes
it you want if you want to have 10
million viewers to start booze and
football church yeah yeah just have
Hastert and review flow we're gonna
change it to boob Church that will
actually give them some more viewers you
know what you might be right
you might be right but I don't think
that will have any of our respected
esteemed colleagues showing up anymore
like Hillary black or dr. Natasha no
they wouldn't they
do it at all we're gonna be out there
gonna be like sorry guys we just we lost
all respect for everything you do and
when you started blues church and by the
way I think God on that note we should
also pay some serious respect to the
ladies because I think one of the one of
the top 10 best episodes is when there
was an all-women's hash Church easy
Thomas yeah Tom yeah it was pretty
impressive because it was like CNN took
over hashed Church with all of these
like professional broadcasters
researchers doctors and really made us
all look a little just kind of like
we're barely holding it together guys
well even though every single one was
framed perfectly you know you didn't see
tons of [ __ ] they all had like these
perfect frames like they were like news
anchors I was like holy [ __ ] ladies are
crushing it but and there was the but
not only that it was the amount of
information per square inch if you will
like when we talk about lumens it was
there wasn't a slow draw or we had to
come to a conclusion together or like we
talked about it it was no interruptions
no interruptions it just full-on machine
gun information like it was like we're
live here down in down in Mexico after
the earthquake we're gonna go here it
was like it was like wow so the amount
of information that got pushed
incredible I thought it was like an
incredible unity and and people need to
need to understand that the future of
cannabis is gonna have a lot of women in
it and it should I think it brings a
good harmony between two approaches of
our industry but hats off to the women
that did that episode one of the best
hash searches it's already full I
thought for the best growers that I have
met in the past two or three years have
been women some women have turned me
under some of the best buds
ever had my hands on including back in
Vietnam days and I wasn't even going to
grow anymore I gave up last year because
I you know I'm getting old and it gets
hard to do but this year I grew a dozen
plants and way do you see the one it
looks like somebody spray-painted it
with glitter and I used my years long
scenario to do it with grab it - if you
have a pool and rabbit bootie with the
only additives in it and I just we
smoked one last night it just puts you
in another headspace you smoked rabbit
poo last night or what did you literally
I guess because the remand made the
terpenes and they made the track chrome
heads and that's what I was burning so I
guess I was saying I was having rabbit
poo red that's awesome so anyway there's
some of my stuff in the background there
you like it yeah oh um when you're
putting your oil real quick I did want
to say this because this is really
important when you put the oil in the
pen John or anybody that's out there you
know just like when you're hitting a
bong you would you would pull then you
would light your bowl then you would hit
your bong then you would clear it and
you would never leave like a stale bong
so like the same thing with this is you
want to pull press get whatever hit you
want let go clear it and when and when
you're if you use your finger it doesn't
really matter but it whatever size your
hit is but for oil especially when
you're using live resin like a BHO
something that's real runny you have to
be able to let the tank cool down and do
that by putting your finger here and if
it's still warm to the touch don't hit
it again
just pull cool air through it just over
and over until it's cool so there were
people that were using that these tanks
for the for like live resins and you
know 20 and 30% oils and things like
that but they're hitting it over and
over and over and the tank will run high
and it's not like a wick it's not a
wicking system so I just wanted to let
you know that before in case this was
there's a hole in the bottom you have to
be yeah just gotta be conscious of it
it's like everything in nature this hole
in the bottom stuff drains out oh yeah
don't drain well miners always if you do
it exactly like that you'll always have
a clean bottom you know just like always
clean I always pull cool air through it
every time after every hit I thought mom
said teaching us about wiping about the
clean bottom yep exactly the same thing
in life is a clean bottom but let me
tell you Tony if you run it in the
vacuum of 4835 you won't be amazed
this one that's what that is right there
yeah it's a totally different oil it's
unbelievable
exactly what you said this is like a low
heat on you know yeah I know I've done
it quite a few times and I know it's a
very good method and if you've got a
specially resistant oil like sometimes
when you do BHO you get it come out and
it'll look like an iceberg or it'll just
be solid as a rock then you raise it to
149 degrees for the 48 hours and it'll
get motile again Deandra have you uh
checked out that new Ken Burns
documentary and your always mentioned in
Vietnam and your time in Vietnam the new
Vietnam documentary I just started
watching it it seems amazing I don't
know if you've seen any of his other
documentaries but it's intense
18 hours yeah it's it's I mean if you
were there I was there for 31 months I
was a combat field medic so I'm never in
a hurry to see pictures again
I've got about 2,000 pictures thirty
five-millimeter that I brought back from
Vietnam with me over the and I've never
looked at them once about a match and I
gave them to my mom and she put them in
a box
don't ever
out like I wanted to see I didn't even
want to look at the pictures of my
friends because every single person I
was with there died there I was the one
person to wit in a company and got back
out and so I've never felt drawn when I
look at that stuff it's like something
gets stiff inside of me you know because
going through that experience I think
what saved me and made me not crazy and
not want to kill myself like so many
guys did because when he came back the
country didn't accept the responsibility
for it they left it on the shoulders of
the veterans and so a lot of them
started killing themselves but soon
after I came back I picked up some
hippies hitchhiking and they took me to
a party where they were passing out LSD
and I was there for about a week high on
LSD and afterwards I thought to myself
well Vietnam that's a memory now isn't
it so I don't really look I don't look
to re-experience and again my sort of my
way of dealing with it was finding my
Center in the universe that weekend
tripping on acid and I truly did find my
we were at a house in the Hollywood
Hills three-story house and they brought
me in on the bottom floor gave us acid I
started passing out Vietnam joints
everybody was really plastered and I
ended up on the third floor and
everybody was talking about the first
acid trips and I hadn't had one so they
made sure that I didn't have one and it
was a dome on the roof up there and you
can see it at night it was quite amazing
never forget it and that memory sort of
superseded the Vietnam stuff you know I
can remember guys in Vietnam on guard
duty taking acid which I didn't you know
that wasn't something that I was
interested in doing there I did smoke
probably two bales of marijuana while I
was there a sized bales of marijuana at
least and I sent a lot back to my mom
and Panasonic and Sanyo refrigerators
because they didn't have customs in
those days and you could send anything
directly back if they didn't have
customs but if you were on a combat
soldier you didn't have to go through
customs your mail went direct so I
started sending my mom send you over for
greater specs with Bluetooth stick and a
lot of seeds and by the way one of the
seeds one of the plants that I grew this
year it's the one that has these amazing
Trek homes or even on the bottom of the
leaf as thick as they are on the top
I've you look at my Instagram account
I've been posting pictures of this
particular leaves and plants on this
it's a green one but it's comfortable
trichomes everywhere I've never seen the
trek home so thick on the bottom and the
top I wish bubbleman was here because
I'd like to take some buds out of this
particular stuff and make bubble hash
out of it is so beautiful the trichomes
are just thick as flies everywhere all
over it
and that was one of the scenes that I
brought back and it was a random seed I
picked out I just stuck my hand in the
little jar that I've got pulled this one
speed up and there it is and I didn't
make any cuttings that were there
anything either sadly but such as life
such as life sometimes that's how it
goes sometimes you take cuts off
everything sometimes she gets lost so
desperate you bring her back yeah I put
some male teeth on one of the bottom
branches on it but even then it's gonna
be a different kind of a plant that the
seed will be able to be this very same
clan but anyway maybe we'll see well
what what a heavy heart this last day
but I understand you know you've made a
long sacrifice in behalf of everyone
else's consciousness and one of the best
things I ever heard from a guru in my
life which would be a good thing
for you was I was struggling at the time
learning Anatomy
and my teacher said to me if you want to
learn a thing teach it and you'll be
here every question there it is and
you'll learn it more thoroughly than any
other person could have taught you and I
think that's all you've done bubbleman
you've you've taught and in that
teaching you've learned yourself a great
deal and so I couldn't deny that I've
definitely learned a lot sitting here
and listening to everyone talk and being
a part of the conversations for the last
three years I have definitely learned a
lot I can't I've come I'm coming out
this end with a lot more knowledge than
I went into it for sure everyone else
and everyone that's panel and although
all the viewers and all the people that
input everything from when we started
learning the static dry sifting when he
was doing carding and tribal sitting on
the back of the iTunes card and just how
everything is kind of there's all these
little steps and all these little things
that have happened over the years it's
been it's been pretty awesome dudes a
fantastic time I mean [ __ ] we've learned
everybody here's lunch it's been one of
the best things that's happened for me
over the last about three years for sure
meeting my brother another thing with me
this fantastic part of life here
absolutely bingo Lombardi it was split
and chat he's gonna hang out on his
birthday have a good birthday dude at
the Renaissance Fair interesting he
probably kind of trippy all over the
world people that are in chat where's
everybody on show you know tell us where
you're from right now because um people
where we from is everybody from
absolutely yeah well we'll see people
are tripping in the chat room a like oh
my god is this the last hashtag ever I
never said that it was I just
that I might stop doing it but I'm just
you know if it's hard to try and
organize and get everyone excited about
a conversation each week it was you know
it was there's all there's been all
these little blows that have occurred
over the over the years and and hashed
Church doesn't get quite the views that
he used to get it's it's probably
getting half the amount of views that it
used to get so you know these were all
things that I took into consideration
and obviously we're not just doing it
for views but I like the idea of knowing
that like thousands tens of thousands of
people were seeing an episode and you
know now we might get five six thousand
reasons over the course of a couple of
weeks see what we'll see what happens I
haven't by any means it's a good idea
that Tony had so if we don't come back
we did a wrap-up episode we went through
some of the history and some of the
important intersections that we had and
that's a bit look this serves a lot of
different purposes there's a girl who
doesn't a channel called digging Brit
which she's got a super voluptuous body
and she barely wears anything she goes
around with a metal detector in this
book and she gets a million hits a week
but those great million people who hit
on that show are there for one reason to
see digging Brit bending over and
digging with the spoon here at five or
six thousand people just hit are people
that figure to him to our society and
culture in a big way we're not just
getting people here who are goggling in
her DNA
you know so I would say if 5,000
builders are a lot more important in
this particular case than a million
vehicles who are there just watching
somebody's body I mean overall influence
influence to spread no I'm not gonna
take the old churches down someone's
like oh don't take the videos down no
the videos are up there there to stay
you know if YouTube ever decided to take
them down
I'd put them up on the bubble man brand
calm website and people could go watch
them over there like they're there
they're secured they're good to go that
the past will never be lost in that
sense and the future is the future we'll
see what happens next Sunday we'll see
if people maybe new ideas and want to
talk about things you know otherwise
it's just I have an idea what if you
like go through and have some crazy dude
edit like edit like go back and like
edit like a series and take out like all
of key important conversations and
discussions and check and do a
basketball game yeah exactly like the
whole basketball game in five minutes
this week came out swinging hard they
were puffing Terps awesome
nine minutes into the episode they just
yeah yeah it's like nine minutes nine
minutes and 32 wade goes off on you know
blah blah blah like pull all these key
moments and I mean because it's a lot of
footage it's like anything else this
challenge live and then like if you film
anything in life live you edit you know
you get like you edit it down so maybe
somebody out there wants to start
editing the hash collection so you could
keep it you know I mean you know to edit
it all out yeah what's he did would you
suggest since we have such a plethora of
crazy goods available to us it's gonna
take years so that way what can happen
is it's the the legacy edit edit
versions somebody would have to work on
that for years I'm surprised nobody's
doing it already like this I got YouTube
so people are definitely downloading
them and stuff like that you know what
people would really notice is if this
conversation stopped they would notice
like Oh weird like where do you go to
find this [ __ ] out now like where do you
go to like kind of have this cutting
edge like what because trust me it's not
like the scenes gonna stop all this
stuff's still gonna keep happening it's
just been really neat that it's been
happening in this little circle of
people that have been really pushing and
promoting and pushing the envelope on a
lot of these different conversations
from soil grown with with rosin from you
know Tony and Horacio with the terpenes
and you know with all of us with all of
our different
areas of expertise it's been interesting
to say the least
well there'd be a lot less people making
good bubble hash listen there I've been
getting really good bubble heads from
Eureka for sixty to eighty dollars an
ounce really light beautiful really
crazy stuff and then I pressed it in my
dark ex a little tiny press to make
fresh frozen with it right and some of
the most beautiful boy some of it's like
it's almost like a sponge you pick it up
the whole thing just soft wants to start
melting and melts in your bubbles not in
your hands yeah well melts in your mind
right yes me there's a lot of it this
year because there's going to be a lot
of hot cuz a lot of people started
growing California is rife with pot
right now and it's gonna be interesting
it's gonna be very interesting we're
gonna see some price drops this year as
all these crops come due and for some
reason or other it seems like
everybody's having a bumper crop at the
same time like you talk to a lot of
friends I've been to a couple of farms
and men who looks like gangbusters and
by the way mr. Harlequin I have got a
boy I've got a little stash of pure CBD
oil for you do and for Forrest a pint
maybe and it's it's what a blessing
thank you when I win tries it and it's
absolutely clean I got all the paperwork
for messy labs everything best could do
was done on it it's nothing but big it's
just the good stuff
it's got point zero four deep what a
blessing I just forced Nora how to get a
hold of um Joe I don't know but I Indre
108 Yahoo will get all of me really easy
or also I've got the website pure exact
thing
pure extracts ink yeah look for an email
from wait at house of Harlequin yeah I
want to get it to you guys it's about a
pint and it's really beautiful stuff and
let me tell you I've been using myself
I've got two titanium cages in my back
being wounded in Vietnam and sometimes
they cost me a tremendous amount of pain
and limited my mobility and I've been
taking about an eighth of a teaspoon in
the morning and one at night of this CBD
oil and really been pain-free I mean I
just I get up walk around I forgot to
take my cane with me I went to town went
shopping all because I've had this
particular CBD for the past month and a
half and it has it I can't describe it
but it's a tremendous feeling of
well-being that I get within just 10 or
15 minutes of I just get my plastic
split in it and I get an eighth of a
teaspoon out put it in my mouth on my
tongue and swallow it and 15 minutes
later I feel I feel like I want to go do
something like I I'm not thinking well
gee if I go out am I gonna run out of
energy or am I gonna be have to sit
somewhere and rest and recover from my
back I just go and do it
and I think this CBD oil for some reason
it's very potent and that's why I really
want to get it to forest you know I if
it can help me not feel the pain that I
live with daily I'm more you know I
think it must be good for those kids so
anyway I get it really cheap by the kilo
I winterize it and I got a pint of it
for you and that's just Thank You India
because it does the job and they pulled
bless many people's lives yeah we'll use
it for sure well I hope I don't last you
for a while I'll get some more about
winterizing it it's a 90 percent of it
is is plant fat and stuff so you get it
to pretend you love it
it's
a lot of muck to handle to get down to
the ten point eight percent pure CBD but
I don't mind doing it for those kids
I mean I'll wait to a mile amok to helps
them feel better I understand the
feeling and I'm glad you're getting
benefit from it that's kind of the way I
experienced dosing with CBD is it's it's
not really about a buzz so much as just
a sense of well-being yeah yeah I can't
believe the difference it makes in my
everything it makes my attitude makes
how I feel how I'm dealing with other
people if you're in pain Oh with them
you're always biting that back and I
believe me I was in pain since 1968 when
I got wounded you know I've been in pain
ever since then until now maybe that's
one of the things that's kept me alive
because I've never been comfortable
enough to die but this CBD oil has
brought me great comfort and solace I
I couldn't believe in the beginning I
was a bit you know like everybody was
like I was like well I haven't seen any
evidence of that yet but this the first
time I got a hold of any and computer in
a pure quality other than some that the
guys give me from guild extracts all the
time when I go by their booth and that
gave me a relief too but this stuff this
oil of quarter teaspoon of it and then
an hour later you feel like Mother
Teresa
on a good day you're just dispensing
love you feel so much better like he
said it's not a it's not a high it's a
it's a high of state of mind because
you're endocannabinoid system is beaming
energy back to your brain because that's
what it's all connected to them it's
saying hey guess what we got stash yeah
I I think of tell you a funny little
thing about it I think of see
most most cultures have some sort of
psychoactive substance that they consume
sometimes it's alcohol sometimes it's
tobacco sometimes it's mushrooms
sometimes it's cactus
sometimes it's vines sometimes it's
roots but pretty much every culture has
some sort of psychoactive thing they get
up to and one of the things that's
interesting is that virtually all of
those cultures have shamans or guides
who take the initiative psychoactivity
and I think cannabis is one of the
plants that we use for its psycho
activity but part of what happened over
the years is that by breeding just for
psycho activity we bred out CBD and CBD
was kind of a built-in shaman that was
supposed to come along for the ride I
think back when I first smoked cannabis
it had CBD in it it was Jamaican
Jamaican yarders has CBD in it I know
DJs short was pretty convinced part of
what he was looking for in cannabis was
to replicate some Mexican cannabis that
he had had back in the 60s down and when
he was at the University down there and
he was pretty convinced that yeah it was
like equal amounts CBD and THC and so I
don't know that it's an essential part
of what cannabis can do for humans but I
think it's an important part and I what
I what I think is coming because of
comments like what you just made is that
increasingly people will start
recognizing cannabis not just for its
inspirational or recreational or even
medicinal but just for the sense of
well-being that can come from it what
you were saying earlier Marcus about
feel when you feel good it's hard it's
hard to feel bad when you feel good when
when the pain stops you don't feel like
biting back
at things that happen in your life pain
especially chronic pain that just goes
on and on and on never stops it's hard
you can't get away from it
so blessings thank you but they'll be
Turner de Durant CBE is definitely a bus
ticket away from pain there's no
question about that and by the way
Marcus we're taking it up this morning I
recently because of viewers listening to
have searched they sent me a giant box
of roots yes we took all those roots
ground them up and we threw them in the
chamber and extracted them so we're
gonna have the great first marijuana
root oil and I want to make sure that
dr. Natasha it's a bit of it examine
and/or look at and if anybody wants to
do any research with it I want to make
all amounts of it available to people
because I don't think there's anybody
that's done a full-on wound extract and
to make sure that we got it we left it
in the chamber like 24 hours to make
sure we got every single possible
volatile out of the roots and it was
quite a bundle of hurts let me tell you
you know it came in a two two and a foot
square box and I think well Natasha was
talking about allying up all the old
books it talks about the many uses for
marijuana roots all the different kinds
of medicines and focuses and whatever
that they made with it back when before
people have opinion about the east part
of it so I was talking about that a few
pens and somebody contacted me and asked
me if I wanted some and I said yes so
here they are and now I'm I suspect
it'll be high in Troy terpenoids
Sam I don't know I don't think I can
send it to you right send yourself
maybe if there's nope he's saying it if
you were even interested anyway
deal is last show I guess are sort of
the last show funny place to come up
with brand new information but you never
know you never know
could be it'll be interesting seeing
what's in it a good a lot of speculation
about it so I did it find out I remember
years ago probably as early as like 99
2000 I made bubble hash from stems just
all the stems not stems cut from pods
either but like whole plant stems like
long branches I just cut them all up
into little quarter inch sections and I
ran the whole batch and I got this like
white bubble it was the lightest [ __ ]
color bubble ever that came off the
stems and it was pretty good it was
melty it was powerful
it had taste it was it was it was hard
to wrap my head around that there was
resin on stalks that could be that's
when I actually not too long after
probably within 5 years or so I started
trying to photograph stems and get
closer to see what kind of a trichome
content they had on there and I've seen
them covered and I've seen them sparse
both both ways dude when you showed me
the picture of one the scene when when
we said that when the leaf just came out
of the seat and had a tripod I was just
amazed that was one of those pictures
that you showed I was right there but
that picture that was definitely what
most people did not know that the glands
are on the plants from the beginning
because they're all like oh I just I
only spray in veg and it's like really
cuz it's like you're still spraying
trichomes you understand that right
while those trichomes won't even they're
gonna fall off those leaves will long
have fallen off it's like alright well
whatever you say well that's why the in
the center of your bud right because
they fall off my guys it's like of
course they start it's cool to see
though man I'm really really cool to see
something different anyway I don't know
I'm gonna call it a call it a day here
guys it's been just under three hours
I'm definitely anxious to get out and
enjoy my Thanksgiving day with my family
here and I'm as always would love to
thank everyone if this does happen to be
the last hash search I would absolutely
like to thank everyone that's ever
appeared as a panelist to share their
time with us as well as of course the
core group of people that seem to be
here more often than anyone we do
appreciate you and all the people that
have watched over the last three years
it's been it's been a good trip you may
see us next week you may not see us next
week it's all up in the air really don't
worry about it too much you'll have
yourself a wonderful week grow some
wheat smoke some resin
sniff some turps
and I guess I'll finish it how I like to
finish my wake and bakes may the full
melt bubble bless your bowl sooner than
later Thank You Martha
everybody thank you
[Applause]
[Music]