hello it's perfect
hey
Dave you're
muted I'm G A actually try right now
here we
go let's see if we
can't let's see if we can't oh it's
being sent to a live
stream be great if it worked
that would be great if it
worked oh look at that it's working holy
smokes well look at that I finally
figured it out I cannot believe I
finally figured this out well welcome
everybody to Hash Church
5.0 episode 4 I think this might be one
of the first
times that it's actually Gone
live on the on the on the screen that I
created in YouTube a week ago so thank
you to Thomas from Grandmaster LED uh
who helped me organize yes John Maddox
it worked uh and that's all thanks to
Thomas from Grandmaster LED who kind of
walked me through it the other day and
uh that's amazing for those of you that
don't know what I'm talking about uh we
usually create a live
video on YouTube a week before the show
and what happens is is that when I go
live it almost always creates a
different link so all the people that
are waiting in the room have to move and
we have to uh you know go to another
room and today we didn't have to do that
so yeah look at that me and skunkman Sam
in the room just the two of us for now I
think we got a decent show happening
today we got a couple of new folks that
are going to be coming in for the
conversation we had a great show last
week for those of you that haven't
noticed I am broken in a way I have
broken my clavicle about 4 days ago I uh
was skateboarding at the skateboard park
in Whistler uh it was my son's 10th
birthday and I was having a blast just
ripping around the skate park uh and I
came down a real steep embankment I came
around the corner and I was flying and I
hit a rock and that rock utterly and
completely crushed me I'm just going to
mute you there real quick uh Sam uh that
rock actually just stopped me dead I
flew off my skateboard 10 to 15 feet
into the air uh and I landed on my
shoulder quite hard I would say the
equivalent of like your good buddy
hitting you with a bat at about
70% and uh now I'm now I've got a broken
uh clavicle so nothing shall stop us
here at hash Church nor rain nor shine
nor broken clavicle I will be here and
uh yeah that's what happens
Mojave so what did you do I broke my no
no oh my god dude wow and you did this
in the last week
yeah did you do it on August 27th no I
didn't and I'm sure it was not nearly as
fun as how you broke your clavicle dude
I'm telling you that but yeah I just
accidentally kicked the freaking
baseboard mess goofing around with my f
my son so I was also playing with my son
at the Whistler skate park he was it's
his 10th birthday him and his Budd are
all on scooters and I'm skateboarding
and uh yeah I just I hit a rock going a
super high speed it made that
sound and then I flew and when I landed
I just remember like o like the the most
insane sound and how I knew I was hurt
before I knew I was hurt because the
adrenaline pumps through your body so
fast was when I heard all the 20
somethings in the skate park like at
least 15 of them go o
when I heard that I was like oh that was
that was probably bad and so you know 20
minutes later I'm at like world class
Hospital top trauma people I got a tank
of nitrous oxide with my own regulator
you know she's I'm just sucking on that
nitrous oxide because I told them I
don't take the opioids they they you
know I I hyper metabolize those things
and they make me feel really really sick
but uh I have to admit it was neat to
take um nitrous oxide not like at a fish
show it really
works yeah it's it's wild it didn't make
me dizzy it didn't usually any of that
stuff just makes me feel weird um I also
wasn't on a psychedelic so it was the
first time I think I'd ever tried
nitrous not tripping balls um so yeah it
was uh it was what it what it was what
it was both you and I uh are broken
today yeah did you have a gravity
event a gravity event yes I did have a
gravity event I had a I had a major
gravity event and uh let me tell you for
those people that don't believe in
gravity it's real I can I can assure you
it is real and uh it it hurts when uh
when you fall down like that I've never
broken a clavicle I've broken most of my
fingers my wrists my arm both my ankles
my CICS my collar bone probably missing
a couple that I can't really remember
but I believe this was my 17th bone I
broke at 51 years old so yeah
skateboarding snowboarding dirt biking
downhill mountain biking just being an
all-around Maniac for most of my life um
yeah well welcome everybody Welcome
skunkman Sam and Mojave and etan and
Colin and whoever iPhone 64 is about to
enter it's probably our new guy because
I don't know anyone else that comes in
on a phone
we'll see we'll see there they are
they're sitting right there with the
black
screen thanks keep it simple I will get
well soon uh it's not as bad as a broken
collar bone that was five weeks of
immobility this is uh not so bad pretty
bad but not as bad that's enough of
talking about my broken
bone iPhone 64 is that uh Mas Edgar is
that you Masonic yeah that's me I'm
getting in here I'm learning how to use
this real quick there we go
boom boom what's up homie what's up G
how you guys doing good to have you on
bro all broken up but uh we've already
been through that so now it's uh
probably about starting to hit some dabs
and let me tell you about the
pain uh reducing benefits of cannabis
you really feel it when you crush
yourself and get hurt and I believe Wade
was talking about that either last week
or the week before you know spending so
much of his life really preparing
cannabis for for people who really need
it but being on the other side of it and
I believe that he said something like
you know I feel blessed that I'm now on
this side and I'm able to use cannabis
and see it from a really firsthand point
you know when you get something serious
like Wade has um I mean obviously we've
been preaching it but when you get into
it like even my wife was like are those
gummies really helping you I'm like
unbelievably so no Tylenol no Ville no
Tylenol 3es just cannabis uh
wonderfulness hell yeah dude this really
works it's a thca bomb and a friend of
mine makes it and you know I'm I'm a
skeptic about everything in life you
know I like to know but this stuff
really works and for a while I was like
oh my buddy gave it to me and when I rub
it on my elbow of course I'm going to
think good thoughts and feel happy
emotions and you know cure my little
pains but after doing this for a while
this thca with some other little stuff
it amazing pain
relief yeah I agree man I I find that
some of the topicals um at high dose
milligrams like 7,000 CB you know 7,000
milligrams CBD
7200 really actually helps um and canono
as well but yeah that brings up a
problem because agreed medicinal dosage
is a higher dosage and your States side
we're limiting dosage right because uh
at least here in California you're
limited to 100 milligrams dosage per Etc
and so since 2018 it's been a problem
for my serious medical patients to find
quality high dosage
products you know because of exactly
what you stated you know Marcus uh I
broke something I'm in a lot of pain I
need something now and you can't you can
get that Marcus and I'm glad you can I'm
glad you're able to find dosages that
work but this is a conundrum on the
ground for the individual patient still
that we are unable to get the medicine
needed depending on the legislation
within the state so yeah you're not
wrong it's that way in Canada too
unfortunately we obviously have a weird
thing in Canada we've got this Federal
legalization thing going on we've got
medical so if you're a medical patient
there's sort of access obviously when it
was only medical and everyone was hiding
behind it to protect their grow I'm not
judging I'm just saying that's what was
happening um it was more accessible the
minute recreational came in all of the
medical people just jumped into message
just let mute you real quick um they
just it's not accessible here either
basically 10 milligrams is the limit uh
that you can get in Canada now you can
go to a Rec store and buy a grand of
live resin or live rosin or distillate
for anywhere from probably 15 to $30 so
if you have a little bit of knowledge
you can go buy extracts and crockpot it
in your own uh in your own uh you know
MCT or coconut oil or whatever else
you're choosing as a carrier but that's
unacceptable for patients you're you
know imagine if you were like oh well
you can buy insulin but you actually
have to prepare it like uh you just have
to prepare your insulin before it's
actually usable so it's a little un
unreasonable here still as well um I I'm
I'm truly a 10 milligram guy I can you
know when I'm hurt I'll probably take
you know four or five of those in a day
which is still only 50 uh milligrams
whereas my homie Thomas from Grandmaster
LED I mean he took 2400 milligrams on
the plane ride the last time I went to
Germany with him and didn't die like
didn't like wasn't a zombie wasn't uh
you know blubbering and slobbering and
like was completely 100% present and so
we all also have different
metabolization rates we all are affected
by cannabinoids uh differently and so
you know I I do feel for the patients
that have that sort of slow
metabolization like Thomas and and
really requires large
doses to to not have it be available is
a is a pretty big bummer for
sure yeah and I I have a high tolerance
to THC as well edible so it's like and I
make my own for that reason because I
don't want to ingest so much sugar you
know like when it's just like someone
gave me a drink and they're like 10
milligram drinks and I'm like man I have
to drink five of these and that's insane
or if they're gummies or whatever it's
like I have to drink eat all these it's
like just give me a therapeutic dose in
an edible form though it's nice to you
know yeah yeah no I I I shout out White
Rabbit because uh it's a local company
here I bumped into them a while ago you
know this dude Dave was just that event
I went to called the collector's cup and
he was way off in the corner and he was
giving away gummies and they were like
the square gummies and they kind of had
the little bit of you know cane sugar on
them so I'd seen this style before but
when I tasted his he had like habanero
mango and banana Maca and he had these
like he had an actual formulator working
with his company that was actually
producing these flavor profiles based on
the flavor profiles of the volatile
organic compounds that were present in
the plant and I thought this is [ __ ]
awesome um no no real sugar a tiny
little bit of cane sugar he was
sweetening them with brown rice syrup uh
you know they were all vegan they were
all just like incredible like the the
quality in the caliber and I thought
well this is a good idea to you know
make this available there's other
gummies on the market I was I was taking
these pearls for a while but it's sugar
right and if you're consistently taking
these things you know and you're doing
it sort of for you know the benefit of
your health you it probably doesn't take
much to figure out that you know
consuming sugar on a daily basis any
extra considering they put it in your
bread and all your condiments and just
everything to to to consume a low amount
of sugar is truly to be a conscious
human being in today's day and age
because it is difficult I saw a guy the
other day and this I don't think we have
these up in Canada we might it was a
Dunkin Donuts and he got this pumpkin
latte spice thing it was like a big
milkshake and this thing had
185 gram of [ __ ] sugar now this is
like Diet diabetes all day long and now
that we're getting to the point where
people are starting to realize that type
3 diabetes is dementia that's
Alzheimer's disease that's the loss of
access to your uh memories and so as
they put that connection and I I think
it was I don't know if it was huberman
or one of these other podcast medical
guys that was the first person I saw
mention that no it was actually uh the
dude that uh turned Dana White Health
around I can't remember him he's another
uh kind of online doctor dude and I I
was like no that can't be true and the
more and more I searched it the more and
more I realized yeah like almost every
country in the world Associates type 3
diabetes with dementia and Alzheimer's
North America is kind of the only
countries that don't associate it as
that so I know this has a a special
place in in your heart Colin as you have
a loved one suffering from uh from
Alzheimer's and Dementia so just uh yeah
keep it's an interesting topic because
it's you know and Parkinson's really is
the main focus for us all the other
those dementia is setting in slowly but
you're it's it's interesting when you've
seen a healthy person go through a
neurological disease and then all this
other constituent start to cave in on it
and seeing cannaboids in the mix on that
at high doses I mean you're seeing I'm
seeing things that I can't explain like
Full Stop on Tremors
um being able to talk better um better
use of their muscles um it's just all
over man but it's yeah and that's where
I think just better product to your
point ATN is like it's just needed man
like we're just in a in a weird modality
right now where everyone it's not it's
not just that it's exactly what you're
talking about that scene it's not just
high dosage one of the earlier things we
learned in the medical community here in
California was that again all of our
products were made by patients because
of their medical needs so we had Suka we
had various types of natural sugar
products available low glycemic all
kinds of different things that people
were making unfortunately due to the
legalization here in California we lost
almost 99% of all those products and
product lines because they could not
make
that leap and so what you're talking
about dietarily especially due to sugar
is a huge problem in conundrum as you
said because what's the most easy to
find product on the market gummies
gummies are everywhere and every Gummy
has sugar in it if not then it has the
fake sugars and we know those fake
sugars are a huge problem depending on
your disease and Etc and what you're
going through and we know if you have
Cancers and things like that you should
be avoiding sugars Al together um you
know outright because sugar helps feed
those cancers depending on the type of
cancer Etc so you know proper
dietary uh choices just having non sugar
choices that are healthy where are they
are they accessible to you because
they're not accessible to me so much as
they used to be and that's a huge
conundrum when high I've just found out
I'm stage four
and the only thing available to me is
all sugar products so consumers watching
you need to talk to manufacturers and
demand these things that's why we
carried them originally when we realized
oh I'm diabetic and I need this type of
product because there's no other type of
product on the market for me and if you
don't know it then create it if you have
something that works for you that's why
a lot of these product manufacturers
started off they realize I don't have
access access I have to create it and
now that I have created it now I have to
manufacture it yeah but I think it goes
back to what you're saying it's like the
you know you have to be a super fan and
also really connected to the plant to
understand that need right and that it's
you know we talk about this a lot in
music where whole the industry basically
sold the cataloges to these streaming
services for Equitable positions in
those companies right and the only way
they get paid is through the streaming
which gives them better Equitable
positions right right and it's almost
the same situation in Canabis where
people like us who really care are
connected to it are not in
positions more often than the not we're
not in positions to make these products
because those people that are making
those products don't have the same
connection they don't understand the
same need of patients they're looking
at profit and loss we're looking at
patient needs right and then whatever
else comes after it it can even be taken
further back in the sense Colin and I
like the way pivoted this because it's
not just the products it's not just the
creation of the products it's really why
we invited Masonic into the room today
it's why we wanted to talk about
breeding it's about the bottom line is
is that these companies that would want
to control this and create these
products and bring them to Market and
stabilize and shelf you know all of
these different things they don't have
the connection to the production and the
creation of these unique volatile
organic compound profiles these unique
canabo profiles although a lot is thca I
will admit I you know even when we made
cultivars that had CBC and thcv and cbga
and all of these other canabo most
people in the dabbing World anyway just
thought it was weird it's got a weird
texture cbga in particular is a weird
texture if you're a big Dabber and you
start dabbing that you'll be like oh
this is this is waxy and weird I don't
think I like this very much but the
bottom line is is when you look at all
of these incredible cultivars that have
been produced and and I remember Wendy
uh Turner uh uh um what's his her son's
name how am I spacing on his name right
now uh Crohn's disease uh the Colton
exactly Colton Turner so when she came
in and she was like I thank you guys
because I said you're such a middle
American mom like you must look at us
like we're a bunch of hippies and she's
like I love you guys more than you'll
ever imagine you guys were the keepers
of the plant you guys were the ones that
kept these plants alive all of these
years so that Colton could come along
learn about this gain access to plants
and and be able to turn his Crohn's
around in a way that we had never seen
before so there's this connection of the
roots of the people who like skunkman
Sam who traveled to all these hash
producing countries who planted these
insane amount of seeds who collected
these
incredible um you know cultivars in
order to use as breeding stock and now
you know we've gone down so many
generations and there's people like
Masonic and there's people like flux and
and Ramone and all of these incredible
people that are just keeping this work
alive to me that is the basis of all of
everything that we're talking about that
is the most important factor and that's
kind of what we're going to be talking
about today pheno hunting and breeding
and and how selection is done I know
that how Sam did it is probably very
different from how people are doing it
now with populations being so decreased
um a lot of people are doing incredible
work really in like their homes you know
whereas Sam was doing incredible work in
fields so I kind of just want to open up
that discussion welcome Masonic to to be
speaking about this uh with us I know
you've had some incredible lines dude I
know that some of the the cultivars that
you've produced have created just some
absolutely insane hashes so we're really
stoked to have you here today and
Stoke to uh maybe have you tell us a
little bit about kind of how you got
into this and where your specialty lies
in regards to how you um how you choose
your breeding stock and how you choose
your your
fenos yeah and the other thing I want to
say about Masonic is you know you know
we we met a few years ago in person and
we really kind of connected on this
concept of the love of of flavor
profiles and then we started talking
about music and you know one thing I
noticed about Edgar and Masonic is that
he he doesn't need permission he just he
does what he feels and I think that's
kind of the spirit of everyone here on
the panel is like what we came up in was
we didn't have permission it just was we
we were we were drawn to this in a way
that was it was it was bigger than us
right and you're you're continuing that
um that spirit in a way that allows you
to connect with culture make friends and
build your own little culture around
that and that's to me that's that's what
it's all about man you know and that's
that's it's great to see you so
connected and just loving what you're
doing like his genuine love that I see
you know so it's it's very cool to see
that and you know just he's working with
shis berry Marcus again and to hear like
that come up as a varietal 25 years
removed from when we touched it and had
like good success with it is is amazing
and kind of brings a full circle for me
so I think it'd be great I saw that this
morning dude and it made me talk about
all that and just kind
of go ahead yeah just tell us about it
man but I wanted to just kind of get
that bid in there to give you give the
viewers you know the color that you know
you're doing your thing through passion
man you know yeah thank you guys uh for
starters for letting me be a part of
this I'm uh you know I I was on here
before but it's a night and day you know
you know from last time I was here I
feel as far as head space um but I I uh
I I started smoking weed like everybody
I'd imagine you know we we love smoking
weed and next thing you know I ran out
of this really quality bag of weed that
I had gotten one U High School summer
when I graduated my father gave me a
pound of Sour Diesel and I lost that
pound of Sour Diesel because I wasn't
necessarily the best Hustler I was more
so a consumer and you know next thing
you know the thing's gone and I'm like
yo how do we get this going again and
I'm like I'm going to have to start
growing it so I started like from like
I'm 18 years old and then I'm probably
growing for like till you know just
growing pumping out the yard to like
2016 and all I knew was I didn't know
anything about like you know
um males and females make seeds all I
knew was kill the ones that are males
and leave all the girls and you know
you'll be happy so that's what I did for
like 6 years and then I opened you know
I I found out about fors and little
forms like uh never got into any of them
though I would go look into it and I
would just look away I'd be like n
that's too much for me like I'm going
just go back to this remedial landscape
you know and I would just do my do my
gardening i' blow up the garden to the
best of my ability so that's what I was
doing and then 2016 came along and um
that's when I finally opened up
Instagram and it wasn't through YouTube
it wasn't through the fors it wasn't
through anything else that I seen this
Big World of uh Growers you know there's
just a bunch of people that are growing
and they're open about it you know even
around that time people were still kind
of like do we show this off do we not
show this off on Instagram and uh I I
was like oh cool this is cool a lot of
people to take a muse from so I started
just imitating the greats from there and
you know um the the breeding kind of
came cuz I had tools like I had a
Tropicana cherry pie Tangi before F2 was
invented which was one of the better
hash varieties so I was growing that
Tropicana on Instagram and people were
taking notice I didn't necessarily know
what I had at the time I just was
associating with people that vibed with
me so they gave me tools to help me in
my journey unknowingly that was Bloom at
the time you know so I'm just like cool
I'm already in good graces of Bloom
still am to this day he's one of my you
know first mentors first person that
ever gave me seeds and he's the guy
behind papaya Tropicana all that good
stuff so he had gave me the precursors
to the Tropicana F2 wave and I'm growing
them and people are taking notice and
I'm like cool I got something cool I
even noticed at the time jungle boys was
growing the same seed stock variety that
I was and I'm just like cool like I'm on
the right path you know and um stray
seeds got made with those seeds and I'm
like very transparent about my Approach
like I like I show everything I'm like
oh look there's freaking you know this
got hit by a random male here and people
are like I'll take one you know and I'll
be like here I send it to a person
around the way and and keep in mind I've
been growing for like six years just
blowing up the backyard blowing up the
backyard filling up the garage you know
uh breaking down all the weed I would
blast a lot like since 2012 I was open
blasting I might have done a little five
gallon bucket wash here and there but it
it like the squeeze wasn't worth it I
was like n like let's not do that let's
just keep blasting it you know and so we
did open blasting for a very long time
like 20 12 till like I started till I
reached Instagram and back to the the
trop can cherry pangi those seeds got
made people started inquiring I started
kind of like liking it like oh that's
cool like that is that you know like oh
this is kind of like you know um part of
that plant is in this seed stock but I
always kept seeds from straight plants
anyway so it was always a thing that I
did but this time it was like people
were inquiring and then I had a mail and
even then I wasn't convinced sh I was
like N I don't want to make seeds yet
because I have to blast all this stuff
to make like anything worth it you know
in order to even consume it you know
because that's what it's all about
because I would smoke my own weed and I
just had enough to nickel and dime on
the you know Compton Boulevard I would
literally sell my weed and on Central in
Downtown LA like I would literally go to
the shadiest places to go sell my uh my
shatter that I made with my open Nug Run
but that's what I did and then I had a
Mel I'm I'm bouncing back and forth I
had a mail and I and I advertised it on
Instagram I was like yo who wants this
mail who wants to like it's the Tropic
caner pangi mail who wants it somebody
raised their hand almost immediately I
gave them the mail I'm not thinking
about breeding or making seeds though
I'm still like oh we're like pumping out
these plants we're taking nice pictures
we're doing the whole thing I'm I'm
growing a bunch of papaya F maybe at the
time cuz that's what was out at the
moment and I'm just like you know being
a team player you know I'm not breeding
with all the tools that are just given
me I'm just growing plants to grow
plants and I'm smoking it after and then
uh you know a whole flower cycle later
from that Mel given to that uh to the
dude that I gave it to um he comes back
to me and he's like yo I got these seeds
and I'm like oh you do have those seeds
like like you do have those seeds so
almost immediately I tell all of
Instagram yo Instagram I have plushberry
Tropic can cherry pie Tangi and agent
orange Tropicana cherry pie Tangi and
people were like I'll take two
and I was like holy [ __ ] like I think
this is what I need to do you know like
this is make this is worth the squeeze
like apparently I have a calling and
that's that's when I went to chalice
that year and uh I met Bloom and and
person because all had all this was done
online all these seed trans you know
seed Gatherings were done VIA mail
online finally I'm all like oh they're
in town they're in otono I'm like two
and a half hours away in Compton I'm
going to make it over there so I made it
over there and I met Bloom and that's
when he gave me the next five tools that
I was going to use in my journey scratch
that that I was growing Papaya at the
time I know where I was because that's
when he gave me you know uh papaya punch
banana OG
papaya fabuloso papaya which is arcade's
fabuloso it's like a he he's he's a cool
dude and then uh there was three chem
which is from Top Dog cross to papaya as
well and there was one more CEO papaya
so those were the five tools and he also
gave me the Tropicana F2 so I had those
six tools took those home grew those out
to grow them like I'm I'm still growing
I'm not breeding yet and then I like I
had a nice Tropicana F2 M and I had all
these nice papaya selections and
something told me like I I hit up a
hairy Palms almost immediately that's
Bloom and I was like hey can I make
seeds with these this is the first time
that I'm going to make seeds and he's
like dude rock that [ __ ] and that's when
Wilson was born that's banana OG papaya
Tropicana F2 so it everything just kind
of just natural organically with the
good graces of the breeder and then kind
of just being a team player you know and
that's how Wilson was born and that was
somewhere around like 17 I want to
say nice dude I love to hear the story
of how Wilson was born that's [ __ ]
awesome yeah I love how you got called
into it too you know there's so many
different ways to to feel the pull and
and you know kind of like Colin was
saying you don't have to you know just
go do your thing you know follow your
journey and let that journey lead you
towards it's these people who have this
Obsession what I've noticed is and I
don't know if we share like a heightened
o Factory or if it's just this utter and
complete passion and love of cannabis
that just you know just leads you down
this pathway and if you don't fight it
it's it it can be absolutely incredible
which I feel like everyone here on the
panel has fought it and has sort of
followed that pathway and we all kind of
ended up in different places we all look
up to each other at for different
aspects but uh yeah dude that is uh
that's a great story man Bill recognize
is real right we we see people with
passion right others who taught us
saw their passion in us and so they
lifted us up right and so that's our
responsibility and that's why we
volunteer time here at hash Church to
spread and teach because we were taught
many of us for free with the only
expense being pay it for it in the
future and we're very fortunate to have
the ability and the freedom now to speak
because all of us used to hide
underground just like you were talking
about you had to go find your people and
they had to absorb you and trust you you
have to build that trust and that is
something we were all forced to do
because it used to be illegal and so
that was another camaraderie that we
used to you know rally around I used to
only hire activists because we were
expecting to get arrested every day now
I don't have to do that because you know
we've changed and the things shifted but
you're carrying on the
noble and I consider the Growers the
most noblest of them all of us because
you're the ones that have been
perpetuating you're the ones who have
been taking the risk you are dealing
with the risk of how you grow where you
grow and what you grow to keep it safe
clean and proper and me and my patients
all appreciate everything and all the
risks that you've taken nothing but love
and great respect to all you Growers
yeah and Shout Out shout out to breeder
Steve I saw that post you made today
Masonic put a smile on my face you know
that was that was the birth of Bubble
Bags the shisha Berry because I had
tried the isolator bags um the two bag
system and I just wasn't I wasn't stoked
this was in like 98 I guess I moved to
British Columbia in '96 from Manitoba
after doing that whole hemp thing out
there came out here the only friend I
really had was Hillary black and Hillary
linked me up uh pretty early on with um
with breeder Steve and so by 98 when I
was trying these bags and kind of sort
of figuring out that I might end up
doing my own bags what led me to that
was the first time I ever ran Shish
Berry cuz Steve had called me up and he
was like look I got some shish fishberry
it's the yellow line uh it's really
Frosty trim let's let's let's try those
bags and it actually produced a full
melt hash from a two bag system so
everything from the 190 went into like
the 70 Micron bag just full of
contaminant and was melting you know
probably not anything like what I when I
finally met Sam some years later and
smoked his dry sift and was like oh oh
so there are actual levels to this [ __ ]
but still was leading me in and it was
probably like a four star I was all
excited about it it was the first time
I'd really ever seen it but without that
shishkaberry and that shishkaberry I
mean I could tell a lot of stories
because Steve was very close I had
access to both the red and the yellow
and I smoked that weed all over the
world and had that weed for hash making
and it was just uh every time when I
first smelt um the Barb from um great
Gardener immediately knew it was Shish
Berry when I first smoked the Nicole
from maros in Colombia Al alesandro I
immediately knew that he used
shishkaberry it's just this crazy
dominant flavor profile that is
unmistakable yet I haven't seen actual
shisher in like 25 years so be nice to
see that come
back that's gota we gotta run those
seeds from you you know the the shisu
berry
sounds if you can find a shisu berry
leaner in there it seems like even with
your Wilson attached to it it seems like
it it may it may improve the line you so
the shis berry came through me U via
hash jar so uh triple og ice house melts
he he won Legends of hash first place
with a a pink 57 which is a shishka
berry old Widow that's that's what uh
that's what they have so he he came to
my house like be like around the time he
had won second place with the lemon dog
[ __ ] he came to my to my garden and he
whips out this jar and I'm like yo what
the [ __ ] is this like this is like like
in that papaya realm you know at the
time I was telling them like this is
that fruity stuff it's not there's no
light on this what is this he's like
that's shishka Berry you know and I'm
like I need this you know somehow some
way a shishka berry plant ended up in my
garden and then you know I made seeds
with it and just kept repopulating the
forward line towards all the peach
varieties that I thought looked better
than the initial so like that's what I
have as far as seed stock every time you
you hear anything shishco Berry from ma
is the seeds made with that clone but um
but that's how I got put on game with it
I smoked I was like yo I need that I
ended up with it and then a couple like
years later like a year later I ended up
at spannabis I'm just walking through
and I and I look to my right and great
Gardener there and I'm like yo whoa
you're the you're the Barb Bud guy and
I'm like let me grab a couple packs of
those so I grab some Rags I grab some F
I go home I throw them in the dirt
almost immediately shush Berry I'm like
cool like like everything adds up it all
makes sense so and then the year after
that I grabbed more just for the you
know just just just because cuz they're
so nice you know and but yeah I'm like
super down as far as that you
know story of where I got shishy that's
it you know like this is who I got it
from that's how I got it and that's the
work I've done with it and as far as the
Clone the legends of hash winning
variety and the Barbara bud it's all the
same shade of gray you know and then the
Candy shishka Berry just won first place
again with the mix of a starburst and um
you know I could only imagine how good
that was but yeah the Shish Berry it's
something old that I'm spotlighting
right now like you know that's why I
always give shout out breeder Steve
shout out great Gardener you know it's
what's shishkaberry [ __ ] let me ask
breeder Steve I went on Facebook time
with him he talked to me like it was you
know one of the coolest combos I've had
with a person in the weed industry or or
the game or the culture whatever you
want to call it in in in a while but
it's just uh it's humbling you know I'm
very very thankful and it's uh it's a
blessing to be around people like that
and have those
Tools H yeah dude well it's important
work you know it's it is really
important work in the sense that it's
only the people who have this Obsession
that care enough to protect and create
these different you know flavor profiles
that are going to end up you know when
they end up in in certain hands they end
up becoming the foundation of this
entire medical cannabis you know like we
don't want swag we want like the best
that we can and it's interesting how it
translates that like the dankest herb
that you just can't put down that you
just want to keep smoking non-stop also
happens to translate to the best
medicine for people that actually don't
really have an interest in like the
maybe the flavor profiles and all these
other things but it's it's an
interesting invisible connection that
this Obsession and this love of cannabis
has this invisible tether to producing
you know these profiles that you know
are great for getting high and I never
uh I never you know that's that's not a
negative I'm like Sam I love getting
high I I would fight for people's rights
to get high there's just like a another
level to it when it's about someone
taking care of their health there's
there's it's always been that way for me
since I met Hillary black uh and she was
doing the BC Compassion Club and it was
like oh okay so this is different right
we over here we've got the hustle and
we're making and selling and flipping
and flopping but over here this is like
we gota we got to have there has to be a
level of philanthropy involved this
can't be the same over here as it is
over here and unfortunately in Canada
right now it's uh they're pretty much
the same yeah
s way in the states too man it started
out you know 215 we all you know you
know before even before 215 it just once
the structure came it just all kind of
it seemed to be a ploy to get to where
we're at but as I said before with the
music analogy it's sort of where the our
industry is at where no one truly owns
anything it's all VCS and a bunch of
people that are investing and those that
are hanging on are so small that it's
hard to
compete with that at that level and then
you know it clouds the water right like
who's who's right in that moment right
so it's and then the
consumer isn't really buying buying with
their with their brain they're buying
with their back pocket because they're
going towards price not who they're
buying it from so well that comes down
to a huge problem and I actually applied
to the dcc's actual oversight board
because everybody say what's wrong with
cannabis and they don't
understand can can I go on a slight diet
tribe for a second and give everybody
why why we're [ __ ] up here in
California the D doesn't know cannabis
they don't use cannabis right so they
don't understand that it's a simple
product right okay let's see all right
so I have a jar here right and I put a
small bud in here that small Bud goes in
this jar this jar is chalk full of
oxygen right what are the three things
that kill cannabis oxygen light and heat
right majority of everything of course
is you know in glass containers so we've
talked about this before but if you used
a simple gas ratio of 80% nitrogen 20%
Argon gas and you pumped it in instead
of leaving this full of oxygen what's
happened is a major shift and let me
walk you back through some history
people before 28
I purchased from small farmers growing
higher small batch cannabis I would take
that cannabis I would hold it for three
weeks where I would have it tested I
would have it actually done with a plate
test and then when those were clean then
we would package it into Gams e and
ounces and maximum I would buy would be
usually three to five kilos per batch
tops Max usually one to two kilos
per that packaged and sold would go out
the door within two weeks maximum Word
of Mouth Etc again before we're we're
all now just 7-Eleven selling the same
product prior I had local Regional
farmers and local products like
afgi constants that people would come to
me for because it was fresh cine
Rich small batch cannabis the problem
that we have now post 2018 we've got
large batch cannabis mid-grade some
high-grade being absolutely uh massacred
from its trimming it's basically
massacred from trimming on down I see as
I travel to large manufacturers they're
putting all the same batch cannabis in
one huge bag sometimes 10 kilos Plus in
a bag okay and they're throwing these
bags around like it's a [ __ ]
football so you've got product being
shaken up not being well taken care of
in non refrigerated environments because
as we know anything above the room
temperature of the grow room it was in
tpes dipin everything is starting to
evaporate right if they're not actually
kept in a safe environment so we're not
refrigerating it keeping it the same way
as a beer or something has where it's
from manufacturing all the way to the
end two we don't have quality product
that's going out quickly it's it's
tonnage sitting on shells in boxes being
eaten with oxygen and that oxygen in
that bottle remember as we've talked
about has church every three months it
chemically Chang es right so it's
actually more CBN and it's degrading
right well sometimes I get my products
that are six months to a year old at my
dispensary and so you're getting stale
product you're getting fully oxygenated
product in glass jars and not
refrigerated so and of course the big of
the issue of course then is 11% humidity
for packaging right to do it properly so
all of these these things are somehow
the conundrum that the you know the the
department of cannabis control cannot
somehow understand but we all do because
one I'm a patient two I was a grower and
I have an understanding as how
production manufacturing and selling
works so where unfortunately why people
are going to their local plug is because
they're getting what they used to get
fresh turpine Rich cannabis you know as
opposed to that stale dun [ __ ] we're
selling in California so that's why if
people are wondering that's kind of a
quick synapsis and the department of
Canabis control doesn't want to force
the manufacturers or Distributors to
necessarily go through these types of
expenses but if they did you see the
quality change everything go up so other
states that are listening we [ __ ] up
you heard how we [ __ ] up do it
differently than how we did it so that
you're better dude you nailed that it's
almost like you're an expert on this
subject that's [ __ ] crazy dude can I
add an anecdote to that aten I think is
uh interesting is I'm not going to name
the grower or the or the the product but
I ran into someone who recently won an
award at an event for some old
flow and it's because he knows how to
store his flow and literally it was past
past doe past COA right but he entered
it he's like dude this is the bomb's
better than what I have he threw it in
there and then like talking about the
next competition he's like yeah I'm
going to throw it in the next one
too so it'll be like a year and a half
old at that point but he's just like
look dude I know how to store flour
properly there's a way to do it there's
right you know and it's like and and you
can easily have shitty flour from three
months ago that looks worse than three
years ago if you do it right you know
that's also true it's all it's all the
supply chain the cold supply chain if
you have a cold supply chain there it is
it's like we're all sell spinach in a
warm [ __ ] container and sending it
across the country and just like oh it's
sitting in the in the in the warehouse
for a couple days it's 105 degrees
Fahrenheit it should be good you open it
up and it's just [ __ ] like liquid
it's like we need a cold supply chain I
tell in Canada it's [ __ ] crazy
because when you when you go to the
store in Canada and it's getting a
little bit better now they have these
little extraction fridges now uh that
they never used to have but what you
would generally see even like up to a
year ago and still today in most of the
shops is you'll see a little fridge and
if you go to the little
fridge it is full of beverages that have
10 milligrams of distillate in it so the
only thing they're keeping cold are 10
milligram distillate shot you know
nanoemulsified Beverages and that's what
they're keeping cold all of the flour
all of the hash everything is just off
gassing like crazy some of the you know
it's in gets hot in the summer man like
30 40° in Saskatchewan and Manitoba this
is like 100 plus Fahrenheit it's just
cooking so yes there would be a cost to
keep their vault cold in those in those
months I think they only are allowed to
display packaging so it's kind of like I
mean you can put kind of buds out but
people realize quick that the way the
Canadian um you know regulatory
framework works is if you take flour out
and you have it on display you have to
destroy said flour can't even give it
away you can't like offer it for free or
at a discount you have to destroy said
flowers so it becomes very expensive for
these shops to be opening up flour just
so people can see it and not even
basically smell it it's a it's a
complete and total nightmare without the
cold chain and with without it you you
will never they are so obsessed with
stabilizing cannabis that they don't
realize that you cannot really stabilize
cannabis the best that you can do is you
can make it very cold and you can can
reduce the you know that vibratory
frequency that's basically off gassing
these volatile organic compounds without
that without that slowing it down and uh
uh Mojave is absolutely correct I had
flour that I grew and
dried well before the fresh frozen days
I threw it in my freezer i c i sucked
the air out of it I threw it in my
freezer it was really not that hard it's
not it really isn't I had it there for
six years Sam six years I opened it up
and people like dude what are you doing
with that I'm like I this is this new
process I'm G to you know make rosin out
of it and this rosin that I made from
this flower and it was actual flower
rosin was like a baby diaper it stunk
from like literally across the room it
was so L well all all you really have to
do
yes he's teasing us he's skunkman Sam's
trolling us
yeah yes he's Frozen see he's talking
the secret is put it in an inert gas
keep it away from light and heat and uh
I mean they do they do it with nuts in
little foil packs right and in your
coffee I mean that was the thing is
originally the the thought was the 80%
nitrogen 20% CO2 but when cannabis
degrades it turns to CO2 so that was why
the suggestion of the Argon on to you
know stabilize the air around it so no
matter how it shifts if it's kept you
know it would there be therefore be as
sh self shelf stable as
possible the other thing with theyed the
reason why they used argon is because
argon is heavier than air so you got to
remember air is 79% nitrogen right so
the difference between just regular
nitrogen 100% nitrogen is the oxygen
that's in there so it's going to take
longer to sweep out a container if
you're just using nitrogen as opposed to
argon argon's heavier than
air that's why that's why in Canada when
we dry suit dive in the cold Pacific
Ocean we use argon gas to inject it into
our dry suits and it keeps us warmer and
so there's another use for it shout out
to Savvy turps for talking about noble
gases about half an hour before we
started talking about them in chat
yeah I mean I use I've used it in uh in
ovens before Mark to uh to keep the
environment in that
oven you know
stely material stay in there in an open
open container yeah um it's I've done
some really interesting work doing that
um I don't know if this is real but like
about 10 years ago someone I know um
maybe less maybe it was about eight
years ago someone claimed to have bought
the rights to the regional nitrogen
packing that everyone was going to have
to buy
into if they did that in cannabis and he
basically took me aside and he's like
you realize that everyone thinks this is
going to be the future but this is a
patented process and the guy who holds
that patent I just made a deal with for
California and he thought he was going
to make millions because the whole
industry was going to go towards the
Nitro packed um cans and and anyway I
don't know if he was full of [ __ ] or not
but it it was interesting to see like
okay this is you know that's the kind of
thought process you have to have in this
business is be like way ahead of the
curve yeah I mean need to be they're
already doing it with potato chips right
because when you fry potato chips and
unsaturated oils they will degrade so
the potato chip companies when they
package potato chips you're blowing uh
nitrogen in there I don't think it's
argon I think it's nitrogen so it's
coffee right
excuse me they're doing with coffee is
they they before they do with all your
coffee and that's why it's open and you
feel that rush in it's because there
along the process uh of the Machinery
there's a puff station right before the
close station and it literally is the
puff then seals in its clothes and it
goes and that is keeping the oxygen out
of your coffee so your coffee doesn't
degrade if you weren't
aware I don't drink coffee but
that I
know yeah yeah very good very good
welcome uh gml just popped into the room
who you in a desert or something dude
yeah
morning morning
morning I don't drink coffee
either I've never drank coffee my wife I
both don't drink coffee people would
stay at our house and be like Hey
where's your coffee and we'd be like
coffee like you can twist up a joint if
you want and they just be like you could
see the conern in their face bro like
people really there's something about
suppressing a denone like just like not
having that feeling in your mind I don't
get it I don't know it but I certainly
know there are a lot of people out there
that uh Beyond love it it it was pushed
on me when I was in like grade three and
that's I just didn't like the taste and
I still don't to this day damn you got
you got hit up with the coffee dealers
in grade three well sneaking out I
remember sneaking out of the house uh
with my cousin and grade three going
down to Commercial Drive and playing
Street Fighter 2 and then at the Italian
coffee shop at the Hasty Market and uh
yeah just remember them offering me
coffee my wife cannot get up without
coffee wow crazy so she's got the coffee
maker in the bed with her
or when you but if you uh if you freeze
uh they make they sell these online
freeze a there's like a metal ball you
can freeze in the freezer or or even do
it with a round I Ice Cube if you make
espresso and have it pour over top of
the the cold fre Frozen ice ice cube or
a frozen piece of metal the coffee will
have a much a much different taste to it
because it's retaining more of the the
the chemical compounds that are bringing
that that aric property to life is that
what you do with that Mojave these are
these are yeah these are actually just
well they're not they're for anything
they're they're just steel um yeah
Frozen you can freeze them and put them
in anything in drinks whatever so
they're they're kind of cool like if you
ever need a bunch of ice cubes but you
don't want a bunch of water after they
lose their coldness um you get a bunch
of just throw them in your cooler throw
them and whatever they're fun probably
not the best idea to replace your ice in
the hash making process with those I'm
guessing a lot of
contamination yeah and pretty pretty
aggressive as well hey one thing always
wondered I wanted opinion on this
especially from you Dr Mark um why don't
good for those of us who chew on ice
right hey why don't people use oxygen
absorbers in cannabis
packaging well um if you have oxidation
happening and
oxidation
is usually how tpes are going to degrade
um you need oxygen so it's just a um
it's a hydrogen acceptor right so when
when um if you look at uh if you've ever
heated heated up THC disate and you see
white smoke coming off that white smoke
is actually
water uh that's being formed from the
degradation of THC which is turning into
CBN and as THC turns into CBN it gives
up two molecules of hydrogen and so
those two molecules of hydrogen
find the oxygen that's in the air and
make water right
H2O so um so the white smoke that you
see is actually steam it's actually
water so so yeah so oxygen is just uh
well it oxidizes but it gets reduced so
whenever something is oxidized
something's reduced so in that case the
molecular oxygen is being reduced to
water but that means something was
oxidized in order for that hydrogen to
be available in the case of THC going to
CBN you're oxidizing THC to CBN because
it's losing those hydrogens and reducing
molecular oxygen from
Air yeah so you want to try to avoid air
so is that the question you want to try
to avoid oxygen no what my my question
is like you see like in in most food
products there's there's two packets one
or two or both and it's usually silica
or an oxygen absorber and the silica is
for humidity and the oxygen absorbers
specifically to combat oxidization and
in cannabis like we adopted the whole
Bova thing and the whole idea of like
keeping a constant humidity in a
packaged product but like other food
products they know the big culprit for a
lot of things is oxygen so I'm just
wondering if there's a if there's a
reason why oxygen absorbers haven't been
adopted by cannabis or is it just that
we haven't thought of it or is there an
actual possible issue that might arise
yeah well we we were we were talking
about how the sour diesel bronzes out
right and there's kind of like a a
Browning that you know certain you know
strains will will actually undergo
during curing which is actually a
controlled
oxidation right you're actually when
during Cur
and and certainly like I I don't know I
mean again it seems as though some of
the more uh oxidized Tarpin could
actually be forming in that curing
process which is going to change the
overall
Essence but I think in general I mean
just like in food like if you think
about like just ground beef for example
uh when that oxidizes right it turns the
beef brown right so if they can grab a
couple more
days of shelf life and keep that ground
beef red that's a big savings for them
you know I mean they just they could
just get a few more days of shelf life
because you're just absorbing the oxygen
and what's happening is that the thing
that's making well ground beef if you
want to talk about that for a second is
the blood and that's the Heen that's in
the blood which is the complex with iron
and so when oxygen in filtrates that it
changes the pigments color to Brown so
that's why aged ground beef will look
more brownish than it does red but um
but it would be like that for any
bloodborne product so that's why I would
imagine like in meat packaging for
example you would have things that would
absorb oxygen but like even in dairy
products and other things where um well
cheese for example you'd probably want
to keep um cheese in the air environment
or else it's going to start or continue
to degrade right cheese is already
degraded in a way so yeah I don't know
if that if that's what you're asking
yeah now it's just kind of it's just
kind of something I wonder about if if
there's a a a reason why certain
products are so Trend towards oxygen
versus humidity anyway guys I got I got
to bounce out for a little bit but I'm
hope to see you in a little in maybe 45
or 50 I'll be back if you guys are still
so Mark you know that's I'll see you
soon mve um question I I wanted to jump
into the the Browning aspect I have some
gel that was harvested and that's
actually it's very similar it Browns out
it doesn't look like good herb but when
you smoke it it's fantastic it's like
unbelievable yeah right and so it loses
the emerald color I mean like it just
looks like just some normal like I
should go grab it it just looks it's
good or it's like when you open the bag
you're like hit with this overwhelming
skunk gas Super Skunk is that pungent
but when you look at it you'd be like
this looks like some mediocre herb like
to be real and but when you smoke it
it's super flavorful and super delicious
all the way down to the last hit like if
you rolled a big Jo joint of it you
wouldn't you you could taste it
literally all the all the way down how
many day C is something like that I
think that's on that's a good that batch
I think is a three- week here at this
point see even that isn't that kind of
pushing it though you need something
more like about two months really it's
still going like it's it's I'm just
saying like where it's at right now like
yeah it's like it's at I think it's
almost at four weeks now but
it's it's yeah it'll it'll keep going
you know but it just it's interesting
because it's it's such dank herb but it
doesn't like in terms of contemporary
herb you wouldn't consider this you
would look at it and be like I'm not
going to smoke it because dude it makes
me want to see it it makes me think that
when we talking about herb yeah yeah
when we're talking about herb especially
if we're growing it I'd love to share
people's grows or any hash making you
know yeah exactly dude show show the
flowers dude like we want to see the
flowers up close I was going to chirp in
with this I actually keep this is my
head stash jar of GMO I call it which is
GMO by gas mask and I got this at a
coffee shop so this is a vac sealed jar
that has like an analog little hand
action
back so it goes like this you can hear
it kind of a thing it's got a vac
release and you just twist turn and it
keeps the nuggies good for quite a while
I kind of go to the fridge with it even
for longer hold but uh yeah and I've
noticed the gas Types on me in the past
especially grown Sun grown whether e
gaster West that they seem to oxidate
really quickly like you got like a twoe
window seems to be a little bit more of
a hold for the you know color from like
a delicate indoor or whatnot holding
it interesting I like the sound of that
everyone's jar should sound like that
when you when you show up a session and
you open a jar and it does that people
are like the [ __ ] that [ __ ]
over there got like I want to go check
that out I would think like deli style
for Med shops Main still medical here
and the recck so like these if you're
going deli style you know and you're in
and out of the jar you just give it the
twist turn not trying to sell the
company or anything I won't tell who
makes it but like devices like this to
keep the air out for head stash at least
oh I think it's okay to tell who makes
it I mean if people want to look for it
and check it out we're not
getting not a sponsor yeah it's called
fellow and it's just at the local coffee
shop you know to keep your highend
coffee beans good so this is what
this is what the Cannabis world has been
doing since the beginning of time we
just adopt cool things from other
Industries they pushed us out for so
long it was like there's other things in
the world that may not be marketed as a
cannabis product but man it works so
well I mean I'll tell you the first time
I made hash it was with a $20 cake mixer
from Walmart like just [ __ ] that hash
was killer it's kind of why you know I
obviously I'm a part of Whistler
Technologies that's I'm a partner in
that company uh and you know all these
other guys like uh low temp and hashte
and SoMo filtration and Delta
separations there's all these different
companies doing it and it's great it's
commercial there's Colin with his I just
think you could still make great house
with a cake mixer that's the jel let me
this like Diesel doesn't it's not the
bag appeal girl that everyone believes
it to be it never was but man in terms
of the flavor and to be real man it's a
great breeding it's good breeding stock
because there's just so much to to take
from it and improve show again I I had
Bri Brian was pinned my apologies these
are small because this is all that's
kind of dry right now but um it just
doesn't look like weed that you'd be
like yeah I'm gonna like I want a whole
lot this right but when you when you
roll it up and you put it to your lips
you're like this is all I want like what
is this flavor profile and it's just
you know like here's some here's some
diesel here same thing
like Diesel's a fantastic varial but you
gotta grow it really well hey Colin
what's the story with the diesel is that
more like a mass Super Skunk sided yeah
so it's a mass Super Skunk I think
chmd yeah this is diesel this diesel is
not really good
um so and then
here got some OG over here too some
Trinity um this is all really nice but
this is yeah I mean all this stuff look
needs to cure for like Mark said for a
lot longer for smoking grade material
but
um the Diesel's looking
good this is
sour um dude we should be having like
the USB microscope set up screen sharing
pop that thing under the microscope show
this is really this stuff is better
without
curing what's that
Sam we missed that Sam can you repeat it
yeah something about cannabis is better
without curing does anybody think that
cannabis is better without curing I know
my haze I used to cure it for three
months yeah I mean I feel very strongly
about Hayes in particular that letting
those monot Turpin like release whatever
that profile is and just letting that
Underside bouquet pop up that's where
you got that perfumey just
incredible Haze flavors I I I never
thought that uncured weed was better
than cured weed although I will say that
it's kind of what's happening with hash
now both in the BHO realm and in the
water hash realm it's all about slapping
it while it's fresh frozen and making
sure you run it really cold and make
sure once you've run it that that goes
into a freeze dryer and you keep your
temperatures down as much as possible in
the sublimation process and then you SE
it right away to make sure there's no
ice particles in there but get it right
into a freezer to you know just stop
that that off gas of any kind so it's um
I remember years ago uh we were up at
Hank's apartment in the oh gosh I think
it was in the lza plane he had an
apartment above the uh his uh what was
it the Bulldog his Cafe do you remember
that apartment Sam you've probably been
there many times we were up there and I
was with Tony from sagam Mara seeds and
I had made some dry SI with sweet skunk
for the great Gardener well I had
cleaned it he had made it and it was old
he had he had it sitting for a long time
he had the plants sitting for a long
time then he then he sifted them and
that sat for a while and it was just
super well cured hash and then I cleaned
it to
99.9% heads and I gave uh Tony a rip of
that and I'll never forget him just
leaning back on the couch and just
exhaling it and being like Oh my God
he's like he's like I think if the
younger generation could smoke hash like
this they they wouldn't go back to
that cuz it was just so smooth you'd let
out a huge rip of this hash and it was
sweet skunk so it was also already a
very gentle soft and just like welcoming
profile you know in the in the haze
lineage but certainly not as rank or
dank but still just so [ __ ] enjoyable
and so I I feel you yet on the flip side
I love a good rip is some fresh frozen
you know that's that has been preserved
all the way and that makes me cough and
makes my eyes almost almost pop out so
who's to say it's cannabis just love
what you
love yeah there's a lot of different
levels to it but yeah I think back to
the genetics thing I wanted to kind of
touch on some of the lines that um you
know Masonic that you might be working
on that you're stoked on now since
you've worked Wilson through the lines
that you have worked what are you seeing
right now that you're like yo this is
really unique
all right so so I was doing a single
male donor pollinations for uh a while
with Wilson like it to the point where
that's what I was identified as like oh
you only do Wilson Oh you only make hash
trins it's it's like no like I cross
Wilson to everything so I make
everything you know I don't
necessarily only grow one type of strain
like I'm very open-minded about looking
under every Rock so that's one thing
that you know I'm always doing is
looking for trying to see what
everything is putting a smell to every
name out there like you guys are saying
sweet skunk you guys are saying all
these varieties like super Mass the the
jel I was looking at my drawer while
you're saying jel because I have like a
a rose flow jel variety that I visited
five years ago seeds I made five years
ago where my nose
isn't in like as as it was five years
ago where now I could like kind of spot
things and label it quicker whereas 5
years ago I'm still learning [ __ ] you
know so I'm like oh crap let me dig
through this gel Rose flow see if I find
anything significant but all that to say
is like what I'm working on uh so I did
the single male donor Wilson
pollinations for like 16 17 18 19 20 21
is finally when I stopped doing single M
donor pollinations with the Wilson I put
it on the back burner and then that year
something possessed me to just let
everything just pollinate each other
like every Single Seed stock that I had
in that seed from That season from all
these dope breeders honey banana hybrids
Skittle hybrids B gear the list goes on
and on you know land race variety
straight from Thailand straight from
India I just let it all rock you know
[ __ ] it I call it natural selection and
that's what I did for 21 22 and then
last year so for the past three years
I've been doing these open pollinations
with different Ms from different seed
stock it's totally random like that's
literally what it is
and so I made seeds for 3 years and I
was happy with all that progyny like I
would pop it myself I'd be like dope
like Mom's in there and even if it was
like a mom that wasn't something that I
like subjectively The Offspring from it
from that natural selection would be
like oh like that's likable you know so
it was like cool we're on to something
but a lot of people weren't with it the
ones that were with it God bless you I
still love it they they they kept me
through that three year the past three
years you know 22 23 two years but kind
of like 21 is 22 23 for like two years
that I've had it finally 24 comes along
I'm like cool let's do something else
now so I kind of just went with the
algorithm of what everyone's kind of
like looking at right now and uh
Starburst I was like [ __ ] it let's rock
this Starburst Everyone likes Starburst
right now I like Starburst right now um
it's not something you can easily go
grab no one's going to give me the
starburst cut I don't like asking for
stuff it's never ended up on my desk but
Higher Ground sold Starburst f one seat
stock and F2 seat stock so I dedicated
um some indoor runtime to some Starburst
varieties and I hunted one pack of f1s
and two packs of f2s uh kept all the
males kept all the females made my
selections now I'm making uh now I made
and I'm making more f3s with them so
right now I'm on a starburst war path as
well as everything else like nothing is
left unlooked like if a new breeder
comes out with a pack I'm the first in
line to grab it just cuz I I it's like
my job to always have my like you know
just just be privy that way when I'm
talking I know what the hell I'm talking
about or I could have something to say
on it and you know I'm not like oh I
Won't Grow that dude's gear like no if
someone's making some noise and you know
let me let me see what you're looking at
you know and I'm I'm always I'm always
wondering what's what so dude can you
can you can you walk us through the
garden right now can you give us a
little little walk I think I can I think
this is so this is one of my two G Mar
love it it's it's just it brings me back
to being like when I was like 23 all
right so this is one of two gardens this
I call the Discovery Garden because I
don't do production here I don't do
light depths here you know I literally
just pop seeds and let everything Rock
here so this is the this is the
Discovery Garden so for starters massive
plant as soon as I step
outside seeds everywhere all brand new
seeds these are all brand new seed
starts all new smells this was a a
watermelon patch that I just untilled
and threw back in the dirt there those
are some huge plants right
there it's just everywhere it's like a
jungle out here you know you go through
here some more plants dude imagine this
[ __ ] guy's your neighbor you're just
like what's this guy all about you find
his [ __ ] Instagram account you're
like damn I just love it it's just
everywhere look I even like throw down
trays it's like just grow some weed man
who gives a [ __ ] you know you have to
literally go through this tunnel to get
through the other
side and then there's more weed over
here and then there's more weed look
those are the power
lines it's they're growing in a kitty
pool and there's more weed down here
there's more look these I've been
throwing plants in there just 10 times
over just throw a plant in there let it
grow you go over here there's more more
weed this is the you know just kind of
using what I got you know I don't have a
farm so this plant I didn't support it
so it kind of just toppled over I'm just
kind of just letting it Rock [ __ ] it
I'll be all right I'll get some hash off
with it we'll get like three ounces 4
ounces of hash off of that bad boy just
chilling but this is my Discovery Garden
this is
it it's as big as the house this is
inspirational you know what this is
relatable this is uh you know it's you
don't like uh grow some weed like you
said you know grow some weed find some
flavors you don't need a multi-million
dollar facility are you planting are you
pollinating with multiple males on the
same female so here uh am I multia with
multiple Ms from the same seed stock
yes I think yes so like when I'm doing
my natural selection open pollinations
to make that seed stock it is different
mels from that same seed stock I think
that's what you
asked cool did you say mels or males Sam
were you asking if he was hitting
multiple different males pollen to one
female can't hit males so I figured you
know you you you do it's the other way
around you know no the reason I'm asking
that is
because oh my God why does his mic keep
doing that no I'm I'm asking if he's
using multiple different varieties of
males on the same female that that's
what I thought you so so more than
likely that is what's going to happen
right unless like I I can't tell right
because it's it's happening by itself if
there's five different males with one
female growing with it I guess it's like
a cat you know cats can have different
dads when they have their their babies
right so I'm guessing it's more so that
than oh you know just one of them hit it
you know because there's there's
different there's no telling you know
you could pop the progyny and wonder
what might have hit it but all in all I
just take it for like everything it
could be anything you know if there's
five males any of those males could have
hit
it and this is just to get it like as
diverse as possible this is just to make
seeds just making seeds and and and you
can label it whatever you want after
yeah to make it diverse as possible it
just so happens that dude it's chaos
breeding I [ __ ] love it bro it's it's
one of like one year two years of like
the next 80 years of breeding that I
have that I just kind of visited and it
worked it won first place Legends for
Christ's sake the Candy shishka Berry
was a Natural Selections lineage you
know so it's like it's not that that's
like to prove that it's good but it's
like well it's pretty good proof that
it's good dude a lot of things came from
stuff that's like oh we don't know what
it
is you know okay what Skittles nobody
could tell you they could tell you all
their lore what's you know a bunch of
strains so that's kind of like the Credo
behind that is like oh we're just making
seeds uh as far as receiving end is
concerned cool I got half the story
locked in as far as the donor concerned
I'll just yeah when I grow these seeds
from when I know like oh if I see
something that has Haze in it tie I
could smell it almost immediately
shishka Berry because there's shishka
Berry candy Shish Berry mels out there
it's like oh [ __ ] I know it hit it
almost immediately and that's a little
selfish but I'm making seeds very
transparently people ask me Yo Ma what
were the mels out there I could explain
a bunch of times but it's all like dude
it's random even if I tell you you're
not going to be able to know because
you're you're going to learn down the
process and if you do know it's cuz
you're a discerner you'd probably tell
me before I tell you you
know I smell Skittles I smell pepper oh
[ __ ] probably Tom Hill hay F3 hit it you
know I had a white Taho skunk that
probably hit it and it's just like but
all that yeah it matters but that's my
thing was like that this this year this
Natural Selections Reas pollination
didn't the reason I'm asking
the the reason I'm
asking yes the reason you're
asking but the reason I'm asking is
because I often use a mail uh a single
male and I hit it towards hundreds of
differ of females but I know what the
male is
yeah that's what I did the previous five
years with my Wilson M and then I
decided to do as I'm doing the Natural
Selections pollination I'm doing other
single M donor pollinations at different
spots just to like do my vision if it
was up to me in a perfect world I do a
whole lot of everything you know oh look
just cross these together and cross but
this is my way of like kind of in
essence doing all that at once per se
you know just what what I have all at
once and still work sing Le male donor
pollinations on the side like I'm doing
other pollinations like I'm doing a
freak Show pollination right now as we
speak as I'm doing a starburst
pollination as I'm doing this chaotic
breeding as some might deem you
know it's all being done at the same
time there's not just one thing that I
do I do it all you know yeah well the
bottom line is like you said cultivar is
winning legends uh you talk about if
it's if there's if it's making noise
you've been making a ton of noise uh for
for some years now people love what
you're doing people love the Wilson
you've been able to fall into it with
the right you know meeting Bloom early
on and getting you know those papayas
that's incredible I just think it's a
great way to do it in the sense of just
using your nose and and following you
know twocan Sam Style just follow your
nose yeah very much so that's it's very
you know that chicken's bigger that
chicken's bigger let's put them together
let's make a big chicken like it's it's
and then
the scientists and the people that are
good with all the jargon they could back
me up and be like oh this is why he did
it and I'll be like yeah yeah yeah that
is why I did it and then I'll resew that
[ __ ] easy peasy you know but that that's
kind of the game for me like I'm I'm the
guy in the garden just planning
thousands of plants and taking care of
them myself with the little space that
I've have but with the passion that you
know is like you know trumps everything
that I do I just love this [ __ ] I want
to smoke you know I hate to be like
weird about it but like I like to smoke
half all day and just have hash around
me and you know like as long as that
sustained the quality of my life is
better and you know that's what I
revolved my life around to this day and
it's I so I just have to be as good as I
can with it lot of nodding heads lot of
nodding heads while you said that at
least three at least three that I that I
saw hey welcome to Selena Selena snuck
in looks like you're sitting in a nice
little Garden or at least a photo of a
garden I'm in the most beautiful garden
right now so this is my friend Garden
you know Drake um he has a really
interesting growing methodology it's the
jadam um I'm sure you guys are familiar
with it but I'm gonna show you guys
really quick where I'm sitting just to
give you a quick
glance pretty rad I'm like
literally amongst beautiful garden if I
look up like these canopies I want to
say it's about 12 feet tall
now like it's absolutely gorgeous these
plants are so vigorous and healthy is
that in Vernon
yeah damn yeah so this is the patient
growth
great just gorgeous so I really wanted
to show it to you guys today because uh
I really think it goes along well with
what you've been talking about
earlier yeah absolutely nice to see you
too yeah it's good to see you guys this
conversation has been wild so thank you
for having me absolutely I can already
tell after today that we're going to
have some some of of mesa's seeds
growing in our Gardens in the near
future talking about all those flavors
got me [ __ ]
drooling oh my gosh yeah I can contest
like I've I've
grown a lot of your work a lot
everything you've sent and everything
we've
bought um has
produced something worth running in
terms of the hash realm so it's and it's
rare to see that
um Thug Pug's another one you're RAR
just like all of his work seems to just
do well um he's another one that's good
obviously Fletcher archive he's got a
good a good knack for it but it's um but
yeah man it's it's cool and it's you
gave me the the Natural Selections I ran
like where
rs1 um I think you gave me a
GMO you gave me a bunch I have to go
back on the list but there's a bunch of
the I remember the rs1 vividly nice that
was like very
good that that came out very
good um so yeah even like the Willie
Nelson not Wilsons that you gave us were
like oddly good how long ago did you get
those yeah a couple years ago I think
yeah those are older I made those old
2018 2019 yeah and those like when I
made those trains like I'm just popping
stuff like I don't know what Willie
Nelson is I don't know nl5 I'm 32 from
South Central we didn't grow up on Hay
we grew up on OG you know so it's like
I'm just growing stuff even though
everyone's like at the time 2018 no one
was like getting props for growing hay
unless you were in The In Crowd with
like the mean jeans and like but like as
far as like status quo hash heads
they're like they disregard almost
everything even nowadays everybody only
wants like the the everyone agrees on a
certain turban profile as far as like
the mass people right and at the time
I'm just kind of doing left field stuff
doing stuff that I'm like you know what
[ __ ] it and maybe it's all I had at the
time too it's like let's rock this let's
rock this uh someone had gifted me those
packs and he was held to a high regard
and I was like cool people like him uh I
like him he's a nice guy let me throw
these in the ground and and it just kind
of happened like that like it was never
like yo we're on a chase we need to grab
that one because we're going to be
rolling in D when we do that one you
know it's always been like everything
natural throw it in the ground and
Willie Nelson nl5 ended up becoming like
one of the strains I threw on the back
burner because at the time it smelt uh
nothing like candy nothing gas nothing
sour it was like a Evergreen floral hazy
Thai type Turk and I was just like
whatever throw it on the back burner
we're going to have I had like a one
gallon bag full of these seeds so we
would just give them away for free a lot
of the times we'll sell them for 10
bucks and it ended up becoming one of
the varieties that a lot of people like
because it ended up being a better
grower than most of the varieties
because of the the lineage that it had
in it and I just learned along the way
that like everybody likes everything I
might like what I like so I ended up
becoming like a record store when it
came to my seed varieties it's like yeah
I like Skittles and candy and gas and
sour and that's all I'm going to buy
when I'm making my purchases but it
would be a disservice and it would suck
for anything else not to exist like oh
train wreck just one day doesn't exist
so I I have all those offers as well I
make sure to lock in and make hybrids
whether it be with a single mail donor
pollination or Natural Selections as far
as receivers are concern and it's kind
of like it's like a record store like oh
I I literally tell people what do you
like oh I like candy oh you'd love these
you know and it's and you know
everything's great for what it is
everything is and Everyone likes what
they like you know Shish Berry happens
to be a safe one for a lot of people to
like at the moment I was actually
surprised to see you come back around to
be honest with all the things in the
world that have come you know
but then again knowing what I know of it
maybe it been here all along we didn't
know right it's kind of like papaya G if
nobody would have ever spotted papaya I
think like the way Harry did it would
have just PC brains right somebody else
would have did it yeah he like so the
way it happened with him is some dude
smoked them out with Papaya some shatter
and he's like yo what is this and the
dude's like here's the CL
and then he's like making
FS right like it's it's kind of like and
that's when it gets in more people's
hands because it's harder to get the
actual clone into people's hands whereas
the seed stock it's like you could send
it to Iran from here you know good luck
sending the [ __ ] clone you know we've
seen crazy things with s1s too man like
we've been running um S1 sours that
we've made just like ourselves and we're
seeing like ridiculous plants that are
very impressive that I didn't believe
could exist so it's just you got to hunt
large populations of it to to Sam's
Point I'm I'm having some technical
difficulties right now guys it seems
like the stream stopped um I tried to
get it going again it says the custom
live stream is going and we're still
recording but I don't see it on YouTube
I don't see the stream I can't find the
chat I can't find everyone so I just
don't want to to yeah I don't want it
yeah it shows that it's it's ended for
some reason
um yeah and I can't find the chat so I
can easily just start this over real
quick and I'll just you know what I'm
going to do I'm going to do the way I
usually do it I'm G to stop the live
stream and then I'm going to live stream
onto YouTube which will create a whole
new YouTube and then we can just
continue the conversation from here and
if I have to splice them together that
that's not a big deal either but uh yeah
I don't want to miss the conversation so
thanks for your guys' patience
what are you in grand grand square there
uh yeah everyone just checking [ __ ]
out M this is blueberry banana this
stuff is ridiculous this is really
really nice we washed this um in
April
this I grew this right here I'm sorry I
got excited when we're talking about our
hat oh hell
yeah I grew this and I washed it uh in
my backyard in Compton and I still doing
so I noticed you're doing some air dry
stuff which I love to see because it's
honestly it's where I think all of this
on at least on this panel here started
so this is all air dry Fatso that I
did I have air dry heads in the freezer
and this is uh this was freeze dry
because I don't get me wrong I love my
air dry technique but I do air dry
because of lack of freeze dryer you know
so we just kind of working our way up
the ladder but we are like good at air
drying as far as what we know we learned
from Pua I think Pua works for Nelson
and Company I think you were showing off
a jar earlier but but yeah that's who
taught me how to air dry was Pua and
he's a really dope hash maker but either
he is he is a dope hash maker I met him
in Barcelona years ago he's a good good
kid man shout out I always say like if
you can master air drying um everything
else is easy right um because you
understand the inherent needs of that
material on a level that you can't learn
the other way around and I wouldn't
learn it any other way like I I like if
if someone gave me the freeze dryer I'd
be like let's learn how to air dry first
cuz that's just I'm like work from the
bottom on the way up and it's like
reverse engineering it like you just
kind of know every piece of the engine
to an extent right well it makes you
think about where Sam's mind was all
those years ago when he was like well
I'm just going to cure my herbs so good
that when I go to sift
it it's like the best of all the worlds
right which is like very very difficult
to do that it's it's with the capital
V yeah you know starts with to grow all
day like U you know that's what I found
it's just like just grow the best flower
you'll have the best hash you know and
that's usually environmental you know in
a lot of cases you know cuz you could
have like the genetics subjectively you
could like care less for it but you know
the clean resin at the end that's from
my my personal uh experience you know
I've been like oh man I could have you
know prevented more dust from kicking up
in the plants and that would have been
the the literal 50% you know better like
it would have just been that much better
I think but um that that's how I look at
it for sure but it start you're right
like it starts with those the right
genetics and genetics nowadays a lot of
stuff's great you'll get your 1%
everything washes you're just not going
to get what you want back on some of
them you know like I washed the 500 gr
of black lime reserve and we got like a
grand back you know it's like it's that
type of thing but yeah still happens
today even with all the information we
have out there and everybody talking to
each other but that's where clones I
think or lines that are known such as
your you know your mail lines that you
you created um that turned into the the
lines that you work um it's you know
like skunk one Sam I'm sure you selected
and leans in leaned into that for
reasons that were most likely towards
the end of you know things you wanted to
make and profiles that you were looking
for
um yeah the blr Wilson does dump as
opposed to the blr mom itself and it's
just that's that's kind of the that's
your answer right there it's like it's
genetics you know but but everything
washes is just blr Wilson dumps about
four five as opposed to blr by itself
where it only does one and blr Wilson
does still carry on that lime uh tinge
not as explosive as mom where it's more
of a Sharp burn your eyes lime but the
Wilson gives it like a cream back in but
it's like a lime cream but either way
like you know you got to kind of work it
kind of kind of work it only Haze thing
that I've seen told me the the black
lime to watch out for Herms if I ran
seeds of it is that I ran what you saw
seeds no no Herms no Herms Herms that's
great no Herms that's cool I see Herms
in in uh in in land race varieties more
than anything I see Herms in my
Greenhouse when I'm growing it in the
Summer with the with the doors closed uh
I don't really see Herms when like I
live in Compton California it never gets
below 40 here it never gives it gets
above like 105 you know it's like it's
always within that frame and it's like
very forgiving for the plants so when I
grow I've only noticed Herms when I'm
growing plants in places where they
shouldn't be growing like in the shade
where they're like getting confused with
the sun in the shade or in a in a
greenhouse where the temperature is
fluctuating a little bit more than
they're used to and and that's when I
notice Herms uh and I also notice Herms
in a lot of like feral land race
varieties like I've grown some stuff
that was sent to me from sapon I've
grown some stuff from that was sent to
me from India I've grown some stuff from
uh Thailand that was sent directly from
Thailand and I had to be a little bit
more
careful
uh you know growing those as opposed to
you know just anything else but the blrs
no I I literally paid pop dollar for
those seeds in the charity auction and I
and I allocated some F1 seed stock and I
also bought the cut that skunk Tech and
mean jeene were selling uh collectively
that they were doing on a on an
Instagram sale about four years ago and
I still have both of my uh selections
and theirs in my living Library as as
well as seat stock for sure skunk Tech
has some really good stuff um that he
had sent to the states that I received
and then eventually sent to him um um I
believe they are from
chamira of Old Stock that he just popped
on um I saw some posts of those so there
should be I think he should be probably
releasing some of those too the trir
stuff was always really good and Sam
didn't you work with chamir
is is that
true Sam mentored
Chimera he's known yeah he's known
Ryan for a very long time 25 plus years
I would guess at this point in
time hey welcome to uh Wade laughter who
popped in as well we had a little bit of
we didn't breathe that much together
what we actually did was uh we worked
together primarily supplying seeds to uh
to to the ne to Canada we we sold to all
the big dispensaries licensed
dispensaries
that's true they definitely had that
figured out before most there was a
window there those guys sold a swack of
seeds into Canada for
sure oh I can hear it in the background
there I can hear Sam
talking echoing on the YouTube that
restarted it's funny so how how are you
doing today Wade
you're muted oh there you go you're not
muted
sorry uh not so great um the
chemotherapy has been uh harder road to
hoe than I had hoped it would
be
um but I
uh yeah decided to dve myself out of bed
and uh see what was happening in hash
church because this is one of my deepest
gloves for conc of this plant and what
she can do for us I
uh yeah that's that's all I have to
report um I am in investing significant
quantities of CBG and CDN based on from
science I saw a couple of weeks ago um
hoping to see some results from that um
but yeah most mostly mostly doing
okay well we're glad to have you we're
glad GL to have you man uh in in any way
shape or form we're just glad to have
you here thank you Mich it's real sweet
for me I've also uh broken my clavicle
here in the last couple of days so I'm
uh dealing with a broken bone certainly
not anything compared but uh boy it
hurts Yeah I broke I broke the cladal on
this side opening a pill bottle a couple
of years ago oh my that that's what that
was that broke I remember
that well I flew off a skateboard going
mock speed and landed on my shoulder at
the Whistler skate park uh so it was uh
kind of like getting hit with a bat it
was it was no
buyo I'm still trying to figure out this
technical difficulty we had we lost
about 175 live viewers we had over we
had 368 people watching live and we're
back to about 150 3 so thank you guys
for being the hardcores that came back
and hopefully we'll the rest of people
will realize that we're back on tune I
you know in 10 years of doing hash
Church it hasn't just shut off on
YouTube many times so that's maybe like
the second or third time that's ever
happened so apologies for the technical
difficulties I did do it differently
today and I'll probably just stick to
doing it the same from now on because uh
that was stressing me out I feel like a
pro after 10 years because I was having
a massive anxiety attack wondering where
the stream went but I didn't want to
interrupt so thank you guys for your
patience maybe it's time to smoke some
help with that Mark I'm curious have you
tried any suppositories for your
pain me yeah no I've been just eating
gummies they've been pretty good I've uh
you know just been CH chomping on on the
White Rabbit gummies the the the
sugar-free uh brown rice syrup sweetened
vegan little gummies they're just 10
milligrams of pop but I you know I'll
eat like maybe five of them throughout
the day and uh it's been pretty good I
haven't had to take like Tylenols or
anything like that although I think it
was Thomas talking about suppositories
last week in regards to how much it
helped his uh his relative there with
the stage four liver cancer is that
correct
Thomas yes yes he um he was doing
actually six weeks of a hyperbaric
chamber um just like uh basic basically
compressed oxygen I guess and um or I
don't know like going under pre oxygen
under pressure and yeah he's been just
taking like a a suppository dose every
single day because he has no tolerance
at all and he had all different types of
tumors all over his liver and literally
um about six of them are gone and he's
down to two and in the last three months
they haven't grown at all it's pretty
mind-blowing so we've all been just like
um like even the doctors are just like
holy [ __ ] just keep on doing what you're
doing and he's kind of taking like a
high dose of vitamin C and then just uh
yeah suppository dose every single or
twice a day now we're just trying to
load them up as much as possible what
are the doses he on for
suppositories um I just was making rosin
and um making it as like putting just a
little bit of coconut oil like I don't
even know if he actually even needed any
coconut oil but um like I had just been
making pure rosin and just maybe about a
10% ratio of coconut oil and then
putting it in gel caps and he's been
taking a couple of those a
day so I don't I'm curious I'm Cur if I
had to guess it's probably like at least
600 milligrams I would imagine or five
500 from each one I I just I haven't had
it actually lab tested it but I'm I'm
using like a good like it was made from
flour too for the most part but it's
decent flour I know I know one thing if
I made if I wanted uh Edibles I would
never get Thomas to make them for me
holy [ __ ] [ __ ] this guy eats 2,000
milligrams at a time no no no that's
duration y I don't eat 2,000
milligrams what what cultivar are you
using for the rosin for these
depositories just I'm curious from a
patient perspective uh it was actually
it's been a combination of three it was
like this death Bubba strain that I've
had for years and then the it was Mac
Daddy and a pink Kush was just what I
happened to have been growing so I just
just been um from that one crop and I
just made like a bunch of oil from them
but we've um get running really really
low I you know I was thinking about like
do I even need to mix coconut oil into
it uh if someone's taking it suppository
I'm not even sure so I've about to make
a whole bunch more for him though it's
like really uh well he was given like
months to live basically at some point
like year and a half ago and um yeah
it's like it's getting better so it's
pretty
mind-blowing and like how's this
Constitution is he getting his energy
back is he like how definitely
definitely he's like I I just saw him
two days ago and he like looked so good
like I was surprised on how well he
looked compared to like six months ago
like where he was always sleeping like
um usually people when they have it they
get really really tired and yeah he's
just doing really like he obviously
still is a little bit tired and you know
he he's completely cut out any type of
sugar in his diet too and I'm just
trying to eat as healthy as possible
and um
yeah that's so exciting thanks for doing
that for him oh yeah it's my pleasure um
it's exciting to see like I said uh I
you know I was when he was doing the
hyperbaric chamber like it wasn't taking
it out like the same way that the
Cannabis has been anyways but I think
that's anybody's best bet like I we lost
somebody else in my family from it and I
got them a bunch of Ro and or RSO and
they were afraid to take it and it's
like cuz you know they're afraid of
getting high and it's just like no one
has an excuse not to take it suppository
why not use as many weapons as you
possibly can if you get into this type
of situation it's what I recommend to
everybody and just push it on your
family member just make them try
it well it's like and obviously they
play well together right like the V is
it vitamin C like IV Therapy that
they're doing as well uh I'm not sure
about that part but I would imagine it's
like a highgrade or I don't know I would
imagine it's like a good type of UV or
I want to say UBC vitamin
C UBC
yes so I've been talking about UVC
lately so much just having a Thomas has
UVC on the uh on the brain Selena those
are the Predator lights that he's
released that uh disrupt bug populations
in a sort of uh pretty miraculous way
can you like I mean just for myself can
you explain a little bit more about how
that
works um well you do get high from a
suppository you you do you can if you
put it up too high like usually when
we're talking about patient care I also
work with medical patients that use
cannabis like to the first knuckle the
higher you go the higher you'll get is
usually what I say there's a part of
your your colon that correlates with the
liver and you can get quite high if uh
you insert it too so it depends and also
you know your hydration level you know
your diet all these other factors um
really it makes a difference and how
that suppository is going to be be
received or not I to be quite honest
I've never got into that part of the
topic about how like how far how far to
push it um I never even thought of that
but I didn't definitely didn't think
that it gets you high well like this guy
or my cousin like he took 20 milligrams
orally he'd be totally leveled so I
guess he's it's keeping it at a level
where he's not getting high yet well and
what I've also seen with some patients
that I've worked with is you know the
the degree of cancer that they're
fighting or the degree of pain that
they're in it's almost like the medicine
goes towards mitigating that first
before it presents as a Euphoria or
dysphoria so like we've had an example
where somebody's cancer went into
remission they were taking the same dose
that they'd always take and all of a
sudden they were very intoxicated from
the medicine and what we found is it was
because the cancer had gone into
remission and it wasn't needed for
fighting that cancer anymore um so I
mean this plant is miraculous we really
we don't fully know but I think it's
really cool that uh you know we're at
least experimenting and people have
access to it and you're providing that
option for your family I think it's
really important well just this topic
got brought up earlier this week um
while there was like a someone had said
something about the legal market and the
and you know the black market or the
Legacy market and before I made a post I
actually went around and I like phoned a
whole bunch of different stores to just
see like how much someone can get a gram
of RSO if they need to fight cancer and
it's like you know at the cheapest I
could get was like $34 for something
that's 650 milligrams and you know what
percentage of the population can
actually afford to take that or do that
twice a day it's it's just it's not it's
not affordable for people but on the
like on the Legacy side of things you
definitely can find stuff that's
affordable for people so there's a real
issue it's um where well like the
government or some people need to start
stepping up or advocating to subsidize
anybody if they if they legitimately
have cancer they should should be a
right they can get it like I know people
that are you know telling me that
they're you know they're trying to take
it as much as they can as they can
afford it which is pretty crazy when
you're fighting for your life it's wild
and then to pay excise tax on top of it
all is just such an insult especially
because it's
medicine well I know when they subsidize
to the most stupidest other things you
would imagine like when you look at
other things or other departments and
stuff
yeah
um well that's where too you know like
I'm I'm in a patient grow right now like
if patients have the option to grow
their own medicine obviously it's you
know the most cost-effective way to get
it but not everybody has the space or
has the capability especially if they're
in a certain you know weakened state of
health um you know and time time is a
really big factor here so this is where
I think like the power of community is
really important being able to have you
know those neighbor grows that can share
medicine and and share resources or
having friends that have you know those
freezers full of extra product that
they're not necessarily going to use and
being able ble to share that amongst the
community for people that really need it
um I'd love to see more of those types
of channels happen on a on a larger
scale I think it's a a great way to take
back our power as as humans as Sovereign
beings awesome well said for
sure I'm still trying to figure out how
the show got cut off but we we're back
to 200 viewers so we got back up there
we're bumping up people are people are
coming back they're finding you yeah
absolutely are you still having your
panic attack are you okay no no I'm
pretty relaxed other than you know the
the soreness butth I'll tell you there's
nothing like soreness or pain to really
force you to be in the moment you know a
lot of people spend a lot of time in the
past or they spend a lot of time in the
future which of course causes anxiety
Andor depression so it's good to uh just
try to be present I think it's one of
the reasons why I love cannabis so much
cuz cannabis is also a nice little like
Hey look how beautiful the world is when
you pay attention to it and you actually
just exist in it in that moment rather
than be like oh I want to do this this
this and this and I got all these plans
for the future and it's like that's
anxiety then you go back to the past and
you're like oh I did this this this and
this and now it's different that's
depression best to just stay in the
moment if you can it's not easy I I'm
not the best at it but uh but look at
this gift you've given yourself this
broken clavicle to just bring you right
back into here and now oh yeah yeah it's
uh and slow me down too I'm a very type
A personality so I move very quickly
very quickly everywhere always doing
things fast so this is like a good uh a
good reminder that slows good too I can
keep up with you in the airport now yeah
exactly I walk so fast I have like
really bad knees it's like a well not
always but I have arthritis and
sometimes it's like such a fight I'm
like dude please just slow down a little
bit my
knee fny he has asked me to slow down a
little bit in the airport a walking
meditation right that like slow down you
actually get so much more done when you
just slow it down and that's that
present that you were talking about
being in the ha now I I walk like uh I'm
about to have a heart attack yeah I used
to I called it hummingbird mode which I
mean is appropriate sometimes but also
you need to stop and like smell the
flowers and enjoy life while it's
happening well it would take me forever
if I we were going at my speed like will
get right in there and I'll like get in
the elevator else i' be I'm letting
everybody go where everybody's just
fighting for it so
yeah he's oh yeah he's not messing
around it's like I have to keep up and
it's like he'll cut in front of one
person I'll have to get with him you
need like one of those like little kid
like harnesses on him where he's got
like the little vest with a little leash
yeah yeah that's that would be him at
the airport I I'm sure if those existed
when I was younger I probably would have
had one cuz I'm sure I gave my parents
heart attacks kids are amazing you know
you don't think so but they they are so
aware of when you're staring at them
when you're looking at them when you're
perceiving them and so the second you
stop perceiving them and they bolt it's
like it's why you're like how could that
kid possibly have gotten away in that
short a period of time it's like well
just just have a couple and you'll find
out in a in they've been hyper
vigilantly watching for you to just tune
over yeah yeah yeah and what you think
is too seconds was actually like two and
a half minutes now your kid's like seven
aisles over hiding in the cereal boxes
think me it's so much fun while you
freak the [ __ ] out yeah all kids I got
cat kids so it's a little different I I
got a mouse this morning he came into my
room and presented me with a mouse at 2
am so that was a different kind of fun
surprise well I get that every day
yesterday was a bird the day before was
a shrew the day before that was a mouse
and it's just been consistent for like
say maybe the last 200 plus days my cat
is a
murderer in fact when my cat gets
consumed by like coyotes or whatever's
going to eat it I'll say what I said
last time when people go oh aren't you
sad and I'll say live by the gun die by
the gun that murderous [ __ ]
killed thousands and now he too has been
murdered oh woe is me well and it's like
the cycle of life right just continues
you probably died doing what he loved
murdering something else or chasing
something else exactly and probably when
he finally when my original cat Dutch
who got killed many many years ago by
coyotes and then flown out of my Village
by a bald eagle um when Dutch passed
away he um I'm sure he realized he was
like
oh this is what it's like to be on the
Dutch loved to like pull baby birds out
of nests he was a Serial he was a serial
killer he was the most sadistic cat ever
and uh I would be remiss I would be
remiss if I didn't show a picture of
Dutch as I'm talking about Dutch because
he was my favorite cat and he was
murderous and he was awesome and he got
eaten by
Coyotes that's what I'm talking about
Dutch would go on Hikes with me he'
cruise around with me up in the forest
clim trees yeah he was awesome like
sweetest little Mountain Cat he was like
25 lbs he was a huge cat his like paws
were like people were like w why do you
have a cat that's so big I'm like I
don't know I saved him from a homeless
like shelter in Vancouver like this kind
of crazy cat lady had him and she
couldn't take care of him or herself so
I was like oh you know I paid her for
whatever I think it was 25 bucks to get
that cat he was a street cat and he was
the best cat that ever
lived you usually are love yes we love
our pets I'll tell you owning cats and
dogs there's a big division in the cats
and dogs Community um owning cats and
dogs is awesome then you get to really
know the the the unique nuances of like
the just un like completely
unconditional love of a dog and the
complete like absolute dismissal of a
cat they're so neat to to to to have on
both sides I I love I love animals so
always have RP to my little dog that
passed away a couple years
ago oh and and Brian's dog as well I
thought you know when I saw the painting
I was like that dog has passed on for
sure yeah that my Stella girl Stella
Blue she died a year and a half ago but
she was 16 and she traveled you know was
from Southern humble and grower lines on
both ends of the family so she had a
good long life and then I just lost my
little baby Lucy at seven years old
beautiful Kan Corso about 3 months ago
so it's been a
change yeah just kind of been like
moving through it and going through The
Grieving and understanding unconditional
love for sure rings a bell you know got
a big lesson and a blessing and is that
a painting of her next to you yeah I
just got this yesterday the painting
here is of my old girl the big one and
then this is just a picture of Lucy in
the greenhouse right next to the raised
beds in the light dab so happy
[Applause]
yeah I have a k Corso named Lucy I I
actually lost uh I I I I had another K
Coro named Leia actually that I lost her
about two years ago and she was one and
I I got her spayed and it was from the
surgery sorry it it was so crazy because
like I had a bad feeling about the place
we were going to like someone had said
something bad so then I went and found
another vet who had the best reputation
around they tested her did all these
tests before and then yeah she when I
got got her home she bled out and I had
another one believe it or not before
that that uh it was another Cane Coro
and it had like a bunch of defects and I
spent like about seven Grand trying to
figure out what was wrong with him and
he had something in a spinal cord and we
had to put them down at like six months
old it's crazy I can relate I'm a can
Corso guy yeah they're beautiful animals
I got to know they're very patient and
taught me like she was real really low
pressure dog so it's kind of carried on
and Spirit you know where it's like a
low pressure lifestyle and it really is
has kind of come in with like a lot of
Peace into my life so I got a good a
good blessing from that baby I love the
canes too nice I was gonna say that's
probably one of her gifts to you
especially in the afterlife now it just
carries through yeah right away very
Vivid is like more you know obviously
noticeable now that she's gone but it
was like immediate immediate transferral
there you know of energy so
well rip to our to our friends that have
that have come and Gone Gone both animal
and uh human for that matter I always
say to people when I hear them grieving
uh I think of Dr Zeus who said uh don't
be sad that they're gone be happy that
they were
here I was like yeah dude no [ __ ] and
then I saw I saw my friend Clint Young
have posted recently he lost his father
not too long ago and he wrote
I miss you Dad I hate that you're gone
and so I wrote in the comment section or
do you love that he was here and I think
it's just this slight ever so slight uh
perspective change um which I'm sure
it's probably one of the reasons we all
love cannabis you know shutting off the
background sound and all the sort of
manipulations and all that sort of
whatever you want to call it it's almost
like good versus evil you just want to
shut off the evil for a little bit you
have a little hoot you open your mind
and you can start becoming more open to
these Concepts and these ideas that uh
life is a little deeper than uh than you
may think I got to share uh my last my
only Academy trip I ever had a big shout
out to the Empower Health Group in
Vancouver um they did a a clinical staff
day and part of my journey was grief and
I found myself on the river sticks in my
journey on my my Cosmic canoe I called
it because it it's this feeling that
you're constantly moving and you can't
hold on to anything but I was on the
river sticks and I was floating on the
grief River and the message to me was
the grief is the love and the love is
the buoyancy that keeps you afloat on
this grief River and it's such a ative
position but it's such a beautiful
compliment of each other right like you
can't grief as deep if you didn't love
as much so that's why it hurts so much
and I think the beauty of grief too is
you know it's it's always with you you
know you carry it with you and even
though more time goes by I love the the
analogy that you know the grief is kind
of like you know this the stone that you
carry and it feels like so encapsulated
right because it's so acute especially
in your situation you know your your
beautiful dog passed away only three
months ago but it's like as time goes on
you have more space and time but that
rock Remains the Same or that stone
Remains the Same and that grief you get
to carry with you and and it is a
representation of your love and I think
it's just so beautiful and I think in
our culture we don't honor grief as much
as we should know or we have like
timelines on it or it should look a
certain way grief is just so ineffable
and it's it's not linear you know
sometimes you'll get a smell or a sound
or a song and it'll just take you right
back into those moments I really love
your brief frame where you can celebrate
it you have I know I I know that for you
Selena that
you really stared in the face of grief
in a different way doing end of life
both your grandfather and your
grandmother in home that is like be
Beyond like Angel status the paliative
care that you offered them I'm sure that
grief was being experienced through the
entire process obviously to the end and
and and on but that is a unique thing
when you don't run away from something
like that and you face it head on you
can uh once again get you can get deeper
in to the to the experience and I I was
terrified of grief I got hit with grief
when my father was was killed suddenly
with his wife on a motorcycle that I had
bought him for his 50th birthday
birthday and they had this accident and
and they both passed away and for me
grief was like a shovel in my face I had
never really been forced to to stare at
it before and so it was uh it was a
little bit shocking I can see how people
would want to run away from it or maybe
get confused by it and think that it was
a bad thing but uh I think as uh what's
his name here flound said here in chat
what did he say the worst the worst that
it is the lucky you were for your
grief foul Bundy That's so powerful
that's so powerful thank you for that
well and especially in your circumstance
right like it what like with my
grandparents it was like a slow grief
process you know and with dementia you
slowly watch this person slip away while
they're still alive whereas for you it
was like a shovel in the face it was
like boom you know so were you able to
lean into it and go into it or did you
run from it for a while until it it
finally caught up no I don't think I did
run run from it I think I pretty much
faced it right away I always say like at
the funeral I was kind of like the uh
the movie where you see the Italian
woman and all black with the veil over
her face and she's like crying on top of
the casket I was basically her like just
like I don't think I had cried for I
don't even know like maybe 15 or 20
years or something so it was the most
incredible release of emotion uh and
deep sadness and kind of just like whoa
like my dad and I I had a great
relationship with my dad my dad was
super Mentor super awesome man super you
know like uh just very hardworking and
all of his e his ethics and morals got
kind of put into me so I looked up to
him he was a fireman so he was like a
hero you know the day I was born he was
in his first fire he became the youngest
fire chief in Canada at 48 years old and
he did that because he went and took
while after leaving my mom getting
together with a new woman who also had
three kids plus his two kids he took his
GED his M or his Bachelor of Science and
His Master's in business in like two and
a half years and I would see him at the
kitchen table just like working so hard
like crazy style for like five hours
after a full shift and then he also
owned his own business so he was a
fireman but he drove semi for a buddy
who owned a semi he drove uh limousines
for herses from my grandpa who owned a
funeral home and he owned his own
fencing and decking company so he built
Fen and decks and often the people that
wouldn't be able to afford those fences
and decks he'd just swallow it so he was
like extremely hardworking if any of you
knew my dad you'd be like oh okay so
that's why you're kind of like that I
get it so I I get to see him in me and I
get to see him in my sister and uh I'm
much more on the happy he was here than
uh sad that he's gone once you get
comfortable with it they're never really
gone I mean if he was gone I wouldn't be
talking about him right now
well and you keep him Alive by talking
about him by sharing those memories like
can I ask like what was one of the I
mean I'm sure there's so many but what
was one of the the gifts or the gems
that you got out of having that
relationship with him obviously he's
your dad but like what was some of the
juice of what he was able to gift to you
well you feel very safe when you grow up
with a father like that you know you
learn about strength you learn about um
you know doing doing right by people and
and proper manners and just you know his
gifts were his
his uh sense of humor he was my dad was
hilarious he would he had a classic
thing where he would kind of you know
tell a long joke hit the punchline get
the whole room laughing and then he'd
kind of pull his pants up a couple of
times and walk out of the room and
although it sounds funny he literally
did that thousands of times I just
watched him do that it was just the way
his timing was with his jokes that he
kind of like leave the room when he hit
a real good punchline so that was uh
something that I'll always be
reminiscent of and happy of just good
times you
know it's awesome I know one of the
things that I took from omop I mean they
both survived the Holocaust so that's
pretty crazy [ __ ] but they always talked
about looking you know for the sunshine
in life looking on the the brighter side
of life always looking for that like
little that little silver lining in
everything you know and considering they
had survived such horrific circumstances
it was always looking for like the the
juice out of life of the moment you
really enjoying that cake or really
enjoying that visit or really being
present you know and just like the
simple things the things that you can't
buy yeah yeah I carry that with you well
the things that you can't buy it's
because money is the opposite it's like
once you're focused on that and we all
have to kind of be focused on it to a
degree I mean thoughts and prayers
haven't paid my mortgage ever I wish I
wish that it did but I got to hustle and
I got to make money on the same on the
same uh side but it is definitely a
strange thing that the the working and
the making money unless you're really
doing something that you love can just
Rob your your soul of all that juice
that you're actually here trying to find
in the first place so and it's funny
that you say the juice because today's
panel was really kind of we wanted you
know we invited Mason to talk about
breeding and feno hunting and really to
talk about the juice you know the the
good part and he even showed some of his
juice earlier he was like yeah I grew
this that looked like ridiculous rosin
by the way dude super fire so it's just
full Circle even metaphorically as we
get into a deeper level of conversation
here on hash Church talking about things
we don't often talk about but thank you
Selina for bringing the feminine energy
into the house and bringing the uh just
the the the nicer slower vibratory
frequency as I see Mark with his furro
brow as I say that because both Mark and
I are like so it's nice to be slow down
every once in a while right
Mark yeah
you guys can speed it up it's all good
get in your hummingbird mode it's all
good um he's been showing his cats and
his dogs see he knows he knows the Best
of Both Worlds the the cat and the dog
dude that's awesome I have four cats and
two dogs a tortoise and a goat at this
house and then my other house has like
40 chickens two dogs and a Farm cat
Garden cat that's awesome I got I got
too many
animals feeding the goat some of some of
the plants he's got good
fertilizer yeah awesome that's
awesome very very
good can I ask you guys if you had any
insight or advice or words of wisdom for
people that want to get involved in
reading and producing different
cultivars and different just to really
like be of service to this plant and
just experiment like I'm so inspired by
your garden oh my God you know even your
plants that are laid over and you're
just letting them go I'm like yes um do
you have any words of wisdom for people
that are watching this that are inspired
and want to get
started I mean it's it's kind of uh
sounds cliche but like easy does it just
do it pop some seeds you know uh a lot
of people try to
replicate like Perfection per se but
like if it's your first time it's never
going to be perfect you know my thing
was just it's it's like we can know all
the jargon all the info all the history
but it's going to be hard work it's
going to be fill in pots up with dirt
and you know watering them every day so
like it's hard work you know you could
do a little bit at a time and be special
at that but you'll become more privy if
you're like you know just taking more
risk and putting more energy into it and
a lot of risk is involved because of
legality so it's like yeah you might
have to take a risk you know or else
you're going to be subjected to Growing
six plants and you know that's not
abundant at all you're not going to
learn much growing six plants so it's
like just do what you got to do it's up
to you finally to to like to to go where
you want to go and sit where you want to
sit with you know all the Breeders and
the who's who's or you could just be who
you want to be and just like kick back
make dope [ __ ]
you know and keep it amongst yourself
everyone knows what they got um you know
that and and just like highlighting
unique stuff or preserving dope stuff
like do what you want to do but just do
it super cliche but you just got to do
it I think it's accurate for the most
part I think it's a good way to explain
to people that uh you know johnnyb
taught me exactly what you just said
which was uh you know everyone's trying
to strive for Perfection when I started
my YouTube channel I was literally just
trying to make per not perfect videos
but I would definitely like clean
anything out of the shot I would control
the shot I would edit I would just make
it I would I wanted it to be what I
wanted it to be right and then Johnny B
would come and he would film with me all
the time and we we would get some views
and you know got the channel up to like
100,000 at one point in time and uh at
that point John was like oh I'm gonna oh
I think actually the channel was up
around 70,000 maybe 50 and John was like
I'm gonna I want to start you know doing
this too I'm like well you should dude
this is the camera I have this is the
computer I have this is the software I
use this is how I use it and so then he
went and started doing some cool videos
and his videos were different because
he's Johnny B he's super relatable he's
doing videos he's making hash in his
basement there's like dirty laundry
hanging from the ceiling looks like a
bomb went off in this guy's house and
it's just authentic and it's relatable
and it's real and here I am creating
this unrelatable unreal you know over
overlooking the ocean making hash on the
boat and it's I still got views but not
the way Johnny B got views Johnny B beat
me to 100,000 view uh followers on on
YouTube and I was just driving me nuts I
was like what the [ __ ] I'm like putting
all this work and energy into it and I
think it might have been my wife that
was kind of explained like yeah like
like Perfection like why are you so
obsessed with this perfection even with
hash Church the first time I started
hash church I did it 162 times in a row
without missing a Sunday you cannot
imagine how much stress and grief that
caused me in different countries without
internet like I would stress the [ __ ]
out and my wife would be like what is
your deal bro like what are you doing
right now why are you so obsessed with
doing the show at 9:00 a.m. PST when
you're not even on the west coast you're
in [ __ ] Amsterdam or Jamaica or
Panama for Christ's sake so it was a a
good lesson that Johnny B taught me it's
much more important to just do it and I
think Instagram it's good to see you
using Instagram differently because I
think a lot of people use Instagram for
Podium wins it's all about not exposing
your faults and not exposing your
mistakes and not exp and that's the
value that's the juice Selena was
talking about the mistakes are what we
want to hear about I don't want to see
you on the podium that's great you're on
the podium every day I'm feeling great
about my life I'm not that's how people
see that it's non-r but when they can
Johnny B would come out and he would
just be like well my Garden's got mites
again you know just like just like
totally expose his [ __ ] oh I got powdery
mildew again I don't know if it's that
grape vine that's hanging out my house
that bubble man told me to cut down 15
years ago but I keep getting this
[ __ ] powdery mildew and people loved
him for it it was like I have powdery
mildew on you know sure you're watching
those videos of perfect grows and
perfect Gardens but people that don't
have that that's not maybe it's giving
them some inspiration but I think more
so it's making them feel bad it seems
seems like the frequency of the
algorithm is that it creates envy and it
creates just a not a great Vibe what I
like about you Mace is that you're just
doing it you're just putting it out
there even showing your grow I also
loved it I thought that's great like it
doesn't have to be like this obsessive
compulsive Perfection like beauty comes
out of the imperfect you know and I
think that uh it's also what I kids need
to learn these days that imagination
comes out of boredom and if you don't
have boredom you will kill your
imagination so if you're watching get
your kid off their [ __ ] tablet or a
or the phone or the computer because
that is the that is the murderer of
imagination and Imagination uh is the
creation of happy children well unless
they're watching hash church right well
unless they're watching hash church just
for a couple hours you know I just you
know like the six to eight hours of day
on the tablet it's uh it's no bueno yeah
my son only likes six I had a I had a
Facebook memory you know how in your
Facebook feed you you get like oh years
ago you were doing this so it was 10
years ago it's just maybe like about a
week or so ago I got this 10 years ago
when
herio had first reached out to me and
said hey man Tony V is up here talking
all kinds of tpine stuff can you come up
on hash church and set this guy straight
so yeah so that was like I think maybe
like October 23rd
2014 or something like that that was
that son so it's it's been 10 years man
so it's crazy it has been 10 years I
remember Horatio hit me up I want you to
invite my friend Dr Mark Salone onto
hash church I'm like okay invite him on
let's let's see what he has to say holy
[ __ ] that I open Pandora's Box let's see
what he has to say oh my gosh gosh that
was uh yeah that was that was 10 years
ago it's hard to believe it's been 10
years so how many year how many years in
a row did you like how many consecutive
EP episodes was it it was like 162 I
think it was three years just over three
years of not missing um a Sunday right
yeah right or maybe just under three
years but it was a lot and I'll tell
tell you I was very relieved even
recently Sam earlier this morning was
like why did you decide to like stop
doing hash church and why did you decide
to start doing it again and I was like I
don't know man I just go with the
feeling it wasn't it wasn't hitting the
same it was you know I just I thought
everyone needs a break to go do their
own thing and well then there was there
was a 2.0 right so at some point you
brought it back and then at some point
the channel Got Hijacked by some Bitcoin
thing right or yes that that was bit bit
finance that was a scam and that was me
at ski school in Whistler dropping my
kid off and I get this YouTube video and
it it was like I got an email from
YouTube and I never get got by this
stuff but I in an instant clicked the
the link and that was it the channel was
gone in an instant and uh shout out to
the gentleman from Russia who helped me
get the majority of my videos back
because there was a guy from Russia who
had ripped all of the hash Church uh
videos like all of them and he said no
no not just all of hash Church Sor all
of my YouTube videos he got me like
hundreds of YouTube videos back because
towards the end of that scam the guy
started deleting my videos I I'd go on
every day and I'd be like oh no so he he
deleted like 15 million views in videos
and that's why my views are like 32
million or something instead of you know
the close to 50 that they would be at if
uh if those didn't get deleted but I
also learned in that experience when I
lost my YouTube channel that I do not
like my YouTube channel does not define
me and although I was bummed about it
more for um hash Church than anything I
was also on the flip side like well I
could just do this again I could just
start another Channel and the minute I
accepted that way of
thinking the sooner I figured out like
people reached out they gave me links to
click on I actually got in touch with
someone at YouTube they got me my
YouTube channel back with you know 600
of the Thousand videos that were on
there and then this Russian dude popped
out of nowhere and was like hey I've got
like at least four or 500 of your videos
and I think he was maybe missing like
like a dozen so it's it's neat how the
world can have your back out there from
From Any Given location I [ __ ] love
that uh that Edgar's in [ __ ] Straight
Out of Compton dude that is so [ __ ]
awesome that you're just smashing it in
Compton that is uh I got to sh something
wild as you're talking about this
Russian dude so I just want to quickly
introduce Drake Drake is the grower here
this is his beautiful
garden he learned how to grow from
him from this all the knowledge so I I
grow with jadam so that's the uh the son
of the k&amp;f practitioner Master cho hanku
cho his son young Sango came up with Jam
the information that I've acquired on
this was from that same individual who
still going to be a little bit cautious
with due to where they're at in the
world um with information but yeah all
the information I got over the last like
three and a half years were from this
individual doing all these meetings on
The Daily uh zoom in and uh yeah I gotta
I got to give so much hudos and respect
to him and if everyone can just take a
minute and put out some good energy and
some just some lovely Vibes they're in a
really bad spot and they may not even be
around anymore it's been a long time
with no contact um but this is a really
really lovely individual going through a
lot of uh a lot of stuff on their end
but is still willing to put time in for
everyone else so you know and just yeah
big loves big ups and it's a pretty
small world we live in so kudos to you
sir if you're watching this I hope you
are and thank positive
message see tan brought a friend back I
did I I have a um I have a a meeting of
scientists from around the world of
cannabis that meets on Sundays at 10:
a.m. so I I wanted to introduce hash
Church to a new doctor this is
Dr
Ortega uh his name is Arturo and uh he
is from UC Berkeley uh he got his
Doctorate there and he is a crisper
scientist so and he works in cannabis so
I wanted to introduce uh Dr Ortega to
the group and introduce y'all so you can
ask questions because he's working on a
very interesting uh field of science
being a crisper scientist and working in
cannabis and as we talked about hop and
vroid diseases Etc so uh Dr Ortega
please introduce yourself to the
world uh Hey everybody
um yeah I uh like said I am chis for
scientist mular biologist
um uh my interest has always been in
Plants um
for tradeit improvement things like that
and my focus now is on on cannabis and
hemp and I work for a company called Max
Gene which is a sister company to my
flora DNA um some of you may be familiar
with them they do uh path pathogen
testing for things like hot L and woid
for Growers and such
so
um right now we're we're working on uh
establishing a platform
to uh Gene edit uh cannabis for trait
Improvement or to offer new traits to
readers and
Growers um we've had
some uhin the last year we've had some
success with developing this protocol um
and we have some regenerating tissue
culture that has Gene edits using
crisper um can see if I can
share a photo everybody
see yeah let me make sure that sharing
is uh on oh oh I mean if if you'd like
or not but oh of course I would like but
sometimes Zoom has these weird defaults
where it says only I can can share so I
just wanted to make sure it was turned
on oh I can uh yeah I can just send you
the photo and then you can share it if
You' like no I've set it up so you can
share man much easier then you can
control what you want to share your
camera's off too I'm not sure if you
realize that or not you don't have to
turn it on by any means oh yeah no it's
it's fine I prefer to have it off but
let's
see
uh well we're not all sitting in
beautiful
gardens right see yet
[Music]
yet all right we got a few people one
second yeah no problem take your time
got a few people that say they have
questions about crisper and cannabis
technology so I'll save those for after
you've explained what you're going to
show and maybe we can get into that
welcome back Mojave hey thanks for
having me
back you know hey while we're waiting
for our T to get that fired up I just
wanted to also mention to Masonic man
because we dropped off before I got to
see a chance I I didn't get to meet you
but I did go to your free seed Day event
man and I was just the other day
cataloging all my seeds and I had just
all these I was like where did these
come from all these packs I'm like pack
pack like oh dude free seed day and just
what a great thing you do to put
together this event brings all these
people together and you guys give away
so many seeds and you create a space for
people to do their thing so just like
big props for you on that man no doubt
man thanks for coming and supporting
appreciate it I want to get one out on
the East Coast with you brother we got
to talk about it no doubt no doubt we
got to run one up together for sure yeah
for sure
all right what is this
do this is a regenerating uh cannabis
plantlet uh that we transformed with
crisper and we targeted a gene called
phyto desaturase or PDS for short and so
when you mutate this Gene uh typically
the phenotype you see is an albino plant
so this is just simply for proof of
concept for our protocol and so now
we've also had some some results with uh
other Gene targets uh one specifically
for Drought
resistance and we're kind of right now
trying to get some insight from from
Growers and and um other scientists on
what kind of traits the Market's looking
for um that we can Target
so if you you guys have any insights be
appreciated mold resistant early finish
big yields on hash Drome content oil
content you yeah yeah there's a few that
I've considered for those um traits
um there's one one Locus Gene Locus that
gives Pottery mdeo resistance it's been
shown in several other plants
so and um as far as far as tricomes
there's also one that if you target it
we predict uh specific Gene um predict
that uh triome density will
increase so what about type of triome
production like less bulbous and more
capitate
Cil okay yeah um I have to look into
like what kind of genes
um uh the triome uh development are
involved in
so it's cool in that pathway what was
that very it's just cool that you can do
it it's a neat way to be able to look at
the plant and go you know deeper I'll
always think of Terence mckenny when he
said how come the deeper in you go the
bigger it gets oh yeah more questions
arise afterwards right Wade had his hand
up oh
thanks yeah um I couldn't help but jump
in I uh know a little bit about crypto
technology and uh I'm assuming you're
doing good prce practices on making sure
some wild variant doesn't get out into
the greater cannabis plant
population and then the other thing I
wanted to say is
um hopefully hopefully you're exploring
some of the finer minor phyto conoids uh
the hemp industry is certainly exploring
a lot of that but as a patient and as a
person who uh pursues minor canid for my
own benefit
um would love to see stronger plants
producing conoids that are of interest
to
Patient thank
you um yeah so we uh have standard
practices to PR prevent the release of
of these of these plants generative
plants everything is in in a confined
space and we're actually just doing
tissue tissue culture right now at the
moment we don't actually grow to seed to
flowering um and it doesn't it never
leaves the lab into an open field or
anything like that and as far as uh
other phyto cannaboid Pathways Pathways
we are looking at those as well um
possibility of confer conferring
different cannaboid
profiles um but it it get it gets very
tricky when you start perturbing those
Pathways because we we're not sure
what's going to happen you know you have
all these turpine syntheses you have you
know the there's a lot like the CHC
synthes and other cannaboid syntheses um
are are very redundant so if you perturb
one the other one might uh compensate
for for the loss of the other one things
like that so those are exactly the kind
of concerns that I have our buo so thank
you for articulating that
yeah
sure yeah those are valid concerns for
sure
absolutely I'm uh I'm I I'm cautious on
both sides I love the idea of using
science to go deeper in and if we can
you know if there's new ways in the
future that this technology can access
information that we've sort of been
blind to or maybe not blind to but that
took it just seems like everything's
about either access or speeding up the
access um I know that's what it's been
like for hash making for the longest
time it's you know once we figured out
how to isolate tricomes to a
99.9% ratio at right after that it just
became well how fast can you do
it yeah I mean in some respect I feel
like breeding was there in the early
2000s where everyone was racing to find
like these fast finishers right because
you could you know you could flip them
faster um and then it we got away from
that and then you know 2010 happened and
we started focusing on Flavor right so I
think that's you know flavor and then
potency as well is really really first
potency now now flavor I should say but
um but it's really you know we're at
this real dichotomy right now where the
plants themselves may not be the best
plants for growing you know at scale
because they're not resistant to the
problems that we see from pest pressure
or you know pathogen path you know
pressure Etc Etc and then on the last
ass church we talked a lot about clone
houses I thought was a good topic
because in some respect and the reason I
wanted to bring Ma on is because you
know if you if you continually just buy
trays of things that exist that other
people have already ran you're you're
bottlenecking not only yourself but also
the the consumers around you and you're
making an environment that's undesirable
for them to go buy it so you know
exploring those varietals and it going
deeper to look deeper at what perhaps
you might be be able to do as a farmer
from let's say you know 100 seeds or a
thousand seeds from from Masonic or
others um you know we're talking about
s1's earlier a little bit where I feel
like csi's s1's are some of the best
seeds I've seen in a long time I was
kind of Blown Away when we first ran
some of his work I was like this was
really eye openening for me you know um
his historically you know in our our
community and circles we used to talk
down on Sans you know we used to be like
oh they're not as strong they're not
going to be as strong they're they're
weaker you know and it's just our lack
of understanding and of of what you know
genomics really truly is so um I think
you know we're I think someone said said
it last week you know we used to say we
know a lot about a little now we know or
we know lot a lot about a little about a
lot and a about a little you know and I
think Mark said somebody said that and I
think we're our way to knowing nothing
about everything yeah and that's kind of
where we're at and I think it's amazing
with all that all our expertise we're
we're still searching for things that
quite frankly I think we've seen before
but we're not isolating enough and now
that there's more people growing plants
you know we're kind of bottlenecking
things so I
think you know looking at the gene po
looking at what even going back to what
Sam is
contributed and all those years ago like
it's incredible that we're today looking
at the gene pool that we have right now
you know and still pulling from things
and then we're all of us are buying from
clone houses you know because it's
there's seeds out there that are
incredible that's what I'm getting at
and I think that Masonic you Edgar you
and others are really providing a
pathway for people to really do it
they're just not taking the time to do
it you know a lot of people are aiming
for that person perfect you know so or
it's just you know that's that's what
people are safe with you know you go
grab the Clone you flip it you know why
would you go well that's been the
standard right the problem is there
isn't a whole array of genetics
available at a longitude and latitude
that will max out in the way that you
need now for there are they are working
on that I just got off of meeting with
the guy from The usda's germplasm
Institute and you know they're growing
over 500 variants so uh in two weeks
I'll give yall a report along with
pictures of the garden um to give an
understanding about you know what
they're doing uh because they've been
collecting seed crops from around the
world and they're seeing early
expressions of full seeded plants
already and it's the end of August and
those are he said from like when Nepal
and Pakistan
Mojave so you know um it's also you know
latitude that's what Rob was saying on
our meeting you know it's a key issue
that isn't uh being discussed because a
lot of people are taking those European
genetics and thinking they're going to
get that full expression in Louisiana
Mississippi or you know in other areas
and they're finding that their what
their expectation is versus the reality
they're getting is two different things
yeah yeah I mean go ahead sorry I was
just GNA say one one of the the big
problems in our industry is that you
know a lot of the the breeding work and
cultivation Tech and stuff has been done
in controlled egg and in controlled egg
we have a very limited understanding of
um photo period and night Interruption
and trigger points so there's kind of an
arbitrary thing that that bleeds over
from a lot of crops which is just add
four to six hours of extra light and
your plants won't flower so so that's
what people do so that for a lot of
different crops so it's just like add a
bunch of light and you guaranteed if
you're growing a short day plan it won't
flower and then the other thing that we
do which is like an arbitrary thing is
that if you give them 12 hours of light
they will flower so over the past 30 you
know almost 40 years we've been doing
that as an industry and by following
those guidelines we lost a lot of data
points which is how many hours a day
does this really need to not flower each
cul of our right because that's what
tells you what latitude you can grow
them that tells you how many day hours
they can absorb in terms of photons
right a lot of plants can easily flower
13 13 and a half 14 hours 15 hours 16
hours of daylight and they still flower
but they're not aof flowers anyway so
that that little that one piece of data
that the USDA is like collecting on all
these different sessions that helps
shape the industry and we weren't we
weren't able to do that because we were
all just in the closet or just running
in green houses with this arbitrary
number but like I've been screwing
around with night Interruption with
cannabis for years and I never add more
than 20 minutes A Night to keep it from
triggering U but what I don't do is I
don't collect the data on every cultivar
that says you know at what point will
this one trigger you know so there's a
lot of there's a lot of really
interesting stuff that we can do when we
can do large scale trials at multiple
locations of the same variety you know
but and I'll just add one of thing on
the seed thing is back in the 90s man in
the Dutch seed world the people who came
they all wanted the same thing they all
wanted you know what what you have that
that yields a lot is incredibly potent
really early and resistant to mold you
know it's like they wanted the perfect
scenario and there were a few varieties
that did that but the reality is most
people didn't really focus for 30 years
the past 30 years they could have of
perfecting all of that in one plant you
know and that's really what ultimately
Farmers want they want just a few plants
that have all the traits that they want
instead of having to pick through
thousands of different plants and
thousands of different phenoh hunts in
order to get to their ingame which is a
successful crop not a failed crop you
know a crop that they can sell but
anyway that's why I think everyone I
think that's we're now all collectively
working on that now Out of The Shadow so
it's like it's a really promising time
to be in cannabis research well it's
it's what the market is asking for so Dr
Ortega what is the industry asking of
your company if you're dealing in
crisper and cannabis what are they
asking y'all to do or what does the
industry ask of the crisper technology
currently um right now
um uh we've had some
uh requests for uh tpine profiles
flavors things like that
and um also um resistance to certain
diseases like hotblade viroid and
powdery mildew things like that um and
that's that's about it for now but um
we're just trying to get more insight
from from other for more PE from more
people uh in the Cannabis industry to
kind of guide us to our next projects
once we now that we have this uh
protocol pretty much established
so yeah I have a question too I'm
curious like from your Vantage Point
where would you like to see this go what
kind of advancements would you like to
develop or how do you think that we can
have these in like real world
applications you know like for example
you know patients with certain types of
cancer or Parkinson's disease or or this
this symbiotic relationship between
cannabis as a plan and and humanity and
how can we contribute to that I'm just
curious where do you see this going and
and what are you excited about
um so I see this going to um generating
new traits for uh beneficial um
molecules you know definitely you know
the plant itself right now cannabis
plant um creates it's very beneficial U
molecules for for
patients um and where I want to see it
go
is uh bringing out those those very um
those molecules that are not as abundant
as like THC or CBD those kind of like
hidden cannaboids or even other things
like flavonoids there's a can flaven I
don't know if you guys have heard of
that um it's a flavonoid that um has
some
anti-inflammatory uh and potential
anti-cancer
properties so I I see it um I see this
going more towards the medical side um
and then the second
thing would be like uh you know
improving
or
uh augmenting the you know drug type uh
cannaboids like TC things like that for
consumers for consumers sorry
um as well as um you know generating
more sustainable
traits uh for Growers you know uh what
if Growers use half or a quarter of the
amount of fertilizer or water in the in
uh in their grows and that leads to more
sustainability you know uh disease
resistance what if you can generate a
disease resistant resistant variety uh
so the you know Growers don't have to
use pesticides or or uh you know other
compounds um uh in their grows so so to
sum it
up um I see going to uh medical
applications and also sustainability
applications and that's what I'm most
excited
about That's so exciting thank you so Dr
artura I was talking about this earlier
in regards to you
know it seems like some of the most
incredible Cult of ours come out of that
wreck Market it comes from these um
obsessive compuls of cannabis lovers
that just are so obsessed with it and
it's connected to probably their old
factory and their level of sensory
science that they're actually able to
perform and they're finding these
incredible flavor profiles um and then I
see what you're doing on that side of
things as well do you ever look at you
know cultivars that are grown from the
black and gray Market you know that are
all these different sort of seed
breeders to see you know these flavor
profiles that are winning these contests
like Legends of hash and the you know
there's a hundred of these different
contests now that you can go to and you
can enter your product into and if it's
done properly there's this there's just
this real high level of of enjoyment
that comes from the recre recreational
Market that I think has a huge and
profound impact on the medical Market
it's not coming from like farma
companies you know they're it's fine you
can split and do all this science and
it's amazing but you can what you're
doing to what these breeders are doing
and growing these unique cannabis
cultivars where you where you do where
you find things through that that the
plant is naturally producing and then
you go back to crisper technology and
sort of put those two things together I
don't know if I I made that you know an
understanding question no I understand
um yeah that's actually what we want we
want to do we are a very young company
um we just had our Oney year anniversary
uh earlier this month um so we wanted to
establish this this protocol this
procedure first before we kind of delve
into um all these Growers that have
these uh specific varieties that you
know have their flavor profiles and
their cannaboid profiles um that's
definitely something that we want to tap
into um and work with with those
readers it's funny I was watching Point
Break last night so it's like you know
you got to become the surfer now you
know
oh what the k re version or you got to
become the surfer now like you got to
just dive in there and like ride the w
go to go to Legends go to Emerald go go
like get in the trenches find out
literally what everybody fan there's
literally key note flavors that
everybody likes you know and that's how
they identify them they don't
necessarily call them by their
scientific name they'll grab a butt and
tell you it smells like Skittles smells
like blue dream and it'll be easier for
you to do your job I don't know I'm
thinking just knowing these like things
that we identify as and kind of just
getting in the trenches and learning our
jargon and applying it to your uh
science and then it just be that much
easier for you to explain too like yo
blue dream I don't know if you're
familiar with it but like that's a very
general like that just helps
automatically with that and then as far
as new streams are concerned like
there's all these new ones coming from
the archives the blooms so like you'd go
grab some of the more newer strains that
people are messing with even though they
might be like a derivative of something
old but like a honey banana you know
that's from like 2016 2014 but it might
be new to you it's new to a lot of
people you know so it's all like just
kind of just being privy to Cycles yeah
and just applying it to the science and
just grab like why does everybody love
Skittles and rainbow belts and all these
hybrids of it you know why does every
why did candy shishkaberry win first
place why is Starburst good and you just
grabb all these you know and then you
would have to know and be in good graces
cuz this is like a different culture
where we're like oh you don't have the
real one you know like we're still in
that day and age but but but money talks
in industry and as long as you go to the
guy Mr Skittles Mr orange Mr what
whoever made it Mr Wilson you know Mr
Tropicana Mr papaya and you grab the
nitty-gritty that'd be better for your
science cuz you'd be alluding to like
the original piece you know as opposed
to like oh I got this from a dudy said
it's papaya well it's probably papaya
bag seed not that it's less of or more
of but it'd be better for the it's not
yeah it might not be the original yeah
that's just my my two cents from
listening to that merge you know it'd be
a merge of you just getting in the
trenches that that's definitely
something that we have to do you know
we're just you know we're not as steep
in in the Cannabis world as as most of
yall so um that's definitely deficiency
that we have um and
we're we're coming to a a point where we
would want to start that conversation
with with with people and kind of get
out there to to these um reunions and
meetings and
conferences or just you know just by
randomly meeting Growers that have
certain varieties or you know uh Legacy
varieties that they might have that
they've never shared with
anybody uh things like but um
yeah I got a question Sam you're the
you're the genetics master of Masters
what would you like to see done with
crisper or what would you do with the
crisper
technology he's muted right now let's
just see if he can
unmute it's a good question though I'd
like to hear the answer to it as well
I'll answer for him
was it didn't he say years ago like Tri
chromes the size of grapes that you
could just pluck off yeah he did that
yes hey Arturo what's that
possibility well uh I was looking at a
gene to Target that could possibly have
the tricomes grow not just on the buds
and increase the triome density so that
it's definitely a possibility but it's
some charted Waters right now so I I
have one for
you I want no clusters I want the plant
just to produce tricomes from the stock
all the leaves everything no clusters at
all and we can grow like billions of
them next to each other like just plant
as many seeds as we can so we can you
can just and it's just leaves right yeah
and then you you don't have to wait to
for flowering right that'd be right awes
wait zero flowering time because that
just never happens right and then on on
top of that you have better surface area
for hash washing because you're just
opening that up um so yeah um yeah this
this Gene I've been thinking of
targeting
um it
was it was um studied in tobacco as well
and was found that when they knocked
this Gene out it um did somewhat like
what you're talking about where the
triom started growing more on the leaves
yeah um not on the stock but um on the
leaves itself
so and then the reverse of that is no
leaves on the flower right like the ABC
plant does that well if youve seen any
stuff that CSI did with
um it was the ABC times like KMD or GSC
or something there was a lot more runs
than success rates in that population
but of what I saw that was successful
there was just big clusters of flowers
with like two or three fan leades coming
off and like from a finishing
commercialization point of view you
could just like snip two you know trim
two little cuticles and you're done you
know what I mean
so yeah that would be to unfortunately
yeah because because of um the
restrictions on on cannabis you know
legally there was not a lot of research
done until recently on on the genes and
Pathways that might be associated with
you know uh flower architecture flower
formation right um things like that so
that's something that we will'll have to
empirically kind of figure out um but
you can take information from other
plants that have been studied and kind
of kind of guess what you know if you
target this Gene it might result in this
phenotype you know like oh you know if
you want a shorter in innerlength nodes
you know what I mean
like what I'm alluding to is like what
ma said it's like go get the plan go
basically go get that cross go sequence
it go look at it oh yeah yeah right
understand what's there from a genic
point of view right and then you could
then that there's your Baseline right as
you know but you got to get it from
reliable sources you know right right
and kind of see like uh you can use a
technology called mapping by
sequencing and kind of see which
you know genes might be involved so so
you like you get a segregating
population of your the phenotype that
you're talking about right and you kind
of like coordinate the the potential
genes that are involved in that fenal
type right so yep exactly so you should
um I text Kevin mccar and I was like you
should really come on right now because
this would be a two wizards in the room
um be great to get you guys talking
because we've done some stuff probably
be helpful to your work and it's kind of
towards at least the work I've been
doing it's towards the end of sort of
this ideology where it's like we're
pulling out certain traits and we're
looking at them and isolating
them but you know the other thing I want
to bring up is like okay so we're
talking about the future we're you know
we're really excited but what are the
dangers of that right what is you know I
think of like Herbert berer I think of
Stanley Cohen
um Rudolph J jck is I'm pronouncing his
last name right or um I'm thinking these
people that started the GMO world right
they're like the inventors of this and
and I read some things about them like a
year ago or so a book about how they
were mandated to make these changes
based on the desires of their clients
like don't bruise look you know tomatoes
need to look redder but they didn't look
at the health impacts of what that did
to the
actual plants and the fruit that it
brought to life and I think that if
you're going to look at this and I've
been thinking about this a lot because
of the work that I've seen medical
genomics
do it's your duty to be very careful
about what you're doing and why and I
think it's important to think about this
as you move forward because you are
holding a very dangerous but helpful
you know call it concept right you
you've got through your concept phase
you you think you can do
it but I invite you to look at that
because of you know don't repeat
history um is what I'm getting at so and
and have you thought about that you know
right yeah I've thought about the you
know ethical and moral implications of
what we're doing and I for
one am thinking about that when I'm kind
of planning
uh proposing projects um there's
definitely so right now we do everything
confined so there's no nothing escapes
we autoclave our tissue after we're done
with it and everything but in the future
once we get to the point where we're you
know doing field trials outside or you
know giving this a variety that's been
gened to a breeder or a
grower there is that potential of uh
escaping and pollinating another another
grow somewhere you know next to wherever
you're growing or something is it
potential or is it um like
guaranteed guarantee guys like we I
would think so it's hard to like control
pollen Hawai sustainable brought this up
about 10 minutes ago in the chat he said
oh these people obviously don't
understand the drawbacks and limitations
of GMO which he follow followed up with
a quote from Cho which is offt Target
mutagenesis is an emerging problem when
inducing sight specific DNA breaks for
genome editing so what um what let's
speak on that a little bit right so
there's other so like you you try to
Target a specific Gene with crisper but
there might be
other uh sequences that in in the Genome
of the of the plant that might be very
similar to your Gene Target
and so those can be also targeted by
crisper so uh there's there's you know
computational methods that we can use to
of predict offt Target effects
and before you release a geneed variety
um you kind of try to also genotype
those those of Target potential off
Target
sites uh and see if they've actually
been been affected or not um
uh it it really depends on your Dean
Target whether you're going to have off
Target sites sometimes you have a
specific uh we call it a guide RNA which
shuttles the crisper to your target site
so it can it can uh Target your Gene so
sometimes a specific Gene Target uh has
low potential for offt Target sites and
some have a higher potential and so we
consider that when we when we design our
our crisper um guide rnas
um but yeah like going back to what you
were saying about um whether it's
potential or guaranteed yeah so you know
wind pollination and things like that
you will definitely make it almost
guaranteed um so that that's something
that we have to address once we get
there whether we're just going to have
all of this
confined to a space that's going to be
sterile and you know there's going to be
procedures to to contain the cannabis
plants that have been gen edited and
make sure that the pawn doesn't get out
it's it's a tough one you know because
we just said like the best things come
from our mistakes but as we get into
these dangerous areas where your
mistakes can have these drastic effects
it's just human nature so if you land on
something and it has any negative
everyone will jump on your throat and
say I told you so and if you create
something that's lifechanging and really
affects people's lives on a massive
scale people will be like oh yeah you
know I pretty much fig figured it was
going to go that way like I was a big
supporter of this technology the entire
time so it's this is why Dr aruro is
part of my science group and works with
Rob and Mojave and as is because he's
ethical and we're ethical and we want to
keep that ethical stewardship so that's
why I brought him here as well so that
the world could be aware of the work
that he's doing but also understand that
we're also trying to make sure the
ethics and the proper stewardship are
followed along the way and we're as
curious as well so you know it Arturo I
think Dr Arturo you understand you know
the gravity and the fear I mean and
that's why I brought you here was to
dispel some of the fear because there's
a lot of misinformation about G
misinformation and now at the tip of
that
spear so this by exposure is putting
sunlight on it so that we could disuade
these fears and so um knowledge can uh
rule the day as opposed to
uh shadows and fears and lies well I
love what you're doing at in the sense
of bringing like mentoring in a sense
guiding offering guidance offering kind
of our perspective from our community to
uh Dr Arturo it's better than judging
trolling you know like kind of causing
just like oh blah blah blah blah it's
like okay look these perspectives are
incredibly important and we should
definitely bring them with us but what
we don't want to do is isolate ourselves
completely from all of the people that
are doing this work and really have no
say or no guidance or no helpful
Direction um from the perspective of the
grower the breeder the hash maker the
community if you
will it's a it's a really important
Point Marcus I really I really believe
that because and and I on our last last
week's call you know I I definitely I I
I I felt the energy around you know
there's a lot of protection we all feel
like we have this um we're steward words
and we feel like this entitlement to
protect the plant and but on the flip
side of that is it is it is what it is
it's the industry is what it is the
direction it's heading is what it is and
the people who are in charge it's a
whole new wave and we want to have a
seat we want to continue to have a seat
we've been along through this big arch
that this cannabis has gone through and
on the other end of that Arch is going
to be something else and we that's kind
of what we've all been fighting for but
whether it's whe whether it's
participating or getting just a seat at
the table with the USDA or understanding
new technologies new Innovations and
understanding how other Industries have
treated all other plants that's just
acknowledging that this is the direction
that cannabis is now in and our role is
really has has a big impact maybe the
greatest impact is in that seat at the
table transition I really believe that
you know because we see how industry
goes we've seen what has happened to
other crops in the past you know it's
just the nature of capitalism it's the
nature of the in the world we live in
the commodity driven International
Market so I think you know it's it's
important that's why you know Canada had
a really big role and how um the
international market unfolded right you
know and California had a big role and
how the US market is unfolding and the
people who've taken the Reigns you know
they need we need to still have a role
in their understanding of the plan I
think it's important hey Sam can you can
you turn off the sorry Selena can you
turn the video off in the background
because it's echoing through your
microphone that's why I keep muting your
microphone had a how the US market okay
I'll mute it until you can turn that off
then we want to hear from you for sure
go ahead Selena so I'm just curious well
not curious one of the things I wanted
to add is um I think that's why it's so
important to ask why are
we know you talked about
here we go sorry uh you had talked about
um you know having these guard rails in
place which I think is really important
but I think the bigger question is you
know why are we doing what we're doing
are we really just you know trying to
find turps are we really just looking
for effects like what are we actually
what what is the end goal you know and I
like to imagine and Marcus you know this
I'm very altruistic I'm hoping that you
know on a larger scale we're helping to
liberate the plant we're producing
different um cultivars and phenotypes
that maybe we haven't seen before um
we're able to benefit human
um but I think it's really important too
to to get back to the core of the
question because you know if if at the
end of the day the thing that's driving
us is let's make more money today than
yesterday that's a a much different why
than how can we benefit um humanity and
the planet as a whole so I'm curious you
know from your company's perspective
like what is your ethos and and I'm so
happy that we're having this talk about
ethics um because it's it's it's crucial
especially at this time um how are you
guys um defining your why
what is your
why
um our why is so
we we definitely are doing what we're
doing and in order to provide or
improve uh not you know not just
cannabis but in the future other crops
things like that for the benefit of of
humanity um specifically in cannabis
for um uh medical reasons like I said
before
um
uh it's definitely U so so we definitely
want um the Cannabis Community to kind
of guide us um we don't want to just be
like cynically just oh just for the
money kind of thing and me specifically
as well so like that's that's
my um life philosophy I guess um you can
say but
um you know we don't we don't just want
want uh you know this technology just to
belong to you know one company that's
going to have all the patent rights to
you know to be able to develop um you
know cannabis using this procedure so we
definitely want to you know develop
something that the community can can use
the canas community and
um we so this one of the reasons I I
came on is to kind of
extend my you know invitation to to hear
from
everybody um in the Canabis Community
what their insights are um because what
we're doing is kind of uncharted waters
right now
so you know what I mean
so do you mind if I ask too like you
know beyond way you'd already shared
what are some of the guard rails to
ensure that you guys are you know
operating as ethically and sustainably
as possible and really like setting that
tone and and carving that pth for you
know other people or other organizations
that want to get involved at this
scale um so you know as scientists we
have to develop um St standard operating
procedures for for the things that we
do um and we kind of used
um you know previous protocols for other
crops to kind of guide us into what we
we have to do uh with respect to
cannabis like you know make sure it
doesn't get out from our lab you know
make sure the tissue is dead before we
dispose of it um also kind of use like
the usda's guidelines um as well uh for
for dealing with a potential transgenic
or Gene edited uh plant right
so um yeah who's to say it's not out
there already who's to say that it
hasn't you know it's it's it's
interesting I think uh when we form our
opinions our our understanding of Any
Given subject even if considered an
expert in the subject is still very
small and so it's it's easy to judge
these conversations there's people that
get triggered by even the mere mention
of chrisberg really quite kind of almost
reminds me a little bit of the um uh the
the vaccinated nonvaccinated convers
ation in regards to the tension that
gets created and the Judgment that gets
clearly pushed through uh just the
digital screen Wade has something he
wants to say try to try to lift your mic
up if you can wait it hasn't been very
clear today but I we'd love to hear from
you let's see turn off these
headphones can you guys hear me all
right
yep yeah way better now so much better
okay um I want to start by saying um
thank you Arturo for doing that work I
um thank you I expressed earlier my
concerns about it I have I have some
friends who are in who are doing similar
work um elener K and uh Karen Bentley uh
at leg um anyway so I know a little bit
about crisper and what I'm on the one
hand I feel cautious and I appreciate
what I'm hearing and your concern about
keeping things in hand if you will I'm
excited on the otherand because over the
years we have bred cannabis plants for
various
reasons
um but there are
limitations to some extent on what we
can accomplished with straightup
standard old school breeding like Sam
does you are bringing a whole other
possible realm of like I was saying
earlier minor phoc canono I'm pretty
sure that the cannabis plant produces
compounds that uh will end up being a
great interest in the medical community
and in patients uh
um yes and
um so there's my excitement I I feel
like what's likely is we'll end up with
some uh canono that have alpha numeric
names for a while um that turn out to be
really Mar remarkably effective DD mui
in Israel uh found a alphan numeric
canono that had really remarkable
properties against 18 of 20 cancer cell
lines he was testing
so there you go it's a balancing act on
the one hand deep appreciation for your
ethics around thank you and the patience
and from my own point of view excitement
about what you might find in this plant
we love so much and I'll stop there and
go back to listening thank you so much
for this conversation oh thank you um
yeah there's definitely so many things
that we can discover from this this this
one plant I mean the cannaboid and tping
pathways are are they're like a
web um they're so interconnected and so
complex so it's exciting and also very
um
hopeful right um for the future um you
know some of these molecules that you
know these lesser fetto Canon noids you
can potentially be used for uh as a
template for developing a new drug for
you know whatever disease you know
cancer or some inflammatory disease
chronic diseases things like that and
with regards to crisper um I know some
people have you know their misgivings
and they're cautious about it um so what
we do with
chrisper
um um you know Gene editing of certain
genes of the of the plant is something
that would could potentially happen over
thousands and millions of years
naturally we're just kind of taking a
shortcut um and that's what the
technology allows us to do we're not
doing anything or we're not putting like
a gene from you know I don't know like a
beetle or or from a bacteria or anything
like that into the plant and leaving it
there indefinitely you
know um
so we're just taking a shortcut in a
sense and we're we're we're
using an enzyme that's found in nature
and we're arming it to Target the genes
that we want to Target and for the per
for the benefit of humanity so and
crisper hasn't only been used in Plants
as you probably know it's been used in
in the medical field um in the past year
I think uh to cure uh some some I forget
what it was but is somebody that was
blind and they had cured their their
blind there was a specific condition
that they had they used crisper to to
cure them and I believe they're also
trying to use it for SLE cell anemia as
well
so but
um yeah I understand people's hesitation
to kind of adopt this technology
um but I I I just want people to know
that there's there's scientists and
people that are involved in in this you
know the crisper world that are ethical
and and and moral and and and you know
if there's any controversy or issue you
know scientists as a community will
will uh uh what's it called uh they
they'll put in a moratorium on certain
things like um you know Gene editing
using crisper and humans for for uh
Eugenics and things like that that's
definitely something that um Community
the the scientific Community has kind
of uh as a whole um tried to prevent or
and I think uh with terms of uh with
regards to crops there's something also
similar to where you know scientists
want
to I guess ethically use the crisper
technology to not confer any traits in
Plants that'll that'll be like uh
damaging to the environment or
ecosystems and also to human health
which is why you know in the past
Whenever there was a GMO that was
deployed uh in a crop there was um
several years of testing beforehand and
field trials and things like that before
it was
given uh brought to the market
so anyway
well it's uh definitely creating a
conversation in the chat room for anyone
wants to read that they can check it out
yeah it's not a bad conversation it's
just you people's opinions so with that
said you know the the I keep going back
to what I read
when you know essentially Herbert Boyer
and his other constituents were again
much like you getting approached by con
you know they're respectfully your
clients and they're like hey we need a
sour diesel we need a
papaya um and the way you went about
it and are going or they were going
about it in their terms was they were
going after less bruising easier
Transportation faster flowering times
Fring times Etc but again they didn't
think about the other aspects of things
and sure they did all those testings to
your point and they did all these trials
but they weren't asking other questions
that were perhaps more important down
the line that we didn't really realize
at the time or more importantly they
didn't realize at the time and as smart
as they are and as brilliant as the team
was they created crops and things that
are less
nutritious actually ended up doing the
opposite in the long
run and we're in a dichotomy with with I
would say farming right now where we're
looking backwards we're looking towards
regenerative farming practices and
learning
you know what what that looks like and
you know you know have you you know
again I just we've talk lot we talked a
lot about what you can do but have you
are there any risks and of those risks I
guess more
precisely of those risks what is what
have you found have you found anything
that is like hey we we shouldn't do
this um there's nothing that I can think
of that we've considered that might be
that we're trying to Target that might
be a
danger um to the environment or human
health anything like that
um how would you know like how could you
how could you know that like whether it
would or not it seems like U an
impossibility I'm kind of on the fence
you know I like the conversation people
are very staunch in their belief systems
they're either on one way or the other
I'm sort of I'm similar to Wade in the
sense that it's like yeah definitely
frightens me the potential the you know
the human eror but then I think like you
know I think on this one conversation
okay it's crisper but then it's like but
everyone's like consuming seed oils on a
daily basis and people smoke rad
radioactive tobacco and people like
consume alcohol as their number one
recreational drug which is just like
holy [ __ ] yeah just like a a brain cell
killing like I'll never forget growing
up smoking weed and drunk adults being
like that shit'll kill your brain cells
right right all right
buddy so yeah it's it's an interesting
uh conversation I definitely can see how
it uh it's very human right it's like
you've got humans that want to live in
tepps and live off the land and then you
have other humans that want to build
rocket ships and explore space and
generally the ones that live off the
land are worried about the ones who are
building the rocket ships that they're
going to D inadvertently destroy the
land so it seems like that's the kind of
go ahead Mojave did I just comment on
Arturo and obviously you you're more of
an expert than me but maybe just comment
on what Colin had mentioned um what you
were specifically talking about is a
bottlenecking through um a large a teac
breeding to create a better product a
better commodity versus a better banana
or something that's more nutritious and
I think that that that's an interesting
dichotomy with that and crisper style
breeding and specifically which is that
they bottlenecking an entire genome by
saying this banana shipped better forget
all the other diversity it all got
packaged in here because what they're
really looking for was mold resistance
shipping blah blah blah whereas what I'm
assuming what crisper can can do is they
actually Target that particular trait so
it's not about bottlenecking the entire
genome into one commodity product it's
about saying okay well if we could
identify for instance what that was that
we didn't want in the banana that
shipping longevity whatever ripening
speed or whatever and then apply that to
all the other crops then we didn't have
to bottleneck the entire gene pool we
could actually and with cannabis what I
think makes an interesting discussion
around crisper is we haven't selected
the cultivars yet there's thousands and
thousands of cannabis cultivars that are
in constant rotation that's not the way
it's going to work forever eventually
there has to be a finite number so all
the breeding work that's been done you
have to pick your lane so like for
instance you look at the companies that
have put a lot of money into triploids
right that's a great idea it's a great
concept right but if you didn't pick the
right cultivars and the right parent
stock to do that improvement work on and
then three years later millions of
dollars spent like oh that's not what
the kids want to smoke this year back to
the drawing board but it but with with
Gene editing I'm assuming in theory that
that one thing like what they learned
with wheat or other crops about
branching applied to all the other crops
because they identified that one
branching Gene and said we just have to
find that same branching Gene in all
these different crops so the isolated
nature of the selection it makes it even
less risky in a sense than having to
lump all genes together into one
cultivar
variety I'm GL went through that yeah
and Dr Toro if you could expand on that
for even the listeners so they
understand and again I'm asking these
questions to up to te it up for you to
talk deeper about what your work is and
why you feel like it's important to the
work that all of us continue to do in
the industry and you know it's I think
it's important to explain it because
it's it's not um it's misunderstood in a
huge way and I think genomics in general
and cannabis are so far behind and to
mojave's point where you alluded to
we're just we're not we've billions of
her Idols are found every day I mean
chemotypes phenotypes found every single
day yeah so I steing that down is like a
you know sounds impossible right
impossible for for what to to distill it
down into let's say 10 varials right
Mojave like oh right asking Rob Clark
like hey man do you think we ever find
like value in sativa ever again he's
like if we turn back time I guess we
could you know right yeah
um well um speaking back to what Mojave
mentioned about
bottlenecking um so with this chrisper
technology you edit one gene or you can
edit more than one
simultaneously and that can be applied
to not just one
variety um to several different
varieties of cannabis so the
the potential for bottlenecking is not
there right it's not like how he
mentioned with with banana you know
banana the Cavendish banana is just one
clonal
population so it's one
genotype so there's you know if a if a
fungal pathogen that's hyper virent
comes it can devastate the entire banana
uh crop industry in the entire world so
um what we're looking at uh like we want
to Target uh uh genes and
cannabis um it's definitely something
um
it's it's I guess it's traits that can
be deployed in not just one variety if
you get what I mean
like uh I don't know like give me two
different varieties you're thinking of
like let's go with papaya and Sour
Diesel slow what are the like chemo
types or
what are their properties I
mean each one would ex you know one
expresses more of a
kopling uh
mercing heavy dominant profile with
uh you know and the other one's more of
a
fruity I'd say has it's more of an
exotic fruit category I guess that's
that's you know in terms of the
constituents that are in there in terms
of the tpine profiles I think would
vary
right
um so like say for
example like a trait that's not even
involving like the you know the the
chemotype or anything that we want in
the background we can apply it to both
varieties like say for example like uh
the drought tolerance Gene that we're
looking
into
um it's something that we can
potentially apply to different varieties
you're not just like homing in on one
variety and then that's it and you can
also like say you have a a certain
variety that you want to use as breeding
stock you can just Target that one and
then do a breeding trial afterwards with
to try to generate something different
you know what I mean so so it sounds to
me like there's so there's two different
asss so like the last guy has more
consumer forward right like I want this
profile to taste like this right and
what you just spoke on is more of a I'm
a cultivator I have run you know right
business and I've got x amount to spend
on my crop this year and I need a
varietal that is trout resistant I need
to spend less on my nutrient inputs
right right so there so it's a lot more
complicated than that like I can't you
know if a grower comes to me and says I
want this specific flavor put it in this
variety that I have
um you wouldn't be able to do that with
with crisper really because it's so
complicated so
complex so I
mean so what I'm hearing is like it'd be
better you a use case for what your
technology does is better use use would
be on the a side where hey I want to be
mold resistant drought resistant
um because perhaps you're doing dry
farming you're in a part of the world
where you don't have much water um
that's historically where cannabis was
grown at scale
arguably um places where didn't have a
ton of water but had
enough you know um you c yeah I mean you
can Target the you know the the
chemotype and the flavor profile but
it's just that you know when you target
those genes involved with
that
um you're just not you're not going to
know what you're going to get until you
do it right yeah of course I mean so
here's even another question like let's
say you did all this you had varidol you
made a new papaya let's say I grabbed a
10 pack of masonic seeds Wilson
f2s I cross that to your genan edited or
your crisper edited varietal what
then then you have to empirically look
at the phenotype of the
progyny like you have to that but I'm
what I'm saying is like because you did
crisper on that let's say it's a
female is that Gene pull somehow limited
or is
it what what would become of that in
your
opinion would it just go back to a
generation you know
so so mutations are we adding destroying
the that's what I'm getting let's just
like imagine like we do a crisper edit
of one gene in a
variety and then so it's going to be
homozygous mutate mutation so then we
cross it right with what whatever you
want to cross it with um from what I've
uh learned about cannabis um certain
varieties are very heterozygous around
the you know on the entire genotype
right the genome yep y um so it's still
going to be something
new uh in the progy because of all that
background uh heteros zygosity yep right
yep so you're saying like you were
asking if there's a potential for there
like to be a bottlenecking of not just
bottlenecking or just you're we're
editing the gene so things are missing
by by Design right right in the progy
it's going to be you know the the
mutation that you put in and then the
the wild type mutation from the other
variety right so you can see what
happens when you do that maybe there's
like a you know Middle Ground where you
get the you know a mild effect of
whatever you're trying to make and then
the homozygous
one in the subsequent progeny will have
the
full uh phenotype that you're looking
for
um just like imagine that it's just just
just picture like just a random mutation
in a variety and you're just introducing
that variety into you
know and Crossing it with this other
Vari that you
have
um I think
um I don't know maybe some people have
the impression
that um when you target some like a one
gene or one
Target uh with
crisper it's like this really
complicated like it's going to change
the entire
genome and make something fixed right
but that's not really the case
especially when you just Target one
gene
um like to say for the like the PDS Gene
that I
showed
um that's going to be consistent
throughout every variety no matter what
the genetic background
because that Gene is so crucial for
chlorophyll pigment formation right so
but that that won't necessarily be the
case for every Gene that you
target sometimes you you mutate a gene
and then there's another Gene that's
very similar or related to it that will
compensate for its loss so you kind of
have to um after you edit a gene you
have to kind
of evaluate the phenotype
so you know it's not perfect right you
can't you you you can't really say like
oh okay um if I Target this Gene I know
exactly what's going to happen in the
subsequent
um uh generation right so do you think
you'll be able to edit a CBD synthes so
it doesn't produce any THC the way it
does
now
yes uh you can knock it out
um from what I I uh know about this the
CB synthes it's very
similar uh to the THC synas right
there's some homology there
so um so you you want to not you don't
want CBD synthes to make CB or to make
THC to what any zero THC correct oh you
you you you don't want any THC in the
specific variety is that what you're
correct I I want a CBD only variety
oh I have I have CBD varieties that are
about 40 to one the highest I've ever
seen right but anything more than 10%
CBD also has
THC right yeah that's that's
uh that's um certainly doable but it's
not going to be as simple as just
targeting and knocking out the
the CBD synthes Gene you'd have to go in
there and do precise edits on the amino
acids that are in the
protein um and you
know that way you can if you could you
could make 30% CBD varieties with zero
TC right exactly so that's going to
so that would take some time to kind of
figure out because
um since the CBD synthes enzyme is very
similar to the THC synthes one You' have
to do very precise edits in the sequence
so that it doesn't um kind of uh doesn't
use the precursor to those cannabinoids
to to direct it to to make THC that's
gonna be tricky but it's certainly
doable with crisper yeah I I i'
suspected it was but uh most of the
other canono do not produce m multiple
cannaboids the way syn
right um You can also
um potentially you could Target
a an enzyme that uh is up the pathway so
before you get to the CBD and the TC
synthesis um you can you can edit that
one and then I I do know that
um for CBD they're they uh in the tpine
biosynthesis pathways uh there's there's
a molecule that gets shunted to the
CBB um pathway so there there's
potential of doing it that way kind of
like
circumventing the THC pathway that way
right
so I was just looking at the hedes ofs
city of the moms that I have and they're
all around like one% to
1.37% one of them is 1.4 and that's the
tter Roa so sorry to interrupt uh Wade
had his hand up did you still have a
question Wade or did we move too far
away from
that oh I can't hear you oh there can
you hear me now yes sir yes okay
um one of the things that I understand
about crisper that I haven't heard you
say Arturo is that most genes
have more than one effect in the
organism in which they are found it's
pretty rare that a gene only does one
thing isn't that
correct right in most cases yeah it
might have multiple
functions um so that is one of the one
of the ways if you will that you explore
new territory right with organisms and
chis
technology thank you
right it's so sometimes um especially in
Plants you have you can have duplication
events so a gene will be
duplicated while you know the plant's
evolving or the organisms
evolving it or it gets you know the
duplication gets crossed over into a
different chromosome or something like
that and so you have the copy of that
original Gene and that the new copy um
evolves into something else right and
that new Gene might have a new whole new
function that benefits the plant or
produces a new
molecule so in a way um that's something
you can do with crisper as
well but in just a short as kind of a
shortcutting I
guess so the only thing you're cutting
off is
time
right oh Selena has has a
question yeah I was just curious um how
do we prove it out over time so you
talked about you know your end goal
being you know about benefiting patients
so let's say you know to Colin's point
we we grow it out um and that's another
piece of this that I'm curious about
anybody that wants to comment on this is
you know the actual culture that we're
growing the plant in you know so if it's
living soil or if it's in Coco like what
are we doing and and then looking at
that like proving out so let's say that
we're um Gene editing for a certain
expression to help you know certain
patients maybe mitigate certain um
symptoms that are going through like
cancer therapy for example how do we
prove it out over time like what could
those types of trial processes look like
and and how do we actually ultimately
know that when you're editing here it's
going to have this effect over here um
indefinitely and like you said too you
know you can you can edit over here but
it might have some um other effects that
we're not aware of so I'm wondering how
do you isolate that and how would you
prove it out the only way is human
trials yeah yeah yeah yeah so yeah with
respect to um you know editing a gene
and getting something completely
different um some effect or new
function you'd have to you can like
let's say for like a chemotype or things
like that you
can uh evaluate the the profile of those
chemicals of those molecules by hlc Mass
Spec um uh
experiments and kind of compare that to
your original uh wild type
plant and then um you know let's say you
produce a gene edited plant
that that uh it really overproduces this
certain molecule that's very beneficial
and that scientists are looking at as an
anti-cancer uh potential drug or
something
then you would pass that off to those
scientists you know that are more geared
towards like the medical field and they
would do some additional
research and then um So
eventually if if those preliminary um
experiments are uh's successful or
they're promising then they do the
trials
right uh medical trials which I don't
know anything about but how they're
conducted but um
yeah it would definitely be a very long
process but if the if it's a very
beneficial uh molecule and it has a lot
of potential I think it's
worthwhile I I just want to mention
Arturo I saw all your work on LinkedIn
the first day and uh I I thought it was
really really interesting uh I I I hope
you can move on to uh other traits that
you can uh
edit yeah uh we're considering um
several different
traits um and I definitely like to hear
from from you guys um for traits that
uh might be be
worthwhile to Target but I think a few
of us have uh maybe pondered this uh few
million million hours in our minds their
existence in our life oil yield oil
yield triome yield yeah I mean just
increasing the overall oil production in
the
plant I I would say is like should be
number one right because Mark I've seen
chrisper edited plants which uh I or or
maybe it was GMO I I forget which it was
but they were using the genes in tobacco
that make
tricomes and that made four times as
many tricomes I thought the heads each
individual head was a little bit smaller
but it it say it it also increased uh
tpine and conoid content so it's a step
in the right
direction I I have a question so we've
all you know we've seen really deeply in
photography the you know the
the you know the the capitate stock that
is
Created from the the actual
plant in the resin itself now I'm
wondering I'm just asking the question
of the group is there more room for more
and how would that even happen because
it seems like surface area would be the
constituent for allowing more to more at
least more resin to happen right it
seems oh but but each resin head is also
different sized depending on the variety
and the method grown so
uh yeah the the ones that I saw
definitely had by volume four times as
many because they were counted I I think
I you've seen that article on
LinkedIn
right right um also
um I think I mentioned before about the
uh this specific Gene in in tobacco
where they where they knocked it out and
increased the trackco density
um the C cannabis has a homologue in its
Genome of that specific
Gene so that could you know Not only
would it could potentially increase the
trackone density but it could have it
have the cannabis plant uh produce trom
on the
leaves but
um yeah um I do know that the you know
there's several genes involved in in the
triome formation so so those that's also
another another potential pathway that
we could Target um to kind of I I think
somebody mentioned a different type of
of triome like a bigger bulb or
something bulb is stocked yeah so is
that would that be more beneficial to
produce that instead of well it just has
a it has a big head so to just give you
a a quick little photo that can show you
this is a Astro Boy I grew some years
ago and it's just got the two kind it's
got the capitate stocked and it has the
cile which is kind of over here um it
doesn't have well the bulbous ones are
on this leaf and you can kind of see
them as blurry circles but they're not
really noticeable from a perspective of
hash making using mechanical sifting uh
even liquid nitrogen and getting
extremely cold using water extraction uh
these heads the capitate stock they just
come off the easiest and so to the
capitate cels the bulbous because they
don't have a stock although they do sit
on a single stpe cell you can't really
see it with the naked eye or even a
microscope uh you end up uh they don't
release as easy they don't come off and
what I noticed as a hash maker that when
I isolated them and and did get them off
uh they weren't good they were like not
what I would consider like highquality
inhalable uh Tricom heads um I I also
believe this is my own complete and
total Theory and it may be just cocky
Pock um but when I ran cultivars through
Dry sifting or wet washing that were CBD
dominant the yields were incredibly low
uh and I always thought that was because
a they were 50 plus percent bulbous
heads under a microscope I was thinking
that's where that CBD was uh in in those
uh in those
heads when and I did dry sift and water
hash uh with uh CBD varieties cuz we
developed the world's first CBD
varieties they uh they all consistently
yielded lower for
me yeah I mean obviously with a solvent
or CO2 or some other way you can get
those it was also kind of what led me to
that theory was the BHO Community
obviously I would I always had huge
interactions with the B ho o Community
people would be like you know I ran this
and got like a this is back in the dry
Days by the way we weren't running fresh
frozen yet people would be like oh I got
like a 133% yield when I made water hash
out of it but I got a 24% yield when I
made oil out of it so it's like oil wins
I'm doing oil I was like all right well
that's [ __ ] interesting and I try to
figure it out and it's kind of what led
me to looking for hash making cultivars
that had less of a vis visual production
of bulbus heads if I had my microscope
out and it was just stacks of of
capitates and cils I'd be like that's
the plant for me uh you know nine out of
10 times anyway and if it had a super
high percentage of bulbous heads I just
found that I didn't get the yields and
the yields that I did get just weren't
as juicy and as as melty as um the ones
I got from I I constantly selected four
as big a heads as possible but on the
end of a stem
yeah absolutely well I'll tell you
something and I've said it before and
I'm not blowing smoke up his ass I've
never smoked anything stronger than
skunkman Sam's skunk number one pure dry
sip that [ __ ] like it almost knocked me
out of my Consciousness I almost left my
body and I remember trying very hard I
was like I can't pass out at Sam's house
I better not [ __ ] myself I hope I don't
puke like these were legitimate thoughts
going through my head when he first
invited me over and was like here have a
bong RP and he's definitely trying to
destroy me like this was Sam's nature
back then 1,000% he loaded that [ __ ]
thing up fired it up with a couple of
matches he was looking for utter and
complete destruction Sher probably had a
camera hidden under the cushion to
record it all once I [ __ ] shimmed and
had a seizure on his uh uh living room
floor you give me some bit if you give
me some Bitcoin I won't put it public
and I'll tell you the day after I was at
his house the first time I was at the
milk V at with at my booth and I don't
know if you remember this there was a
guy next to me selling selfemployed hemp
ployed t-shirts he was a dude from
America I can't remember where but Sam
stopped by he was like hey you want to
smoke some hash yeah of course gave me
another rip I took a big rip this guy
took a rip and this guy was no
lightweight this guy hit the floor so
hard and shook for like five to eight
seconds before he got up oh yeah Selena
this was like happening for real he got
back up and he was pale white and he
looked at Sam and he was like I want you
to do that to this guy and I remember
Sam was like no you can't do that to him
and I a couple of my buddies were like
did you hear what Sam said dude that was
legendary like back in the day this is
like 20 some odd years ago that was like
that meant something to me I was like I
felt like I earned a stripe on my belt
because uh and after that I will tell
you that I I cannot count how many
people I knocked unconscious with bubble
hash at the Cannabis Cup it was a weird
time where yeah there was oil but oil
was made by a weird guy with dirty
fingernails in his garage and no one
ever got to see the process and it was
just like the 70s and the 80s oil guys
it came in a bottle cap and sometimes
they didn't even take the plastic out it
wasn't good this was way before BHO days
hit and that people were like excited
about oil so really the strongest you
could get unless you were skunkman Sam
was like some shitty you know single
screen Farmers hash that was
like honey oil in the 70s from
Afghanistan it was rare
potent it was rare here you know the
fact that someone went there and knew
what they were doing and filtered that
through probably with like activated
charcoal or something to like clean that
color out I don't know maybe they used
cold solvents and they had some of the
tricks but in in in Manitoba in the 70s
and 80s like you got some hash you saw
hash from those countries um but
generally there was nothing like bubble
has available to the masses and bubble
has and BHO basically came out within a
couple of months of one another so
suddenly but bubble hash is what really
changed the world because people still
didn't know about the static Tech so
they weren't able to create the dry SI
as as high quality as you and I know how
to make no they that's true and you're
the anomaly of growing exceptional flour
that process works really only best with
exceptional flower and as you use flow
that's less than exceptional the process
seems less and less magical and less
exceptional whereas when you do it with
like you what you were growing in your
Greenhouse holy [ __ ] dude the amount of
heads stuck to the hand the purity of
those heads was absolutely insane that
changed the game dude because I don't
even think I took macro photographs of
pure bubble hash before those pure dry
sift hash shots water has changed the
game CU you could get it to
Bubble absolutely it definitely did I
won't say that it didn't but this
picture the first time I shared it in
2008 nobody could [ __ ] believe it
dude they were just like what the actual
[ __ ] and that's some proper skunkman Sam
skunk number one like pure dry sift tiny
little bit of stalks he probably only
did like three or four passes you can
tell yeah it's well cured exactly
because otherwise instead of handling
grapes you hand to handle oil that was
smear and it's
horrible yeah no I agree but that that
photo was a game changer for people no
one would stop thinking about the
process for a decade the whole the photo
was definitely a part of how people
eventually kind of got on to it and
figured it out with guys like uh tan and
and M who was one of the first to really
sort of show it with the uh parchment
wrapped around the DVD case uh d420 K
was a part of it it was a whole group of
people just playing around and focusing
and and enjoying these these discoveries
and I wonder sometimes you know that was
an accidental Discovery these sometimes
these accidental discoveries are just
the greatest thing that you could
possibly ask for I'll never forget was
it an accidental Discovery right but the
guy who was actually doing the work uh
with his hand that it was the the the
high quality tricomes were sticking to
his hand from static Tech he didn't even
realize it
I saw it I realized it and I went back
to Amsterdam and wham bam I had it
working really good really fast well
I'll tell you how that changed my
perspective when you finally broke down
and showed me that and I hope I didn't
bug you too much for you to do so
because I always tried to show respect
um no I I wanted to tell you just in
case I
died I want to make sure somebody would
pass it on well I deeply appreciate to
being that guy dude because that day in
your house was a mindblower and when I
saw that I I just started going down
this Rabbit Hole I was like oh my God
like there are great secrets out there
that people hold that because of it it
change it it can change the way you live
if you knew that secret and it really
opened me up to this like that there's
way more going on in the world that
people could possibly understand it's
not until you learn one of these very
very simple secrets that really nobody
knows that you realize like holy [ __ ]
like this is crazy there's definitely
great secrets out there you know this is
kind of metaphorically that are just if
we could discover them it would change
everything it would change our
conversations it would change you know
our understanding and it would change
and pivot our Pathways it certainly
changed mind we're learning about the
canabo pretty good I think it's the
tping canono combination that will
really be interesting the next uh step
well that and stuff like crisper and uh
double haids I mean scientific breeding
will lead the future uh doesn't mean
everybody has to smoke a scientifically
bread plant uh but uh it will be The
Cutting Edge well and you know what as
you say it will be The Cutting Edge it
may very well be but today The Cutting
Edge is [ __ ] Edgar Compton in his
backyard [ __ ] tossing seeds down like
a [ __ ] telling everyone it's
cliche man but just [ __ ] do it that
is The Cutting Edge today no matter what
anyone says put those flavors against
anything anyone's done with a crisper or
any other
scientific uh uh process and they don't
they just don't hold up right now so for
now Edgar you
win Ed and because of it we win how many
seeds do you produce in a
year you're muted Edgar so so any so
like I'm allocated to so much space and
like when I do a pollination you know
it's just gung-ho let it let it hit
everything so it's it's it's it's not
like you know on on it's a lot of seeds
it's a lot of seeds I don't have a
number I don't know how many plants I
have at any given moment I'm I just
always I'm always popping always cloning
uh so it's a lot of seeds it's a lot of
seeds I I don't have a number for it I
honestly don't I made an average of five
or 10 million a year that's that's
massive I I probably don't even for
decades I don't probably make a million
a year it's I'm only I only do it in my
backyard so we'll probably make like uh
every year we probably make like
250,000 to 500,000 or something like
that just like I gave a lot away and I
sold them all for less than 10 cents
beautiful I'm yeah well when you're
growing five
million
yeah yeah that I I I kind of take from
that Credo where it's all like I I have
500,000 seeds I don't mind selling them
for you know you know less than a buck
of seed sometimes you know and let alone
the free seed day where it's all like I
divy up a thousand packages of my own
gear that I make and I encourage others
to do the same and we just like all team
up and we just give away seeds and we
revolve a day around it so I take a a
page out of both of those and you know
respects to the ogs for sure I used to
walk in the Million Man March in uh
Amsterdam and I would take a kilo or two
kilos of my skunk seeds and hand them
out to anybody that wanted them along
the way and all the time I would hear
people in Dutch saying oh these can't be
good they must be hen up seeds and uh
I'd answer them no no they're skunk
number one I'm the skunk man and you
just got handed a billion for the seed
have fun that's dope that's super cool
what do you got there Mojave uh I just
wanted to show you guys this plant since
we were talking about breeding and stuff
um so Jim Goodwin gave me some uh Mel
Frank gave me some flour couple years
ago five years ago or so this Cambodian
which I really enjoyed it was really
nice someone had given it to him and he
trusted the source it was pretty
interesting unique flower very
equatorial the way the the plant grew um
and uh anyway I liked out smoking it and
then he he had it tested and it turned
out it was a one to one uh CBD THC but
it was a one to one with a really
interesting kind of narrow Leaf profile
it wasn't your typical harlean ACDC
Afghan based one to one so it was a
really nice refreshing high and anyway
so I got some seeds out of the flow and
then he gave me some more seeds and then
I popped them and I got this one that I
selected what I really liked but then I
had one little sport that shot off that
had this m this mutation that would go
either fully albino or half and half or
it would go just really beautiful Mosaic
which really I like as just an
ornamental plant um but the cool thing
is that it's a mutation but it's only in
the sport right it's only in the
offshoot so I had cut it off and um put
it in a glass of water and just was
leaving there just kind of just looking
at it on my desk for a couple weeks and
then I was on a call with Rob and ATN
and this other plant scientist I'm like
oh [ __ ] I probably should have cloned
that huh and and then quickly right
after the call I went and dipped it in
some and and I cloned it and it made it
after weeks of just sitting in water so
now I have this mutation which
consistently will show this weird
variegation and Mosaic and albinism but
it's only in this sport so I have I have
this cloned in other versions that are
just completely green um but anyway I
just love it just because for as an
ornamental plant or as an interesting
just what cannabis can do and how many
plants come from sports like if in the
wine industry you know all the penino
ggio and all the white penino plants are
Pino Noir that stopped producing pigment
or that particular pigment and became a
new mutation which became a new clone
which eventually was reproduced millions
and millions and millions of times so
that's just the fun part of breeding and
selection where you get little weird
little mutations well looks like a HP
vroid but
not yeah no no exactly it's not no it's
a mosaic I mean it reminds me of like a
cadium or other ornamental plants and
stuff like that but yeah maybe maybe the
virus is mosaic virus causing the spot
the spark the leaves that are not white
or green but mixed yeah exactly and the
the thing is when I made the Clones the
ones that had too much uh too yellow
they just don't root because there's no
chlorophyll they just wi in the
propagator so you can only when you're
collecting your next Generation every
time you got to collect one that has a
little bit like these ones on top here
and a little green and a little yellow
but if I collected from this Branch it
would just go back to just being green
again so or or possibly going back to
being green anyway it's just it's a yeah
funny and it's also um Sam you might
like this it's yellow stem halfway
yellow stem so you can see on the line
it's yellow stem on one side and then
green on the other as that's pretty cool
for Dr Bo
very cool we got five more minutes till
our 4H hour mark got to thank everyone
for coming and chilling and sharing if
there's anything else anyone wants to
say in the last five minutes they can
put their hand up or or they can just
hash Church tile Shout at the top of
their lungs over the other person and
just [ __ ] push through and just get
your get get what you need to say out I
just want to say something really quick
I just want to say thank you to all of
you for growing this beautiful plant and
for sharing the seed seeds and for those
of you that are watching please share as
many seeds as you possibly can I know
the spirit of this plant is with us all
and I think it's just really cool that
um we're just so inspired to share so
free seed day I feel like we should do
that every day um but just thank you
guys so much for all their work and and
all your Blood Sweat and Tears and
love uh Marcus check your uh the the
chat there I put uh Dr Ortega's email in
there if you want to add in for future P
Church discussions and Arturo thank you
for coming
and uh spreading your uh your your truth
about uh you know crisper and what
you're working on and being very
transparent uh I brought you along
because I I I knew you would do a great
job and I thank you for uh you know
coming in and taking it on the chin and
uh being a good ethical scientist that
you are love and appreciation sir thank
you thank you and thanks to everybody
for your questions and your interest and
for letting me uh join you guys in this
conversation um I'd certainly like to
come back and and hear more from from
all of you
so awesome yeah no thank you for coming
for sure thanks Masonic for making it
out and chatting with us dude we'll have
to get you back as well [ __ ] every
anytime you're doing a new release or
you know you got something new on the go
which sounds like every minute of every
day uh just [ __ ] come by and and
share with us man everyone love to have
you next time if you do come in try to
come in on a computer it makes it easier
then you can also open up the YouTube uh
live because people were asking
questions and talking about your packs
in there and uh I think you would have
done quite well to uh engage in the chat
while you weren't talking in this
particular chat so we'll get you on
again for sure thanks everyone for
coming out you know I really appreciate
everyone and uh I appreciate all the
people we have 265 people we got almost
everyone that was watching live back
over the course of the last couple of
hours so people do appreciate the
conversation um I love it I like the
idea of just uh having everyone open to
dialogue if I saw one thing during the
covid-19 lockdowns was that the division
and the shutting down of a part of the
conversation in any subject is
absolutely um detrimental to the to the
benefit of of humans it's best for us to
always be able to have these
conversations whatever they are you may
not agree with them but uh it's it's
about learning and I said it earlier in
chat you know um without free will you
know you you you can't have just good
with free will Free Will involves both
good and bad uh and it's only really our
perspective that makes them one or the
other they're a very thin veil they live
very close together and uh the bottom
line is is you can't have free will
without both of them so I appreciate the
conversation today and the dialogue and
everyone coming and hanging out from uh
Wade laughter [ __ ] and love you buddy
I'm just so pleased and happy that you
come and share your Sunday mornings with
us I know it can't always be easy I know
just having a a small broken arm I'm
uncomfortable sitting here so for the
discomfort that you have to experience
while you share your time with us it
means a lot to me uh thank you very much
uh Dr Mark always a pleasure thanks for
coming out we'll get you into some
deeper conversations uh this next next
week I'm sure Mojave thanks for showing
your plans and Colin for inviting Edgar
obviously uh Brian again we're going to
get you talking one of these times more
than just about your dogs I want to hear
I think that you and Edgar would have
had a great back and forth dialogue in
regards to the different Cult of ours
you guys have a lot of similarities
going on and I think if you guys don't
know each other you should definitely
get in touch with this with each other
yeah yeah I'm gonna hook you guys up for
sure because uh well his email is is is
also I believe it's on the main email I
want you guys to all have access to one
another uh that's another great part of
hash Church being able to reach out to
anyone that's on the panel at any given
time for any reason that's that's that's
the way that I see it so definitely
reach out to one another if you guys
have an interest and anytime I have
someone that wants to reach out to one
of you from the chat I always hook it up
via email as well so ET as always thanks
for bringing in uh uro that was awesome
really appreciated the conversation I
don't know much about crisper I know
about the ooh crisper like isn't that
the GMO thing but I didn't I've never
heard it be discussed by someone like
you Arturo so I appreciate your patience
with us uh and uh your empathy that
you're coming from with this process I
totally respect people's visions of
being slightly afraid of it and as they
are with AI and any other change I
remember when we first came out with
rosin people said we were ruining the
resin we were heating it up it's way too
hot you're destroying all the turps it's
like really because rosin's [ __ ]
awesome that's all I want to say uh
skunkman Sam love you buddy super Stoke
that you could make it here today and be
able to uh engage in the conversation
you are truly one of the Elders of this
community and you've helped birth so
much of so much of what all of us are
doing uh and I think it's important to
respect and acknowledge that uh when our
elders are alive not after they've
passed so every day I'll say it from the
Treetops dude thank you so much for
being you and just being [ __ ] the the
Cannabis Warrior that you've been
probably most of your life at least
according to the stories that your wife
has told me so thank you everybody
Selena Colin the whole group we're going
to we're going to drop now but next week
we'll be gathering again come join us we
appreciate you and uh May the full melt
bless your bowl sooner than later
because if it doesn't I'll be [ __ ]
sad for you peace
out hell yeah