all right hey welcome everybody I think
this is it welcome everybody to hash
Church 3.0 the bubble hash Rasen episode
yes the episode will start with me
looking around mildly baffled and
confused got some people in the room
right now I'm just gonna drop the link
doing things a little bit differently
today as we have a whole new panel of
people that I have never invited in so
let's start admitting them into the room
what do you say boys boom boom boom look
at that nice I like this new method of
having you guys sitting in the waiting
room and all I have to do is click admit
oh let's admit the og of OG shall we you
guys ready to share the room with skunk
man Sam skunk man Sam in the his a
what's going on Sam nothin much I just
saw that note from you but 10 minutes
ago so here I am beautiful well thank
you man today we're gonna sort of focus
on hash production for the early part of
the show probably mostly bubble but
we'll talk about some traditional
methods and some mechanical screen
separations and whatnot maybe even a
little bit of hand rub and whatnot I
figured you'd be a great sort of OG to
be in the room because I actually
invited a whole new fresh panel of
people it will get to introducing them
here in about a minute and and they all
came from Instagram so there's sort of
all up and coming and some are fairly
already substantiate it they have brands
they're doing you know they're they're
well on their never been on Instagram I
know you haven't which is unbelievably
awesome but you don't need to go on
Instagram Sam your yeah I had to show
you look clone that's also pretty
tripped out that's that's very tripped
out so let's introduce some of our
panelists here today we've got what
we'll start with with Goldilocks he's at
the top of the actually let me see if
that's correct yes you are you are at
the
the queue here bro we know each other
from Instagram briefly having some
conversations and you were one of our
customers at Whistler technology for a
WT 300 getting into a little bit more of
the commercial aspect of water hash and
I want to have that discussion as well
once you kind of you know introduce
yourself what not I want to get into
that talk of is there a way the same way
you know I guess the argument is can we
grow cannabis large-scale and still keep
the quality there skunkman sam says yes
only because he's done it before so now
the next question is can we still keep
the quality there with hash if we bump
up our amounts and we're no longer doing
little hands third batches but we're
rocking 50 60 70 80 kilos of biomass at
a time so introduce yourself brother I'm
here in Sacramento been making hash for
a good amount of years now we're kind of
more so focused on rosin now just
because we've been doing such a large
batch but like you said we are doing
large batches with the new whisper check
equipment I agree with Sam that we can
do a large batch and keep the quality
just the same as it was with small batch
so I think it's just a matter of using
the right equipment having the right the
right people running it really yeah well
you guys aren't just you guys are right
go ahead Sam and the right priorities
quality always has to come over quality
period absolutely well the I definitely
grew that whatever material we're using
is definitely the number one factor try
to only use stuff that's are gonna come
out good and as long as we're doing that
I have no no issues with our actually
but haven't come out yeah the SOPs are
important to and it's why I've always
found that the the most amazing hash
makers that I've met over the years have
had a background in cooking and as a
chef
chefs really understand the SOPs of a
kitchen there's food safe you know you
don't want to cut with this knife with
the chicken and then cut a
we're here with the fruit and these
simple very simple little things seem to
get the mind of a chef prepared for
following steps and not missing those
steps and I find that you know to quote
Sam which is a hilarious quote because I
certainly don't think of them as a
religious man cleanliness is godliness
and it's great if you're using the great
material and you're doing everything
kind of you know you've got the good
tools but if there's someone in there
you know throwing that SOP off by not
following simple simple little rules I
mean one that blew me away was back in
the day when the when alec from Essie
labs told me that the oil cos oil
company had failed their shatter failed
ecoli testing and that's like basically
that's some guy who's made the hash and
gone and taken a [ __ ] and not washed his
hands properly and come back and dealt
with the product and it's just I mean
that's disgusting right off the bat as
generally we are as human beings and
that's why the SOPs these standard
operating procedures become so very very
important and I'm sure you noticed when
you picked up a 300 WT 300 it came with
SOPs out the yin-yang like that thing
yeah I think it did I don't I don't
think we right I don't think I used any
of this refusal big I think we just kind
of the Whistler guys came down we ran it
once with them and I think we just kind
of winged it from there you know kind of
figured out what worked both for us but
I will say the best hash guys that I
have right now on the crew do have
kitchen experience they all the ones
that made it through like the and we're
still working there are all kitchen have
kitchen experience and they they
definitely I think would be right about
that that definitely helps that's
actually untouched by human hands and I
have monkeys doing it here yeah never
past tagged never touched hash tag never
touched for sure so thanks Goldilocks in
the house I think we're gonna move on
over to Bryan for 10 I'm gonna get him
to introduce himself let him let us know
where he's coming from
can you hear me I can hear you brother
okay cool
well my name is Bryan I own best friend
farms
and I'm coming out of me in these days
the last few years
feedback from over a decade in the
Emerald triangle and I've actually focus
on classic cat form so I'm thinking that
we get you know doing some fresh seat or
some fresh frozen into sea but
ultimately anything stick you were
balling up very strict regiment with
living soil organics that's I'm really
flower first and just really enjoying
the beautiful campus flower and it all
comes from that it's really about the
flower the new hash platform in the
classic technique or way I'm approaching
it is really about personal appreciation
for that type of that form of hash from
geez my dad was making hash for
Christmas parties back in the 70s
starting in Maine so I guess it's kind
of like second gen and I aware of the
other processes I pressed for I had an
extra rosin Pro younger guy named have
hash that was pressing some really
high-end rosin probably five four to
five years ago but I've shifted back to
the classic form and I don't know just
attention paid to the resin more than
the tax so I guess it's a little
different and and I'm looking forward to
the new tech coming but I've just really
we started with dry resin Stephen first
so the the hash maker who's only a year
in under me painting which is it was a
chef that's a new day to click up I that
in him he's like an art as a graphic
artist chef yeah and we'll just call him
Tom and he's really just paid the
closest attention and then learning the
resin quality through me helping him to
see it we breed half the string and try
to feature her company's work as well
new strains so yeah I don't know I'm
also I mentioned that I kind of want to
pay attention to the 40-plus crowd not
to exclude the younger folks but I'm
pretty this year myself and it's funny
because the younger folks are turning a
real eye almost sometimes more so on the
classic hash form with really wanting to
learn about it as far as temple ball as
far as even some we press some blonde
but again
really focus on full mil and the bubble
hashing just really turned things for us
and going with it keeping it raw and
trying to just just keep the resin as
good as we can and anyway that's where
I'm at
well I love that you're focusing on the
living soil and the flower first I mean
we a lot of you won't know this but I
had from the original hash Church 3.0
photo I posted on Instagram about three
weeks ago I had already planned the show
but in the post I mentioned hey and if
you know any great hash makers here on
Instagram I'd love to have you guys
tag those names and that's where
everyone who's going to be on the show
today came from they all got tagged
there was actually 48 to 49 people who
got tagged and I ended up doing a free
video with about 20 plus of you which
was a really great video and you'll
probably notice today as we go through
this that you will hear a lot of people
say exactly what Brian just said in
regards to the soils the living soil
that's sort of the bacteria you know
living microbials and and just that
living biome in the soil to produce a
resident well yeah to allow that plant
to express itself in a way that that
maybe it won't express itself being
grown with salt newts so we're
definitely not you know we're not gonna
spend the show shooting on a salt and
you'd grow but I'd definitely always you
know put it put another gold star behind
each person's name as a hash maker and a
hash smoker if I know that that person
is focused on living soils and they're
actually you know focused on proper
cultivars that are that are going to be
producing hashish in a way that's a
little bit more special than your
average you know like I said another
extra little gold star right there so
thanks for sharing brother all the way
oh I do all the way out in Maine we're
gonna get back to you for sure
true hash your hash company bro is in
the house how you doing up I'm good are
you can you hear me
we can hear you great man you sound
perfect sweet my name is Dakota owner of
true hash Co we are based out of Agra
California you know we mainly focus on
just selecting cultivars that are resin
rich cultivars you know I'm not much of
a rosin boy you know I've always
preferred smoking melt you know over the
years and mugs you know the way of the
roots these days and you know we just
try and stay true to what we know and
what we've learned from you know
sometimes it doesn't always work out you
know you have your strains that you know
make more of a full spectrum run or pull
and certain microns that aren't as melty
as others and we just really try and
focus on cultivars that pull heavy and
you know you're 90 to 120 range and
there's really that was like our main
goal this season was just finding very
resin rich cultivars just a lot of less
work and the whole go around makes life
a lot easier especially we can predict
produce a very quality know ya know it's
a very important journey but a lot of
people you know there's two schools of
people and I want to be very careful
because I certainly don't want to get
into offending anyone but there and I
said it when when bubble hash first came
out people were blown away by it they
didn't it was so new they thought it was
fake they thought it was a scam and the
only people who saw the magic in it
where the people who just happened to
have super high quality hash producing
cultivars that they didn't even know
everyone thinks they have great herb but
I'm telling you back in the day I would
sell bags to everyone and super randos
would hit me back up from like the
middle of Texas or whatever and send me
a picture of like full melt and be like
is this good like why does it look wet
like I'm not sure if I did it right and
I was just like yeah you did it right
bro and so there's these two schools of
thought the person who made six star
bubble hash the first time they ever
made bubble hash generally those guys
are hash makers they're not looking to
create a cultivar that they're gonna
make into hash so that they can take it
and squish it into rosin I don't want to
offend people whose trip is making rosin
rosin is an amazing product that it's
awesome I've always just questioned look
if you
and get down this pathway and find that
six star you may be happy with just that
now there's an enormous amount of cool
things we're gonna talk about with rosin
that it that goes beyond and above just
extractions with Rackham's and covert
extracts you're gonna get in here later
records is in the room right now
and talk about you know there THCA
separations and they're they're Terps
slurries and they're you know all of
these different fractions and how they
can be done and that's awesome and
amazing but for myself I won't lie I
have a special place in my heart as well
I'm a hash smoker I smoked it for so
many years straight I haven't smoked a
joint in 19 years if you can imagine I
haven't smoked a joint of cannabis in 19
years
and so that was hash that basically
ruined joints for for me I'm gonna move
on and we're gonna talk to taste of
Cascadia Scott is in the house how you
doing brother man thanks for having me
on absolutely we're happy to have you
once you give everyone a little
background again we're kind of doing a
similar thing that we did in the
preacher CH video you know just a 3 a 5
a 5 minute or a little more as no
problem we'll go through the list and
then oh damn it Bobby's waiting to get
in Bobby Bobby damn it Bobby
late as usual so yeah I started out
probably like mid-2000s just watching
hashes with homies out in the hills of
Portland
or the country of Portland I should say
and you know we were back then we were
drying on cardboard that was the tech
because it was a desiccant not her
natural desiccant you know been washing
year or four years everything from you
know old ball getting a little feedback
from Bobby cool there we go
yeah used to manage a big garden a big
old OMP garden and used to process all
their trim so you know was processing
probably like 10 to 20 pounds of dry
trim back in the day and really
developed everything from dry trim to
fresh frozen
yeah most recently been doing everything
single source like Dakota was saying
basically searching out those good
cultivars that only do good for six star
they crush everything out for both melt
flavor too high the yield and finish
time so that's another good thing is if
it's done in 56 or around 56 days it
definitely helps out because you know
time is money yeah most recently I also
started a six star society a clothing
company to kind of focus on gear to wear
while washing so you know stuff it
doesn't pill up stuff that doesn't hold
on to dog hair
yeah and just focusing on that lifestyle
that's what I love I love like you said
I love smoking hash and it's my passion
I love the plant I love that Scott I
love that you're doing a clothing line
called 6 star that's that's great and I
love the idea of of just producing you
know it's and it should go for growers
as well you know I have a hard time
watching people go into grow rooms and
and finger-fuck their plants and sees
the plants and then and walk by them
with cotton shirts and I'm a macro
photographer so I'm going into that
plant in a way that nobody can possibly
imagine and when I see all their heads
gone like just all it is is stalks like
this like in the plan there's no heads
left because they brush the plant so
many times or the heads are all broken
or worse there's just like large fibers
cotton in like synthetic rayon and I'm
just like out of the hash that's what
that's not even taking us into
beneficial bugs which consume all the
bad bugs and then turn them into [ __ ]
balls on your plants so yeah well even
fans I mean extra agitation from fans
that can create more degradation or more
need for the trichome to produce a waxy
head less melty you know so yeah and and
Eric nug shots is a good buddy of mine
so it's always been helpful to reference
talk to him like hey have you seen what
have you seen you know blah blah blah
just just chat pastor and chat trichomes
with him because it's super awesome to
be able to see his his work and to see
that try come on
a macro level and understand it on on
its level and it's you know on like math
like super small level yeah super big
shout-out to Eric for sure taking it to
the next level as a hash maker being a
macro photographer for me was essential
learning about all these things I mean I
did have an advantage of having Sam in
my corner and being able to ask him
questions and and be a mentor to me but
at the same time when I started taking
photographs and seeing you know a cystal
of hair or a capitate stock trichome or
a bulbous trichome or all these other
sort of anomalies that exist in the
plant i really started looking at the
plant quite differently and yeah it's
helped shape my perspective as a hash
maker just from being a photographer so
yeah good point on that and good to have
someone like Eric who's really at the
top of the game right now taking some of
the most beautiful macro photographs
that's amazing have ever really been
seen so shout out to Eric thanks Scott
let's get to our sideways boys who
aren't sideways anymore they were
sideways they came in like this and it
was kind of fun I was like all right
cool those guys are so cool they could
come in upside-down for all I care
there's two of us I was trying to get it
horizontal you know I totally feel I
knew exactly where you were coming from
dude but thank you that heavy ice and
great lake grease in the house these
guys are a big inspiration to me I love
what they're doing we went into more
personal stories last time which was
really we might get into that a little
bit later that sort of was the you know
you get the profound aspect of well how
are these guys so passionate like what
led them to to have to find the best and
to you know want to grow all their own
inputs and want to start producing their
own food so why don't you guys do a
little introduction heavy ice and great
lake grease in the house first well we
we focus on natural growing and we like
we like to think of going beyond just
the term organics
because it's kind of such a broad term
nowadays if you can imagine you know
what what exactly does organic mean and
with the amount of products that are
labeled organic nowadays and things like
that it's hard to really it's hard to
compare that to using the things that we
have around us outside in nature the the
local herbs the local the local plants
the local mushrooms and we can we can
use these things to to feed the plants
and feed the soil and it's really hard
to compare the two so we really like to
just we really focus on beyond organics
and we have definitely found with our
resin and the few people that we know
and there's a lot of other people that
we don't know out there that are growing
this way that it really produces amazing
amazing resin an amazing amazing hash
and we we love sun-grown
resin that's another thing that we've
noticed in it just seems like the
sun-grown resin is comparatively from
from my experience like tur pure and
like I would usually I've gotten like
really transparent hash we've gotten
transparent hash from indoor resin but a
lot of times when I was washing into our
resin it was it was it was melt it was
coming out clean but it wasn't
necessarily coming out fully transparent
so that that's one way so just just
certain things we love about sun-grown
resin and we love hash
we will Rosen the stuff that don't melt
but
we weave that's our focus is on the
resin I think for both of us Erin will
probably mention this that our our
passion for growing actually really
started on wanting to produce really
really good hash and we couldn't really
find it and couldn't find material that
produced like really really good hash so
it's like you got a got to grow it where
did you guys get exposed to really good
hash was it an Instagram thing where you
would go online and see or were you
prior to that like on a website or
something well I saw I mean in in my
high school days I'm I mean I'm half his
age but in my high school days I you
know I I was I got hash and it was
bubble hash but at what you know it was
it was brick hash and it was you know it
would clear dome but it was not melts
you know and I always loved it and I
always got the High Times magazines so I
was always really passionate about resin
and we would grope like hide plants in
my backyard and stuff like that and like
I was always really passionate about the
resin and the the cannabis plant and it
was it was it was definitely Instagram
and your YouTube channel and a few other
YouTube channels that exposed me to full
melt I can't remember specifically the
first the first you know thing that I
saw but in my case I think it was your
YouTube channel I was already a medical
patient and I had smoked way more flour
than I ever wanted to smoke in my entire
life trying to get the dose I needed and
I had you know the BHO when it showed up
and I did a little bit of that for a
while and like the bigger dose but
didn't like the side effects of poorly
made petrochemical extracts and
a heavy thing weren't you during this
time Aaron like wasn't this during your
getting off Pharma and losing all your
weight and literally switching your life
like a hundred and eighty degrees yeah
it was a complete turnaround at the time
with everything my diet and you know
getting out and exercising more and the
cannabis and everything almost looking
for opiate effects from from cannabis
right I mean that's why the extracts
were so appealing initially because you
know they hit a lot harder than you know
taking ten minutes to smoke a joint or
something like that but yeah it was just
uh it was really watching your YouTube
channel while I was buying all the
flowers in the BHO and I had a caregiver
at the time too that never even gave me
one trichome of material but I was I
kept telling him yeah I want to make
hash like you can I can buy an ounce of
flowers from you but I'm not really
gonna do me any good so just just from
watching you and I I knew that I had to
grow in order to make hash cuz nobody
was gonna give me material and I I even
tried to buy material trim and things
like that and everybody was charging me
way too much so I finally had to grown
this well I'll tell you if you guys
aren't following them already as it
should follow all of these guys will
drop all the instagram names at one
point in time but I've been watching a
heavy eyesore for some time it's just
been a joy to watch him like literally
like just go from the sort of non
heaviest person you could possibly be
like to like the head he went from like
a 25 micron know melt sulfur thing to of
living soil 90 microns full melt clear
dome watching the reflection of himself
while he puffs it in the ball I like it
dude I like your story and I think you
should yeah and it's been like what like
how many years has it been it doesn't
seem like it's been that long no I think
I think my first grow was like 2014 or
20 2014 I think maybe 2013 we will get
into a little bit more of what Great
Lakes was talking about at one point in
time once we've introduced everyone and
that's
regards to this beyond organics and of
course with our regular panelists
dragonfly earth medicine that's that's
their whole trip is to produce your
inputs because for people that are kind
of wondering well what what is Beyond
Organic Beyond Organic is not opening up
an organic farm and then draining the
aquifers for the entire surrounding
neighborhood because you didn't plan to
catch water the winter before producing
your inputs on your farm so you have to
put less in to get more out is what
organic living soil is all about and big
AG is all about putting more inputs from
outside of your farm on each year and
getting less out each year so these are
the sort of things that were that we're
discussing and of course with with Sam
in the room we all know Sam's history
he's probably you know grown a lot more
cannabis than all of us combined
probably even just for one or two of his
his years of his life he has grown an
enormous amount of cannabis and I think
as a hash maker if you can have that
relationship where you understand how to
grow cannabis and how to choose vinos
and how to start sort of looking for
things that you know like Sam didn't
just take cultivars and start making
hash and looking for one that works
Sam was breeding cannabis to make a
product that works in in the end product
like hash so that's that is also you
know I look up to that a great deal
I grew but I've been you know I never
really grew on the level that I was able
to make an effect in you know producing
hash producing cultivars which I also
want to talk about at one point in time
I want us all to share our favorite hash
producing cultivars very important
information for everyone and I know
people want to hold on to their tips and
little things like this as this industry
becomes more more and more real but
sharing is caring and not not telling
someone a cultivar that produces hash
because you are greedy and a douchebag
as well greedy and douchebaggery so we
won't be doing that today on hash Church
we'll be sharing our information
especially when it comes to cultivars
and we're gonna move over to two other
awesome dudes will sauce winery and
resin ranch extraction welcome gentlemen
welcome welcome
you guys are muted so I need that button
and one him go first this time yeah no
problem dude good to see you look thanks
for having us
how's it going it's going great man this
is the hash episode of hash Church and
we're talking about hash so I'm pretty
happy yeah so uh ya know I got my start
in Seattle and we're kind of learn to
grow and make hash up there about seven
eight years ago now and it's been rockin
my own kind of single source hash for a
while and moved down to California about
two years ago and started a prop 64
recreational brand under fully melted
and been running big 30 kilo runs of
material through a proprietary machine
we've made totally like bagless system
and running that for the past couple
months and been and they're calling
clean melt out of it yeah like that I
want to hear more about that for sure
you know we've been we've been trying
our hardest definitely to produce you
know good melt we entered some Melton in
Emerald cup and been putting some melt
out on the market as well as good job
better dry we do all fresh frozen so
luckily I have a cultivation partner up
in southern Humboldt and we grow all
greenhouse in two different places and
like braceland and kind of salmon Creek
area and then we put all the greenhouse
whole plant fresh frozen all toward our
ash material for fully melted beautiful
that's what's up I want to hear more
about your machine as well down the road
I'm sure that's another conversation
yeah yeah absolutely well you know what
he's got going on yeah I keep it pretty
low-key just we've been you know doing a
lot of testing and a lot of you know
just other things to kind of push the
hash game other than just a big machine
washing a lot like post-production
changes and how we just treat the hatch
and stuff like that so it's been
interesting beautiful well like I said
we definitely will have a conversation
about that because
this is this is where we're at right now
we're at the innovation part and you
know there has not been an enormous
amount of innovation in water extraction
almost since the beginning it's still
very much like water and ice and and
cannabis and filtering it through you
know something whether you're using
gravity like Reinhardt Delft use back in
the 90s or whether you you know or Saudi
Sands water extraction secret from back
in the day or whether you're using a bag
system or whether you're using a you
know like a delta separation frenchie
unit or even a Whistler Tek WT 300
there's been a few other people who have
I'm very in a very unique position in
all of this because generally if someone
creates a machine or invents a new way
of doing it
I'd say nine out of ten of those people
email me and we're gonna have and want
to have a discussion about it and I'm
always super down in sign NDA's and
whatnot and just I'm really excited
about maintaining the melt aspect of
hash while running commercial amounts
you know being able to get to a point
where there should be no reason why we
can't scale this up to a point where the
integrity of the wash is not affected I
mean it's not it's not rocket science
you know resin glands sink in water due
to their due to their being affected by
gravity because your biggest factor that
I see in I've seen and I think he can
attest to is the cleanliness of the
material going in is kind of the biggest
factor and worked up and humbled Mendo
with a lot of outdoor farms that can be
very difficult definitely a struggle and
yeah I mean coming from comma education
background as an economics
I've always been focused on like how can
we make bubble hash like more reach the
economies of scale so that we can get
you know most of the market hopefully
smoking like good clean solvent less
residue or at least get them access to
it so if they want to choose it it's
there for them yeah it's not an
exorbitant price like you know $180 a
gram or Belle you know after taxes that
hits home that was before tax week with
Johnny B and I on
last putt two puffs when did Wednesdays
ago we bought a gram of rosin it was it
was organically grown from Whistler and
turned into bubble hash in the WT 300
and then pressed into rosin but 180
dollars a gram and [ __ ] was hurtin I
mean my god I was bummed out with the
black market prices prohibition and that
was generally created based on someone
doing 10 years in prison so I'm not
quite sure how these prices are
according to the legal market but
hopefully they they you know they they
figure it out and I'm sure with people
like yourself and with with our our own
company Entwistle technologies and
others working on getting this scale
problem fixed so you can still pull that
quality that purity because that's
really what it's about it's not about
quality about purity when you make water
hash the purity has already been
produced the the grower and the genetics
did that we don't make pure our quality
we just purify it we unveil what is or
isn't there and that's what we do is
hash makers and that's why for me I've
always appreciated the humble hash maker
the one that understands his his or her
place is that you know sure yeah I have
some skills and I'm doing a good job but
my the timeline of me making hash is
very short compared to the timeline of
someone growing a three-month crop in a
greenhouse oh my god can you imagine
that the the [ __ ] that the grower had to
deal with over three months and then I
come in and I process it all and I post
it on Instagram and everyone's like oh
yeah man yeah see what he did wow what
an amazing it's like come on as hash
makers we got to stay humble I feel like
all hash makers gotta at least try their
hand at growing to so they know they
know the the realities of what that
means and also I think it really
enlightens kind of your whole aspect of
how to treat material and you know how
to process better how to not you're far
more better on what to do I had a same
idea for people who drove I thought
everyone who drove a car should be
forced to drive a moped or a motorcycle
for the first year of their license so
they can be expose
to the dangers of driving a car
cluelessly you know because when you're
in a car you feel this protection and
when someone's just giving you your trim
in your bud you're protected it's like
oh yeah like I got all this coming in
over here you know the whole reason
bubbleman became a name was not only
because I had access to make water hash
before most people but because I had
access to incredible quality flour had I
not had that access people would not
have thought what they thought about me
and and I noticed often it was oh yeah
he's got the quality he's got the
quality it's like well yeah so I have a
good nose I'm able to find quality that
certainly doesn't mean my [ __ ] doesn't
stink and it certainly doesn't mean that
I'm better at this than anyone else and
the whole purpose of teaching people how
to make water hash over the years was
that anyone could do it as well as
anyone now there is no special oh you're
mat you're a magician you know no one
can make it as well as you can man the
first couple of years into making water
hash my mum who was like worked for the
police at the time came over to my house
and I was like I want you to make a
batch of bubble hash and she like mixed
it up and did a five gallon batch I gave
her the material and we called it
Pauly's melt because he came out six
star
my mom made six star the first time she
ever made hash and she was like the
Straight ease of the straight e it's in
the genes exactly the plant genomes my
little spiel since I have a completely
different come up story than this guy we
just live close together become good
friends over the last few years do some
work together but uh I kind of started
out just doing little little girls in
Wisconsin in my basement and I was open
blast and stuff and watching phone to
you on YouTube and it was like [ __ ] you
can dab water hash and dry sift like
what's this you know and actually the
first hash that I ever dabbed that was
melty was dry sift forgot to mention
that last time I got my come up actually
as a dry sniff guy
Kuban gave me a shout-out here on hash
Church few years back after I gave him
some dry sifted emerald cup 2015 and
that's kind of really what opened the
doors for me
and you know one to emerald cups the
next year and we had a little problem
with coming up dirty after and got those
taken away but it was all just a big
learning lesson because year after that
at the Mendo hideout we ended up getting
DM DM certification so he completely
turned things around at that spot not
that we were really being dirty we were
only spraying organic at the time which
you know everybody was there's no shame
in learning and I appreciate being
honest because people are so fake and
shallow these days they want to post the
fake beautiful Instagram photo with none
of the reality being lost over a third
of our crop to russet lights that year
refreshing to hear you be honest men you
know and I kind of the naturals
transition I had been making water hash
too and running a big a big farm dry
sieve just kind of was a lot harder to
scale up and kind of keep up with so I
kind of just transitioned over to the
water hash and then naturally fell into
the rosin as a byproduct of our runs
that weren't full melt well the first
the first the first melt I ever smoked
funny enough was also sift and it was in
1995 and Amsterdam my first cannabis cup
and someone somehow I ended up smoking a
little bowl of skunkman sands dry sift
and I'll never forget Rob Clark standing
on the stairs of this Thai restaurant
that we were at do you remember the Thai
restaurant Sam with all the lady boys as
waitresses it's no it's not it's not but
this was this was a very strange
Thai food restaurant that had all lady
boys as as the as the waitresses and it
was just a place you could smoke hash in
Amsterdam and thought people are cool we
don't give a [ __ ] with people choose
with with their lifestyles and it was
great food and so I'm hitting this bowl
on the stairs of this restaurant and I
hear Rob say if it don't bubble it ain't
worth the trouble and I watched the hash
melt through the screen and drip down
the stem of the pipe making me cry a
little bit because I was like knowing I
wasn't
gonna be smoking that hash that made it
all the way down to the to the Ruhr
downstem for for over three years almost
four years it was three I tried to
recreate that and I tried to make that
and it wasn't until getting turned on to
water extraction that I actually made my
own product that melted and bubbled into
a liquid and when I first posted my
company bubble bags fresh headies and
the and I and I chose to use the logo or
the the motto if it don't bubble it
ain't worth the trouble and that's
really I had seen Sam and bumped into
him and in particular back there and he
was very very strong-willed in mind it
he was almost like a professor that was
just so above it's like if you were the
best kid in the class maybe the
professor's gonna talk to you but if you
were like the middle kid in the class
the professor wasn't talking to you so
with me running into Cuban I had my like
oh this is Cuban he's the tricep guy I
got out you know gift him some hash and
see what he thinks and they have him
then chase me down and be like bro do
you have any idea what you even have
here you know and I honestly had no clue
I know my well imagine Sam's been
smoking that for about 35 to 40 guy but
now we're all noobs yeah we're all work
what what's really gonna change the
industry across the board I mean once
you've got great quality of genetics
that makes hash easy gives a good yield
and you're growing it organically or
biodynamically or super or whatever way
then what's going to change the field is
automated processing so you'll be able
to make the highest-quality
continuous operation so no fun for
batches you just produce it by the ton a
day and now Sam you'd be the guy to ask
because you know I'm not I'm I would I
would say from what I've seen I'm
probably the closest to Cubans
cleanliness of dry sift is you're gonna
get without being Cuban do you think
that that is scalable to that point oh I
it's capable by cleanliness I presume
you're talking about where the resin
heads is 99.9 ever you know we get you
know it's a 99.9 you know it's like he
truly it's just resin heads
[Music]
I hope he's called it 99.999% on Sam's
and keep in mind like no one had seen
this product until I photographed a
product you wouldn't tell me you gotta
you gotta try Sam's dry oh just me it
was the strongest thing I've ever tried
in my life and because there's a
difference Kuban makes incredible drive
shaft and he's got a great breeder Sam's
unique because he lived in all the house
she's producing countries he collected
seeds he bred those seeds in the hash
producing cultivars he grew those seeds
he made hash that's the [ __ ] Holy
Grail right there if you're doing that
you are gold enough a lot of varieties
which didn't really pan out because they
yielded poor you know was it not started
what can I say I say I say I'm the first
guy to say that I kind of got lucky in
the sense that the first thing I ever
tried sifting was an incredible dry sift
strain I'll still say that five six
years later so I I don't think I would
have gotten to where I got if I hadn't
got kind of lucky that first try
everybody should contribute the
varieties but they make incredible
drysuit because that's a resource that
the whole world could actually use also
number one DNA Sleestak and actually a
DNA strain it was a training day yeah it
was a training day I can't remember what
the cross is on that and uh yeah I grew
up about 20 seeds and found one that I
liked and it just worked and I ended up
losing that but
III like dry sip from plants with you
drop I sure and then get the res no you
just look at it funny and they fall off
yeah pretty much
you touch it and you're done you're also
growing all biodynamic organics living
soil so yeah keep them doing that
forever yeah yeah I've uh you know
that's pretty much myself to I'm trying
to do as much single source as I can
there's I have like two or three other
farms that I'll wash for and they they
all are KNF you know it's closed loop as
they can kind of style not getting
noticed that bigger plant so the same
clone but grown twelve feet tall has
bigger residents on it then that same
plant you know six inches tall yeah I
don't know how many people have actually
grown twelve footers on this panel raise
your hand well I will say this Sam yes
and no I have noticed that in certain
cultivars in like Europe and North
America
however I've seen quite the opposite on
cultivars like the Mullen B&amp;B madness
grown in Australia grown 12 to 18 feet
you know twelve feet tall and 18 feet
wide from the mall a madman and all the
best heads were in the 25 to 45 micron
range which was more healed son yeah I
couldn't wrap my head around it it was
just like Markus's that be if they grow
that same plant six inches tall the
resolute heads will be a little bit
smaller because you know when we were
doing huge plants up at the hideout my
my upper bag pulled like the 150s and
stuff I had really never pulled a 150
bag
they had hash in it until we we got up
there and it was you know my the
majority of my ash was 115-120 always
was up there growing those huge plants
well when I first went to visit breeder
Steve in Lugano around 2000 2001
and I've made hash with his material it
was they worth 12 foot tall but they
were pretty big plants that he was
growing in his hoop houses some of them
were definitely like 7 and 8 feet those
plants I produced melt from the 190 bag
all the way to the 25 micron bag every
single grade melted into a liquid and I
photographed it while it was wet I just
that they were all wet on a piece of
paper and I kind of wrote each micron
and that photo was published in redeye
magazine in 2002 I believe so that blew
my mind I've seen it since but not a lot
that's another you know thing that I
like how do we grow cultivars cuz look
we're all looking for the melt well
sometimes we can grow melt between the
90 and the 120 but we don't see it above
the 120 and we don't see it may be below
the 73 you know big yields come in on
those 45 micron bags and it always has
that very oily very specific taste like
a 45 micron I swear I could pick out on
and I've done it like many many times
from any cultivar made by any hash maker
you put them in front of me the 45 is
just so specific and if you ever back in
the day when we were puffing with a
flame or a lighter just gently soif ting
what I notice about the 45 is that it
would take flame it would light on fire
when you were smoking a bowl of it I
haven't jeez I haven't smoked any hash
in a long time I don't think we've been
puffing too many bowls even I saw ganja
Gill puffs and bulls maybe I'll join
join the panel and puffs and bowls we're
gonna introduce at that spliff that kind
of got the handshaking a little nice
well we're gonna introduce a Simpson is
in the house he's next up to give us a
little background on who he is and what
he's been doing with uh with bubble hash
howdy y'all can you hear me welcome dude
we can hear you perfect all right on
awesome there was so much talked about I
wanted to jump in but I didn't want to
be rude yeah so my name is Adam I am
just a hash maker I'm stoked beyond here
get let's get weird with some hash talk
I am in I'm in Arcadia California
I should probably shout out but the
gardener that I work with
in her nature on Instagram that's in dot
her dot nature and yeah so I mean you're
talking about it earlier it's always
good to give the gardener the the credit
that they also deserve um yeah I have so
much to talk about yeah what do you want
to talk about let's do it
just tell us kind of how you got into it
what's your you know what your
techniques are what you're kind of doing
just a little kind of bio on on you and
and yeah but from there what we're gonna
do is we've got so many good points that
everyone's brought up from like I want
to talk about pre-washing material I
want to talk about drying desiccants
versus freeze dryer so we're gonna get
into it deep but just give a little bio
we've still got Bobby and Gil and
Rakim's to go through it's almost 10
o'clock we probably got until 10:30 11
before I switch it over into the rosin
talk so yeah just just a little
introduction Brown was good well I mean
first of all like back in 2009 ish
probably it was the first time I ever
made hash 2008/2009 ish and to think to
be on a panel with a bunch of folks and
that that I can learn from so easily
is amazing I I don't know I'll always
give rosin makers [ __ ] even though I
love rosin but I think that I should
bring that up like a lot of people
haven't experienced the days of buying
moldy hash and dispensed in stores or
just having really really wet hash and
not knowing why or how how to dry it
properly and yeah I don't know
go on take I take full responsibility
because when I first started making
water hash bubble hash I was like taking
wet bubble and like rolling it into
these Frenchie cannoli balls and people
loved it they loved it it was like
shimmering beautiful you know but I was
doing it all wet I only did it for a
couple years before I realized the
massive mistake that I had made and I
feel like I
spent the next 10 to 15 years trying to
tell people not to do that and seeing so
much beautiful hash it was such a shame
to see someone who had great herb who
ran it perfectly and then took it and
rat and rolled it up all wet and of
course we're gonna get into the
importance of breaking water hash up
whether you're sieving it or whether
you're micro planing it or whether
you're freeze drying it you need to get
the moisture out of your hash this is
fairly important and of course if you're
doing fresh frozen there is a moisture
percentage that holds in the wax
membrane and if you're a macro
photography you understand that because
those balls those glands look so
beautiful like a like a water balloon
stretched to its maximum when it's fresh
and when it's dry they tend to dry out
and create ripples like a like a raisin
and so these are the sort of differences
you know dry that's why they say dry
sifting is not a misnomer it's ideal to
have your material dry sure you can do
it with fresh frozen and some sort of
like dry ice material but to me that is
like the way to produce the most
contaminated low-grade hash that you
could possibly make I think a lot of
people don't realize that the water is
very important in water hash and as
water hash makers it's really one of the
things that make us look like we're
doing a really great job because of that
purity 99.9 percent if you think it's
easy try to do it without the water it's
there's a very few percentage of people
who can really you know in the numbers
in in the amount still produce that kind
of that kind of product so why don't we
introduce dammit Bobby into the room
he's gonna he's on mute right now he'll
share a little bit with us and then
we'll go through ganja Gil and Rackham
and then we'll just have a nice little
maybe a 45 minute to an hour long
conversation about all these little
points that different people made up so
try not to lose your your your your
point if you've if you've heard someone
say something sometimes it's a good idea
to write a little note but okay Bobby
and we just jump in if for some reason
it feels like like talking yeah once Gil
and Rackham and Bobby have introduced
themselves it's going to
free-for-all jump in conversation so at
least three introduced go ahead Bobby
I've got a couple seconds left here
before I take a dub give me a moment
well I guess we all better take a DAB
then as my good brethren D 420k would
say bong ripped mother lovers Bobby just
telling us to hang on guys I gotta take
it down gangster concentrated ex in the
house give thanks brother
for producing the fire all day long on
those strawberry-banana
so good right my name is Chris I go by
damn it Bobby on Instagram I'm a hash
maker originally from Texas I live in
Portland Oregon Vancouver Washington
area now originally started making hash
in battleground Washington for a little
company got in 502 here and then
switched to working for archive down in
Portland Oregon and selling all of our
stuff through the dispensary their
archives so everything is is hands
stirred it's all single source you know
we use all our water they're all our Oh
ice it's a it's a cold environment that
we're working in they're full
you know I run ice extract bag so bag
stack everything from 45 to 220 in there
the 70 to 90 the 120 everything to
isolate and then we mix back for rosin
grades if we need to and separate
everything for full melt to do to do
full melt drops here you know along the
road that's what's up we mentioned you
mentioned that in the day in the chat
the other day definitely in a very good
position if you are washing for archive
a good friend of mine Fletch he's been
doing this a long time he really knows
how to grow and he really knows how to
find those fee knows everything he grows
is just [ __ ] fire yeah submission I
wash at Burnside collective Garden Inn
organ so that's the farm where it all
goes down and then all the material the
flour the hash the seeds everything gets
sold it archived in Portland the
dispensary
yeah and Fletcher is you know he's a big
part of everything he's done tons of
breeding the limb until he said to talk
about strains that you really like to
wash that that's one of the posts and
all aliases linen peel it washes
extremely well you don't really ever
find that's hurting profile the wash is
really well it does you know five
percent and three and a half of that
sits in the 90 through 119 so you're
collecting a lot of full Mel let me wash
that one I did was twenty thousand in
some change like twenty thousand and 85
grams hand stir between a few buckets
and the thing dumps you know 598 raised
for us and you know everything you're
looking at about a eighteen percent
yield on that material what is that five
percent fresh frozen yeah it's close to
eighteen to twenty there it always
depends this is the second time I've run
this material here and of course the
materials tends to get better and better
every time as you try and get better
when you grow the people know but for
those that don't because it might be a
place where you get confused fresh
frozen weighs about one quarter to one
fifth of the same material dry there are
cultivars that tend to go towards the
one fifth and there are cultivars that
tend to go to the one fourth is would
that be accurate for it for you Sam that
you've seen over the years a quarter to
a fifth of weight I'm not sure what
exactly you're asking me well I'm just
like from a hash making perspective if
we take a thousand grams of fresh frozen
it's going to be between 200 and 250
grams dried [ __ ] oh I do you know I
don't have a lot of experience making
fresh frozen because the resin that I
like the best is actually dried for a
couple weeks
turd for a couple of months and then
then I would stick it in a walking for
and use a centrifugal brush machine on
it to make traditional drives so I I
didn't really have French products that
were frozen and I don't think I really
have the experience right well thank you
for your honesty I appreciate it all the
other hash makers were going like this
so I know I'm on point for that so it's
it and that's what he was saying 5%
fresh frozen you're gonna end right
applying that by about four maybe a
little bit fresh frozen material we take
a lot of time to buck the material down
you know without touching the material
you know and putting it into very small
freezer bags and freezing you know tons
of these little freezer bags to make
sure that there's no pressure on the
material at all that you know that it's
sitting there with as you know as little
pressure at all you know to keep the
heads intact so whenever we do go to
wash them you don't fill out one huge
freezer bag full of material that's got
a ton of weight you know you're
offloading a bunch of really small bags
so that between 500 and maybe a thousand
grams great thank you for sharing that
sorry I've been trying to figure out
getting the dank Duchess in here I think
she's trying to connect now and she's
into I know I can fit like 40 people in
here at a time it's just kind of a new
one that I haven't done a ton of
churches with so I'm not the best at
doing troubleshooting especially while
I'm trying to moderate the church but
hopefully she'll make it in on her audio
at least and we'll move forward from
down over there she is good you made it
man she'd been trying for an hour one
hour she's been trying to get into the
room so welcome Duchess thank Duchess in
the house we've got we've just got two
more people to introduce so your your
timing is actually spectacular because
we have gone to gill left and we have
Rackham's left and then we're gonna get
into a nice hash conversation which will
sort of leach into our rosin
conversation here in the next couple
hours so not just in the house what's
that no I'm sorry that was me doing for
mother disposition okay no problem no
problem well we're gonna introduce kanji
Gill he's gonna give us a little lowdown
on where
that what he's been doing so give it a
go bro oh we got you muted there you go
look cool hopefully y'all can hear me
josh and kelly from dragonfly we're
letting me know i was glitching out a
little bit so i tried to move closer to
my router so hopefully this is smooth
but rather in the forest is that where
your router is a delight router you know
Trinity County style you know how it
goes yeah that's it's how it uh good
welcome thank you very much Marcus good
morning to everybody the whole panel and
all the listeners feel super blessed to
be with you all right now and yeah just
my journeys kind of a spiritual journey
once I met gondya I was captivated by it
and I just couldn't get enough of it I
mean I just followed it everywhere it's
led me know to the ends of the earth the
other side of the country or whatever I
took you know that's that's what I did I
called it blimey
I like to consider myself a gun to
Shepherd you know taking care of the
plant for the people well it's a deeper
meaning for me personally you know and
when all the licensing and all the
permitting went on you know I'm no
triangle I should say that I'm up in
Humboldt County Trinity County area it's
ganja country up there you know the
baker the candlestick maker their
mothers their grandmothers their
children everyone's involved in ganja
here and when the licensing and the
permanent aim really rocked the culture
it was it was kind of devastating for
most and I was always a small-time guy
doing my small-time thing but I was just
watching my community kind of fall apart
and go to shambles and watching people
put all their money on the line and you
know dough was kind of troubling times
and I kind of asked Don you're like what
do I do
what do I want out of it you know and I
just told me to focus on myself as I
always had and kind of just do my own
thing you know that's always what's the
meaningful for me personally so that's
what led me to living soil and
cultivating outside all this awesome
connections I made you know I stopped
growing
doors for personal reasons not knocking
the indoor growers seeing my best
friends are indoor growers but for me
personally I got into resin farming
which led to Sun grown cannabis which
led to living soil you know the idea of
bringing dirt from outside into your
indoor grow was like always oxymoronic
to me it's like we always tried to keep
everything so clean and so sterile in an
indoor environment so it just didn't
make sense to me you know I was reading
all teeming with microbes and all those
books and I was like you know I just
need to be outside I need to be growing
outside so I got a little spot started
build soil started going out and good
luck the national forest and grabbing
stuff that was there for me that was a
big issue as well is just keeping the
overall cost down you know my time to me
is just my time so if it doesn't cost me
anything to go to a cannabis I'm like I
don't feel like you could ever lose you
know there's just so much to be gained
it's always worth the gamble so I got
really into living soil and found the
teachings of the lane doctor relating
them and kind of got into the microscope
thing for a little bit like it's really
not my thing but it was just cool to
like kind of learn it and have it as a
tool and then I kind of found josh and
kelly from DraganFlyer medicine shout
out to them so much love for them big
time yeah deep love and gratitude for
them I really do consider them family
and uh you know I just kind of met them
right at a really good pivotal point and
like everything just started to kind of
line up and then I kind of asked the
universe for more I was like I just want
to keep doing my ganja thing and I want
it to like be enough for me what do I do
and I don't know everyone was buying
freeze dryers and I was never into the
BHO everyone was doing that up here and
it just never really like interested me
personally so thankfully I never went
down that route but uh I got a freeze
dryer and got back into ash making you
know I no longer had to microplane and
air dry so I could step up production
and it just went really
well you know washing really great resin
strains that under the full Sun um in
living soil I've been building for over
six years and my yields were great the
Terps were great it was just super
fulfilling you know it really truly was
like I was able to do it all myself
completely from seed to harvest to
processing I do it all entirely myself
packaging all of it I stuffed much
freezers myself I washed it all myself
press it all myself I do it all because
to me I really truly love the process
every step of it I often think about
hiring help I need help my back is
broken but then I'd often go back to I
only grow so much and every barrel that
I let someone else wash is one less
barrel that I can wash and I really
truly just cherish the time that I get
to spend with the animals every moment
of it
teaches me so much about myself teaches
me a lot about makes sense I'd like for
me personally know the world's a crazy
place it's scary once you leave your
house you leave your property you go out
there you know it's tough it's tough on
a person like me so being able to stay
home and my god your sanctuary with my
lady and just work with the point and
spend intimate time with the plant
it's beyond valuable to me it's just
like it's priceless and to me this this
way of life sadly is kind of ending and
maybe this we will be the last
generation you know and I'm clinging to
that personally I'm holding on to that
[ __ ] for dear life I'm not trying to let
go we're all you're making me want to
move back to the hill really bad right
now I love love the passion man I love
the passion and the honesty and the
truth in your voice I you know for me
cannabis is also a guiding light I
almost feel like it's been my shepherd
you know leading leading me
for the last 25 to 30 years and what a
what a what a beautiful thing to be a
part of the last 30 almost 20 23 years
now of just sharing how to make hash
with people my favorite thing back in
the day was to travel anywhere and
everywhere and show people this hash
making and watch for their eyebrows
because when I lifted that 73 bag the
eyebrows always went up I called it the
eyebrow raise so here comes the 73 bag
this was during a time when no one had
had I had seen this and didn't no one
understood this this was like 1999 you
know where that it's just it was so new
and such an amazing thing to be a part
of and I definitely am very happy for
the people that came before me that got
me to be able to be in the place that I
was at the time that I was to sort of
just be able to be you know one of the
steps in the ladder of this incredible
hashed journey I'll tell you something
dude and I'll let you know when we did a
legends of hash years ago we celebrated
the legend when we do a legends of hash
you have to understand Sam and I when we
started these parties it wasn't to
celebrate ourselves we don't see
ourselves as legends obviously Sam's a
legend but that's a different story we
were celebrating true legends so one
year we celebrated the garden of khufu
and in the garden of couture man that
was the spot let me see if I have it
here I think I do know that was the
figure of fun let's see what we got here
is this garden of couture here we go
look at that just happen to have it
right here and I did not organize that
this is literally just sitting in the
left drawer of my office and so we
celebrated the garden of the floor in
the 12th century Cairo the favorite
meeting place for hashish connoisseurs
was the legendary gardens of Khufu
Islamic law forbade the drinking of wine
but many Muslims especially the Sufis
were great proponents of hashish eating
and its legality was hotly debated by
Islamic courts by the 14th century
conservative Muslim leaders won out and
came down hard by destroying Kapoor's
gardens burning surrounding hash fields
and starving out the farmers shops and
cafes selling hashish were closed and
the owners hunted down and killed
but how sheesh use can
you'd hope I see a smile on your face
there guilt
hashish use continued in 1378 the
frustrated Cairo government forced all
known hashish shooters users into the
main square where soldiers wrenched out
their teeth with pliers a decade later
hashish eating still thrived in Egypt as
it had become too much a part of the
Arab way of life to be forsaken may the
gardens of Khufu serve as an ancient
reminder that cannabis prohibition never
succeed we're not going anywhere Gil
trust me I love that thanks for sharing
anyway it's gonna manifest and change
and alter and as long as you're in your
little spot you know steering your
vehicle it's not gonna change we're in
charge of this okay not then we have
been for a long time since before the
gardens of before and when they're
killing us and they're wrenching out our
teeth and we're still here
that says a lot to me three men agreed
the plant creates so much passion you
know what I mean it just like I don't
know it just exudes it you know I just
feel like there is fortunately really
great people surrounding it and it's
just weird times right now where
babylons got it scripts on it so it's
just some things going down but like you
said you just gotta persevere hold on to
it and you know not much has changed man
my life's only gotten better I'll tell
everyone that man every year is my best
year including this year you know every
year and you know you just love Ganju I
love you back then it's okay for it to
change and alter how it looks you know
we just have to make sure we don't fall
for the illusion because from my
perspective you know I'm never gonna
fight against access and there's all
this access that's now coming into play
that a lot of us aren't really overly
stoked on but then I know people that
are so it's like we continue with our
civil disobedience we continue to push
the envelope and get exactly what we
and how we want it and we do that by
growing great cannabis by learning about
biodynamic organic you know regenerative
sustainable growing by learning about
you know these different solvent was
techniques for extracting the resins and
creating these wonderfully pure products
and if we just keep doing that
it's it'll work itself out it's you know
in California legalization is cut off
access though to a large number of
people unfortunately well that's why the
civil disobedience will be required
there now right now it's civil do some
disobedience again is exactly right yeah
that's how we got what we wanted I'll
stop to my horn right now and say I kind
of gave them the finger it's handed the
permit back and we're just still rocking
it out the way we have in the past
civil disobedience I tell big companies
all the time you know don't harsh out on
civil disobedience it's literally what
made it possible for you to be in
business right now so you know support
those grassroots you know don't be
annoyed when you see someone like well
why is that guy doing it illegally if I
have to get a license oh gee frontliner
who's continuing to make things better
for your future licenses and seeing us
you don't want to do it because you want
to protect everything you have over here
you should just shut your face and maybe
give them a little support that's the
way I see it anyway one good thing in
California is it you can grow six plants
everybody can that's one bit it's a
small thing you can grow more than that
grow way more than people aren't
embracing that six plant thing honestly
I don't you do I thought I would see
more people doing their six plants and
they're you listen listen growing
cannabis takes a lot of work and it's
not easy and if it was so easy you'd see
everyone growing all their food too and
making all their clothes and it's like
listen they do yeah it's an endless
amount of things with cannabis it's kind
of we've always gotten lost in because
there is this very spiritual connection
to it you know I agreed with everything
Gil said earlier and felt very much the
same way about cannabis
I you know I have a very strong
connection to it yet at the same time
you know I always hear people will
Johnny be he's a proponent of getting
everyone to grow I'm like John you
understand that not everyone can grow
like it's not possible like I know that
I can't grow right now because the way
I'm busy and work and travel I end up
starting my garden I get it up to veg I
flip the lights and then I'm like bye
sweetie I have to go on a 10-day trip
and now for ten days my poor wife who
has three children and runs an entire
household is like watering these plants
that are taking more and more and more
like every single day as they as they
fatten up and flour out so I don't have
the time to do it personally as I as I
do what I'm doing I know a lot of people
who are sick and who are unable to
physically you know take care of a
garden I love the fact that we can grow
plants in Canada and everyone that can
absolutely should on the flip side of
that we need to have access available to
people through shops and dispensaries
and online where they can also access it
from there and pretty much that's what
we have right now you should be able to
do this over your freakin smartphone or
wherever you are in the world what's
that buy cannabis no water your plants
Oh water your plants change you might
check whatever you need to do I mean I
have an acre
it was totally automated watering
everything yeah well your skunk man Sam
and I'm just the lowly Bubble men don't
share pastor Sam you're smart to do that
if you want it I'm even smarter because
what my plan is is to buy a 60 foot
greenhouse put it on the rock behind my
house get some agriculture students from
the University of British Columbia or
wherever and just bring them down to be
like look I want half of it food I
wanted all living soils and organics I
want half of it herb here's the
cultivars that I want and kind of let
them have fun and do that while I do all
of the other stuff that I'm doing
because let me tell you I am busy that's
not my problem ation well that's that's
my
Automation exactly I like people
Automation I like people a it's giving
them an opportunity and B it's giving
it's giving me an opportunity as well
how fun would it be to be in a
greenhouse full of plants right now for
hash search right behind my house like
that I have a 99 plant license federal I
have a federal 99 plant license that I
can grow 99 plants on my property I can
possess on my property 10 pounds of
extracts I'm allowed to have 10 pounds
of extracts at my house which is like
I'll tell you sometimes I need a little
bit more so it's a bit rough I'm joking
obviously who the [ __ ] needs 10 pounds
of extract at their house that's
ridiculous unless you're like the
Harborside dispensary or something don't
need 10 pounds of foot bubble hat that's
your house but listen we're gonna
continue on we're gonna introduce
Rackham's and then we're gonna introduce
the dank Duchess so Rackham's what's up
buddy oh [ __ ] hey cuz everybody doing
good man we're doing good how are you
doing great it's kind of hard to follow
conjugals backstory but nonetheless
my name's Rackham's Nick for short from
the Northern California area Sierra
Mountains originally from the Bay Area
but now I reside in the Sierra Mountains
Sur Sierra Foothills
alongside choo-choo hash but um Rackham
started about three two and a half three
years ago and it won't go into a Long
Beach story essentially it started for
lack of better words is that ode to my
wife's father who recently passed away
in Indonesia for hashish anti stick I'm
using prison there for 18 plus years I'm
didn't get to see a light of day
essentially but yeah then having not
really a grower I am uh my fiancee wife
is a grower she's been going for ten
plus years we do have single source but
right now I'm working with clients such
as Ridge Boys and the real Ridge Boys
and doing my best to isolate as much
tick star as possible if not the best
quality that I could possibly come pie
with whether it's a single source or a
now
side source and either make that into
the best rosin I can and or the best
hash that can be juice that's pretty
much about it
beautiful well thank you confirming
thank you for confirming what I just
said to ganja Gil so 18 years never saw
the light of day died in prison you guys
did not turn your backs on cannabis you
embraced cannabis and as an ode to him
started the Rackham's account yeah
that's amazing dude that's that's
literally exactly what I was reading in
the gardens of couture they can rip out
our teeth and they can kill us but
they're not gonna stop us you know hash
hash making used to be these big
countries that were like a mighty oak
tree but now hash makers have blades of
grass everywhere covering the earth and
good luck mowing us all down definitely
all right cool well we'll finish off
with dank Dutchess and then we'll get
into a little conversation she can give
us a little introduction I'm not sure if
she's actually frozen now like if that
was some bad timing but are you there
Duchess oh my goodness imagine if she
got bumped I feel so bad for her she
took she tried for an hour to get in
here so she just got bumped I guess
we'll have to come back you are on mute
so maybe try to unmute that oh she said
her phone died all right well I get that
[ __ ] plugged in you know what when she
gets in here we'll let her introduce
herself and in the meantime I wanted to
start talking about you know one of the
good things of as a hash maker if you're
looking to really for that cleanliness
is godliness if you're looking for that
chef sop when you get your material get
to know it dump it out look at it filter
through it you know see what you've got
that you're working through rather than
just through the bag and if it's coming
from an outdoor grow it's never a bad
idea even some of the greenhouses to pre
wash your material just really I do it
in not a very very cold water I do it in
a sort of room-temperature water
I'll put material and I'll have my
rubber gloves on and I'll gently just
sort of massage the material releasing
large little little dusty stones and the
many pebbles you'd be amazed at what can
get stuck on the plant from an outdoor
grow giving it that little pre-wash
filtering out those that heavy sediment
that will just contaminate your hash and
look like little black dots in your hash
if you if you get the microscope out
afterwards so are you guys doing that on
the regular when you see material come
in that seems dirty and dusty are you
guys but realize it's really uh pre-wash
fresh frozen it doesn't really work I've
tried but uh when I was up at the men
that I doubt we were doing ten thousand
we've done experimented with the
pre-wash great at harvest pre-wash let
it hang drift dry and then into the
freezers and that actually worked pretty
well I can't really say I can't really
say I did enough experimenting with it
to say we got lost any yield or anything
like that was an interesting thing
ash was still good it was clean we pre
pre wash all our material when we're
harvesting it and then and then shake it
off and drip dry it and in the drying
rooms and then air dry it you're right I
just wanted to say that if it's fresh
material you're gonna have a really hard
time knowing the quality of that
material after it's frozen you know so
be there prepping you know try to try to
be able to prep that material for the
gardener or you know work out something
because that's not want to know what's
in the freezer before it's all frozen
together I definitely love the idea of
and we do it every time of like very
carefully observing all the material and
actually this year we've been breaking
the material right down into the into
the bags but yeah I like you said pretty
much looking at every flower you know a
piece of flower that goes in there
before it goes in the bag I like to look
at the material with a jeweler's loupe
first phone if I'm like actually gonna
wash other people's material beyond that
I
see it look at with like a 30 X or 15 X
see what's really there see the size the
shape how many how dense back in the day
in Vancouver it was so bad you know
living in the Pacific Northwest and
people thinking they can grow Afghan
ease up here and they just they attract
powdery mildew like like you can't
possibly imagine unless you live in the
PAF Pacific Northwest and then you know
exactly how they attract a powdery
mildew but back in the day I first
started making bubble someone gave me
the most beautiful material and I ran it
through my bags and the hash was just
like white and it was like full mount
six star and I took a small dab of it
and it was just sulfur like a heads of
matches and that's when I learned about
defender and all of these sulfur burner
products and how badly they contaminate
glandular trichomes and then of course
people would say things to me like oh
well we only do that in flat in fetch it
doesn't happen in flower and then I'm
like yeah but you understand like
glandular trichomes of presence on the
plant from the time the first two true
leaves come out of the seedling which is
the called the epicotyl comes in after
the coddle of dawn which are those two
round leaves the first two true leaves
the epicotyl if you photograph the
leaves they're covered in bulbous photo
bulbous trichomes from like 1 day 2 days
old type of thing so when you hear
someone say I only spray in veg wow you
can just flush the toilet on that right
away I used to know I was just oh go
ahead no no no go on go on Marcus I was
just gonna say what I would do is I'd
grab the material a little bit a pinch
out of the bag and I would light it with
a lighter and then I would hold it under
my nose with my eyes closed and even if
it had the lightest amount of sulphur on
that material that's how I would
discover it right away and that kept me
from ruining a set of bubble bags
because I'm telling you sulfur is like
the worst you can't get it out of the
oil you can't get it I'll never forget
almost over 20 years ago standing on my
deck which is two doors down from the
property I live on now and Hawking 29
grams of that white foam elk hash
like right into the bush I just I just
couldn't deal with it
people look cool you could've eaten it
you could I was like listen that hash
was an abomination and it needed to go
comes through in the edible - we've we
thought I was going to say that the hash
was also free and we're like [ __ ] maybe
we can make some cake pops or something
with know what you can make yeah disc to
throw that's what you know about that's
about it we actually yeah I mean I've
seen like a couple kilos thrown away
from people spray and sell for too late
it definitely ya can murder you know for
weed is actually double weed I can't
handle it at all and you know it's the
it's it was the worst thing back in the
day and it was a big thing that people
saw a lot and bubble bags really
affected that whole mutant bags
oh wow look at that go rack em rack em
with some sieve tech I'm just gonna mute
you while you do that cuz that's loud as
[ __ ] in my ears what was my bag oh don't
know don't worry about it dude at all it
was I love the fact that you're
processing hash and getting ready to
make rosin so yeah smash extract sulfur
is such trash I've seen so much hash
ruined it's just unfortunate but it did
affect the growers because back in the
day I was able to go to the BC
compassion Club and explain to them you
know this this and this actually has
sulfur on it and that's by teaching them
that small trick for having a little bug
lady and on fire holding it under your
nose even the people who was were doing
quality control for the BC compassion
Club back in the day had no idea and
we're unwittingly buying this material
that had sulfur on it so it goes back to
the you know it goes back to show you
the people are people and you don't have
to be a big company to be a douche bag
very very like small micro grow like
let's just grow a batch and make some
hash can also be shitty and I've seen it
even in amazing places like Jamaica
where the growers are you know these
conscious Rastafarian guys and it's like
well guess what when it comes between
you not being able to feed your family
or have any money for the next three
months versus I'm just going to pour
poisonous fungicides that are illegal in
other countries on this material so I
can at least crop out you wouldn't
believe how many people choose the
latter and you don't have to be a big
evil corporation to do that you you know
a very small farmer small hash makers
have been known to do it as well so for
me I say we get rid of the trust in our
industry and we move into full testing
for everything and I would love to see
it also affect a lot of people want
cannabis to be less regulated I do in
aspects of it but the regulations of
spraying chemicals and poisons and
deadly toxins on the plant I love those
regulations being high I love things
being in place where that can be found
and those people who perpetrate that can
be caught and I also love the idea of
that system having an influence on our
food water and air systems that are
currently completely have been you know
exposed to a vast varieties of toxins
and poisons and and whatnot it wouldn't
be a bad thing if if our food kind of
picked up a little bit from the cannabis
industry and maybe tested things a
little more and maybe when something's
organic and naturally grown we just call
that food and when something's been
grown with deadly chemicals you know
instead of the word organic let's make
them have a [ __ ] word like Chemex
food or whatever yeah this is Chemex
if you want some Chemex Tomatoes by all
means they're three cents a pound buy as
many as you like you know that that's
that's my opinion anyway I agree it's
maybe that's a good time to break into
some of those strain stuff or in terms
of specific strains and to like living
in Maine coming back out of 11 years and
southern hop from Trinity to southern
Humboldt all around in the Emerald I
definitely brought my breeding with me
out there and then back home to Maine so
what I noticed is in many places
Northern California can grow just about
anything other than the polar opposites
of maybe a hard indica hard sativa back
into Maine I really enjoy Sun growing
I'm growing and you know greenhouse
automated like indoor as well all if
it's all organic but I know
Maine has really high humidity problem
and each season is different you get
beautiful Sun depending on location and
the water's pristine which is another
thing coming from a beautiful water
place to move back for the you know the
plentiful water was amazing but then I'm
battling with high humidity certain grow
seasons being better than others and
definitely have a lock on some strains
that have done well outside that are
specific to the region more how early
are you guys having to finish out there
in Maine oh man I have on my Instagram I
actually have a pineapple fields from
dynasty genetics that road till October
30th right on pre-halloween caught this
year I mean though depending I mean it's
we had a later season this last one but
the one before was an early cut you know
it was like really kind of harsh into
October after October first it was
pretty pretty rough you needed to be in
a house it was not the outside potential
is kind of gone you died there early
strains I got a lemon sour banana
sherbert I got a Fino to just pry it off
super early like third week September
outside stop my favorite strain but it's
beautiful beautiful work and turn the
tides locked in on but it's really
taking a lot of work to cycle through
plants that don't do well don't finish
well that are susceptible early to the
mill do they test bad for botrytis so
working through a lot of populations of
plants with just very few keepers like
under hat 3 3 4 types for the outside in
the main that I keep on and then
obviously indoor I got a whole bunch of
them so I can only imagine being from
Wisconsin I never successfully pulled
off a harvest outside working for me
first year back in helping he that was
from Wisconsin actually and he was
amazed with the how well it went into
Maine actually but you know it is sight
dependent there's micro climates per
site I'm in the foothills at like 625
feet so I'm not too low not too high up
and in a beautiful area just full Sun
all day beautiful water so it's
dependent site dependent in May it's not
everywhere it grows for a cannabis but
uh I have a list I guess maybe just sure
real quick and
about my list of strains that make the
best hash if you want to hear it oh we
definitely want to hear it let's go
through our list starting with best
friend farms all right well first off I
thought about it I love my own strains
but there's East Coast our diesel to
that original cut headband that we call
diesel BAM and it's just it's popping
off grease just you can't even touch it
the stuff melts the rhein turns to just
terpene resin sauce by the end of even
like a couple months I have a ball
that's like five six months old and it's
just completely blob like moose poop in
a jar you know honestly that variety is
best for I mean rice and water hash okay
yeah we're just that was from cured
resin cured flour from Sun growing on
this run of that particular ball and it
no matter indoor out it just seems to
throw a turkey and profile percentage
and a reaction of terpene to the resin
like some strains do they just like for
a classic hash temple ball style it
breaks the rind right down and it just
turns to blob whereas other strains will
trap the what I would call like the
cream I don't know how you'd phrase it
but the creepy innards within the rind
and really form a sealed Rhine the
diesel band just completely breaks it
down and I remember from back early days
of the real East Coast Sour Diesel cut
that that was doing the same thing too
so I think it's coming from that notice
the same thing with sour diesels little
butter a lot easier as well okay that's
so that's our diesel right there behind
me that's from fresh frozen but yeah
it's definitely I feel like that like
those og kind of terpenes will butter a
lot easier quicker oh no does anybody
else have that same kind of ID mode I
noticed it all the time I run another
one that's I called yeah snatched it's a
headband by kosher cush man and so I Mac
one it was a Mac timac nail time but it
was too the great cut of kosher and and
then of course the original head
headband cut and that one's just just
amazed does the same thing most of the
strains I'm liking to run for my quality
mics
- classic - temple bawling or Preston
I'm finding to be what would be called
maybe gasps your strains you know these
days
I got a coaster Mac what is it a kosher
Mac Trey along with that coach or Mac
head band that are my top three with the
diesel band but underneath diesel band
and then two ended I go 24 karat gold
from DNA does amazing work it's one of
my favorites to smoke that kosher tangi
yes they enough over here what's that
24k is my all-time favorite over here I
have a few beautiful
comps and last fruit it dumps down like
that orange is pretty played out but
when people get their hands on this one
they're back into the orange yeah we got
us confused and the growth but the
flower is just people kind of hear it
and go oh tangi played out a little bit
or kosher it's not like that it stays
right in my jar on the table with the
headband diesel bands like thing and
then tray start from top dog seeds
actually turns out some like really
fiery really fire you Afghan one two
there trace our dog or star dog work and
I'm just getting some old like greasy
type looking quality - that you know -
throw it back I grew up with you know
Moroccan super Keef and a Nepalese
temple ball honestly as being my
favorites to throw back to so that's
where I'm kind of looking for those
resins that will form for me like that I
wanted to ask can you force flower
plants out with the Sun in Maine or
light you light it light that's my spine
that's my backbone I was trained from
okay six or seven
honestly in Northern California and I
just stuck to it someone threw me in the
mix that there you go and I kind of went
whoa and honestly turned oh yeah like
you know a really big turn of really
really good for slaughter and I do I
stick the light up all the time
I guess my another question would be
you're using lights in that and they're
too great I'm not supplementing myself
okay so no lights in that just just the
black trick and I just manipulate light
structure which I think for like Maine
or even into Canada it's kinda can be
crucial you know in terms of getting the
potential out of your grow season and to
grow types that wouldn't normally grow
outside sun-grown for my Terps in demand
I can pull almost anything you know in
the gap that's awesome we ran a weasel
skunk from nature farm this year
original diesel and skunk eighteen and
so far I'm absolutely loving it it's
it's really really greasy but it's not
like too hard to work with and yeah it's
like sorry it looks like yeah I agree
yeah I mean it's just like it's just and
I agree like a lot and also like the the
piney strains I notice will be like
really greasy to brand last year we ran
was escape scapegoat escape boat
genetics Dale Denton and it's a nom nom
with no pineapple trainwreck and that
was phenomenal that was one of our
favorites last year and it was that it
was that total grease to that like apple
apple jelly type yeah
good relationship between the terpene
profile and the resins it's interesting
to see how they react over time and
curing and it's no doubt yeah cause like
cuz the GMO like one we really love for
hashing it's really like more savory
turps and it's definitely more stable
like it does you give it some heat
definitely grease up with it yeah but
but it not as much as not as much as
others it it's more it's more stable and
it'll stay stable and warmer
temperatures more than than other
strains that's interesting I know that
Super Skunk seems to really pull through
that diesel ban that math super stunk I
believe that's in that lineage and
that's that got that extreme good just
skunky diesel taste but also the terpene
resin Pro you know relationship
awesome good everyone sharing I could
share like probably a hundred but I'm
not going to because that's ridiculous
probably one of my all-time favorites
from back in the day would be the Rene
and that was really the cultivar that
started that you know bubble bags as a
company because it was the first
cultivar that I gained access to in
large amounts that I was able to
consistently make hash out of that would
you know come out white and eventually
when I would let it air-dry and whatnot
it would it would turn like stained
glass window like in a church you know
would be these different like reds and
oranges and Amber's and you could just
like see through it it was a little
foggy and that was that was that was
full full amounts like it was that was
six star hash and one of the things I
loved about it I mean one of the things
I didn't love about it was the terpene
profile and I'm sure I got this wrong
back in the day what we really said and
we based this on the fact that the water
didn't retain the smell when you ran
Rene instead the smell was retained in
the resin so I had assumed that somehow
you know they were water soluble the
ones in the majority of cultivars and
that the alcohol soluble terpenes
perhaps were not and did not wash out
further
for whatever reason I don't know if
that's correct I'm sure if dr. mark was
here he'd be like actually this is
what's happening but the bottom line is
is that yeah those those resins those
terpenes when you washed Rene were so so
strong in the hash it still smelt like a
half pound of the bud and in fact the
cultivar was nicknamed this is a
terrible nickname plot to get you busted
it was pot to get you busted I got so
many friends kicked out of hotel rooms
my friend got arrested on a bicycle
he had a half pound of it in his
backpack riding his bike in downtown
Vancouver and some bike cops went by him
and caught the with this [ __ ] was dank
it was like if you remember hime down in
the Pacific Northwest he did a strain
years ago called the dab the dank ass
[ __ ] and it had like the Emerald
triangle fog
and some other cultivar in it anyway
there was that was reminiscent of the
Renee the Renee had the funk and the
funk was like you couldn't escape it
the smallest amount of it would wreak up
your house in a seriously heat score
manner like I had a butt of it in my
pocket one time like 10 hours had gone
by I went Christmas shopping did all the
stuff went through a roadblock
the cop was like pull over there the
expert comes over the RCMP who's who
says I am an expert in marijuana
grow-ops I've been in over a hundred
this is what he said to me and I can
tell you've just been in a marijuana
grow up and I said listen man I'm gonna
be super honest with you because a I'm
sure on your computer it shows that at a
roadblock just like this not too long
ago I got busted was 16 and a half pound
a pounds of herb and about six grand
cash and I knew he had seen that and I
was so confident I and I had presents
wrapped in the vehicle I was so
confident I said I promise you I am NOT
an idiot I
there is no cannabis in my car
whatsoever and if you smell my pocket I
had a small bud in there about ten hours
ago and he leaned in and smelled my
pocket and completely believed me and
let and let me drive away and it was the
truth so that's my all-time favorite
hash making cultivar if you've got a
cultivar where the smell does not stay
in the water you know the more of that
of those terpenes that can transpire
into the hash those are the cultivars
that you want for producing full melt
because I'm quite certain it's the
terpene profile that is most responsible
for the melt aspect of the hash so
that's my two cents
this is really our tops can we talk
about water for a second without going
off all day on water because I know we
could we could do that but do it I just
wanted to see if everybody really uses
our Oh and yes I also wanted to say it's
not necessarily I mean it from for me at
least that's a lot of water like our Oh
making it's a lot of wasted water it's
hella wasteful and and you know like if
you have clean water you got a set like
a bunch of sad filters maybe your carbon
filter on you know like get some things
going on we're fill it depends on where
you are - I don't want to go you know
compromise build water a sediment filter
right off the spring up on the hill is
some of the best water you can use for
me that's yeah yeah sentiment and
dechlorinator
that's all I really use I mean I'm
important so I'm fortunate to have
fantastic water here just through that
it comes out at 0 ppm so yeah I'm
gallons per minute we're doing 20
gallons per minute 22 gallons a minute
refresh hole in main on my well it's
like a 350 foot it's well water just
pristine running through some testing
and just like carbon filtration right
now but looking into even advanced
filtration for the sediment when such
but you know it's not Babylon water
supply so it's not bleached and
chloramine and chloramine and whatever
else that you got a strip out which I
would do if I'm in the environment yeah
yeah down here in Sebastopol we can't we
have to run in our off the waters
horrible but living up in northern Mendo
up on hill man we literally down a
plastic tube from the Springboks through
a semi the ship like 39 degrees coming
off the hill you know barely had to use
any ice nothing beats that I had that
for six years when I lived on the water
we pulled our water out of the creek
that went right into the ocean and it
was just you know a nice little
filtration system going down to like
point zero 5 micron or something and
we had we didn't have to dechlorinate or
anything cuz it was just literally
coming right off right off the mountain
it was great water I've made wash with
water all over the world and obviously
when you can control and condition and
you know control all the parameters of
your water perhaps you know I think as
hash makers that more people would do it
and play around with it if they had
access to really play around with the pH
of their water and see how the resin
reacts differently on the alkaline side
versus the acidic side of your water so
yeah having an RO unit is great and
having filters depending on where you're
pulling your water from really it's easy
to find out what you need for your water
filtration system go get your water test
it when you find out what's in it you
can then find out the methods of
removing each of those things and then
those are the things that you require to
clean your water and get it ready for
nice water extraction I remember you
making a big old ball of some really -
on a video from way my way back that
with you Marcus that was actually in
Jamaica in the in the back you know in
the bushes Jamaica I remember like big
old barrels and then just coming out
with this like grapefruit sized swirl
eagle acts like that's motivation for me
with those swirly balls that were
falling and stuff just seeing it done
out there do you want to hear motivation
we walked for an hour and a half with
I'm telling you like it had to be maybe
a hundred pounds of ice I wondered if
you had a generator like no no no dude
we this was in the bush we had nothing
we walked for an hour and a half and
everyone took their turn carrying this
[ __ ] thing of ice on their head it
didn't matter who you were
gypsy Nirvana definitely did it probably
for the shortest amount of time Wally
the Australian Wally duck if you
remember that guy what an amazing
character he was it was nothing for him
to work and he was a kind of a little
guy it was nothing for him to work in
like plus 35 degrees or whatever like
it's 100 degrees in Jamaica like in the
shape and so we're climbing we're
carrying this ice I did it as well
it was pretty hardcore and when we got
there I was like oh so what should i mix
with and he just gave me like a fence
post that he had like carved to kind of
like a handle into and I was like all
right so I straight like was doing this
like with 20 gallon batches they had a
mountain of herb in that place and the
look on his face and how happy he was
when I took his you know subpar sort of
mid-grade Jamaican weed and turned it
into a decent for him
I mean I didn't smoke it I'll be honest
no I went home I went home and actually
made my own which was what that big ball
that you saw was I didn't make that at
the place that looked like that I went
and doubled up and went and I was like
okay now I got to go home and make good
hash so thanks for setting up that
meeting gypsy she's a wonderful person
is awesome yeah yeah good good friend
with him good good times with gypsy all
over the world we've had some adventures
so it's a good thing about cannabis it
really pulls you in these different
directions it can pull you especially
the hash you know like there's hash
producing countries that every hash
maker probably at one point in time may
want to go check out yeah that's gonna
be my topic ice we've got ice the idea
go ahead before we talk about the ice I
like the idea of and we're not doing
this really I'm the on a full-scale yet
but we'd like to like actually like when
you're done with awash saving that water
in a reservoir and fermenting it and
using that to feed back into the garden
makes because that at least work where
we do it out a seasonal you know
seasonal scale so we make hash in the
winter we grow plants in the summer type
deal so absolutely put anything anything
you possibly can that came out of the
garden back into the into the ground
feed the feed your soil
and make sure your soil is clean because
hemp cannabis it's a fighter immediate
of plants it will literally pull toxic
heavy metals etc out of your soil if
they're present so test your water test
your soil those are great ways to open
the door to well how am I gonna know how
am I gonna know what kind of filters I
need how am I gonna know you know well
you'll know by testing your soil and
testing your water pretty good spot to
start if you want to start down the road
as of a cannabis grower which is
definitely the best way if you can
because you really have to have full
access and when someone else is growing
your inputs because um you know they'll
show you everything sometimes except
maybe something that they shouldn't have
been spraying or feeding the plants at
one point in time in its life and that's
it's a tough one because it's also
connected to a way of life and Oh like
you've built a family and you're taking
care of this whole group of people and
you have these dependents and now your
crop is about to die and you're in this
position where it's like holy [ __ ] like
we just need to squeeze another couple
of weeks out of this I get it but it
sucks and it's especially sucks for
people who are the ones that end up on
the wrong end of that I wish there was a
better way I wish that cannabis farmers
could be insured you know like how great
would that be it's like not not for
stupidity but like you know legitimate
like you did everything right and and
something still kind of found its way
and got in it'd be nice if you could
probably dream me in a utopian world
here but hey 25 years ago I thought a
utopian world would be being able to go
to a store and buy a legal fashion herb
right that's what's up all right so
we've got almost 11 a.m. what I have to
figure out is are we just gonna continue
on with this panel and finish off the
day and do the rosin panel next week or
are we gonna end this panel and invite
the rosin panel in at 11 o'clock you go
what are you guys feeling you guys have
a couple of how do you feel
I mean we could probably keep talking we
could probably talk again but you're the
one that has to sit in here for another
I like well I'd like to be able to talk
more about hash making for sure this is
hashed Church and I'm sure the rosin
folks would understand if we pushed if
we push the rosin episode till next
Sunday because we haven't really we
haven't talked about it a lot you know
even all of us haven't given our
cultivars we've got one two three four
five six about seven eight cultivars
that three or four of us have mentioned
but there's still quite a few people in
the room who haven't mentioned their
favorite cultivars I know that'll be a
part people like go back to and rewind
and try to write those cultivars down
because that's you know we're basically
giving you a full melt certification of
cultivars and along with that we will
also let you know how the cannabis was
grown if we know that so that that might
be helpful because you know maybe you're
doing a hydro grow and this is only
gonna really do that this this
particular way in dirt or you know vice
versa or something so yeah if anyone
else wants to share some cultivars I'm
sure everyone's listening and we have by
the way 864 people listening which is
the most we've had in a live audience in
2020 so that's really good when hashed
Church was at its peak we would have
about a thousand people a week watching
live so great job panel for bringing in
bringing in almost 900 people have tell
me a cultivars one of the clips of ours
I really enjoyed working with this year
I know Flynn and resin ranch work with
it a lot as well and it's been around
for a while it was a cookies and cream
you know it grows very well I've had
success with it indoor/outdoor and in a
debt and did you know it pretty much
does to work for you in the bags as far
as the 90 to 120 goes and you know it
rosin is great as well dries very nicely
it's a very stable and easy resin to
work with and it presses very well and
it's just a
it's all around you know checks all
boxes for me looks appeal yield
presentation that all the way through
and I even am venturing out into running
some CNC crosses and other stuff mixed
with it and that's definitely one that
I'm gonna keep around and keep working
with especially all the different all
the different fee knows we ran the 5 and
the 7 and the 13 this year and they're
all a little different in their own way
but they all make super great hash and I
enjoyed working with each one of them
agreed I've got some concentrated X
cookies-and-cream right here and it is
absolute fire fair hash brand that's
rosin strain I've seen around even four
or five years agos with half hash it was
dumping just the just milky rosin even
from just cured cured flour don't do
beautiful yeah that in the Kimbo Kush
the Kimbo Kush you know similar genetic
line was fantastic I remember the first
time I washed it it was like oh that's
why Cuban won all those cups like this
[ __ ] dunks and it just is amazing and
that was from dry material I could only
imagine but if I got fresh frozen but
another one I like to do is my personal
favors OG PI breath that's what I've
been running it's a solid Fino tex all
boxes as well pretty stable I've been
trying to search through seeds to see
something new and I just can't find
anything that really has beaten it for
the last five years so I just keep
running
we ran we watched some peanut-butter
breath from a local grower last year and
it washed really really well
and we've been wanting to try growing it
just thought I'd mention it awesome keep
them coming
keep them coming I'll throw one down DNA
genetics strawberry-banana one of the
best out there in white and everything I
run their white walk or two even as like
a classic hash strain for a really good
indica temple ball cured resin temple
ball strain makes a shiny coating on the
outside of the white Walker balls and
just nice octopi nice free on the inside
but it's one of our indica choices more
individuals if you scroll through my
feet on IG you're gonna see a lot of
banana OG it is very similar to that
strontium I mean I haven't ran the straw
Nana Buddha from what would I've heard
from soil grown and other folks that
have run it very similar you know white
in every bag very heavy yielding maybe a
high wax content why it's so Crockett's
finally and say to me there's different
cuts floating around there's like that
straw Nana the 14 is what I hear people
refer to it as you know to me that's
really big yields and it's great unto
itself and then there's also this other
cut going around called strawberry
banana that's you know to me they're two
different things the strawberry banana
is more closely related to the banana OG
that I see around the straw man is more
speared out kind of different structure
but uh that strawberry banana I
personally prefer over the strong Anna
fourteener I get like six point three
five percent melt back on fresh frozen
material the dumps super chirpy and
washing it for years but everyone still
loves it smells like a strawberry
milkshake you know like people can't get
enough of it
dad banana that you wash goes something
really fire to that you know that you
have a super special I get to try some
of the last time we hung out I really
enjoyed those one my favorite bananas
good try it's just a super awesome
banana og cut that's been up here in the
humbled area for years like again I
think it's probably a few banana oh geez
out there but that one that you're
talking about it does stand out it's
just super candy banana it's awesome man
that's awesome the strawberry fields
that comes in pretty hot too with the
Crockett right behind with DNA project
there on this tangi thrown in on the
strawberry banana had some really good
phenols of Strawberry Fields five four
five years ago out there and they've
carried into my genetic program actually
today I do a Clementine cookies and
cream actually to my angel food cake and
yeah just really really gives that you
know fruit forward cookie back type
thing for breeding too with those those
fruity Terps on a Jimmy cookie on the
backend for the look you know and then
the bread just allowed on the strawberry
banana and throat Angie and it's hard to
go wrong that might as such of tangi
type thing yeah I'll throw another one
out wedding cake nice producer really
nice resin leaves very little residual
and grown properly it's got that hash
yes we did last year
did really well really nice vanilla
vanilla cake flavor how the wedding cake
I usually grow outside it's so greasy I
ain't gonna lie it's like a [ __ ] to
work with to make awesome melt it's
amazing but like I lose a lot to the
bags that's so [ __ ] sticky personally
we're not saying I don't love it but
just as far as working with it that GMO
that strawberry banana they're just dry
or resins that are easier to handle for
me personally that's my experience with
wedding cake but it's an awesome full
melt straight
100% agree great strains man I got a
nice long list so far I'm gonna I'll do
an Instagram post and post it I love
that that motorbreath 15 I'm getting
high five percentage yields on fresh
frozen nice dry resin to work with
everyone in California hash brands are
running with it that motor breath is
fire key lime pie is an oldie but a
goodie I've been washing that for years
makes great great resin it's like upper
4%
what about the kind of spot would I just
got that in hell yeah oh yeah I just got
some crosses from the exotic genetics
where it's all the grease monkeys is the
mail that's a great one too there
anybody ran the original or washed wash
the original grease monkey and I just
got that Pino man so I haven't grown it
yet yeah I like the grease monkey a lot
did whenever we rented it seemed to grow
fairly well fairly vigorous and it
dumped and did really well for pacchiana
I was in that you know a lot of people
hate on glue but it did but I love I
love them oh yeah if you can find a good
glue hitter it's especially even bet you
know back to the cookies and cream it's
hard to beat that
we got a Buddha Tahoe I cross for that
Mak mail or I had my friend sent me some
of that Mak pollen actually and I hid
the Buddha Tahoe gee and it's turning
out some just amazing resins in terms of
how they bond and after pressing and
everything just looking wise and then
very classic cushy hash smell it's not
super out front loud I think some of it
might wash back into the water or
something as I'm learning
oh and finding but amazing resins off
the Buddha Tahoe for sure just got
another cultivar in - it's called
Twizzlers it's a kosher tangi 24k I
guess crossed with cherry pie and that's
also a new one to me I had I haven't
washed or and or pressed those strains
independently but I'm wondering if any
of you guys on the panel and the
explorers Cohoes twist
Twizzlers with kosher kosher tangi
crossed with cherry pie that sounds
amazing
- new one from the bay i guess both of
those I know I've seen cherry pie do
well obviously I've seen culture can G
do amazing so yeah that sounds I need
some Twizzlers it's a new strain in the
bay supposedly so starting to pop up in
sessions and around the area that's
gonna be so Bob just all hugs I'm not
even sure who to reader is loving the
list guys loving the list it's good to
get this list what's up Sam use high CBD
strange and you rosin or whatever you
make out of it this does have a
different texture because when I made my
CD strained I found it was very dry and
not very sticky I got super glue out of
my hemp field this year I did one acre
and I actually turned some sour space
candy into some bubble balls the bubble
hash temple balls so I'm pressing yam
ball and some hemp strains just for
trying it I got a purple orange from
Dyna femme that's a you like one to one
- the one thing that I'm running that
makes amazing ash but I'm wondering
about varieties that have little to no
THC yes CB s-- our space candy was
straight CBD almost not even
registerable THC at all bearing it very
little and that made like gluey tacky
black type of hash man I mean we were
even impressed it's not melt so we
didn't get a melt off of it but the tack
on it was like you couldn't pull the
thing apart you have to you know cut it
heat it up or something to get it to
even pull apart it was really gluey had
to hide a lot of glue to it from the
bubble cured resin sorry I missed you
cakey dried [ __ ] you cut out some dry
sift was dry for me on the hemp stuff on
the CBD very dry exactly what I found
yeah no resin headed glands that were
sticky and very little smell it was it
was kind of unpleasant
it was residents with they were dry they
weren't sticky they weren't greasy
absolutely correct
alright thank you I think it's that
cherry smell to that or people that
people say is the cherry smell from the
CBD varieties he doesn't have a smell no
the tree that profile Sam that you know
I've watched the whole content in foot
plant of one of those and it was just
not a nightmare you know all that all
that good stuff just washes right down
the drain I actually just I just read it
I bred at Angie stud or what was it a
taffy stud tangi de la fe and then a
guava jelly mail also on multiple types
from Oregon CBD in my home field this
year so I got some turf forward matchups
coming up for real medicine strains
hoping to pull some beautiful hash with
a flavor from it actually
you
so many hid cultivars we got any left in
the room great pie
I was going to love great pie GMOs all
the GMO I'm a GMO by cookies-and-cream
that does really well walk up ours it's
called Wonka bars they like to try that
so I'm gonna get cultivars I do kind of
dream of a day where cultivars are like
there's you know that they're accessible
that you could just order them in an
aseptic box from a tissue culture
company and they've been initiated and
all of the anything's been like
guaranteed to not be present from a
virus microbial fungi perspective and
just have have the advantage of being
able to choose all of these different
cultivars and not only choose them
blindly but choose them based on data
collected from extractors who are
processing in a variety of ways with all
of these different cultivars and showing
where these cultivars shine the most in
their extraction processes so then you
could order your cultivars like oh I
want to do a dry sift you know I just
want to dry set the whole crop you like
open the tissue culture menu and see
like oh look at this the first two pages
are dry sift cultivars you know these
are the driest of cultivars with
greenhouses these are the indoor joys of
cultivars you know and have each
extraction process down the line have
that available and that would just be a
really beautiful beautiful thing if that
were the case you know clean initiated
vigorous genetics ready to ready to
Express
so what about those half strains that
have large heads you were talking about
that earlier and I've might strain the
og pie breath has pretty melty heads in
the 150 and 180 I mean I found that with
lights that have higher UV intensity
that's actually created more of a melt
in the higher higher micron range is
anybody else seeing that like with CMH
or what's the other one the plaza or LED
I can't really I have first-hand but man
chibs I don't know probably everybody in
your files trichome heavy he's been
pulling huge 221 81 50 bags and he said
he he can't I've been talking about he
can't really put his finger on why he's
getting big heads from growers that he's
worked with in the past and he didn't
you know he said he's getting some on
salt grouse he's getting it on living
soil grows that he's getting he does
just thinks that it's just genetics have
gotten better is it fresh frozen or
dried material works with all fresh
frozen - me - fresh frozen will be
bigger heads than dried material
especially dragon cured material that's
really big though it is I'm not saying
it's only because of that I'm just
saying that fresh frozen material has
bigger heads then dried and cured
material absolutely undeniable presence
starts to raise it up yeah that's the
truth does anybody mess with the washing
partially dried material I know that's
cruel crisp Bobby didn't use it that's
what you guys did it
your last job right yeah we ran a lot of
stuff that was just like harvested hung
for a couple days and then bucked down
like it would be fresh frozen into
fraggers and then washed yeah
like in the freezer Elektra in the hash
or dry in the material your your
hang-drying uh it was anywhere from like
five to seven days it's got an exam that
cold dark controlled environment and
then the material was handled by you
know one to two people and it was bucked
down real lightly into the freezer and
then washed that way by hand you know
and that was just for production we
weren't making there was no like we're
making sick start here and that's a
thing it was just they were producing
bras in there and you know that was that
what do you prefer now now that you guys
do your fresh frozen what do you guys
prefer or what do you prefer excuse me
fresh frozen a hundred percent just the
you know the full melt that comes from
you I've made a lot of full melt from
dry material and it's good but you know
the difference between the terpenes and
the effects is totally different for me
and when you've got really good material
the dumbs for fresh frozen it's it's
such a fun thing to wash that material
versus doing it dry I don't really like
to smoke dry resident near as much as I
do fresh frozen just because a lot of
the strains that we've been running over
here don't you know just the same as all
the dry material did over there like the
lemon peel for example dirty taxi Kim to
lick him moonbow ninety nine and one
twelve those produced some of the
craziest resident have ever seen when it
comes down to like full Nell and there
are a lot bigger heads it all you know
dumps between the ninety through you
know 179 you're getting full mo you know
in my experience washing dried material
all you're really going to gain is a
slight yield increase but you're gonna
sacrifice so much turps that to me it's
not worth it I just did up dry on some
Mac you know everyone says oh that one
isn't a hash strain it's terrible its
turf list blah blah blah I'll say it's
mild on the Terps but uh I fresh froze a
lot of it and then I partially dried it
just for my own
you know I always do fresh frozen but I
wanted to know for myself this is
supposedly not a hash cultivar when I
try washing it fresh frozen and then I'm
gonna try washing it you know sit was a
seven-day dry 60 and 60 I'm all grown
next to each other you know in the same
bed same situation
it's tough with percentage-wise because
you know I have a percentage based off
of dry and a percentage based off of wet
but I only got like 15 more grams from a
pound um washing it partially dried felt
a little stronger on the effects I feel
like a lot of times dried material I
don't know
affects me in a way where seemed a
little stronger
um but yeah like I said there's usually
a lack of Terps it's kind of hard to
tell with melt but when you rosin it
it's pretty obvious the difference in my
experience yeah to the rosin was not as
Turbie as any of the fresh roses
material was so I prefer the fresh
frozen for that reason as well terpene
preservation that's why I brought up the
partial cure aspect because trying to do
it like seven days is even probably a
little too much in in my opinion like
the three to four day max at 1660 and
then buff down and frozen and then
washed I still I still felt like I got
that higher yield but I also kept a lot
more of the terpenes that I would if I
would have dried it completely but
obviously obviously for sure definitely
not as much with fresh frozen but it
kind of got to both but both best of
both worlds at least a few times that
I've experimented with it that's what
I'm having it up how about a research
cure then free to care close up yeah
like freeze because technically I mean
it's a freezers at low temperature and
very low humidity so if you leave your
material and therefore say you know like
a month when you had other stuff to
process aren't you somewhat curing it a
little bit
I got to agree you know I mean so yeah I
mean you're removing a very tiny amount
of moisture but potentially what's
everybody's thought I mean help
how long does everybody like to wait for
fresh frozen before you start washing it
in the before you know for a year and a
half before and washed it and it washed
amazing you know I'm all doing it by
myself so I've had stuff in my freezer
for a long time by no means am i
freezing it and processing it right away
um a lot of times I'm just stuffing
freezers all season long and then in the
winter I process it and work seasonally
so I hear you about a curing in the
freezer but at the same time I feel like
my material isn't changing all that much
and it's Jeff's freezer at negative 30
to negative 50 but again that's just my
opinion
well freezers generally preserve you're
not you know of course terpenes is
extremely volatile and there could be
some things going on there but nothing
compared to like room temperature even
just the cold temperature of a fridge if
freezing
research will change the color of bugs
for example it will darken well yeah
yeah I was thinking more like moisture
like taking a little not necessary like
terpenes but more of like taking a
little bit of the moisture out because
isn't that technically what freezer burn
is is that like all the moistures has
gone out of the chicken from freezing
yep yep pulled it out I had material in
my freezer it was dry it was from a grow
I did like in 2012 and I just pulled it
out like a couple years ago it was like
old it was like six years old or
something and I pressed it I was just
like oh this is just flour I'm just
gonna press it and I just got this like
baby diaper like yellow [ __ ] that was so
[ __ ] loud that most of the people I
showed it to just could not believe that
it was six year old dried bud that I
squished like a day and a half ago like
I would open it and people like very far
away would be like do you smell that
like it was really really loud so you
just never know what kind of
preservation you've got going on but I
wouldn't have guessed it was that
extreme from this material it was
Harmonie a cut I got from reefer man
that harmony is no joke if any of you
have ever bro I guarantee you freeze
pull derisive heads if you freeze it at
minus 30 yeah kept away from oxygen as
much as possible that 10-15 years later
if it's changed it's such a tiny bit I
can't tell the difference
aye well that old old resin do you
remember the old resin that our friend
Michael had it was like oh yeah I don't
think that was frozen dude for sure or
not every year that I smoked it and I
can't remember I think I started smoking
it when it was like I don't know 13
years old or something and then I smoked
it every year till it was like how old
did it get like was it like 8 17 or 18
or something years old did you did you
smoke that til the end I think it came
to I don't know but I think the piece is
now getting social security right all I
know about that piece of hash it was
powder like red dust like crazy dry sift
that was so pure but it was it was old
like I don't know what year that [ __ ]
was from what and I get people wanting
to like cure hash I have some hash here
on my table that's 10 that's almost 10
years old right now it's it's it's like
glass it's like crack it open and it's
real shiny but maybe I'll take it to
that in a bit but it would have been
nice to preserve it so that it's what
you remember years down the road you've
kept something for 10 years but instead
of curing it and changing all of it at
least keep some in a preserved manner
now here's something I want to bring up
four years we cured bud we cured bud
because it was harsh when it still had
moisture in it and some of those
monoterpenes were more caustic and just
sort of sharp
the bouquet of the terpenes that came
out underneath and revealed themselves
as that some of those monos evaporated
out volatize off those that's how we
always enjoyed flower eventually we got
into water hash all the first water hash
I made was from dry material all the
full melts from Renee was from bone dry
material like it was dry and a produced
foam out so I net you know a lot of
people couldn't produce and really it
seemed like the birth of fresh frozen
was also the birth of faux melt which is
you know appears to be full melt but
it's really not it's something a little
bit different and so I wonder in this
new generation where we've come this
full you know 180 degrees from liking to
cure things out so it's smooth and I
remember having some dry sift that I had
made out of some sweet skunk and it was
like the material had been cured for
months and then I sifted and then the
sift had been cured for months and when
you took a dab of it it was just it was
full mouth but it was just so smooth and
nice quite different from that sort of
caustic like whoa I just took a dab of
some really fresh frozen freeze-dried
like white full melt like it's really
Turkey and I just wonder the differences
in that that how we've come like you
know and when I was in Amsterdam it was
actually Tony from Sega Martha seeds
that I bumped into Sam and we I can't
remember we were at like Hanks apartment
above the Bulldog and the lives of
playing and I he had been taking some
dabs he was kind of like oh I don't want
any more and I said oh you know take one
of these it's really special and he took
a dab of it and you just blew this dab
out there was no coughing and it was
just smooth and I wonder what you guys
have to say about the difference between
those two experiences having a hash that
you you know cure the material out
before you wash it wash it and tear that
for a little bit versus let's save every
single terpene the ones that would have
normally evaporated off in the drying
process and let's let's contain them all
and and instead you know breathe all of
those in for for the dab experience you
know there's a conversation right the
difference between those two things
surely you guys fix
since that example is that every year
when I because I used to smoke lots of
Banja III smoke ash for the last 25 30
years before that I broke massive
amounts of down yeah and I grew up in
Santa Cruz and when I harvested it every
year my voice
I would think laryngitis from smoking
weed that had dried for two weeks and I
couldn't wait and and it was really
really potent cannabis it was really
loud campus like either skunk or haze or
one of those type things and I guarantee
you every year for five six years in a
row
I got laryngitis and Thanksgiving when
it was the new harvest season and I know
it was because of the Turks but whose it
could have also been partly from plant
material itself it was rap rock for me I
mean barely dry enough but it wasn't
cured we're definitely smoking a
different profile of terpenes than we
ever had in our history just freshly in
this last 20 years starting to do
extracts different ratios forget about
the adding of kinetic cannabis extracted
terpenes or the the infamous fruit
terpenes but we're definitely inhaling
differently in the last twenty years and
I just wonder how that will affect us
inhaling and terpene profiles that maybe
we maybe we haven't been inhaling for
the last like 40 to 50 years because
that bug was cured and that you know
flower was up it was always about being
cured and now it's really all about
preservation of the entire profile from
the time you cut the plant down you're
fraught your flash freezing it you're
washing it freeze drying that very
little heat can be exposed to that over
the course of its life and now you have
this terpene profile the
guarantee you is quite different from
the terpene profile of the same cured
flower or hash what is smoking higher
terpene concentrations doing to us as
well I guess terpenes are caustic you
know and I know not necessarily for hash
but some of the like BHO sauce they're
getting crazy high herpe numbers I know
at least for me when I inhale that stuff
man it it makes my lungs not super happy
I don't think that's air pit you know
listen for for Adam do you notice a
different in a difference in say Terps
are terpene profiles in the air dried
versus freeze-dried hush
I honestly there's a reason why
everybody's freeze-drying
you know I think that it's it's super
rare to get air dried hash I mean like
what year was that whenever the freeze
dryer just banged everybody over like it
was just like what everybody has amazing
perfectly dried resin back to back to
back to back to back whereas it was like
a struggle don't we been about two years
since a free shower came out yeah
exactly Fletcher really was one of the
first people just absolutely but but I
mean like when it's spread out I mean
you know this is just my experience from
Northern California I'd go to Emerald
cup and then that's where a lot of
people obviously travel and seeing all
of that hash all of a sudden from a
freeze dryer it was just like okay like
this Adam for me it was like 2015 - like
2016 I feel like you were I'm a bunch of
hand dried hash entries to the next year
there was like one if that and it was
just everything was freeze-dried hash
just like yeah I kind of think yeah I
got mine in 2015 after I saw in Michigan
made melt at it and was like I was gonna
buy a backup and to do Cuban tech and I
was like well that's cold that's maybe
what I want to do more so yeah I mean
keep in mind like I'm I'm you know I'm
just it's a seasonal garden so it's
seasonal work for me I just don't have
the balls to buy a freeze jar and put
the the melt through it like that I
don't want to because I know that it's a
really efficient tool but sometimes it
can be a little too efficient and like I
just haven't been able to do that trial
and error yet I'm sure one day I will
you know but um yeah I'm still air
drying everything by hand with a
microplane because like Marcus was
bringing up earlier like I think that
sometimes water can leach maybe not
leach but may
water can sometimes you'll win that
trichome and maybe not all trichomes are
perfect and so I shred them up with a
microplane and like they're not all
shredded up there some that aren't and
it's like really cool to look at the
pictures that were it's like well holy
[ __ ] like I took a microplane to this
and this thing should be shredded
straight in half but it's completely
whole like what's going on so um you
know there's a there's a finesse and a
sleight-of-hand technique to drying air
drying and I haven't seen the side to
side enough to know all I know is that
freeze drying is is a it changed the
game and ya know I to answer the
question
better I haven't seen enough
side-by-side work especially with myself
I'm very ignorant when it comes to the
freeze dryer but I've never used one
personally I've just heard everybody's
experience and tried to if you want to
do some research on them you should
google lyophilization so that's like
yeah side by side I think it was about
2016 when I first got it I was still
doing most of my first run
you know melt quote-unquote melt I was
handed still micro planing and hand
drying and then like my later runs I was
thrown in the freeze dryer so I could
press them literally the next day you
know to make rosin and I did it with the
24k and uh I know I didn't have I guess
the best place to air dry it was on
racks in an open room no HEPA filter
kind of thing you know it was pretty
pretty legit situation but it could be
better
and I I honestly preferred the
freeze-dried hash in the end the air
dried was on the rack seven to ten days
I notice there's some people get in
there microplane - dried quicker than
that so we're doing two weeks dry just
my experience on that you know that one
cultivar what were you drawing it on did
you have it on parchment I had it on
lined yeah parchment lined cookie rock
sheets right so parchments not a
desiccant yeah so you created the area
the surface area for it to draw it but
you own
allowed it to air-dry had you used the
desiccant to pull the water out which
gravity helps plus it's just water will
always kind of settle down and if you
give it something that it can absorb
into it'll absorb dry absorb dry and it
dries like very differently than than if
you don't I kind of said that from early
days you know what happened was when we
start you know I I ended up showing
people you know drying on like pizza
boxes or whatever because I was in the
Pacific Northwest if you have wanted a
hope of getting your hash dry especially
in like November December when it's just
like pouring you know fifty millimeters
of rain everyday you can't even believe
how much [ __ ] rain it is you really
need to have the help of a desiccant and
then nicotine started making hash maybe
like eight to ten years later and it was
like he was like ah you don't need to do
that like you can just do it like this
and I was just like bro you're in
Colorado where it's really dry like if
you tell people in the Pacific Northwest
but they don't need to do that and that
they can just do this it's not gonna
work out for them and that really began
that dialogue in that conversation of
we're not all in the same environments
our terroirs are different and we have
to act accordingly to that when we do
things like drawing hash does a lot of
polarization oven or a freeze dryer take
the some of the worry out of that
absolutely you know especially if you're
selling to a market whether it be rec or
medical medical for sure freeze dryer is
going to ensure that not one single
chunk of your hash was microplaned or
sieved too large held enough water to
you know create microbial content and
you know potentially offer someone
something they didn't need you know
particularly if they were patients and
already immune compromised or whatnot so
freeze dryers do have a purpose I think
that the harvest rights are kind of like
cute little toys they're great for the
beginning of our industry but when you
get into actual production you're gonna
get into you know something like a mill
Rock a large scale unit because here's
the thing you start making large scale
water hash you start getting up
to be able to do really large runs and
make many many many kilos a day your
limitation won't be in the size of your
unit or in your biomass or in your ice
production or in your ability to
condition your water it will be in your
freeze dryer rack space that will be
your limitation and so if you want and
you know if you feel that you have the
ability to produce a lot of good hash
that's going to require a freeze drying
because there are other alternatives if
hash isn't going to be melty here in
Canada what we do with it and my partner
Daniel at Whistler technologies I'm up
with this with that with his partner
Brita and they basically just figured
out quite a while ago that hey why don't
we if we could get a big and the reason
they did this was Canada was stuck in a
place where you couldn't sell hash but
you could take the hash that you made
and infuse it into a plant fat and sell
it in a 30ml vial with a particular you
know it has to be somewhat diluted it's
very small amount of cannabinoids per ml
this was Canada for the last four years
and that's changed now with rec and
medical kind of opening up bigger but
that's the way it was at the time don't
let me lose my train of thought here my
goodness that robot voice threw me off
for a bit so what was an optimization
Latinization ovens right so Daniel and
amber Sh'ma came up with for Whistler
technologies to start the company to
sell a unit to Whistler Medical and for
them to say listen you can take this
hash and because you can't dry it and
sell it as a hash product what you can
do is you can get our Terp reactor which
is about 200 liters and you can infuse
plant fats we can infuse bubble fresh
bubble the bubble never dries and what
you end up with once you filter the map
through a membrane and remove all the
water and the waxes and end up with this
really beautiful you know hash hash
infused oil you end up with a terpene
content that is about two times higher
than the majority of the companies in
Canada that are selling these infused
oils so that's one of the sort of
technologies that Whistler technologies
helped to make bubble hash a commercial
thing
that you know you don't want to
sacrifice your quality if it's there but
you want your workhorse to be able to
work and if there's no quality and
there's some some you know three to four
star hash we can certainly still run it
and infuse it into plant fats and
produce this really great high terpene
plant content extraction so that was one
of the things that he did that really
sort of inspired me about being coming a
part of the company because it was one
of the things that kept you know as all
of you know is hash makers it's very
hard to sometimes make a business with
just making you know water hash you know
because unless you have a really great
connection you know before rosin came
into play when you really had to deal
with the hash that you had you know that
was an amazing method to just take that
hash very fresh don't dry it infuse it
into plant fat decarboxylated under a
vacuum and then filter it through a
membrane to get all that stuff out
that's the very medicine that my own
mother who worked for the police for 30
plus years as a 911 operator my own
mother uses that product you know via
Whistler technologies through Whistler
medical and just orders it off the
internet so we've come a long way and we
have a long way to go 11:33 I'd rock
this out for another half-hour solid if
you guys want to twist and change
direction or if you want to keep on this
direction I think all of this these
topics are great so great that I'm gonna
have to make like a once a month water
hash you know panel where we get like 30
to 40 of us on a list and then whoever
can make it each month each yeah without
one week a month can kind of put their
name in the pile because there's a lot
to talk about with with hash making and
and clearly we're all obsessed and
geeking out on it so the other thing I
wanted to see what breeders people were
like in working with for finding like
hash specific cultivars been really on
point
seems like stable work even and skunk be
a actually for some getting you know gas
tea here turn
and Crockett's family under DNA in
Crockett yeah I did at AC ways from
Psalm PI's that turned out really good
it did like five point three percent
melt so not the best but really nice
kind of had like a kami GMO flavor
didn't really well the 91 Royale I just
turned actual it's not my favorite but
one of two Tino's just was tacky fresh
frozen couldn't couldn't do much with it
it was like really really really gluey
even nice problem to have it involves
some trickery especially if you're gonna
save [ __ ] like that you better leave
moisture content in your patty don't let
that [ __ ] wick out on the pressing
scream some paper towels under there
you'll walk away for two minutes and
come back and have a [ __ ] piece of
Hubble bubble gum that's pressed itself
into a gummy sticky mass and now your
now your micro planing no matter what
anyone else for breeders I got one how
about stuntman Sam exotic exotic yeah
Oney some papaya cake pony that's good
archive does really well archive yeah I
want to get some more seeds of that we
ran some kings - actually that was fire
that made really beautiful just won't
have to be a bunch of that the other day
in 2005 Pike is Jessie pile cortex
vortex let's write it down I'm making
the list checking it twice gonna find
out who's naughty or nice
[Music]
ste junkie that push cake is hidden
pastries those did really well
[Music]
definitely worth washing wedding cakes
enough I enjoyed all this eat jerky gear
for sure yeah
pony pigs in the ponies good exotic dark
got dark horse as well both ugh pug
vessel life science just texted me he's
like bugs been killing it so there you
go vessel I did all I heard was vortex
but we're gonna stay I'll start I'm
finally yet but I'm gonna start now that
it's being open up to share strains and
I'm finding the good cultivars that we
have in house I'll find some way to
share them out at least you know what if
we're folding into adult use at the farm
in the main this really soon this year
looking for a boat in June but we're
doing medical only right now I would
love to share some of the hash plan type
cultivars from us out work and look to
do that later
Oh beautiful hairy palms is another
really good one to mention talking about
Oni he he's doing his own thing now but
yeah hairy palms you make some really
good hash trails I wonder what he was
thinking when he chose that name like
I'm gonna be a me I'm a bad reader I'm
gonna rock the hairy palms name like
that's what's up I wrote him down man
the sourdough bin GMO yeah just like you
today and it did really well don't
forgot about some old-school doc atomic
spice of life
DJ short unlike a lot of bodis geared to
but can't really guy seems like the chem
dog cross with the 88 g 13 hash plant I
like that a lot sure yeah sure
greenhouse seeds in the house actually
from in our gear I got my Clementine
cookies and cream and what is it super
Lemon Haze has worked into that that's a
very super loud on the lemon side not
the favorite for the turf but very very
loudest thing around
super Lemon Haze garden of Greece down
in Southern Oregon
Trish Kirk that's another you to mention
as well that dude [ __ ] crushes we got
some bull punch here from Brandon
frickin amazing news about this he gave
me seeds of that we ran it here in the
in the greenhouse and it did absolutely
amazing you know clay stuck with a whole
grip of some sea repeat yeah he's a
great guy and he's breeding tons of
crazy genetic cell Rize you know all for
resin so check him out for sure he's you
know with well slept on your own food
and you know like he lives on that farm
his kitchen is outside in the hoop house
his I'll pack his feed everything that
he does you know he's a mini soil log
it's it's a crazy thing to go check that
man out you know like go follow him on
Instagram Chris Kirk because he's
trusted him and Scott were the ones that
taught me everything I know so you know
making a full Mel you know coach Kirk
yeah Chris Kirk yeah he's the min he's
got the real OG KB - I thought I invited
him to this he was one of the people
that never got back maybe not but
dragonfly earth medicine hooked me up
with ganja Gil and Kirk push Kirk's
email and pretty sure yeah we'll have to
go to him one of us will have to go to
him that's it we send you up to the
world with the sack with the sack
computer do some live streaming yeah
yeah no for sure
dragon flyers - definitely a video of
Jill and I was lucky enough in with
Brandon with that guy Chris Kirk how to
make hash it was quite an experience you
know is a crazy thing to get to
that time with him at his garden you
know and washing material and seeing how
he lives his life every day and having
it explained to me you know what the
plate means to him and it's it's really
a beautiful thing that process was crazy
you know I think about it all the time
and how grateful I am to be able to get
to go in and share that experience with
him
it was crazy is truly life-changing for
sure yeah man let's gonna say that
visiting his farm we went up there for
the harvest party this year that [ __ ]
literally like change my life man Vimeo
a new breath of life coming out of his
property yeah we'll live in the dream
immigrate on thing they have going on up
there
that's awesome good to hear well we'll
definitely get coach Kirk in the house
one of these days if it works out we'll
get him yeah anyway anyone else want to
bring anything up for the last 20
minutes or so we got 20 more minutes to
rock and roll on this hash episode go
ahead say something about the breeding I
don't I'm not a breeder but I really
like it whenever people are trying to
find those cultivars that work well with
the water hash or just hash making cuz a
lot of them aren't you know like a lot
of them that we probably love or the
smell is amazing it's just gonna wash
right down the disposal you know it'd be
a total waste to make hash out of it so
if you can flakes if genetics and try to
find maybe similar or or maybe it's the
same profile is the one that's washing
down the disposal but it's now viable
and the bag set I mean I know that takes
a lot of work and I it's really awesome
what's going on these days actually with
the hashing to lend back into the better
strain work in the new poly hybrid day
that we're in for cannabis really at
least personally as seeing the resins
get pulled out this way naturally real
raw and then you know feeding it back
into which type of cultivars we're
looking for what we're trying to produce
to create those is really teaching me a
lot as a breeder and cultivator with
with the bubble hash being made on you
know without R&amp;D so it's like cirque
goes back and forth with it also
breeding for your environment just seems
totally smart if you have the
availability or if you're able to do
such such things
you're not only setting yourself apart
from the rest but it seems like India
just a better model if you have the if
you're if you at that level yeah I was
gonna say it's definitely definitely
important to find cultivars that do well
in your and like in your climate where
you're at you know we're in we're in
Michigan and so you know our GMO went
through
three three or four Frost's this year
froze solid
and then sprung back the next day I was
ready to go baby the real question is
been sitting in the cold room the whole
time that's what's up yeah this is our
workroom here two hours yeah yeah three
hours
forget about an hour and a half oh three
hours we've been talking about our love
of hash cultivars and flavors you know
one of the things that I've mentioned
this before maybe not super recently but
one of the things my company in art
health wants to do is in sort of close
conjunction with the tissue culture
company like Sega International is to
collect our data between the two of us
between the growers who are producing
the way they're growing get as many data
inputs as possible when we're making the
hash when we're making you know there's
seven varieties of extraction available
at our facility I'm gonna be running the
solvent list portion of it the dry sift
and mechanical you know water extraction
and rosin and maybe some terpene
extractions collecting all of that data
will really help uncover more of these
cultivars and really start understanding
the cultivars not based on someone's
name because it's a specific cut but
starting to understand them under the
chemo Varick makeup that they actually
are which is really what they are to us
what is the terpene profile what is the
cannabinoid profile what are they
together
because to me that's what that cultivar
is and with people naming things so many
different names and having so many
different cuts and making mistakes and
even just being deceptive it really sort
of spoils the
hot and I like the idea of us getting to
a point where you know something easy
you know where you can just test and be
like oh this is this is that this you
know you can connect it to the name
still but the name will be secondary
you know makeup of the plant will be
will be first and foremost what grows it
makes a huge difference in what what
your you're gonna find when you go into
the washroom with it I mean I give I 24k
cut out two or three people I grow it
outside in Laytonsville which is in
Mendocino I get a lot of shade we get
maybe seven full hours and Sunday in the
middle of summer I've given it to my
friends who grow it in a different
microclimate that gets a little warmer
and they get direct Sun from sunup to
sundown and they're only I'm only
getting you know they're doing basically
same soil mix that I am same Feeny
program I am and the monster Gardens I
hit about three and a half percent off
my garden I hit five and a half to six
percent and that's got me a character
better probably my my hall around mine's
better that's part of the data so
collecting and running a hundred or two
hundred different growers all of that
data will be collected how did they grow
what was their climate what was their
their their you know was it indoor was
that outdoor was that organic was it's
all grown all of these things will feed
into that data plan because at that
point it'll be like well where are you
you know because these are cultivars
that have been grown around you and
these are cultivars that have been grown
around you in using the methodologies
that are similar to what you're growing
there's a lot of data points I'm just
excited at creating something like a
digital landscape out of those data
points that can be navigated to you know
to give us I totally agree we mean I
have a stack you know from this year of
paperwork from you know we just keep
track of our runs what we pull you know
when it was ran all that kind of stuff
is not as many data points as you're
talking about but it's fun to be able to
go back and look at you know the same
strain grown in different areas or just
different conditions at your farm say
the July depth versus you know a late
season depth or full-term plant and just
the differences
it's you know terroir terroir has a big
play on how things grow and it'll give
people their unique aspect in this world
cannabis community and industry because
you know you might live in a terroir
well that just produces something unique
and different from other terroirs that's
generally how it works
you know things find us where they shop
yeah I think the data points really go
back to what Sam was sad too beginning
to with Ava automate things you need to
have all those data points we would do
that so I mean even to where some where
things are grown like different areas
we've taken a lot of things from a lot
of different parts of the state and I
see like a lot of different strains come
out of a lot different in different
areas of the state so keeping all the
different data and all that stuff I
think is goes back to like exactly we
were saying where you need to keep them
as as detailed as possible what the soil
it's grown and if it's all grown if it's
not like you try to keep all that data
and I think like you said it's going to
be what's important at the end
we'll help us navigate the future that's
that's a guarantee and it'll help us you
know like not make silly mistakes like
an example I use all the time when
people are like well how how are your
different modalities of extraction gonna
help any company that's growing and it's
like well a really basic example would
be but you know say you were wanting to
dude rice if then you were a grower and
you didn't really realize that as a
grower who wants to do dry Safet it's
probably gonna be best that you get a
cultivar that produces the majority of
the trichomes are capitate stock and
capitate sessile the bulbous heads tend
to just stick to the leaves and they're
not as effective at coming off with
mechanical screen separations or even
water extraction and I've also often
noticed because I'd see these oil guys
go oh yeah yeah we're getting a 25%
yield and I'm like that's weird because
like the same water hash same material
is getting like a 14 percent to 15 and
that's dry you know that the true return
and I just wondered why is that
happening and what I put it together was
that they're accessing you know what
they thought back in the day was that
there were they were accessing resin
that was inside the plant well from what
I had learned from science that wasn't
really something that was happening I
learned that all the resin was being
sort of created inside the glandular
trichomes inside that little sort of
laboratory and so I I figured out with
my macro photography look these bulbous
heads are sticking around even after
they're washed so the cultivars like
Renee and the ones that really rained
like hash plants for me were ones that
had very small percentage of those heads
I would macro photographs some people's
plants and I'd swear 50% of the heads on
the plant were these bulbous heads and I
thought wow now imagine you're a big
company you want to make dry sift and
you roll the dice wrong and you get a
cultivar that just has 50% of these
bulbous heads and you put all this
investment in time and money into it and
you're trying to you know grow great
weed and dry it and tear it properly and
now when you just start doing your
sifting you're like we're only getting
like a five or a six percent yield
that's like yeah you would have been
getting to 12 to a 15% yield had you
just understood that these different
types
of trichomes are accessible in different
ways
and so I'm excited to sort of create
those data points as well
um one thing that we hadn't touched on
much either that I think plays a huge
part is just harvest and prep and
storage I think that is honestly just as
big as your whole your whole run
throughout the whole year and your wash
and your dry - just because I know I've
noticed a lot of differences in the
gardens and not only yield in quality
but even just at the time I harvested a
plant you know I like to harvest plants
later in the afternoon and at nighttime
and you know try and harvest and the
colder hours just cuz I've noticed you
know when I pulled stuff in the daytime
or early mornings and it just starts to
get hot while you're working and fresh
frozen that stuff just starts to get
sticky and almost grease in the bags and
it just makes it a lot harder to work
with when you know you put it in water
and ice and it's tough it's just one of
the things I've noticed you know with
outdoor resin in full Sun resin what
goes back to that chef SOP you know you
want to make sure your grower is doing
that through and through because we've
all seen Triple A or quads or whatever
they're calling it now 10 is in a row or
whatever the highest-quality herb can
really be deteriorated by multiple great
points by being improperly cured and
improperly stored so that's sort of
post-processing that you know
pre-processing what getting it ready and
preparing it I think the grower in the
hash maker really have to have a line of
communication there
yeah the prep work is huge going from
two facilities that are on there are on
the REC market and seen two different
ways of prepping material it makes a
huge difference you know versus putting
into it all trays stacking it up real
high and letting the resin sit on each
other versus harvesting straight off the
plant in a cold room in a cold grow room
it's dark straight into small freezer
bags that go right into the freezer
that's the method that we really prefer
to do it's the same people the same few
people doing it every time so and it is
all in-house so the lab that I wash it
is you know feet away from where
although the resin is being thrown all
the material so it's easy to be able to
see the plant see the materials see how
it's being handled you know and it takes
multiple freezers to do that to store
you know a hundred thousand grams of
fresh frozen takes a couple large
freezers you know to keep it in small
bags spread out so you're not putting a
bunch of it's few on top of each other
and compromising the material it's
really important if you are trying to
make full melt and not just a rose and
great production you know ash if there's
a big difference for that Bobby I've
seen a hundred thousand grams slammed
into one freezer and I could tell you
that [ __ ] was kind of a nightmare
yeah I like a [ __ ] ice can we had to
do the longest soak on it just to get
those brick is a bit more you know yeah
there was no pulling melt off this stuff
we just we got rid of the 90 and 120 bag
caught it on the seven depressed at all
yeah it were it was like yeah dude for
sure you don't want to be over pack in
those bags you don't want to be doing
bags that are too heavy
like you can leave it all the day
outdoors fresh frozen like yeah now the
Terps getting cooked off can see the
resin just smearing all over everything
just flying everywhere to prepare your
plant matter properly and make sure that
people aren't doing stupid [ __ ] with it
if you're not this if you're not the
source of your plant matter definitely
have
says to the grow yeah I'd want to be
going and having full access to be able
to test anything I wanted to to be able
to look at anything I wanted to open any
door drawer I want to I want to just
know that the cannabis is is being
properly grown and if it hasn't or
wasn't that's okay too because those are
really important lessons where you can
kind of learn it's okay if you're doing
it wrong because doing it wrong is
literally how you learn how to do it
right if that isn't the craziest [ __ ]
ever so don't feel bad if you are doing
it wrong out there there's a lot of good
points that people have dropped today in
regards to genetics and breeders and
little tips and tricks and pre pro press
pre pro pressing and processing posts
with sieving and micro planing I was
kind of space on the micro planning so
yeah they're very different things
there's lots of different big
information that's been dropped today
definitely want to come back to do more
of this want to apologize to the entire
group of rosin people I had Lucchese
when you see I had well Rackham's he's
just been working like it covert
extracts Pedro's grow room Roxy Grey
ogre resins dog man troop and Goldilocks
who made it into the hash so I don't
have to apologize to you but sorted
those advising gals that we didn't make
it in today I appreciate your
understanding the hash conversation just
seemed to be able to go the full three
hours and I'll just plan it for next
week if you know we'll get 15 or so
people so I already have 8 or 9 so
there's room for some more want to hit
me up on Instagram or some of these guys
as a panel want to do it you can hit me
up thank you all coming in from
bestfriend farms to Goldilocks to taste
of cascade true hash company too heavy
ice and great lake grease look sauce
winery and resident ranch extractions
Adam Lee Simpson damn it Bobby Rackham's
of course and ganja Gil set in the tone
with the with the like this means more
to me I like that dude I really did it
means more to me too I think that's one
of the reasons you know it takes me down
many different avenues but the source
has always been that it means more to me
as well and that's why I give it a great
deal of respect to treat it you know
like the Queen that it is and just try
and see everyone have access to this
beautiful beautiful plant and resin that
we are also obsessed with so you know
thanks everyone for hanging out on this
hash tour don't make sure thanks for
having us if you guys thank you if you
if you guys want a shout out where you
can be found on Instagram I think that
would be fair I'll also put it in the
comments section and I'll also post it
in the comments of the Spotify Google
and Apple podcast sites that this will
be showing up in on the next few hours
so you want to start a best friend just
like it sounds
at best friend farms Instagram
Goldilocks Goldilocks seven-ton and on
Instagram and that's ello ex-lax word
true hash at true hash company beautiful
taste of Cascadia taste of Cascadia and
six star society
sixth our society I like that heavy ice
heavy ice rx Great Lakes grease perfect
Instagram look Oh a muted hi me Anna
what sauce winery and then at fully
melted CA as well right resin underscore
ranch under store extraction he did like
six times I bet you only picked our
Instagram name some of us didn't think
that it'd be like damn wanted to put
those [ __ ] underscores and dog
periods and [ __ ] things that don't
fit into the human language when I'm
trying to tell people where my website
let's check ate Adam gotta unmute yeah
simply Adam so at simply dot Adam okay
thank you
damn it Bobby you know yeah you can find
me a damn it Bobby you can find their
ass here in Portland if you're in
Portland of the area at archives
Portland and Burnside collective gardens
so feel free to check us out word
Rackham's unmute yourself there you go
raccoons right there are a KK EMS
beautiful need no introduction ganja
gala at ganja underscore Gill on
Instagram and my more hash motivated
page is at the real ice what real nice
work I like it well i'm bc bubble man
here on bubble man's world thank you
everyone you know for those of you that
it hasn't happened yet made the full
belt bless your bowl sooner than later
peace out everybody thank you all so
much