hey guys okay we're back let's see if
our sound is improved can you let me
know in the chat how the sound is okay
I'm gonna send out the link to some
people so okay so yeah everyone back in
here okay sorry about that everybody so
let's see okay okay so the sound is
better now um so yeah we'll just wait if
everyone could just share I'm not sure
if the link is updated since I changed
it but anyway yeah as we were saying
thanks again last week for everyone
watching and sharing and I think getting
our view count were almost up to 8,000
on our women's episode and so yeah I was
just giving a shout out again to some of
the women who came on so Hillary was
co-hosting with me and dr. Marcia Gilman
we also had Sarah Russo from Project CBD
Wendy Turner who's Colton Turner's mom
she's been on a few episodes before I
invited her to come on today to join us
so we'll see if she can pop on to say
hello we also had aundrea Herrmann I
also invited her back again
she has a lot of knowledge especially
with just hemp and nutrition and even
animal nutrition and different ways of
debating our endocannabinoids system not
just with the cannabis plant but with
other herbs and nutrients so she was has
a lot to contribute to the conversation
we also had Rosie monden Erin also owns
and CEO of quadrant extraction and yeah
we also had Mischa Whitley of author of
chronic relief she was also had a lot to
contribute to the conversation she had
some interesting stories to share about
her mother who had lung cancer and a
nice conversation came up about using
cannabis not only for medical purposes
but also for end-of-life purposes and to
help people die with dignity and so
that's what inspired Nisha to write her
book which is the full title is chronic
relief a guide to cannabis for the
terminally and chronically ill and check
out her book I haven't personally read
the whole book but I've looked through
the whole syllabus and overview of the
book and she does a really nice job of
giving an overview of the medical
applications of cannabis breaks it down
and a really easy to use and really to
understand why it's a book I suggested
my parents check out who are new to
cannabis I also recently suggested it to
someone who contacted me about more
information about cannabis for cancer
because she includes a lot of recipes
simple ways to prepare cannabis
different ways to apply it including
edible topical suppositories and yeah
it's just a really nice overview dr.
Ethan Russo wrote the intro and he's the
person who actually introduced me to
Nisha so she is she's really awesome
check out her book we also had natasha
ray on she was she's also great a great
addition and I mean I like it because we
have similar names
Natasha residues hash array so what's
not to like about
that we also had Amanda Siebert the
journalist for Georgia straight and so
she is their official cannabis
journalist here in Vancouver and so
that's really exciting and she was great
to have on I've also invited her back
because I mean it's always nice to have
and also people to who are excited to
cover what we're talking about here and
yeah we also had well dr. Michelle Ross
PhD she popped in I read her bio but
unfortunately she had some tech
difficulties so we'll try to get her
back in hello hey oh my god it's just
yeah it's just me yeah basically that's
just having a date how's it going all
right
how are you how do you see yeah yeah
it's so nice to see you it's funny cuz
after he sent me a little hey nice nice
episode message Dave and I were saying
hey we need to have a catch up with mark
and then yeah didn't didn't expect it to
be live but yeah we are here we are
right right well greetings from one and
only New York City we're here seeing a
bunch of fish shows oh that's wonderful
is yeah so uh I'll see I had a few
shoutouts to make let's see people keep
on coming up to me and like hey dr. mark
from mash Church what's up and they
always like to see see me out having a
good time with it with the with the
folks so yeah it's cool I don't know
what to say I'm just completely
blissed-out have you been following this
no tell me tell me more so you're there
with your family yeah so usually yes I'm
here with my wife my daughter and we're
just up for this weekend and so fish the
band fish with the pH yes that band
usually plays like a summer tour but
this
some are out east here they decided to
do a 13 show residency at Madison Square
Garden right probably most haloed rock
venue in New York City so it's 13 shows
so they're calling it the baker's dozen
which is kind of cool because I guess
Baker's would always throw in the 13th
doughnut to make the so called baker's
dozen so yeah to cover their ass right
to make sure that they were getting
getting good products out to their
customers so I guess even back to
medieval times they talked about the
baker's dozen being a very very
important thing that enabled loyalty to
the throne somehow so yeah crazy stuff
so each night they have a different
flavored doughnut and so the first night
opening night that the flavored doughnut
was coconut so they they covered the
Schmilsson tomb put the lime in the
coconut and drink it all out and so
every coconut theme song they try to
fill their whole set with coconut theme
songs last night it was strawberries so
strawberry doughnuts was the theme last
night and so we got what was that name
of that tune again strawberry letter 23
strawberry letter 23 and Strawberry
Fields they opened up with the Beatles
Strawberry Fields playing at acapella it
was just so cool sorry about the no hash
content here but just tell them you like
what we're doing here in New York and
it's a lot of fun and so each night
there's a new doughnut and what they do
the band just does a creative vortex has
been taken the theme of that doughnut
and putting it back into the set so for
tight the doughnut is a red velvet
doughnut with cream cheese and so
there's a lot of speculation that there
will be some Velvet Underground covers
because of the velvet fish has got a
song called waiting in the Velvet C so
we'll certainly hear a Velvet see but
each night is a different doughnut and
so
we're thinking like the Boston cream
doughnut they'll play some Boston covers
you know or maybe for the powdered you
know doughnut they would do God knows
you know Neil Young powder fingers up
you know so each theme each night is a
different theme so it's kind of cool is
this something look forward to and they
give doughnut somebody to and doughnuts
are notably the most wonderful food that
Canada has brought to the world right
isn't that what's going on everybody
hey Marcus how's it going we can hear me
pretty good you're on your end
there's a little bit of an echo but
that's just because Sam I think is not
muting his mic yeah I just muted I think
we've got everyone muted okay and did we
get Brian from Vitol invited my email
that I sent yeah yeah I got him the
email because he hasn't received it
either ends Dragonfly medicine they're
both waiting okay I get it
okay I'll try sending it one more time
one moment take the floor and all I'll
resend them but yeah tell us what you're
up to and I'll I'll work on that
well we are here in Montego Bay Jamaica
we had our products registered with the
Minister of Health recently here in
Jamaica the prana CBD products and so
today we are training the doctors and
the pharmacists who will be prescribing
this medicine in the upcoming months
here in the Caribbean and Jamaica and so
it's pretty exciting these are a lot of
there obviously educated doctors that
they don't have a lot of education in
the end of a cannabinoid system they
don't have a lot of education when it
comes to cannabis when you talk to the
majority of them they seem to be a lot
from the sort of knidos standpoint you
know the majority of things I think
they've seen over the years for the
negative you know a lot of them believe
that cannabis is addictive but if you
smoke cannabis in the morning you're
addicted to it and sort of there's
there's a little bit of that sort of
NIDA mental
the but at the same time when you talk
to them they're very receptive and open
to education to proper information and
they're they're intelligent people so I
think it's gonna be a pretty exciting
day tony has built an absolutely
stunning deck it's about 65 pages long
going through the entire mission of our
company from John Barr fellows patience
story this guy right here yeah that's
the guy
to the processing history of our company
to the history of even the master
breeder himself you know everyone's
represented we're trying to build a
pretty cool little thing and we're just
getting that much closer to making
Jamaica a reality where our company can
be here and actually be producing be
producing wealth for the country and for
the company hey welcome Brian from Vitol
good morning good morning sorry took me
a minute to click in always technical
issues here with me yes well you know
what when I'm in Jamaica it's always
technical information I think I'm
literally sitting above four blenders
right now like look at these guys are
like blending like crazy it's a blank
party over there I need to set up the
dab bar for real I hope my background
noise isn't too loud let me know I'll
try to keep my mic muted as often as
possible yeah same here
I changed headphones so hopefully these
ones don't have the feedback like last
time no you sound good I can't but that
[Music]
so it wasn't my I'm when I was speaking
when Natasha opened up the first church
so I want to start over again by
absolutely thanking all the women who
came into hash Church last week and just
crushed it it was very impressive I
learned a lot from watching the ladies
interact with one another
I've always felt like any type of pause
is like not good and we shouldn't have
them but after watching the ladies and
having they will talk and then they
would all stop and there'd be like cuz I
just thought it was really nice and
there was something that we could learn
from that particular experience I love
the information that the women shared I
loved how they consistently kept the
panel full for the entire
oh that was really impressive and just
great job organizing and moderating
Natasha as well as Hillary black you
guys both did a stand-up bang-up job and
everyone I don't I can't even name them
all but it really was an impressive
church and we're definitely gonna get
more of those women back and we'll try
to do some more all-women panels because
I think it's just good I think it's
unique I'm not into segregating I'm not
into you know keeping certain people out
but I think that the woman panel the all
woman panel really it impressed me I was
very impressed
well thanks that was it was fun to do
and like I said on on Facebook like
thank you for trusting me to its take
over and thanks for I mean we put that
together in a week that was very even a
last minute show just I threw it out all
my contacts and yeah for anyone who
feels like they weren't included please
like we're gonna do this again this was
just a last minute thing even really I
was overwhelmed with all the women that
could take part and yeah it's it's not
about the women taking over or anything
like that it's about as Marcus said us
joining you guys let's let's do this
together
I've even invited some more of the women
from last week to come join us today and
yeah let's just have conversations about
cannabis and I'll learn together so
thanks again Marcus absolutely one of
the conversations that was very
impressed which Hillary opened up with
which was the section cannabis talk you
know it almost as though the men are too
immature it's a conversation we've never
even breached because you can only
imagine I mean even when we talk about
suppositories it turns into a search
we're just guys we can't help it but it
was nice and refreshing to hear the
women talking about the topic sex and
cannabis use and I just I give you guys
all thumbs up it was a really really
nice show my wife enjoyed it I know a
lot of our wives enjoy
that mean women all around the world
just saying about time hello sir
apologies for taking 146 episodes to
make it happen but we made it happen so
I'm going to be able to hang out
probably only for another half an hour
to an hour I've got to go do this
triplets uh yeah maybe we could get to
get a little bit more information from
Brian I know people have been really
enjoying the greenhouse talks the
growing talks and what's going on all
right
garden supplies you're in California
you're in the epicenter of cannabis
growing in the entire world I doubt that
there's a larger cannabis community
larger cannabis industry anywhere than
in California maybe Sam knows somewhere
that I don't know but wouldn't you say
California is the market Sam Oh what
about Morocco Lebanon Afghanistan yep
yep just seems like California just has
that purchasing power of buying a lot I
wonder how much of that hash ends up
down there all right Bhangra long rap
hey how about we start by giving a
wonderful happy birthday to his Imperial
Majesty the conquering Lion of Judah
Emperor Haile Selassie born on July 23rd
God what was it 1868 or something he was
a long time ago for sure but prot around
red green yes sorry
yeah Jah Rastafari Selassie and props to
all my rest a blender in that that use
him as a guiding light in their lives
yeah give thanks give thanks you guys
are down in Jamaica
exactly are you high right now oh yeah I
can hear you perfect Brian okay good
good yeah so Jamaica you guys are having
fun
yeah you know it was a good time I'm in
Jamaica we went and visited a field the
other day we went and visited a
processing facility and a packaging
plant that will potentially be able to
package up medicines we've got this
doctor conference which is gonna be a
big one and yeah just kind of going
forward from there you know as they say
in Jamaica forward ever back we're over
it welcome Joshua hey family medicine
yeah dragonfly medicine in the house we
got it dragon fire medicine representing
a little choppy kind of can hear you but
I'm sure technical difficulties fixed
here soon use your best you're kind of
breaking up a little bit station it's
reading the chat
hey guys I just want to let everyone
know I don't like just my clothes I'll
probably hear you a little bit better
you guys aren't oh sorry just hold on
the spring market okay and here you can
you hear me Natasha no they're not
coming through I don't hear them yeah we
can hear you Marcus I can hear you yeah
where's that tenant I know he's
notoriously absent here anyone talk
hello hello Jan is traveling today yes I
can't hear that's okay wait a second
John's wonderful headphones let's try
again
hey there Natasha no I can't hear
anything
sorry guys I'm gonna blouse you guys
hopefully you can make it work okay can
you guys hear me and just like that he's
gone I think yeah anyway hi I'm Natasha
I'm hosting for Markus today nice to
meet everyone so yeah if if we're all
speaking I'll just be muting people's
mics if we're all so don't just so you
know and then unmute and pop back in
when you're ready to talk so we don't
get sound feedback but yeah welcome
everyone and if you want please tell us
a little bit about what you guys do
sorry who just jumped in I don't know if
you had a chance to say anything yet
okay Joshua and Kelly yes Joshua and
Kelly hi nice to meet you okay so let's
R is your sound or King okay Amy Harris
now okay yeah we can hear you right
awesome Kelly and we're from dragonfly
earth medicine and we own a inoculant
company in both Canada and the US and
also Europe but primarily were 27 years
cannabis farmers
appear in BC and we've just done a lot
of Education with organics and living
off the land closed-loop systems really
learning how to grow cannabis without
anything without any help other than
another nature and how that raises
cannabinoid levels and terpene levels so
often so often nice so in Canada do you
grow outdoors under lights in a
greenhouse what's our set up primarily
in interesting greenhouses and outdoors
greenhouses for 25 years no we were we
used to do gorilla grows way out in the
bush and we started growing in
greenhouses once I got our medical
license about seven years ago
I mean we've grown every way in the last
27 years kind of thing you know well for
27 years like the first garden yes over
the course of time we've lived on this
land for 11 years and made it an amazing
thing so well tell us more about the
inoculant ok the inoculants are
basically made out of different herbs so
I am a health care provider I work with
women and children in the third world as
well as on the cannabis farmer so I'm
the Midwife as well as I have it back
what background in naturopathic medicine
and I have always gone to disaster
relief zones to help women and children
out like after Haiti after the tsunami
and we utilize what's around the area to
help bring nutrition to the women and
children so a lot of times when there's
a cut-off or you can't get supplies that
you need in zones and areas which is a
lot like what we're in NBC we utilize
the natural herbs to get vitamins
minerals or trace minerals and then we
lose the immune system so our entire
herbal inoculant is based off of health
and well-being for women primarily so
it's a pregnancy tea blend
Julie and then you add different fungi
and bacteria to it make a brew voila it
just happens to be amazing for cannabis
plants as well and over the course of
the years by working with women and
pregnant women along with plants and
herbalist herbalism and mycology you can
see the placenta change you can see the
women change you can see the healthy
baby change you're working with
malnutrition human beings that live a
third world life and you're giving them
simple vitamins or even just telling
them to drink the Moringa tree more or
eat the tapioca greens more and you can
see how the placenta changes and and all
of the vital signs change and
everything's great and then we're
growing herbs and plants the whole time
to create the medicine for the women and
then we're starting to treat the plants
like the like the women and then we
started realizing you know the beauty of
of using plant medicine on plants so and
then watching the health of the plants
changed due to it and then we lived far
away in the mountains up here so it was
a bit of a necessity and so we just
dropped out of society essentially for a
really long time and just did our work
and did that work across the world in
here and then we started our dragonfly
earth medicine ten years ago now so it's
ten years ago we made our first product
which was lush roots our mycorrhizal
inoculum based off Southern Oregon and
the monumental growing that happens down
there and the mythical amazing families
that have been doing it forever along
with Northern California you know the
the Maiko teas back in the day where it
were a big kind of like thing that that
jumped planted health a lot so we
started on that level and they started
working with herbs and bacteria so it's
been a long process lots of different
steps into trying to find Health for
soil primarily and it just so happened
that it mimicked health for women and
children as well that's really
interesting can you tell us a little bit
more you mentioned you also put some
other herbs that were good for the
immune
system I'm interested in the immune
system so yeah you tell me a little bit
more about that yeah well for our
vegetating plants that didn't work sorry
for vegetating plants we do Nettles
horse tail alfalfa we utilized wild yam
because it's also a natural stimulant
for hormones as well let's see we've got
burdock root in there we work with a
wild turkey rhubarb root what else do we
need a comfrey spirulina raw cacao I
think that's about it and they're all
sort of inner blended in there you add
the bacteria then you add it into a brew
or as a top dress into a soil and then
immediately the microbiology starts to
break down that those herbs herbal
compounds so it makes it readily
available to the plants how did you
choose your microbes did you choose like
microbes to be broad-spectrum or did you
choose some specifics for specific
purposes we primarily chose them because
they're organic so you know the basis of
our product is all definitely organic we
go all the way down the lines to try to
find out exactly you know where our
herbs come from whether it's wild
crafted or we go to the farm itself and
it's human grade organic not for use in
agriculture organic which we'll get into
later being a big difference so we use
that five different bacterial blend that
is grown off of non GMO substrate and
that's really the only organic one that
we can find in the industry that's
readily available and that we know where
it comes from yes here's the opportunity
for a great educational moment which is
that you know bacteria again often get
you know bacteria the bad guy actually
you know the plant relies on a healthy
microbial population to help fix
nitrogen because nitrogen fixation is a
very high-energy process and bacteria
have this ship figured out man prions
and you can't read
and so everything that kind of came
after on the food chain came based on
the bacteria's ability to fix nitrogen
and what we're talking about is atomic
nitrogen which is inert an inert gas
that's 79% of the atmosphere but when it
gets fixed it gets put into soluble form
and and it's a nitrogen molecule gets
turned into an amine and the amine are
like the amino acids which are
absolutely essential building blocks for
proteins for all living organisms and so
again if you try to fight bacteria I
mean I'm not saying that you know again
the guy who doesn't wash his hands after
using the lavatory or you know it
doesn't have good sanitary hygiene
practices bacteria there's a whole host
of good ones and bad ones and I think we
have to you know use this as an
educational moment to let people know
that not all bacteria is bad some
bacteria is bad and certainly you can't
just use broad-spectrum any microbial
biocides because it wipes out some of
these lower rungs in the food chain
ladder that the rest of the the latter
relies on and so when you knock out the
ability for microbes to nitrogen
fixation you have to rely on nitrogen
input and now you're talking about
fertilizer so again I think what you're
what you're doing is really great and I
think we have to figure out a way that
we can use
mother nature's chemistry set which has
had the time course of evolution to sort
of unfold and reveal itself to us yeah
that's actually what we're big on it
vital is combining microbes and NPK
obviously only organic forms of NPK
we're big on using compost teas and
microbial inoculants to break down and
okay it's balanced it's they have it
figured out it's a it's a game of pH but
it's also a game of you know there's a
whole host of things going on in there
some of it I'm probably sure we still
don't quite understand but
I think we take lessons from mother
nature because she's had her chemistry
set a lot longer than we got yeah no no
no I'm no scientist but I have a lot of
experience growing and farming yes you
are you're scientists you just don't
know it well I'm not accredited let's
put it that way and definitely the
microbes make the NPK available to the
plants so it can actually grow all these
people found in their plants with salts
and feeding feeding feeding the plant
can only take so much especially if
there's not a microbe to break it down
and in salt form well and again this is
like we were talking about this a couple
weeks ago about having roots in the
ground you know as opposed to roots in a
kiddie pool or a tires of you know
flower pots I think when roots are in
the ground you're now tapping into
mother earth herself which has a whole
different biome than recreated soil or
hydroponics or Rock well it's just it's
it's it's it's a whole different game
there's a whole bunch of actors that are
involved and because of that it right
need to like chain themselves to I'm
actually seeing people like go from
container growing into ground their bed
growing and then they realize they don't
have to water as much and like the foods
in the soil and the and then my carbons
and the carbon plant has evolved
underneath this light spectrum for eons
disrespectful to our own evolution we're
just trying to be better than mother
nature at that point scientists right we
could take from Mother Nature what we
can learn and share it in venues like
this so we can get people thinking at a
higher level of you know knowledge which
is great yeah and you know you talk
about putting plants in pots or you know
in kiddie pools and stuff and now we're
really starting to realize through
observation is that cannabis is a social
plant they like to be
next to each other they like to speak to
one another they like to share what's
going on with one another not only in
their upper leaf and canopy section but
also in their roots so this idea of
separating root zones just isn't really
good for the health not only is it not
good for the soil their microbial
breakdown but it's not it's not good for
the plants as well as their uptake we've
been doing a tremendous amount of
research on CBG because it's the one
thing that we're really looking for you
know CPG is that amazing catalyst so a
lot in our and our genetics here we find
that CBG is going up higher with the
same genetics the same soil everything
is the same but if we're planting the
two plants next to each other we're
realizing you know where the roots can
intermingle and the roots can have
communication that the CBG levels along
with all the other cannabinoids are
going up and also we do know for a fact
that trees communicate within different
species like out of their own species
they can get a pine tree can get sugars
from a birch tree or you know I can come
up with much different trees so why
wouldn't a cannabis farm continue
communicating with all of the flowers
trees around it and around it yeah I
mean it's it's just it's a it's a
beautiful thing about let's call it it's
called quorum sensing quorum sensing and
chemical ecology is the way by which
bacteria sort of communicate with 20
another and it's it's a language of
chemistry which makes me really
appreciate it again what I think mike
rizzo also is a plants to communicate
through one another I want to go back to
a point you you brought up about high
CBD high CBG strains or you're seeing
prevalence and high CBD CBG so let's
let's dial Sam into this discussion so
Sam that basically means that they have
a down regulated synthase that's not
able to process the CBG into its
productive and use product well maybe
more
productive any news products THC and CBD
so I wonder if there's a a mutant or a
variety somewhere that we could identify
based on a loss of synthase expression
genetically and so what that says is
that you're backing up the cannabinoid
pathway after that first crucial
carbon-carbon bond formation between all
talvik acid and and and when it first
gets preen elated and so that's the
formation of CB GA which happens and so
it's a sort of the stem what they call
the stem cell cannabinoid which I think
is funny but why wouldn't those so are
there mutations in those in those
varieties where we can actually examine
why the synthase is not sort of keeping
up to produce CBD and and THC from that
because they've now there's technology
where they can actually do the CBG in
yeast which is you know scientifically
an extraordinary achievement I don't
know why you'd want to make CBD or CPG
and yeast but maybe again when
cannabinoids get more accepted as just
mainstay vitamins and nutrients for the
human diet they'll be making CBG in
yeast which can then go into a variety
of food and perhaps other products for
human consumption just to start to get
CVG in the diet but yeah I just want to
get Sam Sam's input on the synthase so
why would those synthesis sort of not I
mean could we look for like the same
type of mutant that you see in Skunk one
which has a dysfunctional CBD synthase I
missed the other part of it because I
was in the other room looking up a
bacteria which is prohibited from
Australia I was just curious what it was
and so I didn't hear the beginning part
of your question well we were just
talking about high CBG
riot ease and and does that basically
mean does not make any economic sense
when you can grow develop varieties with
yield 10% by dry weight and yeast yields
less than that and they are not really
doing it yet right the whole point of
cannabinoids that they work together
what's the purpose of isolating one of
the cannabinoids without its whole
family near it okay that's one really
positive thing when you smoke THC with
the right terpenes what other
cannabinoids do you actually need you
don't if you want to get recreationally
high from from cannabis you want THC you
don't want any other to navigate sand
escapes cv actually I'm more interested
if you smoke CBD with THC it delays
onset reduces peak experience makes it
last longer but who wants some people
are last longer that's not as good hey
who says it's not as good what does it
have to be potent to be good that's not
wrong I'm pretty good at judging this
[Laughter]
not for recreational use maybe for some
medical use but for recreational use
that's not true recreational is medical
that's what you think but it's certainly
not what I think well the whole entire
reason that we're sitting here right now
with the ability to talk out in the open
is because of medical and the beauty of
the cannabinoids in the plants so why
does it change when it's recreational
it's the same if it's make feel good why
isn't that medical if all of a sudden
I'm having a really shitty day I'm
smoking a doobie it makes me feel better
I'm gonna think better thoughts why
isn't that medicine you're agonizing
you're cb1 receptors which is the most
prevalent receptor in the human brain
and so that's not a happy accident
the reason why we feel so good when we
enjoy a cannabis so it's the lock
fitting in the key and we just dumped a
lot of keys and we have a lot of lots by
any chance of you guys for recreational
purposes only
forget medical just for the moment and
for recreational purposes only have you
ever smoked a pure THC and then added
one by one the other cannabinoids and
seen what the difference is I have your
muted we didn't hear that I didn't hear
the last part of it we didn't know we
don't we've never done this broad
statements as though you really
understand I'm not really sure if we're
necessarily making broad statements as
much as we're just really trying to say
that we feel that recreational is
medical and think I'm gonna stick with
that I feel like if it makes you feel
good and you're gonna go about your day
and it's gonna make you a better person
because you feel good did I consider
that you're saying that there's no one
recreational user out there that derives
no medical benefit from it or is seeking
any medical benefit not one in the in
the whole world I don't know where we're
going yeah I guess I'm a little confused
where we're headed
I think he's just trying to say for
recreational purposes what you need is
THC and the correct terpenes you don't
require the other cannabinoids for
recreational and use okay that's your
perspective I get it that makes a lot of
sense perspective let's agree to
disagree on that point because I think
you guys are coming up coming at at the
same point and I agree with what Sam
saying there's some people who are
consuming cannabis purely for as he's
referring to rec purposes ie to get high
but I also agree
that feeling good having that mood
elevation even that escapee one deserves
give you one agonism you can't stop yeah
and and I mean that to me I agree I feel
that that is medical and I guess I I
don't think we need to separate the two
but I get what you're saying that there
are purely you could say it's
recreational if someone's just taking it
with that intention in mind but why it
doesn't that also help drink alcohol it
makes them feel good is that medical use
of alcohol medical absolutely I don't
ever drink alcohol because I consider it
yeah it's just not for me
it makes me stupid that's the beautiful
thing but low amounts of alcohol are
very potent anxiety can help produce
anxiety very very effectively and so if
you don't consume alcohol that often and
you use a small amount it can be very
effective for reducing anxiety so it
definitely can have medical applications
but what you're talking about is when
people are consuming alcohol everyday
they often of course
cannabis consumed daily for stress
relaxation to help with anxiety isn't
gonna have the same additive problems as
something like alcohol can have Kara's
once in a while can be okay but I
absolutely agree with you
cannabis is not a toxic poison alcohol
absolutely but we can't deny that low
doses of alcohol do you have medical
applications and I mean even alcohol
topically alcohol for other things it is
a medicine also but it is a poison it's
all in the dose right it's the feeling
of the nation in cannabis but I mean I'm
I'm I'm always gonna say people should
choose cannabis to relax over alcohol
because it's safer over the long term I
agree
absolutely I don't use cannibal can't I
mean I don't use alcohol either but you
know it takes all colors of the rainbow
and there's a lot of different choices
out there so people are making all
different kinds of choices when they go
to light up that joint s the reason why
they're lighting up that joint you know
it may be that they've had a hard day it
may also be just because they want to
get high but I think that it's really
hard to separate it across the board
which each individual is utilizing it
for well mass-produce swill from
multi-billion dollar corporations
looking to hold cannabis prohibited art
the type of alkali mean I like my micro
brew or I like a single malt scotch a
glass of wine it's totally within reason
to think that again humans could have
both and you know Sam we love your
perspective but I think again we all
know that the reason why we feel so good
is because there is a biological action
in the brain call it you know whatever
you want but it's also adding to the
fact that we're putting a lot of fat
soluble antioxidants into our oedipus
tissue and that's slowly released over
time which gives a very prophylactic
effect over reactive oxygen species
which often form free radicals that can
start causing mutations like cancer and
whatnot so the fact that you're
basically ingesting cannabinoids which
have an endogenous system within our
body to regulate I mean think about it
this way the body's pharmaceutical
company is the end of cannabinoid system
right and so part of it is our art
through health we've talked about this
on church health and and also use of
cannabis we're fortifying those you know
immune systems that again have evolved
over the time course of evolution in
humans you know who are we to
second-guess it pharmaceuticals want to
you know give you a pill and yet again
the mentality is oh if I'm if I'm sick
there's a pill I could just take a pill
and it's you know I think cannabis
provides a different option to provide
wellness to yourself and whether you
think you're doing it recreationally
well yeah I'm doing it recreation
right now because I'm in New York I'm
hanging with my Bros and we're all
recreational doubt we're at the fish
we're gonna throw down and we're just
we're all recreational but the beautiful
thing is while we're being recreational
the molecules going into our bodies are
protecting us from cancer are helping
our bodies regulate the immune system in
the way our humans that were designed
and all of this all has to do with again
your own perspective so from Sam's
perspective hey humans are doing this
recreationally because I want to get
high I want to achieve something but
whether you're achieving that for that
reason or not like it or not your body
is being flooded with molecules that are
probably going to save you from things
like glioblastoma tumors I've had a
friend pass away from glioblastoma
that's the aggressive form of brain
cancer that they just announced I think
who's that John McCain one of the US
senators any in a way came down with but
the point is is that our prolonged
cannabis use has basically put CBD and
other antioxidants which are very very
important molecules to regulate reactive
oxygen species and so I do believe that
a prolonged cannabis use basically helps
protect the brain over your lifetime and
your brain is an extremely important
thing it's kind of like your harddrive
you know having brain your [__] so
you're basically putting medicine in and
even if you're doing it right for
recreational purposes like I am in New
York City I would agree that uh okay I'm
all recreational too now but I'm
basically feeding my endocannabinoids
system with these very beneficial
molecules that will help me stay alive
and and longer and be a little happier I
think most of us found cannabis in the
recreational form originally because
most of us have been around it so long
it was prior to any sort of medical
research or any of that so it's sort of
a blessing that we like fell into the
whole cannabis world and you know is it
cool to know
you know we were totally with it's
amazing like back in you know pre any of
these discussions before when everyone
was still hiding behind closed doors you
know we were experimenting with it and
now we have this like platform to like
really expand and help people and or or
or is it that we're just rediscovering
what we already knew you know which is
really interesting because I'm really
interested in autoimmune disorders it's
something that I've been interested in
for a really long time and I'm starting
to do a lot of research on MTHFR and
realizing that you know over half the
population of Euro descent have this
issue and along with this particular
type of mutation which a lot of us have
and don't even realize that we have if
if we're producing things in our body
that produce stress so there's all kinds
of toxins that come along with stress
that actually can turn that particular
mutation that a tremendous amount of
people on the planet have right now can
turn it right immediately into an
autoimmune disorder so the idea of
smoking cannabis are utilizing cannabis
can actually bring all of our levels
down it brings our cortisol levels down
it brings down all of the hormones in
our body which actually help us have a
stronger auto immune system absolutely
without it I don't think I'd be able to
do what I do trying to do is point out
that if your main goal is getting high
then what you want is THC in the right
terpenes none of the other terpenes
contribute to making you higher CBD can
delay onset reduce peak experience make
it last longer if that's what you want
but it's certainly not what I want but
even going back to the feeling high and
even like when you're with your friends
when you're having fun when you're
feeling connected when you're
of your ego mind when you're in the
moment when you're calm all those things
help relieve stress anxiety and even I
mean even if you're going on a
psychedelic charity that is still in my
mind medicinal because it's bringing you
just different knowledge different
things that's separating you from your
daily just [__] and it's keeping
giving you something different to think
about it's giving you a change in
perspective which don't you think more
people smoke CBD with THC they say a lot
of them say it's for medical reasons but
a lot of them say that pure THC by
itself when they smoke it get some high
paranoid and they don't like it when
it's mixed with the CBD by reducing the
peak experience by delaying the onset
yeah they're able to handle it enjoyably
but if you if you wanted recreational
purposes the majority of the people I
know that are really into it they don't
want no CBD with it yeah and I I mean I
I'm a big fan of THC I think THC has
huge medical applications also so I
don't think THC is just for wreck either
so again other people are gay exactly
that's right I understand that some
people feel it's a bonus but you need to
understand that some people that's
absolutely negative to the hi actually
yeah and I I think I was just saying all
colors of the rainbow because the truth
of the matter is is that we're growing a
one to one here and it's about a 12
percent 12% CBD to THC and honestly I
can't smoke it unless it's time for bed
because the CBD mixed with the THC in my
particular body chemistry makes me way
more high than if I'm smoking a 27% C
THC
so you know it's really individual and
how it is that you're feeling and we
need to be respectful to the concoction
of a hundred other cannabinoids that are
available in there and how it's there's
not a hundred other cannabinoids I mean
how many there might be close to a
hundred that they've discovered in the
last I mean though there was 70 or 80
for the longest time but they keep
finding ones but you can't help but
wonder are they truly produced by the
plant or as or the results of an hour
yeah I have a really good question is it
medicine when we don't know about it you
know what I mean does it diancie to like
bring light to us so that we can
actually understand it I think that in
our bodies were like we were feeling all
these different cannabinoids so to say
that you're smoking like just THC or
just CBD is rarely ever the case unless
it's an isolate so it's always gonna be
different well after looking at reports
and THC and CBD levels of cannabis that
I've been smoking for many years that
I'm like sometimes surprised to find
that there's more CBD in it than I
expected and also I think some of that
goes back to how it's grown and many
other different things as well so sure
this conversation is kind of getting
crazy
anyway disease when you're saying that
you know these other cannabinoids are
good for the immune system or whatever
Hey most of these autoimmune diseases
are caused by an overactive autoimmune
system so that's the last thing you want
to do is stimulate your immune system
no but there's a lot of the cannabinoids
and even terpenes that don't stimulate
the immune response but they suppress
the immune response so for instance CBD
suppresses immune cells in a good way
and I mean they did early studies trying
to show that this immune suppression was
dangerous and they tried to spin it that
way but for autoimmune diseases
that it can modify the immune responses
protective I'm pretty sure the other
lady the excuse me I don't you know your
name but she says that CBD strengthens
your immune system system yeah but I
mean strengthens can mean a variety of
things and so it I would say it balances
it keeps it it keeps it under control it
helps suppress overactive immune
responses and I mean this has a lot of
evidence just and people who are using
it i lady no no she's saying exactly the
same thing that was what I was saying I
wasn't actually isolating CBD saying
that that's the only thing that we're
looking for as far as an immune response
what I was saying is that feeling good
helps stimulate or suppress the immune
system because feeling good and our
emotions is an adaptogenic emotion at
whether you're feeling good or whether
you're calm these are things that can
both help your immune system whether
it's suppressing it or stimulating it
that's what I am immune system the
immune system is very complex so we
can't just say suppressing or increase
is a good thing I mean yeah so like if
we could be both stimulating and
suppressing the immune system it depends
which branch or which cell we're talking
about because there are certain early
immune cells that are very critical if
you had something like an invading
pathogen or a microbe or something like
a bad bacteria you want those early
immune responses to be there and active
so cannabinoids sometimes can help clear
an infection by simulating some of those
early immune responses whereas we want
our later immune responses like our T
helper cells our T cells we want those
more suppressed because when those cells
come in over time and don't don't get
turned off appropriately they can start
leading to chronic inflammation and can
start leading to autoimmune diseases so
we have to we also have to consider what
part of the immune response were
increasing or decreasing and then we
also have to consider that there's some
immune cells that
I mean when we think of a neutrophil out
of control it's basically like you can
think of it's like a soldier with a
machine gun it's just killing everything
that great if you have a serious
infection but if that goes unchecked
it's causing a lot of damage to
surrounding tissues so that type of
immune response you might want it
increased early on but then you want it
quickly and then we have other immune
cells like T cells that secrete il-10
and those are immunosuppressive
cytokines and so when those types of
immune responses are increased
they actually suppress the immune system
so it it gets very complicated so again
we have to be a little bit careful with
what we mean when we're talking about
how cannabinoids and these other
compounds can interact with their immune
system living I'm living with the wife
who suffers from autoimmune disease PBC
and yeah the end effect of it is that
you have to be very careful for example
for a while with her medication she was
drinking a grapefruit juice and then it
turns out great producer was making her
medicines act wrongly so you have to be
really really careful and just broadly
saying that the other cannabinoids are
beneficial I don't believe it Wow what
sorry what's PVC primary biliary
cirrhosis Oh interesting
yeah and that's interesting you bring up
the point yeah and it's a good point you
burn the fruit juice and even some other
citrus juices so that's affecting your
cytochrome p450 enzymes in the liver
that break down drugs yeah and so some
of those compounds can affect drug
metabolism and so yeah you have to be
careful whenever you're taking a new
compound during a drug you can't just
assume that everything you eat and the
plants and the herbs that you're
consuming don't have interactions with
your medication so yeah it's important
to look into supplements and how they
can interact with drugs especially if
you're taking high amounts
because what's also interesting I
recently did a 23andme where you get
your genetic analysis done and one part
that was really interesting with this
test is they show depending on different
genetic mutations that you have so
they're called snips single single
nucleotide polymorphisms so it doesn't
necessarily mean that your expression of
that gene will be wrong but it might be
altered in a way and so what they do is
they show you some of these potential
gene alterations you might have and you
can actually go into the system if you
know what you're doing and see you can
actually look up you might metabolize
cannabis differently or you might be
breaking down your basic
endocannabinoids like a nanda my
differently so you can check out those
kinds of things but what I found cool is
they show you what kind of drugs you
might get risk of not metabolizing
appropriately so I found out that if I
ever have to go on proton pump
inhibitors due to my genetic makeup
there's a certain drug that if I took it
actually wouldn't work for me so then I
can show my doctor or like hey if I had
to go on these types of drugs this is
the kind I should go on so I thought
that was pretty interesting and I mean
that's only gonna evolve as we get more
information more data so we can get a
little more personalized with how we're
taking our medications and increasing
safety to reduce harmful side effects
from a lot of these medications and
harmful interactions especially with
other compounds like you said sound like
grapefruit juice snps are exactly what
the all of these DNA cannabis companies
are identified they're not actually
examining the entire cannabis genome
what they're doing is looking at 20,000
30,000 40,000 snps I was talking about
them in reference to human genes but you
understand yeah baby
gal no thank you yeah yeah yeah I wanted
to ask Joshua and Kelly you to go a
little bit more you brought up some
a comment about organic farming and how
it can be done
legitimately versus I guess when you
know you're just slapping on the organic
label but it doesn't necessarily mean
you're doing true organic practices and
I was wondering if you could speak a
little bit to that yes yeah I mean what
we believe is that you know just because
it has an armory label on it or just
because it has a USDA Organic
certification it doesn't mean that it's
truly organic unfortunately you know
there's a big misnomer in this industry
as a whole especially about what armoury
is Omri is a review board it's a
materials review board which means that
they can take a bag of alfalfa and they
can say yeah we're going to put an
armoury stamp on this because this bag
of alfalfa can be used in the production
for organic use or it can be used for
organic use production it doesn't mean
that Army's gone all the way down the
list to find out exactly what farm that
that particular bag of alfalfa came from
to find out that it's organic and even
actually find out if it's even non-gmo
so it's really important for people to
you know if they're going to be know
your farmers you know if you're going to
vital garden supply then ask the guys
there they've probably gone all the way
down the list you know exactly where a
lot of those nutrients or additions or
microbiology that you're putting in your
soils or your teas or your brews you
know you've really got to find out where
it's coming from because a certification
isn't going to give you that full proof
and like Alex said from SC labs Alec
Alec the more that we get into testing
the more we're gonna find things like
glyphosate and different things that
come through to contaminate our flowers
so it becomes increasingly important to
know exactly what you're putting into
your your farms into your teas and into
your soils because we know that our
plants are intelligent thinking feeling
beings with roots that go in and
intelligently find nutrients and
transform it into medicine
and when it's doing that it needs to be
from a pure standpoint that's why we've
chosen to do a pure certification type
thing which is you know utilizing
testing and toxicity levels with what
you're inputting into your Gardens to
know that you're getting things as pure
as possible in a contaminated world I
mean we realize nothing's perfect but
you know that's we're trying to go the
extra mile to not just take an army
certification as the be-all end-all of
of purity and and encouraging people to
really you know grow their own nutrients
the idea if you really want to know
exactly where your nutrients are coming
from and you really want to know you
know what it is then if you're keeping
your farm as much closed-loop as you
possibly can then you know exactly where
they're coming from and you know exactly
what your inputs are and exactly what's
going into your soil you recognize how
easy it is to get contaminated by your
neighbour which other large farms often
get contaminated by their neighbors and
that's an overspray issue or a
groundwater issue and there's a lot to
that but did you solicit break1 yeah I
was just reiterating what you guys said
about you know you got there's more than
what's just in the label but there's
also where the sources come from and
that is something that we really take
into consideration and make sure that
you know we have accountability with all
the raw materials that go into all of
our products and it's true like the word
compost alone like give on the word
compost most people think it's organic
but there's so much compost out that
it's full of glyphosate and other
terrible things that are definitely not
going to help your plants or anything
help the environment or any of that so
accountability is really important and
this closed loop system that you guys
are always like huge on you know
developing and introducing people to is
also a great thing and I always like
applaud people who go in that direction
but what we do is we source products
based on cleanliness to help introduce
them to organics and or provide them
when it's on a scale that they can't
necessarily produce in their backyard so
the combination or they only the
combination of what you guys do and
we do I think is really helping propel
people make that switch because as you
know a lot of our customers both ours
and dragonflies have come from a
background of learning about three part
systems and synthetic nutrients and
sprays that take killing everything and
so on and so forth and now they are
changing in mindset and it's it's really
good to see like a lot a lot of even I'm
seeing huge commercial farms looking
looking for organic certification and I
know the word certification scares some
people but it is a step in the right
direction and you're just showing a sign
of like consciousness and to me that's a
step in the right direction because know
it's not a perfect world and if I see
some large cannabis farm like going the
extra mile and trying to get enviro cans
certified or clean green or even CDFA
that's California Department of Ag
certification that to me just shows
they're at least make an effort and in
this imperfect world effort goes a long
way with me for sure intention goes a
long way and we're finding a lot of
people are moving back to the land you
know in this time of expansion of
cannabis gardens and a lot of people
come to us that really want to create
systems that are more like an ecosystem
garden rather than just a monoculture
crop Carden you know there's gonna be
all things happening we know that
there's gonna be Central Valley
California crazy blowout farms to a real
so really it's no different than really
food I mean you can just look at food
and take that as an example or anything
else you know it's gonna be about being
having a story being different telling
people how you're affecting the world
and the earth and there's a huge
response from consumers to find farms
that are growing ecologic Lee sound
absolutely and then it's a huge
revelation to find out that a lot of
times those cannabinoid ratings are
higher and we know farms that have been
on
ethic regimens or even organic one
traditional organic even traditional
organic farms and then started using
more ferments and started using more
plant compost teas medicines more
compost teas I started realizing wow and
I built up my my microbiology and my
soil
I got higher cannabinoid ratings on
clones that I've been growing for 15
years why do I have we're talking three
percent higher four percent higher up to
seven you know it's it's it's it's a
it's higher standing and it's because of
the plant vitality and its ability to
produce more so we're trying to move
more and more away from you know the
term NPK and moving more and to just
broad spectrum you know it you can't
even put it there's not enough room on
the page for for that for those minerals
and nutrients over the molar we put more
of that in there the more at the plants
responding by providing better medicine
more cannabinoids higher than a bronze I
do firmly believe in biodynamic organic
gardening I was first exposed and
trained by the Alan Chadwick farm at
UCSC back in 1973 and I've grown
organically biodynamically since that
time for more than 40 years now and I
also know that it's not just believe
that I know that more and better and
finer roots make healthier plants with
more terpenes with higher percentages
and also it can increase cannabinoids a
bit I've only used IPM with predators
for more than 40 years I mean III agree
with really a lot of what you're saying
so at least we can agree on something
well it's just that the other
cannabinoids if you have a medical
reason for them pay more power to you
I mean I was the one who created the
program to create varieties in extremely
like CBG and that has 10% in a plant
with hardly any other collaborate and
these were research tools I'm not saying
that's the plant that somebody wants but
you got to remember that when I started
in this game 30 years ago with medical
cannabis there was no source of these
compounds you could not buy CBG you
could not buy THC B so I created plants
the natural way with classical breeding
that had them at very very large amounts
which is phenomenal Fino nominal
phenomenal we love that about you
yeah which is which is what we're really
interested in as well you know a lot of
people talk about isolates and isolates
then goes into the pharmaceutical and
scientific world but our roots are in
herbalism our roots are in the soil our
roots are in the dirt we're really much
more interested in the plant as a whole
plant medicine all of the different
concentrates that we make were utilizing
the entire plant we're utilizing the
roots the leaves the stalks the flowers
all of it to come up with the whole
medicine because I believe that you know
as an herbalist that the whole plant is
offering everything and we believe in
using polymers and mushrooms along with
our cannabis here which is you know just
adding to the adaptogenic you know
abilities to go into our body so our
body can make the right decision I mean
you know when you can't your body heals
you the best you know chemotherapy
doesn't necessarily kill cancer it's
your body that you know really kills it
it chemo kills everything but uh when it
comes to you know just having the
ability to have more compounds more
abilities to flush you know that's
that's what we're we're doing and in
British Columbia it's frustrating as a
farmer to not have laboratories to work
with it's not like in California or
Oregon or Colorado or Washington where
you can take a leaf and send it to a lab
and and get the cannabinoid count out of
you know a plant within four to six
weeks
or something you know in the early
stages I there there there maybe around
it's not common people don't use them
you know as much here I'm British so so
as farmers and as you know observational
estas 27 years working with this
cannabis plant we've had to use our
intuition and then you know study those
plants that we've been keeping around in
our genetics for that long and just
being able to say hey I think that this
is what's been going on and this is
what's been going and oddly enough we
were right so there is something to
intuition there is something to
observation there is something to
farming and then also you know adding
science as one of the spectrums when you
have a full spectrum science is just one
of the spectrums so you guys can get do
analysis know if you have an MMA R or a
CMP are licensing a Canada my husband
has well he had a former MMA are now he
has this ACN PR and you can send I think
it changed in the last year patients can
legally send their materials to have
them tested and I know a nambia John
pages group at ABC they do still Vietnam
you know it they'll do terpene analysis
I mean it does get pricey but especially
yeah yeah we've totally new it awesome
and yeah and we have used them we have
used them but it's really different than
getting the analysis from say steep hill
or SC labs you know we we've been able
to just get more information from them
but UBC has been helpful to us and they
have been really great yeah we have a
19% CBD plan out of our greenhouse two
years ago and we and we had it tested
and we thought that it would probably
was yeah I would like to say something
about the conversation welcome everybody
bubbleman here for another few minutes I
also have had these conversations with
steep hill with SC labs with chimera I
feel that we really I'm not trying to
[__] on the labs that we do have but we
really need this sort of cannabis
focused lab here in British Columbia an
SC type experience I've talked to those
guys it's definitely been a conversation
of trying to sort of like it would be a
chimera obviously would be an amazing
person to be involved he's got a lot of
an all
and he knows a lot of the right people
hopefully it'll be a dialogue that
continues and we can get that because I
feel your guys is pain and I forgot
completely that you guys are in British
Columbia you guys are in the coots right
is it the Kootenai so I can't hear you
guys you're muted you won yeah we're
from the coders from the Kootenays
awesome while I love to see the
Kootenays representing all my brothers
and sisters from the Kootenays from
caslo to Nelson and we miss miss I miss
the coots when I'm not there and I'll
definitely make a point the next time I
come to the coots to look you guys up
we're waiting for you you're welcome
anytime amazing array of flavors amazing
I'd like to hear that I like to hear
that terpene profiles that's what I'm
all about we can hear you can hear you
okay I just doing a Mic Check that's all
good yeah it's better it's better now
it's a little quiet though you can still
up it a little but yeah we can hear you
better as soon as I put these earbuds on
that have a mic in it it my computer
then once I disconnect the earbuds I
can't you know can't figure it out so
that it basically meets me so yeah I'll
keep them on yeah I loved what you guys
were saying about the whole plant
medicine and using you know the the
roots and the whole plants I'm sure the
try terpenoids that are in the roots
you're accessing and all these different
things
cannabis is an amazing plant and the
beautiful thing of Genesis that I've
really finally learned at 44 years of
age is that you know when I first got
into it and I got into water hash I was
water pass water crashes it's gotta be
it's gotta be this it's gotta be and as
I slowly learned certain things of
cannabis and I think it was herb when
herb came on and talked about his shitty
Mississippi bunk weed that we were all
like oh look felt like we knew and he
just said guys it works for me so
whatever the medicine that we prefer
remember to never fight against
other options human medicine or whatever
it is because there's so many people in
this industry in this community that can
use all of these different sort of one
of the new things I say is I don't ever
fight against anything we already have
I just want on a fight for more I don't
fight against access I don't fight
against LPS or I don't fight against
dispensaries because they exist then we
already have access points there why
would I fight against those things if I
want something more I can go out and
focus on that and create that and I
think a lot of people get that lost then
sort of well I want dispensaries so I'll
do that as fight lp's with every inch of
my that's not really cool my mom gets
herb orders it Freder or something it's
like people like oh no not tweet I'm
like listen just because you don't like
it it it's still an access point and at
this one thing we can all agree on is
that we need more access points not less
that's my two cents I love that and I
want to just give you a lot of respect
for upholding ice water and full plant
medicine over all the years you've been
a big huge proponent of that and that's
a really big deal as you know as the
industry wants to jump into BHO and all
these crazy oil extractions and nice
little farms going into it and stuff and
here's BC bubbleman you know doing all
the the plant medicine you know whole
plant extracts so big love to that we
appreciate got a nice you know what our
nice
people would always be like my kind of
like my one big thing that I would say
they'd be like well I like this and I'm
like well it's cool that I'm like but
would you drink it exactly
Oh life on Earth sure water does last
time I checked and that's kind of a new
thing that's one it was one of my
focuses of course water hash is
wonderful but at this point in time you
know it was a car conversation that I
had with Addison de Moura from steep
hill a while ago and he just you know
it's Izzie I know you don't like the dho
and I know it's a chemical and it's this
that and the other thing to use like man
I've seen getting this help hey dude
it's why I've sort of stopped my energy
if I'm not trying to fight against
anything that already exists I would
love for it to be cleaner and safer and
better but I'll - I'll focus on my
solvent less quiver my dry sip my wet
wash and the rosin and that along with
terpene extract since that's that'll be
our little piece of pie that we can
contribute and there's all these
wonderful other pieces of the pie when
it comes to cannabis hemp is not just a
plant that produces 50 thousand
commercial products cannabis is a plant
that produces you know an infinite
amount of medicines and with 180
terpenes or 140 that have been
categorized and 40 that have not plus 85
plus cannabinoids I think we can all
agree that we have a long way to go okay
I wanted to mention something mark
you know it's interesting you think you
don't really need a lab what you need is
an HPLC you know and I guess you don't
need these days are really a degree in
chemistry to understand how to use these
they're pretty hands-on and pretty easy
to use and once you have an HPLC
and I don't know how many samples you
have to send to lab before you realize
that hey I could have spent all this
money rather than a testing lab with my
own brand new equipment to measure these
numbers myself and know what the plant
looks like myself and yeah yeah HPLC is
probably cost anywhere between 35,000
used to maybe 40,000 but you know if
you're testing costs are in the same
regime you may want to consider rather
than oh you could still submit two to
third party outside labs but it's really
great to have the instrumentation
in-house so you can get your own numbers
I love the idea of actually you know
starting a lab like investing in a lab
getting together with chimera and some
other people and maybe I invited SC labs
I was like you guys have all this
knowledge why don't you guys come up to
Canada we'll get an SC labs going in
Vancouver he'll be up here we can get
the investment we can buy the machines
we can get some people some jobs and I
just thought it was a good idea I
started the conversation with steep hill
originally and then labs and have had
the conversation a few times with
chimera just it's something Vancouver
desperately needs we have a big cannabis
community and it's just for missing some
really key components totally agree we
had the same conversations not with
crime era but with steep hill and Alec
and and SC Lausanne we were just talking
about how British Columbia over the
years has done so much genetic breeding
and so many good things it would just be
really nice to have that backing to just
even with tissue culture you know what I
mean
not not of tissue culture of cloning but
of being able to test leaf at a young
plant life age so that you can start 500
seeds and know within six weeks you know
which ones to go forward with that's an
amazing thing you know to prove to
progress our movement forward
so it's essential recipe we have this we
need this science background we wanted
it's um you know cultivars it just
doesn't cut it anymore oh I got the Jack
Frost I got the Jack Herer I got the
dista that it's like what are the
cannabinoid profiles and wonder the
terpene profile it's like tell me what
the constituents are that make up that
name because people throw in throw
around names like it's going out and I
can't tell you how many times in this
business I've seen this one crack some
seeds what is that it smells like
gorilla glue it's like I'm gonna call it
you know such and such it's just like
name a name this weird connection to
like ego or they're like they want to
feel like they were a bleeder it's like
you know just just let's let's go
straightforward with me when I first met
skunk man Sam when I first met him god
it's been 20 plus years now he said to
me said you know when I see when I see
herb get tested I think it was the GLC
you can confirm or not Sam I can't
remember if it was HPLC or what it was
but he said he reckoned a particular
spike when when skunk was in the hybrid
he would just be like yeah there's skunk
number ones in there there's that spike
I thought that was really cool you know
that was back in 97 or 99 or you know 17
plus years ago so but that was using a
GC f ID for turkeys it works better than
HPLC for cannabinoids especially the
acid forms you-you-you need HPLC but
maybe a mess and what was fi D again I
it's at the tip of my tongue detector
well thank you what it does is as the
stream of gas comes off the
chromatographic column so think of a
column that's just like a distillation
column and things are separated based on
their differences in boiling points and
so as those partition gases come through
at that point they're sent through the
flame ionization detector which
basically just looks for any organic
matter that's being
earn and when organic matter is being
burned in that stream the flame
ionization starts to receive a signal
and so you just get an increase in the
peak so it's just a way of detecting
some people use GCF ID that's that's
pretty pretty common but other people
and I prefer something called GC mass
spec where your that effluent as it
comes off of the chromatographic column
goes right into an electron impact mass
spectrometer which measures the
molecular weight of the material that's
coming off as its looting from the
column mark what's the price difference
between GCMs and GCE hep ID yeah I can
give you so that I'm not endorsing this
system but I just recently for a client
made a recommendation on purchasing the
shimasu system this was a the GC f ID
and gc/ms with a headspace measurement
so the headspace is an important
measurement to be able to measure the
volatiles
so that's good for terpene and also just
to confirm that there's no residual
solvents there so that that instrument
itself costs a little over $100,000 I
believe brand-new from shimasu that's
their gc-ms with the headspace
measurement the Cannabis analyzer which
is their HPLC instrument runs about
sixty to sixty-five thousand dollars
brand new but you can get a HPLC you
know for probably neighborhood of 20 to
25,000 dollars used there's lots of
pharmaceutical companies who redeploy
those things all the time so there's a
considerable after market for slightly
used HPLC s that would be perfectly fine
but again just a plug out to you know
the farmers who want to know that
information on their own even if they
are mandated by regulations to
third-party testing it's always great to
have third-party testing when you have
your own results to compare your
third-party results to and so if you
some anomalous data point you at least
have a point of reference to go back to
the testing company and say hey you know
your results say this but our results
done in this in such way calibrated on
this instrument run by this trained
person gives us these results and so I
think it's just more enabling to the
producer especially if you're making
concentrates to have HPLC in-house to be
able to measure the cannabinoid potency
at each step along the way of from
extraction to the refinement of isolates
the crystallization there's no better
way to determine how pure your
cannabinoid acids are then to have an
HPLC make that determination and I also
say that or terpenes DCF ID or GCMs but
that is the gold standard yeah
absolutely just because of the amounts
of material there which is a lot less
and what you're doing in the headspace
measurement or what you're doing in the
GC measurement is you are measuring the
volatile that's coming off of the sample
so yes you're measuring basically the
the vapor effluent that's coming off
with a sample that's just been you got
to remember that the GC injection port
for a lot of these protocols are
anywhere between 200 to 250 degrees
centigrade so it's certainly not nail
temperature but injecting a cannabis
extract that's was perhaps extracted
under low temperature conditions and
that one that's gonna change its terpene
content on heating up that's always been
my thing is that when you put a sample
into the ejection port of your GC
there's invariably some chemistry that's
going to happen with the most sensitive
terpenes that are in there at that
temperature you can't avoid that from
happening the other thing that that
creates at the injection port is sort of
like again like a nail surface if there
are any heavies or residuals and your
extracts it'll start to build up in your
injection port so
it's absolutely maintained one of the
things that you must do to maintain your
GC is cleaning out that ejection port to
make sure that there's no crap and you
run blanks in between your replicates to
make sure that you're not seeing any
residual from the from the previous
injection when you shoot a blank you
should get a blank response
yeah and typically what we do like that
a lot of these things Sam is will like
to add an internal standard which we
weigh out on an analytical very very
sensitive balance and when we add the
analytical internal standard to the
sample we know to the enth degree how
much material is in there so we could
sort of correlate the amount of material
to the peak height and so that gives us
a way of measuring taking the internal
peak heights from your chromatogram
which kind of looks like a heartbeat
kind of thing there's peaks and valleys
and [__] like that and all those peaks
represent all different compounds and
the issue again with chromatography is
you have to assume that each peak is a
single compound and there's not multiple
peaks but sometimes there's shoulders
and these Peaks aren't always
symmetrical so there's multiple things
that can be in there and as with some of
these terpenes when you heat them up
they form multiple isomeric products
which can resolve on the GC as
individual Peaks so it's not
extraordinary to see you know multiple
more terpenes on heating them up than
were they would be at room temperature
so I'm working with the group in Fort
Collins Colorado called Discoverer 64
associated with Colorado State
University and we're using some very
highly sensitive multi-dimensional NMR
techniques where we look at both proton
and carbon signatures and what we can do
is I used to say this was undressing the
Mona Lisa so if the painting of the Mona
Lisa is across the street from you you
can look out your window and you could
say ah yes it's painting of the Mona
Lisa right and so when we look
at the at the NMR spectrum of a lot of
cannabis extracts what we see mostly is
THC a as we should I mean these are
highly bred for for THC production and
like Sam we're growing these things get
high and when we've looked at things
that are like the age a cut of the Sour
Diesel and we've actually looked at also
some of JJ's Nigerian haze it's a
textbook spectrum for THC a but what we
can do in NMR is we can basically
undress the Mona Lisa take the Mona Lisa
out of the painting so we could actually
see the outfit she's wearing and
everything else that's in the painting
that you sort of take for granted when
you look across the street and there's
the Mona Lisa we know that these things
produce THC a there's no question about
it the factories producing THC a
according to Sam and everything else is
the star of the show there's a lot of
other supporting actors in this movie
you think it's like THC a is like if for
the winning the Oscar for the best actor
that would be THC a right would be up
for that role right and then there's a
supporting actor which probably CBD we
could say and you know other various you
know I forget that analogy but I mean so
the point is again I think I wanted to
bring this back home to HPLC testing and
the need to actually both look at the
cannabinoid acid profile at room
temperature which you can't do by HPLC
but we think we can do by
multi-dimensional NMR and so we're sort
of looking at this very sort of
systematically to try to identify all
the other components when we take th CA
out of the picture right so now that we
no longer see th CA we see everything
else and the cool thing about the NMR is
you don't have to heat it up which is
unlike the GCF ID which is as you heat
it up you have chemistry tomorrow and
interrupts we only have 1% left we just
wanted to say hi everyone I'm with Tony
we're hiding in the bathroom because
it's air-conditioned only 40 degrees
outside
Celsius right now we just wanted to say
goodbye to everyone we're gonna go do
this doctor training and hopefully we'll
see you guys in the near future pastures
good luck with this Tony thanks for
doing that work down there guys Thanks
yah mahn so anyway we're gonna try to
hopefully develop a room temperature
technique where we can look at terpene
profiles that don't have to go through
an injection port at 200 and 250 degrees
so stay tuned for that I don't think
that this is gonna be something that's
going to be coming to a testing lab near
you but I think what we can probably do
is characterize this on a number of
different examples and publish this and
make sure that this is widely accessible
to everybody so you can see and if you
have an interest in doing this work you
can go to your local University that's
got one of these machines and and and
perhaps you know recreate this so anyway
whatever NMR the problem with an mr
though is the sample cost prep is too
expensive great it's a lot more
expensive than ung cuf well it's more
than just you know taking a sample that
you get submitted and putting it into
your you know robotic arm which just
basically takes a little you know squirt
and shoots it into the injection port
and that's it this is you have to
basically sit down with a group of very
highly trained sophisticated people to
understand that we're gonna run this
process what are we gonna what are we
looking for and what are we gonna get
out of it because you can get the the
NMR spectrum and it looks just like a a
mess to a lot of people but I've been
looking at these for Oh God how long has
it been like 1982 I think when I first
started looking at Amara so it's just
it's I've learned to basically see the
the forest through the trees and not
necessarily scared by looking at
mixtures of compounds and be able to
deconvolution to their individual
components because we know what the
individual components look like
with this type of with this type of
measurement so yeah stay tuned Ryan I
mean it's not going to be something
again it's coming that's going to be a
standard routine test although I I do
know of a couple labs now that service
the California market that will run in
an NMR for you and again why someone
would would submit a sample for NMR
analysis is probably unknown but if
you're making something like crystalline
THC a it'd be really really good to make
sure that the purity is what the purity
is and when you when you do run it by
proton NMR it's strikingly pure it's
it's it's beautiful to look at it looks
like to me at least the Mona Lisa yeah
well that's cool I mean I understand
where you're coming from the point but
again I go back to the same thing for a
high-throughput lab where you're not
screening one sample you're screening
three like for me I'm screening
populations right so I need to get the
cannabinoid data and the terpene data on
like a thousand plants so it just it
doesn't make sense it's not economically
viable to do that by NMR I yeah we
should we should talk offline buddy
go on you know how to find me the other
thing I wanted to point out to you is I
kind of I was try to log in so I kind of
got a little bit of the conversation but
you know everybody's talking about
there's no labs in in Vancouver well
there are labs in Vancouver John page
has an and yet right they they've got a
full full set up for all sorts of
screening they do screening for the LPS
and they can now legally you know accept
cannabis from patients which was the
case about six months ago I was one of
the things that was updated wagon-wheel
was a company that tried to set up and
do dispensary testing or testing through
dispensaries and Health Canada lost
their [__] mind right they went they
tried to go after them they tried to
really make their life hell so it's not
it's not California it's not it's not
Washington it's not Oregon like we don't
have that written into the regulation
was the way that they are permitted down
and dunk in California so it's it would
be really tough for us
labs just roll in the Canada and set up
because I have been operating outside of
the set of regulations that exist I have
a question if somebody buys their own GC
or HPLC and does their own in-house
analysis is that legal
kind of license you'd have to get again
you have to go and get standards and
it's not this is like pretty fancy
equipment for home growers to be playing
with I agree yeah so and most people
don't have the skills I mean to be to
really have the skills to be able wait
wait John Johnny B who's one of our
regular panelist has got a GC over in
his thing mark get away hey listen no
offense to Johnny B but his results are
like all but useless okay they're not
that's not it's not science it's like
yes he gets Peaks coming off his
chromatograph but great that's my it's
he's not doing terms he's not accurately
quantifying anything so it's yeah
anybody could do that but again what's
the point of just having numbers on your
own it's not about just having numbers
it's about having accurate numbers right
like that's the whole point of the lab
is to have an accurate medicine
measurement of what's in the medicine
right and that's why I like we've seen a
lot of press lately about these handheld
scanners and we've talked about it on
church before we don't need to go there
but certainly a order of magnitude less
expensive than an HPLC would be like one
of these you know sort of near IR
measurements that claim that they can do
cannabinoid and terpene profiles based
on just holding a sample up to one of
these things that you can buy in a
Pelican case III think again yeah I mean
if you're out in the bush and you're
like is this CBD is this THC again just
to go back to I think what Joshua was
saying earlier which is that we go on
our instincts because we know these
plants and we have a connection with
them so it's like one of the things that
you just you you you sense but it's also
great to have something like even as
crude as it is Johnny B's
you see he can do a quick injection and
say hey you know what that's a THC
variety not a CBD variety and just be
able to make that kind of level
determination is that quantitative no
should a comma on a label no is that
going to substitute for an analysis done
it's steep hill
no but it's giving a grower an extra set
of eyes to look at hey here's a tool
that's maybe at second hand maybe I only
got it for whatever and it's pieced
together with a couple you know flanges
with duct tape or whatever and it's a
maybe if you wanted a result but if you
can get it you can get that same kind of
qualitative information off of like $10
TLC plate right yeah no no yeah
absolutely yeah yep we use TLC 30 years
ago
and if all you want to do is get a
finger to breathe in the right direction
TLC works fine but for quantitative it's
not so fine well let's give props to
Kevin mckernon who's really taking this
UPC our home thing and he's starting to
add a whole bunch of assay as I was
going back and forth with him over the
weekend and they were the - well test
just a simple colored color metric test
they can identify it essentially they're
doing away with TLC now right
hey she needed Ryan
oh yeah accidently sorry the muting
please and now I can't unmute him sorry
Ryan I don't know what I did there sorry
Ryan you're right so for tip for a 10
for a $3 prep you can get like 10 essays
out of that so for 3 out of 3 of the
wells you can get the sex of the plant
and whether what the chemo type is out
of three wells so out of three of 10 you
know wells when you're prep so that's a
lot of information to get for 3 bucks
right and it's definitely PLC it takes
less time and TLC yeah I mean to me it's
like a P a P H paper I mean you know I
remember when we used to have have like
red and a blue litmus paper now I have a
little pH strips that tell me any range
of pH no matter of whether I'm acidic or
basic so yeah these are just constant
innovations that help people figure out
what's going on that's totally cool yet
pops off the Kevin sure that Kevin was
gonna join us maybe Natasha
yeah okay there was some issues with the
link some people were having problems if
he you see anyone here he's a family guy
who spends his weekend with families
like probably most of us should I know
just crashed on the bed here speaking of
I think I'm about to dip out guys thank
you good seeing you guys Josh and Kelly
I'm glad we got to see each other before
the Emerald cup again this year yeah no
kidding it'd be nice to be able to see
you more times than that it's always
great seeing you and being with you
Brian we love what you do and we love
who you are in this industry same with
you guys for shared supporter for share
and let's get together more often see
what we can do
I love that we'd love to have you up
here for a little visit bring the family
that sounds awesome
thank you okay you're always welcome
down here too okay thank you rob's Brian
thank you I dropped a link in our chat
maybe one of the moderators can post
that in the in the in the live chat feed
so people get everybody else can see it
but it's essentially the cost breakdown
and a little a little kind of ad for for
mckernon C PCR test so I just want to
welcome Selene along to the room hi
Selina
so Selina was with us last week so yeah
come on pretty good
it's a beautiful Sunday here I'm so
honored to be here again thanks again
for the invite and I have to say the
conversation has been so fascinating so
far on all fronts my mind is just
absolutely blown so if I just go silent
and just absorb this round please excuse
me
and I also just wanted to mention Kelly
just kudos for you and catching babies I
appreciate that work that you're doing
yes thank you and everybody else of
course but it was just a little a little
piece of the conversation that was just
touched on and glossed over but people
understand how I believe birthing is
such a huge a huge thing and the fact
that you're there facilitating women and
empowering them to reclaim their power
and their birthing and being there to
really mirror that strength I think is
really beautiful
and I love what you're doing both of you
really thank you yeah thanks so much we
definitely take the birthing as
seriously as the first seed so see it
the same way you know that first breath
is just important as that first sprout
in the health of a whole entire lifetime
so it's amazing using birth water to
sprout your first
[Laughter]
that's interesting so tell us more about
that so what is it just because it's a
nutrient-rich medium and so you're
finding the seeds sprout faster or
what's the advantage to doing that oh I
just think that you know if you're gonna
empty a tub it's really nice to empty it
in their flower garden or in their
garden because that's just so much nicer
it's like sacred waters and it's looked
at you know baby was born in that water
so why not put it in your flower garden
so we actually do hose extensions to get
it to the flower gardens even it's in
the middle of winter
you guys are so dedicated that's
beautiful that's so beautiful people
don't realize like there's a whole other
world to understanding birthing than you
know the hospital and legs up in the
stirrups and the pushing and the
screaming in the pain it can be
something so beautiful and so sacred so
I'm is similar to cannabis yeah same is
room same as as well though yes I fully
agree yeah I have magical otherworldly
so tapped in multi-dimensional
experience yeah have you had any
experiences in your just with what you
do with cannabis and facilitating
birthing um well it definitely comes in
and out you know for me I think that the
whole reason how we even got into where
I'm at now today is because of learning
about health and human health and
women's health and then learning about
small babies health because then that
just has so much to do with the mother
as well
you know they are one at that time and
then utilizing all of those herbs that
we used to grow an entire baby and what
do those herbs do to grow a whole plant
yeah so then I started to be able to see
you know the ganja plant as a feminine
plant because we normally choose all of
the females and then give those feminine
herbs to the plant for growth and health
and well-being there's just absolutely
no difference to me you know even if we
study it with science or we look at it
you know in all of the different realms
of spirituality or practicality
you know it's a very similar similar
thing life is life and health is health
and you could you know need male
hormonal herbs to your male plants which
you know there's no we do not have a
scientific paper to back that but it
makes all the sense in the world to use
metal roof for example tea on your mail
plants to just put more mail supporting
hormones and compounds into the soil
which will feed the might accrues which
the microbes will feed the plant of
course so anyway it's full circle bed
plus there's nettles all over the place
nature gives abundantly I find and and
she knows how to compliment just so
perfectly so we'll find these companion
plants just sprouting up naturally
around I'm curious just specifically
with the birthing process have you
worked with cannabis to help facilitate
a shift in perception
perhaps on behalf of the mother or the
people around has there been an
integrative portion of ceremony around
that even post birth I'm just curious
you have so much experience and wisdom
well it's definitely utilized just like
many of the other herbs you know I'd say
that there's like eight herbs I'm just
making up that number that I utilize you
know from it during the birthing process
and then maybe postmenopausal as well I
mean postpartum as well postmenopausal
maybe that's where I'm at now no yeah I
close it's getting there feeling it but
yeah to be able to utilize the plant in
birth itself this is fantastic you know
also women in breastfeeding and helping
them relax I feel like hops is utilized
you know and if hops isn't working
immediately then we might go to a nice
cannabis brewed he and it helps so much
for the mother's milk to come down she's
relaxed she's maybe in a place that
feels good so now she's ready to nourish
her baby after you know an extreme you
know birthing process it hops is part of
the same family as the can
to begin with yeah it's another
adaptogen working them together yeah
also you know during the birthing
process of the labor and everything is a
lot about mine space and stuff and in
cannabis Hat can definitely be used to
change the perspective absolutely
definitely happened and there's a lot of
different ritual that's gone into some
of the births that we've done it and
Kelly has done two for sure with other
plant medicine as well but yeah cannabis
is also part of the pregnancy tea
because the pregnancy tea is a crucial
part of being pregnant is to be able to
drink herbs the whole entire time of
pregnancy to build the uterus and the
the walls and all the muscles that
you're going to be utilizing to for the
transformation so cannabis is part of
that along with medicinal mushrooms
along with fungi along with that magical
not magic but magical mushrooms yeah and
we really utilize all the adaptogenic
herbs and that's the reason why we even
got into cannabis it just makes sense
you know when you're somebody who has
deep respect for nature and the
medicinal and spiritual powers of these
amazing adaptogens that are here to
serve us and we're here to serve them
you know it's this beautiful symbiotic
love relationship that we have with
these plants and when we bring them
together a full circle then we're able
to have you know a real healing process
I have a great story just super-quick
that a mother you know was not releasing
her placenta after birth she's just
holding on you know it was her third
baby she hadn't had any cannabis during
her whole pregnancy because of you know
whatever feelings that she had you know
surrounding it this was back in the
early 90s and just was going on for a
really long time she wasn't internally
bleeding everything was fine but you
know we're starting to get a little bit
worried and if I I looked at her and I
said do you need a joint we need to just
have a toke here and yeah she took one
toke and the placenta was born and
everybody could go on about their
business so what it did was it allowed
her to be in that place of normalcy that
she is normally you know that she wasn't
during
the pregnancy and find that role yeah
acceptance and centering so that you
know she could move on and accept this
birth that's interesting you're bringing
up the concept of via cannabis being not
only used again we were having a
discussion previous about cannabis
medical versus Rec but using it to
facilitate shifts in birth or and I
wanted to bring it back to Selena
she's also started doing I don't know
what the proper word is but she
facilitates marriages and she's
incorporating cannabis in that ceremony
also and I thought that was a really
just beautiful thought of I know
personally my husband and I when we got
married out in Dauphin Manitoba we even
took pictures in the hemp fields that
were growing around our area and just
even standing there in the plants and
just even that was really was actually
my favorite part of the way was normally
a picture part is kind of not really our
thing but the way our photographer
helped us calm and it just felt like a
really nice little intimate moment where
we could be alone and we were there kind
of hidden under these huge hemp plants
and so even just the presence of the
plants yeah yeah Selina can you tell us
a little bit more about what do you what
are you doing these wedding ceremonies
and how do you incorporate cannabis or
how do you intend to do this oh there's
so many ways so okay we actually had our
first pilot yesterday which was really
exciting for this wedding it was really
intimate small we ended up actually just
doing the photos at the farm were just
about to crop out which is really
exciting so everybody is just all the
girls are just totally perked and happy
and vibrant and glowing and just like so
supercharged so for them they're pretty
spiritual and very grounded and their
love is I want to say pure but it's even
more than that it's just so sweet and
for them it was it was a really unique
experience we actually got to go and
meet the girls I walked them around
the greenhouse I introduced them to a
few different cultivars that were
growing there we smelled the different
terpenes and we had some fun just
talking about soil mediums and then what
we did is we had a really fun photoshoot
and for them it was really about
connecting with the plants I think only
one person in the wedding party had ever
been in a grow ever so it was a new
experience for everybody and we had some
guests that were from Sweden so it was
extra new and very taboo and very
exciting the ways that we're hoping to
incorporate this in the next year so
officially we're not actually gonna be
launching until 2018 we are booking now
we've already got a couple of spots that
are booked which is exciting and it
really depends on it really depends on
the bride and groom or the two people
that are getting married and their
comfort level some people want to
participate with the cannabis by
ingesting or vaporizing or smoking which
is great we're also mindful of people's
tolerances and having a good time I'm
also mindful that alcohol is usually
President wedding so what we're planning
on doing is having like a precursory
education piece where we really get to
know the couple and we really get to
know what's exciting for them it could
be something as simple as having it
integrated into boutonnieres and
beautiful bouquets I love the idea of
actually having the the buds in the
bouquet and you get to do like hang dry
at the end and in a year instead of
having your frozen wedding cake you get
to partake in your beautiful bouquet
which would be so fun I love that
there's lots of different ways we how
about the obvious party favors for all
these people who come from all over
Kingdom Come just to come to your
wedding and especially celebrate
European you're a total either this day
that you've put together you want to
send them back with a little bit of
nugget so it'd be great to have like you
know a little parting gift of something
I guess we're thinking about taking that
the next step further where as we
interviewed a couple we're hoping to do
it a year prior so we can actually kind
of get a vibe on what their cultivar
would
and one of the ideas that we're playing
around with is actually growing a crop
for that couple for their wedding
something that they could give their
guests that's just for them so unique
kind of like a beautiful vintage wine
that's one of the kinds and really Kimmy
yeah totally there's so many different
things you can do this you can go one
step further and when you make little
bouquets of cannabis flowers make them
with seeded buds that way but you know
what that's like such a brilliant idea I
was thinking about you know seed paper
I've been to weddings where we had this
one mother she was so dedicated she made
sea paper into little hearts and they
scattered them all over the farm and it
was it was the parents farm so forever
these seeds will be growing I love that
idea of just having it as a seeded bud
lives on forever and just think about
how much that would feed that couple
like one of the ideas that we're pairing
with this is this concept that we call
farm table which is growing your own
food having your own food pharmacy in
your own backyard so being able to
provide simple Gardens for people right
off the hop and when people know how to
see it save seed they have a garden
forever so integrating cannabis into
that as well so part of what we're
gifting to the couples is a garden so
that could be a part of that which I
think could be really fun so what if
instead of throwing rice as the couple
exits and if you're hungry you might
catch and just have a little snack be so
good you're neutral
it'll just basically feed all the birds
in the area but it would be interesting
to come back in a few weeks and see if
any of those seed sprouted into little
plants I can guarantee it you know
imagine having the wedding down by the
creek side that Creek could just be so
pungent by the fall it'd be gorgeous
yeah I would love that and you know what
I've noticed more and more people are so
open to it and really like it doesn't
have to be like big smoke out fast it
doesn't have to you know and it could be
absolutely but it doesn't have to be you
know sometimes grandmas are there and
they're not totally keen but the other
idea too is
like part of my other business is I
produce cannabis products so just like
Tash and her beautiful topicals we've
got her online and we're thinking about
having just a beautiful gift to the
bride the wedding party and of course
the mothers of the bride and groom so to
prime their skin to get them comfortable
we have these really beautiful ovule
suppositories for women's health so
having that as something that could be
in conjunction with you know the wedding
night to help her get primed and
lubricated and plumped up and ready and
juicy and really excited to engage and
also for him because they smell like
delicious chocolate so you go downtown
and have a good time I can't believe I
just saw that on hash church but yeah
you know like there's there's such a
multi-faceted realm here that we can
explore with the weddings and I really
think this is just the beginning so I
feel fortunate enough to live in an area
where we work really closely with our
farmers and we've got some beautiful
locations and I've already been offered
up and yeah it just seems like a natural
next step into a way to integrate steak
it's sacred ceremony so the other part
of what I do is I'm actually a reverend
so I do perform ceremonies maryberry and
baptize yeah I love your happy dance
because that's how I feel inside which
is pretty rad so but what we're hoping
to do is also you know to people that
are open is incorporating a full
cannabis ceremony in with their my name
which would be really rad just to bring
in the elements bring in the beautiful
energies of lady Kenna Bay and having
that blessing to be a part of it welcome
back are you
can you hear us Marcus yeah Marcus he's
Dustin Bowles
Dustin balls can you hear us I'm Marcus
today I guess
all right well see when he can hear us
Celina thank you for sharing all that
the sounds are really exciting
Dave and I might have to do a second
wedding just to something yeah I
consider maybe you and Dave would love
to be our our pilot couple where we can
actually roll out a full ceremony and
you guys can be like our tester where
you can let us know what you like what
you don't like what else we get into
great give us some feedback is that a
yes good I would love that
if you guys want to like recreate some
awesome wedding photos I would love to
bring you to some locations and
introduce you to some girls very cool
yeah awesome so I want to bring the
conversation back to something Joshua
and Kelly mentioned before about some of
the how you guys were using the whole
plants and I'm really interested in the
cannabis roots I have a review paper
that was just accepted for publication
so it should be out in the next few
months and we wrote it together there
with dr. Ethan Russo and we put together
a summary of the historical use of the
cannabis roots and the medical
applications and a lot of it is topicals
for arthritis inflammation a lot of
mentions of gout so yeah I was curious
what are you guys doing with the root
how are you incorporating that into your
medicine we do it almost all different
kinds yeah well we utilize it in almost
every application as much as we possibly
can only because whenever you're
utilizing herbs the idea of utilizing
the whole herb you know the roots and
also getting it in different cycles of
its life you know if you want to create
a full spectrum medicine of any type of
the plant then you want to maybe create
a tincture that has the spring shoots
that has the spring roots that has the
fall shoots that has the flowers that
has the seeds that has you know the full
spectrum of the plant and it's not that
there's any science there's a lot of you
know traditional medicinal value you
know that you can yeah wise women as
well as Chinese medicine as well as our
Yvetta that goes
you know well beyond anything that
Western medicine or science you know
today has to offer the some type of a
value in that but I believe that that's
probably a real observational you know
things so we do that in cannabis we do a
slow cook oil that we actually put in a
crock pot so it's on the lowest of the
low heat simmer simmer down yeah and we
utilize the roots in there the flowers
the leaves the stalks we put maybe 11
different types of mushrooms in there
well cut poly pours like foam miss
moment arias The Iceman Amadou fungus
the artist conk which is the Ganoderma
have planets him and then the red belt
the foam is foam mitosis pinna cola
vomit arias yeah the phloem esquema
terrace is the almond yeah i'm chaga
which we can find in our forest here we
see the ones that are really like crazy
and so we get it fresh slice it up and
put the slices in the Sun and dry it in
the Sun to accumulate the vitamin D and
then we take those slices and utilize
them in the in the slow cook we can do
different kinds of oils but maybe a
coconut oil olive oil combination works
good too because of the consistency that
it comes out with in the end and then
add a bunch of other herbs in there
having to do with other adaptogens you
know we'd utilize a struggle acetyl ice
voti you know sort of bringing in all of
the different realms and every time we
utilize those licorice
yeah those plants we make sure that
we're getting the full spectrum of the
plant
we're also utilizing the herbs and the
leaves in those plants as well and then
you can use that oil and put it in gel
caps and get a really easy to use oil or
use it topically or use it as you know
there's a lot of course you can use it
in different ways yeah with the tincture
is used similarly I mean we put a
similar blend into the into the tincture
and now use will use a homemade organic
alcohol that's you know that we know
exactly what's going on
- a type thing to break it down and then
do us but your type tincture with it
where we burn the material afterwards
and utilize the ash and then you're
bringing the whole cycle of life and
death of the entire plant into the
medicine which is what we consider full
spectrum with our Wow incredible helium
incredible stories yeah and also just to
add exactly what we're talking about in
our medicine is the same way that we
make our tea brews for our plants so we
utilize all of these different herbs and
the whole entire life cycle of the plant
to put back into the soil as well so
there's really no separation in the
medicines and the teas that we give
ourselves and the medicine and the teas
that we give our plants that's really
interesting you guys are serious I love
how complex your formulas are and that
you're considering not only what part of
the plant but the season the growth the
even like you said the life and the
death of the plant and how yeah the
whole profile of nutrients and
functional properties shift as the plant
matures and changes when you guys were
talking about what you were doing with
the roots one of the interesting things
that came up when we were looking at the
historical use and as you were saying I
totally agree there's value in these
traditional ways of preparing herbs and
science hasn't caught up to a lot of
these ways I mean like even with a lot
of the plants and herbs that I look at
there might be basic test tube
experiments or some animal experiments
kind of confirming some basic mechanisms
but we're not there yet with what we
know through first-hand experience
versus having double-blind
placebo-controlled trials to confirm
these things and I don't know if we'll
ever get them because some of these
plants are so complicated and they work
so broad-spectrum they don't just target
one specific things like a lot of
traditional or not even traditional but
pharmaceutical medications do but anyway
what I wanted to bring up with the roots
one thing that kept coming up through
history is they used water to help
extract a lot of the compounds in the
root
and as we know a lot of the most I mean
all the cannabinoids and the terpenes
are fat soluble compounds and so usually
we're using like coconut oils or other
fats to extract things whereas with the
roots it just kept coming up through a
history that they were using water
extractions and so when we looked a
little deeper into some of the compounds
that had been isolated from the roots
there were some unique alkaloids such as
a kind of a SATA bean that was found in
the roots and so I'm wondering if maybe
with water extractions and when you're
also doing the alcohol extractions you'd
be able to pull out some of those more
water soluble type compounds and maybe
even improving the effectiveness of your
root compounds with what you're doing
because one of the blends we tried you
know one of the ones we tried was we
used and my husband has his MMAR license
and is a CMP our license as I said
before so he's been a grower and I've
had access to plants to try out some of
these basic recipes and so my husband
Dave was the one who first clued me into
trying to work with the roots and the
recipe we found was basically a blend of
fat and water and in a crock pot and use
that to extract and then basically put
it in the freezer to separate pour off
the water but you can even keep that
water extract for something else I mean
you're more at risk for microbial growth
and other issues so it wouldn't have as
long as a shelf life as the fat soluble
blends but it'd be interesting to start
working with those different extracts
and again you're getting additional
compounds and that still need a lot of
work to be studied and clarified what
exactly these compounds are yeah and
it's really interesting what you bring
up too because it really differentiates
the difference between the fresh herbs
because anything that's water-soluble or
you know aqueous and a non you know in a
water solution you want to be able to
utilize that fresh you know you could
utilize it in juicing you know the
leaves are not gonna be as good in
anything when as soon as they're dried
or they're utilized in a in a water
extraction or oil extraction in the same
way even a tincture extraction it really
does it changes
the the properties of making like a
beautiful steeped tea or something that
you press fresh and raw and that just
goes into access the ability for people
to be able to grow their own cannabis
plants you know really easily so that
they can press them and they can drink
the fresh juice because there's nothing
better than drinking the fresh juice
from those roots you can't even you know
no water extraction no tea solution and
nothing can be quite the same the same
way with fresh pressing any of your
leaves you know getting that juice
that's sort of a one-of-a-kind medicine
and that's utilizing fresh as opposed to
something that you keep long-term like
say the oil and and and I really I'm
agreeing with you know it's interesting
that science is now pairing up with
traditions because we're finding and
realizing that you know these herbal
remedies that you know that they've
given us recipes for for a long time now
science is really proving and so it's
great well you know you're talking about
herbs and reading these papers and it's
just really wonderful it's like it's
finally validating what we've known all
along that we've seen throughout human
history you know these these ways have
worked for eons and our family is
starting to catch up with the knowledge
scientifically which is so even having
the ability to catch up with the
knowledge it feels like with education
there's like a separation of what's in a
like story knowledge becomes not valued
in the same way in this modern time of
Education when we can just say there's
work there's places for education and
there's places for science at this
extremely important and I would love to
see that both were valued equally we can
be like here's the observation estat
have been doing it for a really long
time this is what they're bringing to
the table here's the scientific aspect
here's our they're bringing them
together is the real strength you know
and not having full-spectrum judgment on
one or the other just bringing them
together and just and and and seeing you
know what makes sense because every
situation
different every person's different
having the ability to have different
options I think is our greatest our
greatest gift right now is options I
would say options and as you're
describing this I imagine hopefully
maybe even within 10 years having
schools where kids are in these learning
gardens and these educational gardens
and they're understanding how these
beautiful plants are working
biodynamically symbiotically and then
also being able to pair it up with the
quantifiable research just to drive that
message home I do see it coming and it
is it is full spectrum which is really
beautiful I think it's more of an
integrative process than them segregated
for sure yeah thank you guys for doing
the good work so I wanted to bring the
conversation back to Sam Sam are you are
you there
are you with us still maybe but what I
wanted to ask Sam when we live up here
microphone keeps going off so I keep
turning it back on oh that's me I keep
meeting you because we're getting echo
sorry I'm not for me because I I have my
own mic with an on/off switch that I
used constantly okay so I don't need to
mute use what you're saying we won't get
feedback - if you're so motivated well I
don't want to keep you out of the
conversation I'm more just trying to
keep echo feedback but alright but
anyway what I want to ask you is let's
go back to the discussion on cannabis or
THC as a Rick and you were bringing up
the interesting story of trying pure THC
with different terpenes and I'm curious
what your experience was like so
obviously you try THC in limonene and
THC in little oil and THC and all these
other different terpenes so from your
perspective and how it made you feel do
you think with th see what terpenes do
you think had the best recreational feel
like what the
there is no best recreational terpene
and THC everybody has a different
preference but everybody that we tested
we blind tested we we had a hundred
question organoleptic survey before and
after and everybody agreed that the
terpenes have these effects which ones
they preferred was really up to the
individual so what did you prefer I
liked labelling mayor seeing the small
amount small amounts of pining seemed to
be okay but I like both said modulate
and potentiate and there's only a
handful but potentiate THC there's many
that modulate it Sam say yes I want you
to say limonene not Lima there's a
better how many times I say it I'm just
like sick Mother's Day Moline because
there's no such thing as Lyme alley and
sounds like a kid's nursery rhyme it's
the limonene okay but listen to what I'm
telling you I'm Dyslexic I will say the
same word wrong time after time after
time we know what you mean it's okay you
know what I believe is the Sam limonene
is to the rest of the world
yeah exactly it's probably the one I
enjoyed the most with but I also agree
you don't necessarily want a variety
with one terpene and THC that's very
useful for you to determine the effects
of it but you want the suite of terpenes
that you enjoy Sam if you're really
thirsty and you come off of a I don't
know some adventure or maybe it's a walk
on a hot day through New York City and
you come up to a smoothie vendor that
has all different kinds of fruits and
flavors what kind
smoothie would you get when you get an
orange or a tangerine smoothie
well orange smoothies have always been
my favorite but I'd usually have it with
orange banana and a few more things
thrown it well guess what orange has a
lot of go ahead you say it I want to
hear you say it well it's it's got
labelling or whatever it whether I'm
changing but it also has some of the
other near a doll and some of these
compounds yeah sure it does it
absolutely does I'm just just pulling on
your leg that's all buddy oh that's
perfectly all right I'm used to myself
and so we know for a fact you said you
liked limonene or lima lean however you
want to say it what was your favorite
smell when I smelt single notes I was
actually the most surprised by Mersin I
was expecting it to have more of like a
skanky smell but it was actually really
like fruity and soft I guess because
it's high and and sorry hops hops can
contain about 50% mercy it was expecting
it to have that smell some people really
like the smell of Mercy and they also
really like the effects of it with THC
it's not my favorite cup of tea because
in small amounts it it potentiates THC
but in large amounts it makes you in
other words in small amounts it's kind
of a stimulant in large amounts it's
definitely a couch lock never trust
anyone interesting yeah that was our our
joke mercy lovers I was gonna say just
on the note of mercy and I remember
somewhere in the ethers of my education
long ago something around the the idea
that anything less than 0.5% nursing
will give that uplifting kind of quality
and anything over 1% will actually bring
you down I don't know does anyone have
any science or is
it's that to some degree but you can't
just pick the number like that
arbitrarily say it with everybody and
you can't say it because there is no
variety that only has three five mersin
or whatever level of meshing without the
other collaborators of course it was
just something that I remember learning
through the medical cannabis Institute
years ago just wondering if anyone had
any extra insight on that piece
well it sounds similar to what sound was
just saying in that low amounts have one
effect whereas high amounts have another
effect so I usually cook a biphasic and
I think a lot of different compounds and
cannabis have biphasic effects so it
gets complicated China give specific
dosing requirements for people and that
and of course we're all very
individualistic and how we're going to
respond not even if you're a novel or an
advanced user but if everything else
every time I smoked merci and THC mixed
and they their eyes just like melted
with joy but that's what they said this
is what I love and I says I can't stand
it any time you any time you're looking
at just one terpene I mean you're again
missing the the orchestra by just
hearing one of the instruments in the
orchestra right there's a whole number
of different things that are playing to
the human senses in cannabis that
doesn't have to do with just the first
violin but has to do with the entire
string section combined with the brass
section all of those background terpenes
and very very very you know minor forms
and again I look at Mayer seen as being
somewhat of the maybe I won't call it a
stem-cell tripping but it's some at a
turkey net could actually is a bridge to
a lot of other more advanced terpenes
and terpenoids
and terpenoids and and so again that
paper that we keep on referencing around
hashey Sheen showed a plausible
mechanism for the photolytic degradation
of Mersin to make this new terpene
called hashish een I mean there might be
a whole host of every time you combine
mersin with another terpene you have the
opportunity for a synergistic ensemble
effect and now when you put four
terpenes together five terpenes six
turkey's the full spectrum of terpenes
that are available in the plant you're
creating the music of an orchestra not
of just a single instrument in the
orchestra so it's a symphony really and
exactly and if you just pull out that
one it is the chemical symphony and i
think that's where you're talking about
that full spectrum effect it is and just
as like a little insight just I know
with people that are using
aromatherapies anyways when they're
doing combinations
it is like music it's like notes and a
song and there's harmonics and those
smells harmonize with each other or they
clash so I like to actually pair up the
idea of terpenes with music in another
way of just seeing it that is an
excellent point Celina and that's how I
always teach people even if you're new
to essential oils and you want to make
even just a basic perfume you need to
think of how you're building it like
you're making music and you're building
a chord and similar to music you can
hear a chord or music and it just sounds
right it feels right or if you feel like
a note is off it feels kind of like and
it just gives you a weird feeling when
you smell and create blends like that
it's the same thing when you have it
properly balanced and you're hitting all
those notes and so I like to break it
down into three notes you have your bass
note your mid note and your talk note so
for instance in my little vaporizer guy
back here I can't tell you what my stash
is today but I can tell you what I have
going for a Roma therapy so I have
basically I created a chord we can say
out of three aromas so I used a base
blend with a little bit of patchouli and
so that's considered a base blend
because it's heavier it's slower to
evaporates and the
the aroma comes up later whereas the mid
note is gonna be more balancing and kind
of bring it all together so I used
lavender as my mid note and then the top
note hits the fastest it's mostly
composed of monoterpenes such as
limonene menthol things that hit and
absorb and that really potent smell that
comes off really fast those are the top
notes so today I have a little bit of
peppermint which is nice in the morning
because it wakes me up so when you
properly combine those three essential
oils or plant oils these are steam
distill distill plants I'm using today
you create this cord basically that is
like Selena was saying like music and
when you smell it it smells balanced
versus one of those single compounds
alone and when you look at even just an
essential oil that's the full plant so
like something like sweet orange
essential oil might be 97% limonene but
it has all these other little my new
compounds a little bit of myrrh seen a
little bit of Lin Ahlul just very very
small amounts but together they create
this like unique aroma that is sweet
orange whereas something like lemon also
has a really high amount of limonene but
because of the little minut amounts of
other terpenes and other compounds it
smells very different than orange so
yeah it's very relatable to music and I
find it it's easier for people to learn
and absorb that knowledge when they can
relate it to music
thank you for bringing that up Selina I
like the smell of limes the best of the
citrus hmmm my personal favorite is
neroli blossom so that's the orange
blossom it's very expensive but oh my
goodness once you smell it it's kind of
one of those things you're like oh I
must have this in my life at all times
because it has the little bits of like
sweet orange that really nice fresh
smell but then it also has these really
strong floral notes that come in and if
you can get the right neroli blossom it
is heaven it's seriously one of the best
one that you gifted me is my favorite
smell at the moment honestly I've never
smelled anything like it I thought you
know the
I'm that really orange that sweet orange
citrus was mine but the neroli just
takes it to a whole other level so thank
you for that it's not only like good
it's it's like seductive it is essential
you're like whoa you smell like this
beautiful like flower it looks like open
is just like at its peak you know it's
so gorgeous but it's not overpowering
its no it's subtle foam yeah yeah
did you see the poster at the last ICRS
presentation by Ethan Russo and Mark
Lewis mark Lewis did you like that one
oh yeah they're doing some phenomenal
work and Ryan can think Peter if I'm
correct Ethan just helped write it up
correct yeah absolutely yep yeah Ethan
presented it was helping presented but
yeah it's absolutely mark Louis's work
and so yeah it's nice I got the overview
from both of them so I know you guys
talked about it a little bit on a
previous episode but basically what they
do is they're making plants cultivars
with specific terpene ratios and so the
one that was really interesting that
they are most people were really
interested in was this particular
cultivar they had bred to be specific
for epilepsy and so it also had hi Linna
looool in it and I can't remember what
other terpenes that they were bringing
out awfully yes beta carotene thank you
Jim more to say about that Ryan I don't
know what I can say about it it was the
whole it was the whole team at neighbor
that did the work and that was for one
of their clients and actually wasn't an
apron that was breeding the plants but
they guide the they guide the science
their guide their client through the
science so because neighbor o is a
service laboratory so they're not
actually growing the plants and but yeah
it's fantastic work it's
there there the neighborhood folks are
doing some really interesting stuff
I like poster so much it's up in my
living room wall one-and-a-half meters
by 2 meters well for I mean you know
it's this this is the it's the same kind
of it's the extension of the work that
you started so long ago really Sam that
maybe that's why I love it
yeah I think it's you know it's very
very simpatico and I you know we got to
give credit to the founding fathers I
think without your work and your
teachings I don't think a lot of the
neighbor work even would be where it is
but you know well science right yes we
all stand on giants and I'm glad they
picked up the torch yeah they really
have taken to the next level though
there's some there's some more
interesting things that are coming in
the pipeline so maybe we'll see that at
next year's ICRS yeah we want
to agree with Ryan as well Sam thank you
so much for you know your foundation and
getting us to this point was probably a
lot of rocky roads a lot of dark closets
a lot of black market industries thank
you so much for bringing it forward for
all of us to learn from well Sam shows
that you can you can breach the the the
legal side from the dark side you know I
mean well that is the future of cannabis
is legal and everybody's kind of change
over you can't you can't keep doing the
same old things that everybody's learned
in the in the last 20 years and we've
got to you know come into the light as
it were well thank you use them for
illuminating that path because I feel
like a lot of us wouldn't be here doing
the work that we're doing if it wasn't
for you so thanks for pioneering through
the dark times and being the crazy one
I'm sure to a lot of people and finally
coming old 30 years ago was to bring
science on to cannabis and to bring
cannabis back into Western mainstream
medicine and we've done it a lot and
some of the companies are not
particularly loved that are leading the
path like GW Pharmaceuticals but they
allowed everybody to approach this with
a science proof that this is working and
now we actually get to have the
conversations around it with some
quantifiable evidence and move forward
which is huge so one of the things that
I think people need to recognize is in
order for that research to happen you do
need funding so at least we've had some
people including yourself you know be
there for the right reasons at doing
that research so we could be here so we
can talk to the moms so we can talk to
the doctors so we can continue to move
forward instead of be stuck in
legislation or just you know not having
memories cause so much is because when
you do research and development you
research all these different I
and issues and whether if you're lucky
one out of ten comes to fruit Asian and
leads to a pack that is economically
viable so you have to spend so much
money to get to that point that you have
no comprehension not spent millions and
millions and millions and and I I didn't
make that much in the end
I bent it and thank you also yes thank
you Sam also for still coming out every
Sunday and also on Todd's new show every
Saturday and spreading your knowledge
it's it's important to carry this
conversation on and we really appreciate
you spending time with us and teaching
us and listening to us also and yeah
it's it's it's an honor to be on the
panel with you well there's more and
more educated cannabis folks and we all
can learn from each other and I some
issues I was first but there's plenty of
other issues where I'm just as amazed as
all of you when I hear about it that's
the beauty of cannabis in and of itself
is it's bridging it's it's making those
connections it's sharing that knowledge
it reminds me in a way of like mycelium
you know it's this beautiful network and
we're at this time we're all
reconnecting it's really cool
where's Marcus now that we need him he's
on island time
come on rep you know we'd have a Marcus
but we have a mark can I ask you some
what was like one of the craziest things
that you've seen in your career on what
aspect I've seen too many crazy things
from my life how the windows when
somebody knocked on the door they just
jumped right out the window oh my god
really
when was this and why the 60s because
60s cannabis was fairly serious but
better at the police came to your
facility but not facility I mean your
home where you lived and found cannabis
they could basically trash your entire
house all your property and your your
persona also oh my god it just it blows
my mind it's just such a contrast to
what I feel is like right and now it's I
just feel those people must feel like
such idiots for it's just missing for me
[__] like it just blow their mind I
think they were doing what was perceived
in their minds as their jobs which was
you know you stopped being dangerous
narcotics and cannabis was officially
one of those yeah I mean in the media
anyways in your experience when was that
turning point like what shifted what
started to bring that back around to
maybe we should read really look the
medicalization of cannabis to really
change and also Industrial helped help
to a lesser degree but once people were
and children were sick and being helped
by cannabis
you just couldn't keep it down anymore
it was you know but the whole war on
cannabis took a whole bunch of issues to
end I mean and things to make it
impossible for the authorities to win no
number one might have been artificial
lights that made it impossible for the
authorities just stop all cannabis
production the other thing might have
been seeds and clothes once clones were
able to be passed around then you could
grow the best of the best instead of
just an average version of cannabis and
that made a big difference also so you
know clones seeds artificial lights made
it so the war on cannabis was impossible
to win but it still took another 30 35
40 years for them to really admit that I
have a question that you know is
something that you know I'm looking into
historically and also you know at at the
crossroads that we are at cannabis and
we were talking about bridging earlier
and I'm just wondering how we can now
that it's coming in to legalization and
recreational as a namesake you know
there is going to be more funding that's
put into science there is going to be
more isolates that are being made we're
going to be able to look at it in a
really different way how can we bridge
the knowledge of you know people that
have been working with this plant for
forty years and all of their
observational techniques as well as
their growing practices and what they've
learned and and then bridge it with
modern science seems to me that in
history you know with health of humans
or or and in modern medicine there just
seems to be more of a separation of
these things you know there's the
medical version and then there's oh that
other you know ideology of traditional
and I feel like we have a wonderful
opportunity right now with cannabis to
bridge those two and I'm just wondering
how we're going to be able to move
forward because this this whole
conversation it really is about you know
bridging modern science with with this
conversation yeah how how is that going
to happen I'm not really exactly sure
how to answer a question like that
because I mean cannabis has been used
medicinally for thousands of years and
I'm not exactly sure
I mean modern science also doesn't
confirm what we've been saying over and
over over and I believe I'm a believer
in modern science but it's really nice
when they're able to prove what we've
already already known for me for 50
years and for many others for thousands
of years I think it just in my opinion I
think it really comes down to having
those conversations person a person so
being brave enough to have that
discussion in the first place I think
that's what breaks taboo and I also
think it's what really just I don't like
the term normalizes but at least makes
it more acceptable so the more we hear
about it you know we're hearing about it
in the media now law we're hearing about
it from people that are advocating we're
also hearing about it from people like
Hillary's grandma you know who's just
had such an incredible experience with
it that she can't help but share and in
just my humble opinion I think that's
really what's gonna make the difference
and that's what's going to bridge those
worlds is continually talking about it
engaging in that discourse exposing
yourself in ways just to be that I know
I I sound so cliche at this point but
really like be the change be the person
that doesn't look like
you're stigmatized stoner that can have
an intellectual conversation including
research alongside some beautiful
anecdotal evidence and some stories I
find that that's been the best
game-changer for me it's it's gotten me
out of being arrested so just having
that conversation talking about my
grandma for example like one of the
local police officers were literally
handcuffed on the side of the road on
Thanksgiving three years ago and the one
cop was like totally not feeling it and
the other one we started talking about
my grandma started talking about how I'm
a medical patient that they can look at
my dispensary cards I've got my I've got
a digital endorsement from a doctor and
once we started talking about it I
realized that not only are you know
authorities misinformed but if they
don't necessarily seek understanding the
law themselves it's not laid out for
them in plain language so being that
person that doesn't you know that
doesn't fit that stigma being able to
carry through that conversation I think
that's what chefs cultures and that's
what what bridges worlds the elders and
younger people and and are getting some
of the most amazing results it feels
like sometimes I mean we've you know
seeing youth that have epilepsy have
that I've done everything that that
medical system has to offer for their
whole entire life and literally one day
after taking but you know some oils or
things that we've made they're just
completely gone and then stay gone for
so long and maybe it's I don't know they
maybe they're more you know open or
something but there's there's amazing
results and I think that's what propels
us forward more than anything as results
when it comes to you know health and
well-being yeah and it will be nice if
science you know is able to take those
results that so many people have been
working with cannabis you know in the
black market for so long you know it
would be nice if the
results were able to come forward and I
guess you know what you were talking
about you know continue talking to one
another I just think that it's really
important because I have a lot of
friends who have been working with
concentrates of cannabis for a really
long time you know 40 years and their
results and what they're doing is is
really really amazing but maybe their
stories they're never going to be heard
because science is like oh we got it
from here you know we're good we got it
from here and that's a little bit of my
concern because then that isn't looking
at the plant as a holistic view and what
we're learning from it
that's just isolating yet another part
of it and and I think that you know
having these conversations is imperative
to you know the the future of the plant
and the integrity of the plant tobacco
to happen with Gonzo's basically what
we're saying I mean that's my biggest
fear backhoes a master plant used it by
shamans all over the world for spiritual
awakenings but most of the tobacco that
we've been exposed to here is just crap
with chemicals in it so I think that's
the biggest part of what we've been
doing is not only you know looking at
the science of the finished product but
also what goes into it because there's a
huge impact that goes into the
production of the medicine so what we've
been working on in a huge way and all
this expansion is to keep what good you
know if you've ever looked at the map
that you make like if you have a product
here and every little piece that comes
off all the embedded energy that goes
into that we're taking on the production
of it and that production of it goes
from the farm and it starts even before
the farm and the inputs and we're
utilizing this this moment of expansion
to you know it's clean our earth at the
same time as because the purpose of
growing the Ganj is to heal the human
but the human can't be healthy with
without a healthy environment so it just
it's a it's a full circle Flower of Life
spectrum like look at it so we can't we
talk about
all aspects of it and we're feeling
pretty blessed and lucky right now that
a lot of farmers and production farms
recreational or medicinal are really
really interested in producing it from
an ecological standpoint and also you
know it's interesting we talk a lot and
the conversation has been a lot about
you know how healthy cannabis is but
often we're not talking about how to
make healthy cannabis and you know
cannabis is only as healthy as it's
grown so yes I think about lots of its
cannabinoids and what they all do but if
they're not grown in a healthy manner
then they're just simply not healthy for
us the potency of it if the potency is
all spectrums are building in the life
and health of our environment and our
well-being then that's the that's the
goal so if we have to look at the goal
the goal isn't to flush everything out
to make it clean enough to make it to
where we can ingest it I mean it's done
and if it's done there it is it's done
but I don't see it as a goal I see
because then where is it flush to and
then what's the life after that you know
we don't know because you can say you do
know but anyway having a you know the
natural process all the way through is
is really really crucial and I think it
takes a voice to bring people's
awareness to it totally one note on that
just as a reflection also the health of
the person that's growing the plant you
know if we have someone that is Candida
ridden I can imagine that their plants
might have mold issues for example I
feel like there's this it's a it's a
resonant vibration and it's also you
know it's a it's an environmental
mirroring so I feel like also you want
to make sure that if you're growing
you're healthy from the inside out part
of the problem of the chronic disease
that we're in at this moment is the
transformation of our food and the
transformation of our seat away from
it's a race well yeah a way from its
original setting wheat that was eaten in
Sumeria or the the Fertile Crescent is
not the same
is now you know so and in the course of
that change in that hybridization some
of it was natural and really positive
but other parts of it have affected our
ability to process it which is led into
immune diseases and what we're looking
at that was how to repair that you know
how to to move away from that that cycle
and I think the best way to do it is to
just stay as far away from them as
possible in the production of everything
that we're doing yeah so we always say
seed to seed a lot of people say seed to
sale but I think that it's really
important that it's seed to seed because
we can talk about healthy cannabis and
that you know or we can talk about how
healthy cannabis is for you but it's
important to talk about healthy cannabis
as well because you know we can isolate
a wheat grain and we can say all these
wonderful things that you know this
particular wheat grain has for you but
we're not at all looking at the way that
the wheat grain was grown and also and
that's important
some of the inputs that have gone into
the soils that we know use those inputs
are different and now it's affecting our
soil microbiology and its ability to
process nutrients which is just a
challenge so you have to be able to get
soil testing to be able to know if your
inputs are working properly and you know
that's a lab in itself too so there's
soil labs there's cannabis terpene labs
it turns into like a lot of labs all of
a sudden to back what you already know
really yeah in this modern way of you
know scrutinize ation of medicine I mean
food would be affected greatly as they
had to get laboratory tests to do it
this way well we never did our own soil
testing we we sent that out to a
professional AG lab here in the
Netherlands but I always tested my soils
i've always tested my water i've always
tested my this was either for organic or
any farming or for cannabis cultivation
and i really
believe in the science of cannabis and
gas chromatography in HPLC analytical
chemistry I mean that is the foundation
of modern cannabis and it's medicines
I'm excited now that both worlds are
being recognized as valid and yeah again
that the bridge just happened it's so
inspiring it's so exciting to be here at
this time and be a part of this we
totally agree we think that it's you
know it's it's a wonderful time to be
alive for cannabis and I feel like the
most important thing that you know I
personally can offer because we can only
really talk you know from our from
ourselves is that you know I can aw or a
voice she would like to be represented
and and she meaning that you know
primarily you know it's a feminine parts
of plant that we're using and the energy
of the plant is feminine but yeah and I
think that if we each go out into the
world and are a good voice for the plant
then it's going to move this plant
forward in a way that you know it needs
to go I'm in favor of cannabis
normalization and I presume that means
to be taxed and regulated by the
government
if you're involved in the sale of it and
whether that be for medicinal or
recreational purposes but I also AM been
around long enough to realize that if
you look at who owns the world it's
mostly bankers and lawyers that own all
of the big businesses out there and I
presume it'll be with Gerardus too but
as long as it's legal for the rest of us
to boutique it if you want to sell small
amounts or large amounts whatever and do
it in in a way that we care about like
craft beer or something like that
then I I'm in favor of it and also for
people if they want to grow their own
personal use it they should just be left
alone if they want to sell it then it
should be taxed or regulated so that was
a nice conversation we were all having
here but I just want to jump in with a
question from the chat someone was
asking if we had any experience working
with cannabis and pets and Selina you
had mentioned last week that you did
some work with cannabis and horses did
you want to talk a little bit about that
and whoever else has some experience
they want to share yeah I'd be honored
so we had one horse that we worked with
and we worked with her owner this worse
that actually had an unfortunate
accident where she got her leg caught in
a fence and had a wound that wasn't
healing they had a vet come along they
made some suggestions
they also saw us that weekend's ad alone
this Expo so we have this really
beautiful SABS that is great for open
wound care and we suggested that these
that it contains frankincense myrrh and
lavender we make sure that we use
grapeseed oil as our base oil because
it's animal and pet friendly and yeah
from the feedback that we got healed up
beautifully and no qualms the one
suggestion that we always have
especially with wound care and animals
in general especially to hugs is you
want to put that salve on the wound and
then take that dog for a walk so make
sure that you're getting them to be
active right after otherwise they're
gonna start looking at the wound and
because it does contain THC and
cannabinoids that can be potentially
psychoactive we want to be mindful of
that so you can use it as a spray as a
salve we use drops primarily one of the
things that we have formulated is a
micro dose drop so we can accurately
dose or I believe our cvd drops are like
0.66 milligrams of CBD per drop RTC 10.8
- so
able to really accurately dose low dose
and work out from there
we've helped animals from anything from
arthritic pain to seizures to end of
life care to helping in treating and
being a companion healer in the
treatment of cancers some successful
some not it's in the in the fact that
the we had this beautiful I'm just gonna
tell the story is that okay I was like
oh if I just tell the story okay so
there is this really beautiful dog that
we were helping and he had a type of
cancer that started to just really
affect all of the soft tissue
his owner very heart center did
everything she possibly could to save
her beautiful dog friends and it was
interesting because he had gone through
some very invasive surgeries where they
had literally removed all of the tissue
except for the ligament and muscle so
this dog had a lot of healing to do and
so loved so loved by his guardian and I
she's just such a sweet person to my
heart what ended up happening was he was
able to recover to a certain extent and
the disease was progressing but it was
it wasn't as fast it wasn't his rapid
what we were using at that point was a
one-to-one synergy oil so an even ratio
of THC the CBD and we were beginning to
ramp up and what we were noticing is
that this dog was beginning to get his
appetite back more playful again that
spark was coming back which was really
exciting with this particular type of
cancer that he had there was also a
chance of heart failure so we had
instructed his guardian I don't call
animal owners I call them guardians cuz
Guardian had decided to go with a raw
food diet just lightly cooked and we
were using the flora to support the
prevention of this now it was something
that Steve and my colleague his mother
she's uh she's
fascinating longer the short of it she
was able to guide us in that she had had
the same experience with her dog and she
had given us the warning on this she
also works as a blood technician at an
animal blood bank so she has a lot of
experience firsthand with sick animals
and helping get them better but what
ended up happening was this beautiful
dog got to a certain state of health
where he was happy-go-lucky and really
excitable and they were on one of their
regular walks and he spotted a deer and
he started chasing the deer and he ended
up going into cardiac arrest and she
heard him down just just down the gully
and she ran to him and he was having a
heart attack and I ended up passing in
her arms but the feedback that we got
was that she was so grateful that he had
been able to maintain a state of health
where his quality of life was so good
that he was able to really enjoy those
last moments of his life doing exactly
what he had loved to do and he hadn't
chased a deer for months so it was like
a really big deal so as hard as it was
for her it was also such a blessing for
her to have cannabis as one of those
allies to help make things a little bit
easier and I can say this to cannabis
also helped her go through that
experience as a caregiver and as a
guardian watching someone she loved so
dearly and still does go through such an
invasive experience before he passed but
what I've seen is that cannabis can be
applied in so many different ways for
animals and because animals don't have
these precognition zuv this is devil
drug or this evil plant or it's gonna
make me high or whatever they seem to
respond in my experience any way is
better to the medicine wear of it baby
of course it's cannabis made so so it's
it's for us it's been a really beautiful
experience and we've been able to help
dogs cats with anxiety issues with so
many different things especially animals
that unfortunately have been you know
have been subjected to traumatic
experiences it can help with that as
well just to alleviate that anxiety and
those symptoms of you know where where
they kind of lose control or they can
become aggressive we've had experience
actually with my mom she has two dogs
that both have epilepsy and we were able
to help get the seizures under control
several a day down to none within a week
of using a low dose one two one drop I
think we were at I would say well
actually it was one milligram one of the
dogs was a boxer Gracie and the other
one he's still with us Jake a little
Jake your buddy his little cocker
spaniel but jiggered used to have
seizures all day every day and it was it
was really hard and this was the
difference and for him his quality of
life is much better his appetite of
courses always been there but even for
Gracie you know she ended up passing as
a boxer who ended up going blind who
really had a hard time with integrating
with other animals socially after that
point because she was she's she used to
be top dog and then mom got another dog
who became the top dog a little yippie
your bull terrier so he was the dog and
it was interesting to see Gracie go
through that but I know for her
especially at end of life it was she
looked forward to the dropper she could
hear the little ding-ding-ding on the
little bottle and that was her kind of
like signal to perk up and get her
medicine and those drops on her little
cookie was was something that I know I
mean the cookie was great but she
recognized the drops for what it was was
pretty powerful with animals I mean you
have to make sure that the Guardian is
well educated of course there's a trial
and error I always recommend that we
pair it up with food being mindful of
fats making sure that we do trial runs
just like you would with with anybody I
usually recommend that we start either
in the afternoon or after dinner so for
example after six o'clock so you can
have a first drop you know and we always
micro dose and then just witness for the
next 24 hours how that animal will
respond just like humans everybody is a
little
different so it's not a
one-size-fits-all approach so monitoring
making notes keeping on top of things
tracking it is really important just so
you can get an accurate dose for that
animal and do them due diligence to be
able to get the medicinal benefit that
they're looking for some animals can
absolutely get high so that's the other
thing to be mindful of is if you are you
know if you are dosing your dog for
example and their homework are you gonna
play for us I'm sorry I was I thought I
was muted that's okay I was getting
stoked about you playing this is great
well hey I wanted to add something about
our dog our dog Floyd who is our family
pet suffered from some kind of allergic
response we don't exactly know we think
it could be a grass allergy because it
really became very prevalent during the
warm summer months of last year and
we've looked up so many different
treatments because basically what he was
doing is licking his paws so much just
because of irritation from this allergy
that he would basically lick his paws
raw I mean just licked the fur right off
it and like disfiguring to look at like
this blood swollen paws and we had him
on him on a medicine and new medicine
that's been advertised quite a bit here
in the states called a pack well ethical
is a sulfonamide jak inhibitor jak2
turrets yeah basically again you're
treating the symptom and not treating
the cause by deadening chemically the
immune response of the animal by just
you know basically like giving a
epilepsy patient benzodiazepines you're
just treating the symptom ology of the
electic event and they're not actually
going after the underlying cause so we
were kind of beside ourselves because we
saw all kinds of negative effects about
using this stuff called a pack we'll
which is readily prescribed now in fetta
nary applications
we decided to take him off of apical and
just put him on a CBD regimen of took
him off of everything what else do we
have month yeah he no longer gets on
spot flea treatments which we we hear
that one of the side effects of flea
treatments
you know these very powerful
insecticides that you put on your
animals if they're in a outdoor
environment to protect them from from
you know very dangerous insects and
whatnot I mean a lot of those have a lot
of whole laundry list of side effects
and we started seeing shudders tremors
he would just be sitting there and all
sudden he would just start shaking
almost like a like a like epileptic
seizure our previous animal actually
suffered from canine epilepsy and we
spent a fortune in the conventional
canine you know therapeutic way to try
to figure things out but we're too bad
we didn't really try CBD earlier but
here's the upside so the upside is that
this summer but CBD so the base solution
that I start with this about a thousand
milligrams and 30 mils of oil that's
what sort of a base solution to start
titrating your pets dose and what we did
is we just added it to his dry kibble
you know put a couple drops on and we
kind of titrated them up to what we have
mont about six drops a day eight drops a
day of that of that solution and i'll
post pictures up to my facebook is just
like night and day you could see his
paws my daughter had saved
yeah my fries okay I might have froze up
for a second my pitch and my daughter
the pictures of his eyes after I think I
froze again but um we'll post those and
you could see for yourself the condition
that the animal is in now he has no
tremors he used to get all kinds of
bumps almost like I don't want to say
acne but just some kind of skin
irritation from his allergy we see none
of that we see no yeast infection he's
to get secondary staph infections and
yeast infections from licking his his
fur right off of his it would expose his
skins to start getting staph infections
and that's a really key thing is when
you start smelling a different essence
especially coming from paws or areas of
open wounds you have to be concerned
with staph infections with animals
especially dogs his dogs you know like
to lick themselves and you know I mean
there are in some times not the most
sterile of environments but it is
certainly just with our animal anyway a
night-and-day I mean it's just it's just
like you could see it what do you look
like last year and all posted his paws
red raw from just licking incessantly to
now just having full skin and or full
hair and no side effects so what we feel
that we're doing Selina is where we're
boosting his own endocannabinoids system
to be his own Audis pharmaceutical
company right so when there's an
illogical pathogen or an antigen
response that it you know elicits a an
immune response
his body is fully fortified with enough
CBD to basically keep his body healthy
and again I wanted to say one other
thing before because I think Natasha had
mentioned this you know every time you
take any of these cannabinoids you're
putting Faxon ins into your body
oxidants or water-soluble things like
ascorbate and vitamin C and whatnot fat
soluble antioxidants are just things
that you need to have in your diet and
consuming and again I do believe that
prolonged cannabis
use provides a background of
antioxidants in Oedipus tissue and fatty
structures like the brain that help keep
free radicals and reactive oxygen
species from causing all kinds of
mutations and so yeah again like go back
to the wreck versus medical it's also
been shown that cannabis use will
protect your pancreas from undergoing
oxidative damage which can lead to all
kinds of conditions including cancer of
the pancreas so again I think David
Allen said if at whether you understand
it or not all cannabis use is medical
because these things are happening
inside the tissues and inside the
cellular mechanisms in your body you're
not even aware of it and while you're
enjoying your your creational hi and get
rekt with your friends and everything
you know remember when you said to your
college roommate hey let's go kill some
brain cells let's go smoke one right
you're actually ironically just doing
the opposite you're actually growing
brain cells protecting your brain from
oxidative damage and other oxidative
events that are very important to
control in your body because those
oxidative things can be very damaging
what about like eating versus smoking
versus vaporizing versus topical in your
opinion versus insertion well I mean
again the studies show the the the
famous UCLA tashkent study shows that
you know cannabis users who smoke
cannabis have a lower incident of lung
disease than people who don't smoke
anything at all so that tells you that
these molecules that we're inhaling into
our lung have a prophylactic effect to
basically protect from some of the other
environmental on slots you get from
breathing the air in New York City or
walking behind a bus that's spewing out
all kinds of diesel fumes or we're
constantly assaulted with carcinogenic
materials all throughout our lifetime so
it's a really in our benefit to have in
our daily consumption not only cannabis
but cats and antioxidants and
heart-healthy mala
skills like the the polyunsaturated
fatty acids and hemp seed oil we've
talked about quite a bit I mean those
are the kinds of things that are going
to help nourish your body and help your
body fight these infections and not some
pill that you have to buy from companies
somewhere I totally agree mark and even
eating like not just the cannabis plant
but also the hemp seed plant and the
hemp seed oil and the hemp seed protein
and even just fruits and vegetables and
mushrooms and all of these other
complementary foods we need to access
all of our nutrients Joshua and Kelly
did you guys have anything to add about
cannabis and pets yes I said you had
some experience also um yeah Maggie Lou
she lived to be a we think seventeen and
a half and she was a black lab so
probably somewhere at 12 years old she
started to have lots of tumors all over
and I was treating them topically with
my regular you know our oil that we do
because we make it into SABS or we put
it into the dog food we put it in the
raw dog food every day you know it's
just part of our daily nutrient it's not
something that we utilize just for a you
know an ailment or a malady you know
it's just something that's utilized
every day and we started noticing that
Maggie Lee was getting more and more
tumors and then I thought wow she seems
like she's in pain so then I started to
give her the CBD THC blend of the
half-and-half and she uh sorry I had
like a something happen there and within
a year I just I just thought I was
killing her paint honestly I just
thought wow here's a dog she's in pain
I'm just killing her pain until she
passes you know she's 12 year old big
black lab you know she's had a wonderful
life she's gonna pass we'll just try to
make her comfortable well you know I was
sort of giving her heroic doses of it
just to keep her down you know in the
grass and keeping her just calm and
feeling good and she could still stand
up and go pee and do what she needed to
do so she was getting heroic doses for
about three months and probably on the
third or fourth month I noticed that the
tumors were starting to shrink and by
maybe the eighth month all of the tumors
were gone every single tumor in her
entire body was totally gone and you
know she did heroic doses for three
months and that's just a really
interesting thing that we noticed and
and then she lived to be seventeen and a
half and just died of old age with no
tumors and zero pain what what's a
heroic dose just so we can put it well I
mean III loved I loved that we have yeah
I mean that's what we did we had we
would gauge you know how much CBD we put
in there because we had like a more of a
pure CBD strain that we made an extract
out of and then we had a THC strain that
we made an extract of oil extract out
and we put the two together in order to
make medicine that wouldn't knock her
out to the market yeah but but we didn't
we can't really tell you what the
milligrams were because we didn't have
the ability to test it at that time but
I can say that I utilize it for my
migraines and I would take a heroic dose
which meant that I'm gone and out for 24
hours done just totally sleeping and
gone so I was giving her the same amount
that I was taking which was a full
tablespoon she hasn't even thought so oh
yeah she would just be totally asleep
and out of it and in perfect
he wasn't like she wasn't allergic or
uncomfortable she was just really
relaxed just relaxed asleep wanting to
be outside in the grass feeling
fantastic at a point where she has
tumors on her like we wouldn't do that
yeah
you know extreme situation yeah just
yeah we dosed her up all the way up to
like a full tablespoon which I still was
trying to keep it a one-to-one because I
think the ratio is very important you
know my that I think that talking about
milligrams and percentages is really
interesting but I love the idea of you
know a balance a balance of the
cannabinoids are a balance of the
terpenes or our balances because our
body can only uptake so much you know at
a certain time so it was still a
one-to-one ratio that we were giving her
so we were upping her CBD tremendously
as well at that time a teaspoon was a
normal dose yeah so we were tripling it
for her were you guys like giving her
cuz I played around those dosing and
we've done it where we've like put it on
blueberries and stuff to make sure that
that animal can eat it it was your dog
just like licking it off the spoon no
you know dogs don't really like to have
things on their paws and if you just put
the oil on their paws then they always
lick it off they don't like having
anything on their paws they like their
paws clean and usually no matter how
sick they are they'll still want to lick
their paws so we're making our own raw
dog food now so now we can just put a
little bit in the raw dog food and they
just eat it the difference yeah but for
medicinal you can put it on the paws and
and if you make it a olive oil just put
your touch a touch of olive oil even if
you're doing like a another extract of
some sort you know dogs love olive oil
okay and that was a medicinal mushroom
cannabis oil to that we were using today
yeah at that point it's just you know
throw everything at it and it like you
instead of the kitchen what's in it for
us whatever's in the forest not our land
and stuff so which turns out to be
pretty darn medicinal in the end because
I mean but it's medicinal mushroom
extracts on their own our world to
themselves and to put the two together
with Matt with with kin
I mean we've had amazing results yeah we
encourage other people Mico cannabis we
think it's incredibly important it's
like to mastered genres of medicine
coming together and there's 5,000 years
of medicinal mushroom knowledge in the
Chinese
there's Russians and Japanese and Korean
people at not people but medical papers
there's tons of them you know if we if
we you know could read Japanese or
Korean or even Russian for that matter
there's a ton of of medicinal mushroom
studies on health and well-being and we
can't read those but there's a lot we
can and so putting it together with
cannabis has been an amazing thing yep
we think that it's a world that and the
dogs could I look at it really well
we're talking you know Polly Kapoor's
polypore Madison about that's what we
felt there is as oh and sorry I just
want to mention there was a comment in
the chat are you guys how are like when
you're administering the cannabis Rd
mean THC or TPA or you are you using
Rasta for using D carbs or combo that
was just a question from the chat I
thought would be an interesting thing to
clarify that yeah which is really
important yeah it's a THC a at the
beginning so oftentimes because we're
just keeping that temperature super
super super low and then it goes on for
probably about five to seven days which
is probably around 100 degrees yeah
maybe a hundred and ten at the most you
know at the very very highest there and
then we strain off that and then we put
more oil in there and then that gets
decarboxylated with all of the different
mushrooms and everything in there and
then that will be added as the activated
THC you know the non acidic version so
and then we also have the CBD which you
know is also slow-cooked in with the THC
a so just trying to add all of the
different versions of it it's primarily
low simmer cooked to keep it more on the
less active are you guys doing any stuff
I think you mentioned a little bit
before with raw cannabis and juicing and
even just do you ever feed some of the
leaves or put that into pill form do you
ever work with that with your animals um
you know cannabis is such an incredible
you know fibrous plant I think that it's
really hard to digest in raw form if
you're not you know just to maybe blend
it up in a blender a lot of people put
it in caps and I just think that that's
it just my own intuitive feeling feels
like that's pretty harsh on the
intestines unless you're doing some type
of a parasitical cleanse or something at
the same time which might be nice for a
short version period but for a longer
term I think that juicing is really
wonderful and we definitely utilize that
you know making teas is great you know
that there's so many ways that you and
to be able to start seeing that cannabis
is a basic nutrient but yeah we're
talking about it as like a medicine but
you know the hemp seeds is a basic
nutrient that our DNA has not had for
several generations because of you know
the interesting measures that we've put
upon it you know as humans you know on
the planet but now that we're starting
to get it back into our bodies and our
DNA where we're starting to research and
study it again you know the dogs like to
chew on the canada stocks - oh yeah
always give them the cannabis stocks
they love it they'll rip them up until
it's done they play games with it so I
just want to change topics a little bit
another question for Joshua and Kelly
came up a question from Martin Giles he
wanted to know how to increase
phosphorus and potassium during
flowering using organic practices if you
had any tips sir could if you could
amend or head some yeah I don't know if
you mean add to that oh for sure that's
like our passion so you just can look at
at phosphorus and phosphorus is this
amazing thing that comes from the soil
and it's easily found in
plants that have already up taken it
from the soil you know to take it from
its original form like a mineral or
something makes it really hard to digest
in the same way that a supplement that
you buy from you know a health food
store you know maybe you're only
digesting 10% of that because it's raw
mineral but if it's found in plants
already then it's easily uptake Abul and
that's why I Balaji is so important for
our own bodies to uptake nutrients as
well as for plants so we can look at
different plants that have high
phosphorous qualities and we always know
that the highest amount of the
phosphorus in that plant is going to be
found in the root and in the seed so at
the very end of a life cycle of a plant
it seeds and then it's taken all of the
phosphorous out of the plant and then
you're going to fight out of the soil
and put it into the plant and you're
going to find a tremendous amount of
phosphorus in the plant from the plant
in those seeds so when we study seeds
you know cover crops and things like
that we realize that a lot of phosphorus
is found in seeds and actually oddly
enough one of the highest seeds out
there is the poppy seeds so you can you
can take poppy seeds and you cannabis
and also cannabis see it's super high in
phosphorous and you can blend them up in
your blender and you can feed it to your
tea brew or to your soils to be able to
uptake those nutrients easily the plant
doesn't have to break it down it's just
readily available in the microbiology is
ready to eat it so burdock is another
one Turkey rhubarb is another one you
can use Bracken fern another thing so
there's you can top dress that you can
utilize those wild weeds and compost you
can make teas out of them so like she's
listing off a lot of the things that
we've just used we've used a lot of
ferns a lot of frizz there's a lot of
Bracken ferns all across our property
right now burdock is an invasive species
in the forest so those government
contracts for people to go down and cut
burdock down everywhere so we're using
burdock roots
hi and phosphorous turkey rhubarb's
really easy to grow it's a perennial it
comes back it's it can be invasive in
your garden you just put it in there and
you can use it in all of your teas for
your Gardens for phosphorus so easy
utilizing those roots and teas so we're
chopping them up and making a tea out of
them to get used to utilize an easy
uptake Abul tea raw cacao is easy to get
there's a high in magnesium has every
other nutrient in the world in raw cacao
amazing list and you only need a tiny
bit so you can put it in tea brew and
throw it on your plants and you can get
phosphorous what was the other question
what was the other nutrient phosphorus
and potassium
Oh and potassium potassium is is super
easy to to find in any flowering plants
or that are yellow sunflowers have a
tremendous amount of potassium and
they've pulled it all up and out of the
soil there's lots of roots potatoes Wow
potatoes are so easy to grow and you can
make potato mash this or ferments to
feed your plants and and it's
immediately at a cabal kelp if you're
close to the ocean about sketchy
yeah oceans pretty interesting oils
accordingly so if you're making a soil
think about adding and roots and
different things like that to your so if
you're doing a soil blend if you have
piece of land and you're gonna try and
accumulate those materials that you know
are high in phosphorus maybe it's your
bones that you've been eating or maybe
there's bones around that you can burn
and stick those in your soil you can use
your chicken eggs you can save all your
chicken shells and put those in your
soil over the calcium is top dressing
mm-hmm um if you have an outdoor
situation you just take those basic
principles that we just gave you and you
try and accumulate the biomass and in
the soil if you can get it in the soil
breaking down composting that's your
ultimate and then utilizing fermented
raw leaf teas or raw root or raw seed
teas and the summer is the way to
liquefy those nutrients and put them in
on teas and it's free and you can you
can grow them yourself or you can
from nature or really another easy thing
if people are indoor growers you know
what we're all lacking and what soil is
lacking and what cannabis plants are
lacking and health and well-being or
trace minerals and you can grow an aloe
plant in your indoor garden or in your
in your kitchen garden and you can add a
ton of trace minerals to it you know
that have 90 trace minerals there's 72
trace minerals in it and then you can
easily take those aloes Spears and then
we could either drink it or even add it
to our plants and then all the plant is
getting it easily accessible through
microbiology and soil it's all pretty
easy super good high compost is the
number one basis a question that came up
is when you're using the seeds you
mentioned cannabis and poppy seeds and
you're putting it into your fertilizer
or how are you using the seeds are you
sprouting them or you like are you doing
that first are you just using the seeds
as is someone was wondering you can you
can do either/or if you're gonna sprout
them you just want to sprout them up
just a tiny bit so that the the
phosphorus is still really high from the
seed you could blend the sprouts and use
and make it into a liquefied tea if you
had a lot of seeds you could grind it up
and use it as a top dress on your soil
it should be really awesome and let the
roots come up and eat it
and it's easy to find hemp seeds so you
can just put them in a blender and top
dress over your soil which is really
nice to you a little bit there's lots of
different ways that you can utilize seed
nutrients seed there's such an amazing
way to get all of our you know basic
minerals because they have everything
that they need to grow into a really
large plant at the at the beginning you
can utilize your cover crop like green
manure and just sprout it on the top and
and drop it you know throw it like that
big and pull it off and drop it on your
soil and let you know more microbiology
on the top layer your soil eat and live
off that so your cover crops that you
sprout on the top layer of your soil are
gonna have different nutrient mediums a
nutrient makeup so what you do is just
look at the nutrient makeup of all the
seeds that you're sprouting and utilize
those seeds in different cycles in order
to feed that into your
soil because you know the plants gonna
get different things out of the soil
based off its own based off its cycle so
if you can get in tune with the cycle
and what you're sprouting then using
seeds is a cover for the deficiencies it
into the deficiency is ever also just
teased you can put you know your seeds
and teas and just ferment them in water
you know and utilize lactic acid
bacteria or e/m other cultures and it's
an incredible large worm home for that
question
[Laughter]
phosphate we choose not we're not
interested in traditional organics
letting the night and potash and
sulphate upon - we don't use those type
of charged minerals that are three can
you share why well because it's a the
the practice of gathering that out of a
mine alone is a problem I mean just the
sulphate of potash would go to one go to
a mine it's like he takes two thighs
it's a really hot terrible place to work
with people with a bunch of lung
infections running around building
scaffold and trying to clean but it's
crazy it's basically crazy sauce and
then you put that into your and then
it's a charged element so it can be
organic it can be from the earth and
stuff but it's charged up and your so
which can is to be left down there
reacts with the plant that way but what
we're saying is that even with bat guano
I mean there's a lot of reasons why not
to use bat guano maybe it's the
collection of the back dog treated late
maybe you realize as soon as they
started putting back wanto and ships and
putting in ships with potatoes and bring
them to Europe all the sudden million
people died cuz this crazy blight
happened and which is talking about
microbiology which is so important
different thing ya know what we want to
do is just be like word food ganja
poppies ten officials you know in our
soil and it's not a bunch of charged
minerals for us we're trying to say
alright we want the things that are
gonna react in a kind and gentle but yet
really easily a symbol and potent
I mean you can see our Instagram pages
are different planets and different
things we have giant plants we don't buy
things for our plants like our whole
entire farm is gross the local soil that
we've piled together in different ways
compost that we've made and huge weed
teas we're growing weeds with weed weed
weeds it's amazing yeah growing plants
and it's mean it's easier for the plant
to uptake so the idea is that you've got
this wonderful catalyst or or the
middleman and when you have the
middleman of a plant it's already up
taken everything that it needs from the
soil to then be able to give your plants
or give you so why are we going to this
basic raw mineral that we can't really
uptake and neither can the plan and it
takes a really long time for the soil
microbiology you know to break it down
you can utilize plants as a as a
catalyst for say magnesium you know as
an example of you can grow your own tiny
little alfalfa pot you can give your
alfalfa a tremendous amount of magnesium
and that's a plant that can up take
magnesium like in lots amounts so then
you can cut it three times a year and
make a ferment out of it make a raw brew
out of it but you know a chop dress out
of it sure is what you do it and it's
just easy gardening and farming you're
not driving anywhere you're not having
to do anything and people are able to do
this in indoor scenarios as well it's
not just for a farm we've been working
with really large indoor facilities to
learn to grow their own nutrients and
create closed-loop systems that are
working and they're on like you know
they're their tenth run and they're in
large recreational indoor facilities and
and they're having tremendous you know
growth and possibilities and health from
you know what people thought was never
possible and they're doing it cheaply
along with everyone in the pure
certified family and the pure farmers
that are doing all this amazing work out
there I mean we're providing ways to
grow indoors with soil tests with lab
tests everything Pru
to work were utilizing natural outdoor
systems were utilizing indoors and
commercial settings and utilizing in the
outdoor so it's not just a thing that
can only happen far away in the
mountains on barns it can happen end or
indoors as well
I mean bonemeal is another thing you
know you that that's a crazy thing to
put in your soil I mean where does that
come from and really I mean do you know
blood meal you should think about
organic farms are utilizing massive
amounts of blood and bone meal I mean
you wouldn't believe the amounts that
organic farmers are utilizing you know
that are all certified organic and and
not only I mean you can think about what
what is it like when a when a steak sits
out for you know a few hours as opposed
to what an apple looks like when it sits
out for a few hours and the difference
is between those smells you know meat
and and things that are from animals are
going to really draw they become a
prebiotic for pathogens as opposed to
plants become a prebiotic for more
beneficials not that they can't be a
prebiotic for for pathogens but that's
why you know it's so important that if
you're going to continuously add those
things into your soil that really you're
not drawing a beneficial microbiology
symbiotic relationship in your soil
that's going to help you long term you
know we know that we're feeding microbes
we're not feeding our plants so we know
that on microbes are feeding or so so
what microbes do we want to feed you
know we have to think about those
populations and phosphorus and potassium
are one of the harder things to access
when it comes to farming so that person
who asked that question is asking a
really good question because you know
it's usually a lot of finished off bad
you know well harmful or things that
take a lot to produce you know those
type of things so what we're just
utilizing is natural systems
lots of compost roots and and that's
what that's the alternative the
alternative to it and so the vitality
comes through the but you know plants
growth still to full potential
and then your systems can last longer oh
great great comprehensive answer guys
thank you so we're gonna wrap you on it
so if people want more information about
what you guys are doing do you wanna
give us your contact info your website
info where people can learn more yeah we
have an Instagram page we just are
posting things often just pictures and
some ideas and good things dragonfly
earth medicine and then our website is
dragonfly earth medicine so that's
awesome and if you just push contact
them on the on our website you can it's
just a direct email to us and we're
really taking a make it important to
answer every person that writes it with
any questions so we're in contact with a
lot of people and if people want to find
out more about the p r-- certification
and what that means and what pure farms
are out there they can find that out on
our website and online as well which is
there's a lot of people doing amazing
we're providing really amazing that's an
ecologically seven way one more question
for you guys from the chat people were
wondering do you add what do you think
about adding external microbes such as
mammoths PE or soil balance those type
products do you use anything like that
or do you just make your own tea blends
and stick to your own micro blends well
for our own property we utilize all the
indigenous microorganisms here because
we're trying to create beneficial
you know intelligence here on our
property you know we see your your
entire property as a micro biome you
know and we're creating the intelligence
here on our property but for our for our
products we go out and buy beneficial
microbiology and then add it to our
herbs as we were explaining before and
the most important part of your question
is just to make sure that you know where
that microbiology is coming from and you
know how it's made often these are made
on you know GMO substrates or often it's
pretty
and really large facilities that are
really unhealthy for the planet so it's
important to really find out how its
produced and and the company that stands
behind it so and if it's preserved if
it's in liquid sometimes there's
preservatives and liquid so it's always
best to use raw materials to feed your
microbes so I mean if you don't have raw
material if you think you're out of
balance of microbes I mean maybe you
shouldn't get a soil test but to know
for sure or maybe you just know because
you can cuz you know but yeah
preservatives or another thing thank you
and I appreciate you Thurston thinking
of all these different points of how
your even your raw materials that you're
putting into your your substrates how
those are processed and I mean again you
have to think of all these issues and it
gets complicated because you even have
to think of the people that are making
these things and all right you know
what's the working conditions like for
them even so yeah I appreciate you guys
difficult points and trying to do the
best you can and do the right thing and
keep all the integrity to the plant you
can so yeah did anyone else have
anything else to include with the
conversation before we wrap up I'll give
you a chance their contact information
also we always enjoy having you here and
learning more from you so yeah just to
finish up the conversation mark and Sam
did you guys have anything to add nope
okay so yeah okay
mark mark might have had something to
say I was gonna play a song you're gonna
play a song when we're done but one sec
yeah Celina given this your contact
information and you can find us on
instagram at fol CCS that's Flower of
Life compassion Club Society you can
find me on Instagram Celina sativa and
you can find us on Facebook the flower
of life compassion Club Society
so thank you everyone so much for
joining us so thank you Joshua and Kelly
was wonderful to meet you guys
thank you Brian who was in earlier Thank
You Selina thank you thank you mark
shelled Oh wonderful you could join us
too
today hey thank you down we appreciate
you being here thank you for your
insight
thank you chimera and thank you Mark our
guests are popping in we're looking
forward to hearing more about what's
going on in Jamaica and thank you to
everyone for listening and spending your
Sunday mornings with us thank you so
much so mark you got a we can't hear you
it seems like my Internet's a little
choppy all of a sudden now that you're
on stage I apologize in advance in case
it's like jumbled but I was thinking
like what's the appropriate song well
I'm at a fish show fish has got a song
called dirt that's four-letter word
right dirt sounds good yeah okay so I
don't know some people call it soil some
people call it dirt but in fish circles
the song is called dirt so here it is
[Music]
[Applause]
like to live beneath the dirt a tiny
space to move and breathe is all that I
would ever need help I wanna live
beneath the dirt will I be free from
push and shove like all those swarming
up above believe their heels off spend
my shut me to the wind all wiggled in
the earth and do shout your name into
the way
sometimes I would think of you shout
your name in and if you ever think of me
kneel down and kiss the earth o me was
this thought is worth I never hear your
voice
[Music]
[Applause]