this
computer oh
yeah I just need to share the link real
quick all right here we go here we
go all right everybody thank you so much
for your patience 9:13 only 13 minutes
late today not too bad for someone that
hasn't done a hash church and God I
don't even know how long uh shout out to
Addison and Jameson for doing their
podcast for the last couple weeks or
months or however long it's been they
pumped out a bunch of great shows uh but
everybody Welcome to Hash Church 4.0
episode 4 uh we're going to talk a
little bit about harvesting today this
was kind of a last minute uh episode put
together by Addison and the dragonfly
Earth medicine wonderful to see everyone
wonderful to see skunkman Sam's little
Dr Seuss doll dude it's been too long
since I've heard your voice welcome
every everybody to Hash Church episode 4
welcome
howdy howdy
howdy to see everyone I'm sure we'll
have people popping in and out all all
morning you know checking in on their
plants checking in on their
plans I'm excited to hear about the 800
pounds Mantra and what's going on with
the
pipeline and uh just see everyone I
agree no it's uh we're super uh very
grateful Marcus to give us the
opportunity to come on and talk a little
bit um I'm not sure how this came about
I think I think Marcus contacted me and
then had some ideas and then we all kind
of got together and figured like why not
let's let's have a hash church and talk
a little bit about what's going on right
now and I think Marcus you came up with
the idea about the
harvesting um for solventless and that's
the the kind of topic is like you know
talking to some farmers I was lucky
enough to bring my own farmer which is
uh a friend um from um sugar magnolia
Farms yes sir you want to introduce
yourself and give I'm Jud uh sugar
magnolia Farms honored to be in the big
city La Zone uh Addis and I have been
trying to catch a sesh for a long time
we first met uh at the 2014 Cup in
Richmond I believe he was still doing
testing stuff I was lucky enough to be
working for Sheldon black glass and uh
my pot and
hash Journey began at that same time and
uh honored to be here taking DS with you
guys yeah he's been fing shout out to
Richard yeah Richard man for sure yeah
glass shout out to Richard that's how we
met back in the day old that's an old
brother man I met him through rure
listen before we get started the idea
for this really was inspired by my team
over at Whistler Technologies uh Daniel
and uh Andrew did a little podcast
recently where they did a little just
the two of them talking about harvesting
and preparing for solventless and it
kind of gave me the idea like I was like
man I know a ton of awesome farmers and
cool hash makers like why don't we kind
of do that idea that they did but kind
of pump it up a little bit get more
people involved more people that are
actively uh farming but also the people
who are actively um making hash and just
kind of have a little discussion I mean
it's been too long since I've seen uh
everyone here for sure um shout out to
Alice shout out to ganja Gill shout out
to Joshua shout out to Daniel and Skunk
Man Sam and 800 pounds and I had an
amazing time recently at the at the
Unicorn cup shout out to Chay and his
whole team at the Unicorn cup I thought
events like this were a thing of the
past I thought that this was done and we
were just moving into this future where
everyone was upset and getting crushed
Red by the uh new world of cannabis this
is old school this was an absolutely
spectacular event made even better by
spectacular people I saw one of my old
buddies Alan middlemist from the coutney
crew that I hadn't seen in a decade or
more while I was there paddle boarding
with my buddy Tyler hanging out on
psychedelics in the TP with with the
dragonfly Earth medicine and all the
great people from uh Colona and the Cy
and Kevy and oh my God I can't even say
enough about the Unicorn cup it was just
so so good uh Kevin jfrey was there I I
would uh definitely implore anyone who
wants to come and experience uh I heard
talk of like oh this is like the emerald
Cup in 2009 it really had a great old
school vibe to it um worth coming down
worth checking it out they did an
incredible job chay's Mom owned this
incredible property with this Rose Bud
Lake and all these beautiful Acres of
forest surrounding it it was spectacular
uh I really just can't say enough uh
about it so um yeah welcome everybody
I'm super stoked to get some dabs in and
uh talk to everyone in regards to really
you know solvent list and prepare
preparation of the material and Flash
freezing and all of these things can be
our topics but at the same time I'd love
to hear about where you guys are at
where you've been coming from where
you're going where you're at currently
in this sort of chaotic cannabis uh
experience that we're that we're all
sort of uh I don't want to say trapped
in because I think a lot of us are
lifers and it's something that we choose
but it's definitely been um it's been a
challenge to say the least and a lot of
people have uh have been taken out so I
sort of uh I you know I think of them
all the time people that have been
involved in this plant for so so long
that have just been unable to maintain
with the with the legality and the taxes
and the sort of getting squeezed uh out
so we can of course discuss that as well
and and of course I would very much like
to hear uh any and all stories from
skunkman fam I haven't heard his voice
in h a very long time uh and whether you
know it or not buddy I think about you
all the time uh you've deeply affected
my life you've been an amazing mentor
and friend and uh I Think About You
Austin thank you very much yeah dude a
man of few words a man of many bong
rips
ye so yeah pretty excited to see the
group very thankful for uh for Josh and
Kelly as well as Addison for kind of
putting together a little group I love
the intensity of which Addison is
currently getting dabs ready like you
can see guy is like dabbing the way he
works out he's like no [ __ ] around this
is serious [ __ ] get everything organized
have your tools
clean oh dude I love you I'm trying to
make I'm trying to make Sam proud of me
right dude Sam's proud of you trust
me yeah yeah Marcus I'll just double in
on the Unicorn cup experience and how
sweet that was I I mean Rose Bud lake is
filled with turtles little painted box
turtles which is like you don't find a
lot of turtles in the lakes around here
in the cies they exist but it's like
amazing and so you have this Lake and
you're camping out and it's sort of like
just Trails through the trees and stuff
so it definitely has that like OG flavor
to it and stuff look at all the samples
and and it's fun to meet up with a bunch
of people you don't see a lot so this BC
community in the Alberta big up to all
the family we met you know out there and
stuff and just had the best time so yeah
it's cool to have an event up here the
borders have been hard for us you know
going back and forth and for other
people that are into Natural Wellness so
that you know hopefully by next year
those things change and you know it it'
be sweet but yeah it's only going to
grow and get more powerful so and it's
nice to have like the big dance party
kind of aspect to it which they had this
huge stage
and uh yeah just it's just a lot of fun
just a lot of good
times and now you know we're just I I
wish the Unicorn cup was a little bit
more later in the year only because of
having fresh outdoor gja you know it's
hard to get even light depth stuff out
there by August for here you know it's
nearly impossible so uh but whatever
it's better weather you know and the by
the time the end of August comes like
it's rain times here so
yeah how are you Alice let's hear from
you because I know you're kind of down
in Brazil with the on and off internet
and stuff why you tell us something good
you've been in New York somewhat
recently hanging out with Liz Liz was
also up here at the Unicorn cup so we
kind of had that like love link going on
so uh yeah and Flynn up in down up in La
wherever up or down wherever you are so
yeah tell us something good
the this year has been a literal
trip um first thank you for the
invitation I'm happy to be among you all
uh we came here to talk a little about a
little bit about Harvest but this is
like the first year that me and Flynn
haven't been cultivating in a long while
after some difficulties with the county
last year I think you
know moving from that subject was
experience um bunch of traveling
different cups um and now I came to help
out organize one of the first hash Cup
in Brazil so they did w in Brazil and it
was the first main hash event that has
ever happened here we did a super hidden
uh it happened yesterday it it was
historical to be able to uh experience
this in Brazil in such to blessed in the
paradise land so I'm still buzzing from
yesterday uh and actually from the hash
quality I've seen from their
Brazilians uh multiple hash samples
barely no rosin little little solvents
but everyone was crushing with the hash
and with the temple balls and it was
very very very beautiful to see and to
watch and I'm buzzing so at this moment
this is where I'm at um and I'm sorry
for the internet definitely this is
Paradise wow internet doesn't work well
in
paradise it's working well enough that
we can see and hear you so I'm
appreciative what what thank you what
strains were you seeing down there
anything we would we would
know okay so the people that won
yesterday they won with like a beot
cookies um there were some saw some
cookie things on the menu of course some
like uh different like orange turps like
some of the B the best like solvent
samples were like a super actually clean
uh
citrusy beautiful
B2 I didn't try it I just smell it
because you all know which gam I I Jud
you by the smell and
look um but um lots of like Gorilla Glue
still like people are like kind of like
more tach to this old part like little
OG little old Gorilla Glue and they love
the Gorilla Glue here and they love this
San Fernando Valley tur they love this
this parts stillo so that's what I kind
of saw from the samples from
yesterday cool that's awesome it was it
was a good event everything everything
went uh stealth you said like you guys
didn't have any
issues um the biggest issue was that we
developed an app to run the the votes
and then because of the internet a lot
of people logged in and the C kept
logging out so it took longer because we
had to do it man manually so till this
part was amazing the the end of it was a
little like counting the votes was
stressful but the rest was all good like
it was beautiful they played there was a
rock and roll Bland playing psychedelic
rock and roll the event was held in a
place that it's uh people do iwaska so
it was literally a round circle and with
like uh geometrical like geometrical
Circle was geometrical Circle sounds
crazy right
but it was just like a lovely place and
um the vegetation the music the people
it was small and beautiful the hardest
part was the EP but the EP will work
next year and it will be
fire well next time next year if you
guys want um we just developed with a on
a blockchain with some partners that we
have an entire judging platform um and
we're gonna we're talking about being
able to make it any other event um you
know making it so that other events will
be able to use it for their ticketing
but also be able to use it for the
judging
and it's all secure it's all on a
separate server um so yeah that's uh we
would love to you know let us know next
year we'd love to chat with you guys
about yeah I was gonna say let's
exchange it's always good to like
exchange and grow
better that's what that's what hash
church is all about so is dragonfly
Earth medicine's entry in this cup
number
four I'm not sure dude I think it's your
I think it's your guava punch breath
right here bro first one I picked out I
think it is I was like oh my God it's
pretty like noticeable dude there's 20
of them and the first one I picked out
was yours that's what's
up um Al I have a quick question oh
Johnny playing ahead his camera's off he
might be he might be busy Ask Alice
question then we'll welcome Johnny
[ __ ] be and it's beautiful to see Sim
but I was going to ask Alis a quick
question with the
iasa family you know often with plant
medicine and iasa ceremonies there's a
thing about oh we don't do ganja you
know it's like a tobacco and plant
medicine thing and they're like you know
but then there's different tribes that
you know allow cannabis use and and and
and did you find in this area that there
was obviously an acceptance towards
cannabis and I just wonder what your
thoughts were about that AIT so
different churches and different groups
they definitely have different practices
so definitely some con consecrate
cannabis as a part and it's um it's
Santa Maria that they call it like so
the spirit of the Cannabis is Santa
Maria church and it's also a doine so
some people follow it like a religion so
there are rules and things like this
here was very open the people from the
like the people that have the the
property it's a 52 acre uh eological
property here and they do reforestation
and they they hold some iasa rituals and
some EV um they were very open about it
and um it's not like they do not want
the plan it's just that sometimes it's
not part of the ritual for them it
doesn't not belong uh in the in the
ritual like the way that people use it
and what I've seen is a lot of people
that do go to the iasa ritual and
realize they have a tough
use as like a tool therapeutical tool
and then it helps you out a lot and some
people also have different intentions
and actually the use that it's not
necessarily healthy for them so in
iwaska trips that's something that
sometimes pops up so I heard bunch of
this tobacco use and whatever and they
also consecrate tobacco in the ha form
so it's like a powdered tobacco with
other herbs and then they culate that
and that's very connected with the roots
and the Earth it's more to
help out bring the people um that are
actually flying on their ritual a little
bit more to the ground and to the
earth I appreciate that thank
you ganja Gillan the place we got Ros
kaiia Paul coming in hot we got Daniel
hanging out with sarim and all the
saraphina sorry and just really stoked I
know Josh is out there trying to pull
buds in from the rain and he's got his
some type of willow tree or something on
there dude I love when babies make it on
to Hash church that's my
favorite all ages welcome at hash
Church
definitely and definitely yeah welcome
to kle welcome to Johnny B Johnny
B good morning
everybody I'm in the middle of Sticky
Fingers well that will be at 10 so we
still got 41 minutes 30 minutes till the
10 o'clock
pushup 4,200 push-ups a month come on
it's not that hard 20 push-ups seven
times a day getting it 30
days that's what's up Johnny B has been
getting it which uh you know is pretty
incredible for a guy that's broken damn
near every bone in his body I don't know
if you guys keep up with Johnny B's
drama but the last car accident someone
T-boned him and flipped his car upside
down in a ditch and that's with already
the surgery on his spine and the broken
shattered half of his body and the
broken neck and the broken back and the
broken legs and the broken arms and the
broken jaw and the shattered skull just
some of the things our Johnny B has been
through while he sits there if you've
never seen the power of cannabis as a
medicine this guy doesn't take anything
else other than cannabis and his amino
acids and sort of all these sort of
healthy supplements um should be dead
really or in a wheelchair or completely
[ __ ] uh I mean he is completely [ __ ]
but he's completely [ __ ] in our way in
the good Johnny D way in the loving H
cannabis way so I appreciate you as
always dude it's always nice to see your
smiling face and I'm quite certain that
uh you probably got the best reception
uh in the chat room as well people are
still saying good morning to you in
fact Johnny how did you have an accident
was it your fault was it the a duck
flying from the sky what what happened
so what was going on with this
particular last accident that some guy
was I know just driving down a country
road you know just hanging out things
are good and listening to Napoleon Hill
you know just kind of doing my audio
books and out of nowhere some guy
thought that um being on his cell phone
while driving put his foot on the gas
and blew a stop sign of about 80k and
hammered me
flipp me three times the back end of the
car hit the telephone pole rolled and
landed in a ditch upside down broke my
ribs towards some this cartilage off my
sternum and four days later I was doing
push-ups I was like and ice like well
that's impossible I know while I already
live in chronic pain I do a lot of bong
rips I smoke hash and I said that
blatantly straight out that's what I use
in my pain control and that's about
it and yeah and I just kept going away
movement is how we heal you cannot just
sit there and do nothing about it so I
started walking right away took me four
days off I started walking started doing
my push-ups you know using creams and
stuff like that and just being dedicated
to oneself getting up at 5:00
a.m. it's got to heal you got to move
you got to keep things going plus my
garden was just growing so just like in
the midst of putting that in and you
know it's important that uh well
I actually got a picture here so I'm
like to show you this guys can see this
for those of you that missed it when
Johnny B got rear side swiped or T-boned
and flipped into the ditch he literally
went live on his like social media like
five minutes later that's how I found
out I saw him upside down in his car on
his social media I'm like oh my God John
what now this is also like the third or
fourth accident since it's got to be
like two or three since just your back
surgery no John or your neck surgery
yeah it's it's been a couple since the
neck surgery this guy hit me so hard he
ripped the door skin was attached to his
bumper as you can see
Jesus it's never light it's never
something chill by the way that's an
incredible joint ganji Gill like I don't
even smoke joints anymore but [ __ ]
hats off to you my brother uh that is an
incredible joint when I did smoke joints
that is a joint that I would smoke right
there
already to cut you off Johnny that's
okay don't have to that's that's totally
fine it's been a while since I've
moderated one of these rooms I'm a
little bit Rusty if you know so here you
guys
go what you this is your accident
happening oh my
god
dude dude how do you have
that it's right like this I thought only
Russians had uh driving cam on their
car during his like maybe you were the
reason why you crashed because you were
filming cam now you can see he's sitting
on his cell phone have dash cam it was
all dash cam my God you had the accident
for
likes no I don't know if you got any
likes or not I mean here here here's the
one I got in in 1988 I was H head on by
a dump truck so that was the original
accident so yeah I have been through
several major accidents and you know
what understanding it was 20% of the
problem 80% of the solution was growing
from that and that's what I did I Grew
From My accidents and I grew by using
cannabis by helping it get me through
what I was going through I grew it it
got me off the Pharma it helped me
connect to your community it helped me
build a better lifestyle I mean come on
you guys are awesome we all do the same
thing it's why we're here so we give
back every day you know
what about 20 That's crazy dude I'm
still in shock um welcome to a brother
from another mother in the house he's
been doing the rounds with the veterans
I've been watching them on Facebook he's
been doing all these
speeches tell us a little bit about that
bro well hello uh just got back from
spending a week in Washington DC on the
Capital Hill uh took a whole bunch of
veterans uh and we went after the uh
Republicans and Democrats on the
Veterans Affairs and armed services
committee and uh yeah we literally had
26 meetings on Capitol Hill in 72 hours
and I big shout out to our volunteers
who came out George
Armstrong uh Lynette pardon me pardon me
Marilyn matth uh my wife Michael cowt
Brian Buckley Todd catini Nate landow
Lenor vanales George Armstrong Tony
Landry Michael green and Amy case King
we're all just uh veterans and we went
up on the hill talk the talk walk the
walk made a whole bunch of meetings made
a whole bunch of friends uh but uh yeah
we had an agenda on a whole bunch of
work but uh tired I just literally
walked 12 miles in two days walking
around Capitol Hill so I just got home
yesterday so I'm a little tired and sore
but uh need to get back there because we
got a lot more work to do still
so no doubt it's amazing um from the
Canadian perspective I just have that
because I'm here and that's who I am but
it just uh it's so strange the um like
Valor and that pride in country and flag
and the way they send you off with such
pride and love and bragging rights
almost like these are good men and women
uh but then you guys come back and
things are like shaky and holy [ __ ] I
got poisoned by gas and I I [ __ ] did
some things that that my brain can't let
go of and I I would like to be able to
use cannabis and I would like and they
just they just [ __ ] they're they're
completely against everything you want
like they don't want to take care of you
guys is this an accurate description of
what's actually going
on yes but actually we're using you
Canadians as an example right now
actually we're trying to one of the main
reasons we met is to put uh the Canadian
VHA and American Veteran Health
Administration in the us together
because currently your system thank you
to Aaron Victory and other uh Canadian
Veterans for educating on what's
Happening Canadian veterans can actually
go on their National Canada app right
now if you are at 100% disability rating
such as you you're given 100% disability
rating by your VA the Canadian VA gives
you up to three Gams per day free of
charge depending on whatever your
modality so if I want pill I want a
joint I want an a lollipop I want a
sublingual I want a patch as long as it
equals up to three grams in the end the
Canadian BHA will mail that to you
within 48 hours so um yeah we're trying
to we were talking to them about
reopening the compassionate
investigative new drug program which was
shut down where currently only Iran
Rosenfeld receives it so we want them to
reopen it h staff it with veterans and
grow quality of the Cannabis of
everybody here and what I sell in
California not of that crappy Mexican
varietals that they've been pumping out
for 50 years so we're actually the main
talk is is to facilitate and get various
PE various senators and representatives
to put the Canadian and US vas together
so that we can get something similar
here in the US in the sense of sorry to
bore you uh we just want to uh have a
voucher system so we can actually the
same way you receive free cannabis well
all of our veterans are on disability
with very small limited incomes and the
cost of cannabis is very expensive so if
we could get a voucher system within our
10th Amendment reality so that we could
supplement and help our veterans
actually get the medicine they need
today as opposed to taking it out of
pocket well that'd be helpful so that's
just one of the the things that we're
working we're trying to get our medical
card designation on our VA cards so that
if we're no matter where we're traveling
through all 50 States territories or
federal property we won't get arrested
you know simple things that are logical
but apparently you know is illogical to
you know the system itself so um thank
you to our veterans for coming out
strong this week and making uh the stand
and thank you to the National cannabis
industry Association for uh allowing us
that ability cuz we basically went out
of 12 veterans and hit 26 different um
senators and Republicans um directly and
they were very responsive some ignored
us but yeah bubble man you're exactly
right we we're treated like [ __ ] we're
treated like second class citizens and
we have to fight for everything we have
so uh we have banded together uh and
again we're all volunteers we don't get
paid for this so we're out trying to do
this for the better of everyone so we'll
continue we we got to get back again
there soon uh that seven days wasn't
enough we
got it's great
work go ahead I have a question at Chen
uh who pays for the three grams that you
can get for free as a veteran in uh
Canada the Canadian government pays for
it it's a subsidized program last year
they pulled out 15 million or so
unfortunately there's a scandal I read
that just came out this week apparently
a whole bunch of money disappeared and
there's a whole bunch of Scandal around
it but right now the the Canadian
government is funding about $150 million
per year to uh give free cannabis to
Veterans who meet those qualifications
does that mean the Canadian government
is buying it from private producers
yes I I just want to understand how the
system works I mean they're buying it
from the system and the system itself so
they're buying it directly from the lpas
they're packaging like I said through
the national app and mailing it within
48 hours so we can't keep in mind we
have over a billion GRS sitting like
there's there's there's billions of
grams in Canada that aren't selling
either donate them we'll take them we
take donations of every
kind so I'm sure the Canadian
government's getting that for a very
good price if they have a deal with like
one of these big auroras or canopies or
something
yeah it's not easy cannabis in Canada
let me tell you set it up uh it's about
as easy here as it is in
California if we only that
easy yeah yeah exactly if only it were
that easy thank thank you very much for
having us and having me on this morning
to talk about that we're humbled and
honored and uh needless to say thank you
all for all your hard work and
dedication and thank you for being the
leaders in Canada for us to be examples
to follow so humbled and
honored what uh how can people support
you uh in this cause that can is there
somewhere they can go and read more
about this or do it just really connect
to you on your social
media uh we have a a site veterans
action council.com we're all on on on
social media Etc uh we accepted uh
donations via the battle brothers
Foundation uh which is a
5013 lit anybody who could donate uh
directly uh those that's tax deductible
and it we receive support all around the
country uh from people and we're an
international group we had an Israeli
veteran we had gentleman from we had uh
Amy came from Mexico uh so we're not
just United States veterans we're
fighting for Access worldwide uh one of
our gentlemen changed the international
law Michael krowitz in December of 2020
getting uh medical cannabis removed from
schedule 4 So currently medical cannabis
is legal around the world and one of the
things we were there in DC doing is
reminding the US Attorney General's
office uh that currently the United
States is out of international treaty
favor which we used to follow uh because
if we were actually following the treaty
medical cannabis is legal in the United
States in all 50 in all territories uh
including around the world which is why
you're seeing other countries coming on
board and pushing medical cannabis so
that's why we were in the United States
capital using Canada and Israel and
others as examples to say Hey you know
currently we were telling the guys in
the in the VA and the da uh in the
defense department there that currently
there is an Israeli nasal spray right
now so if you received a TBI a traumatic
brain injury from an explosion or a hit
or a concussion or an accident that they
actually administer this spray right now
and it stops a TBI in its tracks because
as we know cannabis is a natural
neuroprotectant right so if somebody
gets blown up okay in a vehicle or
something like that they're usually down
two weeks being concussed okay so if you
could stop the brain swelling and stop
the permanent damage that happens that
the Israelis are doing then that's
something we need so we were there
trying to embarrass the American
politicians by saying hey look here's
Israel and Canada way ahead of us where
are we why are we not catching up why do
we have to wait another 10 to 15 years
before that nasal spray is available in
our medic packs that's a that's people
could use that today okay so these are
the things that we're trying to point
out the hypocrisies so that we can make
advancements for our brothers and
sisters so that they don't have to
continue to suffer you know we got off
the sidelines we're tired of sitting on
our couches and sitting on and
complaining about things get off your
ass get active get involved and
contribute to democracy otherwise shut
the [ __ ] up we don't want to hear about
it if not get up walk alongside of us
we're walk along with you yeah you got
vote yeah if you don't vote you can't
complain you just just don't vote you
can speak to your Representatives every
single one of us that was there on DC
represented tens of thousands of people
so when you go and you speak to your
politicians you're representing many
people so do so use your voice use your
stance volunteer that's how we've done
things that's how we've always done
things that's how we will get things
done and change things cuz we're not
financially involved
we're our our lives are involved and by
using our voices to act and help out
those who are the voices who can't can't
speak they will vote behind you and they
will push you forward you just have to
get out there and Lead so that's all
we're trying to do is to lead by example
it sounds like it sounds like if you're
not a person who's able to go speak to a
representative and go out and talk to
your local you know politicians you can
if you're a grower if you're a seed
breeder if you're a hash maker atan it
sounds like you can donate product to
you guys so that it does get out there
or donate funds that then can be used in
that way so you know Ju Just because
you're not able to to talk to
politicians I'm not a huge friends with
politicians or willing to to really do
what etn saying but um you know I am
able to and we do donate to to some of
the different organizations that are
doing that stuff that are or or even you
know what's even cooler is grow some
weed and give it to etn so it can get
some uh to some of these guys that's
even [ __ ] cooler I think that's no no
no no don't give it to me find a local
veteran where you are and adopt veterans
adop a veteran give them their your free
cannabis that's what guys did for me
when I was doing this back in 93 Dennis
peron's grower actually grew an eth and
had a free eth for me every three days
so make sure that you adopt a veteran
take care of those who can't take care
of themselves so that they have access
so that they can be strong and be
medicated so that they can actually
contribute and help and use their voice
as well so you know help locally and
regionally it helps everybody nationally
dab a vet bro yeah so get off your I
like it we were gonna talk about
harvesting for processing but how about
harvesting for vets make sure when you
harvest tiny little bit of that is
heading over to your vets there you go
someone's got to take why not the
Cannabis Community that's a great
campaign you know it's uh I I've I've I
was talking I've got some friends that
are vets and they're they're pretty
interesting guys they're like Special
Forces guys and I love I got I dug real
deep into like living in a very
undisciplined life my whole entire life
having no supervision from birth to to
up until now um I I I never looked at
any discipline or any of that stuff like
it mattered I was always just kind of
wild and free so growing up and then
getting really interested in it and
talking to some of these friends what I
learned is that they commit and give
their life to not the government but to
the group of men that they serve with
they become a team and that team is just
like [ __ ] this no matter what us against
the world I got my team and I was
telling them I'm like that reminds me a
lot of like me and my buddies when we
were we were like stealth and we were
just a small group of dudes that all
stuck together that had our grow houses
we'd hang out together after we tended
our Gardens and like we were a team you
know and and and it was like I see a lot
of similarities you know and then I I
talked to them too about afterwards you
know they're out of of you know military
service at this point retired and
they're doing other things but I'm like
you know do you feel like your
government served you well and how did
it end and if you listen to a lot of the
stories that typically they're tapping
out and they're leaving that because
they're either you know a lot of them
get accused of things that they didn't
do because of um you know the the
conditions of like you know engagement
and Rules of Engagement different things
there's all these different stories but
a lot of them in the end aren't really
happy with the government and how the
government you know ends up doing them
in the end whether it's through veteran
services or other ways um so there's a
lot of odd when I talk with those guys
I'm like well you know I'm a veteran of
the drug war and you know we served in a
different way but we facilitated the the
the production distribution transport
for consumption of medical cannabis like
that's what the [ __ ] we did we made
great livings doing it and then we got
into science and we got into all this
other [ __ ] and they're Blown Away by it
and they all love weed every one of them
that I know they really value the
compounds the other compounds that we
value they also value the
neuroprotectant that cannabis is so
that's why it's so crazy at the end to
hear about uh there being a medicine
that's a a spray that works as a
neuroprotectant that's [ __ ] crazy so
that's nuts when when is is that product
available is that like a
drug it's currently available in a medic
pack right now in Israel so why is it
not available at a medic pack right here
in the United States why is it not in a
medic pack for the Mexico why is it not
a because they never wanted us to
succeed with weed it's too powerful and
it empowers us to live our own life and
not give a [ __ ] what the government
thinks that's just but doesn't doesn't
the money go us don't tell Israel they
said [ __ ] all that and did it anyway
don't you guys give them billions of
dollars though didn't you buy that for
them yeah yeah we paid for it we paid
for it the money doesn't go Israel
America you've already paid for this can
we uh talk it out and so they're gonna
try and put us together and have those
conversations if you can get illegal
oxycodon and and all these other drugs
on the street you we should probably be
able to find this I'll call a guy see if
we can get some because this is this is
I guess call Hash church I'm not happy
with the
government or like you know sports
medicine for that spray too you know you
think about all these athletes too you
know like my we were just setting a park
and my little boy was seeing a football
practice and he's like football I'm like
oh I don't I don't know if you want to
play that
but yeah I mean you need it in the
Cannabis
CRA so we're talking about ctiv but
seriously when whenever they go into
that blue tent for a CTE they should be
shooting them up with that nasal spray
because it's the same traumatic brain
injury that's going to continue to swell
which is going to continue to disable
that person cause nerve separations Etc
so between cannabis and then if you use
mushrooms to reconnect those nerve
endings that have separated you're
actually healing and and and and
actually bringing yourself back into
your know homeostasis preferably using
using the endoc canabo system to bring
the body into homostasis which is
[ __ ]
badass also using a very specific
nanoscopic vehicle to deliver those
drugs to break the that that brain blood
barrier and that's one directly absorbed
into the mucal membrane right it goes
straight to the brain right there so so
hopefully in the very near future I'll
be able to talk about what that vehicle
is because I know what that vehicle is
and I have a company right now that
we're looking into that particular
vehicle and uh maybe in the next couple
of months I can I can talk about that
because it really does finish the circle
uh when you're talking about uh you know
delivering the payload and getting it to
where it needs to go and making it um
still effective because the the blood
brain barrier is um it's super [ __ ]
heavy man it keeps out like almost
everything but we were educating that
specifically on what even the endoc
canabo system was okay because the
majority of them don't even know because
again recent discovery so I mean you
could literally start to see their eyes
just glaze over when you started to have
that discussion those were that were
doctors or science and scientists
because some of them are they got it you
know some of these no they don't get it
so much we talked to a lot of defensive
fellows and the thing that got to them
which are basically their officers who
are basically assistance to uh senators
and uh representatives for a year and so
they basically work in their office so
they're basically they're being bred
into perfect little generals however by
using the TBI information specifically
uh that was a way to get through to them
because again we're looking at ways to
connect with these people to get what we
want right and we can talk all the
legalization and medical this talking
that t TBI spray was the arrow through
all the [ __ ] all of them pretty much
for the most part were like oh [ __ ] oh
that makes sense oh that's l iCal oh
that's not a bunch of people sitting
around and smoking pot etc etc so again
it's also about finding how we connect
with these people using language so that
we can get through all the prohibition
lies that we've had for 70 plus years
and make a human connection so that they
understood that this could be you
because we also used Alzheimer's as an
example in using the um the uh uh the
the patent that the US has as a
neuroprotectant and showing these
senator and representatives specifically
your governments has had had this patent
okay so why is Israel and can of being
able to benefit from us and we're being
laughed at and our guys and brothers and
sisters are suffering oh we know why we
we know why yeah for sure yes we know
why but I'm trying to make it I'm trying
to hit them in their third eye and this
is how we got through so these are
skills we're learning and we want to
teach you so that you can be better at
talking to to these Liars so that they
can see through the
truth politican which is the Psychedelic
aspect of life too which in Canada you
know it's not just weed that you can get
for three you know three grams you can
now starting in January
get well every every drug is GNA up to
two 2.5 grams I think I think it's two
and a half grams just in BC just in BC
oh yeah
yeah you get to like
help affect reality which is which is
super powerful and then we don't also
really kind of need to dance to all
those that those songs you know we have
other songs and other rhythms that we
dance too and stuff so it's it's a time
where we can kind of choose our own
adventure and uh you know sometimes you
feel like you're banging your head
against the wall and then you see a
little glimmer of light down the hallway
and you're like oh maybe I'll try out
this other this other realm stuff so I
like it that that everything's happening
at once and uh I'm thankful for it being
fall you know we get to talk about all
the good things that happened in the
summer the the ACT acist stuff that
we're doing and then watch the ganja
develop in front of us knowing that
these compounds are listening to us talk
and the plants are listening to us
they're helping communicate with us
because we're breathing in their air and
they're breathing in ours and now that
cannabis is going to help Propel all
these thoughts forward it's crystals
they're Tricom they're crystals they get
affected by thoughts and they're water
we water so I just really appreciate the
intention you know and everyone coming
together and in a slight shift I wonder
how everyone's dealing with their
crystals right now in in their Harvest
and like is it raining in your
world did it rain in August did you feel
a warm to cold night shift because we
get sometimes rains when it's warm out
and it's terrible for the buds but if we
get rains with cold nights we really
don't get the
because they have this inner plant shift
that happens that they're oh you know
it's the wrong environment so I'd love
to hear what some of the people are
feeling in their Harvest yeah yeah like
what's being what's being done right now
to prep for resin
harvesting like like
Rost what what are you uh what are you
guys doing right
now I saw you cleaning up the plants a
bunch the other day
yeah we we have uh mostly been pulling
in light depths and in the end of August
here right after the Unicorn cup about
August 25th we got heavy
humidity and um we have in a mountain
valley so the mount the whole valley
fills up and then sometimes you get
these just clouds going through the
valley and we just call them death death
clouds and stuff but luckily this we
have we what we'll do push-ups too oh
you're doing push-ups okay
good it's 10 o' man
just 49 push-ups in
a he's on the schedule looks like we had
glitch nice one those are
gooder nice and C but but we're really
thankful this year uh for the Harvest
and it was really amazing and we haven't
watered our green houses for like a
month and a half now you know just zero
water just keeping it dry in there and
then if we do get rains instead of
dropping the walls we pull the walls out
you know so the water's kind of going
away from the the house and in some
cases leave the end walls just totally
open um and that just allows enough a
little flow through but there's no like
blowing
yeah you know Mist coming coming on the
plants and I'm so stoked about the one
Greenhouse left right now there's zero
mold in there and now we have these cold
nights and you can literally see like
whole layers of new crystals come on
like overnight when it gets down to 35
39 you know degrees which is what close
to what we're close to freezing at this
Mo you know in these times and stuff so
big time cool years zero power powdery
mildew around even on you know the
ground and stuff we're using way less
tea and way more just in the soil
building and way more into the the
layering and the mulching and all that
and I feel like it's really helping our
plants because the plants just go into
the soil and they're just like oh this
is what I have to work with and it's not
necessarily over pushed you know with
nutrient
to where it kind of becomes vulnerable
it becomes they become huge and
sometimes it's fine but when they they
have a the cells and the way the plants
grow and they have just their soil going
on um they tend to be healthier and they
hold themselves better and we don't
trellis so much you know but we're not
dealing with 20 pound giant plants
either and obviously you you TR us a
plant like that but um so it's been it's
been good for us this year and I'm so it
sounds like there's a lot of things that
you've got to take care of in regards to
the the flower itself right in regards
to molding and not kind of rotting out
but are there anything other than I mean
obviously each year you're going to make
cash out of your varieties and press
some raw and then smoke those ones I'm
I'm sure you you're keeping the guava
lines going I mean those came out so
beautiful uh in hash and rosin that uh
are there anything else that you're
doing at this time that's really
specific for the
resin
um there is a thing about too dry in the
greenhouse and then sometimes that there
some of the weeds will start dying and
stuff so you kind of have to keep a
little light make sure there's life
going on so that when plants die they
tend to get you know more pathogens on
them to help them die but really it's
not we're not doing any sprays no foler
sprays um
and minimal minimal watering towards the
end and really is just walking through
uh keeping a really good flow through
environment for uh you know to to manage
the the pest so there's we're having
zero pest issues because we have so many
flowers every Greenhouse is surrounded
by food um and uh so you know that
another thing we've just had deer and
bears you know rolling through our green
houses this year more than ever like I
mean it's like oh it's cool to see a
bear but really like when it's in your
house like every day all summer it's
just interesting and then you have like
deer in the middle of the day like
hanging out like f you walk into a
greenhouse you're like she has a [ __ ]
deer in here what's going on you know so
the the animals are coming in quite a
bit more but like I don't know I just
think it's keeping uh walking through
every single you know day two or three
times a day making sure everything is
cool making sure nothing's fall falling
over keeping the weeds lower so there's
flow through and really like just
praying you know just playing music you
know and then also keeping like the
prayer Vibes going and and the
ceremonial sort of aspect you know I
think that helps a lot you know and so
that's what we've been doing and we're
thankful someone ask what the guava
lines that you're working with are top
dog or Oni and then also I will also add
that we've also had the Bears it was a
late winter we were still skiing at the
end of May my friends were still
flooding in June um and so the snow was
really when they came out of hibernation
the snow was all around them and they
got pushed down lower to find food and
when that happens generally they just
stay low you know and and so we saw like
an 800 my kid was on his trampoline the
other day he like Mom there's a bear and
we're just like oh like which which
direction is it running our trampoline
is like down on the road so he's down
there with his little friends right he's
just so chill he's like oh it's it's
walking up the up the hill it's going
into the mountain okay well if it turns
around just come up to the house you
know and my buddies were visiting in
from Vancouver and they're like look is
this normal dude you just have like
giant bears walking around your
neighborhood it's like well if you did
notice we live in a forest and there's
only two options leave the Bears alone
and then they'll be around or kill all
the Bears and you won't have them
anymore and so we went for the the the
first one there just leave the Bears
Alone um when they when they call those
conserv officers the only thing those
guys conserve are their jobs because
they they're the ones that kill the
Bears they don't conserve them
so we have a lot of logging and stuff as
well but I would just say uh there's
there just a lot around it's called bare
medicine how powerful and strong they're
almost like a dragon they're like and
they chop their teeth together but
they're so doile and if you watch them
walk through a garden they in some cases
they'll just bear their way through like
squash you can't really but like in some
way they just tiptoe through we've even
had them open our car door with just a
nail whatever and grab like chicken food
out of the car and walk away and there's
zero scratches on the car which sucks
that're in the car but and we have to
keep the food out but it's kind of like
wow situation um the guava punch lines
came from Kush Kirk in southern Oregon
who I thought might be here today and he
had been working with the purple punch
and the punch
breath welcome to Kell and hi everybody
good morning there was some interesting
blood rain barrier talk earlier today
which would be fun anyway barrier but um
also uh you know just uh i' just like to
say everyone all the de andure family
like uh the coffee from Ka we continues
to grow in the family I know there's new
lines that K has been working with I
know he was at melting of the heads and
you guys rocked out a really fun time
there super excited to hear more about
everyone's varietals I've been getting
just really amazing stuff from family
super stoked about heart rock uh Daniel
and and these uh hashy Autoflower lines
that he's been coming out with um really
blessed uh to be trying those out this
year we we didn't necessarily do them in
numbers this year but we wanted to see
kind of what the the finishing time
would be like up here and and a lot of
them all worked out like super well
um BL beautiful the blue Thunders uh the
lemon head chem is uh just starting to
to come on the the blue
diesel um and uh oh God what was the
last one that we just harvested uh but
anyway you know just thank you for those
and and and a lot of people up here in
Canada and and BC are really feeling you
know are have actually have bought your
seeds over the last few years and are
continuing to work with them so it's
really cool to see that uh and I think
it's good for us to it was fun to see
them oh I was saying I think it's good
for us to readdress know like we've been
pulling tarps for a whole lot of years
and now to be seeing varietals that are
catching up so we don't have to do that
that we can put our energy elsewhere
more into internal work and into family
and community places where we really
want to be rather than pulling tarps so
there's a really beautiful free up I
think for the whole you know cannabis
community and you know putting our
energy where we where we want to put it
and and having good varietals that allow
that so thank
you are
we it was fun to see those grow up there
uh they're really pretty and if you guys
do have good to submit to the Autoflower
cup the injuries are due at the end of
October we we have one I think that's in
mid November in Northern California this
year and I'll be there as a guest
speaker in vending and I had a super
successful Autoflower breeding program
this summer where I probably made over a
hundred hybrid combinations where it was
like part of my goal for these past few
years to just breed the lionclaw in with
full terms and then make them Autos but
make them poly hybrid so that I could
start with an a a poly hybrid that's
fully auto to kind of try to bring some
strength and vigor and some and then go
from there and work down the
IBS and by ful AO does that mean it has
two sets of Auto jees male and female no
no um so the autoflowering is it's a
recessing trait and uh so it doesn't
show up till the second generation of
EMB breeding but takes three generations
to make it auto you know sticks to make
it like stable but it it um you can
cross an auto in with a photo period and
and just inbreed them or outbreed them
so if I did like you know a blue dream
Auto with a cookies and then a cookie
Auto th those are those f1s would would
not be auto flowering but you could
cross those two together and then the
next Generation which would also be an
F1 would show up with a 25% or less
autoflowering so I kind of been working
on
that the
25% that are auto flowering they are
they've got Autoflower jeans from both
the mother and the father correct um
well not if you cross an auto in with a
photosensitive that that but that 25%
would have both parents jeans but it
would be expressing that recessive train
it would be dominant and that was 25%
and then you would select two of those
and then if you really wanted to make
like the auto Blue Dream you would go
three generations down to make an
Autoflower but then you would back cross
and and that makes a lot of sense from
what just what I've noticed from
breeding that you you know to really
stabilize the um trait of
that you'd want to go back cross to the
F1 or back to the Blue Dream because
that would really then bring the
structure and the effects of the Blue
Dream Out further in that uh in that
line and then you'd go a couple more
Generations down to six and then you'd
have a fully auto you know whatever the
photo period you were starting
with I love
it sounds like something Canada
needs so we will send some
down bubble man how are your flowers
looking this year
that's not too bad I uh you know I went
and I thank you for asking that because
really what it allows me to do is shout
out one of my longest time friends and
mentors Ron hickey who I got to see
while I was out in Proctor BC in the Cy
I hadn't seen him for a very long time
uh so for those of you that have watched
the channel for a while you'll have seen
a couple of videos with me and Ron on
the making hash making dve sift and
bubble and just he's a super character
he's just one of the greatest people
that I know and uh so I got to spend
time with him unfortunately before I
arrived he was like rushed to the
hospital with uh with covid he ended up
yeah like I'm on the way I'm like seven
hours into my eight hour drive and I get
a call from his like roommate guy that
helped with the plant Will shout out to
will uh and Ron's on his way to the
hospital he's having problems breathing
and I'm just like oh my God I'm super
worried about him now I'm just like
crazy like I'm at his house by myself
hanging out with sort of the people that
take care of his plants uh and luckily
he came home the next day he did have
covid I still hung out with him for a
couple of days uh he kept at a distance
and and wore a mask while he was in the
house and whatnot and we just uh I still
got to hang out with him a little bit
and Vibe with him of course you know if
you know Ron he's got plants all over
his property he's got his greenhouse and
he's got uh he moves the plants all day
like nonstop as the he's like oh the
plants got to have the best son so he's
just moving all these [ __ ] plants all
around his property in the most insane
of ways that only really Ron could
possibly do like it irks him for the
plant to not be in the best son and so
he had a lot of plants uh six or seven
or eight varieties and so he gave me
seven or eight of these different unique
plants I've got them out on my deck
right now they're probably like three
weeks uh maybe four weeks into flowering
so they've got like another month and
and a bit there's a Congo out there that
will probably do another you know six
weeks or whatever I might have to bring
it in and put it under a um LED light if
it starts raining here soon but uh it
was nice to have plants at the Unicorn
cup I was I think the only ones who had
living plants because Ron was like you
got to take these plants and I'm like
okay so I had these plants around my
tent I was lucky enough to be sitting
with these dudes uh what the hell was
their brand called melts or something
they had a melt something melts uh the
two oh they both have the same name too
I it's terrible that I can't remember
really nice young guys that are working
in the industry making beautiful melty
hash uh and you know he's like he bubble
man you know I listen to you and Kevin
talk and I want to find I want to find a
haze I want to get into one of these you
know
sativas and so the guy next to me Tyler
was like listen if you're trying to get
into a sativa what you need to find is
that damn Congo plant because if you can
find that and as he's saying that I just
get up and walk away because I'm
thinking I'm going to give these guys
the Congo that Ron gave me to bring here
and I did while we were sitting there I
came back and I put it in his lap and he
looked all confused he's like what's
this I'm like that's the the plant that
Tyler was telling you you need to get
and he was just like mind blown his
buddy still didn't know what was going
on until he just turned around and gave
him the plant and his buddy was like
what is this he's like it's the Congo
the the plant we were talking about so
shout out to Ron for for just being so
awesome I can't even remember the name
of all the cultivars there's a Congo out
there there's a Black Domina out there
there is a a white wrecker I think he
called it and one that was
called what plant did you see that made
you go wow this one that he called Ezra
was just like covered in resin it was so
covered in resin outdoors and the Cy it
just reminded me every time I go to the
cotney I see at least one plant like
that and it was that EZ so it's not the
name of the cultivar it's the name of
the kid who was living at his house and
brought this cultivar I'm not sure what
it is uh it's out there right now it's
the first one that's turning like the
hairs are turning pink uh in the cold
night but uh it looks my these plants
are very little they're like a couple of
feet tall just just some ornamentals
really I didn't even you know take them
out of their pots I'm really not a big
grower so when I when I wanted to have
what I am is a is a big hash maker and I
love the relationship of I'll tell you
there's a a show on Netflix right now
and it's all about pizza I think it's
called Farms a Table Pizza it's a six
series six episode uh series and I'm
telling you these people are us in the
pizza world and they're all unique and
different there's a Korean woman there's
a Japanese guy of course there's a
couple Italian dudes there's this really
cool woman from Portland and they've all
changed the game in the face of pizza by
becoming obsessed with getting their
hands into the dough creating their own
dough visiting the flower field the the
wheat Fields visiting the the fig trees
and all the different ingredients that
they end up really changing the face of
pizza it's totally [ __ ] inspirational
each one in it in their own rights you
can tell are just absolutely
legendary uh and it's so it's so you
know they're out forging mushrooms and
they're out forging berries and flowers
and they're talking about the biome of
the and the farming and the regenerative
they're just talking about everything
that we're talking about and it's neat
that we're going to end up there and
even the the the Italian pizza chef
saying you know back in the day Italian
or the Pizza Chef was the lowly Chef we
were looked down upon because we were
just making pizza and now they've
elevated this pizza to what I would call
full melt pizza and it's just
reminiscent of our community especially
you know people like best friends and
ganja Gill and you know the dragonfly
Earth medicine just like
really getting your hands into the soil
and understanding that the magic happens
in the Simplicity it doesn't have to be
overly complex and um I mean obviously
the volatile organic compounds are going
to be very complex and and profound and
have depth but how we can get there
doesn't it it can be very simple it
doesn't look flashy and it's not uh you
know like uh what's the word I'm looking
for it's just it's very simple you know
it's it's a guy just walking in his farm
with his rubber boots on and he's he's
he's now he's walking into the forest
and he's picking mushrooms like our our
community has that aspect of that sort
of farm totable aspect of like you know
when we the one Italian guy says at one
point you know the reason my pizza is so
special is because I make all my dough I
don't let machines make my dough if
everyone makes pizza and machines
everyone's Pizza will taste the same and
so that was like a profound state to me
that really made me realize like yeah we
This Is Us the Cannabis some of us in
the Cannabis industry that are really
passionate about this and love the
understanding of the botony of the plant
and the biology and all of the things
that are happening in regards to the
field and the environment in the Terre
and then the person who takes it those
hash makers we are always so quirky
we're always so obsessed we're always
we're just a different breed of people
and we want to get right in there and we
want to show much like these people to
Makers what they all wanted to do was
they wanted to honor the ingredients
they were given from The Growers and the
genetics and they wanted to create
something that honored that and that as
a hash maker sums up what I want to do
in a nutshell and it really made clear
why you guys are so so so important to
me and the work that I do because I'm
not a grower I'm not growing plants I'm
not getting in the mud I can I can grow
plants but I'm not that's my my focus is
is honoring what you guys have done and
creating something of value and creating
something that can be a little you know
wind in your ear a little just a little
moment of Happiness while you're hitting
that bowl or or twisting up that that
that
joint that's I feel like that really go
forth and be Saucy he
says I feel like that describes the
exploration of just uh fermenting and F
and generative farming and building your
soil and hug culture and making all
these layered beds and all that we just
are like wow look at all these
ingredients we can make soil out of and
holy [ __ ] look at the flavor coming off
this this is not Pete perlite and worm
castings this is wow this is the whole
environment so I mean I think that's the
exploration of the flavors and the turps
and do it for the turps and you know do
it for the soil let the your soil not
the plants that whole exploration is
kind of that pizza exploration you just
described um hey Gil I was wondering now
that you want pizza because Marcus just
said all that um how did you survive the
fire and how are you doing this year and
everything I know you got like sweated
on really hard in Trinity County and how
did it affect your Harvest and how you
feeling right now you're looks like
you're at the coast which is
nice yeah um I
escape the fire unscathed yet again um
I've been at the same place for 10 years
and I feel like I've dealt with fire
more than half the years there but the
last three have been pretty brutal so
it's definitely getting old but uh yeah
doing fine Place made it fire I think is
still burning as of yesterday but we got
some rain this morning so like I'm
hoping it kind of put it out but uh just
part of life in California now
especially Trinity County that was
lightning
complexes yeah man it was crazy there
was like you know that night it was like
hundreds of lightning strikes all in
like a really small isolated area like
really really small and it like lit 15
fires right outside Willow Creek and uh
it it was crazy I was like every year it
gets worse it's like you know it's like
oh it's close then it gets closer and
then these fires now become 150,000
Acres or now they're like really close
to town or there's all multiple it's
just like over and over again that that
immediate area the Willow Creek area has
had it really rough these past two years
so definitely feeling for all the
farmers there really bad just because
the nature of the market isn't super
great and then to have Mother Nature
kind of like throw you curve balls is
just like literally the death blow I
feel like for a lot of people where we
had a really late spring it was really
cold and it kind of [ __ ] up people's
depths pretty bad a lot of the structure
was was off like small flowers Twiggy
stuff you know so that was tough and
then the fires came in and it's like you
know it costs a lot of money a it's like
your livelihood being threatened every
day which the stress is just
unbelievable but like it costs money to
deal with Wildfire I don't know you know
I'm sure people do realize but there's
just all this extra stuff you have to
deal with you know that like you don't
really anticipate so it's like it's
definitely a hard year for farmers in
that area really feeling for him you
know potent ponic has a question for you
he says given all the fires how much
longer do you think the Emerald Triangle
is really viable for long-term cannabis
production the climate is only going to
get worse do you think it will shift
growing to the
north you know it's just real question
you know like uh uh it's hard to say you
know um I I I can't predict the future I
will say it doesn't like wildfires going
away way anytime soon um you know I tell
myself strike the same place twice
but actually did in that sense so like
we had fire just to the south of us last
year now it's just to the north of us
and even with all that
burn it's like there's still lots more
to burn
so it's hard you know do I think it's
financially viable for big business to
be in Humble County I don't even know if
that makes sense to be honest like I
don't think big business belongs in
Humble County in my eyes it's A Place
for Mom and Pops like farmers who live
here and they're so rooted in the
community that like even with all this
stuff leaving so it's like yeah I think
cannabis will continue to go on
personally because it's just part of our
culture personally and tell can you tell
us about some of your hype strains or
something that did kind of turn out
sweet this year and all
that you guys are in Canada you're all
talking like I like harvested weed and
stuff already like it's only like
September like 18th over here I haven't
chopped a single Branch like I had some
people hitting me about the rain like oh
I'm G to harvest it all like a lot of my
stuff like triggered later this year for
whatever reason and I'm looking at like
Halloween like you know November
harvests and like luckily you can
usually get away with that in Trinity
County um especially these last few
years last year was wet kind of went to
[ __ ] quick but uh this year is looking
pretty good we got a storm going on
right now that's calling for like a
couple inches but I'm hoping it then
kind of turns around and is nice for the
rest of the season but uh again my my
Farm's small I don't have a farm like as
I always I have a garden so like I don't
really have the stresses that like all
my friends have like you know living in
the heart of the triangle and balancing
between humble and Trinity County you
know uh everyone I know is a farmer um
it's cool to get to walk their farms and
see what they're up to and hear about
their their struggles but like I'm going
to be honest a lot of their struggles
aren't my struggles like my thing just
not really of that magnitude that it
really calls for that amount of stress
so um yeah that could be a teaching and
itself though you know what I mean just
just hearing that you know you're going
to be around doing the same thing in
five years you know check yourself and
what you're involved in so um that's
cool though cuz sometimes it takes
getting you know steps and everything to
get where you're going and everything
but and I feel like that last question
about you know is cannabis still going
to be grown in the Triangle I just it
it's the big question that Humanity has
dealt with in migratory
patterns of crops you know we've we know
that corn has traveled all all over the
place and was it because corn was so
popular or is it because you know
different climates changed and soils got
blown out or got flooded you know so
it's an Ever Changing Earth it's it's
part of the flow and I think that as
humans we're just seeing a really
another big change in the earth who
knows if it always happens or if it's
something that's just happening right
now but either you know hum humans are
just always going to be chasing the good
soil and the good sun because we get our
food from the earth and a lot of people
don't necessarily recognize that and now
all of us recognize the importance of
medicine from the earth and I think
Steve is right I mean there's a
desertification yes sort of happening in
Califoria it's crazy like it's amazing
how how dry it can be down there but
I'll just say from a fire perspective
like British Columbia can get Gnarly
with fires and we had one really close
to our community re so you know it's it
the fire thing is like a trees and okay
so I think we should do less fire
smarting but I don't know um hey Josh
are you are can you hear Josh if you to
say something Daniel go for it yeah I
mean they're talking about the
desertification in the west I mean we
the logging of the planet you know here
in California there was an old growth
rainforest and in the Western United
States used to have eight times more
surface water because of beavers
and there and even where there are
beavers there's not apex predators
anymore but like so many beavers have
been hunted for pelts or like the
farmers in California like and some of
like the Central Valley area they took
the Beavers out because they would mess
with their um irrigation and
stuff so yeah I mean it's it's wild what
we have to deal with and FL and fire is
one of the the roots of it but I look in
the forest here you can walk I was
showing my son bod and like I was like
look at you know he was like how can we
get the Creeks to flow more because the
Creeks are dry except for the headwaters
and I was showing him the the old growth
stumps that were taken and they're so
well spaced out and then we have this
like thick
forest um yeah and then I I gotta go
definitely help my brother-in-law I just
wanted to say that you know the the
yo the guy I study from yoga nandas is
the goal of yoga is to be unshakable
amidst the crash of breaking worlds
because it happens sometimes
and I would say amongst all the turmoil
like I'm having one of the greatest
heart openings of My Life um not not a
Kundalini Awakening but a Kaa Awakening
from the crown to the root and you know
this is a beautiful planet and we have a
way to go and I don't know when we're
going to get there I don't know if I'll
be telling my grandchildren Grim fairy
tales of the world that we grew up in
but hopefully they'll be telling their
grandchildren or somewhere down the line
of the Seven Generations
um yeah it's it is interesting in the
change I mean
now cannabis was like the last outpost
and it's been we're all in the belly of
the Beast now
and oh it didn't oh no and then I'm I'm
not going out the back end we're gonna
we're gonna all find a way to cut our
way out of this and and and death is the
soil that Roots life that's what I when
I see the the the chaos in the world I
see compost
I see rich
soil anyway love you
guys was that yoga promasa you were
dropping there yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
I've been studying his teachings for 14
years yeah man I I probably read his
book maybe 15 or so years ago
autobiography of a
yogi and uh yeah he he he does lessons
that come in the mail like you get two
every two weeks for like a couple years
very cool very cool don't hear Too Many
people dropping yoga's name hey G wait
yeah go ahead Gil you never mentioned
any of those hype ass strains that you
were gonna be
harvesting oh that's funny man dude uh I
got some cool [ __ ] from [ __ ] seed
that like that's what I'm most excited
for like for clones I you know I got
some guava Skittles some sticky papaya
that motor breath papaya um I'm doing a
little bit of that gush Min it seems
like that's going to be like super
popular strain that everyone's growing
this year but I hear some um I got Kucha
six some some honey
bananas I got a bunch of cool seeds from
that flying lion dude in Nevada County
his like slur and nasty lemonade they're
all like um Dosey and like uh lemonade
crosses and uh trying to remember what
else uh um I got some cool Citrus 25
from Graham Mr Bob hemp Hill crickets
and Zada that that c company runs with
his wife he like gave him to me like I
feel like a couple years ago in like a
sandwich bag when I ran into him one
time and then like when I seen him this
spring and I was getting all his Puck
crosses that I'm really excited about
um go on sorry oh no I was saying yeah I
was talking about this yeah I'm excited
about those pucks um there's some really
cool stuff in there that stuff's really
granular where um I really think there's
some like cash potential in a lot of
those but uh so yeah he gave me another
pack of that Citrus 25 it's like a
Northern Lights cross that he thinks is
hashy um I'm excited about those it's
like orange TPS but they seem like
they'll hash and the thing that I'm
probably most pumped about is all this
tally man stuff that a friend up in
Oregon made um friends with archive but
uh it's basically ton to Rainbow bels
ton to uh that Asus that chmd gb6 tricks
Ton's a dumper too yeah man they said
there's is like an eight percenter
supposedly man so uh I'm excited about
those and uh they crossed it to the
honey bananas and the jungle cake um
there's some there's some cool crosses
there for sure it's you know I have them
chucked out there I kind of just put
them in this one patch they don't get
really big or anything it's just like an
opportunity for me to kind of like walk
around and smell them and check them out
hopefully find something cool in them
but yeah I'm really excited about the
tan the tan honey bananas I'm sure
that'll be fire I'm excited they smell
good but yeah like I said they're
looking like they're going to go forever
man definitely going to be a long time
but I'm excited yeah no it sounds like a
pretty tasty menu thank you [ __ ] I'm
excited and I'm not even in the same
country are you are you going to be uh
because I remember last year I think we
reached out to you last year about
Legends and I don't think you were able
to to come down um um
look it's hard to get out of the forest
yeah well last year it was in November
right by Thanksgiving and then now we've
for that reason we've kind of pushed it
into the first the first weekend of
December now so it gives people a little
more time so yeah I'd love to I'll I'll
DM you if and see uh please do please do
make the
pilgrimage hey Josh what kind of herb
Are you standing standing in front of
and welcome Craig we love you looking
forward to hearing from you and coling
everyone we haven't heard from yet we'll
try and just hit each up each
person hey hey how you guys doing so so
good to be here with y'all um I got some
actually some coffee right here I don't
know if K is on the on the call but
uh G let them go a little bit longer but
we're just getting dumped on right now
and they're just in the window a lot of
our crops like perfectly in the window
right now and you know I was going to
freeze of it but that's what's cool
about just kind of the nice thing about
hash for us is that we can kind of
diversify our crop you know it's nice to
do a little bit of Frozen and a little
bit of a little bit of you know cured
and just kind of play around with it we
like to do a lot of our own genetics
here and seems like people are really
into like small
batch rosin you know a lot of our stuff
I mean I'm interested in things that
dump of course but a lot of times I'm
kind of more into like what kind of
flavors we can find that that's not out
there that's you know small batch or or
I guess niche as you could say because
we've sort of been discovering with the
legal Mark with the new market and all
this craziness you know if everyone's
growing push mins you know the
dispensary can't have like like five
kushans from five different Farms but
you know if we have like a papaya Valley
goo nobody has
that um because a lot of times yeah a
lot oftimes people just want
variety I mean I can tell you what's my
favorite strain right now but it could
change tomorrow or even if there's a
strain I don't think I like maybe the
next day it it works with my body
chemistry in a different
way
um so we're just kind of playing around
having fun just super Greatful to be in
this position that H you know and have
some recognition of being like in the
Dem pure Community people always reach
out to us and they like hey love what
you do like love to support the demm
community and it's always such a
beautiful thing to hear that and we're
just putting one foot in front of the
other just just keep going and I love
this plant like Marcus was saying about
the pizza man that resonates with me big
time it's pouring out here but there's
nowhere else I'd rather be than in the
garden you know it's like it's fun and
like wine it's like this is this is
putting
a our genetics can hold up we might have
like a little bit of mold here and there
um but you know for the most part like
Josh you were saying healthy soil like
regenerative ecology practices
um you know for the most part I feel
like the plant can really feel our
intentions and we get good yields even
this year we were kind of wanted to
scale down a bit and do most of the work
ourselves and keep it real real boutique
style and it seems to be working out
pretty nicely our kids are a little
older now so we're able to do like you
know 95% of the work on our
own and you are you uh Craig Craig is
are you working with Nasha and are both
you working with Nasha or uh I couldn't
remember if that was true nasha's
nasha's been doing some uh I think they
kind of stick to Humble we're in
Mendo okay I've spoken with them they
sound interested but it seems like we're
not really in their in their uh
radius but uh we yeah we do fresh frozen
we've been doing fresh Frozen with a
couple with surprise surprise we have a
couple rosin
out um and we might be working with a
couple other uh you know rosin companies
this
year that's cool yeah it's it's it's
cool to see uh a lot of the farmers up
in the Triangle right now it's a really
exciting time as a hash maker I'll say
that just simply
because the nature of the market has
people looking other avenues basically
for you know more revenue and more than
ever people are diversifying like Josh
was saying and freezing stuff work
looking to work with hash makers you
know doing whatever they can kind of at
this point so it's cool to see all the
different people um now prepping
material for it and it's just nice to
see
um all the different hash genetics being
made and there's a like exciting things
as Bleak as it is at times it's also
exciting to me like I said currently to
see all that's going on and uh it the
rain kind of makes things a little
interesting as well because a lot of
people do do the fresh frozen where I
feel like last year was like the first
year that we really experienced tons of
rain during the Harvest and a lot of
people were trying to freeze their their
material and you know the material is
sold by the fresh frozen pound and
water's heavy so that's got to be a
factor when you're buying material or
you know working out some kind of split
or whatever you're doing so uh it's
always fun to see the challenges that
the rain adds last year it rained so
hard I feel like it kind of reduced some
of my my yields overall when I was like
scoping live plants the apex of the
plants had like less heads on them than
as you move down towards like you know
the lower stuff but it was literally
days on days of torrential downpour and
the Sun never came back out and it was
just a wrap so you know hopefully the
storm passes and the weather gets nice
again but as Josh said it's just like
parts of it it's parts of being a farmer
where you'll just remember oh yeah that
one year that rain came in the middle of
September and there's always challenges
they just always going to be something
you know whether it's pests or weather
it's just part of it and kind of keeps
it exciting and nerve-wracking and all
that
totally I uh I think I want to show a a
real quick clip um because we're talking
about preparing ing material for
um for the um for solventless extraction
and I'm I'm trying to figure out how I
can do this
without it it wants me to make it full
screen but that's just way too big and
then I can't uh see if I can make this a
little
smaller no I cannot all right I'm G to
try and share this anyway it's a very
short clip this is McIntyre Farm in um
British Columbia in the in in the
Okanagan and this is them flash freezing
their material on the field let me know
if you guys can you probably won't be
able to hear it but you should be able
to see
it he's talking about freeze drying the
Cannabis as it comes off the field
yeah those are like those cryo freezers
I've seen some of those for sale from
like the B days where people are kind of
like trying to just get rid of them
where you can kind of come up on them
for like a quarter of the price they
were leaves are the plants manicured at
all I was gonna ask the same thing sub
um to a degree I mean these guys still
have a lot to learn let me just find
where we are here oh here we go stop
sharing um you can check that out at
McIntyre creek.com I just like the
footage of the you know those those
little cryo uh conveyor belts of the
plants going in yes they definitely
could have uh
um uh secured Trimm those leaves a lot
better but just the idea that there's at
least some companies already in the
knowledge of understanding that
preserving volatile organic organic
compounds is important you know and
we're we're a lot of people they ship
this stuff at room temperature they're
they have no interest in making it cold
and this is one of the things we've had
difficulty in Canada when the chain of
custody is with me my hash is at-20 to
minus 40 degrees all the time like once
I've made it it's in a freezer and it's
just staying very cold and I'm
preserving those volatile organic
compounds the second it leaves my
facility unless I pay a ton of money
sure I could probably get it shipped in
a in a in a Reaper that that's that's
cold um but what's going to happen is
it's going to get to where it's going to
one of the provinces and then they're
just going to put in a warehouse and so
there's been problems with that where
people are growing decent cannabis
people are making nice products with it
and then it's sitting like going right
from a freezer to like a you know 100
degree Fahrenheit Warehouse because it's
the middle of summer uh and oh there's
been a problem with the barcode this is
something that happened in my own house
the hash was like white gold colored
when I shipped it out and when people
were buying it it was like completely
dark it literally cooked in this
warehouse for three days um and then
you've got to you've got to kind of deal
with that lack of control in the chain
of custody and it's it's kind of a big
deal like when you're talking about
preparing your material for for Harvest
uh you know preparing it for the hash
makers versus the guys that are putting
it into eights or pre-rolling joints
those are all different
preparations but now you know we do what
we do and there's no more of that CH
like from the farmer to the hash maker
we can really control the environment
that of which the Cannabis and the resin
sits in but the minute we get it to
Market you know I go into these stores
in Canada and they all have their drinks
in coolers and these drinks have like 2
milligrams 5 milligrams 10 milligrams
and that's what they're choosing to use
their cold space for to make these
drinks cold while the hashes and the
flowers are all sitting at room
temperature and maybe they're sitting
there for a while who knows it could be
weeks I don't know but by the time
someone buys it you know combined with
the fact that for a very long time in
Canada people were buying very you know
we were regulated so you have to buy
packaging that is regulated you don't
just get to pick what you like it has to
be agreed by the government and the
things they were allowing and regulating
were very poor packaging one one of them
in particular was you know it was the
seal on top of right here there'd be a
little seal that go over it and that's
supposed to be sealing your jar of nugs
and what would actually happen is the
volatile organic compounds would
pressurize inside the container and they
would eventually consume the glue that
was holding the the seal on just consume
microscopic fissures that allow now this
pressure to escape and these volatile
organic compounds to leave the container
while being replaced he's
back froze yeah you got a Starly CER
link where where where did I freeze off
like you were like said the seal you're
talking about the seal the seal so that
seal was getting consumed by the
volatile organic compounds and pushing
out you know the pressure of the jar I'm
sure you've seen it where it lifts up
and Bubbles up those those compact those
volatile organic compounds they're
they're
volatier and colder and so they they
they would consume the the the glue or
whatever material they were using to
stick that to the top little microscopic
fissures would be blowing out the
volatile organic compounds replacing it
with oxygen and it was all giving a
really bad name to the to the people who
were producing these products some of
these people like from the black market
that came to grow cannabis they just
wanted to get legal and immediately
started getting attacked like they were
big licensed producers and there's very
much a narrative in Canada that legal
weed is shitty weed that there's no way
that you'll ever make it good legally
even though these people literally
support every other industry in the
world like where they buy their t-shirts
and where they get their food and where
they get everything happens the same way
but for some reason we're very we're
very you know and I get it very
sensitive when it comes to the cannabis
plant that we've been stewarding for all
of these years uh and so I still believe
that legal cannabis federally legal
cannabis here in Canada can be good
cannabis I've met enough cool craft
Growers at that unicorn cup I saw some
beautiful products uh but there does
seem to be powers that be the same way
they're in California just trying to
drive the industry into the ground
trying desperately like they didn't
realize that like by jailing us for
decades at a time and you know shooting
our dogs and taking our children away
and really going back to even in Cairo
the the from the hash Church Legends of
carfour there wrenching out the sufi's
teeth with pliers if they had cannabis
or hashish in their belly the hash
eaters like none of these things work we
never sto like those are the most like
what can you do to someone that is more
personal than taking their children and
wrenching out their teeth and putting
them in a cage for a decade at a time
none of that stopped us um I don't know
why they think trying to tank these
industries are going to stop us either I
also like Daniel look at uh the you know
the chaos as like compost we are seeds
the more they try to bury us uh the more
we grow up through through the chaos and
uh and produce tasty loud things that
that attract people's attention they're
not getting rid of us anytime soon so
that's my opinion we were born in the
darkness amen that's right did anybody
else find it ironic that you froze while
talking about fresh frozen that was
awesome I did like that
[Laughter]
actually Harvest down there what's going
on in Humble are you getting the same
Raina how's the Coyote Blue looking
what's your favorite hash for Idol this
year and is naasha working out good
what's up love to your family always
yeah yeah yeah good morning everybody
sorry I was late uh it was a good swell
coming in so my daughter and I went and
got some waves this morning um actually
thought I'd see Gil out there and looks
like he uh was here instead um but yeah
Harvest has been going really really
well um we run seven different cultivars
so that gives us timing and that also
lets us over the we've learned that you
know what's it saying you can only pound
so many pounds of crap into a 5B bag
well so many farms don't scale according
to their drying space or their curing
space so we have a limited space there
so we go with a different cultiv ours so
they come off at different times so we
can really
maximize um the full potential of our
farm so the Coyote Blue yeah we're done
uh we took the second round yesterday
and she's in I left like two plants out
there I always like to test a couple
varieties that I see out there so I left
two full plants see how they push on
through the rain um but for the most
part yeah the barn is full and that's
ready um and Coyote Blue is not a hash
uh not a hash cultivar at all but we
have a really good flower market for it
and um we're actually going to be doing
some Coyote Blue gummies strain specific
gummies through soulful so super excited
about that um and other things we're
running is uh guava gift um through
green source and um uh Kush Kirk so
we've that's second year for that uh
Baron did really really well with our
rosin it was kind of like one of those
outliers like it was like oh barely
produced enough but oh my God after
after it sat for a minute the turps were
just super super nice and after running
through the whole season um through
sales and everything
that our flow market and dumps um uh
what else did we run of strawberry banan
become a staple on our farm like first
run we always we always run the
strawberry banana you know for our dep
run it's we're just running Cold Frame
hoop with uh pretty much nothing nothing
but uh infrastructure just to pull the
cover so we pull off that run in like
you know mid to late July and that
strawberry banana you know that was
breed for a hot house so um it comes off
really good we'll we'll throw a shade
canopy over it to even uh keep those TPS
a little more uh you know I have all
these little things I do that in my mind
I think they work right so I'll throw
some shade over that like two weeks
before Harvest um and pull that one off
um what else did we run the first round
um man my mind oh uh gush mint we had to
do a little fill in because we couldn't
get all the cultivars we wanted so we
ran a little bit gush mins man that was
phenomenal really really happy with it
um and then we ran a little double OG
cam just for our Flower Market
um and then this round the replant and
we do our second round is a set it and
forget it we call it where we're not
doing any sort of deprivation um and the
set it and forget it round is papaya
bomb and rainbow belts so we're working
closely now directly with um purple City
genetics and those guys just put out
fire right so anything that's in our in
our light up situation which is about
2500 square ft is from clone and that's
part of that program and then the other
7500 Square F feet of the farm is all
full season from seed um and it just
this program has really worked well for
us we've been honing it and making sure
that if we run something um we can send
some to our flower market and then the
rest goes to Baron at Nasha and then
this is the first year we did just a
little personal wash last year with uh
simply Adam and that was phenomenal
really happy with that so that was our
little taste of fresh
frozen and um Baron has us signed up for
two larges and a small or two larges and
a medium for freezers and everything we
have we're going to do just a micro
batch that's fresh frozen and that's
that's about as big as we can go and you
know we know scarcity drives a market so
our skew are flying off the shelf which
is really good in this day and age but
that I say that's a big as we can go
because Off the Grid right and we don't
want to fire up a bunch of generators to
do this whole process where if we bring
those freezers onto the farm uh like a
week before we need them we'll fill them
with water jugs and get them get some
bace in there and that way um we're not
pulling a lot of power all at once and
if we have a little hiccup in the night
where power cuts out because our
batteries gave up it's not going to be a
big deal and we're running the two bigs
and the smalls so we can go in and out
while we're harvesting into the small
move into the larges and the larges can
even be loaded in the van and taken
straight and take out some of these
nuances of supply chain like Marcus is
talking about but we're also feeling
what you're talking about Marcus like
the supply chain from from manufacturing
from from the lab to the market you know
I don't know if Baron was on already he
mentioned he was going to be jumping on
but man there's challenges like some of
the big Dro companies are like cutting
corners or doing the best they can and
they send just a box truck and you're
like whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa
back up man we can't do that so I think
it's really what we've always felt
strongly about is working with our
retail partner that understands what
we're trying to do and run these small
batches with the small Vans and really
nurture that market and we're finding
that consumers are willing to drive past
other shops to come to the shops that
care um so we're still the only place
you can get our flow still only at
Soulful but our resin and pre-rolls you
can get anywhere where're Baron's
working you know Nasha extracts and
we're keeping it in that Loop and and so
far uh you know knock on wood but we're
still grinding and we're still doing it
and we still got a smile on our face um
and that's you know pretty much the
story we got going right now and you
know a lot of the other guys I heard
talking this morning talking about the
rain and the nuances you know that
identifies the Vintage right so when you
go you know 2021 that vintage was
this right and and and and with resin
and hash you know this is where hble
County mesino county is going to shine
finally like we've been we've been
producing for resin
specifically um for five six years now
now and and we're just honing in our
skills even more and we just feel that
those plants that can have full season
interacting with our toar and our living
soils those are just a joy to work with
and and baren seeing better and better
results than something that's like being
snapped out in two and a half months
like like it's not the same it really
isn't when you have that full
season uh potential of the all those
turps and the plant and and that that's
it's working for us at least and um the
other thing that that
Baron a lot of that is really important
like Baron kind of feels like Bell's
down in Mendo at Heritage you know
they're handling meno Farms right and
and let those local
ecosystems
evolve and let's not drive product way
back up to Humble to wash it to send it
back south right let's really work
within these ecosystems and support the
farmers that are you know within a
shotguns blast of each of these
manufacturing
facilities macrobiotic cash making yeah
well it makes the product more
affordable too like if you're not
because if you look at it on the
manufacturing side if the product's
getting transported all the way across
state you've added like $1,700 to that
load of material that's going to get ran
that's all going to come out in the in
the cost you know and what that's going
to be sold for so you're right I I love
that idea I've always like I support the
[ __ ] out of that because it makes so
much more sense and and product grows
well in that area there's no shortage of
manufacturers in the area no shortage of
Distributors that can get it down to the
shops from there so it really should
work that way too you know yeah and one
thing we've always done is we've we've
always tried to look ahead as to when
we're going to need transport and we've
never just worked with one company right
we always think of it is FedEx UPS who's
going where when and when can we jump on
when they're already doing something so
we have Redwood Roots literally at the
bottom of our road and they've got air
conditioned Vans ready to rock and I
literally just sent a load to soulful
and it's like hey when are you going to
Santa Rosa oh we're going Tuesday half
hour charge right to go from A to B and
we just needed like a minus right so
that that all helps shave the costs and
and and support these Vans and these
little micro distros so you know well
that that transparency in the scheduling
allows you to to do business with them
you know and if they don't have that it
makes it really tough because then you
know it's it's it's a service so yeah no
believe me I deal with that logistical
stuff all day long
it's
insane yeah yeah and you know I I would
love to get product down the LA you know
our flower we have so many people that
are anxious to you know enjoy our flower
down there I just don't see the
logistics happening in this market we're
in at this moment right maybe someday in
time but at the moment Soulful is about
to open up across from Golden Gate Park
like we're pretty much like you know
scarcity drives our market and We're Not
Gonna expand to hit these needs we're
just GNA be out and then we'll be
calling our friends and neighbors and
having them engage in in the system that
we've you know helped nurture and steer
so one last thing I want to leave you
guys before I uh you know step off here
um we did a farm tour with one of
Baron's long childhood friends and um
he's Himalayan Himalayan Clarity on
Instagram and their friends from India
and uh he has this business where he he
he uh is able to get these uh clear
Himalayan crystals so I know a bunch of
you are waiting these so check out
Himalayan Clarity on Instagram he gifted
some of these after our farm tour and
they are just stunning absolutely water
clear hey absolutely clear he's got got
smoky quartz from
Siberia epic oh look at that yeah I knew
there were some crystals in the house oh
dude how about the from
Afghanistan yeah yeah yeah brother for
sure that's sick true
Stoners yeah I I just bought one the
other day I can't even talk [ __ ] just
like a fire
ass oh Crystal TRS crystals put them in
the soil grow them underneath the plant
I can't wait to charge him up on the
solstice beautiful beautiful crystals
Himalayan what was his Instagram Clarity
clity make sense that it was Clarity
after seeing that
Crystal those are
[Music]
beautiful what's going on with best
friend
Farms oh just hanging out up here in
Maine
feel like you're doing more than just
hanging
out fing do yeah yeah just I'm here
alone on the farm today but was doing
some uh last minute pollinations select
pollinations before the rain comes in
and a little bit of spot leap you know
checking and pulling before things come
in on the
farm but yeah just been hunker down
going at it kind of small team Focus
this year trying to keep everything
really efficient and streamlined really
paying attention to the soil and the
cost down on it coming from the farm
kind of like simple diet for the plants
and it's worked really well this year so
have some cool stuff to share you know
later on when I see more of the Finish
but uh we we kind of focused in on on
our te rhythm with it for the season
besides healthy top dressing and refurb
of the beds we have good living soil
after you know the five years here so
excuse me so we've kind of paid
attention to keeping the bioactivity
alive feeding the soil on a Continuum
for the cost down where we really
weren't paying for much for outside
input but local liquid fish inputs that
we've kind of gone back to a more whole
food diet with fish meal meets compost
with a slurry checked in every week and
anyway kind of simple for cost down and
I'm seeing really good results from like
a well I call it surf and turf because
just very simple once a week hit
and yeah results are we carried great
health with the soil at the point that
it was at through the year and uh so far
for just a really minimal cost down and
I'm happy with the health and we paid a
lot of attention this year to the uh
early onset plant cleanup with like uh
cleaning the bottom third of the plant
really well early on three stages of
cleaning
and yeah so a lot of stuff going on a
lot of new strains for hat and a lot of
new F1 spread actually already and uh
I'm kind of like paying attention to
some stuff when it comes to the well the
prime the really really loud tpin that
come up front noticing that they don't
necessarily always wash the greatest for
plants with the energy divided into the
Tarpin up front really
primary so I'm paying more attention to
some of the what maybe like a subtle
Nuance secondary turps that show up
where they're not as loud even up in the
mid flower but they seem to come in but
not overpowering into the late session
of
flower and I've kind of seen some other
cultivars that people are having success
with at a couple other
Gardens that uh seem to be that I like
that sticker just reading that
Mark and uh
that's going on at least when I did like
the midflower check on some types that
are fairly
common
so
yeah tasty treats what about when we're
always we still always talking about
Tarpin but we know that some of those
more funky intense smells are actually
thols and thoits are we are we getting
close to moving into volatile organic
compounds are we still going to use tpin
as the lingo because I hear everyone
talking and I'm not against it I just
feel like after Nick dropped all that
knowledge a year ago on hash church
about thil and thoits and Esters and
esterfication of terpenoids and like
there's other things going on there and
I get that there's this big percentage
that we're assuming is all tpin but I
wonder you know how important are those
Styles and those styes and the volatile
organic compound profile I know in the
world of hops they're extremely
important um I wonder how important they
are I mean skunk right skunk is a is is
a is a couple of different sty that
create that that very strong smell I
wonder how much of what we think are
tpin are actually different volatile
organic compounds just a
thought I have
some I have some pure THS right now and
I was thinking of repeating some of my
earlier work where I tested uh each of
the individual tpin with a pure 25
milligrams of pure
THC and uh I suspect that the uh the
files I think there's a small chance
that they may contribute to the Synergy
the way tpes do in in uh being able to
affect the strength or possibly the
modulate the effects
the type of subjective
effects I have some pure thigh alls now
skunkman Sam Quil who the [ __ ] else in
this room would have said that that
sentence it's so ridiculous thank you
for being you and you should Rec
recreate those do you realize that was
like 22 plus years ago that you that you
did those experiments in your apartment
it it it was it's hard to remember world
before uh the turine knowledge explosion
because uh we we all had you we knew
some cannabis was better and we also
knew that a lot of the better stuff
smelled better but nobody really really
was able back in those days to show
scientifically that the uh the Tes in
fact can both modulate and some
potentiate uh
THC and also AC Synergy with the other
can
avonoids well I feel blessed that I got
to do that experiment with you almost 20
years ago in your apartments when you
pulled out all those pure can avonoids
and all those tpes I just was like holy
[ __ ] I am in the right place at the
right time I knew it was historical
while I was doing it the fact that it
was 20 years ago actually makes me feel
old um but it's awesome thank you for
that and please do do that with the
files and invite cool wonderful people
from the community as you always do
because 20 years from now we'll be
talking about
that well they definitely are incredibly
more potent when it comes to
volatized and filling the room with a
run over Dead Skunk type
smell so skunkman if you could take one
thol with 25 milligrams of THC which one
is it currently uh I I'd have to look at
my list together because pretty spaced
out and uh but uh the there is one which
uh strongly uh I supect is and that's
the one I have
so dunk one is n butane one thol nane
one file is one of the three that make
up skunk this is from Nick zegler
yeah you say that to all the girls I'd
have to look on the bottle because I
don't remember off the top of my head
and the sulfur compounds that you
know warned over and over and over do
not open this in my
house know I think so s so someone in
the in the audience who's really
knowledgeable sharf um is amazing human
being who does a ton of research in tpes
um he's he's calling out a
GC uh times GC Master spectrometer to
see everything and I think you know he's
calling out it right you know we just
don't have the ability to see all these
compounds and and quantify
them that's where Nick
zler yeah no it's it's we're on we're on
the right track right but I think what
shrief is calling out there's just not
there's not an assay that's easily we
can't just like plug it in like we can
right now with the other tping classes
wish was here because he he spent a
decade doing this with hops and he he
put multiple machines together he spoke
about it here in hash church it was like
it was like to the trillion it was
beyond
the you can easily test for the for
Theos it's no problem at
all much less what happens once it's
ignited those combinations or those new
volatiles that are created that aren't
we aren't aware of yet but becomes
binders between the lung brain barrier
that creates a chemical reaction in the
body yeah I mean it's I yeah I'd love to
have Z Nick on and then have also Sharif
as well chiming because he you know it'd
be great to have this this conversation
broader but um yeah well we can do it
maybe next week if you if uh if Shar
wants to get me his contact info I'm BC
bubbleman icloud.com and I can reach out
to Nick uh and we can get into more of a
of this volatile organic compound
conversation or at least let them get
into it and the rest of us can uh can
listen and
learn yeah no
doubt there is always down for that
there is no doubt that the files
contribute to the smell in uh when
they're present but whether or not they
contribute to the uh the medical and or
recreational value of canabus that's
that has yet to be shown are the are the
are they volatile um when air drying or
are preserved and freezing like like
everything else yes
absolutely okay yes they
are but not as well as tpin they're very
very very vol
okay that's
interesting and Colin are you in New
York right now I'm uh in Massachusetts
and I'll be in New York um on
Wednesday so nice yeah yes and uh we
were we are going to be speaking up by
Zoom at the organic Cup in New York okay
because we're not gonna be able to go
across the border um the way that they
are right now and that's just the way we
we we felt like we had you know
um that it was open in a way that we
were going to be able to do it but we
just don't feel like it is so that's
that's going to be um unfortunate um but
but I we're also really excited about it
though to support you know that movement
in New York and on the east coast and
there's so many amazing people involved
and uh uh all the you know the Farms
that are coming down and the genetics
swaps and just the whole like focus in
New York as it's blossoming you know for
an organic cup is really really sweet so
I'm really excited to see that Blossom
out there yeah that's yeah it's gonna be
great I've been waiting TW as you know
over 25 years for this to happen
and uh you know it's it's going to be
really cool because you know there's a
lot of a lot of H Talent um that just
wants to to come out and they want to
talk just the same way that um I was
once scared to to share the things that
I loved about all of it you know and the
things that I was passionate about so I
think we're going to see a lot of really
cool um just fresh ignited energy in
into the into the scene I'm excited for
that so you know and do you feel
there'll be a mixture of indoor and
outdoor farming because of Northern New
York and and Central and all that what's
your thought on that yeah I mean um you
know you know and you guys were talking
about the the chir and and the the
Appalachia you know New York has
microclimates as well there's really
great pockets of of areas to grow
cannabis and and other crops and um you
know it's been a really good season you
know well it's not over yet but um you
we have to pay attention to the tropics
you know that this is the time to really
pay attention to Africa and what's going
to rip off of there and go through and
up the coast and then that'll eventually
hit us so I've you know over the years
been trained to kind of look at that but
um it's you know the next week we have a
hurricane that's kind of forming right
now and we'll see what happens with that
but you know now until October 10th is
kind of the the time that makes the
breaks you know a good season so you
know there's a lot to be seen But thus
far it's been a really good season not a
lot of rain um it's been really good so
this is kind of like a a picturesque
season for for the East Coast outdoor um
and in terms of just uh what type of
growing Styles we're GNA see I think
we're going to see a bunch it's it's New
York New York is going to be imagine you
know the way I kind of look at at
cannabis in New York is like if I could
imagine the streets in New York and all
the different types of people that's the
kind of growing styles that we're going
to kind of emerge out of all this and um
you know we're going to see a lot of
that personality come through and it'll
have its own kind of you know its own
voice and each each kind of uh
style so it's it's cool I'm really
excited man I'm
I'm I'm really excited to see what what
people bring and people pay attention to
different things in different parts of
the world so you know I'm curious to see
what people are looking looking at right
now yeah definitely and and and just
with uh the way that smoking is in the
city right now I think it's like a lot
of fun for people to to go to the city
um and be able to just smoke anywhere
and and you know the smoking clubs I
know the aster Club is a lot of fun Liz
has talked about going there a lot and
uh you know some of those smoking clubs
are you know a lot of fun and so it'll
be cool to see you know what that
experience is like for people yeah
that's and there you know historically
people have have gotten you know high
quality cannabis in New York for a long
time for decades there's been always a
scene there I'm sure Sam can speak on
that but it's you know um I'm excited
I'm excited to see the diversity you
know that's the exciting part for me
it's just seeing all the people that are
like you know maybe I knew them you know
and we just weren't talking about it
together you know so um that's uh I
think that's the coolest part and then I
want to see you know just the what
people are doing in terms of cultivation
I know a lot of the Farms right now are
just doing Outdoors some people have had
the time and the infrastructure to build
green houses but not too many of them
are actually doing that so um and how is
that is there hash processors and people
like starting to look for farms for
resin or or uh what do you see there not
yet I think it's really early and you
know we don't know what the testing's
going to look like yet here um we don't
I know I'm sure people are putting
things aside for fresh Frozen but um we
don't know what the testing is looking
like so we've no there's just there's so
many unknowns a lot of the stuff the
guidance hasn't really been given out so
that's the scary part about where the I
think the state's at right now is that
there's a lot of people have invested a
lot of time and money into things and I
think it's fresh frozen for a new market
like this unless you're you're
experienced I think it's a scary thing
so it's not I don't know if it's going
to be and plus if I really do the math
on how many AC are being grown versus
how many people are in in population
there there's not nearly enough um you
know if you really break that down so
I've spoken to a few groups in New York
who are you know you're right it's
beyond early like they don't even really
have their licensing let alone like
funding or building but you know the
people that do have the infrastructure
that kind of already grow even just hemp
they're they're definitely you know
talking about getting equipment you know
I've been talking to them through
Whistler Tech technology and kind of
just getting them prepared for an
existence where you know someone said it
earlier on I think it was ganja Gill you
know you have to um you have to find
these elusive pockets of
profitability um you have to be able to
figure out ways that are maybe it's not
quite as easy as it used to be it used
to be real easy which created a soft
environment now people are in this
harder environment and they're working
much harder for much less payoffs and
it's just um
yeah I see them I see them gearing up
and getting ready but you're right it's
very early what does it happen after
January the licensing will be
announced no that's further out that's
that's the thing like you have to you
know it's it's hard to really explain
but um you know take everything that's
been said and you know it's elongated so
we're looking at May of next year for
that real the real guidance for like the
not just the conditional licenses that's
next year like middle of next year maybe
May um maybe May is the soonest that
it'll come for new guidance on like
actual like cultivation licenses and
micro businesses because right now I'm
actually
giving um some you know comments on the
micro business licensing right now and I
think that you know that could be really
interesting you know there's some cool
paths that could be built through that
structure that they're allowing um but
the the conditional we have to remind
ourselves the these two years right now
this 18 months or whatever you want to
call it this is just a conditional this
is not a guarantee this is just like
here's an opportunity to use your
acreage right now for a stop Gap and
it'll help us and give you an
opportunity to try this try this out so
I don't know even know how many of these
conditionals even actually poured over
into real licenses you know because that
you know the the
license you know the whole structure of
all this is just still actually super
infant you know I hope a lot of them you
know transfer over so we just don't know
who will actually want to you know I was
going to share something that it's been
said a few different ways um but I'll
share it in a way that somebody just
shared it with me a couple months ago
and that is good times make for soft
humans soft humans make for Hard Times
Hard Times make for strong humans and
the cycle repeats itself
yeah so we're in that time right now
right we just came off with some really
good times couple decades slay it um and
now now now the the strong are going to
swim their way to the
surface and um hopefully help pull this
whole community Through you know this
community when I say not just here in
Humble but like our Global Community um
and it's moments like this where we can
all reach out and discuss our our
triumphs and our wins and our success
successes and our fails really helps
bring us all together and G gives us
allies right like I love it I love
hearing you know little Whispers of
things that are happening you know with
someone I'm with or someone that someone
else is with and oh I know them and they
know them and we're doing something or
they're doing something and that's all
exciting so I just appreciate all of you
and and Marcus I appreciate you bringing
this show together for sure it's always
a pleasure yeah man super super stoked
uh potent po potent ponic says people in
New Markets unfortunately don't
understand why the higher-end
concentrates are worth more that's the
biggest issue with the higher-end
product just educating consumers on
quality so I'll speak to this you know
when you hear him say that he's not
talking about our inner community of
Hardcore hash heads he's talking about
the people who are inevitably going to
be the future users of cannabis a lot of
them have never used cannabis or
dabbling in it now you know here in
Canada it's the 60 plus percent of
people who don't use cannabis who aren't
using cannabis that the Cannabis
industry is sort of trying to say hey
check this out like it's a better option
than alcohol it's not going to cause you
all these different Health ramifications
it's a preventative medicine even though
we're not allowed to say that right now
like all of these different things and
how how um yeah it's just it's it's a
unique situation um what he's saying is
very true what I found is I can you know
try and release relase a five-star
bubble hash or a six-star bubble hash
out there but the people who would
rather criticize me for releasing
products that they have no interest in
you know dry sifted products pure hash
joints or the hash hits that we're doing
which are built for convenience and more
importantly buil to build a bridge to
that 60% of people who are going to buy
a pre-rolled joint they don't even have
rolling papers they literally have a
lighter as their only means of uh
paraphernalia we wanted to create a
product for them that could build a
little Bridge so they could kind of come
on over to the extract world and just
check it out and believe it or not if
you want to get their attention you
don't do it with six-star [ __ ] bubble
that [ __ ] will terrify them that's like
being like hey straight person come try
this IA waska for the first time it's
gonna be really fun here drink drink an
extra cup you got to take them in
slow and so just even like what we think
of as like you know a dry shifted hash
it's like a single screen hash my God
Sam would call that a farmer's grade
hash um it's not what we are looking for
but it is a great way to create a little
bridge where someone can you know smoke
a little bit of hash instead of that
paper and glue and and maybe flour
that's not even that good because they
don't know the industry and they're
buying pre-rolls from the wrong company
and it's Mill and it's dried out and it
lacks TPS and you know the I just want
to make a better experience for people
who are coming into into this to get
turned on to something that's special uh
and if that can lead them to that full
melt bubble and then they can understand
instead of have no understanding well
they're standing down here trying to get
up here and we're not building the steps
for them to get up here we're expecting
them to do this giant jump and they're
not going to do that regardless of how
we want it to be and in reality is that
really how you want to turn people on to
like the most beautiful like just
strongest most purest
uh you know representation of the plants
the cold water and ice extracted you
know resin or dry sifted resin that's
clean to the same level those are like
up at the same Podium when people can't
just go there right away I'm very much
the the I'm very much into giving people
micro dabs I'm very much into trying to
give someone an experience where they
can still try but it's micro and I've
done this for you know 80 plus year old
people it's like the smallest I'm like
trust me you're going to barely blow
anything out but you'll have the taste
you'll experience and more importantly
they'll get over this real fear that
isn't discussed or talked about that
people have about getting too high off
of cannabis it's a powerful energy and
some people it's just too much to take
them to the moon on that rocket ship
ride like how about hold their hand and
walk them around the the coast of the
ocean down the beach for the first time
and then maybe we'll dwell into the
forest and eventually you know climb
into the Alpine and Peak the mountain
but like holy [ __ ] don't take them up
there for a flight your their first
their first time it Marcus it also helps
if because a lot of people that I knew
that had not ever smoked and I may or
may not have been introduce them was uh
vaporization helps because they don't
like combustion most of them don't smoke
cigarettes and uh yeah vaporization
small little dab hits like you're
talking about vaporization really makes
it easy for them to try it without you
know flipping out or anything but let me
add to this you're right if they if I
have my 14 [ __ ] things that I need to
have to give someone a dab my TP slurper
and my three marbles my [ __ ] bong and
my Dabber and my temp Tac and my TP
timer and my baskets and alcohol and
glass jar for cleaning all this [ __ ] and
dipping it and then my you know Q-tips
and like dude they have a lighter these
people have a lighter this is not
convenient it's absolutely ridiculous
that all of us are carrying this [ __ ]
around with us at all times we're
[ __ ] mental completely mental and
that's the truth that's okay
but hey Marcus with that said man what
are you smoking on and what's everybody
smoking on in this room come on let's
bring it back dude I I've got some Forum
cookies cut hash rosin uh from
concentrated X that's absolutely uh
spectacular I've also been hitting his
strawberry banana and his cookies and
cream all of which are beautiful and
tasty and delicious but I also hit
dragonfly Earth medicines is it a guava
punch breath you guys put in there uh
Josh beautiful greenhouse and plant by
the way that is not going unnoticed I
should put that as the as the main part
of the screen let me see if I can just
pin that there we
go we gave you a strawberry uh what was
it strawberry guava guava punch guava
yeah strawberry guava and guava punch
but it was like a uh one that we've been
working with so there's some coffee in
there and and also a little bit of
listen it's nice it's as nice as
anything like that is beautiful resin
you guys knock that [ __ ] out of the park
go
right this is where we grow this is our
breeding
house right here and it's pretty
exciting like um over here we've got
some CIS skunk times uh let's
see zelis and we B some H purple punch
right here
whoa people asked us why we why we did
like the offset you know [ __ ] name
walk fruit thing was just because you
know we want like that organic flow
going you know we want a little bit of
like that you know just we never know
where the the aisle is going to be and
everything so and right here we have
some fire glue syis stunk we have some
strawberry cream cake beautiful we got
TP wizard uh here's some turp wizard big
up
Conor straberry cream cake strawberry
jelly is that what it's called Connor's
flying into Arcada tonight is going to
be staying at my place for the next
three days helping out I'm super excited
to nice one big love Connor he's about
ready to become d uh DM P certified out
in Michigan and we would like to also
just shout out the whole Michigan crew
everyone I just want you know what let's
take a minute let's shout out everyone
everyone you're awesome everyone you're
awesome you're all awesome you're are
all freaking awesome and
this we have some coffee cake here we
have some coffee grape cream going on
um
so I'll just say that this this is we
never have used tea in this greenhouse
only
water and it's only because of the way
we built the beds we had like probably a
almost two feet worth of mixed ramile
branches and chips and woods from the
trees and rose bushes and some manure
and a little bit you know all kinds of
green you know there's a lace Wing right
here the lace wings are just going off
in here we have a Mothership which is
great it's one of our oldest strains and
I'm not
saying aren't good te's are awesome we
have a tea comp that you look at the
plants and if you look at them and
they're just flat leafed and healthy
their whole life I mean you just have to
give thanks to like the mother and just
let it be
um damn I wish your camera was better
out there those look really nice it
almost looks psychedelic in like a half
cartoon half reality situation on my big
screen here it's uh and just Kelly
walking through the middle of it I want
to get to the fire glue so good dude so
good one of the strains that we're
really excited about if you can see is
this fire
glue I think it was a it may have come
from
the glue on fire from uh Steve at Green
Life
Productions big love to Steve at Green
Life Productions it just came out
amazing and then we have uh the fire
glue cisum so we have like Dominion Seed
Company Duke diamond in the place we
got going on
here we got the baked that's the tur
wizard
Connor the Royal purples were early
beautiful finishers
too I don't know about y'all but I'm
getting cotton mouth just looking at
these
things dude I know I want to do like uh
pizza and like hash making this is going
to be my new like restaurant you come in
you get pizza but then you got to make
hash while you're waiting for your pizza
to be uh
these are my two love bring the tomato
sauce sign me up you know seeing all
like seeing all this flour is amazing
and like the consumers at the moment
have to buy all their herb through a
dashboard and like numbers from a lab
test where we're actually like touching
our plants and and seeing them and
breathing them and living with them it's
like important that experiential
cannabis needs to come into the scene at
some it'd be cool if people could come
out and like pick out like which plants
they like and um oh and do like a up
pick or something like that kind of
thing like what tpine speak out to you
that'd be something we could probably do
through Soulful potentially too you know
I know Nanda farms in New York they did
that with their hemp plants last year
where they actually did a full and pick
and pull where people come in it was
done by veterans and
yeah it's they're doing again this year
where they grow the plants out and then
people just roll on up and they do
it the farm and then they came and were
able to ask all their questions and they
make their own bomb and other things
like that shout out to Sarah stth and
them and their veterans out there in New
York that do that much love and
respect that's
right yeah just take a few nugs home dry
it just dry it there take a couple of
colas I mean that'll last you for a
while yeah they did it by you could
either take colas or the whole plant
most people tended to take the whole
plant interestingly
enough whoa I love it
dude I'm not surprised that people take
the whole plant I've shown a lot of
people different places to pick
mushrooms edible mushrooms never a
problem psychedelic mushrooms eventually
some [ __ ] goes and digs up the
mycelium with a shovel that's how like
crazy it gets it's just like dude just
like this is just a little like I
literally caught my friend digging up
the entire mycelium bed of of a cyan
essent patch that was a big patch in
North Vancouver I was just like dude how
about uh leave some for the next
guy always leave some for the next guy
hey and as speaking of that as we enter
the fall here this is mushroom season
here in Vancouver in the next like two
plus weeks we'll see the semin catas
known as the liberty caps we'll see the
stunes and the Bale systens and the cyan
Essen known as the wavy caps they'll all
start popping up amonita as well but I'm
I'm not so uh not so interested in those
ones so if you uh yeah get out into your
forest and wander around there's some
interesting things popping not to even
mention all the amazing winter shantells
and lobsters and Ries and you know
cauliflowers and all these incredible
mushrooms that are just going to start
uh going off in the forest here soon
it's a really great reason to get out
into the forest uh and it's just the
gift of nature herself we we inoculate
um our straw bales that kind of line
some of our garden spaces and the wood
chips we inoculate it with King
staria and we've been getting beautiful
flushes going on right now um and uh
it's just I love having those wine caps
around and it just it's always a gift
when you show up in the morning and
there's a whole other flush going on
it's it's amazing it's amazing it is the
smile on my face when I picture it is
just uh inoculate the world shout out to
Drew from my Instagram inoculate the
West inoculate the world if you don't
follow follow go follow him awesome dude
that's really collected an incredible
array of Spore prints in the
psilocybin family um you can get them
and acquire them and experience them
these little aliens
hey I just want to give a quick shout
out to our 710 crew you know veterans
they have their own usual um their uh
their local so our vac crew is our local
710 on the hill all week and we will
continue to be so just FYI we're working
it hard for everybody out there so get
it keep it flowing hell yeah Marcus I
just wanted to say thank you and uh this
is the coolest church I've ever been to
haven't been to many churches um the
whole cannabis Journey for me uh has
been the Catalyst to everything good
I've learned in the last you know 20
years all the good people I've met um
this is a true honor to be here and uh
single Source farming uh has just taught
me to search for quality in all aspects
of my life and uh the thing you said
about the pizza kind of was a fun old
irony because it was like when I used to
be at the spot on the hill it was like
you couldn't even order a pizza you know
and that was one of the sacrifices of
being up there for the summer um you
know you're growing your good pot you're
having your couple turns in the
greenhouse and you're full term outside
and you can't even order a pie when
you're tired after like a 12h hour day
so I just love that and you know
anything where people are really into
something they dig that deep and you
make a couple fun and not so fun
sacrifices and uh yeah thank you guys
all for everything you
do hell yeah man and well said and you
know what we didn't hear much from you
do you want to tell us about sort of a
little bit of your journey and maybe
some of your favorite flavors or things
that you got your
ground yeah I would love to um for the
last decade I was lucky enough to rent
this really cool place up in Los Padres
Forest um which is like 805 Santa
Barbara area shout out to all the small
Growers that are still doing their thing
there there's a lot of big money that
kind of bullied our really cool small
community
and uh I was lucky enough to go on an
organic Journey because I was working
for an awesome Egg Farm there that does
the best vegetables around and they
would practically give us truckloads of
compost to take up to the spot and work
with then we started making our own
compost making our own teas uh try to
keep it simple worked on through the old
slab days the envelope days parchment
paper days um yeah a lot of fun stuff
that feel like I got saved by the
solvent list I was kind of Stu cloud of
the DH mountain and then some people
pushed me into some good things and the
solventless came to life and I realized
like
CRC there was a good thing that came
from it and that was the tasty jars that
we're lucky enough to be sitting in
front there's obviously Addison's got
this Treasure Chest sharing right now
which [ __ ]
wild so yeah I have some full terms in
the green house that we're pulling right
now um we had a little heat wave that
kind of [ __ ] us up um ironically we
have a wall of dragon fruit in one
greenhouse and they're just going off
because we had that little tropical
thing go down so there's like 20 you
know a couple dozen dragon fruit in
there um and then Meanwhile we're kind
of little trial and era this year
pulling some of the Masonic gear that we
popped like 20 different things from him
pulling them a little early and getting
them Frozen did some in-house crosses
and uh working with those getting them
in the freezer and then was lucky enough
to pull some depths this year and we're
enjoying those jars today and uh you
know pretty small pretty single Source
but just trying to keep at it so that I
don't have to work for anyone else and
uh that's been the journey so thank you
once
again sounds like a great journey man
Admiral
Journey thank you and beautiful garden
Josh that was uh spectacular you guys
just showing that whole thing the
mountains your backyard thank you for
sharing that that was uh that was tasty
treats right family give thanks to every
day is a a blessing
so what didn't Ka have to say anything
Ka just sat there half asleep I was
actually just
aome laying back
Kaa has a new family member you know
baby in his life and and and you know
all these beautiful kids and and a
superb wife and everything partner and
uh so I'm sure he got busy and stuff so
I guess we're lucky we got to see him
for the time we did Super thankful for
KA Pacific Northwest Roots if you don't
know online uh you know worldwide
genetics Pacific Roots worldwide
genetics just all kinds of stuff he's
always out there he's just a special
person got the Hawaiian Aloha Vibes
going on along with the Northwest you
know First Nations kind of roots and
stuff so you know it's I love our family
is so eclectic and and all over the
world really and um you know no borders
in our family so you know it's uh it's
really cool to hear you know little bits
from each bio region and biosphere we
have so much love and respect for all
you all uh and what you're doing and
putting forth good medicine to the
people because we're all out here just
trying to survive putting forth good
medicine to the people and it's you know
it's our mission in life you know so you
know I'm just really stoked there's you
know ain't Ain't No Stopping Us Now you
know nothing's going to break our stride
you know everything's keeping on pushing
and all those good things and stuff so
we're steady on the grind here at
dragonfly Farm you know we have a new
grandchild in our life we've had two
home births on the farm Total Herbal
cannabis medicinal mushroom herbal you
know no you know checking in with
nothing but you know mother GA and uh
you know we're thankful for that that
mission and Kelly and hermit
wiery uh and uh just you know uh in a
time when it can be difficult you know
it's sweet to see New Life come into the
Earth you know and and our family and
then just gardening with your grandchild
all summer is like it's like a level of
spectacular that's just like you can
never explain until you're there and she
loved doing tarps so here we are pulling
tarps with the gr you know it's just you
know there's just a lot of good news to
be had out there you know so you know
don't don't get worried you know there's
a lot of good stuff going on you know
and uh you know it's these kind of
people out here that keep the
inspiration going and big up to the
community who's writing online you know
there's so many people I would love to
personally say their name you know or
have them on the show so I would just
like to say the show is just is
everyone's comments the show is
everyone's
participation no one person isn't ahead
or behind the other it's truly a magical
fractal team teamwork going on you know
so you know uh everyone's invited and
everyone's on time you know for for
their for their mission so go do your
best and uh you know we're getting
getting on in our day and I have you
know a bunch of stuff to go tend to in
the garden so I I think I might end up
signing out right right at this moment I
love to hear maybe some more things from
everyone but just Big Love from the
dragonfly family DM here all the way all
the family members everyone else the
collective every anyone doing something
good that's what's up anyone doing
something good that's what's up so thank
you for listening thank you thank you
Josh and Kelly and the whole dragon fly
Earth medicine crew they helped put this
uh last minute hash church together and
uh I don't mind going till like noon you
know another 12 13 minutes anyone want
to drop their social media or their
projects that they're doing or something
cool about someone or point us in the
direction of someone we could be helping
or we should know about whatever it is
feel free to say it Joshua thanks for
walking us through your garden I was
tight I pinned it for AIT hey I just
thought I figured uh I figured I was out
here and we could just kind of check out
a couple of things we got going some
pumpkin cover crops here and some plants
that have falling over we kind of exper
we're kind of experimenting with like
less trellising this year and keep it
natural but of these bigger gals over
here last um trellising on and um yeah
just kind of playing around got some fun
like key lime hash crosses
here um got some more pins just coming
through we already did a little bit of
harvesting on here just kind of su
sessions here's some smaller plans
starting to do their
fade but yeah we're just getting some
nice rain right now I mean we'll take it
and plants these plants will hold up
nice we'll
uh it's actually kind of fun to see
which ones stand up tall through all
this and and kind of breed accordingly
and all that kind of fun
stuff um yeah some more of the key
liines here the key lines have been nice
they've been dumping some good resin for
us
what's up with uh what we're we're still
kind of learning like you know optimal
harvesting for for fresh frozen you know
I got we got some buddies who we we've
done you know like cured hash with and
stuff like that and uh he'll see a super
Frosty PL be like oh that one's going to
dump but then I feel like for fresh
frozen do you feel like if you
let him get
right this one's looking pretty nice and
ripe
here hey Sam do the thols really uh
build up at the end of the cycle as well
as the terpenoids and everything from
your experience is that some another
reason to let the plant ripen more I
think you might be losing them a little
bit during cultivation
but I find at the moment of harvest
seems to be when it's has the strongest
smell but then during the say two week
in the dark drying it uh it's a I mean
you can smell it for half a mile away if
it's a large
dry hey uh Marcus can I I want to give a
shout out real quick uh to uh Dean elban
and his victory um uh Glass Works they
gave some donations to our veterans that
we able to use all week for our dabbing
in DC and I just want to say thank him
for helping us out we appreciate it much
love hell yeah absolutely I want to get
Brian on the show again maybe do another
hash church about uh maybe it even could
coincide with uh um Shar and Nick and
the volatile organic compounds because
not only do we want to talk about and
understand how they're produced and how
they're preserved but then if we're so
obsessed with preserving them then too
shall we be to the level that Brian is
obsessed with how we consume them and
and how does the material we consume
them off of them create buffers to
further preserve those compounds right
up until the point where we are
experiencing them instead of changing
them before they get into our old
factory and into our uh you know taste
buds notes taken
yeah I wanted to say something real
quick
Colin um did you get in trouble for
something
today not the place it's not the forum
for it my
friend this is absolutely not the
for that's so funny um no not at all um
I don't know what you're talk
about remembered that we're fine we're
good all it's we're
good that's it's kind of funny because
not it's it's it's the principle not the
fact right that's the whole
thing if that's what you're if that's
you're being convinced to believe
sure hey I also do want to give a shout
out to Wade laughter uh Wade is actually
become part of our veterans group
because he was a Vietnam veteran and uh
he's been working with us and uh he's
been going through his cancer and uh
he's coming out on the other side and he
gives great thanks to uh cannabis
mushroom so uh it really got to me he
literally has metal in his neck Etc but
uh I just wanted to shout out a special
love to Wade um I I I will see him this
week during vac meetings but uh he's
doing well I know he sends his love and
he's put on the fight of his fight and
he's coming out through it so thank you
Wade for the strong fight L man D thank
you for bringing Wade up at I want to
also reiterate that sentiment and send
my love out to Wade Wade you're a
special human being we absolutely love
and adore you here on hash Church you're
part of our community part of our family
uh and uh yeah you know be strong do
well you've got our support anytime you
need it it's always there uh and we're
looking back uh looking forward to the
day that you're back uh enjoying a hash
church with us so shout out to uh to
Wade and if he's not watching now at CH
make sure you show him this because uh
I'm sure we're all sending him our love
yeah
he's motivated in healing he's he
couldn't make it to our lobby day in uh
this past week but his motivation is to
make it in May to us uh of 2023 so we
look forward to having him strong and
walking alongside Us in the halls of
Congress
so some pounds to the vets if you can
help me facilitate that after the fact
operation Evac and Ryan Miller and then
they do that they give away cannabis
free to our veterans and make sure of
all that so in mind out uh that man
right next to you knows how to reach out
to me I love
you one thing that I think would be
interesting to share is um I've uh I've
been running through I'm GNA read read
the list of things I95 times cherry pie
times Tony Clifton watermelon skill
Skittles times uh Z times Tropic
Tropical
Skittles uh times peanut butter runs and
then Gary pton times banana
runs and all of those are hitting above
6% on
yield uh for washing all of them all all
all of those that I listed
so sounds like the progenitors are
correct yeah they I mean I thought you I
know you're a g you're a fan of Gary so
I think the banana the banana runs adds
adds some adds a little little twist
yeah but those are uh banana runs is
from soulfire for those that want to
know i' we've
uh we've got yeah is that stuff that you
guys are have put together or that
you're running right now or what's that
M yeah those are in Mass yeah so for
Mass are you what are you selling most
of are you selling to the public like
Mass
Market um not currently we're working on
breeding projects right now and then
we're going to partner with
a uh there's an outfit here that we're
working with to get those to licensed
producers so we can put those into play
so those have a have a home for them and
then there um will be banked with
canopia and medicinal genomics and then
backed with P pathos which is their kind
of um pathogen kind of verification
system what's what's the max that
they'll pay in the mass market for six
star if if they even get it yeah this
that's that's the other question but um
I think think um it's it's still like
it's still like to 2016 in you know in
California 85 Plus dollar a gram you
know what I mean so um that's just where
it's at right now because the pounds are
still on the on the um just the
regulated side are still reaching three
grand you know so it's just the Paradigm
is still there and it's strong so there
it's still holding somewhat but um
you'll find in wholesaling for like 22
to
30 grand you know yeah
so quarter of the price of the full
Mount yeah it's it's you know they're
not pressing the full Mount they're
pressing
the it's not all the same strains though
like the the six star is gonna be four
or five strains where like the $22 hash
rosin is going to be like eight [ __ ]
strength eight of the same culprit eight
of the same 16 culprits that you see
everywhere
third yeah yeah and then exactly it's
like full it's like a you know mix
Micron and stuff you know all that so
full spec yeah so the East Coast has a
lot of like just in terms of like where
we're at just because there's not a lot
of accessibility still you know like we
kind of forget because we're so spoiled
that um we just don't have it and I
that's I think that's the other thing
people are excited to learn about hash
right now on the East Coast or re really
ReDiscover it I think honestly um so
it's you know it's like it's I think
it's like out there what I see is a lot
of product still goes to flower market
because it has value in flower market
too so it's a little different where you
know and and the reality is like West
Coast and the East Coast smoke a lot of
hash the difference is our Q-tips are a
little less dark on the west coast yeah
I don't know you know when we clean up
our Banger It's like because it's
different material that's going in there
more availability of super high-end
stuff and that's because you have two
different forces pulling there's the
market pulling to flour which is always
viable there and then just you know the
the the P the buying Market it's just
kind of different I mean New York's
interesting to see it kind of turning on
and just watching like popup stuff go
from California to New York and things
happening and other stuff but um how's
that because you're close to that market
too like what's what do you kind of see
you know it's it's the kind of as I
alluded before I think it's like
everyone needs to just slow down and let
like the structure kind of get there you
know and then we can be really truly
excited but um I think it's it's just a
mixture of everybody kind of you know
wanting to get their chance and gearing
up for it and gonna have a lot of
personality you know I think that's the
cool part about it so I I'm really
honestly I'm super excited I think it's
it's GNA be amazing and interesting and
everything in between and um it's a
center of of many cultures so I'm
excited to see what that comes of it too
you know so yeah there's been a lot of
trapping that's the that's the one thing
I seems like Daniel Boone [ __ ]
banging out in New York It's the Last
Frontier though you know what I mean so
um when did the roen caps with the with
the Tails happen then
that's they're coming there's the
push-ups guys anybody going join me
push-ups two every two hours but
yeah there's a lot of cool people that
want I think have uh have have been
doing things that want opportunity and
this is their chance so you know
um gonna be cool yeah that's uh I mean
piff doesn't really make the greatest
cash does it oh no no no no you look the
all this all it um I think again has to
go through its own contemporary kind of
Rance change and all those because
people have been holding things for
decades in these areas that have just
been growing the same
thing they just don't want to go out and
find a new thing or buy a seed pack and
take the chance on honest because they
don't have the space for it yeah so um I
think that's going to be interesting and
seeing kind of what you know because
knowing just what I've kept and been so
insular with and knowing some of the
other people that have been doing the
similar things I you know that crossed
with some of this newer stuff that I'm
now starting to explore I think is is
gonna drive a lot of what New York's
gonna become you know it's gonna be
really
interesting hey guys I gotta jump
off was
awesome thank you Marcus thank you yeah
yeah I'm going to also end it here at
noon I appreciate everyone coming in and
doing their thing and sharing their
Vibes and uh let's try and do it again
next week maybe a little bit more of
maybe we'll get Sharie and we'll get
Nick and we'll get deeper into the
volatile organic compounds we'll go
where we go we'll get Dr Mark shalone in
the house and we'll invite some of the
other regulars and thank you all for
showing up I appreciate each and every
one of
you apprciate it's the road to Legends
now so it is the road to Legends we'll
be doing we'll do at least one big
Legends of hash uh hash Church before
Legends as well so we can kind of update
you on uh everything that Addison and
Kevin and the whole crew have been doing
so it's uh it's coming along very nicely
I also need to mention before I leave uh
what is it Northshore cannabis presents
the Cana art event this is September
24th from 12: to 4:00 pm uh support
local cannabis artists get your cannabis
pressed and THC tested I guess that is
um uh trim test it will be there with
his little machine testing uh testing
cannabis I'll be there future cannabis
project and Rose web Farms I'll be there
with Chay and we'll be talking about
kind of some of our products at one of
the local dispensaries in North
Vancouver so I had to mention that as
well uh Legends of hash will be
happening December 2nd and 3 of this
year and we'll be uh yeah come check us
out on our Instagram uh Legends of
hashish and uh catch up with all things
check out the website as well yeah
Legend of has.com and uh I think just
thank you everyone go forth and enjoy
cannabis and I do want to know what
percentage of you eat pizza when you
leave here be honest with me now peace
out
everybody later
guys thanks again