I have very few people who have replied
today and I'm going to have to go on to
YouTube and I'm going to have to find
the actual link oh there it is right
there look at
that that was
easy all right let's do this sorry about
this guys a little bit Rusty today but
I'll send the link over
here and uh I'm not sure if anyone's
even going to show up so this could just
be me hanging out puffing bowls and
talking with everybody it's been a while
since I did uh a spur of the moment hash
Church of course uh our last hash church
was in honor of Horatio Delbert our hash
Church alumni who uh passed away
recently so we want to send our regards
to his family and all the friends and
all the people that he sort of supported
over the years and inspired and blew
away with all of his knowledge I am
and now we're back I was frozen for a
little bit sorry about that everybody
let's see uh oh yeah so let's say hi to
the room we got uh oh we got happy guy
we got Kelly Kell noog we got squishy
Manitoba goat medically fit Bingo
Lombard's in the chat holding it down we
got dirty 42 and K2 LED and Justin cash
we got about 120 people watching right
now um and I got people in the room that
I'm going to let in right now I got hemp
guy I got Colin and I got someone I
don't even recognize but uh let's see
who it
is what's going on
[Music]
boys hey buddy how you doing good
manit let me see my headset will uh
connect
here cutting out a little bit
working you there hemp
guy your microphone I heard you there I
can hear you okay everything's rock and
roll and then we got this other one here
I don't know who that
is oh it's
Mike it's going on
buddy morning
Marcus dude I got to be honest I was
like who the heck is that dig on m o e
QA how did you get your name to be such
a crazy
name H probably firewall
weird nice what's up Mike
weird hey
Sam you guys doing howdy howdy
howdy I'm on the coast Maine right now
nice just chilling
out see why my headphones my headphones
should be working I'm just you know I
came up here my wife wanted to come up
um we we live so close to Maine that
we've never had a chance to really
explore it and we've been keep talking
about it so it's an hour and a half from
us
so I committed to it and then I got your
email and of course uh it's hard to back
out of the commitment when
you you've committed to it dude the last
time I was Maine was in 1994 and I drove
all the way to Bangor to see Fish play
at like a high school
gymnasium hell
yeah I remember that well I remember the
the the Banger M festival and that was
that was an
incredible just an incredible run of of
music for
them yeah for sure they did the 37
minute long tweezer from a live one at
that show that I was at that was like
the first time I guess maybe not the
first time but it was one of the longest
ones they did and I guess it was a
special enough one that they felt they
were going to put it on their live
double album titled a live one here let
me put you on view so we can see that
Colin yeah hey welcome Johnny B with the
long hair mute myself and I'm gonna
figure out how to put my my ear pods
dude you rocking those
Pros I am and they're giving me so much
trouble these days actually they're not
connecting to my phone right I don't
know why
weird yeah that's not that's no bueno
this is uh some cold cure lemon
cake
beautiful I just oh you went on mute
there I just went and pressed some uh
hash church last night oh how is that
dude it's actually really quite nice it
looks insane the photos were
beautiful I definitely didn't get the
yield that I was expecting but I'm going
to do some more so it was just really a
small press on my um my Helix Pro here
on the side of my desk so it was the
crank
unit not the most amount of pressure
hello good morning
etan good morning sir how are you today
oh you know pretty good I got a I got a
message yesterday from Ian Davidson and
he I've been trying to get him on to
Hash church for a long time to come and
share all of his incredible knowledge on
not only like growing in green houses
but also like starting the tissue
culture company and kind of getting into
the explanation of initiation
and um you know
multiplication and Meemic propag
micropropagation basically everything I
learned about tissue culture like 95% of
it has come uh from from Ian and
probably another probably 5% of it came
from Chimera because he was talking
about it almost 20 years ago uh way
before anyone was I guess really able to
make it economically viable as a
business I know skunkman Sam as well had
done it 25 plus years ago uh so it would
have been good to have him on he's
impossible to get on in the weekends
because he's got a little girl uh that
he spends his time with his daughter but
um he he said last night he was going to
try and make it in so I'm really hoping
today he's going to be able to come in
and share with us uh some good stuff on
tissue culture
but otherwise we can chill out and puff
some
bowls we'll do that regardless yeah I
had a I knew a group in central
California who did that a decade ago but
W they had brought in a woman from South
Africa who had did it in South Africa
for 27 years and just after she did it
she's like okay I'm going to retire now
goodbye oh wow so they couldn't continue
it they basically had it started and
they had to let it die because they
couldn't perpetuate it yeah so
with with tit culture do you guys like
all right so there's a lot of people
offering it I get emails all the time
there's a couple people in the
Massachusetts state or the state of
Massachusetts my earpiece fell out sorry
that um you know the main theme that I
keep being told is it will replace your
mother room now is that something that
it that everyone feels like the
techniques and and the
I guess the Sops that you would follow
are are that solid that we would not
have to keep live plants any longer or
would you say that we would want to keep
maybe both at the same time what what
are your thoughts on that kind of stuff
as somebody who's worked with h tissue
culture I can say that uh when you
reproduce uh mems under tissue culture
so in a glass container with egg or
angger or whatever your formula for for
nutrients uh one of the problems is
every few years you really need to take
the plants out and refresh them by
growing them as a big plant and taking
fresh new pieces so I mean it definitely
takes up less room uh but and if you're
big enough it may make economic sense uh
but Ian at SRA is the to talk to about
this and uh yeah anybody who's
interested can't
wait I hope he I hope he shows up I'm
really go
ahead it's an interesting discussion
because the uh uh it was perpetuated in
a lab so I always thought about that
what would you do would you maintain the
genetic but as well as you know keep it
perpetually going you know my thought
would always keep some sort of backup
data always I mean I have that problem
with the computer so exactly the only
thing I would think of to do would be to
maintain that same situation with jeans
because you know if electricity goes out
and then you know the chamber that
that's stored in dies you know now what
you crack start from those start
collecting genetics from other people
you know I think I think one of the
great I think one of the great ways is
um um maintaining it under like very
small pieces of it just the tissue it
doesn't even have to be the living plant
and you can you can maintain that on um
in liquid nitrogen in a very small
inexpensive method and I think that way
you can really get into redundancies
where you could have two or three
different sites where you maintain your
library and it takes up a very very
small amount of room versus how much
room it would take for um you know you
know you to keep those mothers but I'm
in the same boat I don't think it's
gotten quite to the point yet you know
and it's also when we compare comp it to
strawberries or raspberries they don't
seem to have the same variation when it
comes to commercial production you know
you've got your one banana and your your
driscolls does like your one strawberry
and it's this one sort of cultivar that
everyone's just kind of like oh I'm
happy I'll just buy the Driscoll
strawberries I think they grew 10
billion plantlets this year all over the
world in different parts of the world so
from the for from those companies
perspectives obviously it's going to be
a lot easier to keep a plant that's one
single genetic we come from the Cannabis
industry where you know on average I'm
sure we're going to want to have at
least 500 plus genetics kept alive maybe
it's a thousand maybe it's 1500 I don't
know but there's a lot of different
varieties of cannabis out there little
variations in phenotypes and you know
losing those from a cannabis connoisseur
perspective is is is frightening you you
know you really you want to maintain you
know all those flavors and all those
different effects and when you think of
the Nostalgia that occurs in an old
school puffer when they're like oh yeah
we used to get this one thing and I mean
I've asked Sam how many times people
have asked him about the roadkill skunk
oh what whatever happened to the
roadkill skunk like we have Nostalgia
over these different flavors and it's um
Road Hill Road Hill skunk actually got
ran over on the road and uh doesn't
exist anymore yeah I'm feeling you on
that one
well you said you you heard it here
first
folks it's
per it's it's doing this work originally
30 years ago was exactly to keep it
maintained so I wanted I had 600 clones
at that time and keeping them all alive
and maintain was a pain in the butt so I
wanted a method where I could take
mirums or callus freeze it
and keep it the way you're talking about
in liquid nitrogen then uh you
know like you could have a thousand in a
small portable unit it doesn't even have
to be liquid nitrogen because you can
get freezers that are minus 50 really
easy I think that'll do
it yeah it in in m to Marcus's point
it's it's frightening to lose some of
these varieties I mean it's you know the
the security that always had was to give
it to your closest buddies and and make
sure that you know if if anything were
to happen you could at least call upon
them but it's you know we're so we're so
far from that now you know the the
paradigm's really shifted you know 1800
square feet of moms you're not going to
be sharing 1800 square feet of of cuts
you know it's tough what I was was I'm
sure many more varieties than exist now
have been lost in the past think about
it yeah got some good news it's good
point it's a good way to put it I like
good news so I got word from ebony
Worley who is Shan Worley who is the
veteran arrested in Alabama for
traveling through with cannabis and our
our group the uh veterans Action Council
actually sent a letter to Alabama full
of a whole bunch of people who have
served saying let him out let him go
and uh ebony let us go that let us know
that Alabama is going to be releasing
him uh on parole so we got some positive
news there and on the same side we got
some bad news um friend of mine at the
veterans uh virtual happy hour Jose
Balon and them were vying for uh a
reschedule uh and they applied to the
Supreme Court of the United States and
got all the way through to there and and
then uh this week the Supreme Court
decided not to hear the case so
unfortunately um the you know
rescheduling that we tried for Vi for
unfortunately again it was on
hypotheticals where the court wants to
see you actually be you know damaged or
hurt by the proceedings somewhere along
the lines and they just threw it out so
we got to try again yeah you got to try
again and wait till after the Democrats
win and pack
Supreme Court then use it with facts
instead of theory and you'll do it right
and that's what we're trying to use
we've assembled the veterans from across
the United States and we're going to use
our power to you know go after uh Biden
to work on a Bo Biden medical marijuana
bill you know because his son as even he
spoke of could even have used it so
we're going to not stop we're going to
embarrass them we're going to use our
power and our voices to continue the
pressure so you know two steps forward
One Step pack take it on the chin
regroup reorganize and fight
again but but Mr Worley's going home so
you know that least some good news a
drug war prisoner is going home and dude
when the [ __ ] does anyone ever get let
out of prison in in like
Louisiana it's Alabama too Alabama so
yeah it was a
yeah I mean it was hard finding him
councel uh there's a lot of challenges
there because there's no medical defense
and he had been busted in Alabama prior
and was let go to Arizona to do his
parole and he got busted on parole there
which is why he went back to Alabama so
that he was even to get parole due to
this is pretty much a miracle in itself
and one we're thankful for and hopefully
our pressure helped if not you know then
matter we're going to continue to use
whatever voices we have to help people
who are still hurt so you know don't
forget if you're free send the elevator
back down help out people brothers and
sisters are still in jail for this so
sharing is caring which reminds me to
give a big shout out to one of my
mentors Ron hickey my my good old buddy
Ron who recently sent me two beautiful 5
foot tall congales plants and I guess
it's full circle cuz five or six or
seven or eight years ago I don't know
when whenever I started really giving
the Congo away uh he was one of the
first people I actually gave it
to uh you know it was kind of a
controlled cultivar for a while some
people felt like they were going to keep
this cultivar and and really control
this cultivar and make seeds and sell it
and make the money and I kind of put the
kibos on that by giving it away to I to
everyone literally like Dr Atomic and
Remo and Johnny B gave it to everybody I
gave it to everyone man I gave that
thing out to everyone and so now it's
come back to me John yesterday two 5
foot tall Congo plants beautiful Congo
plants that Ron was growing out on his
deck um arrived and uh so I got the
Congo back and I'm pretty darn pretty
darn happy to have the Congo back and uh
on that note I would like to welcome uh
Mr regenerative uh Joshua to the room
with the orange toque good to see you
buddy what's up man the toque
dude that's Canadian
yeah what's up Colin are you on top of a
rock somewhere what's up brother yeah
I'm actually in Maine right now I I
drove up here with my uh my other my my
better half this nice um we're just
exploring the the coast here it's
beautiful but uh sorry if I feel
towering today it looks awesome man I'll
try to I'll try to CH you know there we
go how are you Josh what's going on man
I'm good man I just heard you guys
talking about the Congo and I got that
cut a couple years back when we went up
there to do the regen conference in
Vancouver it trickled its way down and
um I've been pollinating with it I've
got a few rounds of pollination on it
and it's it's a cool Plant Man the are
we the Robert's Creek one I guess is the
one we're probably all talking about
yeah yeah I mean I I go I call it Lano
Negra cut because it was my friend Alex
who actually collected it from the
pygmies in the Congo then it went to
reeferman and reeferman I think ended up
taking it to the Sun Sunshine Coast and
then people on the Sunshine Coast got
control of it and then you had you had
your Green Supreme and your Al The
Alchemist and befriended Lano negro's
wife Raina genga and started trying to
control this plant that just needed to
be shared it needed to be gifted it
needed to be given to people because it
it is a really unique cultivar it has a
nice you know I've heard it has thcv in
it is actually what I've heard I've
never actually seen the COA from the
Congo wouldn't be surprised if some of
that South African here you go this was
tested by Tim through K selections I
have the Congo here right now and this
is what it has on the bottom tested by
tcva there you go and this is this is
right now guys like as you're saying it
I got gifted this the other day when I
was at Hero's actually in who do you
think gave that to Tim oh you did along
with the East Coast Sour
Diesel you
Batman good get these things away oh it
smells so amazing amazing and on that
note I'm doing a dab with the Congo you
let's hit the Congo
buddy that's what I'm smoking a joint of
this entire time which I'm like yall
like Congo Congo Congo and my friend
Amber has a company called the Congo
Club which I I'll Amber Senator yeah
Amber Center she's awesome and uh she uh
yeah yeah she
does Congo Club so she does uh she's
actually going to be doing a con a yeah
a concentrate infused where she's taking
ke and actually infusing the congales
joint with the Congo Keef so we're
stacking Congo here Cali what's the
profile like i' I've had the tpin I
believe uh from the Blue River tpin
Marcus of the Congo but I've not smoked
the flour or hash from it what what's
the what's the profile it's very exotic
it's very tarpine it's very like
perfumey it's uh it's just something
different than what you you constantly
get with the gases and the fruits and
all these different sort of musky
flavors the Congo is definitely a
special one it's uh I got a big bag of
it right now actually I'm pretty excited
to start uh to start squishing it I
squished the hash church last night and
made a little bit of rosin but I think
today maybe even during church I might
press out a little Congo with my little
bit of nug that I got left how much of
that hash Church did you press and how
much came out I pressed a very small
amount and I didn't get a ton but I
pressed it on my Helix Pro and I didn't
have it um sort of uh tied to my table
with these you need a really proper
table because when you crank the last
little bit where you go from about 8,000
lb up to like 14,000 lbs you really need
it to be steady so I couldn't really get
it much over 10,000 and it was low I
mean I got I put in four grams and I got
out like 0.5 so it was about like
12% uh but then I did hit it a second
time and I actually didn't collect the
rosin from the second Cress so I'm
guessing it's probably around like 18%
he said he got around 20 to 22% when he
pressed uh when he pressed Rosen um it
makes me a little suspicious as to how
it can be so resinous maybe it is these
hooked tricomes I'm going to get in on
the bud later today and photograph it it
really reminds me of an old cultivar I
used to grow
years back like I'm talking almost 30
years ago from Holland that I got called
Dutch Treat and it was it's I've never
seen another Dutch Treat that looked
like this one it was just coated in res
and it had a really musky kind of like
almost hash plant smell so for me I've
got a little Nostalgia on it I love the
way the plant looks and I'm still going
to wash it see how much the Melt comes
out what kind of yields I get uh and I'm
pretty excited about it actually it's
pretty nice H um I wanted to hop in back
on the um the Congo before we moved on I
was just on the phone with a vision
Creator last week um talking about the
Congo and he and I can't remember his
partner's name but they're working with
a university up there in BC and they've
done S1 line of it that they are just
about to release they have 1500 seeds I
think of s1's they're going to release
on that so wow just maybe maybe give a
follow out to Vision Creator if you guys
are interested in getting a hold of
those genetics he's been in the chat
yeah he's been really cool I mean he's
the one that was getting it out to to
all of us you know and it trickled out
too in my kind of circle here so yeah
that's awesome that's awesome you know
it's one of those cuts especially now
where legality isn't really a problem I
generally just if I have it I give it to
whoever asks me for it I just I can't
imagine being like you know one one of
my one of the guys that likes to control
this cul ofar and I won't call him out
because it's just makes him sound like
such a piece of [ __ ] but he was kind of
like you know I got to make sure uh I
got to make sure that uh you know the
person is worthy and I'm like whoa like
dude like that is everything that's
wrong in the world right now like the
person is worthy like what if the person
isn't worthy but his little girl is
worthy and is having seizures and needs
this cultivar to stop those seizures
like why do we create these reasons to
not to be greedy and to maintain control
over something as awesome as a cannabis
cultivar it's like listen I get it if
you spent 20 years in 10 or 10 years in
your greenhouse and you collected the
seeds all I get that but this is a
cultivar that was collected in Africa it
was meant to be given out as a gift you
know the pygmy meant it to be a gift and
it just seems like a strange thing to
try and collect and control someone
else's work just give that [ __ ] away I I
had a I had a variety from the Congo one
time was given to the from the pigies to
Jean Paul halette who was a uh a famous
explorer down there and I I had all
these plans to grow massive amounts of
it and I I had a logo all picked out get
small but uh the problem was the weed
just didn't cut it your Congo
[Music]
is can I ask you this Sam because you
you're probably the guy that's gone
through the biggest
populations you know like when when I
was hear Marcus say that I was thinking
you know well that's usually someone
that has a lot of insecurities it's
holding on to something and as I've
started to run through larger sifts you
know a 500,000 I've gotten really
confident that I don't I don't really
kind I'm kind of sitting in this
position right now and maybe it's it's
an immature position to be in but I feel
like I don't need anyone specific Elite
cut I can find enough stuff if I go
through big enough populations and so I
guess that the question is do you find
that to be true or do you still think
that it's it's like yeah those Elites
are Elites and they they're outliers
what do you consider a big population I
don't know you tell me I mean I it could
be whatever it could be a thousand it
could be 10,000 it could be 20,000 you
know yeah well at
20,000 you uh will probably get a very
elite cut in in a in a closet with 10
plants you're lucky to get an elite
cut right
absolutely
agree they tried to do the same thing
with OG Kush you know where they uh you
know people tried to hold on to it and
it people swore and it wasn't until the
person who made that original swear died
that it finally made its propagation out
through the 90s and made its way out so
yeah I've never understood the
absolute sentencing of a of a of a
genetic to private use and nobody
getting access to it sorry there's also
different ways to uh pass things out if
if you felt you worked for years and
years in selection and selection to get
a particular cut then make seeds and
sell those I mean you can make millions
of seeds and pass it out to the
community and everybody that wants one
can get one what I like is that you
actually speak from experience when you
said you can make millions of seeds I
thought that [ __ ] has done this
already I have done it many
times how about sweet skunk cross with
congales sweet
skunk
yeah oh
Snapper hey I wanted to welcome uh Ian
Davidson to the room Mr SAR himself has
arrived and I got to welcome him to the
room dude how you doing man hey guys I'm
good I run L up chasing some horses
around here oh you know I was in the
forest I was in the forest yesterday in
Squamish picking mushrooms we were
picking yellow foots actually
shantell's and uh a horse was walking
through the forest at first we thought
it was a wild horse but it actually had
had a person with it but uh it reminded
me of you I know how much your daughter
likes to uh to ride horses yeah we had
some breakouts this morning here but
it's all good how's everybody doing
we're doing pretty good we got a little
bit into the conversation actually etan
asked a good or maybe it wasn't etan I
can't remember who asked the question
but it was basically like where are we
in a place with tissue culture in
cannabis right now where people oh it
was Colin who could that we could get to
a point and I mean actually before I ask
this question what I would really like
Ian is for you to introduce yourself let
everyone know a little bit of your
history in the industry and let them
know how you became how you came to
start and become a part of uh the tissue
culture company SAR International that
would be a good start actually sure we a
little Spiel here oh hold on what I do
pushing the
buttons oh yeah you know I mean probably
like most people here have been in this
for a long time in California primarily
and uh any you guys have heard of my
business I started this company biologic
systems and we've got a whole line of
certified
organic uh St amendments and Etc down
here in Cali primarily in
Oregon um so I've done that for a long
time kind of seen the industry through
that lens quite a bit and um you know I
ended up spending about four years uh
down in Santa Barbara County scaling a
fair bit of the several of the big green
houses down there working with these
Dutch guys and helping them to kind of
figure out uh you know what to do and
you know in that process we scaled up to
producing about um uh around 150,000
clones a month and um uh it just really
got out of control you know I mean
trying to manage a Halfacre of mother
plants and trying to do all that you
know with the the pesticides that we
have at hand and and uh it's just a huge
Challenge and so you know about four
years ago I started looking at tissue
culture I mean down in Cali you know we
watch these strawberry Growers come out
and you know they'll plant a million
strawberry plants over a weekend right
all from from TC they all look exactly
the same and uh you know that's the way
that their business ticks you know they
got a little jet they're flying around
with their tisue culture plants making
it happen you know in all their
locations um and so you know the
question was like why can't we do it for
cannabis right we can do it for these
other plants um and uh so you know I
started doing my homework and I spent
about a year traveling around the world
I met pretty much every company I could
find that was claiming to do this work
on cannabis and learned all about it
along the way I learned the questions
that you ask and you know the the key
metrics how the business Works um and uh
and then I met the team at SRA in
Vancouver there and they really to me
seem to be kind of the clear um leader
in the in the space um really for two
reasons you know our doctor zide that
runs our TC program he's been working on
cannabis for 15 years uh under a federal
research license in Canada um and then
uh you know we also have a genotyping
lab that allows us to do you know we do
over a thousand samples a month right
now um just uh checking everything right
checking to make sure we don't mix stuff
up um you know starting to look and
observe at and managing uh somaclonal
variation which is uh you know a huge
piece of the uh of the TC puzzle and is
really kind of the big risk that's
involved in it um if I can elaborate on
that a bit I'm on a little bit of a a
tangent now but it's probably a real
important one um so you know you got all
these TC Labs popping up all over for
cannabis right now um and you know what
happens in uh conventional tissue
culture you know it's usually around
like four years after making clones from
clones from clones in TC uh you start to
see mutation right the plants start to
mutate um and uh you know you're you're
literally uh you know compounding that
clonal process and if there's any kind
mutation that happens there's a good
chance it can carry on because you're
making these clones so fast from each
other so you know managing that risk
like we're seeing in cannabis at about
two years into the process uh that sooc
colonal variation starting to rear its
head at like statistically relevant
levels um and uh so you know there's a
whole process of how you manage that
right you can isolate shoots you know we
have a genotyping lab so we can isolate
100 shoots that have not mutated and you
start building a population from those
you ramp that population up and you
start ramping down the old population
and that's what they do you know
blueberries bananas papayas Etc you know
that's the way that business Works where
you know they all know the mutation is a
risk and you watch for it and you
monitor it and you react to it and uh
you can actually manage it now you know
if you're running a TC lab and you're
not watching those things and you don't
have the capacity to do that kind of
testing it can be a huge disaster and
we're starting to see that in Cali right
now I've seen several of these Labs out
here where they're at about that process
you know they're two years in two and a
half years in and they're starting to
see really weird things happening and
they don't really know any idea why or
like the tools to be able to study it
and figure out what's going on there um
so question that was
awesome would you see the same thing
like that and the say mom's over years
of taking cuts and trying to hold that
Mom say over 10 or 20 years would you
see the same in what you're talking
about right now because I'm just raising
question to myself as you're talking
about that I've had the same strength
genetic drift genetic drift 15 years
right 18 years yeah so so genetic drift
is when you're going to have that
mutation happen in live plants right
outside of TC um however you know our
assumption at this point from everything
that we see all this research we're
doing right now is that 99% of those
symptoms that you're seeing are not
mutation
they are either viruses or they're inter
cellular bacteria right and more than
likely the second of those categories
the intercellular bacteria where what
that is is when you're making clones
right like you say you're the mother
plant and I come in with my razor blades
and I'm slicing you up all over the
place you're probably going to get some
infections right and uh you know
bacteria are going to start working
their way in your body so like when we
do the tissue culture process with these
serial clones like these really really
old clones um a couple of the worst have
come from yours truly on this call or
Marcus truly on this call um you know
these old clones they've been they've
been cut so many times and each time
you're building up this bacterial load
and these aren't plant pathogens these
are essentially functioning like a
parasite in the plant it's kind of like
yeast infection right and they slow the
plant down they make the plant's immune
system drop um you know and uh and when
you do the tissue culture the initiation
process you know we've got a Technique
we do that literally migrates all that
stuff out of the plant it looks like
snot coming out of the side of the stem
and uh and you know there's some tricks
you do to just kind of keep sucking it
out it's it's really wild so you know so
mutation from cloning is very very rare
um and it does it does happen absolutely
um but it happens very slowly over the
course of time and and uh and from what
we can see um from all the genotype
testing we're doing in cannabis um we
haven't seen an example yet with a clone
uh where we've seen a documented
mutation between two clones and any
connection to a symptom so you know what
we all really need to be focused on
there is the uh you know the pathogen
side of the equation that's really
what's causing the problem uh in the
cloning you know serial cloning process
can I ask a definition question um T
tissue culture versus like marry stem
scrubbing you know I think that a lot
lot of people I've heard and this why
I'm asking you can clarify it for me and
for everyone else but I've heard a lot
of people misuse the word tissue culture
when they're not going to a true tissue
culture or they're doing some sort of
scrub I don't know can you expl that to
me I'm kind of I'm kind of guilty right
here misusing it okay so you know tissue
tissue culture is um is a family of
Technologies right okay um and so you
know the majority of people in the world
who are studying the field of plant
tissue culture um they're actually in
the genetic engineering World okay so
like um there's there's really two forms
that you can execute tissue culture from
one is
callous right you've got a little blob
of undifferentiated cells like you'll
see in pictures it's a little blob in
like a petri dish and those cells um are
essentially like stem cells right and
that's where you can go and like insert
your pig genes or you know whatever kind
of crazy GMO you're trying to do right
that all happens through callous tissue
culture um which has nothing to do with
mass production nodal propagation right
where you start with meristematic tissue
culture you isolate the meristem you
know that's what we do you start growing
from there and then literally you're
making clones from clones from clones
right you'd refer to that as nodal
propagation right or you know
micropropagation right so so 90% of the
field of tissue culture are these got
probably more 95 are these guys that are
studying callous tissue culture really
with the goal of developing genetically
engineered plants the people doing nodal
propagation for production is this
really small subset of the business like
you know this guy Dr zide that works for
us there's only about a hundred of those
guys in the world that know how to
manage these Labs that produce over 10
million plants a year um and it's a it's
a you know that world is as much farming
as it is a science right like these guys
that know how to run these big
production Labs you know they can look
at a crop of jars like you could
probably look at a room full of edge
plants and be like oh they need a little
more of this or a little less of that
you know so it's um you know it's Art
and Science but yeah the uh you know
there's a whole Suite of Technologies
like synthetic seeds and you know it
goes on that all of these Technologies
fit within the field of tissue culture
um but what we're really focused on is
just that micropropagation micro and I
didn't understand that I wasn't trying
to call you out I just take k no no no
that's an important starting point right
it's like we should really be talking
micropropagation the most part so if you
know and like you're saying this is
going on in strawberries and I'm hearing
you say how how actually small the
percentage of people you said that under
a 100 people are actually doing M micro
proficiently you know is it I mean is is
bger Big lab yeah because there's about
a hundred of them in the world gotcha so
they're just the ones that are doing it
can throw out so much that they're
making a significant impact like
strawberry industry vitro vitro plus
vitro plus uh in Poland they produce 80%
of all the ornamental ferns the entire
planet from a single lab
Ian quick question there's a bunch of
people who are watching and if there's
only a hundred of these people in the
world what would they if somebody were
watching and wanted to learn how to do
this propagation and learn this science
what would you recommend that they take
in
college um I
recommend that they go to Cha University
in Japan and study with Dr Kai who is
the father of tissue culture and they
have the most advanced tissue culture
program in the world there um that's
where doctors zide studied and uh uh so
you know it's um you know it's great
question like like to get into the field
um you got to get into these Labs you
know it's like I see a lot of people
passing around this like plant and test
tubes book like you're not going to
learn how to do mass production through
that book you know like the uh the the
real what really kind of qualifies these
professionals is experience at scale um
and you know the ability to like I kind
of started out talking about that somac
clonal thing it's like managing all of
the stuff it it's farming you know like
you you get good at it over years and
Decades of experience and uh you know
that's kind of the most profound part to
me of this whole business is like it's
this crazy intersection of like
manufacturing and plants you know where
we really are getting about as close as
you can get to like a manufacturing
process still working with a with a
plant are the schools in Japan you're
talking about do they teach in Japanese
or English do you have to learn Japanese
first no no you don't they teach the the
science is taught in English yeah
doctors zide went there is a English
teacher or English uh student so no you
don't so in this micro propop concept um
in my my mind I hear I've heard tissue
culture and I think that you know you
can hand over your genetics to a
scientist they can chop it up they put
it in the solution and then it's in a
refrigerator and then I can pull it out
of that refrigerator whenever I want or
they can and they can grow it out is
that the same with the microor or is it
more like micro you're
just yeah yeah there's there's two
different um kind of approaches on the
storage side is we're doing it right now
like at SRA we've got germ plasm
collection now for 10 of the big LPS in
Canada and we're like backing up their
stuff and you know in some cases doing
micropropagation right um but all of
that storage um in our method right um
we're storing all the plants um still as
uh as nodes as live nodes in the jars um
but what we do is we put them in a
special media um that makes them grow
really really slow right or it just
doesn't you know so they you know
typically in TC we have to move all of
our plantlets into a fresh jar with
fresh media every four weeks right and
if you don't they die right because
they're you know all the nutrients
they're taking up are in the agar right
their their whole carbon source is in
the agar their the light isn't even the
light is basically just tricking them to
kind of Stay Alive like they're growing
off of the the sugar from the agar
rather than photosynthesis right so you
know we can store plants by slowing them
down where then now we don't have to
transfer every month we can transfer
every three months right and and in that
kind of storage you can call it up
really fast right like let's say you
decide oh I want that plant you know
then the other option is
cryopreservation right and in
cryopreservation we can actually put
that stuff away in the freezer um but if
you say you want and and and there you
know without touching it it can last
essentially indefinitely right um but if
you say you want to call something up
from prior preservation right you know
for us right now you know that's still
an experiment and uh you know we think
that timeline is probably somewhere
between 6 and 12 months to be able to
bring something out and actually start
working with it again so Ian before we
get
to taking something out or even putting
something in for storage can you explain
now as you explained the you know how 80
to 90% of problems with plants are
actually these viruses or fungi or
intracellular bacterias can you explain
the importance of tissue culture in the
sense of
initiation yeah so so you know TC right
tissue culture and micropropagation
right more specifically here it's a
four-step process right so You' got you
know initiation it's the same four steps
whether you're doing blueberries or
cannabis right you know initiation is
the process where you're going to remove
all the contamination uh and then you
move into multiplication where you're G
to you know grow them multiply them
third stage is rooting where you put the
roots on the plantlets um and then the
fourth stage acclamation where you're
going to you know just like with clones
right slowly reduce the humidity and
bring them out into the real world um so
you know the initiation process is is
really quite fascinating and I think
that's where a lot of people are really
struggling where you know they think
that they've made it through the process
and they think that they've got a clean
culture and they start trying to move
into the next phase and multiplication
and they really don't right there's
still some intercellular bacteria in
there there's still things or virus that
are that are slowing that process down
so you know initiation for us um we've
done now uh over 150 Cult of ours and
we've been successful at all of them we
haven't had one we haven't been able to
get through the process yet um but they
range you know some of them are going as
fast as um five months through that
process some are taking 12 or 14 months
and it really depends on how dirty that
stuff when it comes into us right so you
know these serial clones um that have
come in yeah some of them have taken a
year to get through that process other
times when we're working right from a
seed you know that can go super fast why
because the seed isn't chalk full of all
this you know contamination yet we can
move a lot faster with it so you know
you'll hear a lot of people talking
about you know doing this process in in
a you know two three four months and
that's just really not realistic um you
know you really like when we make a
promise to a client you know we say it's
going to take 9 to 12 months and um
we've done about 80% of the cultivars in
like six or seven months um and really
it's just these outliers that you know
do take that extra time and you know
basically what we're doing right is
we're isolating the meristem you know so
you know in the plant you know the
meristems essentially separated from the
vascular system of the plant it's
floating right and there's kind of a gel
layer that separates it from the plant
and that's how these plants have evolved
to protect themselves from viruses so
that growing tip is essentially growing
faster than the viruses can move in and
infect it so you isolate that little
tiny marem you know it's microscopic
right and then you're going to grow that
out and then we're going to go through
that process again and potentially again
if we have to and uh you know so that's
where you know if it's clean enough we
can kind of catch it on that first turn
but usually it's going to take more than
uh more than one cycle to get through
there thing the other thing you're going
to need of course in and I'm sure you
guys got it already is uh test to
confirm the fungi was there and gone now
test to confirm a bacteria is there and
then gone and test to confirm viruses
were there and gone and few people know
how to do that
properly yeah good question so you know
we've got a lab our lab our molecular
biology lab in Richmond you know we've
developed uh molecular based assays now
for was like pther RIS octonia
sclerotinia
Bettis uh there's a couple more on there
that we we have um and then the uh you
know the virus testing right now is uh
really a disaster like in our in our
opinion we haven't seen a lab yet um
that we consider to be validated uh
doing a virus test on cannabis like ANL
in Canada they're ripping tons of these
tests they're issuing uh what we're
assuming are false false positives left
and right you know virus testing like
we're learning with Corona virus it's
like it's the hardest analytical testing
in the world right like viruses are
constantly changing and mutating and are
extremely difficult to fingerprint and
identify um and and so you know the uh
the let me get it didn't beyond that Ian
the truth of it is is most of these
companies don't know how many viruses
have been at identified in Cana in
cannabis whether they have symptoms or
not is a separation right but identifi
27 yeah now are you seeing things with
the older clones like fusarium and and
things that have been passed on from
from just backyard to tent grower to
indoor grower and back again be honest
we were not testing for fungus and
bacteria we were looking at viruses that
was our Focus yeah
y y yeah I think the uh the key here is
like if you look at how these other
Industries manage this risk like
strawberries right um you know in the
strawberry business like they know that
you know the use of meristematic tissue
culture removes uh
99.999% of any of these risks viruses
bacteria Etc and uh you know yeah
they're like studying the viruses of
course you know there's millions of
dollars that goes into that however
you know really from the production side
um you know they're like the dris and
stuff you know they're not wasting their
time right because they know that the
technique removes all that stuff and
yeah on a very rare occasion something
slips through it um so I mean you know
of course they're trying to understand
these things but you know the key
backbone of all this is that when you
look across all of these other crops
that have gone through this process you
know that's the statistical reality is
if you do the process correctly um
you're going to remove everything right
so you know it might be another 20 years
before we really understand all of these
viruses that are in cannabis and
absolutely they're there and you know
the majority of them may well be
completely benign and we're in really
really early days to be able to
understand that and I would use huge
caution in trusting the data coming from
any lab on these virus assays like you
know our uh you know our chief science
officer is a PhD virologist 30 years he
taught epidemiology at UBC and uh you
know his take on this is basically like
you know for us even at SRA it's going
to take us probably another two years to
have our first virus assays out you know
really trying to do it the right way and
we're talking like you know millions of
dollars of of research money that's
being designated to get to that goal so
you know it's uh it's it's a very um uh
tricky issue right now because we really
don't have the analytical tools and and
uh you know several of these labs are
appear to really be kind of running wild
with this testing I mean like in
California now the whole um hop late and
virro deal here you know there's several
Labs offering it and um you know we've
been doing our due diligence like
interviewing these Labs trying to see if
we can find a partner anywhere in the
world to do this testing and we haven't
found anybody yet that we feel like has
really uh has a validated process for
looking at them so um but I think the
key for all of us in the near term is
like we do know like from looking at
these other crops we have a technology
that statistically should remove all of
those things um but no we don't have you
know the ability to do all of that
testing like you know when things leave
our door we go through our list of six
you know we've got these six uh
pathogens we can test for now and then
obviously you know we're doing
microscopy and you know everything that
we can um but yeah it's really early
days um still in uh have incredible you
know virus detection at scale for for
this business it may be the early days
but at the same time it is the future if
you look at uh uh wine Growers so when
they plant a new field of grape
varieties you better believe they're all
certified virus free because they don't
use anything else it is the future yeah
and who you know who's developing most
of those cultivars right it's University
Systems you know and and they've got you
know yeah like UC Davis you know they
got hundreds of millions of dollars that
goes into you know developing these
lines and developing the processes and
you know so you know I think as as you
start seeing like you know the big uh
you know a institutional universities in
the country in the world start to
descend on this you know we're going to
get answers a lot faster but you know
right now relying on you know like small
companies like CRA and you know private
small labs to like figure this out like
you know none of us have the budgets to
be able to really um to really do it you
know did you say there did you say
there's only 27 viruses that have been
isolated at this time well so I
I what did you say David I don't I don't
have a I don't have a number on that I
think you threw a number out there
uh i' I've found 27 viruses that have
been identified in cannabis uh more than
half of them do not have any symptoms
but there's some controversy whether or
not if you have 10 of those non-symptom
viruses then collectively they may start
to show uh symptoms and are these listed
in the hemp viruses and diseases book or
are these unclassified at this
no maybe maybe half of them are there
the other ones uh I've collected uh and
uh been in contact with viral
researchers and AD them one by one by
one by one until now the total is
27 so I have a question you I've seen a
good bit at scale in terms of viral um
decline in a in a plant's health and and
specifically when it when it goes from
Veg into flower you you see the you see
the transformation happen um I've
documented with with photos and and I've
done this over the past few years and my
question is is is from you know a couple
of these things I've kept just to just
in hopes that I could bring them into a
tissue culture environment and kind of
clean them and bring them back to quote
unquote life and I guess the real
question is is you know that hope and
that dream to bring that specific
variety back Is that real in terms of
what you were talking about when you
bring it in to clean it are you going to
come out with genetic drift and how real
is that um and what does that look like
for someone like myself that wants to
save things and kind of preserve and and
keep things it's not that everything is
has been like that it's just there's two
or three varieties that I've noticed
that just don't perform the same way and
you can clearly see it through photos
yeah you just got to get them into the
into the tissue culture process right I
mean it's like we can't you know we
can't answer those questions yet of
exactly what's uh you know what's there
or what's not right and uh um but it's
really kind of unimportant it's like
remove the stuff and you know let's see
what happens with the plant I mean some
of these plants like uh you know we did
uh over the last year and a half we've
done trials with four of the big LPS
where we built the TC lab in their
facility we grew their strains we
flowered the Clones next to the TC
plants like 18 months later right right
and uh I mean in some of those examples
some of those examples the plants came
out and they don't even look like the
same strain like there was one that was
like a was like a um you know narrow
Leaf indicia uh you know seven years ago
and the plants that we initiated looked
like a long leaf sativa and after we
removed whatever we did I don't know
what we removed plants look totally
different they looked and the grower was
like holy [ __ ] like he showed me a
picture he's like dude look at this
plant from you know six years ago that's
what it looked like right interesting
you know so it's the the effect of all
of this on the plane you know is is Far
and Beyond you know potentially just
like slowing it down or you know you
know having little little differences
you know it can be it can be drastic now
that's an extreme example I'm giving you
you know most of the plants you know
what I see are extreme examples like I I
could I should send you some photos I
mean they're extreme you see the even
the inter internal lanks are just it's
insane I mean you you're you're looking
at very different completely different
plants
almost so
y um well cool that's that's that's
really good
information
[Music]
um so are we at the point where you
think we can replace mother rooms and
and put them into uh
you know with a with the trained
operator to really run uh your varieties
over and over like you're saying with
micro propagation or or are we still in
that in between stage where we're still
learning um what the best path forward
is yeah I think uh you know I think
we're we're still kind of in the middle
of that right now you know like at at S
I mean we're doing it you know we're
we're now producing plants at scale we
shipped out orders this year up to
40,000 in a single order um you know so
it's happening um the um you know the
real challenge well a couple things you
know is um cultivars you know they don't
all perform the same in tissue culture
there's some uh that you know really
seem to slip right in there and be very
happy and there's others that aren't
right they don't multiply as easily um
you know and so you know like I said you
know we've got about 250 cultivars that
we've put through the process you know
and out of that there's about 30 now you
know that we feel really confident you
know in our ability to consistently
produce them and and the acclamation you
know to know how to bring them out right
because you'll see you'll see a lot of
these plants they come out looking like
Chia Pets or you know kind of crazy you
know and uh you know that's that's again
the whole Talent of like how do you make
that transition really smooth you know
as you're coming out of the process and
and you know that's something that takes
years years of of uh of Trials and and
so you know there's really kind of a
like at this point in the in the
evolution of tissue culture for cannabis
at least for us you know it's really
kind of a phenotyping process that we go
through again right with the plant where
it's like you give me your thing that's
got everything you like and you know I
put it in TC and you know it's going to
take us some time to figure out how to
work with it in that environment you
know and we've got some Cult of ours
that we're just like that one's going on
the Shelf like we're you know we could
maybe spend a bunch of time and energy
working with it and figuring it out but
it's you know at this point in the game
we can't you know we're trying to just
focus on going with what we have um so
the uh you know I think the the
integration into like production the
thing that's been really interesting is
um that you know these TC plants you
know there's this term called like a
signal curve right so like when you look
at the growth of a of a cannabis plant
you you know it kind of exponentially
starts growing faster and producing more
biomass as it as it gains momentum and
gains size um and uh you know what we've
noticed with the TC plants is you know
for the first uh two to three weeks of
their life they grow they do grow way
slower than a clone word right so you
know essentially if you're going to do
this you really are adding about two
weeks of time two to three weeks of time
into the overall growth cycle of that PL
right so that sounds like a bad thing
right it's like wait a minute I got to
grow that plant for another three weeks
right that's time and money and
resources Etc you know however you know
what we're what we're tending to do now
is you know our product is um if you
look on our website you know we call
them a micr plug where they're tiny you
know they're um they're uh instead of a
a 50 cell tray of clones you know
there's 200 in that same spacing right
um and you know most of our clients are
taking those and then they're putting
them into a 50 cell tray right and
putting them on a rack for two weeks so
like yeah it's taking an extra two weeks
but it's at on a vertical rack using
almost no square footage and very little
lighting you know so yeah you know
little energy what you get in the
tradeoff is you get a plant that's
consistent and clean right but yeah it
does have that extra workflow um so you
know there's a lot of complaints around
oh that you know the TC plants grow you
know too slowly they take too long and
yeah they do take a little longer and
like let's say you're doing a you know
an ultra highdensity indoor where you
only veg for two weeks right right yeah
that's like you know uh that's a
challenge because you know it's it's
going to take longer you know our little
plants grow so slowly in that in that
first phase so you know that's uh you
know one of the challenges like you know
the two real big challenges that we're
trying to manage are you know getting
that consistent growth coming out of
acclamation and then you know keeping
our eyes on this whole mutation
risk essentially Ian there was a
question in the chat it was about
viruses and they said are the viruses
airborne and as far as I know they're
spread by tools by people and by insects
with direct contact yep the only place I
think there could be an Airborne risk is
um is uh in uh you know post Harvest
processing like if you're grinding up uh
you know lots of fresh Mater you know if
you're literally grinding material and
putting it in the air yeah you could
have you know but it's particles flying
around in the air it's not like you know
necessarily just you know like like us
with co co of like breathing bacteria
you know it's not going to just breathe
off the off the stomas of the plants
right so yeah tools you know and I mean
like you see uh you know down here in
California like guys that I know down
here that are getting more sophisticated
yeah they've got systems now where like
every employee is sanitizing all of
their tools between plants um you know
and that's sanitization is an enormous
deal like cloning you know like if you
are doing cloning like you should be
doing it in like a laboratory type
environment you know like you should be
doing everything you can you know like I
mean I'm guilty over the years you know
it's like you just start getting used to
it and you know 's an old cutting board
and some razor blade or whatever you
know like the use of you know peroxide
and uh
and uh uh what's the stuff in cleanse is
it calcium hypoc what do they call it
stuff hypoc chlorate um there's this
other substance hyp chlorus acid yeah
hypoc chloris acid you know you should
be using these tools you know to to make
the absolute cleanest plant that you
possibly can like you know just going
into the grow room with your dirty hands
and your dirty scissors and and your
tray and chopping away like you know
you're asking for trouble so you know
definitely cleaning up that workflow can
make you know enormous uh you know
differences in your ability to manage
manage the problem um you know but the
uh you know the real solution will be a
concert of these things right it's like
moving to a real clean stock kind of
starting material like TC you know and
then also you know amping up the the
hygiene you know like like when you go
in the big uh tomato green houses you
know those guys have uh in a couple of
them I've seen these things like I
haven't seen the product yet in can in
in productize they make them themselves
where like when they squeeze their Tri
their scissors on the
plants it like shoots out a little bit
of this sanitizing liquid right onto the
blade of the scissors you know and
they've got a little like pouch of their
of their uh you know little sanitizer
stuff that they're actually like using
out in the garden I've seen that in a
couple of these big million square foot
green houses and like they both made
them themselves I'm curious if anybody's
ever seen a product like that like I've
searched around for one and I may find
one but uh but yeah you the closest I've
seen in is uh where people use a tool
for one plant whether it's one chop or
100 chops on that plant and then they
put the tool in a jar of a disinfectant
of some sort and uh use a different tool
and leave them soaking in there a half
an hour or so then they can reuse them
yeah it sounds like fun
right it's like you're on the greenhouse
with 100,000 plants trying to use clean
tools on every plant so you know but
it's it it will definitely make you know
all the sanit sanitization efforts like
really do really do it also it depends
how big your plants are my mother plants
used to be 15 feet tall I could easily
get thousands of clones from one mother
then change a tool yeah yeah so most of
these viruses and bacteria come through
the cut part of a plant they're not
being uh transferred between each plant
as they touch each other they basically
get stored in the plant because of how
it's
propagated well you're you know the cut
is um you know just creating an open
wound site I mean you know you think
about in a greenhouse or a Grove like
the amount of bacteria flying around in
the air in there you know of thousands
and thousands of species so yeah it's
really that you know that cutting
process so you know like again when
you're making your moms you know using
sanitized tools you know if you're
making really big cuts on a plant you
know using something uh you know any of
these tree tree wound type substances
you know to to cover up that big wound
you know it's like you wouldn't walk
around with a huge cut on your arm like
you're going to put something over it to
to keep things clean you know um and uh
and you know I uh like anecdotally you
know these these risks really from what
I've seen so far seem to be much higher
with people over running soil based
systems unfortunately you know I mean
I'm a big Organics guy myself but gosh
you know when you got soil in that room
and you know all the biology that comes
in with that you know is uh is just
another you know another another
variable right you know however you know
a lot of those organisms may be really
good at keeping your plant clean too you
know all the good guys so it's it's a
it's a game of roulette right so
beneficial versus is non beneficial
right who wins yep
exactly
awesome I think the real key with it is
that we want to you know support
ecosystems that promote beneficial
organisms you know the the the
microbacteria within the soil that are
going to feed the plants but while at
the same time creating a sterile you
know propagation line that that way that
you know each time time we propagate
that uh
clone it comes out more sterile than the
than the previous time and then you know
it's just a matter of as as you see
those bad you know whether bad insects
or bad microbes show up there's there's
generally a a bigger insect or microb
that'll eat
them um you just have to you know
there's for example lactobacillus eating
uh mil some of the
Milos but the you know I with the rules
and regulations around cannabis you have
to you know start from as clean of a
cutting as possible just to minimize
that contamination when you're re
restarting rooms or or green
houses Ian I want to say one thing and
that was that uh many viruses can be
transmitted by both seeds and
pollen
absolutely so I don't know about
bacteria and uh
guy but uh viruses I would say the
majority of them can be
transported uh in SE
and that's a that's a a key comment
right there I mean it's like if you look
at um crops like pasas right you know um
you know they are produced through
tissue culture um they're also you know
they're a prolific seed producing plant
right it's like and why they're still
done through TC is because the virus
issues where you know they carry right
through the seed and uh you know you
wouldn't have today like a global viable
um you know papaya industry without the
ability to control and and manage the uh
the virus right um hold on just one sec
guys be right
back I was just going to say on the um
the reason I was so quick to pop on on
the hypochlorous acid is because I I
bought this machine about a year ago
that makes hypochlorous acid water for
me um it's kind of a weird deal and um
it's expensive the the brand that I
bought it's not really for Farm use but
I think there's there's some models out
there that are for Farm use and they
basically electroly and use salt water
to make a a sterile low PH
2.5 elect electrolyzed water and um I
got it as as it was sold as an IPM deal
like I could spray the low ph
to kill insects and then spray the
extremely high pH to kill pathogens um
and it's it's been all right we working
for me you know to be honest I haven't
used it as much for that but what I have
used it for and it's really up my game
and in in taking my cuts and and all my
tools because I just push this [ __ ]
button and out comes this W it's it's
sterile but it's not bleach it does not
toxic like I don't mind being being on
me or spilling or whatever using
excessive amounts because I have this
machine I just push the but button and
out it comes and so I use it all over
the place and it's really stepped my
game up in in my sterility you know
because I am an organic guy and there's
a lot of lot of stuff floating around
and then the other comment on that is
just like being being smart you know yes
things compost yes there's a bigger guy
to eat something but you know there's a
time and a place for that and I I I
leave the composting for the compost
pile and try to keep you know things
pretty as clean as I can given the fact
that I have a really you know tons of
plants growing in there that are not
just cannabis there all sorts of
[ __ ] but my what for what about another
uh thing I wanted to talk about in
regards to you know what you guys are
doing with tissue culture is is the lab
work and the potential future of being
able to use I guess genetic
identification like being able to see
the gene synthesis find them in a way I
know we're not quite there yet but C can
you talk a little bit about that if you
have any idea what I'm actually talking
about
uh I mean anything about the breeding
side
yeah yeah so I mean it's yeah like at
you know at SRA like I mentioned we've
got two different businesses really
there's the tissue culture operation led
by this guy Dr zide and then we have a
separate facility that's really run like
a different business um that's our
molecular biology lab run by this guy Dr
John brunstein and uh you know they're
very intentionally in two different
places um you know like at the
genotyping lab we've got permits there
to um possess and uh do testing with all
these controlled pathogens uh so like
obviously we want that to be in a
different place so um so you know in
that in that division of the of the
company you know we are working on
developing um a bunch of different
genomics tools that should lead us
towards the ability to start doing um
marker assisted
breeding um and uh you know there's for
us there's a there's a couple things I'd
mention here where you know the first
genotyping test we developed is called
this v&amp; test um and b&amp; is what's used in
essentially every forensics lab in the
world right and b&amp; has been established
to do to be able to tell like is the
blood on the table your blood and uh you
know if so you're going to prison for
life right so um and it's you know used
in all of these forensics labs around
the world so they have you know a
standardized test to be able to do this
fingerprinting and everybody uses the
same thing right wouldn't that be nice
in cannabis so you know so we developed
that test where like if you give me a
plant sample right two you give me two
leaves I can test the two of them and I
can tell you like a fingerprint if
they're the same or not right if they
have the same fingerprint but I can't
tell any of the trait information I
can't tell you know if that plant's
going to be tall or short or high THC or
low THC like you know that vntr looks at
12 markers uh which is like we found
statistically to be just enough for us
to be able to you know with an extremely
high level of certainty guarantee two
things are the same or not right um but
like the key there is you know as we're
collaborating with other organizations
right you can give us your germ plasm
and you know that's the only kind of
genotype test we would do on that plant
right it's in our contract it says we'll
do a vntr and that's just so we can
guarantee that we're not mixing things
up and that when we ship it out we b&amp; it
make sure it's exactly what it's
supposed to be um uh but then you know
behind the scenes we're developing um
other genomics tests that are really
going to be useful for plant breeding
and um you know the the whole kind of
genomics world of late has really been
chasing this alumina testing like you'll
hear you know phus bioscience does you
know and that's like extremely high
resolution testing it's really really
expensive and uh we've been developing
tools it's kind of like um like that's
like a digital recording you know versus
um um uh you know the um I lost my train
of thought there yeah the the you know
the really high resolution testing like
um alumina is like looking at a digital
recording whereas like the v&amp; is kind of
like a cassette tape right it's much
lower resolution um and uh but it's way
cheaper right right we can run these v&amp;
tests for super cheap so you know we're
working on developing tests that are
kind of between alumina and um vntr that
are like stepping stones to getting you
to those to to using the um the higher
resolution test like a um like the
alumina alumina test so you know the
whole like World here of being able to
identify high value markers um and
utilize those markers actively in a
breeding program
um you know is still very much in its
infancy like we figure we're probably
about another you know two to three
years out from being able to apply these
Technologies to actually utilizing
marker assisted breeding and you know
I'm sure some of these big LPS are are
making some moves there um but uh it's
going to take quite a while to uh for
those like you say it's not it's not so
simple Ian because some markers for
example for a particular canal anoid or
for a particular tpine that that you can
see relatively easy but what you can't
see is how much is the plant going to
express under optimal conditions in
other words is it going to produce a
whole lot of CBC or practically none but
nobody's really got their hands around
that yet and here's another question if
they do see that synthes can they tell
if it will be on or off
not with certainty
yet yeah it's it's you know I think all
of this is uh you know we're in uh we're
in h The Dugout here we're not even in
the first inning you know with um the
application of you know molecular
breeding tools for for cannabis and I
think it's you know like a big part of
this is like you know really like the
University Systems like once they start
getting in and and sinking their budgets
into this stuff it's going to start
really really rolling a lot faster um
you know because like on the private
sector you know the companies that
really have the tech you know they're
not in cannabis yet you know they're not
they're not here so you know there's you
know small companies like ours that are
you know chipping away at the bigger
picture but you know I think the uh you
know the big boys will be coming in here
at some
point it they they know it from many
other commercial crops much better than
cannabis but
they have scratch of surface you know
they can find syntheses and tpes and
other uh markers but uh the ones that
they really need for Vigor for
resistance those are the ones that uh
are going to really change the
industry yep you're
right so all right I um I apologize I'm
gonna have to jump off here fellas I got
to go something here at 10:30 um dude
thanks for throwing it down well it's a
good start we uh I mentioned you Marcus
we're doing this webinar on Thursday um
uh with Dr zabid is doing um the ABCs of
PTC on Thursday afternoon and if any of
you guys want to learn more um that's
going to be an awesome opportunity we'll
have an hour he's going to go through a
deck that like goes through you know all
the different Technologies and um and
then we're going to have a Q&amp;A and we're
going to try and start doing those like
once a month or something like that
different related webinars so we're
getting on the webinar train and if any
you guys want to join us it's free it's
on Thursday you can register on our uh
on our Pages I'll put your website up in
the comments in the description of this
video so people will see it and be able
to click on it and go right to
registering yep sounds good I'm gonna
come check it out as well dude thanks so
much for finally making it on to Hash
Church dude that was awesome throw down
yeah and heads up we're going to be in
we're going to be in the starting to
operate in California this year working
on that right now so we've been come see
us yeah yeah we're getting we're we're
making the move I live are are you in
California yeah I'm in Berkeley so come
see us when if you're in Northern
California you know I'd love to give you
a tour of Berkeley patience group just
turned 21 I live in Auburn up by
Sacramento so so yeah I'm in the hood
for sure so great to connect i' love you
should definitely go see atan yeah let's
do it love to absolutely you will be
very happy that you did I can
promise I'll take that awesome man all
right you guys hey everybody have a
great Sunday and uh love to all your
families and be safe and we'll talk to
you later thanks brother have a good
one well I felt like uh that was some
pretty good information nice little
conversation for about an hour there on
tissue culture and hopefully I'll be
able to get Ian back here one day
because he is a wealth of information
when it comes to this
stuff that was fascinating I I love
asking questions when I can understand
what's
[Music]
going let me tell you it is the future
of cannabis breeding and mass production
that's the way they do strawberries
that's the way they do grapes it's the
future well if we're going to have our
Costco ounces yeah no doubt it has to be
that way you know if it's going to be
propagated nationally in a way that is
consistent so I can get my same OG kush
here is the same OG Kush on the East
Coast without any issues you know what
I'm saying or congales or whatever
genetic that's still the issue and still
the problem so every grower manufacturer
producers dealing with this problem of
how to propagate safely their genetics
and it's one I had problems with when I
was working with Ed because we
definitely Ed Rosenthal went because we
were definitely not in a sterilized room
and environment and we had you know
certain problems that just inadvertently
happen and to know that this type of
research is out there that they're
calling and pulling out these viruses
and bacteria and that there's actually
methodologies that are sound that can be
doing so I can't see why any type of
large company isn't looking for these
type of propagator so people are
watching they gave you the university in
Japan to go to and learn this this a lot
of we need a lot of
you big growers in the future when they
have a choice will take the safe road
you know the clean Road I love it as an
opportunity for small Growers I love
cannabis to get to a point where you
could just open up the computer and be
like I'm going to order up some of these
uh different cultivars that I hear them
talking about on hash church and and
then knowing with like it's it's amazing
to me how many people in the chat were
kind of tripping they were like oh
they're hacking plants they're this is
some scientific GMO [ __ ] I'm like no no
no he's literally telling you this is
the opposite of that he's not doing that
he's taking fingerprints and and marking
a plant so that if you order it he can
give you a guarantee and out of a lab
that that's actually been validated
which is not a cheap thing to do it
takes a couple years and it's millions
of dollars to validate a lab I know they
did yeah to do with DMO it has nothing
to do it's actually cloning that's the
first thing Ian ever told me about Dr
schile he said he's as much a farmer as
he is a scientist and he has to be an
equal of both for this world to exist
this is not callous tissue culture this
is Meemic and to think that you could
order micr plugs of safe genetics holy
my God right dude what a huge advantage
to give that's the true gift for a
patient in my opinion like if patience
could be ordering clean plants do you
know what a listen let's all be honest
it's not as easy as people sometimes say
it is to grow cannabis it's a lot of
attention it's like having a bloody
puppy dog you got to take care of this
thing or it's it's going to die like you
really have to take care of it and so to
be able to order clean plantlets and
have that sort of Advantage right from
the beginning rather than get like mited
aphed out pests ridden bacteria loaded
virus and fungi the whole nine yards and
then you're supposed to Crow something
with that you're like oh I got like 26
grams it's like come on man they need
the advantage we all do it's also that
way with seeds Marcus you buy seeds in
the hope that they're going to give you
what the breeder has promised and that
may or may not be the case you may get
one with 10 different phenotypes in each
seed batch and a virus in that
seed yeah who knows also yeah I didn't
even want to get into that or how many
of those 27 potentially are in that
seed oh that's what I'm saying I think
it's great for initiation I love it as a
service can you imagine if there was
just a facility one day where you can
just bring your dirty ass nasty infested
[ __ ] plant pay a fee and in like 6
months just like return back and be like
have the chance to a put it into the
library you know especially if they
fingerprint it and it's nothing they've
ever seen it's not a part of anything
they connect it to you now you somehow
are making something off that plant and
you you give it to them to to let the
rest of the world have access to it or
you give it to them only to hold just
for you whatever your mentality is I
just like the idea of being able to
clean the plants make them available to
people uh I certainly wouldn't like it
if it just got locked into like giant
universities and it was like oh no no
random no regular people could access it
or you could only buy the product I mean
so be it that's still probably going to
happen but I like the idea of it being
available to everyone that to me is a
successful successful business model it
would be nice if it was a little faster
like a car wash you know 24 hour
yeah that would that's uh that's the
super uer duper future you're you're
living in there or even the super duper
future of you could actually test that
seed to find out what viruses are
actually inside there you have to grow
the plant out currently right uh Sam to
actually you can test seed Embry it's no
problem you can do the seed okay
yes course that destroys the seed then
you know I have that sea right whereas
with a little plantlet you just need a a
punch of of a
leaf need the Home
unit need a home unit Johnny I need a
home
unit I saw you going in your garden and
looking at your garden like yeah that
ain't
sterile oh [ __ ] I'm just like I got like
I got plants everywhere I got like yeah
I'm just yeah doing different feeding
different grow meeting seeing what's
taking what under what LEDs and what's
feeding better and seeing what's yeah
I'm just having fun and having for
months
so yeah but there's nothing sterile here
at all zero right so I'm just kind of
looking around go you know that's my own
research Johnny I've had a greenhouse
for uh 30 years it was never sterile if
it would have the plants wouldn't have
grown as good
yeah it's
definitely a lot of fun looking at how
he's doing I mean I did some of those
first grows with Segar I got the strains
right here remember that Mark so I
remember that first tissue culture one
and just thinking about that I'm just
thinking how he's able to kind of keep
those strains alive and at the same time
just like you say disease bug free
everything that comes to your freshia
curious after like 15 years of having
the strain I mean what what where the
problems lie where I have the tops of
buds just dying and just little things
with different I look at my plants and
kind of Wonder now
so I'm sure it uh it would be quite
different if uh you got it all cleaned
up and
initiated yeah I'd love a mechanic shop
where I could take my plant in will you
please pull this [ __ ] out okay boom yeah
like you said earlier can you imagine
that you know clean your genetics
somebody would make a killing off of
clean your genetics company I mean but
that would take decade to even just get
up not only clean your genetics but
imagine taking a plant or a Seedling or
a leaf or whatever it is that they need
they examine the DNA and they say well
this plant has the ability to produce uh
medium large amounts of DC medium large
amounts of XYZ and they know not only
which compounds they have the ability to
produce but in what sort of ratios and
amounts that will be the
future yeah it'll be interesting to see
anyway I like the idea of clean genetics
I feel a lot of Growers you know are
would
would probably instantaneously take the
credit but uh they're taking the you
know the grief when they're growing
these plants that are just unable to
express themselves even with fairly
decent Growers you know you get plants
that are sick enough and it's uh once
they're sick do you not agree Sam that
they tend to um attack attract pests
like it's like these little insects like
just see that they're weak of course
because they uh their resistance is down
it's either dialed down or it just
doesn't exist anymore those bugs see
that in some
way so
yeah everybody would prefer to have the
best not only the variety they want but
expresses the smells and effects and
taste and can avoids they want but
they'd like the plant to be dependable
so it doesn't have health problems when
you treated it in the normal way you
treat plants successfully
yeah true enough true
enough well that's uh it's a lot to uh
take in today Ian was uh going off on a
pretty high level of uh of tissue
culture my brain's mush man after that
I'm just like I
have right in my head going
man oh me too I'm
you
what you love science you don't just
like science you passionately love
science in a way that porn producers
could never get the pictures
of uh absolutely true I science is
almost a religion to me but I'm not a
particularly religious
person but your perpetuation of Sciences
help propagate generations of genetics
that we wouldn't have known or had
otherwise so thank you for your uh
science nerdness and willingness to you
know go there because you know you've
you you made your mistakes early on to
realize I mean I would assume that you
realize early on that science was your
friend and not your
enemy yeah I mean and I I can honestly
say that because most of my life I've
been doing research and development
that I often learn more from
mistakes than uh I mean I I definitely
have made more mistakes than uh
successes but you learn a lot when you
remember don't do this and
intellectually you may know it but when
you do do it then you don't do it
again that's the key don't do it again
when it's
would they say Einstein made like over a
thousand mistakes before he invented the
light bulb or something or there's all
these things if you don't make mistakes
you're not learning you're not moving
forward you're not growing forward you
gotta make
mistar did you just say Einstein
invented the light bulb no I said that
wrong I'm high I'm completely that was
awesome that was like a Johnny B quote
I'm going back and that's going to be
that is going to be the I I was going to
use one of Ian's little audio bits for
the podcast but now it absolutely has to
be glasses just broke dude that was
amazing did you just say Einstein yeah
know that was
wrong good J that's awesome dude I love
you Johnny B what are you smoking Johnny
B because that's some good [ __ ] I'm medy
Kush um it's uh
it's it's been hanging for 30 days it's
just perfect and it's getting me super
stoned especially for breast breakfast
and I'm like on like number like five or
six plus I'm smoking the hash the bubble
I'm doing dabs at the Congo what a great
day this is hang out on Sunday
right yeah absolutely dude totally
agreed I had to bounce some dude from
the chat he just kept saying the most
ridiculous [ __ ] he's threatened by our
conversation remember I talked about
those
little
um yeah you did I do I remember I guess
I got bags of these and I'm gonna be
sending these out to certain people so
you guys know who you are please send me
your uh mailing address I can send these
out to you Ed Chan and everybody else
involved with hash Church anybody wants
and uh knows his very well please
contact me so um I'm definitely little
momentums of a good friend of ours right
so thanks thanks Johnny
B I guess I don't know if you guys want
to chat for another half an hour I'm I'm
down with making it a couple hours but I
did just plan for a really short hash
church this morning because it was such
last minute if you guys had things you
wanted to discuss I'm absolutely down
we've polarized the chat pretty good or
maybe it was just one guy I had to
bounce from the chat because he was uh
seemingly upset uh about our
conversation about tissue culture he he
suggested that we were going to be
creating the technology and giving it to
the Sharks to rape us I feel that uh
some people are not puffing on very good
herbs these days and I know that people
are stressful and uh or stressed out due
to uh you know this whole weird mind
control thing everyone's going through
it's like any other tool Marcus it can
be used for good or for evil let's be
honest yeah of course I just try to keep
it good I'm trying you know it's just
Sunday morning I want everyone to have a
good day and enjoy each other's Vibes
and not not give audience to you know
because we worked hard for for this
audience and it's if when I see people
being negative in the chat I feel like
you know what there's just uh you got to
go create your own audience for that if
you want to be here and enjoy and you
know spend your time and share then
everyone's welcome but if you're going
to be negative you gota gotta go one do
B
rip one
last for the
hour one last bong rip for the hour did
we lose Joshua did he bounce is he still
here oh yeah he's
there he's there he was uh going to get
in touch with Kevin JRE and see if he
want yeah I sent him I sent him a
message um I'm just here actually I'm
sterilizing my cloners as
we was on my list today which I have I
have four you know big clone or water
cloners and it was on my list today and
like there is a lazy part inside me
still you guys guys and there you know I
had this voice of this this guy ringing
in my head he's like oh I just [ __ ]
put a little bleach in there run him and
and go again and I I actually work him
down and scrub them really hard and it
takes me almost all day to clean my four
cloners and uh so he said that I was
like damn it rord like do your thing
clean that [ __ ] up proper so I just
started that's awesome
dude yeah sorry I'm just torching a bowl
and probably nobody wants to hear the uh
torch
I'm WR no I love the conversation I'll
I'll just hop in like I'm always
thinking from uh you know I long time
ago realized the food system and
realized cannabis is going that way and
it's taken a lot longer than I thought
it would take but I'm okay with it like
I'm okay with the folks that want to
[ __ ] us not not really that but I just
I'm okay that they exist and that's
going to happen and it's a reality and
there there's going to be B big Mega
cannabis and it's going to have a lot of
bad impacts but it's also going to have
a lot of good impacts it's going to have
accessibility there's this whole mixed
box but I look at like my place and our
place in it and and it's always like we
say the smaller thing and so you know
yeah let let them tissue culture their
triploid you know [ __ ] sour dub that
comes in at like 67% you know total
cannaboids and blows everyone out of the
water that's going to be here in a
couple years and that's going to be in
production and what we have is something
a lot more unique that that cannot be
produced you know with our our you know
terara if you will you know whether it's
regional individual the way we cultivate
Etc you know just and then and then
thinking how does tissue culture play
into that into my like craft breeding
program because there's no way I'm going
to compete in my breeding with these
these Mega Cult of ours so I have to
focus on doing something that's unique
and and that's some might want to you
know smoke because they they care about
it a little bit more rather than buying
the Costco weed you know and yeah so
it's just really interesting thinking
like yeah maybe I need to figure this
out on on a small scale and set up a
small little sterile room so I can be
running batches this way and breeding
larger batches like I don't know it just
really I mean just having the ability to
initiate your plants would be incredible
if you just have a little closet area
where you're like I'm just going to
clean my plants and you clean them and
you plant them and start growing them I
mean I saw some of the plants before you
breed with it like you're like hey I'm
going to I'm going to set off this room
for laal and I've got everyone lined up
what I'm going to do let's sterilize it
all and then breed with that clean and
you'll make the best seed
right sorry I didn't mean to just run
over you
there oh no problem I'm also listen
trying to talk to a dude in chat who's
asking me something about like
pgs he's like he can only get like three
and four star from p EGS I'm like well
no [ __ ] like so so your consideration
then is going towards something that's
more Artisan specific Artisan specific
genetics you know is that what you're
considering that's kind of what I was
saying yeah Artisan specific you know
unique the old stuff the stuff that
doesn't work on mass scale which is what
I was doing when I took a break and did
tomato farming I was growing these
heirlooms that no company can grow
because they can't ship and whatever so
if I grow them in regionally and support
just the local industry and I can drop
off my heirlooms on Friday that they're
going to cut up that afternoon and serve
Friday and Saturday night it worked and
I could get a high dollar so this is my
whole like you know I I I took a break
from Cannabis and learned all this by
reading organic agriculture books and
how to like you know do all the things
that we talk about take your product and
and stack the benefits by maybe make it
into something else and and be just
being an outlier and and and not you
know I don't know I just kind of gave in
like you guys won a long time ago you
won you got it you have big business
you're going to take
cannabis where I love cannabis where can
I fit in this you know that's I don't
think they realize how cannabis is going
to affect them you know where you that
is the other Factor you're right that's
what people people should have faith in
cannabis because uh you know there's a
reason why they kept it at Bay for so
long and kept the 9 foot steel door shut
on cannabis for so long because even
deep down they have to know how deep
it's going to get into everyone's heads
whether they're wearing it or eating it
for health or taking different
cannabinoids that are different from THC
or straight dabbing or recreational
using or preventative using or you know
then the the Dozen new methods of using
that will pop up over the course of the
next 10 or 20 years as the science gets
deeper and the cultivars get you know
you know bred and created that have
higher contents of different
cannabinoids different ratios and I for
one looking forward to uh where we're
going with cannabis well look what they
did with wine I mean wine you know they
had bottles of wine and they realize
well just selling bottles of wine
doesn't work so maybe if we create an
area where people could come and taste
the wine okay so I could see many
Cottage or Artisan cannabis doing
exactly that model creating a nice area
a beautiful experience when people come
in from when they drive up to when they
walk in come sample the Cannabis here's
our smoke room our ingestion room and
create that Vibe and that's the way
they'll sell their genetics just the
same way as there's certain venters here
in California that only sell their wine
through a mailing list or through their
door like Visa tuille you'll never find
them on a store shelf but you'll go to
that Winery and pick up a couple of
cases because that shit's good and they
just produce enough just to sell that
way or through their mailing list so I
see that that model definitely becoming
Regional like in the Humbolt or mesino
some of the the terroirs have now been
set here in California I can see that
type of you know communal but as well as
for the Artisan himself to show your
wees such as you know here's you know
you could show a glass off you know wall
that shows the actual cannabis growing
etc etc so you know they could have the
experience of seeing it just like the
wines growing there at the you know at
the winery they get the whole experience
there in a regional situation you walk
in you you're buying outs you get a you
get a two grams of oil rosin you get 10
cuts and you go home and you get excited
for six months or down the road [ __ ]
I I hope you're right maybe you can call
the maybe you can call call me the
breeder and say hey what's going on with
me in July and I'm like oh hey you need
a compost tea I'll Brew you one up come
and pick it whatever like that is would
be the man I would I just cry just
dreaming of that you
know well I I I'm sure it's going to be
true not only that I would not be
surprised if Costco and Kmart also have
uh tasting rooms smoking rooms I mean
come on it's better for society The
Wider it spreads and you know some
people like Bud some people like you
know uh crap beer and
I I think there's room for
everybody yeah know the way it came in
through medical it doesn't seem like
they're going to be able to pull it away
I mean here in Canada we have it's very
easy to get a license you can grow your
own even if you don't have a license you
can grow four plants everyone in the
country that's over 19 can grow four
plants but um if you want you just go
get yourself a license and you can grow
30 or 50 or 100 or 200 you know well
within reason uh it's not very difficult
um you know because cannabis is so
effective for inflammation really
anything with inflammation can get you a
permit so I'm surprised no one's trying
to done it like Christmas tree places
where you can come buy a live Christmas
tree just go cut your tree that's a
nursery talking about that in Washington
but it's all the laws you know we've
been talking about that for patients
specifically in in Co it's kind of
gotten the legislators a little more
open to look at this and that was one of
the things like hey we can bring a plant
all the way to fruition and they didn't
they don't have to pay for the trimming
processing drying they can take it home
they can make it into oil whatever they
need to do um yeah you could have a
freezer on site they could flash freeze
it so it's transportable yeah I I've
been pushing this idea for for 10 20
years and I absolutely agree and uh
economically I think if you grew a
100,000 plants and you sold them for
$100 each for a plant that can
yield kilo or two uh after it's cleaned
and dried uh it's a lot of economic
sense but I think in California the laws
are in the way at this moment but we can
change laws oh we've we've established
that we didn't like 215 we changed that
and we don't like 64 so we'll change
that so if we just know what the
parameters are we'll faking fix it hell
yeah we did the same thing man we had
that uh the the amazing group The
Coalition that took on with John conro I
took on the federal government here and
just basically destroyed the federal
government and maintain the ability to
grow change governments and that's what
Coalition did the medical community got
together and fought for a cause and we
won that was awesome patients stood up
for their rights and we stand up more
for cannabis than we have and it's great
to see we need the rest of the world
legalized don't we we got to do this for
everybody exactly what's happening here
in Canada in different parts of the
[Music]
world access
is every person for any reason anywhere
in the
world I
10 amen
all right I'll talk what about these
amonita mushrooms behind me how sweet is
that saw those are those your house are
those local those are like literally in
the parking lot of my work yeah I have
those all over my yard these are they're
all over Richmond they're all over
Squamish which is both directions of my
from my house North and South they're
actually just fairly prolific in and
around
Vancouver I actually took some a couple
of
times and how did you like the amas
aren't you supposed to dry them and
smoke them isn't that the no you don't
have to smoke them mine were dried I had
collected them in Santa Cruz and uh it
gives you it's it's sort of a
dispersal drug and uh it it it it makes
you sort of take
Daydreams where you have uh
dreams that you can remember
hallucination dreams or whatever it's uh
yeah it it's not my idea of a good clean
psychedelic but uh there are people who
liked it I mean the ancient Vikings were
called Berserkers because they would eat
these and a funny thing about them is of
course that you could
take the urine from a reindeer that ate
them and cleaned out the impurities that
made you more sick if you can swallow
the reindeer piss and the Berserker
Vikings would pee into the bowls of
their servants who would eat it drink it
and and uh they actually had a better
trip than the Berserkers because the
mushrooms also have toxic chemicals
which are not passed along but the
Psychedelic is pretty much yeah the
psych the Psychedelic doesn't metabolize
in your liver it
it piss it out active it's
incredible
yeah if you going to harvest them it's
good to let dry them expose them to 130
de degrees so that 130 degrees will
break it Fahrenheit will break down the
hydren I believe is the poison that
causes the
nausea so Sam have you drank actual
reindeer
piss no I I had never seen that or a
Berserker piss but uh the uh I cannot
recommend these people uh it blurs your
vision it's not a true clear psychedelic
I I wouldn't be eating it I'll tell you
that much but I find them beautiful to
photograph and that's really why I share
reason they always remind me of Santa
Claus or maybe it's a
kabouter yeah well well why don't I
share my golden foots that's that's a
little bit uh we'll put the golden foots
up these I'm going to be making I'm
gonna bounce out you guys I wish I could
talk about mushrooms I'm getting really
excited about them but I got some folks
here but uh season I hope you're picking
I hope you're picking we are we are man
we're we're me and my son are into it
it's like a cool fun thing that we're
learning together on it it's so cool
we're both just like dude we got to talk
about it offline yeah cool man all right
have a good night good afternoon
everyone peace yeah thanks for coming in
Josh appreciate it
cheers yeah well that's good yeah these
are Edibles shantell's golden golden
sorry yellow foots they're going to go
into some cream of mushroom soup later
today M froze
up nope I saw Johnny move but at still
froze I'm moving I'm over here
I see
you think about my shirt I think and
it's my uh friend of mine made has his
brand you see him um uh he's all over
Vancouver back in the days and this is
my when I when I trim I wear my West
Coast CER shirt so it's kind of funny
West Coast croppers West Coast cers or
cwon thanks everyone for coming in today
I appreciate all of you I think uh I'm
maybe going to go pick more mushrooms
today there's edible mushrooms out there
and they're only going to be going for
so long before this the season is over
so I implore all of you to go for a hike
in the forest see if you can't even just
take some pictures of mushrooms and
check them out on the Google uh app with
the camera you can it can sometimes help
identify obviously don't eat anything if
you're not uh you know practicing
myologist but uh definitely check it out
it's worth going into the forest and
photographing all these mushrooms and if
you want to become a great part part of
a really great group uh on Facebook I'll
hit it up here real quick there's a
group called mushrooms wild and Mi uh
mysterious and then it says seminar with
Paul stamitz so I don't know if my phone
now it won't let me with the background
check out that Facebook group mushrooms
wild and mysterious seminar with pul
stamin you can photograph mushrooms in
and around your place put them up there
and there's incredible mounts of
myologist ideally if you're going to
photograph a mushroom for identification
you photograph under the gills as well
as the top and the side three good
photos and and to see what substrate
it's coming out of so don't cut the
mushroom off like at the top so you
can't see what it's actually coming out
of whether it's wood and rot or life or
you know all these different things that
mushrooms grow out of grass Etc [ __ ]
even for that matter but uh thank you f
font and skunkman Sam and Johnny B and
Mike West and thanks Josh um and uh
Colin who was here earlier and of course
uh Ian Davidson who came and gave us the
drop on tissue culture that was pretty
tight I've been wanting them to come on
for a long time so I was appreciating
that and really thanks guys for coming
in such a last minute and making a nice
conversation happen today I know that uh
the I don't know 443 people watching in
chat live right now I think they
appreciate appreciate the conversation
it was fairly polarized today um May the
full melt bless your bowl sooner than
later everybody and uh peace out for
now peace