e
can't
here yeah not
hey
Rob hey how you doing
yeah good to see you again hey Ethan how
are
you you very good we all hear each
other yeah can't hear you Marcus
Oh I thought I heard something there
yeah
yes aha gentlemen gentlemen gentlemen
apologies for the technical difficulties
a little bit of a little bit of a
problem
today make sure that we're live here
I am in Whistler British Columbia on my
laptop computer and it's not being quite
as generous as my home computer little
bit of technical difficulties but well I
can hear you guys now I just want to
make sure the YouTube Channel's
live um as the other chat room is not
really working for me I may need to get
one of you guys to help it says live
okay that's good that's good there
recording as well yeah I'm recording it
onto this computer so then I can put it
on to the
um podcast afterwards I just want to
make sure that I want to make sure the
people that were in the original room
are able to see this room now oh yeah
there we go we got people in the chat
room wonderful I think we're good
welcome everybody
welcome we got skunkman Sam in the room
Mr Robert conell Clark Dr Mark sheldone
and Dr Ethan Russo for a little special
impromptu Gathering uh to celebrate and
remember remember the life of rapael
mulam great uh great Israeli scientist
done some amazing work in our field and
I myself have only met him on a few
occasions but I'm sure some of the folks
in the room have some different stories
to tell as well as just people who have
studied his work and used his work like
Dr Mark over the years and I think we
are golden here gentlemen so welcome
first of all thank you all for showing
up on a Sunday well I'm sure it's not
Sunday morning for all you but on a
Sunday morning for at least a few of us
right Dr Ethan
cor a specific
coaster yes exactly exactly how was uh
your trip to Peru by the way well it's
actually Ecuador
umor yeah there was a very nice uh can
America conference in keto um for a
couple of days and then I spent a week
in the rainforest uh with my daughter
Sarah and um
uh my business partner Nisha Whitley and
a friend of hers so it was
great yeah it looked spectacular I saw
nisha's um photography so I saw a little
bit of the stuff you guys like staring
at giant snakes on the side of the on
the river banks and stuff it looked
pretty wild
right we got some folks in the room here
linking up with us to hear about rafie
today thanks for the idea by the way Dr
Mark I think uh it's crazy how hash
church has just turned into like
gathering for people that we have lost
in the last little while there's been a
lot of that sort of going on so I guess
uh I'll never forget skunkman Sam I
think he was probably in his 50s when he
told me this but he said more of my
friends are dying now than I'm making
friends and I was still like in my 30s
and thought well that's a weird
statement I can't imagine that but now
as I approach 50 at the end of the month
here March 3 first I'll be 50 years old
I have to say it's very accurate I um
seem to be losing more friends than I'm
making friends these days so I guess
that's the uh the way life goes
sometimes yeah well it goes for mentors
as well I don't have a lot left I'm
afraid at this
point no I can imagine that's uh yeah we
all you know if you're lucky you get
older and I say that because my father
passed away at a very young age he was
only 55 years old and his wife was only
49 years old and so um I hear people
complaining about getting older and
they're like oh this and that it's no
it's not a walk in the park anymore but
it's like but you're lucky if you're
getting older so try to remember that
out
there it's better than the alternative
right if you're not getting older you're
dead I mean I think so personally I
think that there's the random person
that doesn't think that but uh I like to
stay POS positive and think that uh yeah
it's good to stay it's good to stay on
the on the
upside how are you doing Rob it's been
so long how was your
birthday no I'm doing good I'll be uh
I'm gonna turn 70 in the beginning of
May
so last week there you go yeah you went
recently we're all around the same time
here so yeah spring kids
yeah life is good I'm I'm in Amsterdam
at the moment I'm here continuing to try
to move out of my apartment it's going
to happen this summer I suppose and I'm
all packed up pretty
much dude that's unbelievable your
apartment spot I moved in here um
exactly 30 years ago on this coming
April 1 and who gets the place I guess
my landlord gets it back I hope he's
happy with it he'll he'll get it and
remodel it it never be the ghetto that
it is ever
again well lots of good times in that
apartment I I'll miss that apartment
myself oh I've had a great bunch of
times here for sure I was shocked when I
read my lease few months ago I thought I
lived here for more than 20 years I said
to myself yeah I don't know put a number
on it I felt like 22 or three something
like that then I got the lease I holy
[ __ ] 29 years time flies when you're
having fun so yeah is unbelievable
that's just not something that really
exists that much in North America like
leasing a place for like 30 years that
you live in I mean I I leased house I I
leased in rented houses for 20 plus
years and it I was lucky if I got like
four years and I didn't have to move
again you know we were just constantly
forced into moving and uh yeah well
thought I was G to live in any one city
for this long I would have bought an
apartment I feel pretty stupid have
rented it for so long but I never really
thought I was going to stay here I just
never left I guess there's a difference
but yeah it uh I didn't consciously hang
here really but anyway that's how it
goes awesome I don't know what the
chat's doing for me right now but when I
punch anything into the chat no one
replies so it'll be a little bit rough
trying to communicate with the folks
that are watching right now it does say
that we have a couple
people in here watching
[Music]
just I think it's just the the speed of
my computer um I I guarantee it's on my
side not uh anything else but it's
unfortunate because I usually like to
pay attention to the chat and engage
with the people who are watching so we
can maybe you'll have to uh do that Dr
Mark yeah sure I I'll Rel anything I
think it's
pretty so I think I think it was 2014
maybe 2015 I don't know maybe Dr Ethan
would remember better than I would but
um for me the one and only real time
that I actually spent time with uh with
Rafi was at the international canabo
research um event in Liden Holland I I
went to the one in Leiden Holland I
can't remember the year was it 2018 or
2014 they do it in a different place
every year so it's uh kind of hard to
remember but that's where I got the
photo um that I used as the avatar for
this particular hash church and I just
uh I just approached him and you know
kind of gave my respects and said it was
really cool the work that he had done
and that uh had a small conversation
with him and uh managed to get that
photo and so obviously um his work was
profound in our in in what we do in in
everything that we do so it's uh I
thought it would be a good idea well
Mark really thought it would be a good
idea to gather and uh to join all the
fellows that are here I mean Sam and uh
Rob had hoard a farm for years and years
and years and I'm sure their paths must
have crossed with uh at least with
rafi's work I'm sure you probably met
him multiple times and I know you did as
well Dr Ethan Russo so maybe we could uh
you know tell tell some some stories of
how we how you guys met and some of the
interactions that you had over the years
and maybe how his work impacted the work
that uh that you guys would have
done and I'll try to get this YouTube
chat
going uh do you need somebody to lead
off yeah any any one of you guys are
welcome to to lead off it's super loose
you know okay I'd be happy to uh first I
appreciate this opportunity I think
possibly we should rename this hash
temple in his memory um but um I also
want a plug for um Shango Los and I
recorded an episode of shaping fire on
Friday and it's already posted as of
yesterday so shaping fire um if you look
for that um we've got about an hour and
20 minutes uh conversation back and
forth uh be supplemental to what we do
here today um so I knew of rafy's work
uh for many years before I actually met
him um you know I was already working in
the Cannabis space for three years when
I met him the same time I uh met uh Rob
and and David uh for the first time in
aapco in 1999 at the icrs
meeting so um we established a good
rapport pretty much immediately he
recognized uh my name as one that uh
could have been Israeli and uh turned
out he was born to a sapharic Jewish
Family in Sophia Bulgaria in
1930 my family came from nearby uh in
Macedonia a town called moner now called
Bola um so there was that also I was
getting a certain credibility by being a
physician in the space where it was
mainly bench scientists and renegades
like Rob and Dave um
so that was the composition of ICS then
but um we
certainly his work heavily influenced me
uh
additionally uh we work together quite
extensively at GW
Pharmaceuticals between uh 2003 and 2014
when I was senior medical advisor there
he was attending um the annual meetings
research meetings where um it was
decided uh what kind of work would be
done on the various phyto canabo whether
it be THC CBD a lot of the work on CBD
was initiated there mostly um among
European scientists um and uh I talled
it up the other day we were together at
one meeting or another icrs or the
International Association for
cannabinoid medicine meeting he was
heavily involved in clinical work um so
between those so we were together in 14
countries um and I was really fortunate
to be able to share many a meal with him
and his wonderful wife Dalia um so it
was a a close
relationship of course they have stories
um one of my favorites was somewhere
around
2008 we in London and he uh tried to
introduce me to Y gar who I already knew
uh but he said something along the lines
of uh this is my friend Ethan Russo and
then he said he has many crazy ideas so
uh to me that was a high compliment and
I've always bragged about it ever since
um um I was also really pleased uh in
um his last book B was released and he
had asked me to write the first chapter
of that on cannabis in India um so again
um I'll always remember for bragging
rights um but I I'll let people go
around we can certainly talk about all
the scientific developments uh that he
spearheaded or in which he was
involved thanks Ethan appreciate that
just uh kind of reading the chat here um
one one question from the chat was can
can Ethan explain the distinction for
Raphael being credited with discovering
or isolating cannabinoids please sure
okay well you know this had a real
history um back in the 19th century
chemists around the world were trying to
figure out what the active ingredients
were in psychoactive plants so they had
great success with the Opium poppy they
found morphine somewhere around
1804 also cocaine cocoa leaves but
working on cannabis they were sort of
stumped um they could get it down to
this red oil um someone in 1896 isolated
what they call canaban but it wasn't
pure um subsequently low in the United
States after being a refugee from
Germany um sort of had the structure of
canaba in
1940 uh but it wasn't until rafy and his
associates it's um goni and Sho um 1963
kneeled down the three-dimensional
structure of canaba dial and then of
course the next year in
64 um they uh isolated and synthesized
tetrahydro canab andol known to
us but it didn't stop there um that same
year they isolated canaba gereral and
had the preci to uh note that it seemed
to be the parent compound of the other
canabo but that same year they found the
real parents the cannabinoid acids uh
cbda uh cbga
cbna and then in 66 they found canab
chromin um and uh went on from there um
so yeah I mean people could argue that
uh canaba was discovered by low earlier
but um Roger Adams Roger Roger Adams was
the first one to isolate CBD from
Minnesota Wild I think that's who you're
referring to right sure I'm sorry that's
right loow was working in the canaban
wood field it was Adams Roger Adams so I
stand corrected there um but uh went on
from there I mean rafy's work never
stopped um after the discovery of the
CB1 canaban receptor in 1988 and 90 um
they isolated anandamide the first uh
endoc canabo that work done with Bill
Deane and lumir hanou um and then a few
years later they found two aric adonal
glycerol 2 AG in
1995 and went on from there so I think
that addresses the
question yes thank you there's always
you know one person in the chat uh
making sure that the history is accurate
so we got Steve from poton ponic just
left right that's not true this was the
it was this guy it was this guy it was
this guy it was this guy I trust that Dr
Ethan Russo knows the history Ethan
Ethan You' love to know I mean how many
people who just think that he was the
first to discover THC and he was the
first to isolate THC when we all know
and and and Rafi no too he re he
referenced all this work very accurately
humbly in in his papers back to uh the
woods bivy easterfield
isolation that you reference in 1896
were the first folks to isolate you know
distilled canabo the first people to
make distillate I guess you'd say right
and then it was really um Robert S Con
in in in in in four backtack papers in
the early 30s who really took so they
they knew the thing that was confusing
them is is that back in the day this was
before spectroscopy and before all this
analytical instrumentation and what they
often would do is they would perform
chemical reactions on these natural
extracts to try to identify the product
of these chemical reactions and
sometimes they would be treating with
like concentrated nitric acid in fact
that was one of the derivatives that
that the wood Spivy uh easterfield group
made in fact I believe it was Spivy was
actually killed in a in an explosion in
the laboratory during some of that work
when they were working with that really
um explosive nitration chemistry the
same thing that killed one of the people
in The Dupont family that was making
nitrates for explosives so this this
chemistry was often just very harsh and
would tear up these molecules and and
and a lot of times like like when you
think of heroin heroin is the acetate
right and so they would make these
derivatives and sometimes be able to
purify these chemical derivatives and so
like I know there's been a lot of
interest in THC acetate these days this
was actually uh one of the typical
derivatizations that they would do when
they isolated a compound that had a free
o or a free phenol and wood in SP and
easterfield carried out enough detective
work and their original work to know
that there was a free there was a free
phenol so that's why they named the
compound canaban and you're right it was
a mixture of compounds but if you look
at their boiling points and you plot
their boiling points on something called
a nomograph which corrects for the the
vacuum pressure at which that fraction
is collected under vacuum it corrects it
for uh you know the the boiling point at
at at at at standard pressure and often
when boiling points were reported and
you know this Ethan because some some of
these are in some of your own papers it
often got reported as this is the
boiling point of THC but they forgot to
mention that it was measured under this
vacuum pressure and so the boiling point
at at atmospheric pressure was much much
higher but the point is is that if you
look at the boiling point of what Woods
Spivy and easterfield
isolated it is smacked on the boiling
point of what Rafi isolated several
years later and so that I think is is
the nail in the coffin that those people
did indeed ident or isolate THC it was
probably mixture of the Ring isomer
Delta 8 Delta 9 who knows right yeah now
we're g to quibble about history we also
have to give credit to the checks I mean
uh speaking to lumir hanu it's apparent
that a tremendous amount of work was
accomplished in earlier in the 50s on
these compounds but it was uh because of
Soviet influence or communist influence
that was published in check and was
never accessible to people in other
countries but um be that as it may rafy
got the credit um and certainly with
these other substances uh he was the
clear winner um with most of them at
least um in isolating them and helping
to figure out what they did well he he
had proton NMR which just was invented
in the early 60s that Roger Adams and
the previous chem so and and and I think
you know Rafi would totally admit that
he stood on the shoulders of Adams and
and brango and all those people Khan and
everybody who came before him because I
think there was always ambiguity over
the position of the double bond Ethan if
you look at some of Roger Adams papers
from 1940 you'll see that he represents
Tetra Hydro canabidol with just the
double bond in like either Delta 7 or
Delta 6 it's just in an odd position
because they had no clue I mean this is
this is during during the war man I it's
like it's amazing that that work was
even done and um and uh he was the first
one that hydrogenated so he
hydrogenated THC that they isolated from
conversion of CBD and he talked about
the acid catalyzed conversion of CBD
over into THC and hydrogenated it to
make
hhc and then uh patented it uh claiming
a compound with marijuana like
activity which I always thought was
interesting somebody in the lab must
have tried it
right chemistry chuckle I like that
appreciate the
stories lots of people in chat talking
about this hydrogenate
canono everyone's got lots to say about
it it's really impactful like Ethan said
when you lose a mentor because mentors
have this incredible impact on the
community because they've mentored
scientists who've gone on to be mentors
themselves and so it's like a a chemical
family connection that you have back to
your your mentor
and um um I never met Professor michul
but we corresponded quite a bit um and
um by the time um I became an active
chemist in cannabis chemistry he wasn't
taking any more collaborations but I
think he found great um interest in what
and what I was doing in some of the
ideas and counseled me and sent me all
kinds of paper ERS and I think he
enjoyed his um his Fame in a certain way
because I think he kind of understood
that there were chemists like me and
other scientists throughout the world
that have now jumped in feet first into
canono science mostly based on on his
inspiration and his story his story is
just incredible right Ethan it's just
it's just a it's a story it's a story
about the war it's a story about you
know Israel it's a story about how the
ni told them to go pound salt
until um the the director from NIH went
over there and then grabbed a bunch of
THC brought it back to to Bethesda and
that's the world
Supply yeah I I can elaborate on that a
bit um so rafie tells the sto would tell
the story that um uh when he first
applied to NIH as Mark said they turned
him down and the explanation was well
nobody nobody uh uses cannabis in this
country which obviously wasn't true but
uh the tune changed apparently uh the
son of a senator got busted for quote
marijuana um and uh Senator was worried
that uh this is make him crazy forever
um suddenly he had funding and he had
funding through NIH for 40 years and
it's true
that um NIH asked for the total
synthesized supply of uh THC which was
something like 25 grams at that time um
and they kept coming back um so it meant
more hashish had to be processed and at
that time um this was seized from uh
Police Supplies um how the hasi got
there was interesting too because it was
grown in Lebanon and it' be thrown over
the barbwire fence presumably there was
an exchange of money involved but um you
know I just uh was in Barcelona and I
met some Lebanese gentlemen and they
gave me the most beautiful pie piece of
red Lebanese hash I've seen in a very
very long time yeah that looks like what
we were seeing in the 70s yeah it's all
traditional cultivars traditional
methodologies they're younger guys but
they're
following uh you know the tradition and
it was just great to uh I what I really
loved about it was you know
simultaneously there was a woman we were
at HQ in Barcelona my friend David's
club we were in this sort of upstairs
private area that you know shout out to
Frenchie can onlyi because the last time
I got to spend time with Frenchie and
smoke with Frenchie was at HQ In This
Very spot where I met these uh Lebanese
gentlemen and so I was there at HQ uh it
was the end of the event when I landed
at the event I was a judge for masters
of rosin and the Masters of rosin was a
competition with 64
entries and basically half a gram per
entry for the judge so it was 32 grams
of live hash rosin that was given to me
as I landed in uh the at the airport in
Barcelona half an hour later I had all
this Ro live hash rosin and so I was
giving out the last little jars little
quarter grams little tenth of grams just
to the people in HQ and the first group
that I approached were these guys from
from Lebanon they're actually Armenian
and
Lebanese and so they pulled out this
Lebanese hash I said come on up to this
little private area we'll try smoking
some and there was a girl up there John
Burell who has a com who works for a
company called flute FL Lut TT I believe
and it's one of these cups that sits on
a base and vaporizes the smoke into the
cup and then you drink you drink the The
Vapor I tried a few before and wasn't
impressed with them at all but this unit
was unbelievable and how how effective
it was now the the this Lebanese hash
was very melty it was um we had a hash
Kettle that we tried to make a snake out
out and put it into the hash Kettle but
when my buddy lit it it just was
Dripping and and and melting so it was a
very nice caliber of hash anyway this
cup was the perfect way you just put it
into the little um coil very much like a
puffco or a a Carta or any of these
units and she put the cup on the base
and it filled up super psychedelically
with this really neat Smoky Vapor right
to the top and I I I I swigged it down
and I just had to say like from taking
the moon rides with the live hash Ros
and you know the rocket ship to the Moon
every hit you take I was very impressed
with the flavor and the and the the
effects of the Lebanese hash it was just
very very different I think that a lot
of people that are smoking these very
pure full melts and live has rosins
would have an appreciation if they could
access product like that and be able to
smoke it in a very particular way that
still made it enjoyable the high was
completely different in in every way it
was just uh it made me appreciate um
that traditional hash and obviously you
know it was done very well as you can
even just see from the pictures but uh
was there a a COA on that
material there was no COA that I you
know these were just couple of dudes
that had it but I'm in touch with them
they've invited me to Lebanon I've told
them that I would love to go there and
bring some hash making techniques and
maybe learn some Trad traditional hash
makinging techniques and so I'm going to
keep the uh connection with them they're
very excited and just very gung-ho guys
and uh I I just couldn't believe the
caliber of of hash that they had from
Lebanon it was uh it was shocking to say
the
least well I I can step in with a little
bit uh I first met Dr mulam in 1993 when
I joined the at that time it was the
international cannabis research Society
later changed to the conoid research
Society but uh so I went to the Toronto
meeting uh of the icrs in
1993 and uh that's the first one I
attended I believe it was their fourth
of 33 meetings that they've had so far
yearly uh I lik Dr Mulan from the first
time we met uh his love of cannabis the
cannaboids and the endoc canabo system
and his belief in their importance to
medicine and uh is something that both
of us really shared
deeply uh he was kind enough to help my
cannabis R&amp;D company uh the first
company uh licensed in the world uh
to
uh do research and development with
cannabis and grow and breed cannabis for
medical use he
participated in the filming of a
documentary by a Dutch Dutch Science
Program n light uh broadcast on Dutch TV
in the
mid90s uh about the future of medical
cannabis he felt very strongly about it
the canids and endoc canids and uh they
filmed uh rafie walking through my 1
acre greenhouse in Holland swelling the
individual plants and talking to the
norite film crew and uh several other
people who were interviewing him on the
film uh at the time many people in the
government uh the government authorities
scientists
and doctors included really did not
believe cannabis had a future in
medicine uh I knew it did as Dr mulam of
course
knew
uh he visited my home with his wife
Dalia and we enjoyed a wonderful dinner
with my wife uh had prepared for us and
uh I I'd like to send my condolences to
uh Dalia their three children
Roy uh Hadas and dnea as well as Dr
mulam had seven grandchildren aged
between 7 and 24 and I hope they will
have a truly wonderful life and I hope
uh rafie rest in
peace uh rafie truly was the the center
like a SP web of uh cannaboid
researchers worldwide cannabis cannaboid
endoc canabo he he he was endless in his
advice and hints and and uh we we we
helped a little bit we we were able to
show that tpes were able to uh
potentiate and uh modulate uh THC and
the other conoids and uh
he was really interested in that but uh
he was a scientist uh I I was really a
pot grower or cannabis grower but uh we
we we reached as far as we could and uh
uh I I love Ry and uh I'll miss him
greatly true
true very nicely said uh Sam very nicely
said indeed it's nice to gather with you
guys on a su Monday morning- afternoon
Das evening in Amsterdam for for Rob and
Sam it's been uh it's been a while I
haven't been doing hash Church uh every
week by any means but it's nice that it
exists and it's a place and it's a
platform that if we ever do want to to
gather if we want to celebrate a a lost
Soldier or we want to just gather and
enjoy the plant that we love so much
it's always here for us I'll always make
it available and uh yeah Scott it's been
it's I think it's going on its ninth
year
for for hash church so doesn't that make
you feel old it's crazy how as you get
older you can just gather decades behind
you just Decades of like oh how many de
like Rob I thought I lived here for 20
years it's like well it's been
30 just a whole extra decade that you
sort of missed there but it was it it
happened pretty
loud that's S I just got my little guy
talking in the background here I'll
probably mute it out if someone else
wants to go into his
story um yeah I'd like to say a couple
other things if I could um rafie was a
real International character and um he
easily could have gotten mixed up in the
politics um rather than the science uh
related to cannabis but um in 2002 I had
a research project in Morocco we were
looking at how can affected night vision
which had improves um anyway I was a
little bit uh concerned there um but I
was fascinated to see how uh rafie was
revered uh in the science community in
Morocco everybody asked me about it and
um they knew that I knew him and just
constant questions and uh the respect
was uh so obvious
um same thing when uh we met in
1999 I wondered what his relationship
was with Mahmud El who of course uh runs
the cannabis farm at the University of
Mississippi he he was Egyptian by birth
but they've been colleagues Forever
on as far as I know politics never
entered into their
relationship additionally uh Rafi had
Palestinian scientists in his lab um so
you know we certainly need more of that
kind of attitude in the
world roie also uh was I had asked him
about Israeli politics I said the the
fundamentalists G is they seem to be
taking over this was I don't know 10
years ago or even longer and uh he said
yeah well we need to separate the church
from the state well
religion from the state but uh he says
the right-wingers in Israel just don't
want that to happen and uh he he thought
he privately told me he thought they
were all
crazy well you know I'd apply that to
fundamentalists of any structure so I
would agree with
you are there any hashish
fundamentalists out there that insists
that you smoke it a very specific way
and process it a very specific
way it's the same thing as cannabis
Growers everybody thinks they have the
best stuff don't they
right Ethan let me ask a question so you
know AR
arguably arguably I think his most
important
contribution is the the fundamental
discovery of the endoc canabo system
system and its impact in medicine and
everyone talked about how oh this is
Nobel worthy and he should win the Nobel
Prize in medicine and when you consider
all of the medicines that have been
develop that act on the endoc canabo
system that have nothing to do with
phyto
canabo why why do you think that there
was politics and the negative stigma of
the plant that that held up that that
Nobel Prize which almost seemed obvious
and at some point just seemed laughable
that he wasn't going to get it I
heartily agree this is a subject of
discussion amongst many of us in the uh
canabo scientific Community we didn't
discuss it with rafy per se but I
discussed it with uh one of the
scientists resident in uh Sweden and he
was going to look into it the nom ation
process is a very Byzantine one uh it's
not something where you know I or you or
anybody else can just suggest the
committee that this person is
deserving I have to think but I don't
have substantiation on this that it
really had to do with prohibitionist
policies in Sweden maybe Rob would like
to address that further but I just say I
think it's a crying shame that he didn't
receive this and he can't now because
they're never awarded
ously um they did um someone was
nominated and died in the interim and
they gave it to his family but um once
you're dead you don't get it um Rob do
you want to say something more about
that any
insight oh I just have uh recent
insights on on Sweden but uh there is
very little of any cannabis research
going on in Sweden um although Sweden
does um handsomely Grant people to do
all kinds of different things I mean
they have a very good system in that
regard but there's uh especially on that
background a real poity of science
evidence and and it extends over to the
industrial hemp side as well there are
still projects trying to to get things
together in Sweden but
they're it's kind of an echo of projects
that were tried to be accomplished 20
years ago and longer that there's not
not really any new fire there and the
government is well able to help these
things should they wish
to
sure yeah the scientist that I had
talked to years ago about the Nobel
nomination for rafie is no longer active
in the field um at least I haven't seen
him at meetings in quite a long time um
so again I think you're quite right he
had students at the time that were doing
good work but um as usual they probably
found jobs in other areas um and this
has been a problem throughout I can't
tell you the number of excellent canono
chemists and uh scientists of other
disciplines who had to find jobs in
other fields hopefully that's changing
now certainly we need a lot of
analytical chemist to deal with um uh
the output from uh us if not other
countries I I think a lot of people have
this experience I mean Rob when you were
graduating uh from Indiana
University uh you had the same problem
you you your uh Mentor uh excuse me I
forgot your your the professor's name
there malberg malberg yes he he said
what are you ever going to do with this
knowledge I mean you can't you can't get
a job with
cannabis he wasn't he wasn't a guy who
just liked to study things like me had
to be practical you
know however rest in peace Paul Gordon
malberg did pass away not too long ago
and uh okay yeah and he
uh he was a just a real straight sort of
slus guy his one claim to fame that I
always really got a kick out of because
it's so different from the rest of his
personality was that uh he got a hold of
some of the limited number of moon rock
samples that came back so around the
department he was known as Moon Rock
smallberg but that that was his real
claim to fame in my mind but well Dr
malberg also uh had Carl hilig under him
and that really picked off the
classification change mhm
now good work came out of his lab a lot
of other good stuff too good uh gland
morphology work a lot of really cool
stuff so he he was really nice to me in
person when I met him he's a good guy he
was nice to me as well and all federally
funded right he had Federal funding for
this he had Federal funding for a lot of
this yeah yeah absolutely oh although
they didn't have enough Nations funding
considerably as well they didn't have
enough money for Carl's work so uh we
gave them a grant and uh that enabled
Carl to do his work for several
years no the uh un grants were more
involved with trying to have some
forensic angle to whatever was being
done like being able to identify glands
and things like that you know it's there
had to be some little twist that might
be able to use to the government's
Advantage but he did really good work
his grad students did as well it's all
kinds of great stuff done there you were
saying that in in in Sweden it's it's
there's hardly any funding for this kind
of work but remember I I I forget his
name uh the guy who wrote the
anti-cannabis
books from Sweden remember he was at the
ISS BR for years and then he just
disappeared yep yeah well I'm sure they
had those uh disperate elements as well
well
but did uh Professor malberg uh have an
appreciation for the impact of his of
his work I've must have read about I'm
not kidding about 20 of his papers on
the accumulation of canono and the
Tricom this is
extremely important seminal work that
this he did he know the impact that he
had on generations of scientists who are
going to read his papers and want to
continue I don't know later in life if
he finally got it but at the time
no he must gotten it later in life I
mean he wasn't just fishing in Minnesota
all the time I mean yeah he was retired
he fully retired when he left Academia
he really left Academia I saw him at uh
North American Industrial Hemp meetings
twice I believe and uh that's the only
time Ian into him and it was really good
to see him but he was uh trying to get
involved after retirement with the hemp
side of things as a as an expert
basically you know expert name yeah that
that's where I met him the one time was
uh one of the hemp meetings in Colorado
and he was extremely nice to me and uh
complimentary the work that I'd done
which shocked me that he'd seen it but
anyway that well I'm glad that he was
that curious still he I never really
thought that he was I mean he he really
wanted me to study um
laticifers it's just another gland that
secretes things you know so and and I
happen to study him as an undergraduate
a little bit too I was misdirected then
also but another gland that secretes
things tell me more
wellers are found in
uh pine trees to to poetas and uh the
main ones in tense their name are are in
uh rubber trees and they produce latex
which comes from lusifer but lusers make
all kinds of pine oils and even turpins
I would assume although I'm not sure
about that but I bet they do and uh yeah
they're all through pine trees and E
Forbes is what studied them in in uh in
undergraduate one of the reasons Dr
malberg was connected with so many uh
famous historical cannabis papers is
that he had a license which meant that
students could actually grow cannabis on
campus and work with it whereas uh there
wasn't a lot of choices about that in
America and when my understanding was
when he retired that that that passed
and it uh just University of Miss
Mississippi was the only one left right
at the time I was there there were five
licenses as I
remember and it was a peak I think John
mcpartland even had one of them right at
that time and Eli of course and malberg
and there were a couple of other ones
that didn't really they weren't part of
research Maryland weed
control yeah weeds yeah yep yep the USDA
in Bethesda they had a license that's
right and then there's one more I think
but yeah they were they were really
limited and only a couple of them were
in any kind of an academic setting
so um yeah University of Michigan in Ann
Arbor and and Bloomington I think were
the only two I don't think Harvard ever
had a license
now just those two as far as I
know so to bring it back to rafy's work
he got into synthetic canabo at one
point what uh can can any of you speak
to that work and what you guys kind of
felt like about that I know some people
feel that it's dangerous but what are
the you know what are the advantages of
doing dangerous work well you know he
was a chemist so one of the things
chemists do is take the natural molecule
and try to make it better uh either
longer lasting or more potent so one of
the those was H2 210 hu designation
meant Hebrew University where he was
working so
h210 is uh a synthetic analog it's a
dimethyl heal uh derivative of
THC uh which made it far more potent um
and so this is used in the lab as
something you tried to knock off the
receptor and testing other things I know
somebody who took this once and had a
really bad weekend and I mean the whole
week was that
bill I I'm not going to say who it was
okay well that's why I didn't say his
last name um yeah but um so this was
never designed to be a therapeutic agent
it has appeared in some of the synthetic
can abono mixes uh through the black
market uh but it was it was developed as
a lab Aid it's
um three-dimensional Mirror Image was
h211 which was non psychoactive this was
actually there were attempts to develop
this as a drug called Dex and naol by a
company called pharmos in Israel
unfortunately after they got the license
they never checked with Rafi again
according to his story and the way that
they gave this was someone would have a
head injury and they would give the Dex
an NA avenol intravenously but only one
time so this worked in initial studies
but in the pivotal uh phase three
randomized control trials it didn't work
um we have to wonder in retrospect
whether they had used it more
judiciously that it could have
worked um you know rafy was also
involved in study of the CB2 non
psychoactive receptor uh that affect
pain and
inflammation um so he had another uh
synthetic agent called
h308 uh that was tested and then more
recently um you know finally after all
these years there was excitement about
the acid cannabinoids but hindered
somewhat by the the lack of shelf
stability uh with those molecules so he
uh made methyl Esters of these and one
called um
h58 is a methylester of cannabidiolic
acid
cbda um and that could very interesting
in treating nausea um and possibly
anxiety it's a pro drug so when it's
administered it'll break back down into
cbda uh in the
body um
so Rafi head is is feet in both camps in
terms of the synthetic cannaboids but
also the phyto canabo many of which he
discovered um or was the first uh to
nail down um to put a fine point on it
but um I mean that just gives an idea of
the breadth of his work and the the the
uh length of his relevance in scientific
discovery over the course of six decades
I mean how often can you say that um you
know a lot of people make an initial
Discovery and then
they're sitting
back we're gone and whatever it
is how about you Dr Mark can you speak
to the sort of you know the the reaction
when people hear about synthetic
cannaboids the in the canab in the
Cannabis Community it's generally like
oh my God that's St is horrible it's the
spice it's like there's videos on
YouTube but like speak to the sort of
potential um reasons that chemists do it
and you know why we're you know that
it's not nefarious that it's not like
they're trying to harm people but
there's you know there there's a good
behind it where you're trying to
learn well there's there's a couple
factors that that influence it one of it
unfortunately is the almighty dollar um
you know Financial return on drug
development it takes a lot of money to
bring a medicine through uh FDA sanction
clinical trials uh hundreds of millions
of dollars to do that and so for a
pharmaceutical company it's got to be
the views got to be worth the climb and
and I I think you know the discovery of
the endoc canabo
system impacted drug Discovery because
people knew how
important this system was because we
knew how important the phyto canabo were
on how they act on it so I think with
without exception all the pharmaceutical
companies in the early in the late 80s
and early 90s started developing uh non
phyto canabo heterocyclic molecules that
look nothing like um the uh the phyto
canabo and these are most notably the
the the JW
compounds uh these are Indo compounds
that look nothing like the phyto canabo
themselves but because of the scaffold
of the molecule itself it displays the
right functionality in the right way
that it it does the lock and key thing
inside these canono receptors sometimes
a whole hell of a lot better than the
natural ligans and the phyto canono do
and so um the other thing is that a lot
of those indol and a lot of those
nitrogen
heterocycles uh don't have the thermal
stability uh for consumption in a
vaporization kind of way so the
synthetic spice molecules and all those
other synthetic canabo are going to
really thermally decompose and degrade
into a myriad of different other
compounds that are going to have all
kinds of bad impact be pulling into your
lungs so but I I think Ethan's right you
know the chemist who wants to look at
the phyto canabo as being the mother
nature lead how can we improve on the
activity of these compounds and you know
going back to the money thing is you
know the companies have to be able to
patent those those medicines because
when they're spending all that money on
all those clinical
trials uh it's kind of I the one
conversation I'd love to have with e I'd
love to have Ethan with with Rafi was
what would what was his opinion on
running clinical trials on something
like CBD which is a public composition
to which GW does does not have have
composition of matter patents on and and
that's usually the the the top of the
pyramid in the pharmaceutical world you
need a a patent on the actual compound
that they've made and usually if it's a
starts out as a phyto avonoid by the
time synthetic chemists are done
manipulating functional groups and
putting different rings and and looking
looking at different structures they've
made a completely new compound and now
they're developing not only uh the
process chemistry to make that compound
economically viable but that's the
compound that ultimately they select and
bring through clinical trials when you
do that with a public composition like
CBD I think it was maybe the notion that
the FDA approval of
epidex was going to somehow give GW the
ability to have the FDA and the DEA sit
down on the rest of the CBD industry
saying No this is the active ingredient
of our FDA approved drug you can't put
it in your tincture or your gummy or
your vape pen but you know there's the
FD and C act which precludes the use of
FDA active ingredients in food feed or
cosmetics and you know the CBD industry
now Treads lightly on that entire
regulation Ethan it sounds like you want
to say something so go well it's a lot
we could say we could spend the rest of
the time talking about this but yeah you
know how patents work initially they're
very broad claims and then they're
whittel down ultimately I think what GW
was left with was a use patent for these
severe epilepsy syndromes D lenux gesto
and tuber sclerosis treatment
there you know I don't know how much
money they're making now taken over by
Jazz but um certainly uh it's not an
exclusive kind of use um and yeah there
is this question now about the viability
of the rest of the CBD industry however
it's extremely extensive and it would be
hard to imagine uh that they're going to
be able to squelch that whole thing um
you know recently the FDA sort of
abdicated abdicated responsibility
uh for it at all and kicked it to
Congress not that there's anyone there
that's qualified to make these kind of
judgments about complex scientific and
medical issues um so it's a pretty sad
State of
Affairs there there's supposedly a quick
a quick fix to this Ethan from what I
understand so um similar to caffeine
they could make an exception to the fdn
C act and that's just one signature from
the Secretary of Health and Human
Services just has to write a memo sign
it and that makes an exception and I
think that's how caffeine could be in
cocacola but it could also be active
ingredient in other
medicines GW did have the world's first
High CBD only variety uh that gave them
a 10year lead in front of any other uh
cannabis companies CU nobody else had it
and uh I think that was a big help for
them to to be able to grow uh
basically uh almost pure CBD because
there's always a little bit of THC in
any CBD variety because the CBD synthes
makes uh
THC
so also too you were talking
about well listen I am a natural guy
that's me but we also had a patent for
uh analoges of anandamide because we
were trying out anide for controlling
glycom and uh we found out it actually
did work better than any of the
classical cannabinoids and then we made
from a nide we made analoges and we
found ones that even worked better
because the problem with most the
medications are first it uh works really
and then it it it doesn't keep the eye
pressure constant it keeps it up and
down and up and down and with with these
analogs that we uh
synthesized we were able to make it so
that uh there was a gloma medicine which
truly uh did have constant uh lowering
of the eye and keeping it constant
pressure very cool how did those guys
know that they needed to like did you
guys sell them did HOA Farm sell them on
you need a high CBD cultivar and we can
produce it or did they come searching
for that no when we we first met them I
I don't know what they were thinking in
the back of their brains but both Rob
and I told uh the Folks at
GW Jeffrey guy and Brian Whittle who
Brian Whittle is dead now but uh Jeffrey
guy uh so we told them that if you take
CBD in equal amounts to THC it will
relieve a lot of the problems that naive
users have with uh you know getting too
high and getting scared and all that
kind of stuff and uh they they ran with
it either it was m and Rob's information
or information they gleaned other places
but uh yeah so when they came to us they
wanted CBD and they wanted
THC yeah well we had talks with them too
so sure Jeffrey guy started as a plant
guy a lot of his initial work um he
actually had a patent on uh CH
traditional Chinese medicine uh mixture
uh to treat the first actually the the
first plant patent in uh the UK and
maybe
Europe yeah so no he was uh real
proponent uh at least in the early days
of the Entourage
concept then it was ironic that uh epid
dialects wound up being a 98% pure CBD
preparation which is not what I wanted
um right so e Ethan doesn't that play to
S kind of like the heart of the issue
here which is that if if the cannabis
plant teach teaches us many things but
if it teaches us anything it teaches us
again this Entourage or Ensemble effect
which you just can't replicate in single
ingredient single active ingredient
medicine and
so been preaching this gospel for a long
time I know so where do we go from here
man like
important um you know there are plenty
of detractors out there there's a guy uh
who has taken Delight in publishing
stuff about uh that the Entourage uh
effect isn't proven or you know other
theories aren't proven how much proof do
you need there's a tremendous body of
literature that's taken place since 1999
when uh professor mulam and Ben Shabbat
suggested that sometimes plants are
better medicines than the single
compounds they pointed out that that was
theoretical at that time but 24 years
later it's no longer theoretical it's
proven we have many examples at what
point do you say look we have the
examples so the claim that it doesn't
matter is it you know it's a done deal
it's already been proven that uh you
have Synergy of ingredience in certain
situations so then it becomes a matter
of trying to figure out the best
combinations and that's the approach
we're taking now at credos science and
um
developing you know complex mixtures of
cannabinoids and turboid from the plant
uh that are going to be fit for purpose
whatever that may be uh and it means a
different thing in different situations
so that's my spin on the thing well
anybody who's ever smoked cannabis and
if they were to smoke p pure THC 100%
pure and then spike it with a little bit
of lolene or marine or anything else
then their doubt would
disappear yeah we're trying um you know
we're doing work now with Ryan vandre at
Johns Hopkins to show the
Entourage and that is through using pure
THC and pure terpenoids um in the lab
double blind um so hopefully in the next
couple of years we'll have papers
showing further proof for these Concepts
it's unreal that we have to prove
anything because think of it this way
you're consuming something it has no
flavor it has no taste that's a single
methodology of consuming it now you're
putting these flavors that you can taste
and you can smell and of course they're
going to add to it that would be like
eating food that didn't taste like
anything and suddenly someone gave you
food that had wonderful tastes and
smells that's a different experience I'm
so blown away sometimes that people are
so unwilling to understand that when you
smell something your old factory that is
different from seeing and touching
feeling hearing that smell and that you
know that's what has probably attracted
us to foods and to one another and to
just all of these smells that that are
out in the world it's amazing that
Olympic system the sights of emotion
tapping into memory locking in memory
exactly I've definitely got a few
memories from very specific smells and
that is uh reminds me of a story um back
when in my neurology days um I saw a
patient came back into my office and
there was a smell of Afghan hash I'm
going what the hell you know I don't
have anything here like that saw another
patient came back in again the Afghan
hash so finally put the nose to work and
echol looc it and what it was was a a
grapefruit that a patient had given me a
couple of days before sitting on my desk
I picked it up and um it had changed
over the course of two days and smell
very reminiscent of Afghan hash between
the lyine and whatever cesare terpenoids
there were in there um so yeah you know
and
uh n katone n n nud katone is the uh is
the grapefruit turpine one of them and
it's so interesting Ethan because the
difference between none and
venine is just a carbonal group it's
like one
oxidation turns a ch2 into a carbonal
group and you go from valencian oranges
to n katone n katone
grapefruit I wanted to share one thing
with you Ethan so my last correspondence
with Professor mulam I sent him a link
to the nose paper I I read the newspaper
and I had talked with Jeremy on
clubhouse before it had come out and I
think he had either sent me early draft
of it but I read it and I was just was
like oh man this is such a cool pap
paper it was just I was like yes this is
it you know and all of this news of lab
shopping and THC inflation this is this
is what I've needed to read this article
right so I sent a link to Rafi and he he
got back a couple days later and he
loved the paper he just I didn't have
the occasion to talk to him about that
yeah I'll see if I can't I think it was
just it was either a LinkedIn message
that he sent he's oh this is this is
terrific thank you you know if you could
forward that I'd love it um I will
really look for it I really will I
believe Valen is a turpine founding
cannabis correct
yes that's right large amounts but yeah
you know these some of these very Trace
Amounts of CES terpenoids make a
tremendous difference and um as everyone
will attest it doesn't take a lot
a few molecules would be something that
you can sense uh with your olfactory
capabilities and um goodness knows what
they're doing pharmacologically
to right what I've been looking at
recently is
uh pure
thca and I'm dosing it with FES let me
tell you FES are Maybe a hundred or a
thousand times more volatile and
stinkier than any tpine I've ever worked
with right I'm very
curious do you have Sam I'm very curious
to see if the thol uh do modulate or uh
potentiate TC or any other cab that's
the issue are they psychoactive right ex
exactly do they tribute so is it the
penal sulfide that you have prenal
sulfides yes I I yes I have a couple of
them uh one of them is the one that uh
the folks that gave it to me I think
from I I'm afraid I don't remember the
name of the lab but it's the people who
publish the
paper Oswald
yes I'm I'm bar curious and that's what
I got this uh pure thca for to with the
th well that's uh that's when you got to
invite Nick zegler on because that guy
did 20 plus years of thol work with yaka
mief Hops and he discovered over 1,400
thol present in hops which is
unbelievable um when you really think
about it how many could there be and if
they're in such small amounts do we have
to think of these profiles I personally
I try not to say Tarpin all the time
anymore I try to say volatile organic
compound
because when I say tpin I feel like I'm
leaving out the Esters and the thil and
the thiolates and all these other again
an area that really needs investigation
what are the psychoactive effects uh of
the Esters because clearly they're
really
contributing um to the fruity Aromas
that seem to be really preferred by a
lot of cannabis
consumers yeah that garlic smell go
ahead you know very well Ethan that
uh before the T work that Rob and I and
other folks were doing with me uh it uh
nobody really truly believed that the
tpin were modulating uh THC or
potentiating THC but uh we we proved a
pretty conclusively 20 years
ago but you proved it in your apartment
to Rand people what are you talking
about that [ __ ] was like I didn't need
to read any papers I was like okay
that's cuz we didn't publish it it was
for in-house work really to be honest
and because I wanted to
know well I loved your passion because I
can still picture myself back in your
apartment in early 2000 and I just
remember how excited you were sitting on
the edge of the couch okay now try it
with the mercine like just so stoked and
pumped uh on the on the you know on the
edge of a a new discovery I love
it when I told rafie about uh the tpine
work he was really excited and I I I I
gave him all an explanation of
everything how it all worked and
everything and uh yeah yeah well did
related to that um people may be
interested to know that um The Taming
THC paper resulted from his 80th
birthday because there was a a symposium
held in Israel in honor of that and it
gave me the opportunity to publish that
in a high-profile Journal a British
Journal of of
pharmacology um so you know that was the
right opportunity to present that work
um so you know and to me um it all came
from the concept of the
Entourage um
so have to give credit there um in
support of
that what are the stats on that paper
Ethan I must imagine it cited thousands
of times it's it's been cited quite
frequently and for four years it was the
most commonly accessed uh uh scientific
paper on on cannabis I don't know where
it Stacks up now but it was on top for
four
years the first place that I released
the information about the tpin being
able to modify and potentiate THC was at
the ICS meeting uh I I I don't remember
which one it was but uh yeah people
there what hungry
oh you're right it was it was hungry I
remember you're right yeah because I I
was with you prior to that hey Sam you
were talking before about a movie that
was made with professor mulam in your in
your grow does that movie exist on
YouTube or can we see that not that I
know of I've got a VHS I've got several
VHS copies of it but I I haven't
digitalized it or anything have you ever
seen that Ethan um I think you might
have shown it to me when I yeah it was
called not light and it was about uh Dr
michul in the Cannabis was it wasn't I
don't think it was subtitled it was yeah
okay sure I think I I have vague
memories of that um in terms of movies
people might want to look for the
scientist that's great yeah so that's an
hour movie that um uh Zack Klein did um
mainly from interviews done in uh
2012 um but a great
uh great uh Testament to uh Professor
mullum his early history all the the
stuff we've talked
about it's hilarious with the the the
the little uh cartoon sketches where he
says well I went and I had coffee with
them so wherever he went he had coffee
so he went and smuggled
five pounds a hash from the police over
but he had coffee with
them so wherever he went he had
coffee but such a unassuming humble man
right I mean I think there's a lesson
for all of us in humanity absolutely but
you know he was a scientist and he did
have a competitive streak I I'll tell a
story in relation to that so you know he
and his colleagues had discovered all
these uh endoc canabo analoges some of
them are seemingly active some were
inactive and I must have asked him
several times what about a docasa
hexanoic acid derivative so uh DHA dcasa
hexanoic acid is a component of the cell
membranes in our brain it's also what's
in fish oil and so it's the reason that
people take fish oil and every time I
asked he was a Vas and sort of waved me
off um I couldn't understand it because
he was usually so veiling uh of his
knowledge um we were at some meeting and
we're on a bus together and he whispers
to me you were asking about docasa
hexanoic acid derivatives and he said we
have discovered that they were about
1,00 times more
powerful um than the phyto canabo in um
osteoblastic function building up
osteoporotic bone just as work that he
was doing with the late ETI Bob also in
Israel um so you know he apparently had
been working on this and didn't want to
say anything about it until he he knew
uh what the real answer was um but to my
knowledge nobody's carried that work
forward um so you know if people thought
geez you know everything's been done
that's never going to be true in this
field it is so deep there is so much to
do and we've just scratched the surface
of what the other phyto canabo can do
there are 150 of them we know the basic
pharmacology of about a dozen and you
know all the bandwidths taken up with
THC and
CBD uh whereas CBG is a f fantastically
therapeutic compound and uh really
hasn't gotten the attention um thcv
again there's been some work but um you
know goodness knows what we can get out
of the other
138 that really haven't had the
attention um so with selective breeding
and uh some funding for research there's
a lot of great stuff to
come yeah that was one of the problems
Ethan in the past like before we started
breeding for single canono cannabis
varieties uh was to get your hands on
the material was uh incredibly expensive
and difficult and uh that's why we set
about breeding varieties that had one
single canabo so that there would be
large amounts for uh research and so
that you could use them as basic
like to paint a painting right yeah mix
and match I have a question for you Sam
how like how does one go about is is in
breeding and Rob can chime in on this as
well is it just standard knowledge that
you can there are breeding techniques to
breed you know certain things to be
produced singularly or is that something
you guys had to sort of discover along
the way like how easy is it to just
start growing a cannabis plant and only
make it produce one can avonoid well it
it's actually fairly difficult it uh in
fact most people including plant
breeders cannabis researchers thought
maybe I wouldn't be able to do it but uh
we were actually incredibly successful
it took four or five years so what we'd
start with uh a variety that say had
tiny amounts of
thcv uh for example uh
we were using uh a South African variety
a Afghan variety a Thai variety and uh
California Orange and that those
varieties all had you know one% or less
of
thcv so we inbred each of those
individually self it uh two three four
generations and each time would take the
seeds
that we produced and uh find the highest
in the Target and kept doing that and uh
the problem is after you inbreed
cannabis three four times I mean it is
the most
inbred uh like I I it has no Vigor it it
it W sometimes it quits dropping pollen
I mean it's it it just has no resistance
it's it it's because cannabis is a
hetero zot plant and when you breed it
to be uh basically closer to homos I got
it loses all of its uh resistant to
diseases and problems but uh what we
found out was that we took those four
populations that we had done that to and
combined them and then the uh hybrid
vager was restored
that's
crazy I love the different sides of all
of it you know from the from the
chemistry that mulam practiced to the to
the collecting of the seeds in hash
producing countries to the actual
breathing uh work you know and then
earlier we were talking about how it's
all about you know the profile the
Entourage all of these different sort of
profiles I'm just talking there
buddy um that it's this it's this hole
that you want but then I you know I was
going to kind of ask Rob about this
earlier as well in the sense that
cannabis produces many different holes
so we can say we want the whole profile
but we're certainly not using the
cellulose and the fiber and the seed uh
the rich amino acid seed for that
cannabinoid you know inhalation medical
Das recreational experience so you can
take the resin and think that you have
the whole but really cannabis always
seems to be about the one from the whole
at least from my experience that when
I'm you know making if I want to make
seed oil or dehaul seeds that comes from
the seed I don't need the fiber I don't
need the cellulose I don't need the
medicinal components and so it's just an
interesting sort of concept that you can
take the one from the whole if you're
making clothing you know which Rob has a
lot of experience with textiles and the
history of of of cannabis and temp
textiles and the difference like do we
see that I mean I'm sure you've seen
breeding for textiles even just
naturally happening whether they knew
what they were doing or not versus the
same concept that we do for the
medicines which are chemists now trying
to figure out ways to like produce
embryos and seeds that produce better
fibers kind of just going on but chime
in anytime
Rob oh you're muted it it's
what do people mean by whole I mean I'll
be cynical for a minute but whole plant
extracts
are extracts that include more than one
class of compounds let's say okay you've
got some tur beans in there it's a whole
plant extract okay whatever whole flow
extract whole whatever it's I'm just
being cynical but it's overused it also
can mean natural in some ways that
people use it um it doesn't mean either
of those things
Rob what it means is it's got to have
every canono and every turpine and if it
doesn't it's not whole right well that
would be the ultimate definition but of
course no no product no extract no even
lab ever can do that things get lost
especially volatile uh organic compounds
they go by by real easy all they have to
just sort of think about it and they
disappear so yeah it's it's an overused
thing I mean it it's back to kind of
like the arguments years ago again
natural versus organic until the USDA
just co-opted the word organic and
decided to rule it but it it's yeah they
they don't
necessarily in a world of branding and
marketing they tend to mean things um
considerably different than their actual
definitions if that
helps yes absolutely just uh replying to
some of the people in the chat room here
people are enjoying the conversation
amazing panel
Marcus always appreciate a good panel on
a Sunday morning I get to check out of
my hotel in about a half an hour here
and drive home there nice couple of days
up in Whistler riding with the family
and enjoying life and do you have heaps
of snow there now we got so much in
California like more you guys have more
yeah you guys got it all most of it we
have snow but nothing like Tahoe and
like you guys got like 50 feet or
something got the biggest snowfall in a
100 years and then a week later before
any of it's melted at all except on the
roads maybe it snows another four feet
and then it snowed again so it's just
like yeah well the water reservoirs in
California needed it they do it's true
they need that but it's flooding like
hell everywhere and it's just beginning
to think about yeah for all those huge
glass houses in the middle of the stay
growing mids right yeah how m is going
to be
rampant I'm just weather everywhere it's
not a good year for it's not a good
winter for growing California never is
I'm busting on Mojave on that on that
statement there Rob yeah
yeah yeah
yeah so what what what what is your
current life like Rob like what are you
working on right
now um I'm
just finished sorting through a lot of
hemp Texs I just came back from turkey
and over the last 10 years I built quite
a collection of hemp rugs and grain
sacks and a few saddle bags things like
that um practical kind of hemp products
heavy hemp not fine hemp things and uh I
have a lot of them stored in a warehouse
in Turkey so I spent four days all day
long going through those things and uh
trying to figure out what to do with
them largely um a lot of them were're
keeping for collections Marcus is known
about this activity for a long time
because I do it with my partner Amir and
Marcus introduced us back in the day so
uh we had a great time doing this
and made some serious decisions about
what to do with things and then I came
home and I I had shipped a lot of things
back to Turkey years ago I brought
things home you know a few dozen kilos
at a time sort of and got things DHL and
filled up my house so I had I had more
than two tons of him things here that
were were Turkish so I I got them
shipped back to Turkey about five years
ago and put in a warehouse so we could
spread them out and and deal with them
um but I kept some things of course as
collectors do and I put them under my
bed so I did the the what my my lady
calls the [ __ ] under the bed hemp and
went through and uh organized it all
which is cool cuz I managed to look at
everything that built up in Turkey I
bought a a lot of things after I'd sent
things back and i' never cataloged those
and still Haven but i' got to look at
everything again so now I have a head
around all of it and the project is to
write a book about it of course what a
surprise so yeah well
we selections and photographs and I've
wrote a bunch of text already over the
years for our websites and things so
yeah the pieces are there we just got to
put it all together well I want to give
a shout out to Amir because you
mentioned him probably maybe quite
frankly the kindest human being I've
ever met very considerate just very kind
just an awesome allaround dude so if
you're watching Amir we love you shout
out to Amir and he loves to
smoke oh my God he's a hashish a ficado
of the highest
order yeah I was just uh talking in
private with Ethan in the chat room
saying maybe another 20 minutes if you
guys have anything else you want to
mention about Rafi or anything really
just uh got to get going here after the
2hour mark and get out of my hotel
and get back Homeward
Bound well if um there is an incredible
body of of work that exists and a lot of
it is open share
accessible um I don't know what his
final total was Ethan I I think I must
have about
400 papers by I have a I know it's north
of 600 North of 600 he was a tremendous
collaborator it wasn't just his lab um
one thing about the sci cannaboid
scientific Community is that they're
good collaborators
a lot of these papers will have 12 or
more people in different institutions
it's like you know rafie does this part
and Roger Perle does this part and Paul
paker does this part and um so you know
he he was a contributor and it wasn't
just the the basic science stuff um I
should point out he was highly involved
in clinical
applications the first paper on
canaba uh for epilepsy wasn't in
relation to the work at GW it was back
in
1980 uh collaborating with the
Brazilians Kia Carini and that group um
and when the International Association
for um cannabinoid medicines was formed
in 2001 he was there and he was at every
meeting um and helping to guide people
in what was done so um it wasn't a
matter of
making semisynthetic analoges that could
be patented he really uh was into use of
uh the natural cannabis extracts uh and
how they could be harnessed
therapeutically um so that was the way
he was a renaissance man he had
interest uh in all these different
facets we all also were in contact with
the Brazilians and that influenced our
early CBD work because we bred uh a high
CBD variety at that time it wasn't uh as
high as the one I eventually licensed at
GW but it uh was good enough that uh
they were really interested in it uh in
in Brazil because they they really
couldn't afford to get the CBD materials
that they needed for their work yeah
wouldn't have been been able to grow it
in the tropics very well
either so Ethan when I asked before
where do we go from here and you started
telling us about all the exciting work
you're doing at
Crudo how does how does how do
government and Regulatory bodies catch
up with where we're already at which is
they need a different way of regulating
this mechanism was that was that the
capitulation that they recently made is
that cannabinoids don't fit in this mono
single ingredient medicine so we need to
create a different process for you I
really don't know how it's going to
shake out um irrespective of what they
or anybody wants they're always going to
be three echelons of activity herbal
cannabis and its different uh forms um
the supplement industry hopefully with
some measure of quality control and
finally the pharmaceutical approaches
hopefully with phyto canabo
you know we're trying to focus on all
three um more selective breeding uh
development of rational um supplements
and also pharmaceutical approaches um
because anybody who thinks it stops with
satx and epid dialects has got another
thing coming there are fewer companies
that are working on it but um we're
involved with two uh at this point in
Deer Pharmaceuticals out of Vancouver be
and canera out of the greater Toronto uh
area um and it's not just canabo and
terpenoids the can flavens are of
tremendous interest uh medically and um
poor tend to provide really great things
in the areas of treating inflammation
cancer and maybe even neur
neuroen neurodegenerative disease easy
for me to
say and
that that that can coexist in framework
where prohibition is ending and adult
use Recreation RS coming online well
these kind of things could coexist yeah
there they aren't mutually exclusive
there are plenty of people approaching
this on in their own way um hopefully
it's a big tent in that respect and um
we don't get in each other's way too
much
the flavonoids is what we were
interested in next after the Turpin we
found that the tpes could modulate
potentiate the canabo and we were
interested in the flavonoids and then Dr
Mulan told me that if flavonoids are
combusted or vaporized they're de
deactivated so they're effective orally
but they're not effective smoking and uh
I I dropped the flavon after that
because I was I was really looking for
patients that were smoking because that
at the time was the delivery form
sure again more to
do well the potent antioxidants and
maybe they have something to do with the
overall stability of whole plant
preparations right Ethan where maybe
they're not doing something medically
but they're doing something chemically
on on the on the mixture so yeah why not
um yeah it's a good point uh if people
think that's not likely we can give the
example of St John's wart H hypericum
perforatum uh one of the so-called
active ingredients as a treatment for
depression is a thing called hyperforin
it's a weird molecule it's uh only
two-dimensional of it be like this in
this plane but on its end it's like the
rings of Saturn you might not see them
if it's at a certain angle anyway
hyperforin when it is isolated is
extremely volatile it has to be stored
under liquid nitrogen but in an extract
of the plant it's stable uh
so you know there's a good reason that
we've had galenical um you know tentures
have been popular in medicine for at
least a thousand years and the reason is
it's a good uh extraction and
preservation system so they ain't going
away
either I'd like to thank Dr mulam for
the the Gathering Place of the icrs I
mean that that is where all of the
modern cannabis science has been
announced first and most of the people
doing the work while members but
uh Incredible World uh the ICS sure
still going oh I I know in fact
it's the first meeting I went to was uh
1993 in Toronto and uh the meeting this
year is again in Toronto Y what goes
around comes
around fortunately it's in the
summertime when it's nice in
Toronto but you don't like minus
40 no I I live on Lake Champlain so I I
yeah I get my taste of winter every
year that's what's up so where where do
you guys see you know rafy's work going
in the next 25 to 50 years who's going
to pick up the torch and where where is
cannabis chemistry heading what's what's
our Direction there there is no one it's
more like throwing a stone into a lake
and the ripples just spread out in a
concentric Circle in all these different
fields I mean as far as I could see yeah
no his his legacy is going to be
remembered uh forever uh as far as this
field goes uh there's no worry there um
and there are plenty of eager young
scientists interested in this stuff My
worry is can they find jobs after
Graduate School uh it's a constant
problem one of the great scientists I
met at my first I ICS meeting in 1999
graduated and I had to go to work for a
tobacco company uh great loss to the
field so um that's well the good thing
about that of course is most of the big
tobacco companies now are diversifying
into cannabis
so maybe he he what comes around goes
around yeah but maybe not
too true
enough yeah I mean I think it's it's
it's um there's an old saying he's not
really gone if you remember him and you
keep him in your heart and so I think
about that when I think about my most
favorite
musician Mr Jerry Garcia who passed away
a number of years ago and I listen to
Jerry's Music every day and I appreciate
Rafi for his body of work I treasure the
correspondence I had with him and Ethan
I'm now collaborating with Allan howlet
we're we're looking at some of these um
minor isomers that are formed in this
Delta 8 uh manufacturing process where
they're converting CBD into THC and
these ISO isomers are found along the
way so collaborating with Professor how
to understand do they behave like
cannaboids from of these byproducts so
as you said Ethan there's just this this
whole landscape of opportunity and we
all stand on the
shoulders of Roger Adams and of Robert
Sydney Khan and wood spiv in easterfield
those first three guys who the first
people who made thisit and someday
Marcus they're going to be talking about
standing on your shoulders and going
back and watching episodes of hash
church and listening to us three talk
about hash and and laugh and and and
look at you know the time that we
witnessed here which is the ending of
cannabis
prohibition and you know there's just an
incredible opport Unity for gifted
people to get into this industry and and
apply knowledge and creativity and it's
all going to be thanks to people like
Professor michul so it's just kind of
like the um whether or not cannabis H is
all medical or not whether you like it
or not it is well whether you like it or
not if you're in cannabis today you're
thanking Professor michul for all of his
work and all of his contributions Marcus
thank you for having this church too
thank you
Temple yes let's I will be changing the
name once it's done I will go into
YouTube and this will be the first hash
Temple I think that's great absolutely
that
was
shalom shalom all right you guys thank
you everybody super good uh bunch of
people together yeah thanks for coming
out guys appreciate you Rob Dr Ethan Dr
Mark stenman Sam and all the people
watching um we'll we'll do it again one
day peace everybody good to see you bye
good to see you everybody byebye