hey what's going on everybody welcome to
hash Church episode 144 sorry for being
a few minutes late there I was of course
doing a little research and I got a
little stuck on the research and now I'm
gonna send out the links pop that down I
hope everyone's doing well today I'm
just gonna course get the links out here
doing a little bit of research today
trying to find out what companies have
been lobbying the Canadian government to
shut down dispensaries and it's a little
bit interesting it's not that easy
because a lot of these groups do you
know they hire a group to do their
lobbying for them and I'm sure we'll end
up talking about it a little bit here
today in the meantime let me make sure I
got those links all sent off good
morning at ten good morning sir good
morning Todd and a rousing [ __ ] Mickey
this morning cuz uh we lost a good
activist this week cuz [ __ ] Mickey cuz
[ __ ] Mickey and God bless him love him
rest in peace yeah I talked a little bit
about him on my wake-and-bake show
yesterday good morning uh maybe you
might Johnny B good morning Johnny B and
skunkman Sam and Todd McCormick as well
as a TA and ya long ribs for Mickey this
morning another cannabis activists has
passed away I never knew him as a
cannabis activists as much as I knew him
as an internet troll and I don't say
that as a negative
I just really only knew him as that and
seeing the beautiful wonderful things
that people have said to him I'm pretty
much concerned I believe that they're
not saying it just because he's passed
away the guy actually did some great
things and had a lot of people actually
loving him so rest in peace Mickey
thanks for the good work that you did in
the cannabis industry yeah Mike Mickey
was a pioneer in the edibles here in
California and he was busted and did his
time and took his lumps and yeah always
yeah he was definitely a troll he gave
people their [ __ ] he was kind of uh he
was a [ __ ] stirrer but he was our [ __ ]
stirrer right he was never afraid to
call everyone in anyone
I was very fortunate not to be on the
[ __ ] list at the same time if you were
you resent you received samarth and it
was usually justifiably so you didn't
just pick on anybody just to pick on
anybody
no body who was doing [ __ ] and he gave
you the shit's I don't know I will ever
replace somebody like him in our
movement irreplaceable but I just want
to send out my love to his family and
friends absolutely I saw Debbie Gold's
brewery and many others just writing a
really great [ __ ] about him so it was
that's always nice to see when people
have nice things to say about people
rather than the tossing of them under
the bus I don't even see him in the room
yet yeah get in the room oh my goodness
how's everyone doing this fine fine
morning I'm alive as well well that's
great to hear
we're glad that you're alive and well
just doing bone ribs loving you missing
you some cabins some Davin's wow chat is
moving so fast that was an insane I
looked over at it it was like well
wasn't for you and Sam I wouldn't be
smoking sift every day so well if it
wasn't for you growing your own weed
give yourself a pat on the back Johnny
be well I agree if you can't yeah I
agree
I was a morning and just oh just soaking
up a client's life and just talking to
her and just having a great conversation
pretty old sighs you know it's just one
of those things you do and yeah when
you're a gardener I was looking at he's
got plants and flowers and vegetables
all around this place I'm not hanging
baskets and stuff like that you gonna
put the Sun just to get the ladies going
yes
nothing like talking to your plants you
know how many people here talk to their
plants whenever they're working with
their plants Todd's like I don't talk to
my plants they gave more do
I give my plants the passive-aggressive
cold-shoulder is what I do not me man
man please grow plant please no I'm not
I don't think that works as much as love
care nutrients air water like I go with
those things
well the dank Duchess is in the in the
room right now and she says she does
talk to her plants I think she's saying
that she said me with a smiley face
hello welcome good morning thank done
that's just good morning Darrin mr. d
420k
oh you're late bro we've already done
that whole bond rip another lovers thing
get in here Chloe plants around your
house that yeah you're on your own guys
well on that note the other day I talked
to my mentor kind of letting the cat out
of the bag kind of thing and I don't
know if it'll manifest but I feel if I
talk about it especially to thousands of
people it'll be more likely to manifest
in my newest dream my newest
manifestation that I'm trying to get
going is thanks to Todd for inviting
forever flowering greenhouses in here
because I'm still thinking about that
greenhouse non-stop thinking about
putting it in behind my house thinking
about getting my mentor Ron Hickey to
move from his grow in the Kootenays to
come out here and take care of the grow
it would be the r grow in the back yard
here and just do shows every day with
tips from Ron I mean the guy has he
truly knows how to grow great cannabis I
put him up there with a lot of people
that I know we often say he's forgotten
more about cannabis than most we'll ever
learn and so we were looking forward to
maybe getting that manifestation in the
next couple of months a reality build an
ice forever flower in green house in the
backyard start the project plants a
whole crop of Congolese is what we were
thinking to do it may be 99 Congo plants
and I just think it would be great just
for the social media for the wake and
bakes for me to be able to hang out
one of my best and oldest friends mentor
father figure grandfather figures so
that's sort of something that I'm hoping
that's gonna happen in the near future
even if the grow itself didn't happen
and I just got Ron out here living out
here in my kids life in my life that to
me would be a win-win-win but if the
green house happens and the grow happens
well it's gonna be fun I'll tell you
what it's gonna be fun well why not well
that's just it I have a federal license
for 99 plants and I don't have a single
plant in the ground like what is wrong
with me think of all the money you can
save don't have to buy pot if you just
spend a couple hundred grand growing it
ya know it's for real and and cuz Ron
and I obviously have no interest in
undermining the the program and selling
the plot as much as we just want to the
value really will be in the sharing of
the information the social media
promotions the photography that I'll be
able to get and all that sort of eye
candy and then for me really the real
value I'm not gonna lie he's getting to
spend time with one of my mentors man
like these these guys are getting older
and older and I just I'm getting older
and older and I want to spend as much
time as I can like I wish I had 50-plus
years to spend with my mentors let alone
the 20 or 30 or 40 that I might be
limited to depending on how long we get
to live yeah I know Tahoe bird an unused
federal license hmm yeah I know
nice how was that it's cool they're all
in their 60s and it's funny to see all
these like raging hippies that are like
you know professors and all welted ooze
and there's still such rage and put it
but their lawyers and their professors
and their scholars and you know it's
it's it's a cute mix it shows me that
even stoners can grow up to be very
productive successful members of society
established that's not that's the truth
right there there's no doubt about that
a STONER I mean even the word stoner it
always seems to have this sort of at
least through the prohibition lends this
a negative connotation although when I
hear stoner I think of I think of more
positive things I'm not gonna lie
because well because I'm a STONER
well we've accepted that myth pride
because what else you gonna do you know
yet to accept your you know stoner you
know badge with honor because yeah
because of the misinformation and you
realized it's so early so we went out
and preached about it and yelled about
it and sit on street corners and people
were like what the [ __ ] you talking
about weed
y'all are high yes we're high we're just
trying to make sure everybody is aware
that we're successful in high as well
you're more than welcome to join us
along the way if you like highly highly
misting the other day man starts talking
about all these cops stopping searching
on us after they legalized in various
states you know what I gotta say this
after the whole Alma our Alma Alma
whatever you guys want to call it the
arguments against and for it really
seems that Todd from you prop 64 you may
have fallen on the right side of things
because I'll tell you not a single
person who argued against it is
continuing to I haven't seen them say
post about look at this [ __ ] the
cops aren't even searching us anymore
and a bunch of people got led off the
head that had charges that's [ __ ]
man I need 300 grams $300 a gram for my
[ __ ] it's like sorry actually right even
the people that aren't that we're hating
it love it now because they're not sweat
and driving their [ __ ] around they're
not worried it's a different world right
now and you know they can all kiss my
ass I mean it was the right side of
things to fall on you know we need to be
free we shouldn't be criminals and
decriminalization the answer is an idiot
because it makes you a criminal in the
first place
we should be decriminalized because
we're not [ __ ] criminals to start off
with yeah I'm surprised I'm really
surprised at how these posts that are
coming out after this Prop 64 seem to be
extremely positive I mean people that
were going to be charged having their
charges dropped cars not getting
searched by cops I mean those are major
major major big deals
one of the reason it is so major is
because that gave them access to all the
other charges in other words if they
could get inside your vehicle and start
snooping around who knows what they
might find well I can tell you exactly
what they're gonna find in my vehicle
and it's not going to be good like when
I got pulled we can smell cannabis and
that led them to my searches
yeah they searched my car's which John
replied I am cannabis yeah I'm actually
I love it that I handed him the
container what smell proof he opened up
smelt and gave it back to me I'm a 44
year old flowering cannabis plant well
the great thing about 64 is it should
move the line in the sand completely I
read I have lawyers that I follow on
Facebook and every day I read someone
else dismiss someone else felony
dismissed felony dismissed and I would
love to just stack those the the fifty
to a hundred that I have seen go by of
people and just you know really hit
those people who are giving us so much
[ __ ] for 64 you know and just remind
them hey you really were happy with this
person going to jail or going through
this your you know where are you to not
celebrate these people not going to you
including somebody with staunch against
it came out and immediately had a case
and I mean it was thrown out right after
it happened and they're like oh I'm
loving rim on Dennis perón's Facebook
page after I saw that thousands of
cannabis cases are getting dismissed
because it's like how could anybody in
this industry not support thousands of
people getting their lives back and get
of course and not having to pay lawyers
actually dependent on the trade and
Engel prices DePaul bingo well I'll tell
you what it's pretty shitty that that
many people faust people that claim to
be activists that fought against prop 64
I don't see them doing any activist work
anymore and it just seems to be a like
what what if Shh like that got real
personal it wasn't like people were
being mature and arguing on amateur
level [ __ ] got super personal which I am
inclined to believe Sam because the
level of personal that it reached was
like you're taking away my livelihood
which is like guess what if your
livelihood is based on people going to
prison and prohibition [ __ ] your
livelihood and [ __ ] you so no offense
but come on like that's not a good
profit margin we deserve it I love you
I'll be like for the Americans
perspective [ __ ] full offense if you
think your neighbors should go to jail
because you deserve to get high-priced
or pounds of pot you are an [ __ ] hold
on that's an insult to [ __ ] cuz
[ __ ] are useful people do not err in
that mindset or straight off pieces of
dog [ __ ] with the dog on the arm the dog
on the arm expert in dog poop well you
know what we're still not seeing prices
drop link here in Canada we have legal
cannabis access for years but
legalization happens in 2018 let's see
those prices drop so axe accessibility
will be more there for everybody can't
wait that's it access for everyone I
mean you know what it's funny because
this industry is a lot of different
things I mean we we all came from
different aspects we let ourselves into
this sort of you know cannabis led us
down this sort of guiding light that is
all there's really a lot of good that
you can do with this plant like it's
bigger than just getting high it's
bigger than me having access to it it's
bigger than me grow
making profit and you meet people like
Forrest and you meet you know these
people that are that are doing really
really incredible things and it makes
you feel proud to be a part of this
industry you know and I'm sorry but
fighting against something like
proposition 64 which is gonna let all
those people go free and lose I mean
Todd you yourself went free like what
the hell you got off did you not yes yes
they finally after four years no no they
didn't drop the case against me because
I wouldn't cooperate that's right now I
know I know you talk you know you're
solid guy you you talk a real game you
say hey jail is not the worst thing in
the world bla bla bla bla bla but I will
tell people out there who have never
been to jail and who are only
potentially facing jail there is serious
energy that goes into that it's like
getting audited it's like a family
member passing away sometimes if you
don't have that if you have that fear of
like oh no what they're taking my
freedom away their take and that's a
heavy thing to lay on someone for years
of their life four years of his life
without even getting five but but let me
say this the fear is worse than the
reality people who are through prison
get out of prison make meaning yes and
like for me I I self surrendered to it
way a long time back because I figured
I'm [ __ ] with fire and there's no way
I'm not gonna get burned at some point
I'm debate and guys like the DEA head at
had freaking University of Miami I'm
pretty much sure and there's a target on
my back
and Joseph featuring yeah [ __ ] him but
but at the same time the reality was is
that you know it wasn't that hard to go
through and I tell anybody that's facing
any case don't don't fear it don't run
from it just go up show up show up on
time be polite go through it get out and
trust me it'll be behind you quicker
than you can imagine
I mean that I so mean that if we all
threw ourselves at the courts the courts
would break if we all pled not guilty
and and push them to trial they would
not be able to afford to prosecute us we
could break the system it's just that
fear inhibits our ability to do so most
of the time and it's changed the
dynamics ten years ago for the ad
Rosenthal trial I had to go before a
grand jury and into federal court and
declare my fifth and tenth Amendment now
that wouldn't be necessary
you know due to the law change and one
of the reasons we're also celebrating
the life and the past that was federal
that was federal McCarran that was your
and I could still go down that could
still go down and this and the stance a
teen took was I will not cooperate in
this prosecution and he was facing
rockin prison because he wouldn't
basically testify on stand he said no I
plead the fifth at that point they say
okay you realize you can be held in
contempt of court and the choice is
either ok speak or go to jail and you
know at that point I love you 18 you
chose jail and a lot of people should
choose jail you have to stand in the
fear you have to be there you have to
you can't run away from it once your
subpoena knew you're in with the Dragons
Claus oh yeah well you have to ride it
out and you have to hold your head high
do it right you have good lawyers don't
capitulate as Todd said don't cooperate
in any way shape or form there's no need
for its them to prove it against you no
need for you to give them any more
information that they need to to
prosecute you but dynamics are shifting
and hopefully they're they'll shift
federally but as I was saying and one
reason we're talking and celebrating
Mickie Martin's life is because he was
one of us who got busted and and when he
was busted after he was busted then he
started a toy drive every winter every
Christmas he started a toy drive to
raise money for toys for kids whose
parents are in jail right now for life
sentences or or less and he and I
donated to it every year and then he
started to do in the fall he did the
same thing for back-to-school so we
could buy them new shoes school
equipment anything you need to get back
to school because as you know when
somebody is in jail they lose everything
and those kids are in foster or with
grandparents or with the set parent and
their lives are completely upended and I
will forever give mad respect and I
think they're gonna rename the toy drive
for Mickey Martin and they should
because it was his instigation to never
forget those right now even though we're
celebrating our victory never forget
right now somebody is in jail right now
suffering and he never got those kids
and their faith
we're taking care of along the way not
just someone not just someone that that
is in jail either a tan but you called
it with the children you know it's one
thing to say I'm gonna go do jail when
you have no children but you know Lois
Lane who's in the chat room right now
said her father got 10 years in the
1980s for growing cannabis he was in
jail he was not there to watch her grow
up he was not there to protect her and
when he came out of jail she was a
stranger to him and that's an extremely
serious heavy heavy thing that if you
don't have kids you can't possibly
imagine the level of sacrifice that
you're making when you go off to prison
for 5 or 10 or 15 years and those those
kids just you know they don't get raised
the same way no and you know one thing I
want to say I felt like after five years
of like living in and out of a visiting
room in a US prison i watch families I
see what it does to them and one of the
reasons I was such an advocate of 64 is
because something has to stop child
protective services from destructing
families and ripping us apart from our
from our kids or from our parents and
putting us through hell I mean because
that's really what's happening because
our parents don't drink wine they smoke
a little pot that means that that their
families get ripped apart I just think
it's a horrible situation and those
those poor kids are doing time with
their parents and that's what's [ __ ]
up you know you're locking up some dad
for growing you followers and that poor
kids crying every night that kid is
missing his dad that kid doesn't have
mentoring for why because the guy grew
flowers in his backyard it's just gotta
stop you called it dude those kids are
doing time as well and there's a lot of
kids doing time through their parents
you know and their loved ones and
opportunities are lost they'll never
have they never know you know that
confidence lost is that affects all
throughout their lives so it destroys
you know it's it's sad I've seemed way
too many of it and I'm glad to see that
least there's a ripple that's started
and hopefully it'll spread to other
states and across into other countries
by the way congratulations for medical
marijuana in Mexico did you see that
this week I did see that yeah [ __ ]
pretty I can't help but felt that was a
little like Trump jab
at present no I don't thought it wants
to be really honest I think that a lot
of countries you know what in some ways
that his presidency could prove to be
very positive because it will cause a
lot of other presidents a lot of other
powers that be to be proactive about
what it is they don't like and can't
stand that makes sense yeah yeah you
know people are like oh they knew the
consequences so it's like listen this
isn't murder this isn't robbing a bank
this is growing a [ __ ] flower the
fact of the matter is the consequences
shouldn't exist in civil disobedience
until it doesn't exist absolutely must
the kids didn't grow them I like that I
really I couldn't meet my mic fast
enough to say absolutely at most and and
you can't blame the kids the kids didn't
grow the plant the kids are the victim
of the the circumstance of the decisions
of the adults they had no sir no clothes
you know no planet in any way shape or
form they just have to write it out and
are the victims they've lost their
parents their parental unit and you know
there's stability what they knew is
their lives growing pot for his kids
what about something like my mom was
giving me pot when I was nine I mean a
lot of times the reason these people are
pushed to this is because they're trying
to save their health of their children
right they've got no other risk they've
got nothing else to lose they've lost
everything else is this is the last
dance I mean look at force look at
everyone else and many of us who have
found cannabis it was almost like you it
was the last stance your mom finally was
like I mean how many cancers had you
gone through seven to eight cancers by
the time she already decided to finally
give you pot you know that nine okay
that's kind of I might want to back that
up a little bit you know I'm saying I
mean I know you were released what you
were to in the earlier honestly now how
I mean do you think she should have
given it to you at two she well now that
I know about animals but she wouldn't
look they were giving me [ __ ]
chemotherapy and put me on radiation at
age two so I don't know I mean if you're
if you're able to give me chemotherapy
at four or five six why the hell can't I
have pot I mean I wish she had given it
to me Oh
years earlier she didn't give it to me
until I was nine and I had it in soft
tissue between my left London my heart I
only wish but I'm glad she gave it to me
at all I mean to be honest where would I
be without it I wouldn't know yeah and
I'm glad I know yeah I'm sorry went
through it but like you said you know
you hate that I went through war myself
but I'm glad I went through it so I was
a patient so I met knew all of you I
don't you know sit there and wish any
illness on Ronnie Lee I want to say this
alone I actually embalming went through
it and ironically I've actually I I
caught a little slack to saying that I
wish Jeff Sessions our Attorney General
would get cancer so we'd have a change
of heart and you know and I'll say flat
up if it doesn't kill you if it brings
out compassion and people it brings out
empathy in people because they
experienced the end of life and it
changes your whole view and everything
so I'm really really appreciative of the
fact that I went through cancer as a
child I'm really appreciative of the
fact that I had to face death and I
learned about life and I learned about
passion and honesty and and everything
good in my life through that so I'm glad
I had cancer and honestly I don't even
feel bad when I meet some people that
have cancer because I feel like
something in life is gonna kill you
anyway
and I made the comment to people it's
better to die with your eyes open
then they hit get hit by a train and
live your entire life with your eyes
closed not even knowing they were closed
hmm yeah that's heavy dude only someone
that has lived through what you lived
through could really say that have that
perspective you know it's a great
perspective life is a lot of people
walking through life asleep zombie dried
out and it's even if it's right at the
end of life if you can get awoken if you
can see a different perspective there's
real value in that eat that red pill
we've only all on the plant panel here
you've eaten the pillow you gotta think
sessions knows some family members that
have cancer like you got you can't
imagine his entire family just like it's
impossible whose family doesn't have
cancer well you know what though I mean
he comes
part of the deep cells where things are
a little bit old-fashioned and
realistically the hard prejudices are
hard to lose and and we're dealing with
some real and green to bigotry with
these people going way way way way back
and the reality is and unless it's his
loved one or his daughter or somebody
and somehow his mind is opened up hey
listen you know even if you watched the
DVD extras on the culture and you
listened the Annie story which is dr.
Lester Grinspoon talking about how
resistant he was initially to giving his
son Danny cannabis when he had cancer
and it was his wife that went behind his
back went to the schoolyard hit up one
of his friends got him some pot and gave
it to him without less for knowing
because Lester was worried about what
Harvard would think if they found out he
was breaking the law and doing this but
that so makes sense Todd and you know
what it's a perfect example too because
we know that Lester is a loving
empathetic man he is a good person but
the power of worry of a prestige of a
position of a doctorate degree all of
these things and I've met incredible
doctors out there who are terrified not
even forget about giving their son or
their daughter cannabis they're
terrified to tell people that cannabis
can shrink a tumor they won't even say
it it's like a bad word they're like oh
oh no we can't say that well why not why
can't you say that it's a fact it can
doesn't mean it always will but the fact
that it can means you should be able to
say it they're scared man they got they
got a lot to lose which is crazy because
the person dying has a lot more to lose
hey let me say shout out to dr. Prince
Boone he turned to 89 years old
yesterday I saw that happy birthday
Lester but doctors became the frontline
as stated before you know when prop 215
pass the they went after the doctors and
the doctors had to physically band
together and actually push back against
the prosecution of the federal
prosecutor at the time or the head of
the drugs or even was coming out and
publicly shaming them and they were
taking that type of ribbing I mean that
that's that's huge when you
have literally the top lawmakers in the
country [ __ ] on you in the national
media that goes out back when the press
secretary and everybody all went in one
location and got debriefed I mean
actually really tried to destroy their
careers and they actually used Todd
McCurry as slides and put his quotes on
CNN in it and it was our drug czar what
was his name at the time barry mccaffrey
and he came out and publicly went out he
actually came out and named dr. todd
materia because I mean at the time in
the 90s there was a handful of these
people that you could point to all over
the country that were actually vocal
advocates writing books and calling for
change I mean really literally I could
rattle their names off the top of my
head and unfortunately a lot of them
have passed away you know like dr. John
Morgan who wrote the Jonas in marijuana
fax who was awesome what a great guy dr.
Todd McCurry ahooo the CMA California
Medical Association went after around
215 because he was one of the most vocal
advocates that we had he was one of our
first whistleblowers anybody listening
to this should look up his name Tod with
one D and it's mi ke you are iya is how
he spelled Nick areia and he is one of
the pioneers in this if it wasn't for
him in dr. Lester Grinspoon I don't know
what it would have looked like in the
70s and 80s trying to get information
about medical cannabis and fortunately
they led to then my doctor dr. frank
lucido who in berkeley became a
predominant one and actually joined in
suit with Tod mikuriya against the the
feds to actually win the right for
doctors to be able to continue to have
that confidentiality between patient and
doctor to discuss your medical cannabis
so and that still goes on today as each
one of these new states go on now
enlists the challenges and the fears of
now doctors to write the prescriptions
because those earlier ones that write a
lot of prescriptions like dr. Todd
McCrea had CMA you know those state
medical boards come after you and are
vindictive so it requires strength of
be educated then in those states to
actually ride that hind actually skate
on that razor's edge doing that right
for everyone still and that's happening
with each state's accession you know
vindictive another word for
endocannabinoid efficient so true I just
I couldn't even I smoke so much cannabis
and I've had people do me so wrong and I
just like I wish the best for them I
don't want them I don't want them to
have suffering I don't want them didn't
you know I I just vindictive is such a
strange energy it's not the energy that
if you use cannabis on a daily basis
that you want to feed that's fish but
those medical boards are nothing but
those strict run the line line followers
can I just say this it was because dr.
Todd and guys like um what they were
such a threat and that's that's really
the the reality of it is they knew the
information they were presenting was
true it was not something they could
debate so the easiest thing to do was to
attack the person presenting the
information and they did you know I was
gonna say doctor dr. William Idleman who
was one of jack harries earliest other
than doctor materia recruits into the
activism game is still an activist today
and he put his medical license on the
line to advocate medical cannabis after
meeting jock he was really a hero he
still is it's a great guy out of Los
Angeles and I've always had so much
respect for him but the California
Medical Association tried to revoke his
medical license over his stance on
medical cannabis and he fought them
tooth and nail that's what they love to
do I'm just talking with dr. David Allen
right now who's also been through some
some similar things with his license etc
I've invited him on he doesn't have the
right computer he says he has an Apple
phone I said if you can figure it out
and put your phone down so you're not
moving around we would love to have you
on for discussion Alec is also going to
be at his lab in about five minutes and
from SC labs and he'll be coming in in
the next ten minutes so I have a feeling
our conversations gonna get a little
scientific here in the near future
well it's good it'd be great to have you
good from a doctor's perspective
you know because to hear from you know
they're educated standpoint regarding
all the different fears that they have
to actually face you know from going
through school from doing their actual
you know I know students that actually
become going on to become doctors that
they took a very great risk by choosing
to you know research cannabis as their
thesis all the way through their
doctorates and we're very successful in
doing so and you know they had to
actually physically take a risk because
that was their financing whether their
professors would accept or reject it or
anywhere along the line to where they
got their you know doctor certification
much less when you step out into the
real world so there's risks all along
the way if you really want to come out
and be one of those that are spoken out
regarding cannabis well you know I'm
gonna say something because somebody
wrote in the chat on the video the other
day that you know I was crazy if I
didn't think that people were still
getting the doors kicked in and and
getting raided and stuff and let me tell
you something I am all too aware of
what's happening everywhere else in the
world and I really still one of the
reasons I hope that we do the show and
that more information gets out was
because I hope people see the
normalization of cannabis that's
happening here in California and in
Colorado and in Washington and in other
places like Oregon and and demand that
happen where they live I hope that our
stories inspire people in places that
aren't yet legal together take the step
forward and go engage and and you know
I'm not saying go to prison I'm not
saying you know go compromise your
families but I'm saying don't be afraid
anymore
you have so much information behind you
use it you know you know if your
smartphone get educated people like me
don't have to go to places like Kinkos
to hand you copies of the book that is
expensive and hard to get anymore you
can go on your phone and read every
single chapter of Jack Harris book The
Improv wears no clothes free on Jack
CARICOM if you want to and get inspired
it's that easy I mean and I and I
implore people to do it and when they
meet their politicians don't let them
escape the fact that they're carrying
smartphone because you're stupid if
you're carrying a smartphone and you
don't know how to look stuff up yeah for
real
so reopen the word ham hit enter go to
the Wikipedia and start learning some
history because this is all of our
history this is connected to all of us
it doesn't matter what color what race
what country you came from cannabis has
a connection to you when you need to
learn it
hey dr. David Alan just wrote me a
message saying the California Medical
Board targeted him because the drug task
force called the Medical Board in
California and I guess that was where he
was where he had his problems I think it
was in Maryland or something it was
definitely not in California I thought
it was like out east somewhere that he
originally had his problems with the
drug force just criminal unfortunately
this is gonna happen state to state this
is gonna happen cuz there is
institutionalized bureaucratic bigotry
that we are dealing with all the way
across the board so every single state
in this Union that legalizes is going to
be dealing with some jerk along the way
it's gonna resist resist resist
I think what's fortunate for us though
is that we gained momentum and as we get
more numbers behind us and we get more
wins behind us and there's more
information around us it's easier for us
to overcome the people that are in our
way with misinformation
Jeff from Aqualab says the cops came
into our borough two weeks ago I just
walked out got in my car and drove away
that's what we did to it I guess
I hope cops did the same thing yeah
seriously I hope you're okay dude I hope
all is well with everything down there
for you Jesus
cops yeah let me say this though even if
this is the beauty of California right
now there was a story that it doesn't
matter if it's 2:00 or 2000 it should
have been 7 or 7,000 because any number
over the 6 plant limit is only being
charged as a misdemeanor so there's
really so you could go girl 4,000 pot
plants 4116 park lands in your bel-air
home and the state of California can
only charge you with misdemeanor
manufacture I guess they're still gonna
call that I wonder
they're gonna call it cultivation yet I
wonder if they've learned that it's a
plant quite yet it doesn't seem so
because the absurdity of what they're
trying to do would just be so unveiled
if they actually had the realization
that it was like like what you said many
shows ago these people are habitual
florists like habitual florists think of
how absurd that is I love growing
flowers and plants you know though can I
say straight up and Johanna probably
totally agree
and anyone who grows understands you
know I was lucky to learn how to grow
car when I was 13 years old because it
taught me the cycle of life it taught me
how to plan ahead it taught me how to
use nutrients and think about what I was
feeding living a living thing in my life
you just want me how to feed myself it
taught me the value of pH and water
it taught me actually how to not care
too much for something and to let it
grow I mean growing cannabis was the
best life lesson I could have ever
experienced and and I've said this to a
lot of people I was lucky to be grown
apart at 13 14 15 16 because mother
nature looking over my shoulder always
always rewarded me for my efforts
meaning if I grew an extra hundred
plants I got an extra hundred plants
worth of energy but my friends on the
other hand who were working minimum wage
and and kind of doing minimum amounts of
work for that minimum wage in return for
getting the least amount of money they
could get a they did the least amount of
work they could do they I on the other
hand was learning how to like work hard
and apply myself and to like throw in
all my effort because I knew I would be
rewarded if this makes sense whereas my
friends at work they could bust ask for
three months go to their boss out for
rays and get laughed at and that's a
[ __ ] up lesson to be learned and when
you're 16 17 18 and instead having
gardening they actually taught me a very
different lesson taught me how to wake
up early and work hard and [ __ ] stay
at it and I'm so thankful for that it's
good to be thankful hey what's going on
Alec I see you've made it to your lab
hey what's up Marcus how you doing good
morning good man setting the phone down
getting it all sorted out yeah yeah
sorry I apologize have been some
unreliable in the past what happened bro
we had Tim on last Sunday he was so
enthusiastic and then we saw the website
on Wednesday so we'll figure we wait and
ask you totally well last weekend for
what it's worth I had just the day
before I got back from a 16-day
whitewater rafting trip down the Grand
Canyon and and when I got back I didn't
have my internet in my house no you know
I meant the show was canceled the the
country fair was Hollis yeah yeah could
you just a little bit because we wanted
to talk about the contest in the way you
divided up the turf in categories but
obviously now you have some information
about the show not happening yet totally
yeah yeah and I was just going to worth
making a shitty excuse for why I wasn't
able to make it but but anyway yes so so
yeah we're really excited at Kemps
Country Fair you know we're about to do
a real cool kind of interesting way of
basically having the judging process
take place you know taking into account
kind of chemo typical profile is a
little bit more you know and use it you
and and just try and celebrate a lot
more the diversity of what cannabis has
to offer
you know um through this new type of
judging that we were gonna try out um so
so for most worth you know that you know
they were going full-bore and they had
some really really interesting big
production team backing them to help
kind of make this event happen and you
know it's it's it's interesting because
you know just with as many events as
there are now and as much as you know
people that are holding events and doing
promotions are vying for people's
attention throughout the summer to try
to come to these different events
you know when they they just kind of saw
I think some early signs and early red
flags on you know it possibly not
getting you know the type of turnout
they were looking for you know just your
kind of the full moon eclipse kind of
symbiosis event happening same after
that with you know and that
is kind of I think well okay that's the
summer you know that's like sold out
kind of tens of thousands of people I
think from Southern Oregon but no you're
right the logistics are doing it around
other event has to be considered earlier
on and it's yeah it's definitely a
reality you know you're talking about
drive oh you're cracking up on us Alec
something something just blew with your
mic that sounds like a death sounds like
something actually gluten yeah hear us
no no we can't hear you anymore we can't
meet that mic for a second yeah it went
correctly correctly bad correctly
exactly correctly
yeah his audio just went pooched it was
that me yeah I think you're okay now I
think it was like a weird feedback or
whatever you know another thing I was
gonna say is probably he had mentioned a
serious production company that he had
gotten into partnership with for this
project and I kind of got the idea that
it was them that looked at it and said
listen like we just can't we're not
gonna be able to get all this happening
in any time yeah you know I think I
think they're some of their insights
kind of yo on some of the red early red
flags were kind of you know I can get
the really big indicators that kind of
Tim took to heart to kind of make that
decision you know but yeah I mean it's
for what it's worth though it's it's
it's it's funny because you know the
emerald cop has become such a you know
logistical just like it's it's the you
know where the the biggest you know
influxes of samples that we ever see out
our loud and so kind of peachy earns now
that we've been doing it for the last
seven years you know we've we've we've
tried to put together a team to a lot
more early on in the year you know kind
of help to really work out the logistics
and how you know the deadlines and the
in-sample intake and stuff like that are
gonna go you know to avoid this huge
kind of collision nightmare that can
very often happens you know especially
when the the Emerald cup could have
sampled your total amount of entries
kind of has gone up from
you know five years ago around 100-150 -
each year almost doubling you know and
and last year with all the categories
combined it was like I want to say
there's like 1,300 entries and 800 of
them came in in the last like two days
or three days which is after Tim had
pushed and extended the deadline trying
to include more people because there's a
lot of people up in arms and so my cups
happen in this year but can you wrap a
little bit because you were involved in
the thought process that broke the
contest into a new a new kind of contest
and turned it into these five different
turkey in categories yeah and I really
would love to you to talk about why you
selected those five terpenes and also
what those those five terpenes are and
also um as a lab are you you just using
spikes I mean could you explain the
little process a little bit talk about
that because I find it so fascinating
awesome no no but absolutely um so yeah
so essentially you know for the last
nine or ten months at here I see labs
we've been working with a data scientist
a gentleman by the name Stelios who's a
Greek dude from out he used to do a
little bit of work with bedroo can and
and are no you know kind of you know
attempting to you know look at their
chemometric data and kind of identify
trends and you know interesting kind of
you know aspects of their data and and
so so you know we started working with
him because we we have a lot of turkey
data that we wanted to aggregate like
look into and so and I think I might
have potentially mentioned this before
on here but we basically set out to
create
terpene classification system and you
know when when we came into it we you
know didn't really know what we were
going to find or see but you know after
nine months and a lot of back-and-forth
it's kind of working with this data
scientist to kind of fine-tune this
these different statistic data tools he
was using things like pls da which which
is like partial least mean square and
analysis I want to say if I'm not
mistaken and then like certain types of
clustering algorithms like or clustering
tools like k-means
Kings clustering artificial neural
networking we started using combination
of these different tools to kind of
develop a novel oh wow that was quick
just got bumpy d boomed
I almost thought for a second I
accidentally here's a funny thing
sometimes if I'm typing and having
off-screen conversations and my cursor
is on the chatroom here in the Google
Chat it will it could dump people hey
welcome back Alex Alec I almost thought
I bumped you out there but I see you
just left by accident yeah no I just
dumped me
anyway if there was a way you could send
me the Google hangout a link to my email
I'm gonna try to shift from my phone to
my computer I think that'd be a little
bit better oh yeah dude you tell me the
email what is it Alec @s Sealab Sealab
is exactly Seb Escom yeah okay so
hatched cool but I don't know where I
fell off there but essentially we've
been working for the last nine or ten
months now to you know basically sort
through and cluster our terpene data to
to type in an effort to create a terpene
class system and and you know what we
found is really interesting in that you
know with about 95 plus percent accuracy
and predictability you know we can
essentially send any terpene report that
we test of any strain that comes across
our labs and and it fits you know very
interestingly into one of essentially
about four major primary buckets you
know or clusters and then within each of
the primary groups or clusters there's
an additional you know between like two
to three subgroups that that you know
any strain that we pass into it
essentially very predictably falls into
and and it's it's what's what's
interesting about the system is it's
very intuitive if you know the smell of
cannabis you know and and you know so so
kind of on on you one spectrum of
of this of this class system you know
you have Turpin lean as this primary
terpene that you know you know from from
from the clustering is either you know
they're pretty significant amounts or
it's not all there and and Turpin lean
is the dominant primary terpene in you
know such a range of the you know quotes
sativa stimulating strains that we know
like jacker air train wreck Durban sage
you know you know Dutch treat you know a
lot of Hawaiian stuff that you know that
is around are still barely around but a
lot of those xjj one you know you know
that those strains all smell slightly
different from one another but yet
they're more closely related in
similarity than trying to compare that
to say Sour Diesel you know which and
Sour Diesel you know you know kind of
intuitively from the smell that it
shares probably more in common with say
chem dogging Gorilla Glue and you know
oh geez and such you know although there
are still slight variations and
differences and in I think the OG group
is one of the hardest groups to get your
full grasp on because instead of one
primary terpene you know typically
making up the brunt of the terpene
profile OG is like almost put the most
or the this fuel group is almost the
it's almost the best version I would
think of like what a hybrid kind of
terpene spectrum would look like because
it's it's not one primary terpene site
three to five turkeys and and it's
always predictably limey mer seen
beta-carotene typically at almost like
codominant amounts and depending on the
pheno it can slightly shift to become
more limonene dominant or missing
dominant element but those differences
are enough to make up you know the
differences between say Girl Scout
cookies and and and you know because you
know Girl Scout cookies is is a beta
caroling dominant strain cultivar and
the beta carotene
so its share is similar to similar to
say like Kem dog and Sour Diesel
it is Baedeker though it though all
those strains are big are typically more
beta-carotene dominant but but in the in
the gorilla glue is in sardis the Baker
ethylene will just be slightly higher
today than the codominant Mir senior
limonene as opposed to Girl Scout
cookies are some you know or strains
similar you know it'll be a appreciably
higher in beta-carotene compared to the
limonene nursing etc etc and so so in
this in this gas or fuel kind of group
you know you seem to have this kind of
shifting range of you know the primary
turkey either from like limonene to Mir
seem to be traveling the the secondary
terpenes in that group are typically
lynn Lula and human but but anyway so so
that's that's kind of one group and then
you know on the on the far other side of
the spectrum is you know the the
classical near seem group you know which
you know is is you know well it's the
biggest group that you know of all the
strains of cannabis we test you know
Mears cane and kind of the and the kind
of the fuel groups are the the most
populated groups that we see find and
and so in the mir same group you know
everything all the fruity type strains
you know kind of tangi Agent Orange you
know kind of Callie oh you know on those
classic type that smell but but you know
in that same group you also have all the
purples purple or or GDP Grape Ape you
know all those types of strains but and
and the difference is between those two
groups like that you you know from what
we see the the tan G's and a lot of
those strains are in the same primary
group as the purples and such but the
difference between the two is like a sub
grouping where the beta-carotene is you
know maybe a third of the total strain
as opposed to the mere seen which is the
primary Turkey but then you know when
you look at the tan G's and and you know
even things like blue dream and stuff
like that it's it's typically really
really high Amir seen very low
everything else but then it's
like alpha pining or some of the
chirping that's you know in some small
secondary mouth but but you know the
relationship between the primary and
secondary terpenes which typically and
and you know we just for 30-something
terpenes and it's but we what we only
see about five to nine terpenes ever
really show up in any significant amount
you know and and you know but you know
the really cool thing about the system
too is you know we have like an outlier
flag you know so if something passes
through that is you know significantly
off the norm you know it's flagged as
kind of not able to any of these primary
secondary or primary groupings or you
know these you know subgroupings
and and so so through that you know
we've been able to identify very
fascinating novelty that's that's you
know created and entered through say the
mo cup like last year you know a group
called true humble you know kind of big
farm kind of co-op type group up in
humboldt Mendo they they had to strain
the sense in which is actually for what
it's worth it was an in the pines cross
and so in the pines is you know is this
pineapple type smell strain that you
know has has historically had had high
placements and as one emerald cup in
certain year and and certain a certain
fee no it was crossed with royal cush
called it royal pines and this royal
pine strain was dominant in awesome mean
awesome mean is a really fascinating
interesting jerking that we don't really
ever see in any significant amount
except as this as a secondary terpene
that makes because so in this museum
group and i'm sorry i just were rambling
but in this mere singh group you know
you have this is one group where it's
really high mira seem very low
everything else kind of like tangi a lot
of typical kind of like you know fruits
smelling strains blueberry a lot of
stuff like that then you have this other
subgroup where it's like higher and beta
karolina is the secondary terpene and
that all of a sudden makes up all the
purples you know and then you have you
know this other subgroup in the mirror
scene of primary group
that is the secondary terpene is awesome
mean and awesome mean is OC IME Andy and
and Austin ever awesome scientist
trained that all of a sudden makes it
you know it's fall into this group that
is is like green crack dream Queen
papaya mango you know those you know you
know that smell it's like it's AI just
distinct kind of but those strange smell
similar you know same thing is like
super skunk if you've seen suitors come
it's kind of in the same world and so so
so it's so awesome even whenever it
shows is typically secondary but less
you know typically fifty percent or less
the primary perking and so so all of a
sudden now through this outlier kind of
flag you know we identified in the pines
cross that was now dominant and primary
can also mean and so so you know we
thought it was really interesting we've
also same kind of a borneol dominant
like Siberian ruderalis strain that
might one of my buddies called bacon
that he's been breeding for a little
while and so so just I'm sorry no
problem
excuse me I have a question about
classification you're making terpene
groupings and are these terpenes based
on their ability to potentiate or to
modify the effects of the other
cannabinoids or they just because
they're they're on the GC so yeah so
pretty much I mean there's no there's no
kind of combines or introduced like
Entourage you know effects you know to
it you know because essentially all
we're doing is taking the raw you know
terpene data off of the you know that
everything around from all the
chromatograms that we test through my DS
yeah I understand exactly but I guess
what I'm saying is that most of the
terpenes we talk to you about our
potentiating and modified tac for
example Mir seen certainly does lie
Moline certainly does
pionen does and little walk to a certain
degree certainly does but carry ethylene
does not it doesn't particularly
potentiate or modify recreational
effects of THC although maybe for
medical uses there might be all kinds of
applications because it's basically is
the the one terpene own to buying the cv
2 as well right
yes that's true and so I think it's
really interesting because if you if you
vaporize it with THC and pure to carry
out lean it doesn't potentiate or modify
the THC effects that's all which-which
and and that's and I think that's really
fascinating and I think these these kind
of things to tease out or some of the
most interesting things that that can be
found to help anecdotally add to
people's experience and take away some
of the the you know suggestive selling
you know because whenever a patient goes
into a dispensary or a consumer goes
into a rec you know shop and they're
looking for a strain and they know very
little to nothing about say cannabis or
the nuances of these different terpenes
and you know that they're looking for
some effect you know so much depending
on their metabolism their user
experience with cannabis you know what
you know their their food intake that
day there's so many different kind of
nuances about how strange some of the
austrians gonna help fact one person
versus another and then further you know
there's the whole idea of like biphasic
activity which just throws a whole
nother life you know a crazy aspect to
it but but but what we're hoping with
this system is you know because when you
go into a collective or dispensary and
there's you know fifty to a hundred
mason jars on onon shelves you know it's
almost you know incredibly
unapproachable is your system well is
your system at your website or online
no no it's I mean it's we were just kind
of now working on kind of the graphic
front-end you of course seen mr. Lewis's
nape row system yes
yes yes at this point is at this point
is the one that I like the best
until somebody made a better one
absolutely absolutely um you know and
you know they've definitely done a lot
of work to kind of add different aspects
of you know an algorithm to take and
combine you know data about the
entourage effect to help kind of suggest
what the strands gonna make you feel or
what have you and and you know and so I
definitely think that's that's at yeah
at this point you're pretty much when
when we did test with double-blind
patients we found that people all agreed
on the type of effects they were getting
from say THC with the people one
particular terpene but they all had
their differences in preferences to
which ones they liked but some you know
so yeah but they all agreed that it had
a similar effect with each other
what well let's say they smoked 25
milligrams of or baked 25 milligrams of
THC with the tiny spike of labelling
they all said it was stimulating
uplifting you know whereas mere seen
face in large amounts they would say
would be more couch locky for example
right and I think that's and that's that
I think such fascinating kind of
insights that we can gain also from just
the anecdotal user response that you
know people of naturally kind of you
know found and in certain strains and so
and so adding I think this level of you
know specific terpene kind of data to
help empower people's user experience or
you know kind of bun tenders
understanding of the smell of cannabis
to help make recommendations I think is
is you know one of the the coolest
things that we could help to with kind
of the data that we've got cannabinoid
level and the terpene profile levels
then in the future people will be able
to make a very educated guess on the
type of effects be even before they try
it and and and i think because
especially to interp m
like what I would ask I would actually
ask you your thoughts on pure penalty
mr. Pendley you know from all the
literature is you know fit when
vaporized is suggested to be a sedative
you know but but on you know contrary to
that what's really interesting is most
you experience I've ever had never baked
turtle I've never baked it by itself or
with pure THC like I did with the other
the other maybe top does and terpenes I
did try nice because yet because Turpin
lien you know is the good is this
primary tripping you know again and all
these like really typical quote kind of
sativa strains that people you know
think that effect with with train wreck
and Durbin and sage Zeta all those
strains and you know and so so I wonder
if kind of you know the the literature
out there that suggests that Turpin lean
when vape to the sedative I wonder if
that somehow that's mercy is reported to
be that way too if you take a small
amount of Mir seen its stimulating you
take a lot about personally its couch
lock flip there we go
so this biphasic the way cannabis and
itself is in general where at first it
stimulates and then that depresses go
degree and yes so that's and I think
it's really fascinating and then you
know also just kind of what you're
talking about with beta carolien here I
wonder how you know so so sure beta
carotene and what you're saying you know
my daddy carry alkalinity HD and it
didn't help it in any way I also tried
Barry
Terry awfully knock side that was nasty
but I wonder I wonder you know if you
had Crohn's or irritable bowel syndrome
or colitis or sometimes no no I don't
I'm a really healthy guy who just smokes
because I like to get high you're making
a lot of terpenes do have medicinal or
it's true yeah and and that so I was
gonna ask this question is what are some
in both to Sam and Alex what are some of
the most beneficial terpenes that are
found in cannabis and what do they do
with cannabis it's the most common ones
you know mersin Lima lean
pionen Linda Lau and you were mentioned
some of the other ones like gwil and
never much we don't really see those
very and very significant very large
amounts I agree come on what about
awesome mean I can't talk about it other
than I know it exists
well here's a question is that is that
you know okay there's gonna be dominant
terpenes certainly but are we going to
learn the importance of these secondary
terpenes and the effects they have on
the dominant terpenes and just a tiny
little bit being present go ahead Alec
throughout the process you know we've
been trying to kind of identity and this
further and kind of your whatever my
partner's Jeff has kind of made this
interesting kind of you know kind of
comparison to spices you know because
it's like you take you know a dash of
salt and throw into soup you know barely
affect the taste but if you take the
same you know kind of - its throw of
like you know cumin or something
you just made cumin soup and so so it's
like the presence of certain terpenes
might you know substantially be you know
these minor terpenes that are there in
faeries you know almost what seems
inconsequential you know what the actual
having you know pretty substantial
effects you know but but whenever you
look at you know kind of hundreds of
these terpene reports and you see kind
of you know these Dominator bees pop up
you know it's it's you know it's clear
that you know there's these yeah like
just like Sam was just mentioning you
know these you know what we see is about
five to nine terpenes like the major
ones exactly our mayor seen
beta-carotene limonene so you know
missing mango hops
you know the sedative effect you know
beta-carotene pepper clove
you know cb2 receptor agonist you know
I'm you know so and then which gets into
the whole idea of Canada's
other countries also too what we found
was that widely drug varieties in
general have a different suite then
narrow leaf drug varieties which have a
different suite then help varieties
which have a different suite they're all
the same terpenes a hundred and fifty or
so have been identified in cannabis but
they they tend towards certain terpenes
in certain widely narrow leaf and hemp
varieties and yeah and that's what's
interesting cuz you see certain things
clustered together where you know and
then I was bringing up earlier the
example chirp in lean you know you see
you don't usually see in any of the
other groups like the primary groups
there's the pining group there's the
mere seen group there's the kind of
combination limonene or C beta caroling
group and then there's the terpene Ling
group and in the drilling group it's
either kind of air or is not there you
know in certain times you'll see it in
summer seem dominant strains in a little
tiny amount but it's you know certain
terpenes seem to cluster together to
whenever you know and have that might
have the potential to draw certain
widely trucked high for an early
prototype i think they'll be more than
one classification system there'll be
one based on sequence e or amounts and i
think they'll also be one for ability to
potentiate or modify in a particular
direction right yeah and i think i think
that some of the most interesting ways
to use the turbine classification system
is to have an effect on breeding
potentials you know and and to be able
to combine you know fascinating terpenes
that don't really ever show up and you
know with with other terpenes you know
that you know like and and i think the
you know also means a great example that
because the AUSA mean what we see it's
either it either shows up as a secondary
tertiary chirping in this mere scene
primary group which is on this one side
of the spectrum and again that's like a
dream clean green crack that kind of
papaya mango all those types of smell
yeah like yeah and then on the other
question here if I can if I can add
before I got to jump off I got a check
out of a hotel but I just wanted to add
two things first of all I think it's
great what you're doing but always
comparing flower profiles to to extract
profiles I think is a very useful thing
to understand the impact that the
extraction process has on manipulating
is a lot of these terpenes that you
mentioned are not thermally stable and
if you stare at and frost supply
cross-eyed they do different things so
it will be really interesting to
actually correlate would be not only
from the flower to the expertise but
also what happens at a nail temperature
so if you would actually do a
headspace-gc measurement of an extract
that's a nursing dominant I will bet you
a dollar to a doughnut that at nail
temperature that mayor scene does all
kinds of different chemistry to actually
make other turbine turbine oils from
just oxidation else and if we're gonna
do this mark then we should also get a
sample fresh bud and GC acid terpenes
dried bud and then extract all from Sam
I mean I'm in the process of doing that
I mean I try to put together a data set
that I could share it that's on curing
that actually chemistry is happening you
know based on your anecdotal results
good hey folks I got a jump my people
are telling me we got to check out of
our room I will see you guys next week
thanks for coming on mark just off the
coast of Venezuela
I used tons of people that hid their
money there it's funny cuz it's true
to to to Mark's point you know it's
really interesting you guys like we have
seen a fascinating kind of you know
trend in extracts and that's that
typically most to all extracts are beta
care awfully dominant and in so many
cases seems like yeah you have the the
monoterpenes that boil off the lower
temperatures seem to go first in the
address the Lizzie true nice nice and
and and yen so so those are the more
precious delicate ones that you want
that also contributes the substantial
you know majority of most of the strains
and so in the pursuit or effort to
maximize your preservation of the cured
terpene you know potential that could be
there and how much total put terpene
potentially could be there you know it
seems like you know yeah the obviously
and everybody always knew that you know
the heat and the purging and kind of all
the curing process is Kim's kind of such
a huge way just completely have you
stray have you looked at the amount of
terpene that a fresh bud
alive fresh bud has versus a dried one
versus a manicured process one versus
extracts have you done that with the
exact same plant material to try to
understand because I always assume more
than 75% of the terpenes are lost from a
fresh plant when you dry it yeah none
exactly then that makes not a sense you
know just by it just by smelling the
terpenes in the air of like a final you
know flowering room that's about to be
harvested it means that they're boiling
off and you're you know they're getting
if you knows that so absolutely and and
so I think yet everything you do from
the moment you know throughout the
cultivation cycle and the the levels of
heat you know that you allow your room
to get up to I think you know from the
get-go are gonna have a huge effect on
on you know the overall loss and terpene
but then yeah it's like um I mean we
haven't spinner asking what a terpene
what a tripping samples like in water
half Alex
I mean you know so so what we what we
typically see is in extra
you know across the board
you know like typically between three
see about three you know one to three
percent of the you know total terpene
content in in the act and in extract
whereas if you know it's you know and if
from both water and you know kind of you
know other types of processes whenever
plant whenever you know that material
has been extracted you know you with
with care to you know and it's really
good quality material and then you know
low temperatures are used to heat purge
whatever I'm you know we see you know
put you know certain certain types of
extracts you know up to five to nine
percent total terpene content you know
and then there's these turkey super
Turkey enriched processes that you know
we see you know like holy water and
these different like terpene fraction
type processes you know we see kind of
get up to anywhere from you know twelve
to twenty percent total concentration
and then you know they get to the point
where they're just like very runny
always thought those people are actually
adding food great drippings to their
product and it would be very easy for
them to do so especially when they're
getting to these you know triple that of
a flour number of their overall terpene
in and extract so especially when you
consider what you're talking about that
almost any solvent across the board
don't matter if it's water co2 butane
propane washes the terpenes down period
and you know I'm so it's so either
they're not purging it or they're
amplifying it because if they're doing
it from a base of cannabis and they're
getting four times as much terpenes that
were found in the cannabis I suspect
[ __ ] and I this is also the my next
question what terpenes and you found
that are hazardous that people shouldn't
be breathing in what just real quick to
what you were saying you know I think I
mean I I have seen both with SIA both
done with co2 and with butane a type of
product you know that that's just you
know kind of cold oftentimes like holy
water or like Turk juice and actor
there's there it's up for it so type of
process you know and and and and is you
know not adults
and and I think that's really
fascinating you know in the potential to
kind of however they're doing it I mean
and typically in that type of extract
you know the cannabinoids don't
necessarily that high
it's like forty to fifty percent overall
cannabinoids and then you know kind of
up to you know fifteen plus percent you
know terpenes what you know what have
you well I think all plants aren't
created equally and you know some plants
are one to two percent terpene content
and there are ones that are four and
five and there are maybe the odd few
anomaly out there that are close to ten
if there are ten they were created by
man sure they were bred for sure but
imagine taking imagine taking a town
imagine taking a ten percent or a 9 or
an 8 and creating an extract with it
you're probably gonna get a higher
return in the terpenes than say your
buddy who's using the one two three
processing is losing a lot because if
you've got a couple percent terpenes and
you make the and it's twenty percent THC
by dry weight the plant material then
that means you should have eight percent
when you've got pretty much pure product
made for an extract made from it but
it's not it never is
it's always low well you say you've seen
a few people who have done it who are
especially trying to capture terpenes
and they're using really low
temperatures and specialized methods you
know I want to throw this out there you
know I have been fortunate enough to be
the photographer for childless for two
years in a row and for the secret cup
for a few years and I have seen a [ __ ]
ton of really beautiful super incredibly
well done extracts that were not
adulterated and that were super Turkey
and no disrespect to any of those guys
when I say this but they'll say it too
that they know a lot of people aren't
really doing it like this and there are
a lot of people trying to tell trade
really low par stuff
so buyer beware as I get part of my
message you know there's there is both
sides of the fence here 107 but you know
what I think we see that really
fascinating about your point Todd is
like you know you know you can I mean I
think there's so many people that test
with us so basically like they think
they're gonna they have this business
planet in their mind where they're like
alright we figured out short path and
we're gonna like you know spin [ __ ] into
gold you know and and they see this huge
margin kind of opportunity and they're
like you know and then you know come to
the realization I mean there's so much
intricacies to just the distillation
process so many people are just you know
destroying so much the THC creating like
Delta eight another kind of like
breakdown isomer like kind of almost
junk cannabinoids you know then
wondering well THC is for that's process
what-have-you but then you know I mean
it's just such a heat intensive process
to distill and create 95% Delta 9 THC
you know which you know it was often
really difficult process you know and
and so people then will you know kind of
have this kind of essentially single
it's kind of like a single molecule
isolated distillate and then you know
they think that they're gonna go tests
you know the bunch of most popular
strains on the shelves and then recreate
these Turk profiles based off the test
results and in 0.o cases I would say
it's ever worked I never had any success
which further enforces the theory
further enforces the theory that
potentially these very small amounts the
secondary and maybe even tertiary
classes of terpenes are having a deeper
effect than we understand the fact that
there's these alcohols esters and all
these different potential kind of
flavonoids and I mean and it's just yeah
it just seems like it's such a you know
amazing complex matrix of terpenes
cannabinoids all these things and it's
it's almost unform asleep utilizable in
that way or you know where you can just
like make a mixture gonna have these 13
synthetic see back whatever and get the
same effect and you know because because
for what I ended up telling a lot of the
clients that we work with that are doing
that
I'm like dude a lot all this kind of R&amp;D
you're doing is almost it's almost a
waste of time because if you're gonna
take if you're gonna try to add terpenes
back you either are gonna create you
know for the connoisseur kind of like
flavor market where you're actually like
taking distill off like you almost like
you know blue river Antonian like you
know my goods you guys are doing such
awesome work in the whole world like
natural extracts of like perfect you
know preserved terpenes off of plant and
then being able to add them as the
dilute ins you know to make a cartridge
with distillate office it makes that
cartridge taste amazing or if you
combine those turkeys with any you know
kind of crude cannabinoid you know that
you're gonna make into a vapor and
what-have-you one but for the people
that are doing trying to take limonene
your CV to coffee and blend it in
certain amounts to re-add I mean I think
it's kind of dangerous road to go down
because for one all these terpenes you
know aren't really known like you know
the I mean there's these these aspects
to like toxicity and how much you're
adding of any one of them you know and
and how you might be substantially
deviating from what cannabis would ever
produce of these certain terpene
wrestler know it's scary and and so I
mean so what I tell people is like I'm
like if you're gonna if you're gonna try
to recreate a profile you know you're
failing you should just go full banana
or you know go full watermelon you know
like strawberry lemonade you know it's
like if you're gonna do that then go
full for it you know and you because
there is some type of the market that's
gonna you possibly be interested in that
because of the whole faith community and
everybody just like you know shooting
clouds of these crazy like pg/vg like
flavor blends you know and I don't think
that's good I think you know there's a
lot not known about yeah what are those
thinners from from a scientific
standpoint like what the hell are those
strawberry watermelon bubblegum flavors
may have I don't totally clueless as to
what they are but I'm asking you what
are they what are they paper izing
right well I'm not I'm not exactly sure
you know I think maybe I don't know if
them or somebody might be able to speak
more to that but I mean yeah there are a
lot of like you know compounds mixtures
of compounds that you know probably
pretty hard to kind of enunciate and you
know it's a lot of flavoring
preservative you know there's just a lot
of crazy stuff in these in these in
these products and and yeah and whether
it's like a low temp that you're hitting
it or you're dabbing it or whether it's
up to you know like skulking hot nail
you know I mean it's like what are the
range of compounds that are basically
turning into other compounds when you're
lighting them to these heats you know
these different levels of heat because
yeah I mean you know certain things
might be attorney I mean like that was I
think that's one of the big ugly things
of the vape industry and people you know
burning or vaping PG and VG all day long
you know it's like when you're doing
that you know at these different
temperatures assess you very well
creating other types of very harmful
toxic compounds like formaldehyde and
other types of things and so it's like
is that any better for your long-term
and your chronic exposure than you know
nicotine or what have you and not not
nicotine but definitely like radioactive
nucleotides that they spray on that [ __ ]
I would have to say that that [ __ ] is so
bad that's the that's the comparison
that's why this this glycol or whatever
it is that people are clouding out on is
so nasty
but people like oh it's still way better
than cigarettes it's like oh yeah but
cigarettes a radioactive that's not a
good comparison right yeah yeah and and
so so so I think you know the idea of do
no harm you know in try to represent the
cannabis plant to the highest of its
potential integrity you know it's like
you know they're people should just you
have Wolfram a consumer and buyers
standpoint and then from people
producing products it's like she like
you know step carefully in like the
directions and really think them through
and identify you know the potential you
know hazards because yeah if you are
going full strawberry banana flavor and
adding that to distillate or CBD crystal
so you can sell it in the vape stores
you know it's like is
any better for you than you know a lot
of the other harmful products that
unfortunately were able to buy everyday
um and and NCIS I think I think from my
personal standpoint you know I prefer
you know the and I prefer my cherish in
tribute artisans able to recapture and
preserve the natural certain expression
of a plant so that they and is like wow
that's that's amazing this that's like
my favorite sage I've ever smoked in
flower form you know probably the best
way to do that is the dry sim then
nothing is altered you do have the
original terpene yeah I mean aside from
the most caustic volatile ones that
would have evaporated out in the curing
and drying of the herb and they the time
that it would take you to get those
heads off whatnot but still very correct
I mean you know Tony and I the main
reason we're really doing that alik with
you know having designed a pen that's
not disposable because I was like 20 was
like listen we got to be a part of this
California market all these pens there's
so much swag it would be great to offer
something great and then I was like well
then we got a redesign like a pen
because you guys are doing great dude
well but it's taken so long and it's a
you know what integrity is just like if
you want high profits you can't have
high integrity that's so far what I've
learned in business I learned it at my
raw food cafe which was super high
integrity super low profits like we just
couldn't bring our profits up high
without lowering our integrity and when
you go into a project like the pen
project that I'm doing with Tony it's
it's very high integrity so it's great
work but it's you know in the meantime
all these distillate companies are just
pumping hundreds of thousands of
disposable pens that people are like
those aren't good you know that's not
like California needs to be more let's
be honest that's the worst ask you this
blood wrap have you ever tested any of
those the
whatever things that they wrapped in
[ __ ] right you know I would love to
bro if you haven't you should Alex
yeah like backwards that would be that
would be really horrifying because I do
enjoy use them oh my god that's not very
scientific sir that's not exciting you
should been the first one that was like
what's in this yeah well could we
request that one for the people bro you
just uh could you test one see cuz I
would love to see the pesticides I would
love to see if there's any molds or
fronts I would love to see what's in
these things we have we have been we're
working with gentleman Roy Upton he's
the executive director of the American
herbal pharmacopoeia and he's the guy
that kind of helped ovo create and lead
the whole project to create the cannabis
monograph so it's a we've we helped him
find some funding to help kind of
further develop out the cannabis
monograph and one of the big parts of it
was to push and substantiate more of the
kind of questions concerns around the
micro different aspects of microbiology
impurities on cannabis and which ones
are benign which ones might be native
you know and westerlyns kind of our
actually pathogenic hoping to only focus
on pathogenic or I mean have to know
hoping to be a document to help
reinforce that cannabis is safe and it's
like how much are we can go to regulate
all these aspects to get zero on this
crop of these different microbes where
most of them are benign there are these
ones of concern you know that produced
mycotoxins what have you but law but
it's an effort to kind of substantiate
that further and then we're doing the
same thing with pesticide side of it and
so so we one of the projects we're gonna
do is you know so I'll add blunt raps of
all sorts and types to to to the list
but we we basically have already bought
a bunch of different types of tobacco
brand tobacco like tailor-made rolled
cigarettes
American spirit pouch tobacco a couple
of things you know we in the you know
about six months ago we did micro
testing on a lot of it you know you know
is actually about a year ago now because
before we have our new ABC x mass
spectrometer
but now that we have these new math
specs you know where the sensitivity is
down to the single-digit part per
billion etc you know kind of we're about
to kind of do a controlled experiment
type you know where we're able to
identify a document yeah a wide range of
different products that are sold
recreationally to the market to see kind
of similarly what has pesticides what
doesn't what what certain microbes are
there what aren't on the micro topic
what we saw is like a lot of you know
kind of there we see very low to no
yeast and mold but but in in a lot of
cases like America spirit powered
Chicago and bunch of different types
packs we would see about five hundred
five hundred thousand plus colony
forming units per units per gram and in
those products so so I don't know
whether that's there might be some type
of bio insecticide somebody's using them
et or yeah and so so you know in the in
the not-too-distant future and I'll
totally share that with you in our group
we will have pesticide data on kind of a
lot of these different recreational
smoked products you know because I think
those are the most interesting and
comparable to cannabis you know after
that big NBC article where you know
pesticides kind of made this huge splash
and you know what have you in Southern
California you know we didn't have a
couple couple dispensaries we work with
send him like random samplings of like
Safeway produce and vegetables you know
to test kind of tomatoes and grapes and
celery and kind of all these different
things for pesticides you know one of
the problems though is like you know in
order to do like an apples to apples
type of comparison of these pesticides
and the concentrations of these
pesticides you kind of need to try it
out similarly to cannabis would be dry
you know try it out because if you if
you're doing it wet you know the
concentrations gonna be that much less
because that much more of the weight of
the samples can be in water and you know
I think that this goes back to the you
know the question I think or you know
the experiment I think Sam was
mentioning you know we haven't done kind
of like the same plants you know kind of
measure to see loss and you know kind of
terpenes to from drying or from there's
different aspects but
we can kind of make some assumptions
based off what we see with they're just
different extraction processes like
fresh frozen live resin but yeah well
it's definitely interesting welcome
Indra we were talking about some
different terpenes I remember I remember
you would sent me your thing recently
saying that you finally tested those
terpenes that you'd been collecting so
we got you muted they're gonna unmute
your microphone that try that oh one
more time there it is yeah that's the
one
we were both unmuting your mic
simultaneously because I have the
administration abilities okay well did
you read the list I did yeah I didn't
count them or anything there was I I
didn't really understand like the
parts-per-million and stuff like how
small some of those amounts were like
which one was the primary were they in
the most to the least list is that how
they went your phone's making a lot of
weird sounds right now you something's
wrong
oh yeah well that's because the phone is
the worst possible way to do this here
oh yeah the it doesn't go to the email
huh
oh yeah sorry let me try that I guess
that's I'm amazed that people that don't
have the phones and the computers
connected I never think that way but I
can yeah yeah go go on the email I'll
send it to you there so you can get off
the phone because that's terrible okay
all right all right yeah I mean this
we'll head out okay good one thing I was
gonna add real quick before kind of we
jumped in that psycho are you familiar
you know cuz it kind of gets into that
question of like okay well terpenes are
toxic is it dangerous to be adding like
unknown concentrations different to
ravine but I also think there's
something really interesting to it
because like with Ethan Russo's new
paper you know beyond cannabis by
exploring
their cannibal mimetic plants you know
kind of one of the plants that gets into
is this you know this plant that's you
know very near and dear to me it's a you
know it's copal copal is a it's this
like an you know this is the sap from a
tree that's you know used indigenous in
the you know as a smudge you know in
ceremony spaces you know you know and
and and for what it's worth
copal has a diterpene in it that by
that's a selective seed be juice sorry
it's a it's a selective cb1 receptor
agonist so it's a its binds to CB one
and it's a terpene that and the only
other thing you know that we know
binding CB one you know any cannabis you
know primarily is THC so i think you
know what's that going to do when you
combine this terpene that binds a CB one
with THC that binds to CB one i think
it's an interesting kind of thing you
might there might be new effect created
absolutely yeah no that's cool man
that's definitely interesting i think
we're just at the cusp of learning what
we will learn in the upcoming ten and
twenty years i think it's going to be
vast when we have this next generation
of young people coming out and getting
their degrees getting their PhDs and you
know going into it with the full focus
of working in the cannabis field is
going to be a whole different ballgame
it's gonna be interesting
i see a lot of young people excited
about working in the cannabis sector if
you will and it's very it goes off in
many many different directions you could
go in a thousand different directions
with this plants in regards to focusing
your life on it well there's also
there's job descriptions and jobs things
in different states you know where you
got 28 medical states now and six to
eight coming online for a recreational
so it's a lot of opportunities out there
and i mean we're still waiting here in
california to figure out what all the
regulations or all the different things
to come on down and get solidified so
people can start working on their their
niches because there's a lot of niches
for a place for people out there you
know science key very key we're gonna
need more laboratories all over the
united states because there's going to
have to
you know ring testing all that you know
as well as people managing you know
greenhouse management come on that's
gonna be major realities and working in
you know handling gardens and doing
everything proper so before we're these
were all OJT were on-the-job training
basically you can now actually actually
get you know degrees and actually apply
them to cannabis where in the past it
was a little more difficult not saying
it's easy now but it's there's a lot
more opportunities now with the
regulation everything that's taking
place then there has been you you also
you also can't say enough about on on
the of the job training aspect of it
because you know it's it's it's
fascinating to me kind of you know how
much you can't how much of this whole
reality you can't learn in school and
and how much of an advantage and
headstart there's so many people that
have been working within this industry
in community for so long there's such a
depth and profound amount of knowledge
about this plant how to take care of it
how to you know not be reliant on
pesticides whenever you treat it and
grow it and I mean and and although yeah
I mean I totally get the point that you
know for all the new oven coming kind of
passionate members of the cannabis
community you know they're added
schooling is going to take this to a
whole another level but it's like such
deep tribute and props to all our
mentors that helped us individually get
to this point of course a lot of [ __ ]
you can school you know know know for
sure or not well that's why those people
will be working for our companies or our
these people have started their own I
mean I can't tell you about my own
employees who started in BPG that have
gone on to become doctors lawyers
scientists laboratories also of open
their own dispensaries all over you know
it's it's a constant spreading of you
know and that it's as I said goes back
to OJT but there will always be a
certain amount of OJT but there will be
a less need for OJT in the future as
more this becomes standardized becomes
you know formulas for businesses
standard operational procedures that you
know like i said back in the day i
didn't start off with
a book of rules we had no rules but over
time after nearly 18 years now I got a
lot of rules because there's a lot of
people who helped along the way that
showed us you know and shoutouts to our
mentors and those that like the forest
that showed us how to do it because back
in the day you know III was the quiet
one
doing changing the reservoirs now we
don't even have to change reservoirs
we've got dosatrons and things like
that's the technology has changed even
what I used to get paid 25 bucks an hour
to sit there and do now you know people
are getting to pay to trim now you're
talking about the wine industry is
worried about competing with the
cannabis industry because of how still
labor-intensive cannabis is and is going
to be and they can't afford to pay the
wages that cannabis companies can
currently play due to the
unsubstantiated you know false market
that exists due to prohibition that will
change as regulation comes online but
has no no not at all in any way shape or
form it's still very inexpensive to be
at the tip of the arrow but we're we're
leading the way so that you know I've
always felt 7 generations to come so
that 7 generations from now they won't
know our sorrow they won't know our pain
we've laid the groundwork I am I am one
that believes that I'm planting a tree
that I will never sit under the shade
butts or some reason I've been blessed
to sit under the shade a little bit well
that you know the the people in the
industry are basically are mostly good
people I lost my wallet at the cup and
dropped out of my pocket when I fell
over on my scooter while I was going
around rolling over one of the many
bumps to keep the wires from I had quite
a bit of money in it had my entire life
in it I didn't realize it until last
part of the day that it was gone
I was kind of bummed I didn't know how
to feel about it and three days later a
package arrived in the mail and I had a
lump and I pulled it open and dumped it
on the table and it was my wallet would
be all of the money and everything there
and the most beautiful note
but the guys who pawned it said hey done
we found your wallet and its contents
near the cash can right next to my booth
I don't know if this would reach you
safely but here's the wallet and call
this number and I will get your cash
back to you immediately DOM and Chris a
couple of really sweet guys sent back
all of it man and this was you know if
this would've been at any other fare or
whatever it would have been a GaN
gorgonzola for sure but people at these
events are people like the rest of us
that are trying to rise up and not be
the scenario that they're constantly
playing our finger at us as criminals
crooks nerdu wells and so forth if we
were nerd who else this industry
wouldn't have climbed to the point where
it's at right now in the face of all
negativity and in the face of the
politicians trying to remain power in
the face of the people who constantly
talk bad pot we still risen to the point
where we're at I went to a big giant
fair lost that wallet with a couple of
G's and it became packed in the mail
tell me that the people in this
community aren't good people I mean it's
just not gonna play with me at all
that's pretty awesome dude that's really
nice to hear it's good you know those
are always opportunities when you find a
wallet full of money and unfortunately
often people think the opportunity is oh
I found a bunch of money but really the
opportunity is to do the right thing to
be good and to you know send send it
back to where it belongs it's not yours
that's the whole thing about the whole
community is exactly what you just said
mark we're not there accusing us of
trying to make a bunch of money there
are some people in the industry doing
that let's face it there are there are
people in the industry who would steal
flies from a blind fighter okay and I'm
the first one to admit that but there's
the majority of the people in the
community are good people and they're
trying to do the right thing and that
constant pressure
of trying to do the right thing back in
the face of this approach them what's
gonna save us now look that VA is
starting to tremble a little bit because
there's so many vets right now crying
back to the government the that death
rate from suicide for PTSD is rising as
we speak and people who are trying to
keep at it
yeah there's people trying to combat it
as we speak but you know you you've got
a lot of people out there who think that
the little tiny caveat of pot that it
did should I this and all the healing
stuff it does is driving the rest of
when it's crazy you know it does
something good and just because you get
a little high well it's doing it people
don't want us to have that but they will
drink and they'll smoke and they'll
drive their cars fast and all the rest
of the things that are truly a danger
they all have guns
I'm sick and tired of guns I got shop I
want to be it non so you can imagine I
don't have one I don't want one don't
even one them anywhere nearly and so you
know and not change subjects quickly the
the terpenes they were listed there in
parts-per-million but that wasn't the
point the list was long and there were
many many campaigns on that list that I
haven't seen on other lists yeah even if
they were just there in
parts-per-million it points out the fact
as to our technology grows and were able
to advance enough understanding we're
picking up new turf beans beans that we
previously haven't been picking up and
I'm going I'm just always for advancing
this whole deal as much as possible for
good if you make sure you know let's do
it on it Turpin's we enjoy if you if you
wouldn't mind what were some of the
terpenes you you were just describing
that you were seeing that you know
aren't kind of currently being tested
for by some of the labs
that's what's tested in a lab in Oregon
and did you send it to me on an email or
something is that how you sent it to me
oh yeah oh yeah okay so maybe I can
screen share it or something I don't
know I would be really psyched to see
that and look into it because and if I'm
a real quick to chime in on that and and
and talk to your pointer I think I think
it's such a huge one because you know
there is such you know there's you know
the the the the terpene science and such
is such a new frontier and and and you
know the alcohol esters and kind of
compounds that are their tiny part per
million mounds you know seem to you know
and like what we're talking about
earlier with the spice comparison and
how you know a certain amount of salts
will do some thing to a mixture and then
steam eventually change the entire
profile of the soup you know it's it
it's really into interesting and and how
much the certain things and tiny amounts
are substantially affecting the overall
and and you know but what I would say to
what I would say that really complicates
a lot of this whole kind of conversation
which really sucks up to this point is
is the the need for Standardization of
laboratory data to be able to make apple
establish comparisons because up to this
point unfortunately what we've seen and
so much of the terpene testing that's
done is you know oftentimes you know
kind of complete wrong terpenes being
you know quantified or you know or orbit
or reported you know from an unverified
or unvalidated terpene kind of run on a
GC and my greatest example of that was
you know one of the biggest labs in
california you know for so long has been
putting kind of out these terpene
profiles you know she's showing and
suggesting that mining alpha pining you
know was the terpene dominant and in in
all these ranged strains from Jax a
train wreck 2x j2j who want that street
to dirt into you know sage and and and
that's completely
you know and kind of and from that from
that unvalidated terpene run and that
amount of publicly display being the
data of this wrong terpene as the
primary chirping in this this whole
class of strains you know they really
kind of took a hit you know and some of
their scientific integrity you know and
and and unfortunately you know in in
most states including california
including Oregon
you know there unfortunately terpene
testing isn't yet the test that is being
required to go through you know a
further accreditation proficiency
testing process you know to be able to
do that test so and because in Oregon
the Oregon really set a standard an
amazing standard in California is
following it and it was that okay if
you're gonna have if you're gonna
regulate I have strong kind of you know
limits and regulations on the producers
and processors and products and these
regulated markets you actually have to
have an even stricter level of scrutiny
and regulation of the laboratories that
are doing the testing and and so so and
so so Oregon was the first state to
substantiate that through their
regulations California's following them
and what they're requiring is that you
know an Oregon a lab has to go through
basically this this group called or lap
the Oregon laboratory assessment program
and and and they have to go through or
to go through all out basically and do a
proficiency testing process to show and
substantiate this laboratory evaluation
program that they can do the levels of
testing that are going to be required
for them to do and to pick up these
compounds in these amounts in these
mixtures and Spike matrices
well I this one particular lab that I
used I don't know if you've heard of
them or not but it's MRX labs and they
did a pretty thorough testing of it they
came up with alpha pining camping mersin
beta finding preparing alpha
serpentine lemony sameen gamma 13 Turpin
alene little lu i so peel ago there
now beta-carotene humulin Norrell idle
transfer like dog while and alpha busy
ball visit doorway which was a fairly
live vocalist of a lot of terpenes yeah
absolutely the greenest I learned a lot
from these guys I learned a lot about
the terpenes for one if you're not
careful when you store your terpenes
different stuff happens to distribute
next thing you know you start finding
isopropanol and acetone Peter terpenes
and that's because some of the terpenes
thermally degrade into those compounds
and you keep them in a amber bottle and
you got to keep them cool otherwise they
start going off that's no problem with
shelf-life warning one of the bottles
that I carried around with me at the cup
in my pocket and for four days was in
the heat I sent him to them and
immediately it came back and it had all
these this other garbage in it which
blew my mind I was like isopropanol
there's no way that that could possibly
because I collected these terpenes using
our new machine the blue meanie and it
refrigerates down to minus 20 pretty
easy and so we were getting a copious
amounts of terpenes but when I sent that
in it came back with a little bit of
tiny tiny amount of acetone and
isopropanol in it and that just blew my
mind and so I did it over again and then
I set that back into him when it came
clean and then I talked a lot with
Clancy of Callahan the guy at scientific
7/10 where they they make the machine
and they had the same thing and I found
a number of people now that I've been
looking that have come up with the same
info about the terpenes that you got to
be careful how you keep them you've got
to click look into the ones that you've
got you know we found a couple of
terpenes that are very interesting we've
been separating them out as best as
possible we've come up with a
vasodilator all you have to do a smelly
he's sticking
your nose and take like three or four
deep breasts you can feel your face get
warm you can feel your hands get warm
it's opening the blood flow all over
your body we found a bronchial dilator
3-4 breaths of it and I have two friends
who are who are on these asthma things
and they're using this bronchial dilator
curtain up and they think it's the
hottest thing since sunburn they don't
want to be removed from it and I think
if we can get start getting a really
complete feed out on these thirteen's
one of the things that I was doing that
somebody wasn't happy about but when I
get card for people occasionally and
when they wanted to stuff the card but I
always put the turkey collector between
the vacuum oven which is what I use for
D carving and the vacuum pump in at
around 75 or 80 milliliters of gold and
terpenes but when in those terpenes are
the ones that will thermally be great so
you have to be very careful with it I've
been on a aggressive program separating
him as much as possible
I found one method of gaining the
isopropanol and acetone artists put
three or four drops of water in with the
vial of Turkey and shake it up good put
in a scepter i final drain the water off
because both the acetone isopropanol
will go into the water phase of that and
then you can separate them and have your
terpenes clean but I'm pretty sure that
it's gonna take a lot of time and effort
to find out how to combine these
terpenes with the various oils to come
up with the effects and I can try work
on that somewhat this year now that I
know that I've got a source to collect
terpenes the way I need and want to
collect them you know what's unique
about these degradation of terpenes is
they're probably not only going to
happen on their own when collected but
they could potentially also happen in
the gland heads while they're you know
in cured bud or old bud you know these
are mad that that's such an awesome
thing you said because that really
connected for me kind of this this
interesting kind of you know we
thing that we've been seeing that might
be adding to both your points and that's
that you know in certain flour and and
and and extracts you know oftentimes we
will see these small kind of trace
residual solvent levels that are present
that are not used or should be there
kind of in general and so so kind of
yeah fascinating you kind of work in
drawing on what you're doing and seeing
because yeah that's from what we see
absolutely the for the analytical
reference standards that we have with
these different turbines it's so
important how they're stored and and and
and how the calibration ladders are
built and and and the runs developed
because it's so they're so sensitive
that they kind of seem to break down
really quickly in these different
conditions you know and then and then to
to you know what you were just saying
Marcus with the flower there might be
these weird and doggedness levels of
certain compounds that are there you
know that might be happening from
different you know overheat overheated
kind of you know rooms or you know just
different kind of you know in processes
that are being done you know and then
the extraction I like let me ask you a
question one of the things I've been
thinking about for a long time we
they've talked about it on the church
air quite a bit about what's in the stem
of the plant what's in the leaf and then
how it goes into the little factory of
the trichrome and manifest ultimately in
the head of the Trico all of that while
i was listening to it made me realize
that that must mean that when you
extract the planter when you separate
that up that there's going to be a race
mix in there of the pre stuff the stuff
and the after stuff going on and it's
going to be as we start using finer and
finer equipment to analyze what's coming
out in these expansions we're gonna
you're gonna start seeing little ticks
here and there I know that that recently
somebody pointed out at one of the
research labs that there's a bit of
butane naturally in the helix
and so there there must be a mix of
things that we haven't entirely paid
attention to yet and I'm hoping that
would the new lab certifications and the
new requirements for people working in
the lab will start getting some real
information it's awesome absolutely
can't agree more so Alec do you think
now with the I know you were trying to
with this new competition with the
cannabis County Fair going with that
type of you know terpene classification
where you know grouping them together
etc how did you were you involved in
that decision-making process to arrive
at that point or was that something that
was brought forth by the cannabis count
country fair because I can see
competition it was largely me okay well
I can see by by having that type of
classification you can start to drive
other labs into other competitions into
raising their standards so that they can
speak of this competition because even
less such as when I was over in
Barcelona this year for spannabis I
talked to them and of course you know
they were testing their cannabis that
was in the competitions that I was
involved in but they're only testing of
course for THC content or CBD they did
write of any type of anything else
beyond that is like well what are you
guys looking to step your game and
they're like yes absolutely by seeing
what's happening in the United States it
causes them to put pressure on their
laboratories they're awesome pushing
them to that they can be at the
standards because I have to give you
know Barcelona props their quality is
grown exponentially as well as their
testing ability but it also shows that
there's still holes in the system so but
it also shows through what you know the
cannabis Country Fair was trying to do
with its competition I hope it spreads
into a potentially mo cup and into I
take it that cannabis Country Fair will
happen then next year next summer on a
more reasonable date and time and with
more time planned and kind of effort put
into it yes
and I pre I really appreciate those
words you know because um you know it's
such a large array I mean I
such deep love and admiration respect
for Tim Blake Blake's tailor Blake and
how much they personally have been
mentors involved in my life and why I'm
with an in the cannabis community and
why I see labs exists and and and so
being involved you know I mean I've been
work with the mo couple s 10 years and
since I moved out here and we you know
Taylor and I we're living up at your
area 101 and involved you know kind of
organic farming and life changing in
every way that was wishers after I got
of the Navy
but um being involved in the cup and
seeing it grow and seeing it gets the
point where there's no you know eight
hundred plus flower entries you know
last year I mean it gets to the point
where all of a sudden the the integrity
of the overall judging what might be you
know even like a really strong kind of
plan you know from the top you know and
how the judges gonna be done it really
kind of you know brings a lot of
questions overall to help people can
even judge that and and how people can
kind of make similar you know kind of
judging criteria if there is smoking
that many strains a day and and so you
know in so many ways kind of just you
know the judging process is involved in
just like the the overall quality of the
look feel the bag appeal you know the
trim kind of you know how you know it's
if it's sticky and still cured you know
and just all these different aspects
kind of go into judging but but you
can't deny the importance of the
chemometric data cannabinoids and
hurricanes and and and and in in in in
so many ways you know with what we felt
with this turbine classification system
I was really kind of you know going to
Tim you know hoping that you know with
you're hoping that eventually it can
kind of evolve into the Emerald cup but
you know with with the cannabis Country
Fair there's gonna be a lot smaller but
total data sample set so that we could
try this you know try this out for you
know for just in general try it out just
to as an experiment to see how well it
works in the judging because the idea
was gonna be you know besides micro
gonna be run residual solvents and if
anything's out of spec then it was gonna
get disqualified anything else that was
qualified you know basically was gonna
get sent through this algorithm for
terpenes cannabinoids and then sorted
into these different primary
subgroups and then they were hopefully
going to be given to the the entrance
you know in these already sorted groups
so that you can make similar judging
against similar smelling or similar
profiled bud you know hoping that the
the data wouldn't necessarily bias all
the other judging attributes but it
hopefully would help inform you know
well it definitely helps inform because
it separates the wheat from the chaff it
means we saw everybody who used to oh
look at the size of my bud I got a great
donkey dick well that's great and all
but what is the data displayed right so
now we can see what's actually inside
there so you know it no longer size that
matters it's what are your Terps say and
what's their retention and you know on
top of the THC content CBD and looking
for you know to you know all those
things you're going to find that you
know yeah and I think and I'm sorry just
to finish the point also it's like I
think also you know why the big efforts
was like hoping to you know celebrate by
you know through using or identifying
these different categories and giving
awards these different small groups you
know you'll be able to in a way help to
celebrate and bring out the diversity of
cannabis because so many times what
we've seen in the Emerald Club is people
would enter some like really interesting
and unique kind of novel strains that
you know what actually they would there
would be complete outliers to the entire
dataset and should probably get an award
but because nobody even knew what it was
you know couldn't even get it judged and
so a couple of examples of this would be
some weird Landry strains that we're
like one to one
THC one to it you know - 101 THC th t
v-- you know there's this like Black
Beauty strain out right now in
California one to one you know and a lot
of the Baron strains kind of our bread
around from that and and so you know at
the time nobody even knew to judge it or
what have you and so just kind of slip
through the cracks and so so you know
with with being able to kind of put
things into these buckets and then give
awards in place you can also then to you
know identify these really unique novel
aspects that
my enter and then you know through that
help to breed out that overall kind of
terpene into the broader market and
elevate it and elevate it to the public
as well as which of course causes
further market saturation of the
diversity of products that have since
come out of me look since CBD has been
synthesized resynthesized and look at
the plethora of products on the market
that have spilled forth just off that
one compound alone not saying it's good
or bad etc I'm just poison cutting out
causality well what about what about
guys when it goes up and they will
believe me
constructive concentrates that is
concentration constructed from really
extremely fine oils and terpenes
collected separately but mixed back in
and offered as in the concentrate
contest what you guys do about that when
that stuff that's already been showing
up it's happened already people have
been kicked out of the cups because of
that at least why and Indra also you
know you know and I was making this a
point kind of earlier before you jumped
on and and and I mean if anybody that
might figure it out
I would imagine you probably would be
one of them but from what we see mostly
like whatever people are attempting to
take all these you know other flounder
I've terpenes and then re-add them or
reintroduce em in certain concentrations
to you know a distillate or some other
type of product typically it doesn't
work out well for them you know and if
you compare that besides you saw us live
resin holy water national trip
extraction kind of preserve you know
extract or you know rose in with like
natural Terps we added like I mean it's
crazy how how much natural games getting
and the synthetic kind of a reintroduced
game doesn't seem like it's it's it's
quite as perfected yet and and you can
usually typically pull it out side by
side and immediately kind of be like oh
that's you know not well probably 99.9%
of them don't know their ass from a hole
in the ground and they're overdoing it
and they're pouring too much stuff in
and they don't really understand the
rules
around combining something back together
anyway so they're never gonna figure it
out they're gonna always tip the thing
and Darrin there's two of you it's just
means it's twice as good but hey but
anyway these people will mix these
things and they're greedy and the greed
is the universal blindfold and yeah I
don't want to let the cat out of the bag
but is it can it be done you bet I
already did it and if I want it to I
could I don't want to play that man you
know that's not it I think we should
have a category being judged there of
just pure terpenes you know I know when
Tony when I bumped into him at the cup
he just wanted to dab the Serbians he
didn't want any the oil he just stuck in
and dabbed the terpenes are in fact
about 30 or 40 people just wanted to
push that's a good call you know I think
I think there's a need actually for that
I mean there's yeah I know what's the mo
comping with and even even you know the
Hitman crew I mean I think they hit man
crew with like chalice and stuff I would
I need to go back and look but they
might actually be having a certain
terpene category this year in their
event in July but you know you know
that's it's it's it's one of the
fascinating things I think a lot of the
really novel innovations within the
community are kind of almost pushing the
need for these novel you know unique
categories to be populated but it's only
once there's enough of that demand
within the kind of cups or within the
market or the judging I think that that
you know begets the need for that we
created in the event but I mean
absolutely I think that time is now I
don't think there's anything wrong with
creative concentrates
I mean I've one of my favorite ones is I
could Jack and I make Tony and
bubbleman's banana star manna goo and I
mix that with Jack and I put that in my
dabber and dab it and it's a delightful
combination man I mean I think you know
this should be a room for combining
things the terpenes and oils or whatever
and judging them because there's
fantastic ones out there you know III
I'm just in love with some of the stuff
I picked up while I was there but going
back to what you were saying I like it
was our demand of testing in labs in the
first place that started you know we
started going in those directions so
right there's a Kassala T of demand you
know so we can then propagate you know
that's the reality is that we have to
spend our hard-earned money and it costs
you know people don't realize how much
it costs the Emerald cup to test those
800 flowers or the a thousand plus and
now add then at any type of other
testing as you know cost you more to do
which means it costs me more to get done
by you however the more that gets out
there the more the questions that are
asked and get out there and then these
other laboratories start ring testing
and next thing you know you've got a
community that is well tested and you
can feel very good about taking those
next steps so that we can add because as
you know just we start off with THC and
now we're stepping into all these
complete and other boundaries that are
opening up even more doorways and know
your point 3 where you having a little
construction done in their lab so I
appreciate your point probably because
you know I think I think not enough
tribute is given to some of these events
and and and how much they are actually
influencing and affecting you know the
culture and the industry and then and
you know it was until the Emerald cup
took on its level of burden and testing
and money to do the testing so that they
could help substantiate their event that
some of these interesting realizations
about pesticides and extraction
processes and and all this was actually
even an issue
you know going back a couple years in
California and I'm you know then kind of
hitmen crude with shallots and having
place you know and did something very
similar and I was commitment to doing
that level of testing to help qualifier
this bowl of likes apples but in the
process of people in the sprawl being
disqualified and and having somewhat a
public shaming you know or Instagram
trolling of their brand because they
failed for pesticides in this public
event you know it since I have so many
of the for my you know kids incite
biggest players or biggest kind of you
know brands within California canvas
community you know evolve their ways cut
things out in their program like
phospholipid master or or certain
systemic fungicides and pesticides you
know because they took it so personally
from failing the mo Cup or failing
chalice and so I think you know yeah but
not enough for the props is given to you
know the judges and the people you know
helping with the events pushing the
boundaries in a lot of ways you know
that getting people ready for place calm
with regulation well the emissions the
people want they they want the truth
they want to know what they're what
they're seeing is proper and they want
people to follow the right things and it
is shown because you've seen a whole
different sociological experiments crop
up in our community because of social
media and testing and failures or
successes or successes that were
successes until the tests came out and
then came that and that they failed then
those types of public shaming these are
things that we've never really seen in
our community because we never had a
standard there was never a shelf that we
could say hey that THC is actually that
so it has changed a discussion it really
goes back and I got it out forever give
props to you know the first ones to
really put out well they were Harborside
to see an Oakland to really put out THC
and it caused an initial stir because it
caused a problem because I started to
see vendors coming my way saying hey
what I was getting for this amount of
money for I can't get anymore because
the testing says it's
this number down here were in the past
they were getting in at this amount of
money with no problem at all going off
of their organoleptic which is their
visual cues etc etcetera they could see
where as science has literally separated
the wheat from the chaff because we are
now have a standard that we can look to
and hold on to and grasp on to and thank
you for being a pioneer in that and
thank you for holding yourself to the
scientific standards so that we can all
rise together equally hey you guys
posted all your lab test results on the
public board and if you don't would you
consider doing so you know for the last
few years actually you know we have this
tested tested button on our website and
you click that and any dated that client
had that we worked with or a collective
that we work with have done if they if
they click and made this animal public
you know then it was basically viewable
in this on this aspect of the website
within the last few months for what it's
worth we temporarily kind of took it
down until we could figure out a better
way to do it because what we found is
there's about there's like three groups
that were from different parts of like
United States and one part you know one
from outside of the country that were
basically mining or a website and just
like they had kind of I guess they had
just like some scripts written to where
they were basically just taking every
data point and just mining it from from
our site had like news trackers that
were just basically anytime so we make
us our public there basically be pulling
the data and and so you know yeah we
just you know basically took that down
in an effort to try to reach figure out
how we can long relaunch the public
display without basically getting
pirated for the data you know because
for what it's worth I mean that in so
many ways the data is like not as
valuable I guess a lot of people think
you know and and and the project we've
been working on this turkey
classification
you know there's gonna be many systems
that are launched you know there's
already a couple out there you know
marquees this is the best there is at
this point and then you know and we're
not looking to replace it we're looking
just at how the system that we can
basically you know have all our clients
and people that we work with be able to
use to better you know further help them
understand and value the data that we
provide you know I love old color
graphics you had about the terpenes it
was great
but we were just kind of hoping you were
gonna bring something like that back
that is absolutely you know there we are
taking kind of our current graphic
displays of terpenes and charts and
colors and you know launching that to a
new level and a new it Ben should have
that launched in the next couple you
know in the next month or two with the
with a turkey classification system and
hoping that they know colors can help us
to you know to ative ly bring out some
of these complex kind of serving you
know data points like because it's
really hard for a lot of subsets of the
community to you know start to really
understand that you can be able to
pronounce choke Emmaline or Bittaker
awfully mean these different terpenes
and then let alone kind of understand
how certain ones might be affecting you
know working with JC to affect strained
a certain way or another so hopefully
you know what you know this is a means
to add a little bit more clarity and and
then just you know bring word you don't
like to the rainbow of effects and and
variants that cannabis has you know and
also addendum last point of that you
know to understand how unique certain
things are because you know whenever
it's the most strains of cannabis that
we haven't passed through and most of
the groups and so everything there's a
primary but most of the subgroups within
you know the nursing class because
that's the biggest in most primary class
you're seeing these things be most
dominant or and around them but but you
know there's there's other primary group
that has you know a tenth of the total
data points but is there's enough
samples to just to signify the need for
its own primary groupings and that's
alphap I mean you know you vary
see also finding this dominant routine
but you know is look we lose ELQ yeah I
don't you see did we lose yeah I didn't
catch him oh well I'm sure he'll be back
in a flash
yeah you know one of the things I wanted
to mention was you know we're just okay
for twenty years or so there's been some
terpene talk a little bit less thanks to
Sam and his experiment in early 2000 but
I wonder how you know beta carry off
Elena's the is the terpene that drug
dogs are tested for correct well that
they smell the most or that they test
for that might I thought they were -
they were trained with it I thought that
they trained drug dogs with true okay
right so I heard this as well so that's
interesting that like probably when most
people in the cannabis world didn't even
know what beta carry awfully was somehow
the police knew what it was and knew to
trade their truck bugs with it they had
terpene knowledge before us well that's
the closed market ethylene Empire and in
those days they probably were only
measuring I don't know Sam will probably
tell me I'm wrong on this but I think
they were only measuring for a few of
the terpenes by the police labs went to
the other labs and asked them hey what
should we look into and they said well
alpha PI named beta carry alpha Lane
Leno loop any of those might be good
candidates because there's a lot of them
present in the 13 count on that but
[Music]
carry on went blank no worries I'm not
sure what happened with Alec there a
little bit Todd said he's out for the
day and will see us next week with beta
carry awfully and there you go yeah
yield extract said we should give all
the car window washers at the Mexican
border spray bottles with beta carry
awfully yeah
that was the joke on the ferry here
actually for some years one year they
just on the BC ferry from the Sunshine
Coast they did this big thing where they
just like brought drug dogs on the Conn
the ferry
walked through the area and like busted
a few people with pounds and so the big
joke was to take you know five gallon
batches of bubble water and just like
pour it on your down the ferry floor yet
dive up by the cop cars with a spray
bottle roll your window down spray the
tires on the street side of it and every
time that the police cars go back in the
compound and the k9 dogs come out to get
in I'm gonna go [ __ ] nuts over the
tires on the police cars mmm you know
what I'm just glad to slowly but surely
be moving away from even having to fit
like you know you're definitely not
figuring out valuable like say terpene
profile and how it interacts with the
endocannabinoid system and how to like
put your body better at ease if you're
focused on how to smuggle how to get
away from the police how to evade how'd
it like this is insane court costs
lawyers like this is these two things
need to be disconnected forever because
what's that somebody voted for it I
don't know I'm not one of those people
that believes voting actually gets
anyone into power yeah I think
politicians believe in the old you can
fool some of the people some of the time
you can fool all of the people some of
the time but they don't like to believe
in you can't fool all the people all the
time right well that's the system that
we seem to be living in anyway well they
fixed that Sam the way they fix that is
the ones that they can't fool they get
put in jail for smoking pot or the yeah
they just say there's it's illegal to
not not be fooled all the time whoa
and what about this gentleman from New
Jersey the New Jersey med man the stood
with the dreads that's constantly
getting arrested and in trouble from the
police I guess they gelled him again New
Jersey I might be getting this name
wrong does that do you know him at yeah
cuz activist I don't know him I know of
him the New Jersey weed man he's he's
kind of always been on the front lines
and he gets out there and waves it in
their face and is fearless and yeah they
have as we all know as loud as found out
firsthand and others have you know when
they want to [ __ ] with you they will
make your life a living [ __ ] hell and
they have unfortunately made New Jersey
and weed man's life hell and he's trying
to do his best out there on the East
Coast with the draconian laws that are
there but I'm hearing that New Jersey
has a governor somebody running for
governor against chris Christie who is
cannabis friendly and this wants to
legalize cannabis in New Jersey and look
I went to West Virgina University as
people used to say it's the New Jersey
University because it's just far enough
away for the kids from New Jersey to get
away from their parents their parents
couldn't sneak up on them but they could
all say it was a partying school as well
so but you know New Jersey really needs
it the economy could you know help it
and remember the motto of the state New
Jersey the Garden State exactly
Hempstead New Jersey even you know
instead it says that on the license
plates the garbage state know the garden
I'm just joking state know that I'm not
sure which was I'm just making a New
Jersey joke I got love for my New Jersey
peeps come on they got that joke it was
funny the New Jersey Turnpike is garbage
come on but last I heard you had New
Jersey weed man was still getting [ __ ]
with and I have no idea where this saga
in lies currently but I wish him luck oh
all the time but he's pissed off the
local cops and the state cop sudhi
on a hunger strike this Edie for Jean
the New Jersey weed men two weeks into a
hunger strike right now and then we
can't we can't not mention Peter Tosh
his son right now who's also been like
beaten in prison into a coma they beat
him into a coma and he's in there for
like joints herb he got caught with herb
he was doing six months and got into
this big got a big beating put on him
and he's in a coma so yeah you guys can
google that and find out what's going on
with that support to the Tosh family
rule Peter also Peter Tosh had also been
beaten many a time I'm not sure if he
ever gotten beat into a coma but he
definitely got smoked and cracked it
they cracked his head open a good few
times with batons I believe it happened
in America the the Tosh's Sun let me
just do a quick quick a google so I can
give you a little bit more beaten into
coma in New Jersey jail damn that's a
Garden State yeah
[Laughter]
jailers it doesn't necessarily have to
be the prisoners that beat him up the
same people who beat people up all the
time hang them in themselves mysterious
hangings of course and people die in
their cells from lack of water not too
long ago the black guy who was gonna
join Homeland Security it came out that
a pregnant woman died of thirst in his
jail and so then he said well I'm not
gonna take that job now I mean like you
Jesus Ike you could get it in the first
place and killing people I mean the
torture State yeah what goes on here in
this country anymore passes for civility
and we call ourselves civilized and
Mahatma Gandhi when they asked him what
do you think about a civilization in
America and he said I think it would be
a good idea
and Jesus damn yeah well that's crazy
that we were talking about New Jersey
and then that's where young Tosh got
beat
I don't think Mahatma Gandhi ever went
to America
I know he went to London and he wasn't
they they just asked him in an interview
what he actually what it was was they
said what do you think about the West
which is claims to be civilized and he
said I think it would be good idea you
can find it online if you look enough he
didn't have to come to America to say
that either by the way I'm sure enough
of America came to him or maybe not I
have no idea wasn't there I do know this
much it's time for Bhangra damn Darren
you sleeping Darren just let you hear he
was he just cut your grass hard bro you
know what we can Rev line across the
planet bone rip everyone everyone can
say yeah sure enough yes Peter S says it
upside down every time how about that
he's very Cubans sift and attends pipe
Thank You
chunk and a chi how about that that's
your pipe now so beautiful D wreck and
hit man pipe that it is it is the best
I've had a couple of three four
different pipes given to me since then
and they're all sitting on the shelf
somewhere and I still only use this one
okay I could put a detail on it because
well I just lazy I cop I'm lazy so I put
you know on it and now it's ready all
the time but that didn't change the fact
that it hits amazingly and every single
time I pick it up and hit it I think
about you Mike that well many blessings
I'm glad you get much use enjoy of it's
a great design pipe shout out to do
who did the design on the outside and
yeah Dougie and M do design some good
pipes and that one hits like a [ __ ]
champ so I'm glad it's being used all
the time every day includes ten hours a
day I miss you guys at the cup but I got
a bottle of terpenes for you guys inside
that I've been keeping in the freezer
and I want to later get it because
everybody tried it so I think it's
pretty good it's always more effective
to let those who have complimented you
be the ones who complement you I know
but that's what I'm saying when you blow
your own horn it sounds like twenty
percent but if Tony was in here saying
that you'd get the full hundred percent
out of the value of that comment I'm
just saying I got you heard I've invited
him a bunch of times today I wanted him
to come in for the terpene conversation
but he's busy I think Sunday's like one
day he can actually probably get a
little bit of a rest although I wouldn't
even be surprised if he's [ __ ] moving
or doing you know not even in the
country or something also to you were
talking about Marcus you were talking
about you know the effects of minor
terpenes as on the effect of the major
terpenes how they're affecting
cannabinoids and that's absolutely true
when when I did analysis of scourge
number one I found over 50 different
terpenes and there was a few Peaks that
I didn't wasn't able to ID but so I mean
that there might have easily been 60
including minor terpenes
that's quite a sweet smell there must
have been certain ones that were just
constantly there or was it more in the
cannabinoid spikes because I remember
you saying in the past that you were
able to sort of distinguish by seeing a
GC test of something whether it had
system that's because
had a particular profile it was I am
mayor scene Lima lean and I don't know
if everyone else right now but and you
could very easily if you had a DC of a
tie and the GC of a skunk and the GC of
an Afghan and then you crossed them eat
in some way the offspring you could
easily easily tell what families they
were originating from what progeny they
were grown because the profiles of the
GC dispelled it out really clearly well
if you on the test that I had done the
things that were in there in greater
quantity was alpha pi name my scene a
little beta beta Kari awfully and by the
way pronouncing these things I found the
key to it is simply get a clothespin and
put it on your bottom lip and you can
pronounce them correctly mmm all good
questions guild extracts we'll have to
get him in here next next week he's got
lots of good things to say he's talking
about how we can you know discover
different pesticides and terpenes
peaking at the same time as some
pesticides and giving false positive
negatives
fortunately Alex no longer here we
didn't get marks skull dome today so
I'll try to line up Alec again get
killed in the room have mark maybe get
chimera and have a nice good longer
conversation about these particular
things for sure it's definitely a point
of interest you know as well forward a
little work we've been doing is the
silicon gel filter properly configured
in the extraction unit will pull
insecticides out of the extraction
excellent I'm not sure if that's a good
thing that you're cleaning up extract
with insecticides part of that game what
the [ __ ] are they put new check beside
target well I look I just am mentioning
it because it's a fact
I'm not advertising we have it within
our system which goes unnamed and
unmentioned hereabouts anyway but I
discovered that that does that and so I
always say to people well you before you
extract you should have the stuff tested
so you know whether or not you have to
defeat like the site or not because I
wouldn't do it as a regular thing and I
wouldn't advertise that you should do it
as a regular thing people should start
testing from the moment the plant comes
out of the ground or it gets harvested
you know by the time it gets to the
concentrate maker it should already have
a clean bill of health because
everything that goes to the concentrate
Metro will do exactly what that says
concentrated that is how it works
concentrate the good with the bad
unfortunately best to make sure that he
just got the good in the first place
have a little bit of integrity have a
lot of integrity actually have a lot of
integrity it's worth it
it doesn't affect quality it doesn't
affect quality like integrity does not
infect a new way it just you spray it on
it's really fast
oh nice like just that at the end of
flowering you just spray it everywhere
yeah you spray it everywhere I don't
even know we're just being sometimes
Sam's humor will just I don't even
understand it but I laugh anyway cuz
it's funny though and I don't understand
it always alien humor it's alien humor
for certain we're definitely an alien I
would say that much it's a lovely Sunday
afternoon maybe maybe that's humor of
off on him to say some of these things I
know that jokes are decidedly different
some of the world's top comics are from
Holland oh wait no they're not make
Canada I don't know I think we have like
I don't think we're the funniest I think
we got a few we got we got a few yeah a
lot man there's a ton of funny people
from Canada yourself included John Candy
he was pretty funny John Candy Jim
Carrey
he's just a piloto Mike Meyers Mike
Meyers
anyway proportionately Canada comes up
with more funny people than they do here
in the USA they're funny people they
come up here in the USA are people like
Jeff Sessions who recently lauded the
Filipino dorte a guy who's been killing
people like crazy doing sessions Laden
his efforts to clean up the Philippines
Jesus that's [ __ ] ominous man yeah
it's not too good when you got someone
like basically going for the mass murder
record and then you did it it's pretty
pretty crazy that was some disturbing
imagery that came out of that of people
just getting blown away on the streets
that's that's a level of prohibition
that Wow I mean holy might even have
been drug users
you know you've spoiled when you're
worried about like what's written in the
proposition or the latest release of the
federal licensing and people are
literally getting like shot in the back
did you know that the Philippines
legalized medical marijuana at the same
time I did indeed hear that I remember
hearing a friend of mine saying that he
was gonna be going there for a meeting
and I said what now I said what now
thanks
I sure wouldn't be going for that
meeting I'll tell you I'll stick with
Jamaica you know what even when it was
illegal and they were bashing them over
the skulls they were still fighting for
it those are my people
hey didn't they just the Chinese just
built about a twenty billion dollar new
highway system in Jamaica Oh
the Chinese are always building crazy
highway systems in Jamaica they they
yeah they definitely I don't know how
much they spent on it but there's
definitely one that goes from like close
to Kingston like all the way into ochi
and it's quick compared to how it used
to be I have to do this real crazy thing
and in fact Joe and I can tell you a
story that while Tony and I were driving
with our partners from Kingston to a
property just passed Oh Jose Rios we
ended up on that Highway late at night
and we ended up getting to a point where
it was blocked off there was a guy
standing there like a flag guy and it
was late like dark late and so we pull
up and we're like I'm like damn we're
gonna have to go back this is gonna be
so long and Tony and I are kind of
huffing and puffing a bit and our
partners like don't worry he gets out he
kind of pays this guy off a little bit
the guy moves the the cone and we drive
through this like rubble and worked like
fully under construction highway we're
now driving through the construction
driving driving driving for about 20
minutes and we end up at a dead end it's
all rubble and this little car we're in
can't drive over the rubble maybe a big
truck could but the car can't so we so
we try to figure out turning around we
go back to where the flag guy is and my
business partner who's driving the car
basically does a u-turn on to the other
side of the highway which is the wrong
side of the highway and we drive the
rest of the way down the wrong side of
the highway going like a hundred and 20
kilometers an hour it was definitely a
pretty wild experience that was before
that highway got finished it was it was
nuts
I went on once Sally it was they recall
me they were just like listen it's not a
problem and in the end it really wasn't
but we did
understand that we were kind of like
this seems like this is a problem like
I'm sorry but going down the highway the
wrong way but you know what lo and
behold they were right and they got us
there totally safety safely without any
weird experiences but holy [ __ ] that was
insane
only in Jamaica I loved Jamaica honestly
I loved Jamaica can you take taxis for
super long distance rides there KP
oh yeah well any car will be a taxi and
it's just a matter of knowing the prices
because obviously if you're just a
tourist well then that's a you know
you're a valuable opportunity for people
who don't make a lot of money to maybe
make a little bit of money off of you
because that's that's what tourism is in
Jamaica it's extremely uh I think it's
one of them the biggest ways that money
comes to the island so you'd have to
probably be there for a while and really
understand how to jump into a cab and
just go like you know an hour and a half
up the road or whatever for a few bucks
hey did you see the new IAC M that came
out today about CBD reduces blood
pressure and healthy people I I
swallowed two huge capsules of it every
single day I've been doing that for
about seven months now and my blood
pressure I used to be on four blood
pressure medicines because my atrium is
enlarged and I have an enlarged heart
and now I'm down to two plus an
occasional other one and I can tell you
that the only real thing that constantly
consuming CBD though I'm I'm all with
that particular study I believe in it
but well the great
it's Oxford it's not just anyone this is
that done at Oxford so this is not not
messing around
so his well my study of nine healthy
male volunteers a single dose of six
hundred milligrams of CBD significantly
reduced blood pressure
researchers at Nottingham and Oxford
discovered I did this one in my own ass
which is even more important to me than
Oxford
understand this is for the other people
not your ass thank you first you know
literally backing it up my entire body
but okay yes sorry I yeah I'm a firm
believer in human lower humour lowers
your blood pressure as well alright
update on Tasha's son from young
visionary in 1985 he says he's been in a
coma for four months was attacked by
another inmate he was in jail for having
65 pounds in his trunk
supposedly in 2013 supposedly supposedly
damn that sucks I'm bummed out for the
65 pounds and I am bummed out that he
had to spend even a day in jail for that
Florist you know imagine if that was 65
pounds of roses how absurd that would
sound i if the cops turned in 65 pounds
I wonder how much was accident there
I've never seen them do anything honest
with regards to seizing pot and
arresting somebody yet and I don't think
I don't expect them
true-true well you know what I'm telling
ya I feel pretty good about today's
episode Alex said he was gonna come back
maybe next week I'm going to invite gild
next week I'll make sure Tony's in the
room try to get chimera in here John you
can come back and talk about you know
just get this conversation again going
about the terpenes and the testing and
all of this stuff to me is wonderful I'm
always excited to learn more and that's
one of the reasons I do this every week
is so I can sit and listen to you guys
and learn more so he thanks everyone on
the panel that was here mr. Todd
McCormack Johnny B Scott man sandy 420k
like from SC labs marks Sheldon who
popped in just for a short time and of
course a chance gunk man Sam and Indra
who are in the room now and need the
bubble Man always happy to spend my
Sunday afternoons and mornings with you
all and yeah we'll see it's moral for
the wake-and-bake episode I don't even
know it climbs much faster than hashed
Church I think it's around 69 now so
maybe something Jimmy Hendricks tomorrow
what if six were a nine I'll leave you
with that peace out everybody thanks for
watching has church bell on guys