hash Church episode what is it 19 19 I
think hash Church 3.0 got ET F and Mr
skunkman Sam in the room all right all
right all right good morning
everybody well good good morning oh I
know what I need to do I need to create
the link copy the link for the new chat
and then I got to post it into the old
chat and then you know what else you
have to do actually if I don't post
something in the chat
it
doesn't it actually just sits there with
nobody able to type I did that for about
20 minutes last uh last week so Eden I
have a question for you yes
sir uh have you ever seen a variety that
was extremely high in CBD like 20
25% which had less than
3% THC
uh not that I'm aware of unless there
was a hemp varietal I was working with
back in the day
no what where was that question coming
from Sam yeah what what genetic is this
well it's just that uh there are people
who claim they have varieties which are
20 25% or even higher of CBD and they
say it had zero or really a tiny amount
of uh uh THC but the trouble is that
even if there's not a THC synthes making
THC for the plant the CBD synthase
produces about a 20 to 25 to one ratio
of THC so even if there's zero THC
synthes CBD synthes makes some THC and a
25% that would be equal to about 1%
THC so it's biologically
impossible am am I still you're you're
oh so either I was frozen or you were
frozen so you're saying it was
biologically
impossible as far as I know
yes duly noted and I will keep an eye
out for that and people were watching
I'm I'm pretty clever with this stuff so
yeah I I would say you yes yes anybody
else that would be a little skeptical
but you yeah you're the master
geneticist of Master geneticist so I
would say yeah I
agree I'm just liking how clear his
voice is today it's all like loud and
clear and it's in my ears good the last
couple of weeks Sam's been in a tube
like at a distance from his microphone
so you sound great today
Sam and I guess we better
I have no idea why because it's
definitely the same old me ah yes that's
true well welcome to Johnny B and Colin
and Wade skunkman Sam and etan myself
just the old schoolers in hash church
today doing it up on a Sunday morning
how's everybody
doing I'm all I'm doing great how are
you guys Johnny Be I couldn't hear
you I said I had to learn how to shave
again this morning as you can see oh
dude I didn't even
know a
shave off and I keep I was like what the
hell so I got always willing to share
his failures always remember you're
supposed to wash it in hot water and it
shrinks okay that's how that works I
think you know what I got this new
really cool razor and I put it all
together I'm like this is awesome like
Ow like Ow like joh we love you man it's
it's amazing
you're awesome man A B oh Jesus oh I'm
gonna hit some of my Hank I'm G to Hank
it up with you guys dude yeah I've been
seeing you post Marcus man how I'm so
proud of you man it's like I just want
to reach in through the photo and give
you a hug man that's such a long time
coming and dude you know it's a long
time coming it's it's also you know like
look this this isn't this isn't six-star
hash this isn't me being done this isn't
even under my own brand this is under a
brand Hank that we created for a
mid-grade brand for me mid-grade is
almost 70% THC in this particular hash
what makes it mid-grade to me is the
tpine content is not high enough I would
love a 10 to 12% this is like around
four so it's you know at room
temperature it's also been kept cold but
I left it overnight so now it's got that
nice Afghan flavor to it when it comes
out of the fridge you know at 4% tpin
you're not going to smell much because
everything's kind of slowed down it does
bubble um uh and melt in my Banger I can
vaporize it I wouldn't put it past a
fourstar personally so from a
perspective of Bubble Man The
Connoisseur of course I want to release
six plus star bubble hash but from the
perspective of the amount of sheer work
and and obstacles and burning Hoops that
I had to jump through just to make this
available and of course I'm so spoiled
when it comes to Hash that I'm sure 90%
of people are going to be like dude this
is some of the nicest hash in the market
right now but for me as a person I'm
like we have a we have a long way to go
so I've been uh already since this
released I've already been in touch with
some craft Growers we're going to look
at doing some fresh frozen we're just
going to try and oh it does have a nice
smell though as it's open under my nose
that old school just Afghan kind of
flavor looks pretty darn nice I think uh
Johnny B ended up going and getting one
as well
I'm g hit some in my Banger right now I
got three coming and it um I went away
on Friday at one o'clock and came back
at two and when I got back there was a
card in the mail I was [ __ ] mad so I
went to the Shoppers yesterday to try
and pick it up they're like yeah know
you got to come back Monday so Monday
morning at 11:00 a.m. I'm going to go
and pick up your hash I got one gram to
squish one gram to smoke and one gram to
put away because that's just me nice
well I bought one from Cannabis BC
Cannabis stores because I wanted one
right away of course that's not getting
here until the 99th or the 10th of March
so then I went to Up In Smoke who which
is owned by Dom and um max they used to
own Sunrise Wellness Foundation they
changed their name to up and smoke and
if you check them out on Instagram Up in
Smoke 604 they got their Instagram
account busted so many times now they're
just meme dealers they just have funny
memes up on that page uh and it's a lot
of it's just busting LPS balls yet
they're totally in support you know it's
funny to meet people in the industry who
are you know come from this super high
level and they want to get this thing to
a certain level but you are forced to
retake all the steps to get to that
level you don't just get to jump into
the legal uh realm and then hope that
everyone's growing cannabis that's good
enough and and all this sort of thing so
we're we're pretty excited to be in the
game we're pretty stoked to have you
know Hank in the marketplace uh a high
THC and a mid phc what I really did was
I just broke up the microns you know I
put like uh I put my 73 my 90 my 120 and
my 45 into this which is called um a
high THC and I put the 190 the 160 and
the 25 into the mid-grade all of them
being golden hash none of them being
full of contaminant they all came out
pretty decent but that's why there's a
massive uh sort of price difference in
between the two grades whereas the THC
difference doesn't seem as massive you
know these are more things I was forced
into would I have loved to have released
a 90 Micron uh absolutely would this
have gone from a fourstar to maybe a
five-star had I isolated the microns and
sold them separately quite possibly I
think the 90 probably would have been
there but then I have to pay a $1,500
COA for every single Micron that I that
I yeah $1,500 COA with full you know
microbials with Tarpin with canabo with
fungicides and pesticides very expensive
um but forced to do that and also take
out like 10 plus grams of the product to
sort of you know send that off it's not
as as cheap as as we would like it to be
so there's minor things where we're
forced and then there's you know as best
that we can do we kind of try to figure
it out so uh all in all pretty stoked to
uh have a little Hank bubble rip with
the hash churches here in the morning so
I'm going to mute my mic and torch my
bowl and uh Marcus the amount you have
to uh send off you said 10 grams is that
whether it's weed or hash or whatever
because with weed you know that's only
uh you know a little bit of THC actually
whereas with hash that's a whole lot of
THC yes agreed we're trying our best to
kind of get you know the regulatory
framework lined up with the QA people so
they realize look like 10 grams of hash
is a lot more than 10 grams of of of
flour and we need to we need to identify
those differences uh big time yeah this
is part um there's also there's also
something we keep we have to retain
samples as well and that's like 20 to 30
grams that go in the vault and sit there
basically forever so it's uh you know
they take your margin and they just do
this to it
slowly slowly now keep in mind 20 GS
that you put in the vault uh is that
Frozen or refrigerated or otherwise it's
going to change a
lot exactly yeah well we keep it as cold
as we possibly can but these are things
that we've been noticing as well that
the regulatory framework doesn't have a
deep understanding of and it's not like
we're going to be testing it all the
time but yeah they keep it for retention
in case anything ever goes wrong in case
they ever find something that's wrong
with that
lot we need to be able to go into the
Vault and pull that out and uh go
through it if you remove the oxygen and
freeze it at like minus 30 Centigrade
then it does not change really hardly at
all in 10
years I I agree I've seen the exact same
thing from my own freezer um and then uh
Jeremy spoke about that last week as
well in regards to using potential noble
noble gases to uh well removing the
oxygen and then replacing with um
nitrogen argon nitrogen yeah there's a
variety of uh of noble gases that you
can use but what you speak toward Marcus
is a reality I think a lot of us are
facing is we're finding these regulatory
loopholes that we're forced to deal with
because we're in the overregulation uh
Commodities of of the reality and I mean
$1,500 per COA I mean Jesus that is
just yeah I mean for micron pricon
that's that's just absolutely ludicrous
well that's why I'm forced do you how
hard it was for me to put the microns
together they like we got to they got
they're like we need only two grades and
I was like whoa what they're like we
need two grades I'm like listen I can't
do two grades it has to be three I have
to take the 220 out and keep that as
like you know and then of course they
wanted me to destroy the 220 which came
out at 48% THC I was like no I'm not
destroying the the 4 the two the 220
what we need to do is create some Sops
and some pcps that allow us to take the
material once it's been worked put it
back into the Vault so I can send it
over to Mike West on the other side and
uh have him do you know CO2 or
hydrocarbon or one of the solvent
extractions on that because holy smokes
can you imagine like 49% yields when you
run your material versus like 10 to 15
or 3 to five like some of these hemp
guys so the other thing the other thing
that extractors are doing is when they
don't have enough of Any Given product
whether it's flowers or water sift or
whatever they mix it then squash it and
it's all just one homogeneous
mix yes so they can get one single COA
Port bubble man is there is there an
appeal process or a process of Education
you can make them aware that they will
actually take hold or they're just the
system is what it is you deal with it no
the system is like all systems we've
always had to educate the system like
this is what all of us have been doing
for for 25 to 30 years some of us longer
um this is the system this is the system
requires self-education and so we will
do this but when you've climbed up to
the almost peak of the mountain and then
you kind of fall off the end and realize
oh like okay we're in this regulatory
framework now but I'm not where I wanted
to be I'm down here now so there's a a
massive appeal that needs to be made and
not just in education it's like the
knowledge needs to go not just from the
government folks but into the people who
own the companies into the understanding
of living soils and regenerative farming
practices and living biomes that produce
those precursors that Express the tpin
to the point that we actually want them
at to get to a system that's not only
representative of THC percentage but
actually gets into some of the other
components of the plan
to be able to allow people and not
handcuff them into being able to succeed
in this industry rather than fail and
right now people are up against a lot
the regulatory framework is absolutely
incredible and I'm not complaining about
the framework I'm just mildly bummed out
that for the last 25 to 30 years we
spent all this time sort of preaching to
the choir and now the choir's gotten off
the stage the doors have opened at the
back and now we have all of society
actually listening but they're listening
back down at this level they're not
coming in up here we need to come back
down to a reasonable level and hold all
these hands that we that we basically
begged to you know to be a part of this
and to to to come into this with open
arms now we have to very patiently you
know be like okay well look this can't
be like this because this is hindering
the ability to grow living soils and
this can't be like this because the
excessive packaging and testing uh is
keeping certain products from the market
and this can't be like this and so you
know they're not evil they're not like
out to get us I really don't believe
that I've spoken with quite a few of
these people they're just people that
literally were in the wine industry two
and a half years ago and now they're in
the Cannabis industry you know feeling
like they want to do the same thing so
you know what it is Marcus that they
want to air on the side of safety so
it's going to take a long while to drag
them to see what makes sense like 20
grams of of 80% THC hash is not the same
as 20 grams of uh 20% weed I mean that's
just reality we know it yeah yeah I I
agree I agree and someone said you are
complaining about the framework well
certainly some of the framework I'm
complaining about we need to fix that as
we always have we fought and and
practiced Civil Disobedience to levels
of such excessiveness to get the
framework that we have now well we're
certainly not going to just stop and and
and stick with what we have now it needs
to be it needs to be bettered but within
the framework itself you also have
people who think they're going to grow
amazing cannabis with shitty techniques
and without the the awareness and the
compassion and the love that really is
required so there's education that needs
to go there that has nothing to do with
framework um you know just all sorts of
people coming in to commoditize um
cannabis we need to make sure that
happens the right way and doesn't happen
the wrong way so I think there's
complaints uh to be had there and uh all
in all don't get me wrong I'm absolutely
Beyond elated that I'm finally you know
after 30 years of being involved with
this plant after 21 years of teaching
people how to make hash you know super
proud of my team you know shout out to
pran and to Abby and to Randy and to
Jazz you know the frontliners that that
made this hash that you know like they
made this hash more than I made this
hash I was in the in the lab and I was
training them and overwatching them but
you know I'm really really proud of
those guys and proud of our whole QA
team and proud of our finance team so
all shut up but I needed to give them
all like props uh to the whole team at
Embark for uh you know do this was not
easy I cannot express
how difficult this was to do and how
many amazing people had to work like 247
in congruence in Synergy to make it
happen so shout out to my team and uh go
go celebrate with them celebrate them I
mean you know it takes many hands to do
the lifting but you know things like
this you have to celebrate because these
are game-changing events and lives and
that's a Herculean lift you've actually
p toist it over your heads I mean
celebrate celebrate celebrate and it's
only going to get better every time you
go up a notch and till finally you're
able to produce the absolute finest in
large quantities well thanks to you
skunkman Sam I know what that is had I
not met you had you not allowed me into
your life and trusted me dude thank you
so much for trusting me because your
trust that you put in me is one of the
huge reasons why I am here where I am
today and I never have a problem uh
giving you the props for that because
holy [ __ ] I I cannot be happier to say
that what I want to see is everybody
able to smoke the equivalent of
99.9% dry sift whether it's water hash
whether it's
rosm how it's made is not as important
as that it's clean safe and uh suitable
for
consumers Sam did you ever think you
would see this in your
lifetime I I'm surprised it took so long
I under Carter we thought we were G to
get this you know move towards it he
promised decriminalization and then the
whole
Bourne uh setup where uh the drugs are
well he wasn't a drugs are he was the
drug advisor or whatever he was you know
he he got popped and everything
everything went skewy and uh we honestly
expected in 76 we would have full
Federal decriminalization or even
better and if it hadn't been for Keith
stro it probably could have happened but
you know unfortunately he thought he was
doing the right thing but it was not the
right thing and it set us back a couple
of
decades you guys yeah please atan for
those who don't know Keith strop was the
head of normal normal was actually
started with a $200,000 donation from uh
Hugh
Hefner and so needless to say he was a
huge supporter but um at an event
apparently um key stro did lines of coke
with the actual drug advisor for the
president and basically came out and
went straight to the media and said hey
it's time to legalize you I just did
lines of coke with the you know the drug
here he was really annoyed because of
the whole paraquat thing and uh that was
the Tipping Point in his his mind if
they could spray poison on our cannabis
then why the [ __ ] are we protecting them
if they're going to be taking drugs you
know but uh yeah it's snitching just
ain't a good thing well there were they
were killing people and that's why they
were upset paraquat was killing and
harming people because of the government
uh zealously to you know continue its
prohibition policies and they started
spraying poison on uh cannabis and it
started affecting people's lives so I
understand the anger however as well as
the the wanting to change it and the
vitral going along with it but you know
Keith's decision uh ended up you know
costing us decades well he Keith's
feelings were correct his actions were
not
dude I had no idea I honestly am not
going to lie when you opened up your
mouth at Chan those are not the words I
thought you were gonna say about Keith
strob holy
[ __ ] hey I got no problem being not nice
to people who weren't kind I mean I know
he worked hard and he has tried to write
the wrong that he did he he done a lot
for cannabis but he he also put one of
the biggest foot in the mouth of the
I don't even know what to say I mean
Carter had all but promised and then it
just completely fell to
dust yeah I mean look Willie smoked on
top of the roof of the White House etc
etc so you know this is why we've had to
continue to fight is because of the fear
and the ignorance and the perpetuation
of this drug war and you know drug
Warriors meant their best but you know
we screwed up and we [ __ ] up along the
way to the point where we've had to
continue to fix things and we're still
still dealing with the Fallout and the
picking up and we're still not there yet
I mean we've done it in the 10th
Amendment you know States but nationally
you know we're we're working I myself at
Chen I look forward to Federal Beyond
decriminalization true legalization
where Interstate Commerce is allowed to
happen International
Commerce I want Lebanese hash I want
okay but let's start with interstate and
then move on to I mean Canada's right
there and I'm sure Canada would love for
us to grow all the weed for
Canada said no no Canadian ever well we
used to grow quite a bit for you guys so
I mean we don't mind it going back and
forth let's keep it
synergistic I would be in Hawaii and
people would uh bring me BC bud and say
Yan this is Dei WWI
I want to know why they had a Jamaican
accent in in Hawaii and they had BC the
Jamaicans day everywhere the herb is M
all right this is a perfect segue into
rest in peace Mr Livingston the final
the third sad story Mr Bunny Mr Bunny
and and my goodness I don't know of you
any of you that actually know the whole
story but his wife went missing uh a
while ago she just wandered off and no
nobody has been able to find her for a
very long time uh and then bunny just
recently passed I was lucky enough to
see bunny many many times in concert was
lucky enough to puff with him and meet
him and be at his house and uh he was a
super Tripper and uh yeah the last of
the living wher so I suspect that uh
Peta and Bob and Bunny are you know in
Zion right now just uh enjoying enjoying
the good herbs enjoying the good music I
can only imagine the music that is being
produced in the
afterlife there's some pretty week
before that it was you Roy it was yoy
rest in peace to yoy as well and yoy
used to come to Amsterdam and we would
get together at his hotel and uh smoke
skunk and I mean he was a really downto
Earth nice guy I mean isn't it you Roy
that hooked you up with like culture and
all those guys well I I connected with a
bunch of them here in Amsterdam because
uh yeah I I I was very free with my
herb yeah you were and you love reggae
music that was another thing that I
always knew when you showed me your
reggae collection I was like this is all
okay if he wasn't a brother from another
mother before this he just opens up
these two drawers under his television
and they're just like full of CDs and
then he's like oh and uh I've got these
uh recordings from the last 25 years at
the mky ve like every reggae show that
was like at the Paradisio or the milk
vag I can't remember which one it was I
recorded them on D digital so they're
really good dude you gave them to me
I've been listening to them for
literally 15 plus
years one of my favorite one was uh aam
on you turn me on to IA man everybody
was singing his songs with him and he it
just like took his breath away and he
quit singing and would just hold the
microphone up to the audience cuz they
were doing such a great job dude bubble
on you turned me on to that song so long
ago you were like this should be your
theme song and it was I jaman bubble on
and for those of you that haven't heard
that song I I remember doing that
absolutely and uh I I I really love a
Jan's music and his backup band were
really nice guys too totally yesterday
Clinton Fon who's I guess living in
Seattle uh did a little um sort of uh I
guess it was you know in honor of of uh
bunny uh and he just had his acoustic
guitar and that's another incredible
reae artist that you know the guy by
himself in his living room sounds so
full his voice is so perfect his tone is
is is just perfection and then he's just
playing beautiful acoustic guitar um he
did like three or four songs but for
those of you that don't know Clinton
fear on uh he had his own band The
Boogie Brown Band um couple of great
albums that you can that you can
download um I can't remember it was
something about the devil uh don't
disturb the Devil is a really good album
with Clinton me and the wife were in the
grill uh either the last time or the
time before I don't remember because
they all get kind of blurred but uh we
were there uh at I forget the name of
the place it's the really big V you
there on the beach uh for when you go
south of town but Alfred maybe
or it doesn't really matter but the end
effect was bunny was performing he
jumped off the
stage gave my wife a big kiss and then
uh you know shook hands with a few other
people and stuff like that and then jump
back up there but uh it really made my
wife's uh night
oh yeah I could imagine she would be
stoked on that I could imagine why he
would do that too because no one is
beaming more love than your wife while
dancing to reggae music like truly I've
been at regae shows with your wife and
she really is in heaven when she's at a
great reggae show particularly from one
of the reggae Elders because we we went
to quite a few reggae shows together and
she was always like there's no way the
person the artist on stage didn't see
her
beaming
yeah like you said we we've seen more
than a 100 or 200 I don't even know how
many Reay shows uh you know e even some
of the early uh Bob wher ones we saw him
perform twice in Santa Cruz at Pacific
there and it was amazing amazing shows
and you could easily see the difference
between the uh show that was about 3 or
4 years before his death and the one
that was a year or two before his death
he just did not have the energy or the
pizaz that he had from his previous
shows you could tell he was running out
of
steam yeah it's amazing that you got to
see him pre- running out of steam and a
little bit running out of steam that's
that's I just can't even imagine someone
said uh Steel Pulse guys are super chill
yes I'm I'm lack to farai I got to meet
those guys back stage at the I can't
even remember it was in Amsterdam with
Rob and I I had my two-foot rure in the
crowd and so Rob kind of found me and we
just took bong rips through the whole
show while Rob told me a cool story he's
like I know the bass player really well
I won't share the story because it's
Rob's story to share but he was like we
should go backstage after the show and
and bump into him and uh wow the guy was
very receptive to Rob they were
definitely brothers from another mother
he stopped everything when he saw Rob
and ran over and gave him a big hug they
have an incredible history they were
friends both here and further south yeah
yeah exactly so uh it was that was also
a cool experience to just be like I like
meeting kind of bands that I adore and
love in that situation I never want to
go backstage as the Rando like meet and
greet guy and just be like I don't know
those guys weren't as nice as I thought
it's like well no [ __ ] dude you like
interrupted them while they were working
like that's the truth Marcus and a lot
of people don't understand that that's
they that's the they're showing up to
work tonight you're you're yeah it's not
the same it's it's not the same but when
you meet them with a friend you know
like that that becomes quite different
and that's you know of course we all
want to meet these amazing musicians
that have inspired our lives and like
you know created the backdrop for the
soundtrack of Our Lives of course you
want to meet those guys and give them
high fives and respect and be like man I
love what you're doing and I just want
to be supportive of you but there's
definitely a right way to do it and a
wrong way to do it and Uh I leared that
many you right when he would fly into
Amsterdam when he checked into his hotel
he gave me a call and tell me this hotel
room number so that I could bip over
there and uh help him uh get
herbal get herb belated I bet you those
guys weren't smoking the hash though
were they uh no some of them did you
really smoked a little bit of that
mainly they smoked herb but uh they
would also uh put a little bit of hash
in their joints or even puff on hash I
mean when we were in Jamaica huge
amounts of the really hardcore guys they
all smoke
Dabs Mark's kind of got this like Jerry
look from 87 you remember that one where
he's like looking down above his glasses
what
what you doing a little
it's true you you're he does have the
Jerry look right now especially dude go
look at Mark's old pictures he has been
Jerry for a long time like I went
through his 90s photos and I'm like damn
this [ __ ] was Jerry Garcia show
us both your hands let's see your hands
Mark yeah Gotta See got all your
fingers that would be Commitment if he
was just like oh yeah I had that removed
you know when I was 12 when I realized I
was Jerry Garcia is that the The
Grateful Dead Yakuza does that or
something like that that's the that's
the great I got a Grateful Dead shirt on
I think this is like a radio City 1980
shirt oh my God
1980 how long ago was that oh [ __ ] what
do you got going on there that is a nice
shirt too 41 years Mark yeah 41 years
geez I've got my 1990s one remember this
one his master's Choice Oh
Yeah from the m CA kind of thing where
the dude sitting in the lazy boy getting
blasted by the the speakers but it's the
The Grateful Dead Dog well that's also
that's also reminiscent of the RCA
Victor thing with the dog kind of making
the dog dog face in into the uh into the
old photograph
right
voice the dog's name was Nipper because
my dad had a stuffed uh Recreation of
the RCA dog that's how I know because it
has the the thing on his name that says
Nipper I'm impressed that you knew that
actually when you said that I was just
like what is this Trivial Pursuit this
guy just happens to know the dog's name
I know some useless random [ __ ] man but
you know to the Deads you know what a
long strange something something long
strange trip yeah well today is a great
day in grateful Deb history because
there's an incredible bird song from
3781 that everyone should go listen to
up on YouTube It's like a 17 minute bird
song and Jerry's just off the hook 81
it's a great year it was my senior year
in high school what a what a great time
to be alive right so I must be 10 years
older than you because I think my senior
year in high school was 91 91 that's the
same with me Marcus maybe that was the
end of end of Brent was that the the end
of an era yeah Brent
died yeah right so
I I I remember everything in Grateful
Dead history just so you
know yeah you wouldn't be a true dead
head if you actually remembered
everything that's the big joke you know
but uh my parents were lucky enough to
back in the early 70s and us and H San
Francisco and all that that's where they
met but they weren't huge dead heads but
they did get lucky to see like the
closing of winterland in San Francisco
and W and all that and that's really
special I've been really enjoying
watching the old Grateful Dead parking
lot videos
does anyone like go back and sayg
Grateful Dead parking lot 1980s Grateful
Dead parking lot 90s I mean there's so
much good feelings in the lot there's so
much we're part of something bigger
we're saving the Earth We're natural
beings we're listening we're ecstatic
dancing together we we're we're an
alternative to you know the system of
the governance and you know it's really
what really had us that's why a Grateful
Dead is is not just music it was an
incredible
movement watching some of those old
parking lot videos to just really
understand wow this is Ground Zero in in
America North America for keeping
culture alive and the cops knew it holy
[ __ ] unbelievable Sam what was your
first Grateful Dead
show like The
Grateful I honestly don't remember but
it was in the late
60s so it was a while
ago that's the right answer for anyone
that saw the Grateful Dead in the late
60s just uh for your information did you
go to the Honda but you know I was never
a serious serious dead head I probably
saw him a dozen times but uh yeah I
mean back then in the late 60s I like
Jefferson Airplane and Country Joe and
the Fish I liked you know I mean the
dead is not as
psychedelic as some of the other music
and or at least I interpreted other
music as more
psychedelic Sam I got a question just
disagree with
that yeah well I I'm not saying that I'm
the the music God and my choice is final
but uh uh me personally I found uh you
know Jefferson Airplane really really
and and Country Joe and uh yeah there
was uh bu yeah
whatever I'm I'm not gonna it's my
personal taste well the the dead were
the house banned for the acid test for
for key and the pranksters when they did
that so when when that first whole
experimental thing mixed I mean the dead
were was in that melee not the airplane
not Quicksilver not anyone the dead were
the house ban and I guess
Sam was there this is just I was I was
at some of the he's just telling us
where he tripped the deepest where he
where his trip really vibed happened to
be with Country Joe and and the
Jefferson Airplane I'm sure there was
some other people that F and are totally
amazing players and and to watch them
solo even nowaday days is truly
phenomenal so Jack Cassidy yor M calinan
huge UPS you know white r abbit and
Grace I mean Grace Slick is an amazing
artist if you've ever been to the
emerald cup since we're weed Zone I mean
she was at the emerald cup a few years
ago with all of her art and everything I
mean her Art's Amazing Grace Slick is an
amazing awesome person who's very
intellectual very much still turned on
um a total artist still so I mean it's
not that you're far off it's just the
Grateful Dead of millions of hours of
psychedelia and stuff but it's good to
have recognition to all the Psychedelic
movements of you know that
era hey Sam yeah I mean the first one I
remember was 13th floor
elevator you're going to get a shut
down I don't know how people do reaction
videos I remember for the longest time
if you used half a second of someone's
copyrighted music they shut you down on
YouTube shut down they do but then
there's people doing reaction videos
where they're like let's watch Stevie
Ron do Texas flood and they're just like
watching the entire video on their
Channel without basically breaking and
I'm like this must be a loophole of some
sorts maybe we need to do some reaction
videos on here hey Sam did you ever
listen to what Miles Davis was doing in
the in the late 60s and early 70s was
that ever I I what I really really
really liked was the Psychedelic side
coming out of San Francisco I mean the
the or north of San Francisco uh I
listened almost everything I listened to
rabish Shankar I listen to all kinds of
different stuff but what really turned
my crank was what I was talking about
awesome that's awesome
man man I miss music I miss live music I
miss going to concerts I miss seeing my
concert friends I miss traveling for
concerts I miss tripping out at
concerts me too hey Miss tripping
concerts Colin do you remember the name
of the synthesizer person um not moo but
the synthesizer uh analog from San
Francisco yeah yeah I mean there was
some incredible psychedelia going on
there if you want to talk about crazy
yeah that yeah the dead actually were
really into buchas and and the Moog
synthesizers and they used to do their
own private acid tests together as a
band and just be in one room with a with
a modular synthesizer and you know from
what I understand talking to them behind
closed doors they would just get in a
room and just play with this and try to
understand soundscape and that's really
where like Mickey Hart and and you know
started looking towards midi and
starting to understand like hey like
sound what about sound what what's
removed this idea of an instrument and
um they really talked about a lot of um
you know different ways that they would
connect with the universe and and
spiritually through that and it's it was
very new to me as a younger guy because
I didn't really I always looked at that
stuff as like not real music and this
and that and I just you know as you get
more educated you start to understand
that it is and it's just sound it's it's
all in how you put it together and um
super interesting fascinating how they
got into that but bua is amazing and
that's the you know is the precursor to
where we're at right now with all these
modules and instrumentation that's being
built um it's fascinating man it's super
cool can you put that person's name in
the chat CU people could check him out
and see like crazy wires and walls of
analog sound and stuff it's very
interesting I mean San Francisco is
always gonna be a point of Awakening but
wow in the in the 60s with the MK Ultra
studies and if you watch a Ken key
documentary you'll find out that not
just Ken key but also ROM dos was part
of those MK Ultra Childs and it was part
of what made ROM dos become spiritual
and become an enlight you know whether
he's enlightened or not but a spiritual
being on Earth and you know kenkey you
know just getting filled up from this
this lore and then bringing it to the
people you know a lot of people talk
about them messing it up but at the same
time it was just an uncontrollable thing
that the the human beings needed so it's
it's fascinating to see the Psychedelic
Awakening that happened in the 60s and
we talk about it plenty but it's just an
amazing time I mention last time I
mentioned him last time and I'll mention
him again Sun raw if you want to get
psychedelic and trippy space is the
place it is when I when I went to high
school first year was
1965 LSD was still legal in
California that's how different the
world is
today but it was also the experimental
uh nature that the the sound due to the
technology was there so it was you know
colum what you're speaking toward is you
know you're a musician so now that
you're putting it together it's one
thing when you orally hear it when
you're not a musician but when you're
actually producing it you know where you
mic it you know where you do your vocals
you know if people knew how many actual
hit songs were actually recorded in a
bathroom because the sound vocals were
actually awesome would blow many minds
but you know the modelization the
continued experimentation between you
know what Pink Floyd and uh Grateful
Dead were sonically doing really changed
a lot of the atmospheric sound and
access because then they started you
know the access of the eight channels
and started you know expanding just
really fascinating if from just a
musical standpoint of just understanding
of how the musicians would just come in
as Studio musicians back in the 40s 50s
and 60s Bam Bam Bam Bam go off as
opposed to now having an obnoxious
amount of time to sit around in a studio
and just
experiment I mean really push the edges
of the boundaries well yeah it's like
Jerry Garcia said that you know we they
always talked about how they got really
their education uh in the studio that's
that's really how they they learned was
being in the studio his quote his quote
was recording in the studio is like
building a ship in a bottle playing live
music is like being like a rowo on an
ocean think about you know think about
uh you know uh Sergeant Pepper's Lonely
Hearts Club plan four four tracks four
tracks that if you really think about
that it's
mindblowing yeah and most drum sounds
from the 40s and 50s were recorded in in
defunct uh movie theaters with One
Singular microphone over top it was a it
was a ribbon mic and it would just it
was just a single monos source and we we
think about like all these you think of
drums you think of all these mics and
it's just the it's environment it goes
back to plants right it's your
environment right it's your environment
that you're actually in uh that's
creating that nuance and that that
intricacy has anyone ever seen the
secret life of
plants
yeah it's so beautiful how Stevie Wonder
does the soundtrack to it and it's just
so interesting how in the 70s they're
playing with Sonic sounds and you know
there's a new device out these days
called the Healy and it's like a
frequency healing a biof feedback tool
and people use it for healing and you
know it might be uh a lot of reasons to
believe it could be useful in the garden
you know as a as one of those
subsonic you know it's kind of like the
schumans resonance thing where it's the
7.8 but it could be any any uh frequency
and you know so like Sonic sound and
life go together if you find out it's
beneficial and you want to grow cannabis
by the acre then what do you do do you
get loudspeakers
or I think you're right I think that
once you get into the field you just
understand that you don't need a
subsonic resonance because you have the
Earth's resonance these types of tools
are used for fake environments like
green houses and indoor uh settings I I
think but you
know yeah there was some science back in
the 70s about
um the effect of sounds and the onset of
Morning Light opening the statti on
leaves and uh a whole transformation in
their metabolic processes going on
associated with the sounds of Sunrise
and the change in
light that is
awesome hey just on the covid uh uh
development man they're just there
continues to be a number of papers and
reports showing efficacy uh this one I'm
looking at right here on a combination
of tenses and CBD this was
reported uh by a group in
Israel and there's like two other groups
that are getting a lot of press now one
um in the
University of South Carolina and the
other one up there in in Canada
University of Lethbridge that showed
cbd's impact on taming the so-called
cyto kind storm which is one of the
things that leads to acute respiratory
dpress syndrome which is what shuts
people's breathing down in covid so
there really is some you know
biochemical rationale and basis for not
only preventative uh measures against
covid but also this paper right here is
actually pointing out specifically the
antiviral potential of just tpes and CBD
so that's pretty exciting stuff it's
been my experience yes it makes perfect
sense CBD works with the immune system
it just it's it seems like a no-brainer
Mark I mean I it just and and I can't
wait for the Science World the medical
world to catch up with this idea yeah I
think they're beginning to figure it out
and there's a real biochemical mechanism
because again the way that CBD impacts
homeostasis and you know canono and full
spectrum canono sort of impacts um
homeostasis and they're not saying that
these compounds are antiviral but
they're they're showing that I guess
both preventatively and that they can
treat um uh the the real killing part of
the Corona virus which is the acute
respiratory distress syndrome was and
it's a
overstimulation of your own
immunological response that again I
think the canono depending on your your
endoc canabo tone if you will uh uh can
have a real impact on changing how your
endoc canabo system is dealing with
fending itself off from the virus so it
also leads to believe that there is a
genetic basis for fighting viruses like
the Corona virus that you know the endoc
canabo system can help understand the
mechanism on how that works can you drop
that link uh Dr Mark because I've been
reading various uh preliminary studies
but uh they haven't actually gone
through or I haven't seen any actual
study that's gone through the process
but you know I've been reading numerous
articles that have said that they're
working on this so to to to hear that
they're actually getting some actual
traction would be amazing yeah I mean I
I think that there's right now the the
the research is very preliminary and it
shows that there's a whole lot more
research that needs to be done and
before they really get to conclusive
here's how you you know you know keep
yourself healthy or here's how you can
treat your disease if you have to get it
I mean the point is is I guess there is
a a a biochemical rationale for why
these treatments should work and
understanding that rationale is actually
helping scientists figure out how they
could actually deal with the virus a lot
better and the other thing is that I
don't know if you saw this statistic but
because of the social isolation and
people using mass and all that all the
other forms of transmittable disease
including influenza are all down so so
really if we can just get Corona in
check you know I think a lot of the new
practices you know not saying that
social isolation will remain but you
know just our our overall you know
education on how to not spread virus and
how to not live on top of each other and
breathe all over each other I guess is
going to be useful but I'm with you
bubble man I'm looking forward to live
music coming back I see festivals that
are now on the calendar that are selling
tickets and selling RV passes and
they're talking about doing festivals in
Social isolation mode so God only knows
what that's going to look like but yeah
looking forward to music coming back for
sure you know my question is this if we
okay think of just how we were just
coughing in each other's faces never
washing our hands touching everything
people coughing into their hands and
then touching things how many people out
on a cake right dude how many people
were did we did did Humanity like you
got to think all the influenza cases
like 40,000 a year deaths was the same
thing as covid like that you got that
from your family members and from
friends and from loved ones like that's
how you got it I that's never been a
part of the ation you know 40,000 people
die a year from influenza and never did
we think hey like maybe we should uh try
to clean this up a little bit uh we
might be killing our elderly population
by coughing in their
faces well I'd like to make a special
note that there's been a hundred days of
protest in India does everyone know
about this the Farms Indian farmer
protests about it and
there's 200,000 and more people living
in trucks on top of themselves with no
mask on eating food together communally
fighting for food sovereignty and small
farmers I find it really interesting
that there's no sickness spreading there
and I wonder what's different about that
human reality than the United States
human reality because when you talk
about people living on top of each other
you would automatically think of India
or Nigeria and logos and I just I find
it really interesting that they they
don't have the fear and the the numbers
of spikes following it and I just I find
it
interesting well I mean India definitely
has a ridiculous amount of cases I work
with quite a few Indian people who are
in contact with people back home all the
time so they've definitely got it going
on there but if you ever go to India
what you'll notice is that like Corona
virus is just like put it on the list
bro there's like 10,000 things that can
[ __ ] kill you there you can't even
wrap your head around it it's kind of
scary you know there's 10,000 Corona
viruses that we deal with every year on
an every year basis we we're dealing
with Corona viruses so that's also
interesting I'd love to jump in here
about what Mark since we're talking
covid and and infection and all that and
point back to the papers that Mark was
talking about um part of the education
program that I've been doing is a a
conversation about covid and how
cannabis might have effects with with
covid and um so the starting point there
for me is the endoc canono system tone
or health that the system has and every
person's ocono health is different based
on all the factors that can affect
conoid health and when you start looking
at the functions of the of the endoco
system there are things like appetite
and mood and but one of them is
healing and so when you start looking at
viruses in the context of healing what's
true is we evolved being exposed to
viruses of All Sorts bacteria fungi you
know it's all going on because we're in
it uh it's part of our gut it's part of
our skin you know we are creatures of
many different sorts all walking around
together in this
body we learn our endoc kinoid system
evolved to deal with all of that and
yes to some extent all of those things
passing through there's a certain
thinning of the herd if you will of
people whose genetics Andor conoid
Health caused them to be susceptible to
an infection and I think that's true
today with covid yes it's a a new
version of a virus but it's the fact
that I'm certain every one of us has
been exposed to that virus at some point
but we at least in my own case so far
have not contracted the virus virus
haven't allowed the thing to take root
in my body and replicate and therefore
result in me having an infection that or
a diagnosis if you will and I think
that's part of what endoc canono health
is about is our body's ability to
identify a virus and prevent it from
taking root in our body and then there's
the whole aspect of what if the virus
does take root in your body and
replicate and start pre reproducing
madly all through your
system how your body's immune system
eventually responds to that again is a
function of endoc canono health and I
think this is why cannabis chemistry
again it's all about the dose and the
type of chemistry that you're ingesting
or getting into your body however you're
getting into your body but it's an it's
an aid a supplement to enhance your
endoc canono systems health because the
plant canono very closely mimic many of
the compounds that our bodies make to
pre preserve our own homeostasis or
endoc canono health and I think that's
why science is starting to recognize as
they build data over number of people
who have been exposed to the virus have
contracted it or a asymptomatic all of
those various permutations of how this
virus plays out in our bodies are really
a function for each individual of their
endoc nanoid health and their body's
ability to recognize the virus as other
and control its ability to replicate in
your body and or limit the damage it can
do and yeah Mark cyto storm you know
that term but that's what kills most
people with covid is their body's
overreaction and again CBD particularly
I know that one a little bit can tone
down immune response it's a fascinating
compound to me well regulate as well as
down regulate the immune system and and
and that's and that's the fundamental
basis of so many disorders like
psoriasis and and and eczema and and
other things where your immune system is
just on overdrive because it knows it's
being attacked but it doesn't know by
what so it's kind of like when Jean Luke
Bard in Star Trek said fire all weapons
it just fires all weapons and there's so
much collateral damage that yeah the
patient succumbs to that but you you
know the thing like you say like the
endoc canabo tone and that's almost like
something that is is something that's
nurtured that's genetic it's part of the
diet I mean the my wife and I were just
saying that old saying you are what you
eat I mean it is never more true you are
what you eat the molecules that make up
you is because you ate those molecules
right so I mean it is just the the how
do I say this so when we switch over and
part of getting away from the whole
marijuana and cannabis stigma is to is
to switch over to thinking of
cannabinoids as vitamins as essential
vitamins that we need in our diet and
Wade you'll love it I was in a uh I was
in a herb um Clubhouse early today as I
was drinking my
coffee and listening to this fella who
claims um his health has been turned
around he was overweight I think a
diabetic I think he had other health
issues but he has claim that cannabis
juicing has literally saved his life and
that fresh cannaboid acids a fresh diet
rich in cannaboid acids has completely
changed his health
and that he needed like he had smoked
for years and sounds like he had done
other drugs and kind of like like a lot
of people just kind of you know did it
recreationally didn't really consider
the health benefits but now he said this
is part of his routine like I wake up
and make a cup of coffee he wakes up and
juices cannabis and he does it every day
and he claims that again the cannaboids
in their acidic form give the um uh
health benefits that you're not getting
when you smoke cannabis and you're
decarboxylating it and part of it is
that the acidic forms those acids bind
to other molecules and create different
things that are happening Downstream and
so I was just listening in this room for
like about 10 or 15 minutes but got a
whole lot just from from just hanging
out and listening it's cool no I I think
I think that it's fascinating to me how
many manufacturers insist that you have
to decarbox your plant material or your
oil while you're making your product or
it's not going to work and what they're
really talking about is they're they're
they're making product for
psychoactivity right if you're making
product for any other reason from the
therapeutic benefit that possible with
cannabis uh not be to leave it in its
acid forms the canono definitely have
different effects in the than they do
once they're decarbox yeah he claimed so
he had started with full spectrum
decarbox oil like like you said and what
he said he got sleepy and it helped him
with some of his digestive issues but it
didn't really give him the full health
benefits that he leaves now he still
consumes and still I guess Vapes and
still decarbox and gets plenty of
decarbox can canabo which help on a
whole different level maybe help them
more in his brain because when you DEC
carboxilate you're putting things in
your brain as opposed to your body but
your CB2 receptors which is your
peripheral endoc canabo system are
located from your toes down to your you
just everywhere all throughout your body
and so again if you're trying to get
your health in line it makes sense what
he's saying because um he's kind of
getting a a full spectrum in that
carboxilate canab oids are giving him
one health benefit and the decarbox ones
are giving him another
one I agree with that Mark thank you
that's a great description of my
experience well the thing about the
Corona virus uh I've got my second shot
the other day and so uh the nurse was
explaining to me how of course the
problem is the spikes so basically the
RNA vaccine that they give you basically
protects your system against the spikes
penetrating and of course what Marcus
said earlier which was most fascinating
is that you know the nurse stated me you
know there's been no no flu this year
and I looked at her crazy because my
wife had the
flu but she's like universally there's
been none because we're washing our
hands and wearing masks
so um yeah I I I agree with you
completely Wade is that you know there
is definitely um you know CBD and
cannabis in in in its way produce the
the protection in the body and I have
not seen the breakouts you know of
people who have I know people who have
used cannabis and do use cannabis who
have caught covid but a lot of people I
know don't and haven't but you know
again people are isolating so that's a
longer study you know still fascinating
science has anyone read the BBC article
about the gentleman who's got uh I I
don't even know what they're calling it
you know they've got a term for it like
he's he's super immune or he's got a
certain antibody in his body that is
deflecting the spikes it acts as a as a
defense mechanism against those spikes
that you're talking about ATN um I I
wasn't sure if anybody had read that
same article or had any thoughts on it I
don't really know enough other than what
I read um so I just was curious is
anyone had read that same article or
seen that it's fascinating he's a
actually African-American guy which is
also
just opens up a whole Vortex of of
questions a Vortex of questions you
say yeah I mean s you know they they
were they were talking about how certain
subset of communities were were really
affected by by the the virus itself and
uh to find this gentleman um they're
looking for more individuals like him um
they're trying to to understand what's
going on uh but you know I thought that
was really fascinating you know just
just reading that on a basic we you know
very basic News website um so check it
out I don't know if there's any Mark Dr
Mark I don't know if you're if you've
seen that at all but I just thought it
was fascinating to be honest I read it
just yesterday yeah I so there was a
woman again going back to this Clubhouse
room a woman who is a doctor in there
and she said that she was aware of this
uh she was over a hundred years of age
this woman and she's I guess is so old
that she's actually never been
vaccinated for anything in her life but
she's never gotten
anything in her life and she's 111 or
something like that no so she's not
going to get vaccinated and they think
that yeah again I I think a lot of it
with viruses Colin has to do with how um
tuned your immune system is and how well
your immune system is able to respond
and I think that this is different for
different people I mean like like my dad
for instance my dad was in a house where
my stepmom got it and I think my one of
my stepmom's uh uh uh children got it
too so my dad was around it and my dad
is immune compromised and he had
something called um uh valley fever
which is a
a a fungal uh uh infection that you get
in your lungs so he was already very
prone to getting this and we were just
like oh it's just a matter of day I'm
gonna get a phone call my dad's got
covid I gotta go out to Arizona and de
it you know I was just waiting for that
whole thing to happen never happen for
some reason again my dad just seems to
have this super strong immune system
that even though he's been around it and
he's probably been exposed to it he's
able to you know deal with it or it
might just take the form of a couple
days of sniffles and just not be as as
life-threatening as as it is to other
people and and and nobody quite knows I
mean it's a virus viruses a weird like
that if you look back to the AIDS virus
and what happened with AIDS there was uh
most people who contracted AIDS
particularly early on died pretty
quickly but it turns out that one of the
earliest patients and I wish I could
remember this person's name he's become
publicly known but he was diagnosed with
it back in the early 80s and he's still
alive he's and it wasn't he never
contracted any of the conditions that
typically result from AIDS and again
AIDS is a virus most people and I it's
to me it's just it's really about the
genetics of the individual and how well
their body is able to either resist
infection or deal with the infection in
a way that doesn't compromise your
health and so genetics plays a part in
it but the epigenetics of our life and
it's just like the cannabis plant in
this way we talk about how the cannabis
plant and our cells are related in the
way that we can care for our plants or
care for our bodies if a plant if it's
genetics are such that it's not going to
have any trouble dealing with molds it's
probably not going to have much trouble
with molds if it's genetics are you see
where I'm going with that and I think
the same is true with people and how
well a plant sits if a plant is sitting
in very poor soil and is overwatered its
genetics may help its ability to resist
pest or disease but you contrast that
with a plant that's in full sun in full
living soil living water everything is
as good as it could possibly be for that
plant it's likely going to fully express
its genetic ability to to resist pests
and infection of various viruses or
fungus or whatever and I think it
carries over to humans as well and just
to be really clear I don't I'm not
saying that cannabis is the Beall end
all answer to it there's so many things
about life where we have Choice the
quality of food the kind of rest you get
uh how much stress you allow to build in
your life all of those things play a
part in in how well your endoc canono
system can function in your body to
allow you to enjoy good health I really
feel like there's a fundamental thing
there that's going on there's all these
things we have choice about genetics you
don't have much choice about but
cannabis can help you to find Health in
the midst of all this madness that is
life on this planet in this
three-dimensional reality that we call
the world on that note yes here I am
stoned
again I wish you wouldn't have muted it
I would have loved to have heard your
laugh that would have been the perfect
mic drop for that uh well uh it'll
happen
again anyway yeah no I I feel really
passionate about this I really feel like
a lot of the health issues that are
going on in our world today are because
for many of us we've made poor choices
in our life you know riding motorcycle
in my life was resulted in some aches
and pains that to this day linger and
cannabis helps me deal with those
traumas that didn't heal properly and
again healing is a function of the ECS
it's just all of the choices that we do
have however you make those will be part
of what your endoc canono health is
going to be and that is part of how we
respond to
viruses
so anyway enough of
that well it's it's just amazing how you
know science has to you know appeal to
Politics as opposed to politics appeals
to science
um which is why I'm going to kind of
segue here for a second um I've been
working with the last seven months uh
with a group called the veterans Action
Council we're basically a group of
cannabis veterans um who've been using
medical cannabis as well as other
psychedelics and we've come together and
tomorrow we're going to release our
first white paper which is actually a
green paper uh we're calling it which is
uh basically it outline significant
concern
uh within the medical cannabis Community
for veterans and what we feel are
potential remedies so uh we're going to
be releasing that tomorrow it also
includes um Robert Randall and uh Alice
o submittal to the federal government
back in 1993 and to the Clinton
administration because that's how far
back we haven't done anything here in
the United States at the federal level
and um sandwiched also in there is is
Michael Crow's recent success um as we
all know in December 2nd of 2020 medical
marijuana was actually legalized across
the world because our friends spent a
decade getting it pulled off the
schedule 4 off the
1961 uh convention treaty so um medical
marijuana is legal and we want access
here in the United States especially
veterans so uh we're launching this uh
green paper as an educational tool for
people to take at the federal level
other veterans uh to uh use you know
around the world because this is uh real
literature real information uh Robert
Randall for those who aren't aware was
patience zero he was the first patient
to sue the federal government and win
his right to receive marijuana grown by
the federal government uh and which it
opened up to 22 other people until
1992 when they compassionate
investigative new drug program was uh
basically shut down for uh the addition
of any new patients we want to see that
reopened um in the sense that we want to
be able to get veterans to be able to
import cannabis since we can't have
access to the night of cannabis uh but
at the same time I think we also want to
pressure Dr alol and them into actually
growing medical grade cannabis to the
Quality that we're actually selling on
in our dispensaries today uh because
they're only down to one patient now do
you know that yes and to be honest Dr
ooui doesn't make these decisions it's
the Nida that gives him a contract what
to
grow agreed and we're going to utilize
the uh this information to utilize to
pressure them into changing and either
reopening the system so that cannabis
can be grown uh you know to the
standards that we're seeing today or
we're going to import it from countries
that are internationally doing it and
that have over-the-counter products
available such as Canada Uruguay Israel
and the
Netherlands you know that's amazing that
you're doing this work man you know my
dad is 100 first Airborne first of the
506 he is fullblown Parkinson's has had
it for almost two decades and um you
know he's been someone that's
been struggling with access and um you
know he's got plenty of access through
me um however the the type of access you
know there's a certain kind of ideology
that I think he carries you know when he
thinks of the VA and and you know he
wants to keep that camaraderie there and
it's really hard I see it from a lot of
different levels with with certain
patients coming from the VA and and
veterans in general um they want to feel
that camaraderie but it's just not there
from the VA at all um and it's a really
touchy subject but but I really commend
you man that's that's a a very hard
thing to be you know hard path to be on
so really excent work man that's awesome
well that's why we're doing it we're
doing it for your dad and for others
because um we have access where we are
so we're trying to utilize our voice and
our privilege for those who don't have
and don't have access for those who
don't know I'm a combat veteran of
Operation Desert Shield Desert Storm 30
years ago today I was in well well no I
was in I was wounded in Germany uh but
uh you know um so I was put on uh going
from morphine to congratulations uh I
want to get off morphine I asked the
doctor he said hashish and I was in
Germany so that basically started me off
on an exploratory journey into the
underground into trying to not make
criminals out of my friends and not get
myself murdered or ripped off which you
know thousands of other veterans a deal
with on top of that it's expensive I
mean there needs to be one of the things
we want to see is what you have up there
in Canada Marcus is having access so
veterans are actually subsidized so I
you know depending on your disability
you're given a certain amount of grams
of access per month so then you can go
down to a dispensary and however you
ingest if it's Edibles hases or
flowers the gram situation is applicable
to whatever your usage is so we want
that same access that you have in Canada
because we can't go get it filled at a
px so if we have to go to a dispensary
then we want a voucher program so that
it alleviates the costs so many veterans
like your father are also on a 100%
disability which means you're on a very
very limited income for the cost of
inflation food etc etc and when you
start looking at the cost of cannabis
not including the cost of your uh
paraphernalia which can Canada actually
you do if you use uh you know a certain
cannabis paraphernalia the C the country
will actually subsidize that and
reimburse you for that which again we
have none of this type of access so uh
our our veterans should be able to have
this type of access and access points
without a doubt and um here soon yeah
we're working on some other things as
well but this is kind of our first
volley so we're going to be putting that
across the wire at 6:00 a.m. in the
morning or so but oh here I'll drop it
in chat you guys can get a preliminary
it's on our veterans Action Council
website on um under uh projects and uh
this is our first project that we have
that we've released so uh we're just
trying to uh be a rally point for other
veterans so that we can actually uh
pressure the VHA into these changes that
we want to see because you know veterans
are an encapsulation of society and so
we're a small piece of Society so we're
trying to do our best to crack the glass
ceiling so that others have access as
well so we're just trying to uh lead the
charge by storming the beach and um
follow us I'm out can we go back to the
German Doctor Who told you
hashish sure well I was actually
American doctor and I was in uh the
hospital and I was uh they put me on
morphine um and of course they give they
they give you a button right so you can
do take as much morphine as you want and
I was an artist I was a creative person
I was a musician so if I wanted to sit
and drool all over
myself morphine is perfect for that
however I didn't like the feeling I
didn't like the sedation I didn't like
the coming out there was nothing about
it I liked except it stopped the pain
but I could not be in my creative mind
I'm left-handed so I'm always in my
right mind right so I couldn't I
couldn't travel there naturally or as
free flowing
so I asked this I asked the physician
when he came
in I said I want to get off this
morphine and he said have you heard of
hashish and I laughed and he laughed and
I kept laughing and he stopped laughing
and I realized that you know he was
serious and he said look I I I've heard
of people you know utilizing that to you
know get off it and I basically said
well where the hell do I find that and
his response was I don't know try a
bar and that's where it started yeah I I
got went to a bar in ansbach and uh
Germany and you know in my my terrible
German English uh was able to score a
little bit of hash and it was very I
don't think I don't I don't think it was
a full gram you know it was very small
and then how do I ingest
it got one of them they're bar
grams so oh and it was it was you know
it it was all crumbly it didn't squish
you know it was you know probably waxed
you know Afghan they already made rosin
with it and they were just giving you
what was in the
bags you never smoked before you never
smoked before that I had but you know
when we had hash which was very rare it
was the old you take a pen you put it on
the pen you light it you put on a piece
of cardboard and put the glass over it
and you do the the slid under the
glass so yeah hash under the glass so so
you you you grew up in in Louisiana
right so so the kind of hash that you
were getting was like black hash or
Lebanese red hash or it was never golden
right no no no I didn't see golden hash
so I was actually in Saudi Arabia and I
actually bought real Lebanese uh
everything that I had seen and
everything from that I would if you go
along in certain areas in New Orleans
you know they would try to sell you
scrapings out of their bong if you smell
it you could smell bong water you know
so you knew that was fake ass hash uh
but the other stuff you know you kind of
kind of looked hopefully for a little
piece of gold on the top of it from you
know where it was chipped off so I knew
to kind of look for that but no no no
all all we had access to in Louisiana
was crappy uh you know Coca-Cola press
Mexican it wasn't until I was up in West
Virginia that I saw real hash and that I
tried it and we did the whole you know
stick the pin through the cardboard and
put the glass over it and then my
friends went to a head shop in
Pittsburgh and bought one of the old um
what was with the glass dome but it was
a a heating uh a vapor soldering a
soldering plate on the top vaporizer
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah and
you know those oh that was oh we're
gonna get so high off of this and then
you're like oh this sh all burnt oh my
God this terrible yeah uh so there's
just no access to Quality cannabis or
hash until yeah I was D we we've come a
long way that actually makes me feel a
lot better about where we are right now
sometimes I forget where cuz where I am
and where I need to kind of go back it's
a very small Journey compared to where I
was in high school also buying all these
different hashes no coas no you know
Sops like this [ __ ] was like oh yeah
looks like they pressed this with their
feet or something there's like some hair
some weird skin in in in there like but
there it was you know we were just like
happy to smoke it I was lucky to have it
to get you high yeah of course man I for
me the my I I got got to you know we got
Afghani we got a little Moroccan we got
red and blonde
Lebanese and we got Indian and Nepali
Charis and that was pretty special um
you at least back in the 90s yeah Manali
cream or
Parvati you know just like nice nice
nice things and then you know Nepali
cream which was kind of like way above
that whole region and uh that was kind
of always the nicest and Jamaican
Jamaican gun so so the kicker is when I
moved here to the Bay Area the only
place I could score weed was actually
going across the bay to in front of the
Ben and Jerry's on haon ashberry and
because that's where all the dead head
kids were hanging out and you could buy
the eighth quarter three quarters or
quarter right off the street so you know
it's been a long way to think about how
and where we get access to our what year
was that ATM oh that was
93 93 94 absolutely yeah yeah yeah I
would have to I worked at that I was an
before I got hired onto the Cannabis
Action Network I was a night manager at
an ice cream parlor and I used to get
would close at 10: I'd shut down shop at
10:30 I would jog to the North Berkeley
BART catch the BART to the transfer
point at uh MacArthur make it into San
Francisco jump on the 7 or the 5 uh 52
bus or 53 going up to hate ashberry jump
out at the corner of hate and Asbury
score my [ __ ] real quick on the corner
then jump on the other Corner real quick
to catch the bus going back to the BART
and then Bart all the way back to the
East Bay which is usually the last BART
to the East Bay and then walk another
mile home so that's how I used to score
weed on the street so to know that now I
only have to go to a dispensary and
actually purchase it you have no idea
how thankful I am of just that simple
Trek because that used to be a two-hour
you know Trek just on and and trying not
to stink up when you score that that
that bud from those dead heads that [ __ ]
stunk and of course all you had was just
a quick [ __ ] you know roll up and
just stick it in your [ __ ] and just hold
that people weren't [ __ ] like staring
you down the [ __ ] boser on the BART like
I know what you got on
you that's Monica and I used to live at
Paige and Clayton one corner from the
corner of pton ashbery where that Ben
and Jerry's is and yes even even up to
2010 uh there were still kids standing
at the corner selling uh one two and
three and four finger bags it would
stink when you walked by that corner
right like you would smell you knew you
knew were walking up
there was a certain number of and I hate
to keep being you know pedantic here
certain number of dead heads and a
certain given environment it there would
it would smell like weed and like you
walk by a cluster of like three or four
people it would smell like weed and yeah
I mean isn't it funny I mean it's like
when the Grateful Dead wasn't on tour
this is where they set up
shop yeah and which was ironic I ended
up with when I was with can I had one of
only like five Street permits where I
actually was given by the uh chief of
police of San Francisco where I could
set up and I could set up my booth on
the corner of CH of uh of um haon
ashbery so I mean it was just really
weird to go I used to score drugs right
there and here I am working for
legalizing it right here with an actual
permit from the actual Sheriff of
[ __ ] San Francisco allowing me to
give out car cannabis information right
what's the name what what what's the
name of that onpo record store that's
like just a couple blocks away from
Golden Gate Park I mean it's just like
if you if you're oh the one on the
corner there yeah that one Record Store
I mean my God it's like if you if you
like records if you like vinyl and
you're in San Francisco it's a place to
go right I would assume oh if you're
going by the park yeah Park yeah oh my
God we you can score your weed and go
score your wax just in a couple blocks
we we get so baked and we'd go into the
record store and you could literally
it's like a library in there you could
literally spend just like hours in there
and you're not listening to anything
you're just looking at all the records
oh my God it was I spent hours in there
high after getting high on
hate it's a place to
go so
fun oh w
gone of the days speaking of getting
high I haven't stopped puffing since we
started well that's because we haven't
heard from you since we started someone
said where why is Johnny B not talking
I'm like cuz he he got baked what do you
think what do you think the be stands
for in Johnny B it's Johnny
baked no sitting here popping I know
you're sitting there talking about the
beginning of all the changes and I was
gonna you know mention the changes with
the growing and and Chin's talking about
the morphine trip and I remember that
and having to get off of all of the
morphine by using cannabis and and amino
acids and stuff so I'm just mean
listening just like listening on
clubhouse and just taking in all you
guys and chatting away and you know
saying good morning and then my newest
thing which I really like is I mean
actually putting dry sift directly into
my smoothies so instead of juicing the
leaf and I've been just sifting those
gland heads I've been actually putting
dry sift into my smoothies and I showed
it yesterday and I've been talking about
that and I've really seen a difference
in just my mood and everything lately
just last week and a half CAU your mouth
and like when you because I throw it in
the smoothie and and I mentioned
yesterday I could taste a little bit on
my teeth so I kind of yeah was like it's
was a little bit there on the teeth but
the flavors of the tpin from the sift is
so much different from just the juicing
of the leaf that I get that grainy taste
so I've been experimenting too by
listening to a lot of people in
clubhouse and finding the best regimen
for my medicine because I've been
hitting a lot of high THC and I see how
that affects me but I also want to see
how the more
of
i' I'm just testing my own body right
now again like always so you know good
morning I would think that it would
leave like a little grit in your mouth
like like even if you could really
really homogenize it in your blender and
make a really fine dispersion in your
smoothie that it would still like after
you after you've completely drinken your
smoothie it doesn't leave like a grit
behind it all
or I occasionally do what John's doing
and I find the taste kind of pleasant
it's like finding a little nuggets of
flavor exactly that's what I like about
it it's those flavors that I'm getting
from those T that I'm not getting when I
was actually just putting raw Leaf in my
smoothies for a long time then I used to
do the juicing and take the raw I used
to freeze it in the freezer and then
like put those in my smoothies back in
the days after my surgery and stuff like
that so I've been doing this for quite
some time but I really really enjoy just
putting the sift in the smoothie in the
in the morning because you do get those
little genuine little nuggets of
different flavors like oh yeah are you
adding lethin or anything to your
smoothie and if so what smoothie flavor
are you using with what resin I'm using
good food and I just order these suckers
online I get a dozen delivered to my
door every basically two weeks and I
have different flavors so some I use
almond milk with some I use grape juice
with so I have a Kai they're all natural
more raw food drinks that I've been
getting into and stuff like that so been
paying attention to that type of Healthy
nutrition like crazy so I mean this one
in particular um yeah everything's
really healthy so I mean I got cold brew
coffee bananas cashew budy vanilla bean
cocoa nibs roasted coffee beans U mocha
power and Himalayan pink salt well the
reason I was asking if you added um any
any spikes to it in the sense um why
does my video keep cutting out it's
really weird um like that picture you
John yeah there you go um it's
um oh my my my my brain transport for
better absorption is what you're talking
thinking about well it breaks down if
you use uh something like soy leathan it
actually breaks down the acid so it's it
it's more uptable for your body whereas
it sounds like you're going for the thca
experience for the acid experience for
the the feeling as opposed to uh the
body high Etc because that would
actually break it down uh
thought hey I'm just you know I I I like
the thoughts I think I might have done
that in the past but sunflower seed
version of it too atan I don't know if
You' used that before um that that's
also a nice a nice one sunflower seeds
or oil just the oil the sunflower L
letin letin okay yeah let's say this
letin Le
ask Mark I wanted yeah I want to make
sure
we yeah the sunflower letin actually
comes in sunflower oil that is a great
vehicle for canabo so it's it's a good
way to to emulsify them absolutely I
agree with that and sunflower doesn't
have um as it's a taste is pretty
neutral I mean there's definitely a
flavor to it but it's pretty neutral in
flavor as part as far as oils
go yeah so my daily is being a smoothie
with sift as you can see I'm just
getting
healthy I'm uh thinking you might need
some stitches on that shave job on your
chin there Johnny B what uh I'm working
on that come on you know I just then I
riped it off and I B again I was just
like haven't shaved in a
while I thought that was a tattoo don't
shave for a while I thought that was a
tattoo it's just a teardrop on his chin
it means something totally different I
thought it was that's what I thought it
was oh Johnny Be is not gonna get a
tattoo on his chin no he's got some
tattoos though I you
know the Phoenix the dragon that I
chased and the Phoenix that rised above
my he's cracked but he's not broken
absolutely I feel like we're all a
little cracked but not broken it's one
thing I wanted to discuss here and when
you were talking both the new changes in
the system and how you got into this how
Everything's changed quite a bit with
the IPOs and being able to get hash on
the legal Market I find that over the
last 30 years growing has changed quite
dramatically in the last like few years
with LEDs and VPD and looking at the
soils and the microbes and and the root
Temp and like there's so much different
from when I was talking with my old
friends been growing for 30 years and
like now they're like it's a whole new
game they have to learn how to grow
again with the years of experience
theyve had so um yeah I'm just touching
basis on that and how there's been so
much change in the growing Community uh
in the last few years it's been quite
actually a new learning curve totally
well Marcus when you were gushing before
about about your uh you know your guys's
tremendous achievement at a bar in bark
and I I it sounded like something I said
on hash Church a couple weeks ago I was
really you know complimenting you guys
and part of it is that anybody who's
who's has to
undertake getting the the mass
production not at an artisan level but
at a mass-produced level a product out
under GMP manufacturing knows the
tremendous challenge that that exists
and and what underpins that is is
quality it's all about quality and it's
all about quality at at a reproduced at
a at a higher level
at a higher higher volume of production
which is not a trivial thing to do with
anything that's plant-based let alone
cannabis and so that that's a tremendous
Challenge and the last thing I'll just
mention is as you know I mean any
company has got products you know
products is the PW right but really when
it comes down to it it's the people man
it's the people that make these
products and the companies that are
successful
are the ones that know how to retain
their talent because if they treat
people in this quote unquote industry is
just throw away you know5 $20 hour
employ but if if these employer
employers don't realize that their
employees have to see a future in that
company for them or else they're going
to split they're going to go elsewhere
and they can't just be viewed as some
Expendable Workforce they're there in
your lab markets getting once in a
lifetime training from a Pioneer like
you who's basically taken this thing
from Artisan level to GMP production
I'll bet you guys that you guys get like
hundreds of resumés of people chomping
at the bit wanting to just get in there
and get that training and again like if
it if it goes anywhere from here it's
going to be towards GMP level production
so really it just sets the bar so high
that once you once you hit that I mean
it's like everything else working up to
that has been just such a a huge
nonlinear adventure and something done
with Incredible headwinds because if you
think about that stuff was illegal for
so long taking any technology out from
you know the way we used to kind of keep
everything really quiet now we're all
out on the internet you know bragging
about Brands and trying to get you know
big deals going I mean it's no trivial
event and the shareholders the people
who throw the money down that make this
whole thing happen need to make sure to
defer risk that it's done by GMP if it's
not done by GMP you know then they're
taking a tremendous risk at putting
products out there that are going to be
just you know falling flat on their face
so you guys have set the bar and you
know I hope we can get there soon here
in the US and I hope that someday the
Border won't make a difference anymore
and we'll be able to get your product as
you'll be able to get our product and
there'll be a free flow of technology
and commerce at the US Canadian
border that would be something indeed
Mark that would be something and I'd
eventually love to see it worldwide I'd
love to see how people in different
environments can use their Terre to get
their plants to express to this unique
method and and see like oh well this
particular area of the world just seems
to really like this Cult of ours seems
to do the best there and you know it
might take 20 or 30 or 40 years but
we'll suddenly start learning the way we
know that the best lavender you know
comes from France and then the second
best Lavender is in the black forest in
Germany and you know for whatever reason
everyone grows lavender all over the
world but it doesn't seem to express
itself the same way as it does in these
two regions in France and Germany and so
cannabis is going to do the same thing
so many different cool cultivars um
really quickly I want to shout out
denail I haven't used this yet but they
sent me their new blender um uh Banger
that is supposed to just be absolutely
it's like falling film Mark the dab goes
in and then it goes up the side so this
is your heat Source you heat the sides a
little bit and it's really as it goes up
and down the sides uh you get your your
dab and you can and just put a marble on
top like that for uh this is a super
trippy puke and Beagle uh carb cap that
they gave me years ago but I'm going to
use that as my my marble well hook it up
and let's do an online on camera demo
right are you ready dude well I'm gonna
when this one I'm G to I'm going to film
yeah he 3D printed this dab tool for me
as well so this is like a really nice
dab tool that um that that unscrews from
here and so you can replace the handle
with some other different ones and then
they also sent me um his new thing which
is called D modium and I'm not even sure
what I did with the D
modium um he it showed up in like a
little Jeweler box I probably lost it at
this point but it's a new uh material so
he sent me these really cool tweezers so
I could pick up these hot little DM
modium balls and get them into my Banger
um so yeah I'll be doing a video on that
with the 4K camera and uh putting that
up on my channel in a bit I always
forget to shout these guys out when they
give me these amazing things so I wanted
to shout out Brian from denil another
thing I wanted to shout out and I have
to remember this is 1 hour and 43
minutes into the show so I want to shout
out my uncle Gio my Uncle George Who
we've always called Gio since I've you
know been a little little little baby
basically he's was my always was my
coolest Uncle he was my one uncle uncle
that like puffed and was just cool he
drove the old 70s van with like the
unicorn picture on the side or the
wolves like all furry inside he he is
just a cool cool guy I'll never forget
the first time he gave me a little bit
of a nugget and I was just like wow like
this is so cool I'm connecting with
someone in my family who Puffs and he
was really the only person I ever had
that connection with until slowly but
surely I convinced everyone in my family
that they should be using C
which is kind of the case now uh but it
wasn't really the case back then so I
want to shout out Uncle Gio it was his
birthday yesterday I can't remember if
he's like 65 or 66 or 64 6566 comes to
mind so shout out to you Uncle Gio who's
probably hanging out in the big white
shell right now in his cabin you know
taking pictures of foxes and cool Wild
Life and just being an allaround [ __ ]
awesome guy thank you for being my mom's
brother and just being one of the
coolest uncles ever and happy birthday
let's all have a birthday little to for
Uncle Gio and if you guys want to say
happy birthday to Uncle Gio feel free to
do so happy birthday Uncle Gio Happy
Birthday is his real name
George
yeah George is the name that's never
done spelling itself right g e o r g e o
r g e o r g e o r g e o r g e well his
is the French version of it so it's
actually georgis g e o r g s so gorgeous
George right there Gio in the house
happy birthday I'm ripping one for you
the furnace is getting turned on that's
what he calls my electric nail he calls
it the furnace hey are we uh we going to
be turning on the furnace
or shout out to Dil as well solid
information and stuff needless to say um
but uh yeah uh hopefully uh what you're
talking about there Bubble Man uh
hopefully my veterans will be the some
of the first ones to import your bubble
hash into the United States you know um
because uh yeah we all got together
started checking each other on Wellness
checks you know it's been this whole
covid reality where we all been kind of
worried about each other and as you know
uh our veterans suffer from you know 22
suicides a day on average we've lost
more to suicide on unfortunately than uh
we have to war and um by checking in
with each other we realized you know we
could probably do some work together and
then seven months later here's our first
you know green paper so what's the
what's the latest on Sue sisley's
work is that continuing do you know uh
standby um she is at um yeah uh I'm not
sure exactly where she is um
part of one of our guys Rico Pera was
part of uh her studies and worked with
her at the University of Arizona and is
very much in contact with her but right
now I'm not sure what necessarily is
happening as we know uh one of our other
uh Brothers uh Brian Buckley at the
Helman Valley Growers company they just
got an IRB uh to do human studies on
their Vape cartridges in Sandy Diego so
uh they're going to be uh recruiting I
think around 60 or so Veterans for a
control study of where they'll be using
uh real world cannabis uh cartridges
that you can buy currently and they'll
go to dispensaries pick which ones they
want there have a selection of of four
to five or something like that to choose
from and then they'll do the study uh it
is basically uh on the effects of PTSD
because to do the IRB they could do
post-traumatic stress altogether so
they're going after the individual
symptoms to show that in the end have
the scientists go oh wellow those are
all the different symptoms of pts uh
oh so yeah there's uh there's scientist
going on observational study right uh
Rico's making me know that uh Dr sisly
will be publishing soon so uh we'll let
you know and as soon as I get that
across my desk I'll send that to you
right 18 in the study you were talking
about there the the PTSD study the with
cartridges that's just an observational
study that they're doing right uh he's
working with yes uh nedic out of uh
Israel uh so they're actually doing uh
full study and uh replications I think
they're also when uh his company expands
into Michigan they want to replicate the
same study with the veterans in Michigan
so um let's see he is also stating that
the uh study is complete the results of
the doc study will be released soon so
that's where we stand oh watching hash
Church hi
r hi Dr Sue also if you're watching yeah
we should have Dr Sue
on oh yeah we could we could totally
have her on and we have access to her oh
she's a very engaging speaker and you
know I mean again I think we need 10 Dr
sus or 20 Dr sus or 30 Dr sus Dr Addy
Ray is also very well spoken and I I
like uh what I've heard from her and had
a few conversations with her on
clubhouse she's another one we could be
inviting on great yeah we just had her
on our clubhous the other day Dr ad Ray
and um also Dr suis Le works with the
Dem Collective as well and uh I bet we
could even potentially get Ethan Russo
to join us one day if we you know if we
had a a plan for that and you know we
could get some good conversations also
I'd like to just say Kevin mccurnin you
know continues to do amazing work and uh
Kevin mccar has put out a lot of
information you know about the current
pandemic and then just different
scientific things so we really love and
appreciate the work he's doing out there
as well I invited him
today uh Dr Mark also just to clarify of
course Dr ssle was stuck with and for
the audience she was stuck with the
actual Nida cannabis uh which is the
stuff that's grown at the University
Mississippi held in crates fails
microbials all that other stuff while uh
Brian Buckley and the HGC they're using
you know real world cannabis uh that you
can get dispensar so doc Sisley was a
blinded uh Placebo controlled with that
ditch weed
so yeah well I mean even even that ditch
weed we know will will work better than
than nothing at all but I mean h how
ridiculous that they still you know have
researchers especially people who want
to do observational clinical research
their hands held to well you need to put
a proposal through naida to get you know
University of Mississippi you know weed
that that Monopoly is just about to
end and hopefully we're going to be
pressuring that with our green paper as
well because we're presenting it and
it's to be Ule you can take it and go
educate your Educators as well as your
constituency senators and house members
so that you know at the state level and
at the federal level because uh we're
able to do these uh cannabis through the
VA at least recommendation discussions
in these states that are legal and uh
allow for medical cannabis but we're
trying to kick the door open for all 50
uh States and territories so um the
work's going to be not easy to do but uh
you know this is a tool for you to
utilize to educate people so that we can
change the discuss and move the Line in
the
Sand and we can import Bubble Man hash
into
America yes that's that's our real
agenda here which is we need to get
Marcus's hash down
here I'm always I'm always talking with
Colin about certain things and I've got
some conversations going with some
groups in California so maybe one day
again we'll uh we'll have the brand down
there we'll see how it goes it's you
know it's so much work to really just do
it in one place that uh I didn't want to
detract what I was doing here just give
you a mute yeah I think I think we'll
we're gonna
be might seeing it sooner than later
Mark yeah exactly it could happen it's
all the timing right it's not like I
haven't been having these conversations
they just always seem to go sideways in
the 11th hour and because I've had this
brand for so long I'm like yeah I can
wait for like years more more so not
rushing this yeah you could wait the
market won't wait for you though right
so you know what funny thing about the
market was it wasn't the same thing it
was before I started selling these bags
and so then I had this different
perspective than most people I had this
perspective like oh like so you can
follow the market or you can create the
market and those are two different
things and they're very different
Pathways that may very well lead to in
the same direction but they're just one
little Notch off changes everything and
that's kind of what I'm you know trying
to
constantly convince my team of is that
hey like we should be more along the
lines I mean straddling that line
delicately not picking one Camp blindly
but kind of straddling that fence on
both sides and and gaining access from
both those perspectives instead of only
one
be the
market be the market isn't that what go
ahead in general people like to go for
quality or quantity I'm talking about
producers and generally generally the
quality comes from smaller
sizes generally speaking that's why it's
so difficult to bring the quality to the
big you st stage and that's why Mark is
you know Mark scallon's given Marcus so
much Kudos is because it's not super
easy to have quality at at a at a large
scale it it can be done and it's always
a hard you know it's always a goal but
you know generally the quality is in is
in the small uh you know small holder um
and I like what Johnny B was saying I
mean things have changed in the growing
world and we've seen an absolute you
know let's say explosion of of living
soils in indoors and uh you know it just
continues to prove itself and when you
say you have to relearn everything one
of the things you're relearning is you
don't have to do so much so once you
create the bed once you create maybe a
wooden bed or some kind of a bed for
your plants to grow in and you recognize
that a larger soil and a bigger root
base you know is going to keep a health
to your plants and then maybe now you're
using predators maybe 30 years ago you
never needed Predators honestly 30 years
ago I mean who had a lot of pests so as
cannabis grows and as cannabis gets used
all over the place you know and the
environment changes and more extreme
conditions are created pests get created
so you know the use of predator mites in
in nurseries and even kangan water as uh
Eric from uh you know the greenhouse
down in in California talks a lot about
is uh you know this kangan water used in
in clones and nurseries um and even for
folar sprays I mean there are some new
technologies that can be used but you
know having living soils beds uh you
know um an IPM through Predators I mean
you find you have to use a lot less
attention and and that's really
beautiful to see and incredible amounts
of people are changing over so really
right now it's how to build a bed and
how to layer in soil and make it last 20
cycles and then create the the and then
help one of the things we need to do is
help influence like the recreational
regulations because in some cases the
regulations are so stringent that it's
hard to produce living soils and a
recreational thing but we'll always go
back to green life Productions in Steve
cwell down in Las Vegas area up in PRP
but uh in in Nevada has very stringent
microbial laws and also they've had to
work together with digilabs Laboratories
in Nevada to to be able to bring um
living soils to a stringent market so
they are real forerunners in an indoor
market that's one of the reasons why
they've been pure certified for a really
long time they're one of the ones that
really made a difference and they've
really brought LEDs to the Forefront you
know and how to use those proper how to
recycle all your water and everything
from your air conditioners and
dehumidifiers I mean these are closed
loop how to have wor worm farms and
everything and continuously build their
soil they're on 24 Cycles right now
indoors in that situation and what one
thing that's really exciting is they've
been recently able to bring hash to the
market so ganja Gill who's been on here
a few times you know is is has been
helping them get their Tech dialed in um
and green life Productions is now
bringing beautiful to the market in
Nevada and Las Vegas so you know um
beautiful Works being done even in
stringent High microbial uh uh
jurisdictions or States I just wanted to
mention I've been using bio controls
good bugs to kill the bad bugs for 45
years I recently like that I like copert
over there in N and in the Netherlands
sorry to interrupt you please come on in
a sec but uh you know place people like
s companies like
senta support GMO and really harmful
practices on Earth and and one thing
about copert and and correct me if I'm
wrong but they they you know produce
bugs with in non- GMOs um and they don't
uh involve themselves in a larger
companies that do harmful practices on
Earth so cprit's been a good one there
are other ones plenty of other ones but
that they sell all
over I was going to say I've recently
added these to my uh bug line so
actually and since I've done this a
couple months ago my plants have never I
don't have spidermites or nothing so um
it's been living bug living bugs for me
is actually changed so I'm using uh
perus Hotpot I'm using spidermite
Destroyer I'm using Predator m I'm using
M preventor so these are little things I
actually added to my garden for the
first time of growing after like 30
years and guess
what I'm
happy a
long yeah when I added everything in
Combined I used to try ladybugs I used
to try these little fix but I've never
added everything at once and I think
that was the biggest thing is listening
to all you guys and really just taking
that next step just being an old SCH
grower not want to go to that next
little you know that next little okay
I'll jump over the fence so I finally
did that and um it's been quite a great
thing of looking at how this whole thing
works because I mean we got to consider
we got to look at right now we're
looking at Spectrum coverage yields the
grower and what's coming from that right
so lots of good stuff hey Johnny also uh
check out some nemoes definitely uh I
have those too sorry and I have Nemo
toads in my soil
awesome and then inject in those
nematodes into your soil in a way that
they don't die off right away you know
and you can do that in in different ways
the way that you apply the nematodes to
your soil you know um to slowly disperse
them evenly throughout your soil will
help them live longer and and and in the
bed you know so I've done them when they
come on on a form where you just
sprinkle them over or then you can
actually get them in a little thing we
throw them in our reses and then they
just apply by water so I've had two
different methods
okay that's super good one thing that's
often overlooked with people we still
see it is the misdiagnosis of broad
mites and russet mites and it really
really takes having a microscope and
turning the leaf upside down and looking
at the leaf I mean a trained eye can see
it right away when they walk into the to
the um to a garden generally the The
Leaf tips are bending down with broad
mites and and and russet mites it's
often the the leaves are tacoed and then
there's also that yellow look to the
leaves and so um swiki and cucum Maris
together um we have found really works
really well with with both broad mites
and ret mites it can also work for thrip
because it's it can be a thrip um thing
too as
well and um using those like we said
before in your uh in your mother room
you know and in your cloning and and in
your vegetative place is essential
because to try and it to try and you
know take care of the Colony after it's
in the flower room is you know say it's
too late you know you're already your
but your plants need to build buds
rather than worry about getting sucked
on from underneath the leaves
so flat leafed very flat Supple leaves
is is what we're looking for and any
compromise to the leaf you know that
there's some microscopic thing I mean
the spidermites are easy to diagnose
because you walk into a room and you
white dots and in the worst case you see
you you see webbing um you know so there
there there's different things for
spidermites but it's nice to maybe name
your species get uh you know pilus and
Cal fornicus or two that work really
good with spider might some people use
Anderson um you know but uh talk to your
local bug you know supplier and if it
can be expensive but when you get
into trying to combat a situ ituation
that's going out of hand it's very
difficult to to do that so keeping ahead
of that is always good for anything even
powdery mil you know Milos or dowy Milos
or different things so anyway uh
prevention is the
key say that again prevention is the
key prevention is the
key got it
well I told my family I would do a short
hash church today I don't know if you
guys want to keep going for a while I
can always uh leave it on for another
hour if you guys want to chat and puff
some bowls and get deeper into the
conversation I'll kind of live leave it
up to you guys I'm uh I'm gonna go hang
out with my little son who's waiting for
me on the other side of that door
anxiously so we're going to go too our
son turns 24 this week Sky his birthday
week so everyone can give Sky some love
and and Kelly for you bring into the
world G is he on the other side of the
door uh no he's outside getting ready to
go on a snowmobile Excursion up into the
mountains he just got a knowboard for
his birthday which is very very popular
in the area people can look at no boards
it's without bindings and very popular
up here as well
exactly so um yeah so we're gonna you
know help him prepare for that and also
we are coming out dragonfly Earth
medicine Kelly and and the family we're
coming out to Victoria and to to
Vancouver this week so we're really
hoping to meet up with you Johnny B
Marcus maybe get a chance to check out
Embark look around check out Whistler
Technologies and uh seeden stone is a
dispensary that's um highlighting a an
MMA uh fighting event where Elias th
theodoro is is is a cannabis athlete
here in in Canada and it's going to be
one of the first sports events where in
the world where you can legally um use
cannabis not as a performance-enhancing
drug but as a food as an as an
essential uh you know element for your
for your body so he's gonna be able to
go into the ring and and have a vape off
his pen and uh and be able to to go
right into the fight and it's a really
big moment so the First Nation the SES
First Nations is also uh gonna be a part
of the event so we're going to talk
about how you know rightful access to
First Nations communities in Canada can
be enhanced through regenerative farming
and through uh intentional medicine and
and and good products like we talk about
here and intentional products and maybe
you know I don't know how First Nation
could maybe interact with American um
you know native groups and Nations but I
think there's good communication you
know potential there so we are very
excited about what can happen um the
First Nations uh different First Nations
groups in Canada are able to create
their own Realms still in a lot of ways
so it's really important for them to be
able to get education in the way that we
give it and other people give it so that
they can help with their addiction
problems and different ailments that
they have within their communities and
maybe diff this CBD medicine Mark like
you're talking about today and some of
this intentional ways that we are able
to analyze cannaboids could be very
beneficial to these First Nations
communities which do have a lot of
issues with health and well-being and
and there's a lot of reasons why that is
so we're really excited to support them
and everyone else because they have the
ability to influence
other Federal jurisdiction laws if
there's success there so big love to
everyone we really appreciate your heart
and your your intentions uh we
appreciate you you're awesome have a
wonderful day make the best out of drop
behind Josh look at that backdrop right
you look no no no no no you have to
right just that's good perfect it's an
analog backdrop it's a Banes
uh Boutique so big love to our family in
Bali because we have a you know very
special family out in Indonesia and it's
non-cannabis related it's heart centered
Temple related and uh we appreciate
color and sound and gamalon and food and
if anyone gets the opportunity to go to
Bali again in the future they'll find
that there is a an amazing International
permac culture Awakening happening there
and the use of tropical permaculture
models and bringing that from Farm to
Table with raw foods and incredible
recipes from the world Bali is an
amazing place to eat food meditate
resonate and give
thanks give thanks
everybody peace out