okay oops one second what's wrong my sad
how about now hey all right a little bit
of technical difficulty today but we
made it work didn't we at 10:00 can you
hear me I can hear you beautifully my
Jess all right
I'm having trouble with my logitech
camera I'm back to my FaceTime camera
for some reason when I downloaded
everything back to my computer yeah some
still some technical issues but good
morning good morning good morning good
morning let me make sure I sent off the
link to the hash Church aficionados in
the other room I did but it's only
really been seen by you so far yeah I
got it no problem no issue excellent
well nice to have you back my friend
it's we missed you last week yeah I had
a computer crash I had a corrupt file
vault and yeah my computer completely
locked up every time I turn it on it
would just go black Jesus yeah so I had
to wipe it and then my wife my my
reinstall was corrupted so I had to
literally go everything all over again
so it was you know a total fun time suck
as you know yeah no one here up watching
has there ever any any problems with
computers right they're perfect they're
awesome how was your week sir oh you
know very busy very busy I'm just still
trying to make sure that all these
invitations get out to the right people
cuz I know well we had I talked to Brian
from vital garden supplies he said he
was gonna make it in today so I want to
make sure he's got the link I also
talked to Wade
wait laughter they're from yeah so also
hoping that he's going to be making it
in and I also talked to Peter from soil
Balance Pro and he also said he was
gonna be making it in so between those
three guys right there we could have a
nice little conversation about bacteria
and soil and greenhouses and such right
on right on
shut up to our people down in chalice
right now is bearing the heat oh my god
dude it was Oh what is that 100 and I
thought 100 910 yeah but much love to
everybody pulled it off and yeah it was
interesting to see with their they did
testing her everything and they had
quite a few fails they didn't really
post and they just said they had fails I
saw I saw a little bit of fails oh man
it was surprised that's still so many
high numbers of failures in these
competitions which you know that's part
of the reality of people not realizing
what and where they're getting their
product from that they're making their
hash or people just outright lying you
know which is here way is crazy to to
know you're gonna get your material
tested and just be like I'll just spray
a little Avett it's they're not gonna
figure it
hey welcome Wade and welcome Brian thank
you Mark appreciate you having me yeah
yeah good to see you both you guys both
came in almost instantaneously love the
big smiling face Wade thanks feeling
very good this morning that's odds of
exciting things going on that's awesome
well House of harlequin representing and
Brian representing vital garden supplies
dude thanks for showing up man no
problem appreciate you having me you
want to know how your invitation came
out I think it's one of the coolest
stories you know I've been doing these
giveaways on my channel I do awake and
bake every morning that's not hashed
Church just kind of wake and bake and
shoot the [ __ ] with the audience and
sometimes we get pretty deep and we
cover some pretty awesome things you
know I people start sending me stuff all
the time and I don't need this stuff
too much stuff for me so I've decided
I'm passing it all like all of it I'm
just gonna pass all of it out and send
it to the people who appreciate it type
of thing and so I've been doing these
giveaways and then I started doing
contests and of course people were like
oh I answered that before he did look
here's the screenshot from my screen I
won the contest not him holy Christ
and so I I turned the contest into a not
contest I turned it into random
giveaways like people would say to me
hey did I miss the giveaway and I'd say
no actually you won the giveaway today
send me your address and oh man that
iCloud Nachman so I did that the other
day too this kid named Eric and lo and
behold he's a good friend of Brian's and
he sends me an email and he says dude
you're such a great guy thanks for
hooking me up but was such such a neat
way to win something and you know if you
ever want to have Brian on from vital
garden supply and like of course I've
been talking about that with Tony I just
don't have the connection and he's like
well let me connect you right now and
that's how Brian came to be on the show
today so well that makes me even feel
better Eric's a good old friend he's
even more of an honor to write email
like I mean literally he was like it was
one sentence thank you for you know like
whatever I gave him a bottle of DC glass
cleaner or something and then like 10
paragraphs of how awesome Brian from
vital garden supply is and I'm like
those are the people we want on
pasturage for sure
nice well like I said it's an honor and
I'm stoked to be on and actually I see
etienne's on and I don't know if you
remember but way back in the day 18 nice
to hang out at my nightclub called Anaya
pinky dance-off yes I did because I used
to have the club next door called the
dry well it was the machine shop whoa
you have changed a lot you got a hat on
it's all right I don't
yeah-yo hippie so that goes back to
Morgantown West Virginia back in the
early 90s folks yeah yeah yeah they
brought culture there was a place called
the Underground Railroad which was
basically if you ever look on the old
Black Flag album who's got the ten and a
half at ten and a half inches is
Morgantown West Virginia because Marcia
who used to run the old Underground
Railroad
he used to hook all the artists up when
they would come through because she paid
them you know back in the early late 80s
early 90s nobody was paying for [ __ ] but
she paid and so a lot of people came and
unfortunately she disappeared to do
whatever actually happened a bad coke
deal we don't really know but she's
never been found but that's right yeah
he Underground Railroad set quiet quite
dormant for a while and then you guys
came in and picked up the reins and
really really restarted the fire there
and Morgantown so thanks for kicking in
the culture we appreciate it yeah the
tradition continues and yeah they end up
buying up the machine shop and made that
not part of the one two three so now
it's a rather large venue it was pretty
large as it was before when you guys had
it but yeah good to see you still there
good just you know worlds collide right
here we are now in California and you
know you're providing that the good
information because as we know good grow
information was hard to find especially
back in the day you know I told people I
used to have to go to when I first
started growing back in the late 80s
there in West Virginia I had to go to
Ohio to actually I grow equipment out of
fear because one yeah yeah I had to go
to Columbus and we even parked like two
or three blocks away out of fear you
know that's how heavy the the green
merchant fear was back then and then we
would yeah I remember my friend Nathan I
we had to you know I'd look around as we
would try not to leave we had to look
all paranoid walking out of there with
just a little 400 water that we ended up
putting in a closet and growing through
the closet but you know it was
yeah the heavy fear back then and you
couldn't ask anybody for information you
know the best you could come up with
those uh Tomatoes right you know and
even since then you know
depending on who you talk to you they
look at you funny about your tomato so
how bigger your Tomatoes and where are
they in season and you know just there
was brutal questions you know everybody
remember this right right do we ever you
know I didn't grow up in West Virginia
but Winnipeg Manitoba is definitely in
the Bible Belt
it was definitely harsh and if you can
imagine when I was 17 years old I went
to the local hydroponics store and I met
my mentor Ron Hickey and this guy he's
talking to a 17 year old first of all
imagine this and he takes me to his
basement he says look you you and I both
know we're not talking about tomatoes so
why don't we just talk about what we're
talking about we're talking about we
talking about ganja and he just was
basically like from that every single
day forward that I knew him he paid the
price with 11 years of his freedom and
he never stopped giving away all the
information in the way that it should be
given away he even put two thousand watt
light bulbs in the front window of his
hydroponics store that he opened after
he got out the first time showing
everyone how to grow weed and that the
cops actually made him turn those lights
off because they were so bright out on
the main front street it was causing
problems with traffic so shout out to
all the mentors all the all the giants
that we've been able to stand on the
shoulders of I mean for sure it's gonna
bonus and all those low key people in
those hydroponic stores that knew were
talking about that didn't say [ __ ] but
gave us information we needed
first-first
crap I ever grew up back there in
Morgantown West Virginia was 1988 and
just been learning and trying to gain
knowledge ever since and you know you
could keep it clean and organic raus
raus johnny was the first person that
turned me on to kind but in West
Virginia and I never forgot that I'll
never forget it because he was one of
those things where back then you gotta
understand I was really ignorant about
cannabis people so I was slinging Mac's
and I had a little bit of Mac's and we
were in the back of my club and I was
like you want to smoke a bowl and he's
like hell yeah
and I pull out a pipe he's like no no no
close that this little green thing and
I'm like what is that he's like oh this
is weed I'm like no not any weed I'm
gonna need more than that to get high
and you know just all embarrassing you
know and green as hell and man I hit
that weed and it changed my life forever
and then I was like Johnny he's like oh
about I can't get you anyway but you
know this shit's good you know you
should try throwing it it's a weed you
know mega thanks I wouldn't have weed
without what you guys are doing no
problem
so I was thinking of maybe asking Brian
to kind of introduce himself to the hash
church group here let it let him let
everyone know what vital garden supplies
is up to and what they're doing and sort
of the groups that you guys are working
for cuz I know who you are and I know
what you're up to but maybe some of the
audience doesn't yeah vital garden
supplies a purveyor of high-quality
organic farming garden products we cater
to the cannabis industry especially I
think we're going on our 11th or 12th
season now every year we try to gain
more and more high-end products under
our own label we searched high and far
throughout the world to get the best
that we can to bring it to people so
they could have clean successful gardens
without the nasty stuff that a lot of
people are pushing that those same hydro
stores that we started going to way back
in the day they yeah some of them have
evolved and learned how to teach people
about the organic side of things and
some have it so I've taken it upon
myself to make sure that our products
are as accessible as possible for people
for sure very cool very cool it seems to
be always the smaller group choosing the
more righteous higher integrity process
you know like to not grow with chemicals
it just seems like less people grow
organically than the not would you would
you kind of agree with that or do you
see a lot of people picking up organics
I do see a shift for sure like nice I'm
really excited about that and that is
one good thing about all
one of many good things about all this
legalization and things coming
aboveboard there is going to be some you
know testing and some you know regiments
that people are gonna have to get rid of
that they used to use get rid of things
such as powdery mildew and mice and
things like that where now that are
gonna have to use organic solutions so
that their product is sellable and
considered medicine and even actually
now that we're gonna have rec even like
smokeable material so like there's been
a lot of hiding behind closed doors all
these years so it's gonna be nice to see
everybody you know really have to like
show the proof and the paperwork behind
what they what they produce
where were you located right we're in
Nevada City California we also have
where are you I'm in Nevada City
oh no I've been into your store Bryan
and yes one of the one of the complaints
I have about a lot of gross stores when
I go into them they the sales people
seem most interested in selling products
as versus informing and helping the
person that's standing in front of them
and my experience in your store has been
that your employees actually try to
educate me on the various products that
you've got and what implications that
they'll have in the final products that
I make well that's really good yeah no
you you're you're sterling example of
how in my opinion a cultivation provider
should be in terms like I said you're
not really pushing product so much as
trying to help educate people and that's
a really thing I think is a huge need in
the cannabis industry thank you yeah we
definitely obviously our business is the
sell products but we also really do
appreciate those farmers or take things
upon themselves and make their own
compost and they're self-sufficient and
they're building their own you know
microorganisms in their flora and in
their soil yes on the other hand
we have products if they need aid in
that and you know though as our industry
is growing there's going to be many
different paths that people choose and
the way I see it is you know the people
who are trying to go a larger scale and
want to stay organic they're gonna have
to source products and I want to make
sure that where they are for them so
they could actually source things that
are safe and that are gonna actually
have success so they don't like it
scared that oh no this organic thing
isn't working we're gonna have to go
back to synthetic style and I think
that's one thing vitals been really good
about and my employees especially are
all super passionate about Guerlain
cannabis and they all love it so much
and they've taken on this thing that
we've like inside we call it a vital
pride and you know I didn't even realize
it until several years into it that like
some people really take it upon
themselves to really appreciate what it
is that we've done and then then take
that knowledge and take that like
specialization and put it into their
garden and put their little twist on it
and it makes it so that they're able to
have like that little success mm-hmm
well you're raising everybody up you
know that's the gift and when you're
passing out knowledge it's one of the
things or earlier on when Y was the
buyer there at DPG I realized that I
could just send somebody away with their
cannabis or I could actually you know
you can tell you can look at a plant now
after you've looked at you know tons of
it as a lot of us have you know you can
look at a bud and tell exactly what's
going on with the nutrient issues are
and so I would actually tell that to
them and then the mind would blow but I
always would say okay well here's the
problem and they'd be like oh my god
were you in my garden I'm like no the
bud is the truth teller no matter what
you tell me you're locked to me
the plant is telling me the truth so as
I look at the truth here you've got heat
issues it's picked too early you know
and etc go through the standards and I
would say you fail this time but next
time you know come back to me and let's
see if you've applied these things and
what you could have gotten this for you
can get this for if it's at this quality
I had to take a bud out
something that I haven't shown and say
this is of this quality and this is what
I expect and if you can deliver that
then I can give you this price and then
people would go home with that knowledge
and apply it as you know dry and you
know people really are searching on a
thirst for information because a lot of
the earlier grow books were so full of
miss well not misinformation they're so
technically confusing to a lot of people
that people just want it simple
information what does my pH need to be
you know what is my you know what's the
best nutrients I need to grow etc and so
it's been a wonderful shift with you
know prohibition collapsing from you
know to 15 to where you could start to
talk about it now with legalization you
don't have the fear anymore you know you
actually have suppliers aren't worried
that you're selling to cannabis people
anymore so the whole paradigm is shift
for you whereas back when you know back
in the day with green merch and
everything else you know you had to act
like an undercover agent just going into
us you know a hydroponics store just to
buy your stuff much less ask for
information or get real information or
information you could actually use so
thank you Brian for taking it and
raising the standards and you know
raising everybody up together because
that's why I still have suppliers at PPG
is because you know 1718 years ago we
decide you know we need to educate these
farmers so that they can make better
cannabis because we're reliant on our
patient cultivars we'll give you the
clone but it's what you do with that
clone and we know people can ruin a
clone and ruin every aspect of growing a
plant but by putting good genetics out
there we knew that good genetics would
come back if people would get to grow
grow information and now with that it's
spawned into good information so now
everybody is benefitting from it you
know the local regional you know people
are making more money which means they
can now spend more stuff at the
hydroponic store the grow stores so that
they can actually you know make bigger
and better crops for them themselves the
next time so that sustainability and
they learn from that each time and that
they only help everybody get better so
thank you for taking that philosophy
because back 20 years ago you know we
all were thirsting and craving for that
no doubt and that is something that we
take upon ourselves to like be the first
most important thing knowledge is power
for sure we always sponsor
in classes and special people like
Laningham to like educate our clientele
of how the right thing to go about you
know using beneficial microbes organic
fertilizer and not feeling this thing
that you gotta use a synthetic or like
scared to like get away from there
three-part nutrients so yeah education
is everything and once people get
comfortable with what they're doing
it makes them enjoy what they're doing
even better and feel a little bit more
you know confident in all aspects of
gardening and finding and growing
cannabis and taking it to the next level
that's it you know it's 20 20 years ago
plus it was vegetative growth let's see
how much we can grow let's see how fast
we can get it and slowly but surely
thing yeah that's changed by people
becoming more focused on the actual
medicinal components that are growing on
these plants these small little
glandular trichomes whether capitate
stalked or sessile stalked or bulbous
all three of them contain the profiles
that we seek and desire and as we learn
that we start growing a little bit
differently focused maybe more on the
actual medicinal components of the plant
at least as much as the vegetative
growth in the and the vegetative plant
matter that we're going to be yielding I
gave up on vegetative yields maybe 10 or
15 years ago now hey I'd like to welcome
injure to the room and I'd like to
welcome dr. Marsh aldohn to the room and
we've got Peter back from soil balance
Pro I thought he would make a wonderful
addition to the conversation along with
Wade and along with Brian I'm not sure
if you guys are all familiar with one
another but you're all kind of doing
really wonderful [ __ ]
in different ways you're all little
pieces of the puzzle that I just see as
making a wonderful panel here today so
welcome all of you to the room thank you
very much nice to meet you gentlemen
okay I'm gonna go back to you for a
second what are the most common problems
that people are coming in to you that
are vexed they're looking for solutions
that you're be that you're able to find
or that are new
Lucian's that you found to assist people
good question there 18 back to what you
were saying a little bit earlier to like
a year and a half ago give or take I
approached the Marone company they make
a couple of organic bio pesticide
insecticide pesticides in fungicides and
they're all certified organic and made
from by microbes and I had been using
them for quite some time but unable to
really obtain them for distribution and
they were definitely scared of the
cannabis industry and it took quite some
arm-twisting to get them to you've know
considerate and you know I really thank
them for finally coming around and some
of these products are definitely helping
buy great great proportions on powdery
mildew that's one of the most common
problems and then broad mites and
Russert mites I'd say are like right
behind the powdery mildew as much as an
issue and then for serían we're seeing a
lot also and all these products are all
these issues have organic solutions
which in the past a lot of people didn't
realize and anything from using a
Trichoderma which can kill all the
microbes that are in your root zone and
then you obviously have to reenact you
late the beneficials but it will kill
that fuss area and help your plant
bounce back so you don't completely lose
it the broad mite thing we've definitely
seen a lot of people have infestations
and with a couple products like the
grande evo and the venerate been able to
like knock it out and actually harvest
their crop Wow
that's kind of incredible when you think
about it because man every time I've
ever seen those little things come into
a garden it's like okay we need to set
off a nuclear bomb we're gonna be
rebuilding in a different zone yeah well
that's the reality right before you had
those solutions if you want to do
organically basically if you had those
type situations it was just cut and
start all over again so at least there's
at least as beneficial solutions now as
opposed to the having to restart all
over again all together I mean the best
the best solution was trying to have a
healthy flora in your soil
have a healthy beneficial microorganisms
population so your plants are able to
fight off anything that does come their
way but unfortunately it was so much
interaction and people trading plants
and people go into different Gardens
these pasts are like innovative and they
figure out ways to get from one Garden
to another and before you know it that
garden that you were sure of was clean
and past three could have been
contaminated by you know one of the one
of the biggest disease you're talking
about is powdery and downy mildew right
yes for sure okay so a lot of people
don't know this but it's actually the
scientific name for like downy mildew
this paranhos burrow and so what happens
Perez it actually comes in the form of
what's called an oo spore that yes okay
so so these oo spores they're like tiny
little bowling balls right like if you
think about where earthworms come from
right where do we reforms come with how
do they just kind of colonize the soil
okay when they're not there before
where do birth worms come from in a
healthy soil they come from from little
eggs and that's kind of how powdery and
downy mildew come they they're in this
little tiny ol spore which is like a
bowling ball very very small very
microscopic and these guys can travel in
from different soil mediums anaerobic
pockets within
well somebody needs to fight there Mike
[Music]
oh that's fine line and me back okay
that was injured injury you need to work
on your mic there buddy oh my gosh I
thought it was me I was like what is
going on continue on Peter continued on
so about like these low scores that are
in let's say an anaerobic pocket of
undecomposed compost right so you're
making your slope mixture and and these
little o scores are only going to you
make when obviously the temperature is
perfect and the moisture is perfect and
that's how you're going to get the
increase in colonization within the soil
aggregates that could actually gain
competency and then hit the root of the
plant and then boom and it's going to
spread to maybe one plant but as it as
that para nós pura colonizes the plant
itself it'll jump it will jump to other
plants so you know the universities will
come out until you hate molds and
mildews are just there in the air in
it's an environmental factor you know
you're going to get it whether whether
you want it or not but well what what a
lot of science sustainable agriculture
scientists are finding is that the these
oo scores are in oil in high amounts and
there's really nothing that because
again they're these little like bowling
balls they're one of the hardest things
even with like a fumigant like methyl
bromide or or or ahora systemic
fungicides these little low scores are
are super tough to destroy they're
almost impossible to destroy so like
Brian was saying the only way to to kind
of inhibit the colonization of powdery
and downy mildew which are two of the
most predominant diseases in your
industry as well as linked your sick and
I think verticillium Fusarium
rhizoctonia try this and Pythium all
those guys are pretty big problems too
but I don't know your product but
soluble humans concentrate if you can
humans which contains 100% aerobic
beneficial microorganisms you can get
that diversity and and colonize nation
up it's going to limit the impact or
colonization space on a microscopic
level that that that para nós burrow or
pottery and downy mildew can actually
have in your soil but but but an
important thing to know is that they are
coming from the so low those those those
microorganisms are developing in what
you're bringing in your soil medium so
you just have to be really careful on
what you guys can use say yeah I totally
agree and I think a lot of people are
like do to like the huge emergence of
our industry you know a lot of soil
companies are like not necessarily doing
their quality control on the compost
that they're using and they're using
lower and ingredients in their soil to
bring something to market that may be
more affordable than others but may not
necessarily be helping the farmer
because it's a bunch of composted
product or low end or has ingredients in
it that are more susceptible to these
spores like Peter said yeah yeah totally
Brian life even in vermiculite or peat
moss or something like that you know and
again especially in the green waste a
lot of these guys what they do is you
know they take the green peas from the
community environments and they let it
sit in these huge anaerobic piles and
just rot for about nine months and so
you know they feel like all the
pathogens have been killed because it
gets so high but that's not always the
case when you're looking at microscopic
pockets where these like these little
balls of RO spores are are sometimes
smaller than a microorganism they're
really small and they contain colonies
of powdery and mildew absolutely
absolutely and that's one of the reasons
why we like pride ourselves on using the
highest quality ingredients and
encouraging people to like not cut
corners just because they may have some
local soil and has some mushroom compost
from the local mushroom farm that hasn't
really been properly composted but is a
giant waste stream so basically a lot of
these waste streams just need to be
educated on how to manage them properly
and the world could have a lot more
higher end compost and that's one thing
that we have coming down the pipe we
have a project that we're going to work
on this canal where we'll be in charge
of all the ingredients and the inputs
and how the compost is actually made so
we're looking forward to that project
for sure I make compost for a lot of
years and I I made a loop key compost
and that's out of Germany and and what
it is is it's been insoluble huge
compost and it's composted we don't let
it get past 140 degrees that way we can
essentially just keep all the aerobic
microbes so we do and static yeah
totally you know that turned you know
that that process when you was compost
so we would turn it every day for the
first four weeks but but even with that
compost when you don't microbial essay
on it you know again it almost
impossible to eliminate 100% of the of
the pathogenic organisms in any type of
an organic material because it's the
natural balance there there are good and
bad organisms within any type of outdoor
ecosystem so so with that being said
what we've done with skill balance is we
isolated specie strains of your
beneficial microorganisms so that we
don't have any inkling of a pathogenic
in there so we're making micro team that
is 100% pure beneficial aerobic
saprophytic organisms that actually work
to help decompose some of the material
in a in a compost that hasn't been fully
decomposed yet because even if you're a
master composter you're never gonna get
100 percent of the bad guys out in in in
a compost it's it's it's naturally
impossible to get out all of the the bad
guys so you have to be careful any any
organic material you're bringing into
your grow room you know with those
pockets and like you said the thing that
you said Brian it makes
much sense is that if you inundate your
environment with tons of beneficial
organisms a lot of the health a lot of
the the things that people that growers
trying to grow organic who are reactive
to the health issues that they're facing
they just naturally won't have them any
kind of like a human healthy body once
your your your community is diversified
you're gonna have just plant health
vigor and you're gonna have
nutrient-dense product because those
those beneficials will act almost as as
let as like a chelating agent for the
macro micro nutrients in the soil
I love the go ahead go ahead wait I just
have to mute Peters because you were
getting a little bit of feedback and
welcome to Tony to the room as well hey
Tony
yeah I wanted to talk a little more
about what you were just speaking on
feeder right I I think it's really
important to recognize that they're
these pathogenic organisms are
everywhere and it's really very
difficult to create a scenario that is
free of pathogens but my experience has
been from when I worked indoors it was
important to make sure everything was as
clean as possible and as many beneficial
organisms as possible now that I'm
fortunate enough to be able to work
outdoors on a farm where in the last
coming on eight years now
I've been able to build the beneficial
organisms in the soil learn how to make
proper compost and source the materials
that are going into that compost and I'm
finding that different cultivars
different versions of cannabis have
better resistance than others to these
various pathogens particularly the
mildews I'm really finding that some of
the things that are high in CBD low in
THC which is primarily the focus of my
interest I'm really finding that there's
so many different versions of this plant
and some of them are actually quite
susceptible to mildews and others don't
seem to be bothered by it at all and
they have identical situation in my
garden so one of the things is the
nurseryman I'm trying to learn more
about is what cultivars flourish in
different scenarios and then to try and
make that information available to as
many people as possible
so we can reduce some of the
environmental impacts and increase the
quality of the medicine that people are
producing I really think this thing
you're talking about is really important
the way you're saying and from a
biological standpoint you have a
question that you just asked why are
certain cultivars more or less resistant
and and again addressing that from a
biological standpoint I think it has a
lot to do with the tree that each
individual plant is producing you know
think about a natural agro-ecosystem
period really right you're gonna have
different biodiversity and different
thresholds of for instance powdery or
downy mildew so that plant over time
just naturally has Co involved with its
natural system to be able to inhibit the
colonization of certain diseases so yes
naturally survive so when taking these
strengths and where mono cropping them
or reproduced in our own environment and
we don't have those exact strains
aligned with that particular plant then
what's gonna happen is the plants not
going to have its natural organisms that
it co-evolved with in nature
it'll just terpenes and it is necessary
to inhibit pathogen colonization yes yes
yes yes interesting that's good stuff
that is good stuff great panel today I
love I love the diversity some new folks
in the room some old schoolers we got
marks caldo looking slightly like a
Simpsons character with his with his
green hue but welcome dr. mark oh well
really a little bit a little bit oh I
could fix that I'm not you kind of
looked out the window and it almost went
away a little bit there especially right
no no no we love the green here bro you
yes green as you like my friends so
Brian are any guys working with the
state of California regarding the new
regulations and others start starting to
talk about organic certification or
working on that sort of ideas so that
you know people can actually take that
full shift in the future so that they
can actually get organic certification
for their cannabis in in the future in
California well indirectly yes I mean
we've taken the proactive approach of
getting all of our products certified
CDFA which is California Department of
Ag in for seeing that the future is
going to be that you know going to go
that route it's much easier for a farmer
to use product that's already certified
organic to get his own farm certified so
we did go that route for sure and we're
definitely working with a lot of farms
in the Monterey County and just some of
the more friendly counties that are
allowing permitting to using our
products and providing MSDS sheets and
providing you know derivation statements
so that they can get their approval for
organic certification so we had a
question from the chat room here a lot
of people asking about neem oil and it
seems like half the chat rooms kind of
like oh that's yeah I use that it's
great and the other half is like oh it's
poison you shouldn't use it so it many
people have asked the question what the
panel thinks about yeah maybe start with
Brian what do you think about me email
well neem is definitely the Mac t'v
ingredient neem is acid action and as a
bactrim is a pesticide so amine kills
things and you know it has its time in
place you know so a lot of people been
putting neem cake and soil and neem seed
meal and soil for quite some time and
I've always been like perplexed by this
whole concept and it's starting to come
out that the neem seed meal is actually
killing microorganisms in the soil and
causing or anaerobic conditions so
doesn't surprise me I'm not a scientist
but I have you know a lot of experience
being a farmer and I just I kind of like
think of a plant like a human and I like
try to think what does this plant need
similar to like how I would think how a
human would need nutrient and by giving
putting memes something that's going to
kill microorganisms in the soil has
always been counterintuitive for me so
something I've always stayed away from
and now that the information is more and
more is coming out it totally makes
sense to me you know we want to keep as
much microbial life in the soil as
possible much oxygen we want those
microorganisms to be able to breathe
down there great answer I am the best
use I've ever seen of neem the most
natural use I've ever seen of it was not
you know extracting the oil the plant
oil and spraying it it was in Jamaica
where my friend had a giant neem tree in
his garden I'd never even seen one it
was like 40 feet tall big huge leaves on
the thing and the leaves would fall and
then he would just put them in the
pathways he was growing in you know
classic Jamaica style inside tires so
well that all the earth was in the tire
so it was like even the neem that was
falling on the ground wasn't probably
really affecting the soil that the
plants were in although the rubber from
the tires probably were but I thought it
was a neat use of neem in the sense that
because I was like what are all these
leaves that you've got that we're
walking on over the pathways through the
plants and he's like that's neem on and
I looked up and I was like damn Jamaica
style you don't go buy a bottle of neem
you just use the entire plant it seems
more natural to me I'm on grow to tree
month grow to tree but I like your
answer with this you know affecting the
microbials that's clearly if you're not
thinking about the microbials in your
soil then maybe me might seem like a
great idea to you but coming to the
understanding that it's it's it's
potentially killing those or affecting
their colony then maybe it's not such a
good idea I have similar feelings about
me my particular objection to name is
that it's a hormone disruptor it
it's one of the methods that one of the
ways it works on insects is by
disrupting their breeding cycle and I
think we're putting way too many
materials like that into the environment
hormone disruptors you can look at all
the weirdness that amphibians are
showing in the environment from
everything from birth control pills to
soaps and whatnot who knows but with
cannabis particularly if you're
cultivating cannabis as medicine
it seems really essential to me that you
wouldn't add anything to the plant
either systemically or as a foliar spray
that eventually could compromise the
well-being of your end user and
particularly in the context of calabria
snake I've really had to focus on the
cleanest purest version of cannabis
medicine that is possible to create and
so neem is one of the things that I
asked the folks who cultivate for
caladrius Network - if they use it to
tell us all about when and how they used
it I don't want to take a chance on hurt
and one of these kids that's using grams
of oil a day and we end up concentrating
something like neem into their
bloodstream and who knows because again
I'm not a scientist I tend to take a
conservative position I don't want to
take any chance at all of hurting that
end user well I don't like name oh sorry
I was on mute
go ahead I know people like Tony
probably don't doesn't like affects the
oil flavor and components and overall
profile of it so as more and more
extractions been coming into play nîmes
losing its place in cannabis if you ask
me mm-hmm
I've some information on the plant
parasitic nematodes that I could share
if you guys wanna from so I work with
quite a few different scientists and
with regards to like alloy design or
which is root-knot or forests or skiing
there's lanced nematodes so there's
there's quite a few different um plant
parasitic nematodes and the plant
parasitics are our carbon feeders right
so so if you have a lot of plant
parasitic nematodes what they're gonna
do is they're gonna cruise in and
they're gonna go and they're gonna
you're fine root hairs the the root
hairs that actually absorb most of your
your your micro nutrients those
nematodes especially like lance and
sting are gonna eat those those fine
root hairs first before they attack a
meeting root because those are you hear
me okay oh man
very they're like aesthetic it's a
little bit of a delay but we can hear
you okay okay so so those those fine
root hairs are the ones that the
nematodes eat first they got these
little mouths they go and they just
gobble up cuz they're very like fibrous
fine right here so that's the first
thing that they eat so so that's the
plant parasitic now beneficial nematodes
and soil what those guys will do is they
actually feed on humans so think about
that so those beneficial nematodes won't
eat your roots it will actually feed on
humans or like mineralized carbon in the
soil so so there's a big difference on
the beneficial and the plant parasitic
kind of like the bad guys of the bugs
the good guys of the bugs and flow so so
if you have a very healthy human rich
soil you're going to counterbalance the
nematode essentially you know
multi-celled organisms that are in that
soil if you can really increase your
earthworm castings your your
communication of that soil the plant
parasitics will still be there and
there's there's other things that you
can do to inhibit you know those but
that's a whole nother conversation i'm
just talking about the types really i
just wanted to let brian know that i
muted his mic so when he goes to talk to
unmuted it was the thing
that was causing the tiniest little bit
of feedback on Peters microphone so I
know you're on a phone and it might be a
little bit harder but just try to click
your mute button to unmute yourself when
you talk and yeah there we go
I'm just figured I'd let him know oh we
might have lost him now I don't know so
how did oh there he is he's back but I
don't know if he can unmute his mic now
sometimes when I mute people's mics it
messes things up but let me see if I can
unmute you Brian all right let's try it
out no it's still muted weird lets me
mute him but not unmute him always been
controlled air you're unmuted now all
right sorry if I'm causing any issues no
no you're fine just I guess when you
don't speak it's best if you can mute
your mic on your phone there if I can
figure out how to do it I think I see it
yeah no problem
I know it's trippy right yeah I'm
technologically challenged I'm a plant
guy not a computer guy hey I'm glad you
made it in today anyway to share to
share with us and I'm glad that say it's
because I wanted to hook you up with
Peter any yeah and then and then Wade
was like oh I got to bring wade into
because he's just like he's exactly what
all of you guys are talking about put
into three dimensional reality for the
last I don't know how many years of his
life so just he sounds like he's the
neighbor - yeah wait I'd like to get
look forward to it man I'll come in and
ask for you please do yeah next time I'm
up there an incline I have a dispensary
an incline I'm I have to swing over in
Nevada City and come say hi yeah
absolutely we must sesh I was also gonna
say earlier when Brian was talking about
or sorry it was Wade who was just
talking about not wanting this this
responsibility of dealing with
catastrophic lis ill children who are
extremely hypersensitive to anything
let's just be honest our confidence our
faith what we believe in is cannabis we
believe in cannabis we believe in the
profile we believe in the terpenes we
believe in the cannabinoids what we
maybe don't believe in is you know a
whole [ __ ] ton of
like sprays and you know I'm with Wade
on that where it's just sort of like
when in doubt throw it out stick with
the stick with the most popular best
sort of way of going about it which is
maybe by breeding plants that are you
know going to be maybe a little bit more
pushing away these these certain pests
and mildews and whatnot I've definitely
seen it in a room I've gone into a room
and I've seen all the cush is just
covered in powdery mildew and then
there's one in the background I was like
what's that over there it's like oh
that's like a Congolese you know one of
these kind of exotic cultivars and I'm
like yeah but it doesn't have any
powdery mildew why do you have one
Congolese in your room and a 400 cush
when you grow in the Pacific Northwest
I'm just curious
no I think it's a huge thing there is a
wide range of different cultivars
available and what I think we're missing
is sharing information with each other
about cultivars that flourish in the
different environments we're in just in
the folks that I've worked with in the
last few years
folk on the Central Coast or even the
north coast have a really different set
of problems if you will and a different
group of cultivars seem to flourish
between those two areas and an area like
Nevada County where I'm at we have
incredibly hot very low humidity summers
and meanwhile along the coast you've got
high humidity from the marine layer and
rarely do you get high temperatures in
the day because the fog gets drawn in so
my sense is that what I've tried to do
is learn more about like you were
mentioning the congolese it seems to me
that that's a radically different set of
conditions that that plant evolved in
than what some of the other cultivars
from the the cush area of India might
have evolved in and I think the trick
for us is sorting out what are the
genetics of the plants were working with
and what are the environmental kin
those plants are seeking so that they
can flourish the one thing I've noticed
is seems like people aren't necessarily
growing what is the most proper plant to
grow for their region yes people people
are growing for all sorts of purposes
somewhat financially driven somewhat
terpene driven so that's the one thing
that like cannabis is like has such a
like broad spectrum of types of types of
cultivars and you know where where
plants may be more appropriate may not
be as desirable to some people as others
and so on and so forth so mm-hmm
that makes things really complicated as
far as like a cannabis grower choosing a
cultivar it would be nice to be able to
just grow the things like our best in
your region but we all like a little
variety in life and people you know have
options so that's one thing that like
greenhouses and indoor and treatment is
making making uh taking advantage of
your environment environmental controls
and things like that
are you go do but in general it I think
providing the most natural at
environment for your plant from the soil
to the air to everything else has to
always be taken into consideration so if
you are growing something that is out of
your region that has to provide a
greenhouse for some sort of different
environment and it's normally used to
just take into consideration that give
it what it wants and it'll give you what
what you want to get from it yes I would
share a little story if you want to hear
it I've worked with a CDC which is a
cultivar that produces c/bb
about 25 or 30 times the amount of CBD
and in the plant material as there is
THC and particularly for some of the
kids that I work with that's really a
desirable characteristic
but I believe ac/dc was first identified
as a plant of interest along the north
coast of California
and over there it seems to flourish and
I've met people who work with it indoors
and the beauty of indoors of course is
you can create the climate you want and
ac/dc the first two years I worked with
it outdoors in my garden here in Nevada
County it grew like a fawn it could
barely hold its own weight up and and
then I met folk who were working with it
indoors and said no it was a very much
of a typical heavy bearing strong plant
and when I discussed how that could be
when I was growing it outdoors and
seeing something that acted like a fern
we got to talking about temperature and
humidity and so last year I had four
little plants of ac/dc that I put in the
ground
under a shade structure where the shade
structure would allow 60 percent
transmittance of light and the fabric
was white and meantime I used wood chips
in abundance with various types of grass
types for mulch and I keep the mulch
moist for evaporative cooling and the
ac/dc last summer instead of growing
like a fern very much grew like a more
conventional plant and from those four
little plants that I didn't put out
until June 20th I got almost just a hair
over 6,000 grams from four little plants
put out June 20th and from those plants
the medicine mate besides working within
they got eleven hundred grams of oil
which is extraordinarily twenty-two
percent yield so on their extraction Wow
clearly did really well and that house
is way more plant material than it ever
produced in my garden in the two
previous years I've worked with it and I
had more plants but then but they
struggled to repeat how didn't do the
operation the hexane it's a hexane
extraction with a saw
phlex machine not socks yes and brought
it back to draw the hexane off and
terpene separation at the final stages
of extraction of the solvent and was
this a high CBD cultivar yes okay so
here's a question for you now this is my
own theory and it may hold no water
whatsoever but what I notice is when I
do extractions with mechanical screen
separation whether dry or wet bubble
hash or dry sifting but I'm able to get
the sessile and the capitate stock to
trichomes but the bulbous stay behind
you get a very very small yield when you
when I work with high CBD cultivars and
I my theory is is that the majority of
the profile is inside those bulbous
heads and they need to be melted off or
heated off steam distilled solvent
extraction whatever in order for you to
actually get that yield have you seen
1/2 of a yield coming out of this
material when you run it through sifting
or wet washing back in the day when I
was first working with Harlequin I
enjoyed smoking hash in those days as
well and yeah Harlequin is not a great
producer in the hash realm is my
experience and I think it's part of why
my medicine makers were working with
hexane is they got such good results for
extractions I'd be interested in hearing
what Tony had to say about this because
I've heard something similar to what you
were just asking about Brian or but I
don't really know Margaret yeah yeah I
know John John BIRT fellow who's not
here today I'm just gonna let Tony's
eaten right now so I'll answer and then
he got yours he can chime in right after
me just that John Breaux fellow has also
seen the same thing with the Halley's
Comet
Cheryl T Rose whose daughter Hayley has
a form of epilepsy that they came up
with this high CBD cultivar called
Halley's Comet and it was the same way
like when we ran it through screens when
we ran it through water hash that yields
were just so low that it you know and
it's it's really hard when you're trying
to produce an actual medicine for
someone now the interesting thing was is
that
the much higher yields were gotten
through oil extractions but hey and I
wish Cheryl was here to share this
because it's really her information more
than anyone's but she Haley had been on
this oil for some for some time and her
seizures went down 80 80 percent some
massive number she was still having
seizures but it wasn't until she started
making bubble hash with this particular
cultivar that she went like she stopped
all her seizures now I'm sure that they
have come back because I think that they
maybe lost the cultivar or something had
it happens but she went for hundreds of
days maybe over 200 I'd have to once
again get Cheryl T rose and any of you
want to Google Sheryl rose as well as
Haley you can find out all about them
and go support them because they're
really good people but just some
interesting thing that I found wouldn't
it be interesting if Stevie Dee was
being produced in higher amounts in
bulbous trichomes and if so why did they
winterized the hexane extract I it was
all done
yeah with temperature and vacuum I'm not
sure exactly what you mean by winter ice
but no the plant material would get
dried to one or two percent of moisture
content and it'll dissolve why facts and
lipids right you're gonna dissolve those
components they have to be removed and
winterization is the process by which
they're removed I was just wondering if
they winterize their hexane extract
because you're gonna get oil from that
like you said they're getting CBD oil
well purified CBD we all know is a quite
crystalline solids so what are the other
components that are in there and what's
the CBD concentration in the oil that
they extracted we've seen as much as I
don't remember the specific variety but
we had a seventy some percent CBD and
two percent THC oil in abundance right
so there's about 25 26 28 percent other
stuff in there right yes
other extracted fats and waxes is my
take on it yeah it's a heavy oil
tari not clear at all but again because
I don't know I'm really trying for a
whole plant extract I want all of it
I ask the guys to mix the terpenes back
into the oil when they give it to us
they did be in the in the sock slips
extraction oh no most of the oil is
still in the acid form the class just
think that that's really kind of cool
because you would think in the so I saw
I'll explain what it is Sox list so Sox
lid is kind of like a little cup that
sits in the reflux zone of a solvent
that's being boiled and so in this case
it's xane so what happens is the hexane
vapor sort of reconned ences on the on
the whole ankles cocoa finger or
whatever it is that's the cold surface
in there some people like I've gone
typically called a reflux condenser and
so from the condenser then the the fresh
solvent drops over the plant material
and then goes back into the pot and it
just does that it's kind of making
coffee right yes you know coffee
percolator not a single you know past
curing or something this is like the
coffee circulator that you put coffees
to water into boil it like the Cowboys
did you know on the you know stove or
something so and yeah so the sock slit
is basically interesting because again
you're passing through hexane after it's
condensed so it's no longer hot but it's
typically in a hot zone of a condenser
in that you're it's kind of below where
the where the reflux condenser is which
again is stuff that's being condensed
back at you know room temperature so
it's basically just running through
there but you're going to concentrate in
the hexane pot down below which then
they strip on the road of that and again
you can probably strip hexane without
doing much D carb I'm just surprised
that in that whole sock slow extraction
process they can't they can't just them
any carbon another interesting thing is
a good recrystallization solvent for the
cannabinoid acids are things like hexane
and pentane they're very very nonpolar
and if you could stature eight that
solution on your road evaporator might
be able to kill it down cryogenically
and actually crash out cbda crystals so
it would be cool if you could actually
concentrate and make a CBD a isolate
that's that concentrated you can just
crash out the crystals CVD a is somewhat
of an elusive thing again just because
of decarboxylation so if you take like
an ethanol extract or if you do anything
where you have to do multiple
stripping's on route of apps you figure
that you're going to end up heating it
up to some point that you may get some
haven't issues decarboxylation but being
able to get CBD a as a crystalline solid
would be really [ __ ] cool because
then you could just you know
decarboxylate that to be activated CVD
without having all the other fats waxes
and lipids and those are the often the
culprits for giving those purified
cannabinoids off flavors because when
the fats waxes and lipids are heated up
they thermally degrade and to noxious
smelling compounds well thanks for that
knowledge drop-in welcome skunkman Sam
and Alec from SC labs to the room I
think we got a full panel gentlemen
almost 700 people on the live viewing
and the check is bumping testing good
morning you are tested I passed this
time I found out what was wrong with the
microphone it was plugged in two
different places and I'd like to ask a
question I I'm sorry the kind I've
forgotten your name
Peter Peter you know I sent off for some
of your stuff and then I was talking to
my friend who still lives in
Phillipsburg campus
and he volunteered to go over to where
the largest 7080 church plants growing
that I've ever seen in a long time
besides in Rishikesh India but he
volunteered to go over and dig around
amongst the roots and then me a sample
of the stuff he came back with and I
thought maybe you might be interested in
having that sample to have a look at
because it's just marijuana plants
growing there yeah we can do is we can
actually test the colonies that are
actually conducive to a cannabis plant
growth in the rhizosphere so we do
microbial analysis basically and we look
at all the different beneficials
that we know are going to be conducive
to all of the things that we're talking
about and we can actually isolate and
tell you how many what are called colony
forming units or microorganisms per gram
of soil that you contain not only in the
soil aggregates but in the in the
rhizosphere so if you wanted to send us
a sample I could pretty much analyze you
know the beneficials that are there and
and then you can start to do that's
something that our company hopefully
will be in to do in future is is help
people become microbe farmers you know
and and actually have a precedence on
the amount of colony forming units or
microorganisms per gram of soil that are
conducive to the results that you guys
are all talking about which which in a
relay to every aspect of what those
plants genetic capability I really love
the panel right now I gotta say just
looking at you know master breeder
skunkman Sam and the work that Wade's
done with the ACDC and the Harlequin you
got Brian in from vital like trying to
share the good soil information
Alex from Alec from SC labs coming in
who's testing everything Peter with the
soil balance the living bacterias to
symbiotically live on the roots and up
you know and then you've got our
scientist Marx shalt shall dawn in the
house laying it down Roger what yeah and
congratulations on your new patent bro
like seriously congratulations and then
listen it doesn't even end there because
then we have Indra old school you know
storyteller extraordinaire with like the
oil history that goes back 30 plus years
and then the future we got Tony vers
aura who's pumping out products like you
can't even believe xylitol sugars and
turps syrups and blow in my mind even
dude I'm the bubble man and you all
humble me thank you all for sharing your
time today and I know the panel or the
chat room right now is absolutely loving
this so thank you everybody for putting
this to all the beautiful synergy man
that you've created so you are an
eclectic human being who's brought some
I'm using in there those years thank you
so I guess what's to talk about maybe a
little bit about chalice I think what
did they give you a backpack for all
those trophies Tony yeah you know it was
a pretty was a pretty interesting
there's a pretty interesting event still
going on today but I felt kind of geeky
I think so did Joe but when Alex was
kind of telling people on did he
disappear from this panel come here oh
it's just such a big pale I see you have
to move yeah so you know I think that
what you guys are talking about it's
really important they have all coming
down to responsibility and also
education you know if you're gonna be in
the industry you have to take some
responsibility and if we had a
commission like there's NFL commission
or there's different industries and
organizations out there that have to
abide by come
missions and those Commission's haven't
been set up yet
for for cannabis yet we're still still
working on trying to regulate this and
monitor every gram and make sure people
are you know in these regulated states
they're not using pesticides and
concentrating them and putting them into
edibles and into public which is harm's
way but there's no real repercussions of
responsibility and so when you look at
when you look at that and you say okay
what does that really mean
well there's things that I would like to
say that are what we need to create the
ten commandments if you will the things
that are not acceptable if you're gonna
be in the industry then if you're gonna
be in the industry you need to be held
accountable you know there's things
there's things that are out there that
existed even blow my mind so a lot of
people with the prohibition base
mentality think that Pacific in the
distillate hold that somehow you can
make some kind of shitty contaminated
BHO and clean it up into some magical
golden oil that that is that will test
clean of all contaminants pesticides
residuals and things and maybe once upon
a time that was like a thing to do like
take somebody's really nasty dirty oil
and do that but I think that the
competition that that was held a chalice
and the standards that the labs are
trying to be preaching to everyone out
there isn't necessarily just about
pesticides but it's a responsibility as
the grower and the extractor come
together to produce a product that is
acceptable for public consumption since
there's no Commission and no one's
really regulating that right now
especially in California where that's
the biggest you know one of the biggest
markets in the country if not the world
and so in the in
the categories that we had you know with
distillation is we're now we're not
taking some kind of contaminated shitty
pho and turning it into magic you know
we're doing the whole clan extractions
on flowers that were grown by
unbelievable growers with you know
greenhouse growers like lemon tree all
organic and what Brian was talking about
with certified green growers these are
growers that go to particular
certification processes in which they
don't spray their plants they have
healthy genetics then they have a
healthy way of sustaining those genetics
and what I mean by that responsibility
is you know you've got to be able to
have the right starting material so
we're we're starting with the best
material making the best particularly
well that we can make and then a
distillation there's just a final
refinement of cleaning it up to the most
highest concentration so if you have any
any hiccups along the way you're just
going to concentrate your mistakes so
really when somebody says distillation
think microscope very very very very
very very strong microscope into what
you're doing and so it's not it's not a
process in which you should do to fix a
mistake but rather refine your process
to the highest quality and standards
that could be if that's the desired
product and now I'm gonna put some
people on glass so I told some people
are long I'm gonna go a little further I
hate to do this to people
I'm not gonna call any names out but
I'll show you some of the things that
are not acceptable in our industry and
if there was a commission I would find
this person $500,000 in 10 years about
10 years to be alse from the industry
without without review so if we had a
commission with cannabis and you saw
what I'm about to show you this person
this these types of people should be
fined
minimum half a million two million
dollars for the damage in which they're
causing and they don't know and we're
gonna talk about why they got here so
let's look let's look at this phone and
you will be seeing something oh Jesus
that's crazy dude
watch it what you're looking at people
is so spider mites covered buds come on
that's what it's like worst case
scenario Oh as bad as it gets if you see
a buddy completely covered like that
burn it with fire it's not extractable
that made me feel sick exactly made my
heart beat really fast when you get to
this stage except pull out a [ __ ]
blowtorch and torture entire garden
that's a negligence at that point maybe
the property that's beyond negligence
that's just outright denial I thought it
was those are crystals I mean not to
smoke ash with mark there was you know I
think there was like 80 or 90% this year
knowing that put you on blast actually I
feel like there was some change that
happened because there's about 50% even
though even though they knew they were
going into competition mode and they all
of their stuff so you know you're going
in the comic and you know they're gonna
put you they're gonna put you and in
some categories 20% so I was happy to
see the numbers change substantially
down because people would be coming more
and more where and when they talk about
pesticides something aside
there's there's the word is death
there's there's catastrophic human
change that can happen when you are
consuming pesticides or combinations of
pesticides which we're going to talk
about it and concentrate some of them
and tape them directly to your brain but
yeah we talked about if you take lung
from say a mothering room and they use
equal 20 and its stomach and it's in the
plant and they clone it and then they're
like okay we've got tons of these clones
and that grower never uses pesticides
tough titty you just you're growing with
contaminated genetics and so the
genetics is extremely important if we
all started from seed if we all started
from seed we have a very fair shot of
having something and that's clean but if
you start from a clone you need to have
a clean room so when you walk when I
walked into other people's grows and
trust me there's examples of the
opposite of what I showed you like when
we talk about you know we're working
with green dragon food is the complete
opposite of a girl like that who's
monitoring all of these things so if you
have if you see a grow and somebody's
like oh yeah where do you get your
clothes from where do you get your
mothers from and in there is no mother
row okay and your cloning from your
garden so if your cloning from your
garden you better be the best [ __ ]
grower and have all of these points in
place and all these checks in place
because imagine you're this is how this
garden got this way okay at one point
they had to grow their first polar their
second pole was pretty decent and all of
a sudden some of the girls got a little
caught the weather changed right they
get a little bit of a condition you get
a little scratchy throat oh let's uh
let's use a little uh let's use this
remedy here and it might be a pesticide
or it might be some kind of chemical
that will try to help this car so
instead of this instead of you know
there being a cough once a week there's
a little scratch a little cough then
they clone it so now you cloned your
first condition and you've passed it
along the chain then let's say if there
was humans let's say that that
particular batch now has cancer okay and
then you clone it now you've got the
coughing got cancer then the next time
well let's just throw aids at it let's
throw a mess at it let's just start
throwing every possible health condition
you could possibly throw into this into
this gene mix and keep mixing and keep
cloning and click cloning so eventually
where you get is you've got cocktails of
pesticides and different chemicals that
you're fighting well I've got thrifts
I've got spider mites I've got green
moss that produces more heart and having
topside spiders full-on webs around your
buds it's not acceptable vacuuming them
up washing them in hydrogen peroxide
vacuuming them off I would drop a
nuclear bomb on that facility I would
first go and apologize to all my
neighbors and let them punch me in the
face as many times as they wanted to
because I'm seriously sick to my stomach
for their neighbors I'm not even joking
that is I can honestly say Tony but I've
seen much worse we're visiting visiting
somewhere in your own garden a people's
greenhouse especially novice growers who
just have no experience yeah I had to
say I saw the similar situation in Los
Angeles back in the late 90s and the
entire the entire garden which was
probably 8 by 8 and everybody looked
just like that and the guy was like
what's wrong thing yeah fire fire I was
like well you know you could produce a
special product that we
to produce coke mighty weed yeah well if
you were yeah exactly if you were
growing for the bugs what I said I said
I don't know if you're just in the
business for baiting spider mites
mutated spider mites for our generations
to come because you've done an excellent
job with cocktail bombs of every type of
pesticide you could possibly throw at
this thing and you've got a topside
party I mean these are these this is
like two pots come back and nothing but
again okay if you use pesticides your
plants would have looked a lot better it
just would be terrible for you listen
since you started talking Tony the look
on Brian and Wade and Peter's face has
just been because we started this
conversation with the highest integrity
children's alike this is why we're doing
this it is kind of crazy to see just
metaphorically how ridiculous Li's some
of these contests are man like what are
people thinking we as a group need to
take people like that and do the game of
thrones strip em naked walk platinum
with bills shame shame that's what you'd
be doing at shallots you should be
walking we'd have those bastards walk
around naked yelling [ __ ] it's one thing
for a contest it's one thing for a
recreational market the fact that it
could be leeching over into this
medicinal component and to this like for
people who are really sick like it
becomes it becomes really not funny and
on a side note and I'm gonna get right
back to you Tony I have to shout out a
chant because I forgot at Ken how could
you forget Etienne he's been first in
the room every day for the last hundred
and forty six episodes the guy's been an
activist longer than I've been into
cannabis he's definitely one of the
pioneers and he's one of the kindest
Souls I've ever met so I do want to
shout
as well as I already did the rest of the
panel my good friend Betty thanks for
being you
thank you kindly and I want to give a
shout out to my biological father he
passed away
day before yesterday so thank you very
much for the love and support everybody
have shown and I'm doing my best
everything's good and I appreciate the
love they're both mine mm-hmm
much love and you know and just just
just to kind of throw in you know just
from what onion you know everybody was
just kind of discussing with regards you
know kind of some nasty you know
practices oftentimes unknowingly nice
and practices completely ignorant
you know practices that are being made
you know especially around using a lot
of these systemic pesticides you know
one of the something that just
complicates the whole topic that much
more also is you know the difference of
whether or not plants were grown under
the Sun exposed UV a B and C versus any
type of indoor lighting which is
completely void any type of UV a V or C
which is one of the biggest thing that
is what's breaking down systemic
residual pesticides you know and so for
so long you know working with in the
hydroponic industry you Hydra stores you
know so much information was passed out
to the community and you know on forums
everybody thought you know oh the you
know eagle 20 lasts 60 days or 40 days
residually on the plant and you know
it's just this kind of like ignorantly
agreed-upon kind of thought you know to
justify you know somewhat unscrupulous
actions you know people just getting
away with spraying whenever they spray
because they didn't preventively take
care of their issues instead they're
reacting to full web mode you know so
and so you know with that being said
it's like once moms are treated or
what-have-you and then grown and you
know indoor lighting mom runs you know
I'm you know I will I'm very curious I'm
how much longer the you know kind of
systemic residue is compared to you know
something that might be thrown under the
Sun you know which in its own is gonna
have a really long residue residue
effect but mom in the whole situation to
you bring up a good point because the
ego 20 belongs to the class of easels
and all easels
acquire biological degradation to
basically degrade those in the
environment and again in an indoor
environment where you have a different
microbiome than you outside and like you
bring up a good point with photolytic
degradation but the microbes the
Pseudomonas that live in the soil are
basically the things that are
responsible for most of the degradation
of those things and most hazal
fungicides like Mike on azole and stuff
like that are very low mammalian
toxicity you know they don't really have
much I mean they're used for athlete's
foot and you know you know those types
of you know topical applications for you
you know yeast infections and stuff like
that because they're very broad spectrum
and they're typically low toxicity what
is the issue is wonder when they're heat
it will concentrate it and when they're
heated up because most of those are
chock-full of nitrogen's and a lot of
those nitrogen containing compounds
degrade to all kinds of nitro so and
oxides and all kinds of Hofmann
degradation products that you don't want
to be inhaling into your into your lungs
isn't formaldehyde one of those mountain
is used in jarred ation product that's
just almost ubiquitous in the
environment right now because it's used
in so many different applications as a
monomer in plastics the monomer of big
plot of big lighters which is basically
formalin just poly formaldehyde is
formaldehyde itself and so yeah when
those things thermally degrade they
released formaldehyde what they're
finding now is paraffin based candles
like I don't want to call them thrown
under the bus but like Yankee Candle
brand and most popular brand candles
that are paraffin based have a lot of
residual formaldehyde and formaldehyde
components and degradation crap that's
left behind and they don't know if
that's you know responsible for you know
cancer or anything but it's just
exposing people more to formaldehyde and
yeah formaldehyde is typically a thing
you don't want to be exposed to if you
can help
you know what to get back the easels for
a second the thing with you who you call
it a nasal hey there Connie Connie those
are man there's like Teddy Coty's all
propiconazole flu Silas all there's so
many ones it's just amazing somehow that
the one that one thermally heats you
know can degrade and give off cyanide
it's the one in Eagle 20 right it's just
amazing that that's the one that's so
widely used there's so many other ones
that you don't have the cyanide issue
with it all and that's the only one
really that I could think of that it's
cut that you know you heat this up and
basically it degrades the hydrogen
cyanide well it's at a much lower
concentration typically but again when
you concentrate these things into
concentrates God knows if you have
something that's in high concentration
could you actually get enough cyanide to
basically get the dab that will
essentially kill you because you're
overwhelmed by cyanide I don't think
that that's actually possible unless
it's there in like super super high
levels because if it's based on the
actual toxic dose of hydrogen cyanide
you would need that a lotta evil 20 in
your dab to basically kill over from it
well importantly let me for scute my
white rose those those that the
synthetics over time with the different
extractions let's let's stick the bubble
hash for one moment and pesticide what
we do now is we work for different farms
particularly for whether it's prana or
bubbleman no but let's let's stick to
prana because that's the one that I
usually taking in take on CV material
and I've bought material from from Wade
before and from from Brian so on the
opposite note hats off to the people
that actually know how to grow and
understand that from the second Billy is
out of the plan there's there's resin
there and what you put into the plan is
what you're going to get out of it every
time and
so my hats are off to the people that
are actually doing a good job because
those are the ones that I seek out but
we have a account with se in a bulk
testing and now what we do is as soon as
we get flowers we we say okay well is
there pesticide tests done at the lab if
the answer is no then we send the
flowers off we take 10 grams of the
flowers we press those flowers off we
take that flower oil and we send that
off we clean the plates and clean
everything and sterilized nuv between
each one of those runs and flowers and
we have one particular we have three
presses so we have one particular press
we can dedicate to that so we get a
constant trick we get a the plant might
test under the the pesticide level but
then if you make a flower oil and this
is why I would say a lot of people are
kind of against flower rosin because you
have to have extremely clean flowers
because then you're just you're
concentrating all of these oils and
anything that's on the plant right there
without any kind of first second pass or
any kind of refinement like what Indra
does you know with a hydrocarbon or
anyone else that would use a solvent
they've got different passes and
refinements that they can get a lot of
things out so we a lot of crazy failures
so to the point where I actually called
my manager to tell IC Labs hey by the
way we're not making this we're just
testing batches for different people
that want us to buy and it's failing
pretty poorly but in the water hash
though with flowers you might not see it
until it's concentrated and then it's
too late and then you're down the road
with all of your medicine and your lab
contaminated so there's a step there but
with with particular water hash what I
see I've seen this twice now not saying
anyone's names or anything like that but
these are different farmers that are
growing outdoors in greenhouse and the
trim itself maybe they said oh well we
don't use any pesticides we're clean
okay that might be fair but some of my
friends that said hey do you want to buy
you know this full-spectrum bubble hash
and the bubble hash was testing in the
parts / carts for million like 2 to 4 so
washing the residue separating the resin
might have might have got why what was
the dominant Tony oh it was micro micro
butanol or whatever my club you know
company yeah I was like bro we'd sent
something to you it was like 4 part it
was like a 4 not point for not pointing
on the one point or it was 4 and that
was any rosin concentration they thought
that maybe the hash didn't have it so
they tested the bubble and then they
tested the hash rosin when both both of
them tested highly positive so what I'm
getting at is that for whatever reason
even if you're washing and separating
the resin there might you might be able
to not see any PM because we talked
about this before we're actually around
the resin heads you might not actually
see any p.m. but the pesticides are
getting in that are attaching themselves
are getting into that resin in some
capacity and ester flour the resin not
the plant material but you didn't test
the plant material I didn't have the
plant material to test they were trying
to sell Oh bad news really they're gonna
give us bubble and then they were trying
to give us hash rosin and both of them
would test positive but what I'm getting
at is the resin so somebody washed it
separated dried it went through that
process it's still in the resin is what
I'm getting at
so it's not just in its inherently in
just that in the actual resident so so
what I'm hearing is going on a lot is
people are even like testing their flour
and it's coming in clean and then when
it concentrates then they're seeing
signs of some of these other toxic
pesticides that was in reason why I was
asking
that's what we're seeing here is you're
not seeing in the flour you think the
flowers process the flour into a hash or
a rosin in this case and now the rosin
is probably out hot is that was that
what I'm hearing the Trinity
that's one of the things that's like
really scary to me because here are all
these people stores in plants from all
over the place and that who knows how
many generations down the line there
could have been this you know toxic
chemical use where it's still going to
show up so that's something that well
vital and working with yeah yeah I was
just to say here's worth sample
preparation and sample collection you're
processing a whole lot of material but
you're only taking a bud from this
branch over here well again you need to
be able to represent the entirety of the
material if you're going to be doing a
statistically significant measurement
well I think we got to take a more
proactive approach on the other end of
things and provide clean plants so
farmers can be assured that they're
gonna make medicine that is acceptable
in our modern test ride facilities it's
not like if you're buying wholesale or
you know you have a deal and it's like
okay someone's bringing you some herb it
looks really good but you know you don't
know whether or not it's contaminated
you need to do really statistically
valid measurement of the entire batch to
make sure that you don't have sun
contamination surprises like those
absolutely well the way we go ahead yeah
real quick that's actually what we're
using the flour rosin for so somebody
has ten pounds you could you could take
20 grams randomly from those ten pounds
stuff a couple screens press out twenty
twenty grams
get a black all those batches that's why
I like flour oz and then you get the
flour oz just for testing purposes yeah
that's a good way to test okay now I've
got I've got two or three grams and sent
to the lab and do that it's a super good
way to to check that before you get to
down but I also think this opens up a
new a new era of clone certification
meaning when the plants in its mother
stage take a take a cut of the lead
go get the leaf tested and get us and
see if we can get maybe this doesn't
exist yet but I thought we maybe it
could get there an ST could probably
answer this but if there was a way to
test the leaf not the bud while it's in
bed yeah yeah no that's something that's
when it's gonna be in the highest
concentration ever I've seen by the
plant you know in the time when it was
dipped so I mean just from me I mean if
we had a mother so we say okay where are
these clones this mother was certified
then we made these clones these clones
are now have to go to a certification
process and then the genetic banks is
where it starts so if you're gonna be a
clone bank then you're gonna be a
genetic thing you need to have these
certification processes because farmers
like what Brian is saying is like say
let's say the farmer does everything
right he's got live soils he's doing the
greenhouses he's got in controlled he
[ __ ] slaves over months he's bought
all these these clones he's like I'm an
all organic grower he doesn't test
positive and his flowers somebody says
okay great we're getting this you know
our collectors gonna purchase these
flowers and make it into all this great
amazing medicine we do a quick rosin
test or a first batch of bubble and it's
warm long and then you know it and now
they failed but they didn't do anything
particularly wrong this is happening all
over so now we're actually destroying
and pushing out good farmers that are
trying to try to be in the industry
because we don't have this is this very
significant first step checks and
balance on the genetics right you know
and Tony and you know on that you know I
think I think there's a there's a couple
couple things I wanted to kind of bring
up on that point um as you know with if
you're farming you're going to Irv you
know it's I mean it's pretty cut and dry
you know you either sprayed a systemic
or you did it you either source treated
clones that you know we're treated by
you know your mom's the mom plants are
treated with a medical predator forbid
or whatever you know or you're going
them in the house or you know from seed
where you're able to
control that supply chain aspect that
much more or even more horrifying you
know and you know you you could run into
this whole idea which in the National
Organic Program there's an acronym for
it it's called uric you re C which is
unavoidable residual environmental
contamination and it's a term used to
like that the National Organic Program
has an effect to help organic products
still get on the market you know for
people that are certified organic but
you know they're in between the
neighboring strawberry farm and grape
farm who like aerial dive-bombs with
like micro butanol you know but yet
there are certified organic you know and
this whole kind of idea of trace
hartford billion detectable levels of
these pesticides you know coming from
the inputs that we use you know and
source you know for certain
dirty sources of compost I can Colorado
where you know kind of lighting people
off for a minute Chlo Priya and it came
back to this you know heavy source of
compost that's you know that's that's
you know ultimately being made from kind
of municipality kind of lawn trimmings
you know that are treated as
imidacloprid and so so I mean the whole
input view reality is such a major issue
now because of all these unlisted in
sorry one second
well and coupled with the ability to
look at the part per billion level
because when you look at part per
billion you're looking and you're gonna
find just a whole host of everything
because it's just right I liken it
taking a lint brush to a New York City
sidewalk you're gonna off hey Mitch was
saying something good we're talking
about that you can get right back to it
in one second Alec I just wanted to
mention what Mitch had said in the room
which was a simple you know asking these
growers when there's you know giving
their material to be to be processed or
first tested you know to get a sample of
their water or at least be told what
kind of water that are using and what
the nutrients are like what are you
using just tell me what you're using I
want a list I want to know what you're
using I don't want to find it later it's
tell me well walk throughs of interviews
that goes on now at least from my own
it's like it becomes a intimate like
interview all right brother let's talk
about let's talk about everything
it becomes an investigation about every
single step of his entire grow in what
he goes through
are you using quest filtrations and HEPA
filters and you these in your rooms what
are your you know it's like a plethora
of every single you know you don't even
need to ask any of those questions in a
sense you can just say listen we're
passing this on to the scientists and
they're gonna run it through all sorts
of fancy machines and come up with
numbers and graphs and man I'm telling
you it's gonna look bad on you if you
put some [ __ ] in here you weren't
supposed to go ahead Alec it one thing I
was gonna say sorry dinner it up real
quick I do have to cut out soon but I'm
involved in a project and we're working
closely with SC labs we're actually
Pacific reserves the name of our nursery
we're opening in Monterey County and
we're going to specialize in clean green
organic certified Jeanette Nicks that
people don't have to worry about
purchasing
that are not going to be contaminated so
that's a big important part of my whole
concerns as far as being an organic
advocate and allowing getting product to
people so they can do their job the
problems you have any idea how many
generations let's say you have a mother
plant let's maybe the [ __ ] out of
someone these were the some of these
systemics then you make us a small clone
permit you grow that at another facility
that's totally clean and there is still
little tiny bits of systemic left in
that plant so you grow it big and you
chop it up and you start making more
clones you treat it as a mother clone
well many generations will these
materials keep showing up how systemic
are they well that's something I can't
answer yet we're still trying to learn
this and one thing we're doing we're
doing more and more testing now that we
have a platform that we could actually
grow more plants and test more we are
you know actively doing that the one the
one way I know that cleans up plants and
genetics is tissue culture and that's
another part of our business that we're
going to expand into at the nursery as
well and the grape industry in
California they for for wine they supply
rootstock which is guaranteed virus free
it would be easy enough to do the same
thing with cannabis with systemics
poisons and viruses because even from
seed you get viruses viruses can carry
over in cannabis seeds so that's not
guaranteed it's clear it's clean from
pesticides but not from diseases mm-hmm
interesting well it's a good absolutely
absolutely well I just wanted to thank
everybody for having me on I'd love to
be on again this has been a really
incredible experience and incredible
panel you guys have had today I do have
some other obligations so I'm gonna have
to
and yeah I love real quick Ryan yeah if
you in reference that you know I mean
where you I have such a deep respect for
kindest you know the teeming with micro
restoring the soil all kind of the
microbiome in the soil approach towards
prevention and you know I've known Brian
for a long time back when I used to work
in hydroponic industry and you know I
feel very honored and blessed to you
know how people working with Viator the
vital and on this input review we're
doing for this third-party farm
certification program we're doing in bio
Canada by organics because you know in
this brave new world of you know
pesticide regulations are so tight you
know it's like there's just it's just
such a scary world of like what products
do I use cuz you know just four or five
years ago people were unknowingly using
Bushmaster and gravity thinking it was
derived from seaweed you know and you
know all these products here like
Guardian that's getting got pulled for
having unlisted avid in the product and
like the most recent army listed as a
trawl you know army listed as an actor
and kind of concentrate from neem which
also turned out to have like three
unlisted synthetic pyrethroids and pylon
in it you know it's like it's just this
mind-blowing reality and there's you
know the room for error of like a farmer
knowing you know or having confidence in
the product you know that's going to
help them succeed especially with
enterprise the right thing and maintain
the plant to the highest integrity you
know it's like looking to more more to
to you know quality products that are
vetted and you know actually going
through some type of process to
substantiate the product it because can
be so important because yeah I mean
people are you know it's like either
drift is coming through soil you know
from neighboring farms that were people
are at they are in battle implications
and just you know there's so much Chemie
agriculture going on around them or you
know it's like you know using you know
all these products in your closed-loop
kind of organic system that you know you
you don't necessarily know or should
have the full trust in that they're
organic because you know oftentimes it's
showing that they're turning out to be
hot you know or you know the different
products that are sold so yeah Brian man
very nice to meet you
it was a pleasure I hope to talk to ya
offer one of these things
for your work man as a pleasure yeah no
problem thanks everybody and my anyone
could reach out my emails Brian at vital
garden supply comm I'd be stoked to
connect with all you guys out there and
just continue making just an abyss
industry cleaner and better
do you have an Instagram that you want
to share yeah vital garden supply we are
active always putting different things
that we're doing up and work with a lot
of great people in the cannabis industry
super stoked on Alec and Essie labs and
Tony's been doing incredible work and
bubbleman we've been using your product
since Hugh as far back as I can remember
more insects rats and thank you for
being a leader and beating by example
because others around you will see what
you're doing and we'll want to replicate
it in other counties too so great job as
seeing great job Idol and Brian much
love buddy it's great to see you again
yeah I will talk some arctic air yeah
man thanks for coming in very good very
good
Wow we went solid there for a couple of
hours got pretty deep I like the
conversation I did just end up sending
the link out to forest who may or may
not make it in he was watching so the
panel was wonderful and it was inspiring
him he's kind of a big part of the
underlining conversation really of all
of that we're talking about because
really let's be honest where do we will
all want to align ourselves with the
highest of integrity with the with with
no poisons with with things that aren't
even questionable in any real cause yeah
to do no harm right that's our
Hippocratic oath it's like the cannabis
community really with this core group
right here I believe wants to do no harm
and there's so many different aspects of
the community that we cover with each
little box that's currently residing in
here right from the roots right up to
the to the resin heads and I love it
yeah give a shout out I want to give a
shout out to Greece for legalizing
medical cannabis and also to Spain for
catalona
for the barcelone area for legalizing
consumption cultivation and distribution
why'd ya do
you know that in the 1920s Greece was
the largest has she's producer for
Europe I had no idea but I would have
been pretty good hash shout out the
grease for saganaki flaming cheese it's
the one they like it's right next to
your table and they bring it to you
awesome it's like doing dabs of cheese
it's the best appetizer oh cheese dabs I
definitely see a Hulk meme coming up
called Hulk do cheese dance Okla fondue
I collected about several hundred
different Lebanese cloth bags that were
used for for hashish because that's the
way the Lebanese produced it in like the
linen cloth bag you have any to show us
I can go get some in the other room yes
just a couple hundred at yeah yeah what
I was trying to say was I wish I had one
from the twenties and before but Lebanon
was doing the exact same thing in
leather bags
yeah I've seen some of your linen bags
and every time you've allowed me to look
at them and touch them I'm always like
this is so cool like what a unique part
of the history yeah I've heard I've
heard but never seen even when I scored
Lebanese it came in that very thick
filmed cellophane it wasn't in the in
something like that but yeah that's that
they're even around or collectible and
that he of course has hundreds of them I
know I have most of the ones that exist
on the planet currently in one spot he's
got the just in the other room I'll be
right back I make a suggestion to Alec
this is just an idea for when you see
samples come by that are hot with
pesticides we're gonna be really cool
you know they sell these little
pack cartridges with silica gel which
you can do is basically do it just a
quick flash filtration of that sample
through the silica gel and you know when
you give the customer their bad news
that their sample is contaminated you
also can give them good news that they
can basically flash that [ __ ] through
silica gel basically remove the
contamination and and make it you know
good medicine again is that possible you
know you think you're saying that's a
successful like yeah I mean absolutely I
mean most of the pesticides at least
again Diesel's will get hung up on to
them if they're there and just trace
amounts
I imagine that again I was thinking I'm
really intrigued about this hexane
extraction of CBD but if you were to
take a nonpolar media and basically run
that through silica gel your your
pesticide contamination should be polar
enough that it gets hung up on the
silica gel where the extract and all the
nonpolar components and the cannabinoids
and [ __ ] come and so now you're
providing your your customer again with
the bad news that their [ __ ] is coming
back in Tama Nate but good news that
they could basically just flash it
through a column of silica gel and
basically clean it up and then resubmit
it and then see if it actually so here's
a question now when you say clean that
up and say you're doing it regularly and
you're getting this what I would suppose
is some toxic waste or something that is
very bad that you don't want to like
what do you do with that stuff what do
people do it just gets hung up on the
silica gel right and it just yeah
basically you'll where's the silica gel
go do you throw it into a landfill the
ocean does it like I don't I don't
understand you sell it to the jello
company and they start putting it in
jello along with the cow hooves yeah and
you know we still I could please a
silica gel filter right underneath the
main chamber in our extractor to
sequester the insecticides but those gel
filters come in a package that says that
when you're done with it you can put it
back in the package and dispose of it at
a place where they take stuff like that
so it's
it's not like you're gonna put it in
jello or pudding or send it to Bill
Cosby you know the penalty here you're
getting out of the concentrate and at
that point I mean again they can be
incinerated where they get completely
burned and you know I turned in the co2
for the atmosphere but you know whatever
I mean I'm not saying that we have that
problem solved I'm just saying that if
you know again I always look at those
you know decisions where vendors are
looking to either you know buy a whole
lot of material and then you know
they're like having kind of like what
tony was saying somewhat of an interview
with the grower or with the supplier to
understand you know that the stuff is
pesticide free even if they do see
results maybe they got results on one
bag but they're buying 20 bags how did
he know that the result from the one bag
is representative especially if you're
talking about microbiological
contamination which is a whole different
issue but I was just referring to
pesticide contamination in particular
which is that again you can sample one
part of the plant that has pasta side
contamination other parts of that same
plant could be completely mated so how
you sample a large batch of material to
get a representative sample so when
you're looking to make you know a
purchase of you know several a lot of
material that you could actually have a
reasonable you know idea that that
material is not contaminated but again
I'll go back to one last thing and then
I'll shut up which is when you're
looking at the ppb level the part per
billion level holy [ __ ] you're gonna
find [ __ ] everything dude you're
gonna find viagra you're gonna find
cocaine you're gonna find everything
that you Bick what is in our environment
at that level which unfortunately is all
our lines are you saying that cocaine
and viagra are ubiquitous in your
environment mark it depends on the
region or this in municipal water supply
you didn't
and a triple quad mass effect that you
can roll out any large bill in front of
that triple quad and it's got a sniffer
that will find the cocaine on just about
any bill that comes from anyone's pocket
no matter if it was used for coke or not
she said looking a part per billion
level again you're finding things that
are really you know liquidus within our
environment Alec don't you agree I mean
part per million is one thing right does
that want to understand what when we say
part per billion part so there's there's
percent right that's part 400 then
there's part per thousand right that's
even small then there's part per million
now we're talking part per billion man
that's just very very sort like a yeah
that's like a one shot of remove inside
a railroad car foliage in in terms of a
dry martini I mean the fact is is that
the dilution of these things in the
environment and the sensitivity of these
instruments I mean again can you run
Whole Foods produce through the same
level of scrutiny and not find trace
amounts of some of these insecticides
and plant the regulator's the art per
billion level you know so I I think you
bring up really interesting like
conundrum you know I'm and you know they
kind of reminds me I if you're familiar
with Michael Pollan's work botany of
desire you know and in the Bundys I
retakes these you know for crops can be
several hatched you know like ten
episodes a hashed Church it always comes
on oh it's amazing it's so amazing and
it gives me such future hope for
Humanity honestly beyond like all the
political [ __ ] of you know just the
whole coevolution thing and how much
who's really in the driver's seat how
much effect is this kind of cannabis
plant having effect on our personal
cultural evolution and the industries
that are being created from it and the
awareness that's being you know kind of
brought up you know to you know to to
everybody that's you know working with
this plant you know and it's fasting
because in you know in bodies are he
believes the future hope his future
hopes for you know kind of
then coming you know global food
commodity market and like you know kind
of the shifting to the slow food
movement farm fresh local produce model
you know in so many ways you know you
know can't give us props to the cannabis
farmers because of how intensively we
focused on how to perfect growing this
plant optimally for the most resin for
all these things and you know doing it
organically without any pesticides all
this stuff and and and you know
regulations it's really interesting
because you know it's you know
regulations around cannabis specifically
on pesticides you know I almost think
it's like the cannabis plant is almost
gonna shake a lot of people that aren't
really in line with the integrity of its
message off you know real quickly
because you know it's like you know if
so many people coming into so much money
thing they're gonna come just crush it
you know and like buy all these you know
old cut flower greenhouses that have so
caught your so dirty soil like you know
that the rip my point is the pesticide
regulations in cannabis I think are
gonna expose the dirty dirty secret
about how ubiquitous pesticides are in
our environment and how you know a zero
is almost a really difficult thing to
ever produce again because of how much
spraying and how much contamination is
taking place you know and I'm really
hoping deeply that you know kind of the
ethics of the leaders in the cannabis
movement and in in kind of you know kind
of dedicating and doubling down to
that's you know knowing the farmer and
you know you're anti mono crop you know
kind of being able to have you know you
know tighter understandings and controls
over the supply chain management of like
where you're getting but that's making
products that you're trying to put under
your brand you know I think it's it's
you know it's the biggest topic in the
industry I think and and I think it's
kind of you know in so many ways
highlight you know the in in the global
agricultural movement it's gonna bring
up the pesticide issue to people's
consciousness and and hopefully in some
bit of a way it really does begin to you
know shift or accelerate kind of just
you know awareness around slow food
movement and you know kind of yeah I
mean we supply a lot of our product to
multiple sustainable agriculture
consultants in in conventionally
produced commodity industry where
they're growing tomatoes and stuff like
that
and one of the the larger clients that
some of my guys sell to is well these
are independent distributors that are
selling to large agricultural operations
one of the things that some of these
larger producers are doing is they're
actually using systemic fungicides once
per week whether the crop needs that are
not like on tomatoes they'll go ahead
and put down so you know we're pretty -
some of these protocols that these guys
are doing and so what'll end up
happening is they may use contact
fungicides but they're also using
systemics once a week again whether the
plant needs they're not it's horrifying
well what's what systemic do you know
what they're using exactly yeah I do I
know well there's there's a multitude
there's there's there's quite a few but
rather than get into the details of the
actual chemical compounds which I think
will poor people I think this will kind
of be more more of interest so so the
DISA stem expose their actually
encumbering the vascular system of the
tomato so if you go into you know a
major retail store and you see a tomato
that's grown there like back when we
were kids you would see those little
brown spots that the tomato would get
and now those little brown spots that
the tomato get mixtures which was
botrytis the tomatoes don't get those
anymore because again they're using a
proactive approach now those systemic
fungicides again we're talking about
micro doses so think about this this
systemic fungicide that's going into a
tomato on a part per million basis so so
that systemic is actually killing all of
itself it's working as a biocide so it's
killing all of the bacteria good and bad
yeah well we really wait so now like
antibiotic yeah what what chemical are
you talking about exactly don't a basis
what's happening is when you eat you
know a fruit or a vegetable what
what could happen and again this is
being disclosed to me I'm not saying
this is fact or truth but that that
systemic fungicide that is penetrating
the entire vascular system of that
tomato is is working as like an
antibiotic within our microbiome in our
digestive diseases Whitford is justice
this is what's being told to me it's
horrifying it's not something that I'm
disclosing on the basis of our company
this is just what some of our
sustainable agriculture consultants have
disclosed to me I just want to get that
straight so you think about the rise in
gluten intolerance you think about the
rise in celiac disease autoimmune can so
you think about the fact that possibly a
fungicide that's designed to kill
bacteria is easy now a fungicide is
designed to kill fungus a bacteria side
is designed to kill bacteria and are not
necessarily in the same bucket any
microbials in general there are broad
classes of antimicrobial some kill
fungus some kill bug of some kill Bowl
some kill one to kill the other because
it creates a biofilm and the biofilm
becomes basically a zoo for a whole
diverse population and new microbes that
basically colonized the people who came
in there before them
so let's and I'm really interested in
what you're telling me so what you're
telling me is that and again I'm
somewhat of an expert in this field of
antimicrobial so I want to make sure
you're not being bullshitted which is
that systemic fungicides are put into
the plant not to kill bacteria it's to
kill fungus right and so the systemic
fungicides that I know that are used
basically control fungi on the plant and
in in the soil but are very very
short-lived you know they're not there
for all for a whole long period of time
what you're telling me is that there are
things that are being applied to
Tomatoes that are persistent is what
this is what was disclosed to me more
but I'll tell you what is the active
ingredient I'm just curious because that
active ingredient must be registered for
human consumption because if it's
persistent in tomatoes that means you
can eat a tomato that has some level of
this stuff and that means that some
company registered a whole bunch of
products based on some safety data that
said that a whole bunch of human beings
can eat this [ __ ] with this level of
this stuff in these Tomatoes
or else it wouldn't be on the US market
right that's supposedly environment
those limits will harden actually to do
what you're probably right of like what
this gentleman told me and I again I'm
not publicly disclosing it on the MOR
actually I'm just being told that these
bio science right this is what I was
told these bio science can actually
eliminate a lot of the bacteria as well
so they work as a bio site not
necessarily just a fungicide so so
they're there destroying all of the
bacteria like you know an antibiotic
would essentially yes so broad-spectrum
and again broad-spectrum and it's a any
microbial it's a it's it's a biocide you
know it's definitely something that
they're not being specific on whether
it's a fungicide most biocides
there are certain again ones that
basically have no activity against fungi
at all fungi have their own you know
they got their own [ __ ] kingdom i
think right they do yeah and you know I
was just gonna add one thing I mean
there's a whole lot of chemicals that
are used in the production of food and
processed food and and and and and
produce but what makes it what makes it
register today is not necessarily you
know chemicals that that kill bugs
there's a lot of chemicals that kill
bugs what makes a crop protection agent
registered today is the fact that it has
a really good safety profile is that
it's got no mammalian toxicity
so a lot of the mode of actions of new
low use rate agrochemicals are based on
specific action that are specific to
insects so like calcium channeling and
and and potassium channels there's
specific mechanisms in insects that
don't exist in humans so they can
develop essentially you know medicines
if you will just basically knock those
out but let me just finish this last
thought so the point is is that this are
used in foods today somewhere a long
time ago or maybe not so long ago a
company spent a whole lot of money in
doing safety and assessment studies to
get that stuff registered for that end
use and again here in Canada bias
yeah we're faced with the pen and room
that there is no safety assessment for
any of these products being applied to
to cannabis because no company was
forced to do that to register the active
ingredients so they can sell products
and it looks like the [ __ ] that Trump
put in there is going to basically keep
companies from being able to register
stuff with the EPA which is completely
[ __ ] stupid and thank you Trump
voters and the thing is is that you know
there are biological ways of controlling
plant disease that can aid cannabis
cultivation so this is really the EPA
taken two steps backwards and that
register is progress you know sorry
biocontrol agents there's at what
activity a Syrian name there's those
products and and I've heard that they
were created Galia I grande Evo no I
don't know yeah the letter D Peter did
you read the letter that that Scott
Pruett wrote honest it's just so no
Gallo and so thin it's just oh you know
we can't the EPA does can't do this
because cannabis is illegal and uh just
[ __ ] [ __ ] letter but anyway
actually all this talk of pesticides is
a bit of a downer I mean we do need to
have safety standards we do need to
produce clean safe cannabis
but Sam is that oh I'm sorry what that
letter shows is that you know they're
not taking a step forward in letting I I
agree with my mark I read the letter
yeah it just yeah it sucks go ahead show
so your show and tell now read Lebanese
can you see it looks green
we had see that see the red is a triple
ice cream yeah I'm afraid but light is
very poor oh it's pretty good it's not
that bad I can kind of see it's for the
kids
[Laughter]
ash oh my god such a character no I
agree Sam it is I mean it's definitely
especially with the with the level of
the people that are in here right now
even Brian who just left a lot of the
people really most of us here are at the
point where we'd much prefer to just
have product not have to become sick and
have these poisons used on them but a
product that could be bred specifically
for strength and for resilience used
with you know like proper root symbiosis
and living soils and teas and organics
and I mean that's what what I would like
to see I just I just want to see the
plant in the most natural of ways be
boosted to express its terpene and
cannabinoid profile - you know back to
the ten because I really feel like we're
living in the age of the seven right now
where everyone thinks a seven is like a
9.5 and it's it's not that you have with
soil balanced both men we really do the
soil balance will will return things to
that balance and I'm excited I was just
gonna add thinking about what Alex said
though this is
[ __ ] cool the toll pesticide issue
which they want to have you know
cannabis with zero pesticide zero
I mean this is rising to the level of
awareness where people are beginning to
think about how this affects their food
and and and so that's like you know hey
how you know our is the food that I'm
you know eating raised you know is this
botrytis you know free tomato the safest
thing I could be so you know I've got
whole bags from Lebanon plus I have
where I just cut out the design on a
bunch of bags
samer those hemp is that these are
probably either cotton or linen nice I
like to leave the lady with the big
rifle that you could tell by just
mortise awning yeah yeah she's a that's
definitely what's from the 70s or
something like that something like that
yes I also have two horse two horses
brand and there's Christian ones and
there's Muslim ones because we were both
in the hash trade that's awesome dude I
mean what a killer informations right
beautiful great collection of history
one paper one oh the paper one look at
what does that say miss normal hashish
misses normal yeah I think it does
indeed miss is normal
hey welcome forest hey what's going on
guys you know we've been talking with
sorts of things all sorts of things yeah
got this epidermis in the summer that oh
it's really glad to hear that systemic
pesticide discussion one of it sending
that message and tell you thanks but
thanks for the invite
come on yeah you know no matter how safe
we think they are let's probably not put
them into everything we eat and inhale
into our lungs right sure that cheers to
that you know we had enough
up or not but we had 40% of our
medicines once we make concentrates 40%
of them failed Formica butanol from
organic farms so I've been really making
a big issue about this and I haven't
heard it talked much anywhere which is
why I love love this show good job
what was the woman and especially
especially 21 of the really trippy
parties you know since it's such a
similar boiling point as cannabinoids
when it's distilled it's so common
concentrated absolutely with
cannabinoids also as most other things
that might not be what I really wonder
if we're talking about systemic
fungicides Azhar is and maybe Mark from
the office are they are they selectively
you know when you talk about the
diminishing titor's of fungi within the
plants vascular system is that
particular synthetic capable of being
selective in what it in what it kills I
mean will it are you sure mark that that
these products and I studied them great
but do not I'm not I'm not sure die I
think it's safe to say though that the
Green Revolution model of mono crop
super kami agriculture with dumping
pesticides just proportionally on your
plants you know you know without any
regard you know as obviously that just
incredible you know loss of soil
microbiome you know and so I mean I
think it might be all things your mind
right you know and because it gives yeah
if you kill off the fungus in the soil
and you you you allow an environment for
certain bacterial colonies to grow
disproportionately and you know you lose
your balance protozoa and nematodes
bacteria to fungus you also use
significantly throw off the soil for a
food web and and and then yen when you
is continuously dumping like whatever
chemicals I mean you it seems like
they're obviously I mean you know have
you heard about the Indian farmers that
have killed himself
drinking months on the fertilizers over
the last 10 years by the hundred
thousands you know because of how
quickly like the soil
happened and you know like they're you
know a lot loss of natural soil you guys
heard anything about that
yeah good forestry have no they have no
future anymore so they drink the inside
decided themselves because it's the
cheapest way out and I work because well
also because they become almost
indentured servitude to big AG you know
in like you know the the loans that they
then get so far behind on that they
can't even ever pay back have to use
increased you know kind of chemical
fertilizers that they didn't have to buy
just to get the same sustained yields
because their soils dead now you know in
the end in the end what Monsanto and the
other companies are doing there is they
they do make them into indentured
servants at first but then later they
actually try to get a hold of the land
and they can run these guys off of their
land because of the way the laws and
financial responsibilities work in India
well that that's all that's why I think
that the regulations and cannabis
pesticide use are gonna be you know
actually so good for the plants survival
and for the survival of all the mom and
crop mom-and-pop small-scale farmers
have been doing this all their life you
know because it's so hard to grow
especially on scale really amazing
quality kind of a super turbed up that's
clean without pesticides and if you
haven't like gotten smashed by broad
mites or russets or like don't know how
to deal with identifying all these
different plant pathogens or plant pests
that are invasive is like your you know
the room for error where you can like
not know how to diagnose it and just
bomb [ __ ] with like the tryout of eagle
forbidden floor might look those days
are gone you know and and i think i
think the room the margin for error and
not knowing how to have a really strong
integrated pest management program you
know it's going away real quick so it's
like i think the people that have
figured it out are going to be super
successful while a lot of people fail
you know cuz a lot of people are
throwing huge money and building the
most sophisticated build-outs thinking
that they're just gonna crush and become
like the biggest cannabis millionaires
ever but it's like it's it's interesting
because it's like this is very different
playing field because the pesticide
thing is yeah I think it
one of the single dividing factors who
makes it who doesn't yeah but you got to
admit if you look at the food supply in
America the vast majority of it is not
organic is that I know right but you
know that's also why like oncology
doctors and and like autism specialists
like always first and foremost get
parents to not or to choose organic
foods and produce for their kids because
of the presence of all these random
endocrine disrupting different types of
like you know okay gnarly kind of their
neuro toxic pesticides you know and then
also like you know considering like I'm
gonna corporate you know imidacloprid
neoneun nicotine noise pesticide is one
of the most frequently used common a
accepted acknowledged you know
pesticides on you know most produce you
know nationally but it's also one of the
biggest contributors to the calling
collapse disorder and mass be died off
that's happening and one of the biggest
which is one of the reasons why
California went so you know kind of
regulated even though I'm inappropriate
you know regulated freeze on tobacco
it's not going to be for cannabis at the
end end in California that what super
strict on it especially because of like
how much California is trying to remove
neo nicotine ODEs from you know kind of
the supply chain you know or just from
you know the agricultural use you know
so it's like yeah there's so many
pesticides approved by the EPA but does
that actually mean that you know we're
not getting harmed icky or chronically
from the exposure to all these different
you know whatever I don't think the
average American gives a book I mean why
do they eat it we do them and why do
they buy all their food from you know
places that are manufacturing with
pesticides because they so but like the
cheap prices and you know yeah
absolutely but also it's you know
hopefully that you know there I mean
there's this very interesting kind of
oxymoron or I don't know if that's even
the right word you know you have so many
people buying you know $100 grams of
extract and just trolling people
relentlessly on Instagram about having
dirty product
we're like residual butane or pesticides
even though yeah they're going to
McDonald's and eating a Big Mac after
that three times a day but I think you
know hopefully you know this educates
makes us aware and you know pushes us to
you know change our ways what sealed
mean about the the hippie girl with the
fish show the dead show bill needs
organic and vegan but it's taking the
tan the mystery the mystery liquid in
the parking lot how much I happen to
have money
a recent active test results here and if
for those you out there if you want to
have clean and do clean medicine that's
what it takes is testing everything over
and over again so I just went through
this real quickly to see if I had any
fails in this stack that I have here of
recent tests probably about thirty or
forty tests and I pulled out three this
came up really quick from organic farms
so with the mic will see this one's got
Michael butanol 2.1 parts per million a
lot Carrboro twenty point three parts
per million to I knew how you say this
one to Tabuk ozone Cebu kosoul that's a
triangle
Debu console there you go thank you
that's what we got experts on the show
they trial fund site that's point two
parts per million so that one's quite a
bit from before on an organic form at
least carpet roll is a big problem metal
pops up quite a bit that's right yeah so
at those levels would you think that
that could still be not coming from a
foliar application and it could be
coming from say like a mulch or a non of
mulch what what we were talking about
the dirty implants yeah like like dirt
dirty soil could this be a dirty so
or adrift and not necessarily hey I
never applied that material to my plants
at all you know some of these folks
sorry not to jump in but just with her
with our organization because we're
dealing with such fragile and small
children we don't just take whatever
somebody wants to donate we try to get
to know these people and some of these
folks I know well you know it's been a
it's an uncomfortable situation I'm sure
that Tony's had this as well or
something you have when you have to go
back and say hey sorry you know we had
to destroy this or not use it and they
get pretty upset because people put
their life's work and passion into this
so I know some of these people are not
intentionally contaminating you know so
I was I was personally the guy that's
kind of like the Grinch of chalice
because part of my job was to basically
contact 79 disqualified entrants that
had pesticides their products knows
basically they're letting him know that
they were disqualified because these
detected pesticides so yeah people super
pissed but it's like one of the big
things I was focusing on like with all
these people I was talking to you I was
like you know and I mean this is
honestly although you lost $500 per
entry you know entry fee you know it's
such a small price to pay to figure this
out right now where you still have a few
months to cook the way ahead of it
because if you don't you're done and
it's like it's almost too late to figure
how it's like if you're finding out
right now that you have you can and that
you've never cleaned out your
closed-loop system you know and your
sourcing from all these farms or all
those material you know and your
pesticides and the same concentrations
across the ten samples that were entered
so I guess so such clear cross
contamination in your extraction machine
or in your gas and you know and so just
people coming to where this right now
it's like a small price to pay to get
publicly humiliated and this you know in
one of these you know events and
competitions because you know six months
from now it's a quarter-million dollar
product recall or a liability lawsuit
yeah you don't test your your race car
on race day okay you don't right okay
you don't test you are also to some of
these really persistent and
systemic insecticides pesticides
fungicides they get into the soil and
they persist there for quite a while
ya know that's exactly right because
it's like you know if a foliar
application is applied and then UV from
the Sun is the biggest thing breaking
down that systemic residue what happens
when your route drenching imidacloprid
or route drenching any of these other
compounds you know because what is the
half-life or the residue effect there
you know I would yeah I would totally
grease that's probably the the biology
if you have good biology in the soil
I'll actually buy into a lot of the
synthetic hydrocarbons that are in the
soil and bind it to the the soil kind of
like like bioremediation so they can i
it's a microbes will actually degrade
some of these actives because again the
actives are necessarily antimicrobial
some of these insecticides again will
have no activity on the microbes and
when the microbe sees that carbon it's
gonna eat it like there's no tomorrow as
though it's sugar you know so again you
know a lot of chemicals rely on
microbial degradation to make sure that
they're either not persistent my arrow
bo hydrolytic these are all the you know
reactive handles that they put into
these active ingredients so they don't
persists in the environment like the oh
voice you know i just wanted to give a
big shout out to the vegetarians out
there you folks do realize that all the
white sugar produced it goes through
activated bone charcoal nice man first
jello and now this but you know real
quick cause something i want to kind of
share a story on one of my really good
friends you know for a long time santa
cruz his family has a lot of pear
orchards or you know massive pear
orchard up in northern Oregon and you
know he's an organic certified perform
but and so so they you know dedicated
organic and such they go up there they
get into
licensed whatever and they you know have
over 44,000 square for your greenhouse
going now you know but they've run into
a major problem and that's that you know
pretty much all the all the surrounding
farms in the in that Valley all are also
per orchards are not organic and and
when they when they spray for pesticides
they basically have like a like a metal
pipe grid kind of going around the
entire orchard with like kind of holes
kind of throughout that basically they
charge the line and it just shoots like
20 30 feet into the air you know these
these you know these this you know water
kind of with diluted pesticide or
undecided in it and and you know there's
all these these you know rules for when
these pesticides are allowed to be
applied like no wind you know certain
times of the day or night you know etc
etc but he's pretty much already had to
threaten lawsuit to a lot of these
neighboring farms in the valley you know
because of how how regulated cannabis is
is you know that they have to be
notified with X amount of time so they
can basically batter down the hatches of
all the greenhouses and then attempts
when they're spraying to like prevent
any drift coming in their greenhouses
and you know they've already although
not detected and flower
you know once they made you know kind of
their product that's all organic and
extract they're they're seeing this
consistent like detectable level of like
a fungicide called boscola
possibly and it's one of the sides at
Oregon in California on their list but
it's a it's a fun set is used on pears
quite frequently and so you know just
kind of you know considering kind of how
how kind of drift travels you know and
and you know when you don't have like
positive displacement or kind of you
know what have you it's like I mean is a
lot of people like when you think about
you know all these huge acquisitions of
all these old kind of you know kind of
cut flower or farm green houses
throughout Monterey and Salinas is they
I mean I my holy [ __ ] did there might be
he might be shown that a lot of areas
can't grow herb that is in compliance
with what the state requirements and
limits bus has really at least in
greenhouses
the pesticide is a bit contained what's
worse is when they're growing
strawberries and other outdoor crops
I was just the nation like airplanes to
spray I was in the in the 90s and you
know how they use the plastic on the
strawberries well one they were using
methyl bromide back then they didn't
think about good and our grapes they
were injecting the methyl bromide to
strawberry fields that were in kind of a
residential neighborhood the wind came
and blew that plastic tarp off from weed
control that actually sustained the the
the the gas within the soil that the
tarp came off and they had to evacuate
four blocks of houses because of this
methyl bromide that was used on
strawberries so yeah I grew up on the
Ares I grew up in the Central Valley in
California and yeah there's no
containing add those crop tests we used
to play as kids next to some of those
fields and because we rented houses
there growing up and I remember they'd
start spraying you know twenty yards
before the field and we would just get
dosed in it you know it's it's just a
sloppy application and it's really gonna
happen things impact do you think that
dosage while you were as a kid had
anything to do with what's going on with
you your kid now now I think it's where
I got my superpowers yeah I have no idea
but yeah you just bathe in it I know I
know I used to follow the mosquito truck
down my back lane while it was spring
zyklon-b I used to do the same thing
following a mosquito truck when I lived
in Florida my bicycle
oh my god people gasoline and the
mosquito trucks drove around spraying
DDT all the time and as kids we rode
behind it and bicycles because it was
the only mosquito free zone we could
find own wealth story and well we're all
gonna die I want to stir it back to
how cannabis can flourish in scenarios
where pesticide and fungicide isn't
really needed I really you know this
plant involved without our interventions
and I really think there's a thing with
soil biology and also identification of
the types that grow in these different
environments and again indoor and in
greenhouses to an extent you can create
different environments outdoor you're
kind of limited but this is an
incredibly diverse gene pool that we've
created at this point and I really it's
been my experience and I really want to
push the idea that with the right
cultivars and the right attention to the
soil or the biology and whatever
material you're growing in including
indoors and greenhouses you can find
plants that will give you what you're
seeking and not have to get any
applications of any of these things that
we've been discussing today and I'm
really pushing this idea because one
Alec was mentioning that small farms
have an advantage here that large farms
aren't going to be able to work with
because at a small farm you can source
your inputs yourself you can control
what your compost is just like if you
control if the biology is like you can
make friends with your neighbors so that
they're not spraying on your stuff and
it's been my experience I'll say it like
that that I've had some success finding
plants that flourish in the environment
I can offer here and I I want to suggest
to anyone that cares to explore the
different plants that are out there you
can probably find something that's going
to give you what you want in the
environment you're working with and
you're going to find it's not going to
need all these things that we've been
talking about and when I find a plant
that I really love and it isn't
challenged by bugs or whatnot insect
frass is one of the routine supplements
that I use in the soil amazing
but I also like a certain plant based
amendments that I can use in the soil I
like comfrey
stinging nettle and horse tail makes a
tea that irritates bugs but doesn't seem
to really be a pesticide per se and
meantime plants seem to be really
stimulated and liked it a lot
that's an example one of the only foyer
sprays that I use is water especially
adjusting the pH of water but and I've
heard Mike there's been discussion here
about using electrolysis to do that but
yeah boiler spray of water really has
remarkable effects when you spray water
is it at a specific time like I mean I
know you don't really want to do it when
the Sun is high in the sky and burn a
lot only if I'm indoors it's right when
the lights come on or just before I
don't like to do it as the lights go off
outdoors again just following that same
thing in the mornings when the stomata
on the leaves open up it's a real good
time to give them some moisture rinse
the dust off they'll take in some
moisture there that happens in nature
that's really the guiding principle
about how I work with plants is to try
and understand what nature is like for
those plants where they come from and
then my duplicate thank you
yes exactly and I think because the
plant the genetic pool that we've
created is so diverse I really think
that whatever conditions you're working
with you can find plants that will
flourish in your scenario and then all
of a sudden this conversations about
various things to control pests or
diseases in check are not so relevant
and this plant it's incredible what this
plant is capable of I mean we all every
one of us has some aspect of deep
respect for what this plant can do for
us humans and I really do think that we
have evolved with this plant to benefit
from it and it has evolved to benefit us
all indefinitely hints
that in yes look the botany of desire
and I I'm in agreeance with them like
what a great companion we have both been
to one another cannabis and humanity
it's like it's like the dog to the plant
world right it is it is a very
successful plant
yeah it's our companion so it's
coevolution you know and I'm the kind of
teeming with microbes approach yeah I
mean you know whenever you're looking to
nature for more efficient design and
you're able to like as close to
potentially possible recreate that you
know and you know and I know people that
are having such amazing success
especially on kind of big scale Kai
production Canada you know working with
and teeming with kind of predatory mites
like for similar some sworsky mites and
you know and kind of just having this
very methodical never deviating from
kind of preventative approach you know
the whole ounce of prevention is worth a
pound of cure
you know and you're using different
rotational horticultural oils and bio
fungicides and bio insecticides and
compost teas it's like I mean it's just
amazing because it's like that's the
leading possible potentially penitential
way to grow plant to maximize ability
with a you know maximized increases in
secondary metabolite production you know
it's just so funny and amazing that kind
of you know cannabis farmers have
figured out how to be become the if they
choose the path the best farmers that
are possible and so yeah i really hope
and have a lot of faith that that's
going to carry over and you know
hopefully empower through hemp
production a lot of other you know or
other farms who you know might have been
growing GMO corn up to this point you
know but hopefully you know it's the
thing that is catalyst to help shift you
know luck with corn 90% of its GMO
ninety-four economic model that drives
the cannabis industry right now is based
on quality right now our food is not
that way you know most kids right now
don't give a [ __ ] about the nutrient
density within the commodity that
they're ingesting they're right it's all
about price well they're not even seeing
the hypocrisy of
alik just mentioned spending days
trolling people relentlessly for their
dirty extracts while just consuming the
lowest quality of food known to man
we're good about McDonald's you making
me want to go get one
[Laughter]
preventative you know so if you got
clean certified genetics you started to
grow and you took all of these best
practices that's being discussed today
to wade and kind everybody there Cohn
roots with his product let's say you're
doing everything you can possibly do to
give the plant its most healthy
environment and its best potential to be
as strong as it can be and it has
exposed her to you via the Sun in some
capacity it's going to it's going to
naturally ward off pests and and p.m.
and things like that so I mean that's
what that's what the the bottom line
here is prevention and and systems
approach you know systems of how you
manage your IPM is the key yeah and also
considering - you know it's it's it's
really interesting because you know he's
so when I used to work in the hydroponic
stores in Santa Cruz you know have one
of the most frequent things I would see
happen as you know people would like
essentially cut corners on you know
build out or like dehumidification say
and then like they'll go overboard and
get like the full 20 part kind of you
know nutrient kind of you know PGR is
everything - you know almost
overcompensate with their nutrients for
a shitty environment or whatever and and
in you know 80% your success in so many
ways comes the environment that they're
that you created and you know when you
consider like light DEP revised like the
private herb you know most people and I
think we talked about this on on house
courage before but you know when you
take a blackout tarp and you cover up
like a row of class that you're light
that being you know you you create this
micro it's almost like putting a clone
phone trade Oman to create a hundred
percent humidity you know so for the
whole night you you know you have this
like shift and in humidity to where it's
it's at seventy to eighty percent for
the rest of the night and that's like
perfect proliferative environment for
these microbes and powdery mildew inside
that's that's what that's what is on
your fans are more you can easily
control humidity in the darkened
greenhouse I've done it for 30 years
right but how many people I mean and you
know and I think it's a part of people's
own evolution it's like understanding
how much the environment that you create
is also one of the biggest things you
could do so like prevent pest and
pathology and using your attention like
sprays from the time the plants are
small to where you can get full plant
coverage with neem or peppermint oil you
know by the time they're huge you're
just doing your weekly sprays and even
though you might not cover every
understand every topside every single
leaf you know since you've been doing
methodically every week since the plant
was a baby it's like you know you you're
pretty contained you know but that's
such a body of knowledge and work and
dedication devotion and so many people
like that are scaling a thousand percent
it's like you know they you know it's
just it's hard to maintain a really
integrity based IPM strategy you know
whenever you're you know overextended or
you don't have enough staff because you
know it's always been you know you can
handle so much more canopy space with so
many less employees because this place
pesticides but you know financing your
operation I need to protect your crop
and you have proven methodologies that
are gonna do exactly what you're talking
about Alec that's one of the caveats in
this industry as well
the economics you know it definitely
cost more to use IPM III was the largest
biological control person in Europe for
years and years on cannabis
and thank you very much for that Sam
deep respect Sam mmm
Sam butan Sammy I'm sorry you didn't
know you were did you have disease pest
management that's McPartlin correct
excuse me what was that question it's a
little bit quiet
sorry hemp disease pest management was
that McPartland did you have a part of
that to do with that work all all of the
practical suggestions were for me
John did research in libraries Robert
took photographs and I wrote the all the
how to use the materials and what works
and what doesn't because I've got 40
years experience Jeezy and I think
that's still to this days like the the
guideline textbook kind of in the
subject so thank you for your work my
goal at that time was specifically to
allow people to have alternatives to
dangerous pesticides insecticides
fungicides and I hope it helped but yeah
we're - being honest people almost have
to be driven into using IPM it's not
enough people have a good enough
conscience and they just not like they
they prefer to save time save money and
do it the easy way which is nuke them
with some sort of nasty [ __ ] well and
also because usually whenever somebody's
going at a hydro store - you know it's
like even though you know the products
you recommend there's like oh you're and
week two or three or flower you actually
shouldn't really spray anything but if
you are going to spray something here
are these organic products that you can
spray if you do you spend 30 hours in
your room just spray and coat every
plant you know but it's like by the time
so many people are coming in to the
hydro stores to try to find a solution
it's because they have a deep
infestation and by that point you know
it's too late but you see people's like
moral compass shift really quickly when
they're faced with huge loss to be
honest the only thing I ever sprayed was
bacteria Thurn Janice BT I would do that
in vegetative but I I never sprayed any
things on my plants no teas none of this
kind of
i biodynamically fertilized my soil in
between crops and the plants never seem
to need it that and super super heavy
prevention I was using at one time 22
different kinds of predators
preventively there was no problem I was
using them preventively the majority
well and that's I think what's so
exciting about like the the future of
what we're talking about it's like you
know with biodynamic farming and
permaculture models and sustainable soil
models of like regenerating topsoil
creating the most you know rich
biodiversity
that's cannabis really fit does cannabis
really fit into permaculture it's an
annual it gets harvested every year I
just need more in the model of like you
know yeah it's like using local source
inputs and might you know like you know
kind of acclimated kind of microbes that
are from you you know then just covering
all the bases and buildings so because I
mean whenever you have like all the
necessary microbes in your soil you know
oftentimes you're they're both helping
to find and transport all the nutrients
needed and break down and you know kind
of send around but also you know kind of
they're they're as natural plant without
a ball stomach microbiome and it's in
for an immune system you know what I've
also found in greenhouses is even if
your soil is perfect and I'm talking
about the soil of in the earth not
container soil and you biodynamically it
enriches your soil furred for decades
pests will still take off if you
introduce them into a greenhouse you've
created a perfect environment for pests
in an enclosed greenhouse
interesting long drawn-out pause
everyone's taking a breath hmm
all right barrio it's true you make the
environment safe for the plants
everything else as a conversation for a
second so I'll take a bong rip with you
at 10:00
[Music]
naturally cobalt particularly I do find
plants some plants are resistant to some
pests and diseases but unfortunately
most growers although they might be
looking for those what they're really
looking for is what's popular and what
sells at the moment to be honest well
and I also think that from our last
conversation if you were able to express
the different types of terpene profiles
like when you were we were talking about
having all nine of them light up in
people equal equal right we you know you
were saying what that flavor and all
that kind of stuff was for but these
plants also are responding to different
environments and different areas when
they're growing but and her pains are
can be repellents for different things
and they using and expressing is like a
language I wouldn't be surprised if some
terpenes are attracted to some insects
insects and fungus they are their
natural plant defense mechanisms right
so like lure predator prey or to Ward
predators and lure pollinators well look
look what it does top it lures us in and
lures deer and all kinds of animals my
little Pomeranian loves cannabis if you
if she if she can get to it even if it's
in an edible zip lock up black locked up
in a backpack put in a closet if she can
you
to it and and get her mouth into the
backpack and open it she'll hunt it down
and find it if you put her in your
garden and we walked a greenhouse and
you've got like you know two-foot plants
all the little lower leaves along our
little path that we walked she's gonna
nibble at him all along the way she has
no control over is she always that baby
or endocannabinoid system needs a little
shot honey tell me she'd be happy he
doesn't have a Great Dane like my sister
I try to keep everything away from her
and then I would come home and you could
tell that she was getting high yeah
where is she getting all this stuff was
they've got no edibles they got nothing
she's to the point where even the q-tips
that I clean out just the little
residual on the corpse and I put those
down she's been taking them out of the
ashtray and has a little hash - and it's
like dude think about it you're like
prohibition for your dog but it didn't
work on us and it won't work on her and
her animals so the dog do dogs have an
endocannabinoid yes yes everything does
not insects don't receptors for the
terpenes though how's that how do you
explain that well that may be true but
they don't have cannabinoid receptors
cb1 and cb2 that's correct
aaaghh that is a pretty reliable
indicator for me of when I have a plant
in the garden that's high in CBD and has
certainly no THC he will walk with me in
the garden and with great respect
reaches in and takes off son leads
usually kids three or four at a time and
every year he's been accurate that it
turns out to be a plant that's high in
CBD low in tea
that's pretty much I think into specific
medicines this pertains to a way to
brought up as far as which environments
do the plants express themselves most
beneficial is
far as not being success susceptible to
pests and other things we're also gonna
find that they reach their fullest
potential and certain terpene profiles
in different environments differently
because of what Tony mentioned is they
react for the environment that they're
in and that's what I'm really excited
with some of these companies are doing
as far as genetically mapping and doing
scientific surveys of cultivators
building the same strains in different
geographic environments because in the
next you know five years we're gonna be
it's so much further ahead as far as
understanding some of those
manifestations of plants in different
geographical areas and as a medicine
maker in someone who's have a huge
interest in that how those plants
interpret their environment and how that
changes the terpene profiles and the
levels of certain terpenes is very very
interesting so I decided mostly it just
modifies the profile it doesn't create
new terpenes because right the boughs
are determined by having the terpene
synthase for that particular terpene
right right at those different levels of
those terpenes that's absolutely true
because I I grew an identical clone for
25 years it was grown under 100 thousand
different and we did GC analyzed it and
the profile would would alter slightly
depending on the environmental
conditions they were the most favorable
or the least favorable well here's
here's my guess I'm the whole thing the
first thing I share was a new study that
came out with the Institute of ecology
and Netherlands
so my first hash search I talked to you
guys about this was they was they came
out saying that the most widely spoken
language on the planet is terpene so
what's happening is and and a couple of
you have mentioned this is that these
terpenes are actually you know a
hydrocarbon lighter than air so they're
coming into our our nasal passages and
so our biology is actually communicating
with that
biology so there's a whole nother
physics dynamic happening with our bio
communication with the plants as well as
the energetic one so when we're talking
about the Burpee profile taking
variations of them actually do it's
pretty comprehensive alien language
shape everything here fits in with
everything else and so when you take a
look at the fact that we've got into
cannabinoid systems everything else does
- must be that when the Syrians are the
dog star people left us off here they
left us with a pot plant and said look
we're gonna call this a mono machine
it's actually mono wanna but this will
sustain you until you get going so I got
some beans just good as any other theory
hey you spend enough time behind a
mosquito truck anything will make sense
after well what a great quote if you
spend enough time my god Tony's just
shaking his head I woke up for this
super complex endogenous cannabinoids
system and you know with some of the
understandings that you know so many
types of disease and disorder might be
rooted in some type of endocannabinoid
deficiency syndrome you know and you
know and then and then kind of you know
some of those new work with kind of the
whole idea of cannibal mimetics and you
know other types of plants beyond
cannabis that you know have
endocannabinoids system stimulating
effects you know it's it's really
interesting this whole kind of braving
the world of like almost like compounds
pharmacy of these you know blending of
you know cannabinoid terpenes from the
cannabis plant with potentially other
types of plants like echinacea and you
know kind of agonda and you know
different things like probiotics because
you know they have these different up
regulating or different you know and
okinawa system you're stimulating
aspects but you know one interesting one
you know and have you guys hurt you if
you know what copal is copal it's this
like smudge that's a sap from a tree
Summit's it's a smudge that's very
commonly burned in like sacred
ceremonies so my incense yeah it's
exactly these incredibly distinct smell
but you know there's a there's a mana
there's a certain like diterpene or
something in copal which binds to CD one
which is what happens to TAC team tapes
I partial CB one cb2 receptor agonist
you know and so see you know binding to
CB one is what helps to give the
psychoactive feeling in effects you know
then modulated slightly by the different
terpenes but you know I wonder what you
know you know to take some amount of
like this copal tripping that binds the
CB one as well you know and adding that
into some type of preparation is that
gonna slightly create new effects
because this is too similar you know and
this bc you have to be a little bit
careful when you're when you're
vaporizing or combusting new terpenes
that are not found in cannabis with a
cannabis all the terpenes that are there
we have hundreds and hundreds of years
of experience right you know that they
don't cause major problems when you
start breathing in huge amounts of copal
with THC it may or may not cause
problems although copal with since it's
used in religious ceremonies I doubt it
right and it's so common like I inhaled
or just yeah whatever but interesting
well you know I mean we're running that
time here but that could be a whole show
about you know the endo family system is
unlocking what we've seen in other
aspects of natural healing anecdotally
it's it's really pointing to how those
things are interacting with the body and
if anyone it hasn't read the paper that
was mentioned here this dr. Russo's new
work on cannabinoids outside of cannabis
it's really interesting and you just see
all these have this yeah you just see
this some trail of things that we've
known forever kava root is another one
that he does a big piece on in there and
in how they're building things to
interact with the cannabinoid system but
we see you know essential oil therapies
you know you know there's natural
therapies that we didn't understand kind
of why we saw the the benefits they did
but then you start to look at what is in
lavender and Layla will we see how
they're interacting with receptors in
the body you started to understand I
think I think this endocannabinoid
system is going to unlock you know far
more
than just how cannabis interacts with
the body it really is the greatest
discovery in medical science on
generations and it's just yet funny how
under under promoted it still is to this
day outside the circle we're putting you
know it's only if you're interested in
are you you know what you pay attention
to you become conscious of now we're
like so geek out on it and and nobody
else is you know so that's why we're the
leaders of like bringing so much this
information to today you know but but
you know that also brings me to the Jean
McPartland paper care and feeding of the
endocannabinoids system because when you
start to understand okay no mysticism is
like master regulator system that helps
to bring about homeostasis among all our
systems in our body you know and it's
it's so crazy how somehow intuitively
stoners and hippies had it right all
along you know because in the paper it
shows like how certain you know exercise
you know things do you know yoga and
like you know aerobic activity up
regulate your cb1 and cb2 receptor stuff
what have you you know it's like through
kind of doing things like traditional
Chinese medicine complementary
alternative medicine things like
acupuncture there's all this research
coming about how the endocannabinoids
system is being stimulated in all these
ways from it you know and like eating
probiotics and drinking like kombucha
and sauerkraut juice you know it's like
it's really funny how it all kind of
comes back to show that you know these
alternative ways are actually kind of
supportive of this like you know balance
in our life I would be surprised I would
be surprised if there's not a bell curve
when it comes to endocannabinoid
deficiency meaning that the other side
of the bell curve is over the
stimulation of the endocannabinoid
system and positive from having too much
anand amide or some of the other
endocannabinoid natural endocannabinoids
I wouldn't be surprised if there's
disorders connected with the too much
right well you know and and that's I
mean too much fog you know fog which is
fatty acid one of the enzymes that
breaks down an and amide and you know I
was ma GL is what breaks down to AG but
too far they're finding you know in you
know elevated levels in the gut
of patients that have certain irritable
bowel and gastrointestinal tract
disorder conditions like Crohn's ideas
colitis what have you and you know sort
of seems like there's some type of
dysbiosis of your new family system in
the final also with those same patients
they're finding out that what are the
most effective therapies is hypnosis
which to me implies that they are
creating the stress internally that is
causing the disorder rather than
straight biochemically based that's
awesome because that kind of that also
gonna then gets into the that new Martin
Lee and Adrienne devoutly paper that
they wrote on its they call it they put
the project CV it's called mind over
matter over minds and it's it's amazing
because it's all about you know these
different mechanisms and actions of how
the placebo effect and the nocebo
effects or the belief that's a medicine
or treatment is going to work or a
belief that most and is not going to
work in so many ways is also regulated
specifically by an OU cannabinoid system
function and tone excited absolutely I
know the topic for the next show the
endocannabinoid system is what changed
cannabis science then after that appears
later they discovered Ananda mine but it
was the endocannabinoid discovery I
think in 88 that changed it it was
announced that the I CRS meeting I
attended yes things start to miss Yulan
hmm hey before I go I want to thank
everybody in estrogen the last time I
was on here people we were talking about
the colliders network when people
started throwing donations in there and
I just want to take a second to thank
everybody who's for watching who did
that
I sent what I think I sent the receipts
to mark yes sir but what we ended up
getting but we were able to get you know
the childproof
proof lids we needed a bunch of models
for kids a lot of just the logistic
things the jars and we were able to get
what we needed for most of the year
because of the help from the past church
community that didn't have to come out
of my family's pocket and our volunteers
where we normally try to chip in and get
these out to the kids so I thought to
take a second to thank you guys so much
let you know how much of an impact that
had literally on the lives of the kids
that were working with so much love to
you guys out there it's very much
appreciated
much love us
yeah awesome man that was very nice of
everyone - that was almost 700 bucks
that everyone can't down and I made sure
that I got it all - Forrest and I trust
a hundred percent that he's doing the
good work with it so it's it was a nice
episode to be able to make that happen
for sure yeah that helps
I think the Lebanese were decades ahead
of us
you saw that bag I had of kiddie hash
that was for people like you right it
was the it was the children hash it's
the hash for the children Sam's always
got to save it the one quote they'll
take from there was a guy on there
promoting hash first our prime minister
is constantly trying to protect the
children from cannabis so I'm not quite
sure if he understands exactly how safe
cannabis is but they do one day maybe
one day more work to be done well thanks
again for us for what you do and what
you're doing you know if you can see it
and we understood and you know those
pictures rang and struck a lot of souls
and thank you for just doing what you do
and keep at it well it's it's really
it's it's touching - and touching hearts
everywhere and I want to come on here
maybe in a few weeks or where the time
is tried to talk about huge strides
we've had here in California and huge
progress they've had with the state
legislature legislature that it's gonna
be changing the laws in California to
help make what we're doing and it helped
kind of shift how the cannabis industry
looks at the charity and opportunities
businesses have to participate in it so
we're making huge strides I couldn't do
it without everybody supports and
what's really exciting to say I think
we're gonna start something out of these
this effort here that hasn't been done
that once we get to laws written
appropriately can be adopted nationwide
and hopefully be a model internationally
for people to pick up and take on and
just allow this industry to do what it
has the potential to do which is thrive
and more importantly create and spread
healing throughout the world and just
we're gonna keep working working at a
tree keep chipping away at it but yeah I
want to come on here and when when that
gets closer to where we can talk about
it publicly and share with everybody
what we're doing it's just really
excited and I'll work on a new joke I'm
trying to figure out a good one with
your name forests oh man there's a line
the trick is train comes in original
wood you can't see the forest for all
the trees yeah I've heard mole but yeah
you keep working on I'll let you know
well really
you've had two lumber through many of
them as what you said builds character
those character yeah all right guess I
gotta take off run Forrest run
yes you're not even close to really I
still get that my favorite thing to do
though is when I get that from people on
the bonus just pretend like I've never
heard of it you know like what is that
from it's this movie you haven't heard
of it yeah what the hell are you talking
about not only do they feel original but
then they're blown away that I've never
heard of this movie but you have to say
to them as lap is back the chocolate how
about for rest of us that's good I'll
give it a six out of ten it's it's out
there with about the standard quality of
cannabis that I seem to see these days
we need to bump that six up to a ten
yeah yeah we're gonna you know just put
a little effort into it yeah well you
know what it's not even a little effort
because I'm looking now and realizing
that it's like expertise on all levels
it's like deciding to do a YouTube show
because you have a little bit of
content and you're like oh I'm gonna do
a YouTube channel and all of a sudden
you realize you have to start learning
about sound and microphones and you have
to learn about editing and transitions
you have to learn about all this other
[ __ ] that you didn't even know existed
that's what I love about hashed Church
that people are specializing in their in
their spaces and when we can all get
together it really puts a beautiful
picture from you know from seed to resin
head and even beyond to the testing and
the consuming which we all love to do
it's just it's awesome it's it's a great
thing Tony's bounced all right guys
thanks so much I will talk to you soon
thanks for just sayin Forrest thanks for
words be safe out there
right on guys yeah that's smart of
sub-cooled some cool said [ __ ] that and
hired a sound man and an engineering guy
well it's it's true that's awesome that
sub did that I just unfortunately did
not do that although one time when I
filmed with Tony he brought a sound guy
that was pretty awesome
speaking of sound I do also think that
conversation ultrasonic vibration and
frequency for pest control is isn't been
explored all the way yet on a massive
level and also vibration in music itself
and how that might enter how that
impacts our emotional spiritual level
that translates through how our
endocannabinoid system works in itself
so I think music unlocks quite a few
different things in humans and if you
study the life of plants and the
emotional projection that you can put in
a plant what I mean by that is you know
the vibe of if you had two of the same
plants growing in two different lab
controlled environments and in one
environment you came in with positive
vibes music and
to the plant in a reassuring way and you
know you're beautiful every day and I
appreciate you
there's actually science behind that
versus somebody coming in and screaming
at the plant cursing at the plant saying
you know saying I hate you and
projecting that on to the plant they
they feel it and they actually respond
and I do think Johnny yes I just read
last night where ultrasonic pest
repellers seem to be through research
right now stressing plants out big time
when you have them on mmm okay what
about around the property though in any
strategic gridlock I don't know I I just
read work they did some research and it
looks like the plants were stressed by
the constant non-stop on the mix I think
about it makes sense I think I said it's
it's in the early stages I mean I think
that right yeah frequency n roll I think
frequency and sound though has another
ability to unlock a lot of things - are
you familiar with cymatics yeah yeah you
know a little bit it's a fascinating
subject but like you know your secret
life of plants - you know it's like this
yes without adding I think be respects
even your prayers and their blessings
Tony when I was younger like 18 20 years
old I used to honestly believe that the
vibes of the grower somehow affected the
potency or quality of the cannabis I I
don't believe that anymore but Taggart I
know a lot of people who do believe it
and I just have never seen any
scientific proof of it you know I would
I would I would say it's what's funny
I'd you know there's a gentleman in
Oregon who I would say is a testament to
working and it's a breeder good friend
of mine named Greene bode gentleman
named John and he's in this whole kind
of idea of like intentional horticulture
you know and he's a you know kind of
really deep down is like Buddhist Dharma
philosophy path and he's right now out
kind of kickin with the Dalai Lama and
his crew at this big teaching kind of
situation and over on the East Coast but
honestly to this day the best weed I've
ever seen in my life
from Oregon and it's like space weed
and organic has grown really simply but
you know there's yeah that's an anecdote
but and me what you mark is the right
genetics and to grow it the right way
but I'm not sure whether the bar vibes
of the farmer has any serious effect
well when the vibes are conscious and
raised in high integrity and you're
focused on much more of what's going on
like maybe not spraying poisons and
maybe not doing things that would bring
harm to others I think from that I agree
with that about if everything is
identical except for the mental attitude
of the grower but everything else is
totally identical well I hear you
promote that did that dr. Emoto work
with yeah messages in the water yes
that's a real thing for me that's a real
thing that's one of those it's funny cuz
you know as you you know the moment you
start talking about that around more
scientific reminded people it
immediately kind of gets thrown out you
know for hippie dippie [ __ ] but you know
it's it's it's really interesting
because you know I think you know
cannabis is this power wisdom plant you
know conscious expanding kind of
paradigm shifting similar to a lot of
these other plant entheogens have been
around for thousands of years and you
know I definitely I don't know
I don't know if it's romantic like hope
you know so much my hope for Humanity
lies within the wisdom of and the
teachings of these power plants you know
and shifting our awareness ship your
consciousness and helping us to live a
more mindful
based approach towards life and you know
being kind so hopefully well obviously
we're getting there when you think about
just the fact that how many people I've
met over the years and the cannabis
industry are truly like maybe not taking
the best care of themselves in other
aspects but just so focused on the plant
that they love that they want it to be
the safest and the healthiest and you
know like I'm not laughing at that
hypocrisy because I'm sure I've lived it
and I'm living my own hypocrisy zazz I
speak so I'm not trying to talk down on
anyone but it's in that experience it's
in that hypocrisy that you can learn to
be from one side and to move over to the
other side the part that you weren't
thinking about the part that you weren't
aware and so people should welcome that
hypocrisy they shouldn't look down on it
like it's the worst thing ever
hypocrisy is the bridge that leads us
from where we were to hopefully where we
want to be absolutely ignorant is the
state of being uninformed and an
opportunity to learn if you're open to
it and not cognitively dissonant yeah
true
did you have something you wanted to add
Wade well you're on mute I'm also
technologically challenged I'm here yeah
I got a sign off here pretty soon - I
want I want to just thank you for the
invite and anytime that makes sense I I
am thrilled to join this panel because
yeah I really feel blessed by the
perspectives the different points of
view that are being offered here and
some of you folks are people I've known
for years and never had a chance to meet
with or talked to and Marcus I really
want to bless you and thank you for
putting together panels like this and
hand doing it every day over and over
and I think it's really important that
this information be available to more
people I'm really hoping that the
Chester pastors turns into a huge
presence in
cannabis world simply for the both the
depth and the heartfelt nosov belief in
the plant and what it can do for us and
I really think for the world it really
is the healing of the people to use a
phrase and yeah just over and over again
I'm amazed what I hear in these few
times I've been with you guys and it's
very affirming to me to be in your
company thank you to be really effective
we need to reach out within our own
community everything you're saying is
true if if you're a cannabis convert
already it's all true but the vast
majority of the planet are not converted
and or not can yes friendly yes all
right well thanks again guys and
blessings thanks for coming in wait
we'll definitely have you in again I'll
look forward to it man try man have a
great day yeah Oh such a great panel
today good people good conversation I
loved the way it started the middle
throughout the end of the the
conversation I loved I loved having us
call each other on the information that
we know and might not know it's just it
is true it's like Sam said you know and
one of the things I don't very often
sort of request which he'll hear me
maybe in chat at least more and more so
now listen if you're watching and you
want to help you want to be a part of it
sharing the link to hash Church is a
good way to do that if you can share it
and get it out and help build the live
audience we'd love to get back up to a
thousand or even above and beyond that
and I'm gonna try and make a photo a
nice beautiful photograph each week
where we'll have the hash Church episode
and maybe who's gonna be some guests and
we'll be able to share that via
Instagram as well and that is definitely
a way that you guys the audience in chat
can do that and I'll also make a point
on putting up the link to hash Church
every Saturday you know afternoon after
I do my wake and bake show and we can
feel you'll be able to have a place to
come and chat for the
you know almost 24 hours prior to the
show so we'll make that happen
[Music]
epic and Alec thanks for coming in today
dude it was awesome I know you're a hard
guy to get in and you probably when you
said a few a few of the things you said
today made me laugh so hard like you
said something like something about the
webbing in full web mode if you're in
full web mode and then you also said you
also said oh I was the Grinch of chalice
this weekend which is so [ __ ] sorry I
had to go through thank you for doing it
bro thanks for doing the grateful so
amazing kind of take you take a lot of
[ __ ] Alec but I mean in the end that I
mean you just defer to hey science is
science is science you know I didn't
poopoo your [ __ ] reality you proposed
your reality science just verified it
and validated it sorry
hey I'm sure it's amazing because like
I've I've had this conversation so many
times and like I I can so many in so
many words
help people deduce down to a specific
space where they didn't think about the
contamination coming from and so it's so
I feel so great you know to help people
arrive at like ah ha moment you know
about a certain thing of the
vulnerability their business that they
took to take such pride in and so yeah
it says I'm in service to the plants the
honest truth is people have ignored this
for decades it's it's been going on with
imported products that they were using
poisonous sprays to have in Mexico and
until it's publicly acknowledged and
people are forced to admit their
mistakes that move out they will not
change well what a great way for them to
be sort of forced to see it through the
perspectives of you know critically ill
and catastrophic ly ill both adults and
children who these these
small amounts that might not seem to a
healthy persons daily consumption to be
that big of a deal in fact some of them
are a great deal and I'm sure some of
them are probably accumulative in the
body I don't know the science behind it
but I wouldn't be surprised to hear
that's you know some of these things are
pretty oh yeah it's just terrible
everyone should know like that should be
the law if you're consuming something
that's accumulative in the body that
tends to stick around for your lifetime
that seems kind of insane that there
wouldn't be some sort of a little maybe
giant huge label that actually has an
audio button that you push and it
screams at you well they do it with they
do it now with cigarettes cuz they got
sued for so long now it's basically like
hey we just want to let you know that
we've got a hundred and fifty additives
in this there hundred and something
different addictive chemicals in it it's
more addictive than morphine and every
cigarette takes 30 minutes off your life
if you didn't hear that website
commercials truth campaigns we're trying
to tell you not to buy our product macro
photographs of Kansas heavily seized at
least packages of cigarettes they have
pictures of people who are all [ __ ] up
from cigarette smoke at your own risk
that's [ __ ] up they give you
everything that you should know just so
you know and by the way they're ten
dollars of that Jesus what a racket
it's unbelievable it is truly an
unbelievable racket I don't even want to
get too deep into that one because I'm
hypersensitive to cigarettes they make
me very ill I tend to turn green and
throw up if I'm around large
concentrations of them and I've always
felt like it's kind of the worst payback
ever when you like turn on someone to
this beautiful cannabis resin that you
have here have this you know smoke a
little bit of this and try it see how
you feel and then they're just like oh
that feels great you don't mind if I
light a cigarette do ya like
I do now feel like a bag of [ __ ] yeah
you end up you and I are very similar
somebody starts smoking a cigarette on
this we just happened to scatter as
quick as possible I'm a militant smoker
yeah spray ozium on people cigarettes
airplanes allowed to have cigarettes
well that's when I was in Amsterdam I
rolled up you know just a joint with I
think I had some bubble or something I
smoked it and everybody gave me the evil
eye the pier at the pier why you smoke
the pier at the pier right crackhead
back then I wasn't the reason the Dutch
don't smoke purest because they're too
cheap tobacco's cheaper so they mix it
with tobacco yeah also cannabis is a
learned experience and if the first time
you smoke cannabis it's mixed with
tobacco then that's one of the cues your
body is brain is looking for you smoke
pure you have trouble realizing you're
even high yeah that's a backhoe I'll
tell ya whoo harsh on the throat harsh
on the lungs like what do you mean I'm
like I'll show you what I mean it's
because tobacco was a sacred plant to
the American Indians and of course they
were not growing it mixed with chemicals
and all this other crap like modern
cigarettes with blisterin to keep it
burning but still it was a sacred planet
they used it they would take big doses
of it and get psychedelic on it well you
know you know also you know a psychic
you brought that up you know about yeah
tobacco has always been viewed as this
really sacred super powerful plant
medicine and a lot of different healing
traditions for like thousands of years
you know and and you know one of the
most I was sitting in
I was experiment once in this shaman
from Brazil kind of blue am I so hard on
this what you said he was he talking
about tobacco he was saying how tobacco
is such a powerful like amplifier spirit
to like amplify your prayers and
intentions and blessings and which is
one of the reason why so commonly used
in these ceremonial spaces you know and
the shaman will be smoking it and kind
of blowing it on somebody or you know
it's used in a tobacco like in the
preparation that you blowing your nose
using aren't they using commercial
cigarettes are not using say no to back
no no I mean sir I mean it's ceremony
typically like they'll use like tobacco
Rustica you know kind of grown down
South America or what have you but but
but my point is is you know what what
was spoken through the words of the
shaman was that you know tobacco is used
so improperly by the Western world's
because in all healing traditions it's
never inhaled into your lungs because
tobacco has the power to create or
destroy and and whenever it's taken into
lungs
you know it's smoked in the way that's
done in the Western world and just
thinking about your stresses and all the
things there was no shellac it was hoped
there was no tobacco you couldn't hail
into your lungs until after the 1860s
when they invented bright tobacco in
America by I mean I mean wasn't blue
during it whether she believed it was in
Peru have been using kind of tobacco
rooster cover you know same thing with
you know certain tobacco
you couldn't inhale that into your lungs
no no but it's not meant to be and it
kills you if you do and it's what it's
the way the way in Native American
traditions the way to back because use
this has taken in your mouth not inhaled
and then blown out with the power of all
your prayers and superior you know it
continued no intention you know and so
so it's used so the way was described by
this shaman is that you know it has the
power to create or destroy and it's
destroying someone to more because of
the way it's used you know and it's so
far off the medicinal use of it you know
and and I'm not advocating for you know
taking smoke in your mouth and blowing
it out not inhaling you know but but you
know certain tobacco preparations like
hot Bay which is so commonly they still
do that with pipes and cigars sure sure
sure sure yeah he's found it very
interesting because it's like it's you
know it's it's so so so common used in
so many different healing traditions on
the world for so long and it hasn't had
the same effect on just wiping out
populations as as here and then you know
they attributed basically just to our
disrespectful and improper use of it you
know what Jamie let's fall back oh right
which is an alkaloid which is again a
completely different ballgame
nicotine is toxic right you need so
imagine again the cannabis plant doesn't
have a non-toxic component right tobacco
has a toxic component I think like a
dose of somewhere between 50 to 80
milligrams can kill a adult human being
imagine a dose of 50 to 80 milligrams of
THC if that killed it would mean oh my
god
so they're two different biologies two
different plants two different
chemistry's and and I'm like you know
nicotine or unlike tobacco the cannabis
essential oil is remarkably free of
nitrogen containing compounds where if
you look at the essential oil of tobacco
and nicotine itself which is a parola
teen based alkaloid these things are not
thermally stable and they undergo
Hofmann degradation when you heat them
up in the presence of air so they
degrade into a variety of different just
downstream products so it's like they're
two very very different plants it's very
very different tobacco itself when you
when you blue carrot bright to produce
bright tobacco which is all modern
cigarettes
it changes the pH that allows it to be
inhaled and absorbed through the lungs
which made it way more addictive
well yeah it's an interesting plant that
obviously you know when looked at from
the shamanic perspective many shamans
using tobacco as a ways to sort of
almost you know uncover things and also
leave breadcrumbs to get back from these
journeys on certain psychedelics that
it's not surprising that somehow you
know you know we got a hold of it and
turned it into this in itself a lot of
shaman's also will take a mouthful of
distilled spirits and spray it on their
subject and yeah I don't use distilled
spirits I don't use tobacco
no North nor do I never did do you just
spit on people then III tried to as
often as I can what do we got three and
a half hours a hashed church pretty
slammin pretty slamming you have
anything you wanted to tell us about
anyone anyone have anything they wanted
to say that they didn't get to say yet
but they've been sitting on the whole
time I wanted to go back to the thing I
was saying earlier about about
contamination so if you do have you know
for whatever reason like a contaminated
batch of material you can we claim so
there's a lot of advances in in membrane
separation and chromatographic
separation technologies that will enable
you to basically remediate contaminated
oil and if you think about it just like
water filtration systems a lot of these
are basically membranes that have again
certain wetting capacities so there it
is a disposable again Marcus what
happens I was thinking about your
question that you asked before like if
you do filter the stuff through like the
silicon what do you do with this total
job well it's kind of like well what do
you do with the cartridge in your filter
that filters your water for your you
know kitchen or your refrigerator
yeah or anything so so these things so
even if you did like indras always
talked about having you know activated
charcoal and molecular sieves well
there's a lot of different
chromatographic supports that will
basically bind up any trace amounts of
residues so if you took an ethanol
solution of these things run it through
hang up the stuff and then just Tyrael
tested by Alec before and after and see
if your chromatographic separation
actually gets rid of the material I mean
that sounds malleable yeah absolutely
oh yeah this is used in in water
remediation I yeah I work with companies
that yeah did do this all the time all
the time these didn't oil in the food
industry as well and again there's all
kinds of different membranes and
different types of separation technology
I don't think we should be spreading
this knowledge because the truth of it
is if it will encourage people to use
and pesticides to produce big dietary
so-called healthy crops and then they
say well we could clean it up afterwards
no you know that for what it's worth I
actually really appreciate bringing that
because I didn't know if I want to say
I've done some romantic level I kind of
was hoping that pesticide removal wasn't
gonna be scalable or would ultimately
fail because I feel like the biggest the
biggest you know demand for that service
is going to be the big mono crop gnarly
guys they're just trying to cut you know
and you know it's figured out like that
and I feel like as long as there's type
has that regulations and you can't
remove those there's almost it's over
it's almost gonna work out better for
the small guy you know but the people
who are do use them in the first place
well I'm just thinking just from the
point of view that someone's made an
investment and some material they did
some testing they had a good idea that
this material was contaminant free now
they've taken that material
processed it into a concentrate like a
rosin and now it comes up hot
well [ __ ] what do they do they just
flush that $50,000 down the toilet or do
they try to remediate that material to
make medicine out of it
I would point out pine makes them I'm
not trying to say that this is how it
should be done but the point is is that
there are ways of basically cleaning
these things up so you can actually
recoup the medicine that you that you
don't know don't you think of people
know that it will encourage the populace
to mass produce with pesticides and
clean it up later now because cleaning
it up basically marginalizes the product
somewhat you know because now you're
you're probably cleaning out other
things as well and again I think alec
asked a really important question is it
scalable so I think it's very very
important to be able to point out the
fact that you know when you're removing
trace amounts of material from say a
large amount of oil or a large amount of
extract you can easily overload the
capacity of any of these smaller columns
so it's just like you know running a lot
of crap through your water filtration
system for home yeah eventually the
capacity of that column is going to be
overloaded and it's not going to
function anymore which is why you got to
do it test before and after and again
I'm not saying that you should use
remediation as part of your production
process Sam which i think is what you're
trying to say I'm saying that if you're
in the situation where you already have
material that you've already made an
investment in rather than throwing away
it can be remediated and it can be
purified and test results can show that
this stuff now passes the the you know
pesticide test you know it's a tough one
I see both points I see the one point
more than the other but I see where
marks coming from - I see every time he
says what are you gonna do throw that
$50,000 away and that's where like Alec
and Sam
my most yes I would throw it away the
hot sack me too and I have that's the
problem that's what that's what Marx is
addressing is that they're not and then
what they're doing is that they're
getting it into the market whether it's
quote unquote medicine or black market
they're just getting it to people
because they're there it those people
are turning a profit they're not turning
medicine they're like okay [ __ ] it we
just need to move this yeah those sell
in a market where they don't have to
have testing requirements on the package
or you know it'll be black market I mean
it'll lose some value in the market
right because they can't put a label on
it and sell it for the market for which
it was intended but the point is is that
I I don't know and again it the ethics
of it is that the material can be
salvaged it seems like able to have a
way to reproducibly clean up
contaminated oil that shows
contamination at a certain level when
again some of the contamination could be
there not from a follower application or
anything that the cultivator debt did it
could be contamination from either the
soil or just unintentional contamination
from some other source and I think if we
if we were in a much more regulated
situation and we the industry itself
took the all of the things that we need
to do to be proactive in this middle
ground right now we're you know there's
no repercussions but if it was organized
and we had all of these lines of defense
if you will from the genetics to the
cultivating and extracting if somebody
or their material was found with
contaminants and had pesticides you
don't even want to just throw it away
it's bad for the environment
so as a remediation process maybe what
happens is you know material can't go
into the market and it has to be
processed prior to even getting rid of
it so I think there might be but
potentially a
potentially a it's kind of like I'll be
clean hazardous waste
you know our sewer systems work in the
clean hazardous waste before it gets
re-released I think that that would be
on it on a larger you need to worry so
much Tony because if you think about the
average trash dump it all of the
America's food is getting dumped there
and you don't think they said hey
pesticides yeah so the the problem is
not delusions and pollution terminating
the environment the problem is the
people are using the goddamn things in
the first place well on top of that you
also have you know statisticians are
coming out saying that even in legal
states and where things will come online
and regulated they're still expecting a
third of the market to still remain
illegal so as much as I'd love the
utopian idea was that you're opposing
there that if something is you know
negative it should be destroyed which I
agree because that's what happens in
other environments nobody takes barley
that's failed and goes along and sells
it you know on the side on the cheap
maybe some people do illegally etc but
you know they're still not allowed to
carry that into other markets etc but
that's still going to continue until the
it's going to come from the individual
consumer they have to demand the test
that's where it all came from the black
market will continue as long as we
remain so high as soon as the prices get
below a certain level there will be no
black market because there's no money in
the black market
it's just interesting that when you
consider how much like tonnage of herb
is grown in California every year and
like literally probably like eighty five
percent of it or something like that
goes elsewhere you know it's it's
amazing to think how I mean it seems
like such a impossibility for a
regulated model to actually be able to
get it all to stay in state and so it's
not it just seems like it's gonna be oh
because it can't because it can't you
can't stay in state and say over girl
the government everyone wants cow
or like not just California you know how
are you gonna this is the problem with
these legal sort of platforms if they
don't allow for everything and they put
rules too many rules then the black
market just continues to do its thing
it's like oh well especially when the
prices are still based on prohibition
and not on straight agricultural
conditions exactly look at look at my
alright I have two dispensaries in
Nevada and the the prices of Nevada are
high and there's and there's no way that
the illegal market is going to go away
as the ungodly amount of taxation and
over taxation that we have seen in these
regulated environments that has to also
go the way because there again as we
have talked about the past they're
looking through these prohibition
induced eyeglasses that have produced
this false high price of cannabis and as
we see in these legal states it's
considerably coming down and it's only
continuing to come out creates time
rates in what are the tax rates in
Nevada because I've seen a couple posts
on this week that I couldn't believe the
taxes that were on a receipt but I think
the receipt may have been fake news
never like smoke well what an eighth
like is an eighth gonna cost somewhere
between 40 to 50 bucks and be taxed how
much how much are you gonna walk out of
that transaction and I have I have not
done than than an actual transaction at
the retail at the adult use yet it's
being done every day at my facilities
but I have not actually gone there
because it's only in one facility in in
Las Vegas currently are inclined one we
had to wait for the laws to change in
Incline which are set to take pass at
the end of this month and then on August
1st we'll be able to do an adult sale
but the adult sale tax is unfortunately
very high I mean it can be as I know is
up to sixty to eighty dollars per a DH
Wow with that's all right yeah that is
that's it's obnoxious but this is
unfortunately we're dealing with limited
cly limited suppliers there's also
already happening what happened up in
Washington State is happening to some of
the others suppliers is that they didn't
order enough stock for when they went
legal and now they're already running
out of cannabis and a lot of the
distributors don't have either the
licenses yet or the ability to transfer
so we're still dealing with
unfortunately the realities of supply
chain isn't even fully up to snuff yet
and we have already been inundated under
prohibition people were basically
growing under lights that was the
biggest method and the production costs
under lights has a certain basic minimum
it's it's probably like a little 500
bucks a pound or a thousand or whatever
whatever the price is I'm not an under
like grower so I don't know exactly but
when you grow that in a greenhouse you
cut the price by three-quarters when you
grow it outdoors you can cut the price
by ninety percent again yeah that's
$10,000 pounds that's just like over the
top no and that's what over-regulation
is done but it's gonna have to we have
to go through these growing pains
unfortunately to finally get to the
reality that we're going to because
again we're dealing with major reaction
to the state the states can regulate it
the state of Nevada the state that is
full of a bunch of wise guys man yeah I
think the price of herb is gonna go up
before it goes down you know because I
think although there's such an abundance
flood of weed everywhere and you know
people are growing outdoor having such a
hard time getting here for like seventy
thousand dollars a pound right you know
it's it's you know I think I think it's
an artificial floor I mean I think it's
true point well my point my moment I was
gonna make it's just like although
there's an abundance of herb on the
market I think a lot of the big
manufacturers and producers who are
sourcing so much trim trying to find
abundance to trim they're having this
reality check of like how actually
there's a crisis of scarcity of clean
material and so I think I think
for the clean material the price is
gonna go up before it goes down well and
that's one of the reasons why it's also
so high is because it is tested you know
and and it we have prices and prices and
dispensaries are like you say going
slightly higher or in any constant or
whatever but wholesale prices in
California they're a fraction of what
they were but again that that
fluctuation will change with the regular
with the regulations that have been here
in California oh yeah and you know cuz I
think you like if you look at Colorado
the price of trim in so many ways cuz
it's so hard to find really good quality
trim you know I mean for really good
generally be a forty eight hundred bucks
a pound people have been known to pay
you know and and you know when you
consider how what people are selling for
California how worthless you know or I
mean or just people yeah it's just
there's so much abundance of material
but again you know I think you know just
working with a lot of really big
manufactures people who attorneys who
pays 48 hundred dollars a pound for trim
I've never heard of such it they don't
know for not 48 I said four to eight
hundred pounds 400 even that's quite
high yes yeah and so I think you know I
think whenever Bhalla realizing the
scarcity of clean medicine I think
indoor market outdoor you'll see it 50
to 200 all indoor yeah yeah and you know
but but just in general I think I just
think you know as as we go into this
regulated space I just think the value
of clean herb is gonna spike much more
you know I because I think I is part of
my consistent clean unlimited source
material and I think that's the biggest
problem
supply chain stuff that most have you
could have all the dreams you want but
if you're if you know once regulations
kick in it and you're relying on
hundreds of thousands of pounds of trim
a month it's like if you don't know any
dude holding clean weed you're like you
don't have anything you know you're dead
in the water okay I got this from my
guys and in Las Vegas
$65 pretexts with taxes about seventy
six eighty six for an eighth
okay shelf that's all that's top shelf
that's top shelf so as a percentage that
15 20 percent it's a sales tax by county
plus a 10 percent excise tax for
recreational customers so they play a
specific tax like and ten percent their
it will be 15 percent here in California
same in Colorado I think it's the same
same system I believe if cannabis is
legal the taxes don't bother me yeah I
was gonna say just complaining about
taxes sure seems less serious than
complaining about how your house used to
always be like 20 years ago with the
joke you know it'll never happen in our
lifetimes then it would turn to the
conversation well if they were to tax it
you know I'm fine with it well now it's
taxed and this is the reality and this
is the it's the short-term reality as
what it is because there will be
adjustments as things happen but this is
reality if we got it it's here it is
this is what is to lower basic
production costs then an approximate 10
or 20 percent but it's only costing $100
a kilo of manicured dry who cares right
and then it will have to be taken by the
distributors as well and be all across
the chain but again this is the still
growing pains listen they'll still be
someone when Sam comes out and grows it
for a hundred dollars a kilo they'll
still be someone that says listen we
have to charge three thousand dollars a
kilo because we have a very large
overhead and I mean we need to keep our
head above water here I mean it's hard
to take the price of herb down because
truly like first of all there's never
enough of it like Alec was saying like
how many companies if all you do is
extractions or processing if you don't
have relationships with people who
actually have a material that is not
latent with pests diseases pesticides
all these things then you have nothing
I figured it out one time 50 square
miles I think
maybe even 40 nice well produce all the
cannabis that is consumed in America for
a year oh so you weren't even taking
into account Canada's cannabis thanks
sample no just just Americans whether
they were smoking the straight herb or
whether they were grinding it up and
making extracts or whether they were
making dry cept or water hash I was
looking at the whole picture and I
figured the consumption was between 40
and 50 square miles per year Wow what
year was that about six months ago I
figured it out based on cannabis
consumption when though because it's
grown right
yeah the present one okay so fine it's a
hundred square miles just just in case
it's 50 square miles give or take it's a
small speck of California agricultural
property well you know what it makes
sense Sam because isn't like most of the
more opium that's grown for the
pharmaceutical industry grown on like a
small island like ninety percent of it
or something well Tasmania grows it's
actually a GMO opium plant which doesn't
produce traditional morphine it's got I
think I forget what the mark probably
knows what it produces but then they
convert that to morphine so that junkies
can't use the flowers themselves
interesting they just want to create
like soccer mom junkies not like you
know junkie junkies well no you have to
buy pharmaceutical drugs and it's okay
to be addicted that's what I mean right
like if you go get your your [ __ ] from
the pharmacy you're like all right these
are the junkies we want to create it's
crazy how they've changed the face of an
addiction because here in here in
Vancouver I mean six thousand overdoses
last year not death six thousand
overdoses last year in 365 days six
thousand people overdose
unlike fentanyl and it's like
unbelievable and it's unfortunately
widespread all across the entire United
States right now yeah it's such a that's
so evil you know that that's a compound
that's been able to be creative and
pharmaceutical eyes because of how much
more multiple like exponentially more
addictive and strong it is than morphine
you know it's like that's why we're
creating is alternative healing world
right yeah truly they have newer and of
the logs which are ten to a hundred
times more potent than pure fentanyl I
trust those even less that's carfare
working brutal brutal [ __ ] unbelievable
it's serious though I mean when you have
that many people passing away and not
just like the you know and for me I
never see them as undesirables but
society does they see people who are
junkies living under bridges it's easy
for them to say goodbye to those people
oh they are drug addicts but now with
oxycodone and fentanyl drug addicts are
everyday people they're not living under
bridges anymore they're living in homes
and they're just like teenage girls and
boys and they're and they're our
brothers our sisters our fathers our
brothers our sisters they always were
they always were but they were harder
those homes long they need to sell them
so they could buy some more fentanyl
well it's crazy you hear about the
addiction quality of fentanyl and how
often they have to hit that every day
like four or five six times a day or
they can go through withdrawal four or
five or six times a day can you imagine
fentanyl is maybe two that if you take
the exact same measured dose time after
time after time one time it just kills
you it becomes a clue man to Tilburg
something there's something different
about it
heroin doesn't do that if you had the
exact same measured dose it doesn't kill
you all of a sudden if in fact heroin
kind of preserves people
lookey Keith Richards somebody in the
chat was saying they lost a friend on
Friday from an overdose
Richard looks Haggard by the way he does
he does he does look Haggard but he's
alive that was the third best thing he
said today Alec I don't know why there's
just been a few key things that a baby
laughs but Keith Keith Richards looks
Haggard that was great
clearly I'm baked anyone else enjoying
their day big time although you may have
noticed I was a little bit late that's
because I was asleep until my wife came
and woke me up I know I was it was funny
cuz people like Sam not coming into
church I'm like no what do you mean of
course Sam's coming into Church and then
like a half an hour went by I was like I
think Sam's coming into church and then
it was like 45 minutes so yes I will
admit I sent your wife a message hey
what's going on we're looking forward to
Sam on church she wasn't home either
which is part of the reason why I was
sleeping she was off at the beach but
having fun with our granddaughter and
having a good time at the beach and she
came back hashed heard she'd been on for
an hour and I was asleep well we're glad
you made it
honestly I'm thankful it was a there was
definitely like lots of stuff that was
being said in the hour that I felt was
pertinent to your being here so I'm glad
you ended up making it in for for
certain and in the meantime I guess well
I guess I should really thank everyone
for coming in what a great panel today
Alec thank you as well I know it's hard
for you sometimes to get up at 9:00 a.m.
on the Sunday morning for everyone it's
maybe only one of the only days you get
to have to yourself but I do appreciate
you coming in and represent the
perspective thank you so much proud me
yeah dude all that you do we certainly
don't think of you as the Grinch here at
has change that's awesome and of course
thank you to Etienne for always being
first in the room and always staying
right to the end as always brother sorry
to hear about your old man but I know
you're doing well and I'm glad you got
your computer fixed and you're back
Hastert's with us here who is that still
happenin next week that you were talking
about I'll let you know in the private
message right on right on afternoon I
won't be around week next week I will be
around but the weekend after I'm taking
that trip and unfortunately when I do
come I'm going to the island just for
like four hours and it's during hash
Church hey you're on the island that's a
good four hours do you'd enjoy it will
be thinking of you and as always I've
been from Aruba come on now you did but
only four hours come on that would be
really serious commitment to be chiming
in for like any amount of time if you
were only there for four hours
thank you dr. mark for coming in and
always setting us straight on all things
scientific chemistry based and skunkman
Sam are glad that you woke up and made
it in here for us I was happy to have
both weighed in from the house of
Harlequin and forest in from the khalad
rias Network and check those guys out by
just simply googling their names and
their networks House of Harlequin and
khalad rias Network and as always thanks
Tony for making it in as well I know I
have a long night yesterday at chalice
collecting trophies with gold drop and
blue river so props and those guys swept
it yeah totally good good job guys and
thanks to Indra for coming out and Peter
from soil balance Pro anyone else I'm
forgettin I hope not but thank you
everyone in the audience we had a good
700 people watching pretty solid today
we're down to 500 now but thank you man
holy [ __ ] four hours committed to hashed
Church one of the best for the books I
thought it was spectacular and I look
forward to next week when we'll do it
all again thanks for coming everybody
peace out