hey welcome everybody welcome welcome to
episode 145 of hashed Church welcome to
bubbleman's world i am going to send out
the links here and see if we can't get
going all right
block that send this and that I hope
everyone's having a great day today
definitely gonna do a nice little church
now I had a a Facebook link ah here we
go here we go boom and boom like I
mentioned we got a tent out this week as
well as Todd a chance computer has blown
up and yeah hopefully those guys are
having a good weekend a good Sunday and
I'm so wound up seeing them again one of
these days soon in the meantime I'm
going to send out the links to oh let's
see we want to send it out to Chimera we
want to send it out to PETA hey look at
that there's Peter in the room already
as well as Indra how you doing Peter
I'm good great I'm doing great Marcus
thank you
awesome dude good to have you here man
talk about on time bro you you told me
to come at night so you're anything else
yes welcome to Indra as well in the room
our resident oil maker and mr. John her
fellow Oh
our resident all-around good guy I don't
even know what to call John other than
over for a session maybe Johnny B and
mr. skunk man Sam is in the room I'm not
sure if you're familiar with all of
these guys that are coming in Peter I'll
kind of give you a little bit of a a
little download on them and then Peter
Peter is has come to us I guess I guess
I hooked up through Peter from I'm not
sure if it's a colleague or a friend or
both Nate I guess he's a colleague is he
yeah yeah Nathan is our a head of IT and
he's kind of helping us spread the word
on the internet so
well he's doing a great job Peter has
come to us from soil balance Pro and
he's gonna be talking to us today about
we had a really great conversation the
other day just in regards to living
soils and the bacterias and the
different strings that Peter calls
givers you know the ones that are gonna
produce the most sort of symbiotic
relationship with the plant and I
figured because he was talking about one
of the things that their company talks
about is raising the levels of terpenes
that was something that was of interest
to us as well we're always talking about
terpenes over here it's one of the
hottest conversations these days on a
lot of these shows that happen obviously
Tony starting it off while even prior to
Tony we had Kay really into it way prior
to Kay we had skunk man Sam that's the
first person I ever heard talk about
terpenes and it was God it has to be
back down to 2001 2000 and maybe two so
it's been a long developing conversation
I know Tony's excited to get in the room
today to discuss terpenes as well as
living soils and yeah welcome my Defour
20k and skunkman Sam to the room as well
happy belated Canada Day to everyone
thank you good morning yeah man cannabis
day happy cannabis day yes it was more
of a Canada Day for me I'd have to admit
I didn't go to I haven't gone to
cannabis day I have to admit in many
years I used to go all the time for July
first and go do the little gathering and
puff mat bowls and I guess this year the
art gallery pulled a move on us and they
were like like a month before they said
that there was a children's event
happening that they booked for that same
day so you know and Dana Larson and the
rest of the activists that organized
that event they were like man we can't
do this we can't we can't go and have a
giant smoke smoke Athan at a Children's
Festival so hats off to Dana and all of
those activists that make that decision
showing that they don't have to be so
stubborn that they can easily move on to
the next to the next
it's about the people in the event I
think more than the venue anyway yeah I
didn't get a chance to make it to the
camera state yesterday but it looks like
it was a fantastic event they were down
that the old train station they're down
in Vancouver and main in terminal right
there was a live event it looked like
quite a few people showed up because I
kind of watched it viewed it I didn't
get a chance to get out of the other
other out of the home type deal it was a
busy busy day but looks like everybody
enjoyed themselves and hey can we have a
happy 150 it was fantastic that's
awesome
hey why don't pee tur would you like to
start and give us a little lowdown on
how you kind of got into this soil
bacteria you know kind of focused that
you've been focused on yes sure
so I'm 39 now when I was 19 I was living
in Southern California and I was working
outside of a hotel and I met these two
gentlemen that we're talking about
facilitating you know cosmic energy to
into the plant so that the plants would
have super high nutrient density so that
way it would kind of elevate our species
right they were talking about what's
called biodynamic agriculture and I was
just kind of like wow you come when
you're that age you're kind of trying to
figure out what you want to do with your
life so I just was like that's me like
I'm tuned into that I want to make the
food better
I want to I want to increase nutrient
density so that you know people can just
elevate it just kind of felt right and
it made sense so so I started studying
sustainable agriculture and I studied
soil physics soil chemistry and and the
last part to that equation was the the
soil biology yeah a life that's in a
soil so what I did was I started
applying the practices of
the fertilization and the macro
micronutrients and the cation exchange
capacity and working with the pH and
working with paramagnetism and working
with the the energetic frequencies that
come from bio dynamics but a life was
missing so what we were having was you
know we were putting all these good
things in there and and we needed
something to kind of tie it all in you
know kind of like the soils digestive
system so what I did was I I went out
and back then you know this was like in
97 I think but a lot of people really
cared about organic agriculture
sustainable agriculture wasn't really a
topic of conversation back then you know
I you guys remember you're in that space
I think so mm-hmm
what ended up happening was you know you
would talk to somebody about organic
food or nutrient dense food and they're
like that's widening here and so so
anyways they made kind of a really long
story short I started researching and
trying to find top microbiologists stuff
again this was like 1819 years ago hmm
and I found multiple guys back then the
industry was kind of small kind of like
this industry as the canvas industry is
just starting to really bloom but I
ended up meeting some of the best
world-class high-level microbiologists
in the world and these guys were kind of
like the microorganisms that they were
trying to create they were givers they
they understood that there was going to
be this this this evolution of organic
cultivation and so they saw these guys
these organic growers struggling they
were like hey man you know these guys
are trying to do the right thing they're
trying to work with nature and earth but
they don't have the right tools and none
of the tools are there for them to to be
able to cultivate without a lot of the
health issues that they were facing and
so way back then these scientists these
micro biologists were like hey man we're
creating you know and these were guys
that were tree
major stuff for countries like these
guys were petitioned to new projects by
you know Australia the United States
like they were they were helping mostly
with plant diseases at that time and so
they said we need we need to put
something together we to come together
as a group kind of like what what you
guys are doing and what this industry is
doing we need to come together
collectively to support these stewards
of our lands these microbiologists and
that's when I hooked up with them
because I was on a whole other end of
you know the spectrum I was more into
the fertilization and biodynamic element
so I started to learn from these guys
they embrace me they were you know
really beautiful giving human beings and
very very beautiful people
so they taught me a lot about
microbiology you know I wasn't a
microbiologist by trade so they've kind
of cultivated me over the years and
helped me really understand how
important it is to add the light to the
soil to make everything that you guys
are doing new growers that much more
tuned into the plants and that's one of
the things that that we can talk about
with regards to the terpenes so I'll
kind of shut up now I get rolling light
stuff so no awesome dude glad you're
giving us a little breakdown on what
you're about and it's no it's great it's
definitely where I want the conversation
to lead today and get a little bit more
into these Living soils you know I
started growing back in the late 80s and
it was really all about at that point
people were trying up this hydroponic
thing I didn't start growing
hydroponically personally but it was it
might as well been because it's these
living earth not living soils quite the
opposite soil lists soils soilless
mixtures that are like it's an inert
material that you know sure it might
change the pH a little bit but it's not
a living breathing thing it's just this
dead soil that you kind of get the idea
once you grow a few crops out of it
you're like I wonder why I'm growing
sixes instead of tens and it gets to
that point of like are you giving the
plant what
needs to express itself and so that's
that's why I found what you were saying
I always like my spider-sense always
sort of Peaks out when I hear anyone
claiming you know to be able to
manipulate terpene content with with you
know like a you know there was a product
years ago that Remo was using called the
turbinator and I was just like I don't
know about this stuff he said no man
it's great you pour it on the plant it's
sort of I'm like I don't know I think
the name itself is throwing me off but
you guys were a little different you're
not really claiming that you're you know
using a certain product to manipulate
levels as much as to creating perfect
balance to create exceptional
expressions yeah so that's a little bit
different than saying oh we're you know
manipulating the the hydric of the the
terpene content of the plant inside the
trichomes compared to we're producing a
you know a symbiotic relationship
throughout this plant and soil that
allows for it to express you know at
least from the tests that I saw you guys
do they were substantially higher and
terpene content than the ones that
obviously were not grown that way you
know so the see we've just kind of come
into an awareness right now where people
are understanding how terpenes are even
produced but a lot of people actually
know exactly what that compound within
the trichome how how its created so it's
very fortuitous that right now the
Netherlands Institute of ecology they
know a thing or two about growing grass
out there you know the Netherlands we've
got we've got one of their most
exceptional growers in the room right
now
Oh fantastic so so the Netherlands
Institute of ecology came out with this
article recently that said the world's
most spoken language is Turkey so what
they're saying is and I'll actually read
it it says it says microorganisms
communicate with each other and the rest
of the world through smells if you're
small smells are a good way to stand out
a team of researchers led by Ben
ecology as demonstrated for the first
time that two different types of
microorganisms bacteria and fungi use
fragrances known as terpenes to hold
conversations that's awesome
yeah they're saying that it's well this
is a quote he says no way is that
limited to terpenes at all form sensing
is how bacteria communicates and it's
through all kinds of chemicals and it's
not limited to Turkey in Turkey in just
a very very small fraction there is a
sort of a field called chemical ecology
which studies basically the insects and
how they use chemicals as different
signals and so like beetles and whatnot
and ants and all those little creepy
crawly insects all communicate by
chemical emissions through their anus
and it turns out it like leaves a trail
for those who are coming behind to make
sure that they're going in the right
direction kinda like the the breadcrumbs
that real interesting kind of like
eating Chipotle with your friends yeah
[Laughter]
it's pretty obvious that organically
biodynamically grown tomatoes vegetables
fruits have a higher terpene content
more flavor more smell and in general I
would say that's obviously true with
cannabis - yeah it'll also usually grow
more with really good rich soil organic
biodynamic soil it'll grow not only more
roots but really a lot of the really
really really tiny fine roots it makes a
matter of tiny fine roots and that's
where the energy to produce all these
terpenes comes from yeah you know so
think about this this is kind of an
interesting concept that was
communicated to me recently so so when
we sweat our tibia creates a an odor
right
some people are drawn to it some people
are repelled by it
in the same way we're communicating more
that's right you guys as growers you
guys feel definitely like an energetic
communication with your plant but
there's also you know in this reality of
physical type of communication and a lot
of that's happening through the transfer
of biology so as the plants terpenes are
you know hydro carbon that's lighter
than air that's going into your nose
you're your own communication is is is
transferring to that plant with a lot of
these smells this this trippy molecule
this high pet hydrocarbon again that's
lighter than air so when you think about
the fact that you're tuning into your
plants you feel like you're tuning into
your plants you you really are not only
on an energetic level but a biological
one and so that's that's something that
has really just impacted me when you
think about the fact that could a plant
actually tune in to create the type of
medicine that we need according to our
own biology I have definitely had this
concept and thought years ago at first I
thought it was a form of cognitive
dissonance that people's egos were so
attracted to what they themselves
produced and grew they were just always
like all of my shits the best I got that
nobody can touch my [ __ ] it's just
unbeatable and I got to the point where
I somehow wondered like is there a
relationship going on where these plants
are producing these resin glands in
congruence with us being around them
constantly the more time you spend with
your plants the more time you're
touching and feeling and moving them
I've always thought of it myself it's a
very psychedelic thought it's not one
that I that every sort of very hardcore
staunch maybe scientist that needs proof
in every aspect of what they do ie I see
you smiling Mark Scott child owned it
right me too but I think it's an
interesting concept we used to grow
plants up along a riverbed on an old
horse trail and every morning my wife at
the time and I would go up and she was
pregnant we would
sit in the plants for a couple hours I
would bring my sitar and my club string
up there and play my mic friends told us
that in the morning when we first went
there the plants are all reaching up
very high because we grew them under
trees but by the time we got done two
hours later the plants all leaned
towards us and they I used to have some
pictures dispenser all in over to the
center where Annie and I were sitting
and when we left they would straighten
back up and go towards the Sun and we
always felt this they leaned towards us
because we were dismissing something
that they wanted to have vibrationally
by any chance where you grow in South
Indian say again by any chance were you
growing Kerala South Indian weed maybe
that's why they wanted to hear the music
better no I didn't but we grew in
Bangalore but the plants never got over
two and a half or three feet tall they
just started flowering from the second
set of leaves and become two foot long
but we could never get him to grow very
big there but that was in San Diego
where I'm talking about a friend of mine
his name is Bruce Pearl Owen he's a big
industrial hemp grower actually back in
the 90s they called him the king of pot
because he smuggled in a ton of it
through San Francisco so we were having
a conversation recently and he said the
Peter Ike I heard that if you take a
cannabis seed and you put it in your
mouth you allow your saliva to kind of
coat the seed again I don't know if this
is true this is just what he told me
you take that seed and you allow the
biology of your own body to to kind of
penetrate it and absorb within the
seaton and you plant it
that plant will produce the medicines
and the oils and the things and the
nutrients that your body is either
lacking or that that is necessary to
heal you we told
well she deeply hard to believe that one
[Laughter]
home it has Church Brava
what's that I guess you're right at home
at hashed Church with all the rest of us
hi brothers
sure enough true enough yeah well who's
to say who's to not say I guess it's a
scientific experiments for the future
one thing's for sure everything has
order and the borders are ambiguous and
so if you put a seed in your mouth you
can be sure that somewhere along there
if some of your DNA is getting
transferred to that seat they find DNA
in the craziest places that's the police
department they'll tell you just how
crazy that is
but and they recover it from all kinds
of places so the idea that there could
be a penetration into it the question is
does it really affect that but then you
get into the area of well does the
emotion of love affect these things
that's getting into emotive Asura I know
seed for example can pass right through
a human digestive system or birds and
still be viable that's very true
I'm sure many a bird have helped crack
many a seed all over the world does that
mean most of the weed out there is birdy
it's possible no but look at all the
[ __ ] seeds go through yeah no it's for
real they are they are protecting the
most delicate of things it's amazing
sometimes when you crack like a 20 plus
year old seed and it's just like what it
just grew that's amazing
really blows my mind 25 I still got 96
percent with some varieties Wow
well you're you're the man dude I'm
gonna I'm not gonna pretend that I got
96 percent I got 9 percent
but other varieties I got more like 9%
also but some of my better ones 26 it
actually shocked and surprised me
wow that's pretty 26 years old 25 years
old 96 percent germination Jesus well 1
33 year old seed crack out of 2 dozen
and it's sitting outside the front door
in the Sun right now and it's an Afghani
I don't know what it is all the other
plants that are around it are all much
taller than it but I was very surprised
to me it looks very healthy this green
beyond green it is deepest emerald what
what about the idea of potentially seeds
even lasting longer when grown with
plants that have these beneficial
microbials and bacterias well if you
grow a plant to its ultimate potential
the way you would do let's say an
heirloom organic tomato your your your
package is going to be longer lasting
and better the other thing you can do is
instead of making seeds in five weeks
from pollination what to do is you make
it over a 10 week period wait until the
seeds practically rattle in the in the
calyxes through the racks and that
produces a much healthier seed otherwise
when you take seeds a little bit early
they can be grayish or sometimes just
the base would be near the obsession
layer whether joining the plant the
flower you'll see it's wider than the
rest of it whereas a seed truly truly
finishes its it's dark and it's the same
color from the tip to the butt
so one of our clients of yours said
germination percentages I don't know if
you guys would be interested in that
with the biology absolutely yeah thank
you for the space and I wanted also
preface to you guys I really appreciate
you guys having not
like I I'm so grateful to work with good
growers and it's just something that
I've been so passionate about for seven
years so thank you guys for the space so
so one of our clients that was used in
the biology mixed in with the seeds they
were getting you know maybe maybe nine
or ten percent of their seeds were not
Germany I was just the case with all of
the students that they that they had
historically and this was a client that
had been specializing in students for
the last twenty years when they added
the biology the correct biology the
germination percentages not only went up
by about six to seven percent so from
like he goes eighty nine percent to
ninety six percent germination rate
which was pretty significant Wow yeah so
they were able to germinate ninety-six
percent of their seeds consistently with
the correct life on the on the scenes by
what I received were these these were
tall fescue grass seeds okay this was a
huge company that sells a lot of see
nationally yeah so ten percent is a
serious number when you're rocking
metric tons of seed yeah but what was
cool was the tall fescue see that they
had tested was normally germinating in
ten days and we circumvented that like
three days so so we were at seven days
germination nice quicker and more
efficient it makes sense I mean it's
funny that we're coming around to this
as Sam said earlier it's like it kind of
makes sense that if you throw that
heirloom tomato organically biologically
like living soils the whole nine yards
it expresses itself greater they it's
why when we taste them like all this
tastes so good compared to these
tomatoes that have come from the grocery
store now that almost they look like a
tomato they just don't have any flavor
at least if you're used to actually
tasting heirloom tomatoes which I feel
bill Hanson I was gonna say that I
strongly believe in organic biodynamic
farming I was taught in 1972 at the
Santa Cruz University Alan Chadwick
experimental garden and I still keep
those principles close to my heart and
I I prefer growing cannabis that way
absolutely well thank you
you know I'm kid listen when I first met
Sam and smoked his product you know I
thought that I wasn't quite sure exactly
I just thought holy [ __ ] like okay this
guy's on another level because he's
doing things that other people not only
are they not doing they don't even have
a [ __ ] clue that that is a reality
and he's just over here you know raising
the bar while everyone else is kind of
playing with their marbles when I first
smoked his product and I of course it's
gonna sound like a story but I'm telling
you Peter it was shocking I'm strong it
was shocking like it shocked me it
almost knocked me off my feet I was like
mildly I was mildly scared in my head
sitting in this man's living room who I
looked up to and didn't want to like
pass out [ __ ] myself like and then he
gave and then he gave me like 40 more
hits trying to kill me he's like I'll
see what this kids made of it was like
oh my god like if there's something to
be said with proper bio dammit but
biodynamic growing but also breathing
for what he wants he's not just taking
other people's plants and being like oh
yeah this one's got I like this one it
tastes really good he's going in and
he's breathing specifically what he
wants and how he wants it to be and so
all of that put together puts em on a
whole other level I was just lucky and
that I had suspected for several decades
that the terpenes were responsible for
potentiating and modifying the effects
of THC in the other cannabinoids but I
thought I finally proved it in 2000 and
then once that happened it really
changed my picture of what was important
in cannabis because I had focused on the
cannabinoids and we we developed single
cannabinoid varieties for you know the
top 12 but then I realized it's terpenes
that are really creating most of the
majority of the different kinds of
effects the people really love from
cannabis some people like it up and
speedy some people like it
knocking your base couch what narcotic
physical but it's not what you want it's
we should have the ability to breathe
what you want hmm absolutely well I'll
tell you it's shocked its shocked it
shocked me and the rush that I could and
I've kind of like I'm not gonna lie like
I don't see much of that sense like
there's but you know like Tony's got
some of that going on you know with his
with his little mixtures and creations
and stuff but since Sam was just there's
just been very few people to put a ten
in my bowl that's like it was grown
perfectly it was bred perfectly it was
harvested perfectly it was cured
perfectly it was processed perfectly and
then smoked perfectly and on that note
long rip everyone ba grip and I'm
heading to live alley to go hiking with
my honey nice you're gonna go hike the
lynn canyon falls you gonna go jump off
the falls or what oh if i get hot enough
maybe
well my fifteen-year-old daughter did it
last year put it on now pretty much
today yeah I know what you know what
honestly dude [ __ ] that [ __ ] it is so
dangerous people die there all the time
good just hang out in puff bowls and
watch the kids do it look if it wasn't
we were on mark yeah that was lynn
canyon that was the falls we were
looking up people were jumping off no no
that was the popcorn one you have to
jump off because you've already jumped
off the 80-footer that one was like 30
feet the other ones under the bridge and
you'll see them sliding off of it it's
you go there and you think it's nothing
because local kids that are like 12 have
been doing it their whole lives but then
you you start reading the little plaques
that are all around that say Oh on this
day this person died and this person
over here there's even a woman who died
sunbathing at Linn Valley a giant
boulder the size of a house cracked off
the mountain and literally landed right
on her they didn't even ever move the
boulder
just slap the plaque right on that
Boulder and called it a day
Wow yeah they tell you sunbathing is
dangerous but Oh dangerous you know it's
why all the kids when you go there and
you're like you know this is dangerous
you shouldn't be jumping off there and
they'll say well you should be careful
of standing here cuz that's dangerous
too bong wrap
she got squished people don't squish
well now she's not rosin and by no mean
am I trying to downplay this poor
woman's death but holy [ __ ] don't well
she got stoned exactly dr. mark by any
chance did you go to the ice ers meeting
in Canada last week I didn't know I was
in touch with Ryan and dr. Natasha I was
told I'm gonna get a phone call from
John McPartland oh that's pretty cool
but now it was a great meeting I mean I
I just saw it stuff that was on the web
I didn't go myself I look really good
did you see John's a new paper no can
you send it to me what you in a robot if
not Sam don't worry about it I'll get it
some I'm not sure if I'm supposed to
it's called models of cannabis taxonomy
cultural bias and conflicts between
scientific and vernacular names in other
words don't use strains amongst other
things
right yeah hardly knew I should have
gone to Montreal that was a bit of a I
wasn't paying attention all of a sudden
I see all my friends in Montreal at this
epic event and I spaced it looks really
good though I like the posters I got
sent us some good posters I don't think
I'm allowed to share them either but Sir
some good ones a chimera had a pretty
good one up there that he was a part of
anyway hopefully he's gonna come in we
are still waiting we're kind of just
getting into this conversation because
we've still got Tony coming on we've got
Alex from SC labs and we've got chimera
and those three guys are gonna be a big
part of this sort of terpene
conversation so my favorite paper from
the what was actually a poster night of
paper was development of indication
specific campus team of ours to improve
efficacy and safety and that's by Ethan
Russell and Mark Lewis Louis used to be
Ryan's boss right yeah yeah I know
exactly Ryan had a little bit of
something something to do with some of
the work on that paper or great I have
it on my phone right now it is pretty
amazing
it's yeah exactly development of
indication specific cannabis team of
ours to improve efficacy and safety well
awesome
how about to improve all-around
awesomeness I'd like to see that on it
to improve all-around awesomeness of the
plant on a on a paper that would be
quite funny maybe that you could do that
paper mark Sam probably has copyright on
Awesomeness anyway well trade mark for
sure hey enjoy it in Valley D for 20 K
it's another nice shoe Sunday everybody
oh yeah brother
let's meet you hell yeah Tony says he's
getting out of the shower here soon and
we'll see him soon not sure what's going
on with mr. Chimera yo yeah we got to
get Natasha back into my center the link
you know Natasha I've sent the link
every single weekend and I just send it
to her I know she's busy and she's doing
a lot of stuff but yeah when she has the
time we're always happy to have Natasha
laying down knowledge and hash Church
that is for sure so it was easy when
people show up earlier that's for sure
poster please everyone wants that poster
we will share that poster when we know
we're allowed it's not really ours to
share and I'm sure that they produced it
for the very reason of sharing it but
there's a book about strikes you can
that you
can read the abstracts online and all
that information if you reach out to any
author most authors are kind of genuine
enough to send you a PDF all you need to
do and they're usually there's email
information in the abstract itself so if
someone really wants to get a copy of
the poster it might take a couple email
correspondences with the author but
they'll eventually send you you know you
can get it yeah we'll send it to you I'm
gonna go back you guys to first talk
devote about when people are growing
they always say they're the best grower
and I see that with a lot of people and
I used to have worked at some compassion
and stuff like that
and then we get back into terpenes and
stuff like that which you're mentioning
and and and everybody when they came in
with their own way that just growing for
the first time like smell this is smell
some ways the best we give them for
tribe and and then I mean Paul for me to
laugh about it because every grower used
to always be the best grower because of
that they used it whole time nobody no
was not not used to but you know still
stuff but you know there's a name of
diseases it's small fish I mean big fish
small pond but but it also comes down to
that terpene expression you're talking
about that as they're growing it they're
smelling that every day and so when it
first comes to the harvest it's it's
that except like wow cuz they're always
that's always well even this spring we
you can barely smell the kiss so amazing
yeah and then I mean I really believe
that well you're talking with those
turkeys and stuff like that I want to
make mention of that because I've seen
that so much and even like myself I grow
the best wheat of course because it's
mine and it's for me and I I'm so used
to that strain and that smell on that
accustomed to it and I find how that
helps me would say my pain control in my
condition and the person that's growing
it it's helping them because of those
terpenes it's just like we're talking
about the turkeys you just its how it
helps me over there and you know yeah
it's it's interesting because I have a
growing that grows lavender lavender is
a very fragrant
type of a plant and he grows it in
France and he also
in the United States and as he does and
those different indigenous soils
he says the smells are completely
different where that plant naturally
co-evolved with he said it's just a much
more fragrant lavender but it's the same
screen it's the same plant he's grown
when he grows it in this United States
it's not as potent it's not as fragrant
imagine France is well known for growing
the best lavender they are but that's a
certain air was a cold breast or breeze
where they grow it but yeah it's hard to
beat when you find a particular
combination of soils and local eco
environment that you know and that means
that we get to discover now all over the
planet the best places to grow cannabis
and not necessarily the best place to
grow cannabis under prohibition which is
different you know that's different when
when people say in Jamaica all the best
herb grows in Westmoreland it's like
does it or is that where the furthest
place was that you could get on the
island from the police that we're all in
Kingston my tribe was told the higher in
the mountain the better but I think it
was just they were further away from the
authorities of course dude I think that
that was literally connected to that
relationship and almost every time and
now that we're in a position where it's
like maybe we could grow anywhere we
want and find these perfect terpene
expressions welcome to the room Tony
Tony V in the room attorney chick Tony
it worked
yeah but he froze up it worked for a
second and then he froze up he'll be
back he'll be back depends hey and now
when we say depends on strain we can
still be being correct we'll just it
we'll just we'll tell people we're not
talking about this strain of cannabis
they're ours no such thing talking about
the bacterias the beneficials
all right that's it yeah it's we don't
have to run from the law we can we can
the right strains in our closet now
awesome there's Tony again how you doing
buddy the lavender thing we expect
you're havin Harry for checked checked'
parole okay for 11 years they tested us
they had today
Peggy lavender in Kansas they grew
avender in south of France and they were
comparing the two all the time so we
went through a number of that of course
you can just never did grow is nice have
we tried growing cannabis in the same
region of France that this lavender
grows in that's the variety that grows
good there is lavender cannabis right so
miss lavendar I mean it's the South of
France it's a very dry yeah not that
we're getting back are just really weird
with with the different bacterias that
we're using so for instance um you know
like a certain strain kosher cush might
be I in in you know one specific turkey
but then when you use more or less of a
certain bacteria that that expression
within the profile will completely
change in the same stream very very but
what else is altering is is it a
different photo period is it a different
light source is it different daily
temperatures different entities I mean
it's not that simple if you grow the
same clone under a dozen different
environmental conditions you will get a
dozen variations of that basic profile
absolutely yeah that's what makes it
such a difficult game that's why it's
just not so easy for people to just be
like I figured it out it's all I have to
do is use this product called the
Terminator and it's going to raise my
it's like yeah there's variables for
sure that's out I never used the
turbinator now it's is it gone oh I'm
sure it's not out there
I'm sure it still I'm not bummed out
with with soil balance what we did was
we and this is kind of how the product
was invented which is which is
interesting
the gentleman or the general the people
that invented it would travel all over
the world so what they would do is
they'd go to like deserts different agro
ecosystems and they would isolate
strains that grew on the roots of plants
in all these different areas so this guy
you know how some guys collect cars some
guys collect you know different stuff
this this one of them our microbiologist
would just collect different bacterias
bioprospecting yeah yeah kind of like
you know stamp collectors or coin
collectors he collected microbes and
heat that's what you do you go travel
with his family and find microbes so did
he collect any of these off the roots of
cannabis or all over planet yeah
cannabis strains as well as like desert
strains and rainforests strains but what
we found was the desert strains actually
work the fastest so so think about the
amount of rain that comes into a desert
yearly it's like four inches of rain so
when water comes into that environment
the microorganisms that are dormant on
the roots of those plants need to do the
work of a regular microorganism in a
very short amount of time so kind of how
it works in their little world is as
soon as the rain comes in they're like
okay it's time to grow really fast so
they proliferate extremely fast rates
and then they have to signal the route
there's water here you've got to absorb
the water you got to absorb the
nutrients it's time so what they do is
they create like signaling molecules or
enzymes that actually communicate with
the plant took grow larger and in this
direction and so the the proliferation
rate through binary fission is
exponentially higher than you would see
in like a a rainforest strain that has a
lot of time and water and moisture to do
what it needs to do to create that
nutrient availability that makes total
sense that's interesting yeah so we
isolated a lot of the desert strains but
but we also combine
with strains from from like rainforests
and cannabis plants and strawberries and
and trees and what we found was if you
take the strongest strains of the
strains that innately understand that
their survival is contingent on the
long-term health and and viability of
their host plant then you're isolating
the giver than giving strings the
strains that understand that they will
survive if they just simply take from
the plant like a pathogen does they're
like Rhizoctonia Fusarium verticillium
Pythium those those strains are born to
just take from the plant for their own
short-term survival but the strains that
we've isolated are the ones that really
work together and give of themselves to
improve that environment it's a very
beautiful elegant thing and and and
we've done it and so what we've done is
we've increased amounts of these
bacteria that you wouldn't normally find
in in like a regular soil so if you
think about what we're doing with the
cannabis plant you know we're putting it
into a slowly that might not naturally
have ever evolved naturally you know and
so because we're doing that we need to
reproduce the biology in there that it
would kind of feel that it had in nature
and so when we increase that biology the
terpene expressions are just incredible
like you know we've seen nine or ten
different types of terpenes all it
balanced levels which from what we're
told from a lot of laboratories you know
and this will be great like to ask you
that most of the campus cup winners have
one or two or three or four different
types of terpenes all at very high
levels and then microdopes the doses of
the others whereas our trippy profiles
are consistently coming in with nine or
ten different types of terpenes all that
balance levels and it's again because of
that increase of the naturally occurring
bacteria that that plant co-evolved with
nature is what we're trying to mimic
yeah that's a pretty massive move a
little bit more than what might be seen
with a small variable I've definitely
you know Tony might be able to talk a
little bit better about it as well
because he's had quite a few terpene
profiles done with SC labs and I know
little things have moved but having a
massive move like what you're just
saying like eight or nine terpene levels
that are that are high rather than a
dominant with many many smaller ones
that's something I haven't personally
seen in a test yeah nope no laboratory
that we talked to has ever seen that
they said this is a scientific anomaly
what we're seeing here how do you see
have you seen anything like that
mark Sheldon yeah I've seen you mean
terms of a profile where it's pretty
flat and there's really no single
dominant and there's like about four or
five or maybe as many like you say is
eight or nine but not small amounts
still larger dominant amounts yeah so
what are what's the overall level of
terpenes so are you looking at basically
a lower level of all of them or you're
bringing up everything to just a higher
level so you're not exactly telling me
yeah I'm sorry to not scientifically
equate it so so on a percentage basis
what you find what we normally find on a
micro dose is under 0.1% right so like
for instance let's see a lot of of
strains we'll have certainly net like
maybe like like 0.02 or 0.04 0.05 so 0.1
would be you know a pretty high level of
amateur pain in any profile so we're
talking about in common I enjoy all
levels of terpenes are just saying you
said that you you're seeing this across
the board right and and so actually that
level would be lower for say like
something like Colleen depending on the
strain and depending on are you looking
at the flower you're looking at native
flowers so this is like a
a hole-punch analysis in a grow or is
this cured material or is this what what
are you measuring terpenes on thank you
yeah so just flour so a flour simple
flowers now was it a dried and cured
flour sample with with or without leaves
are yeah it was a dried and cured and
and so one of the analysis is that we
did it was it was a it was drying
shirred it was four months old we sent
it in and it came in at one point by
five percent told her people and they
were that's how that's pretty average
1.5 yeah that says yeah so the average
on the low side and depends you know i'm
like there's so much variability and
test results because what's dry the one
person may not be dry to another it's so
mean water has a great deal to do with
the overall mass fraction if you just
measuring percent terpenes so typically
what that's done with this internal
standard where it's normalized to here's
what the internal standard is we added
this now we're basically normalizing all
the concentrations of terpenes based on
at because we know how much we add into
that so the question is is is your
biology or this technique resulting in
an overall increase of beans beyond the
baseline of what is typical typically
observed or is it within that with levin
what's known that was really quick the
average that we found after testing 164
different flour samples with the same
laboratory and this is with about 30
different growers just their flour
samples was 0.2 to 0.4 percent so the
fact that we were at one point five on
this is significant maybe it's the
laboratory that we need to or maybe
because it was so the material was so
dry maybe people i samples that are
being done by se labs and other people
at the Emerald cup
they they have varieties which were
approaching 5% that's like seal I see it
all the time yeah exactly 1.5 is nothing
nothing
we don't even run it if it's one I mean
it's not it's but I don't know that I
chimed in on the subject matter I could
tell you that like I like it's
interesting because of let's talk about
a variety called black lime reserve from
aficionado THC is like 7% you know under
10% but the terpene profile can be five
to seven that's our world record I mean
we've seen like 25 mils a pound in terms
yes yeah yeah no it's significantly
different than anything else I've ever
seen some of the farmers that are
growing that I asked them what they're
doing because there was several
varieties that they were called that
they were cultivating and all of them
were to the 3% and he said to study he
studied he had studied he does like a
no-till like I don't know live soil but
he had added forget what he was doing
with different kinds of minerals that he
put into the soil but he studied
cucumbers and he studied the effects of
terpenes increasing terpene and terpene
and flavonoids and fruits in different
vegetables and cucumbers was something
he was studying and he was this this
farmer was able to - what I could see
from the average people out there that
were growing you know when you start
seeing 2 3 4 or 5 percent coming from
from a group of their flowers they're
doing something different well you know
what would you lower that tea it's funny
for all these years so we kind of get
the highest THC it's like really cause
like you can distill that [ __ ] super
easy from like any schwag oil
why don't you bro the hydrocarbons the
terpenes that are you just can't get
them any other way like [ __ ] the THC
yeah I would say on most all of those
they weren't above 20% so there you
could see like it was interesting
because if you think about according to
what we've
talked about on this panel and I know I
argue against some of it sometimes but I
feel that there's you know the heads and
the resin itself isn't the only thing as
the carrier for these types of terpenes
and and/or cannabinoids so you know
there's something if you're looking at
it like as a grape or you know you're
looking at it in a macro level and you
see those big heads you can see the
different varieties it would be strange
to have the THC lower and the terpenes
higher if we're talking about just resin
heads but if we're talking about
terpenes overall terpenes on a plant
material I it makes a little bit more
sense because you would think the bigger
the head the more the THC you would have
but not in the case that I've seen if
that's what it's producing though
because think keep in mind that THC is
produced from the building blocks of
hydrocarbons and phenols so the the
place where where we went from just on
this particular grower in his style his
approach so he was growing open-loop no
co2 and with an old strain kosher cush
that you know he had never modified or
done anything with and he had tested his
product before and he was at 0.19 and
after with the addition of the bacteria
it took him to 1.5 a fire now when I've
seen with a lot of the extremes that if
you go on and you look at the High Times
best tasting buds in the world the the
average is around two to three percent
but the profiles are so different the
profiles and you see one or two or three
or four different types of terpenes but
to get the plant that will correct
biology to produce a much more
comprehensive combination of the
terpenes I really believe with all my
heart that if you can have nine or ten
different types of proteins all at high
levels you're gonna have a much more
comprehensive efficacy to that will then
then then isolating you know strains
that are maybe just for just be showing
that does
Kersey doesn't mean that's all of a plan
Tanis
I mean me for example right I've always
seen more than 50 terpenes every variety
I've ever tested
did you say maybe I missed something and
I probably missed it on the last hash
search or something did you say pecked
the word bacteria yes is are you
introducing bacteria to the plant to
increase terpene level correct okay so
maybe that's pulling out some kind of
defense mechanism in the immune system
or something well it was like Sam was
saying earlier it's like not a great
stretch to know that if you grow your
tomatoes with shitty store-bought food
and a soilless mixture they're not going
to taste as good as the heirloom
tomatoes right proper genetics grown in
the proper environment with living soils
and like bacterias yeah we have us some
farmers in California that they take
their their Tomatoes down to the farmers
market and they actually I mean I I know
I don't want to like boast like our
stuff is the best these growers are
great organic farmers you take their
product on to the farmers market and
they literally have a line of people
waiting to get these tomatoes and they
sell out within hours because the flavor
is so sweet and so Gator naturally drawn
how can I get these Tomatoes I'll head
down and check it out
I used to have I used to have a raw food
cafe so I know exactly what you're
talking about because when I had my raw
food cafe I was forced to get to know
farmers there was no distribution
companies that just you know what I mean
it was independent relationships with
farmers and so I got to know a couple of
really amazing heirloom tomato growers
and you know that I've never experienced
the pride of tomatoes like almost on a
level of cannabis pride like they were
so proud of this work that they had done
they it put love into these Tomatoes and
you could taste it with each and every
bite it's it's also hard to find
heirloom tomato shippers yes heirloom
tomatoes split easy and you know it's
what you got to do is either make a
tomato sauce out of it or eat it within
a few days yeah he'd bring it in a big
basket and they'd all be kind of like
have their own little things around them
and the colors were just it was like
I've never seen that many earth tone
colors in a single box like unbelievable
so impressive really cool so bugs are
our friends well I'll tell you I'll tell
you how much that statement is true John
old Rastafarian friend of mine named the
doctor he was the guy with the 7-foot
long dreads and I took Remo up to his
place and I took Pete Brady photographer
from cannabis culture up there and I've
done stories on this guy in the past he
would take we'd be out in the bush and
he'd be like oh do you want some
sugarcane he'd pull off of a cane and
he'd hand crack and juice this cane in
the bush hand juice sugar cane do you
understand how [ __ ] hard that is he'd
smashed the middle with another piece of
cane and then he turn it into a gourd
and go get a little lime and a little
passion fruit but he would always choose
the fruit that the bugs were on because
he said the bugs don't like poison so
they don't go on the poisoned plants and
I thought that is so [ __ ] genius
where I come from people only eat the
poison plants because they don't want
bugs on their food listen to this
concept with regard you guys have eight
bits right so uh an aphid sees in kind
of like like a predator style like heat
spectrum so that's their field of vision
so this is a sustainable agricultural
methodology to get rid of aphids so so
an aphid when it's flying around
if the macro micro nutrient levels
within the leaf tissue are not in
balance and harmony the the aphid will
see like a heat signature on the on the
leaf kind of like the you know the
predator in that movie sees so they'll
actually Zone in and they'll concentrate
and and and lay their eggs and begin to
ink colonize in that area and so if
you're able to properly balance the
micro and the micro macros of that plant
what will happen is the plant will
create a natural ultraviolet frequency
so it'll almost be like a blinding light
to them so when ba that's flying over
not only will they not go to the plant
but it'll be so bright that they'll go
away
that's savage that's like the eighth it
is like a lion really looking looking
for the weakness you know there's the
weakness and you can you know it because
people with the weakest grow rooms oh my
god I can't even go in there but that
ignores the ultraviolet and goes right
for it well that would make sense with
terpenes as a defense mechanism to while
you're getting certain rises in certain
certain ones you know because as you
said as you introduced different proper
techniques like that the plant and this
particular plant loves to respond to a
lot of things it's been on the planet a
long time so you know I think that you
can you can manipulate the outcomes
without any kind of genetic manipulation
by what you're talking about
whether you're using spores there's
people that use different types of like
spores in the soil and nematodes and
different kinds of like beneficials and
predators that will actually attack the
things that are that are attacking the
plant and so it likes it makes sense for
what you're talking about
that's pretty cool I'm with Todd in the
sense that [ __ ] these these these other
bugs being put on my plants because I if
you're a macro photographer and you see
the bug [ __ ] I don't care if the bug
[ __ ] comes from beneficial bugs or
[ __ ] bad bugs
it's bug [ __ ] and I don't want it on my
resin so I love the idea of creating
this more sort of living you know
symbiotic relationship I'm not sure if
you were in the room Tony but one of the
things that Peter said that was really
interesting was his friend was going
around collecting bacterias from all
these different plants and all these
different types of ecosystems and one of
the bacterias they found was from the
desert and so these desert bacterias
when the rain comes you know the three
to four inches that they get every year
it sort of pumps the roots in
to overdrive saying hey hey hey the
waters here we got to do this we got it
and it's like this unique sort of aspect
of taking that bacteria and putting it
on a plant a little helper it was a very
unique and of interesting yeah that's
how we get our roots to grow so fast is
we've put some of these desert strains
that are signaling the route they're
saying hey there's an enzymatic
communication so the the microbial
product industry has kind of been in a
holding pattern for for several years I
mean we use bacillus subtilis we use
trichoderma we use mycorrhizae you know
a lot of those were discovered in the
1800s and they're great strains they do
a good thing but we've been focused
exclusively like on you know what a
microbe can do on its own versus what
they can generate together so we'll be
looking at nitrogen fixation or
phosphorus solubilization you know or
certain things that these organisms can
do what we've done is we've we've looked
at what microbes concret news together
that give them their efficacy kind of
like us you know the Sergi of what's
creating in this group is a much higher
level and a much higher resonance then I
I saw your website is that is I think
two different microbes
does that include two Khedira yeah yeah
they're great strains but again we're
looking at what one can do versus what
they can't know I'm asking about what
what if one of the 50 to you used was
pretty dormant and I'm glad to hear you
do use it I found it to be beneficial
I've used it for 30 40 years yeah yeah
it's a great string yeah great strain so
so what we've done is really focused
amid the the majority of our company to
try and understand what these guys
produce in combination
so what those are called as they're
called secondary metabolites so it's
basically a microbe ship micro micro
pissed
so each organism will create like you
know a certain enzyme or a chemical or
an acid or a hormone and so when you
when you have all these different
strains and they're all you know
creating what are called the secondary
metabolites what
they're if they're able to colonize the
rhizosphere the root if they're raizo
bacteria they'll create like a like a
sludge together like a film like a
biofilm that's just taking every they're
like encumbering every centimeter of
root the fine root hairs as well they
protect that so so so it can work as
like a natural chelating engine some of
the some of the things that they do like
for instance the acids that they create
think about when you guys put your
fertilizer in and you've got a think
about a microscopic level and you've got
a piece of calcium right so so a piece
of calcium could be like the size of an
the Empire State Building and our
microbes are the size of an ant and that
calcium can't go into the root so if the
microorganisms are creating an acid it
works like a natural chelating agent to
juice that calcium and allow it to beam
it's called bioavailable or plants
absorbable so we increase the efficacy
of conventional and organic fertilizers
exponentially but that's just one thing
I think about about this concept so the
root is is communicating enzymatically
with certain strains so so what what our
guys will do even in a hydroponic system
is they'll they'll they'll find you know
where the concentrations are of
nutrients and that'll talk to the the
plant and they'll say hey man grow your
root that way that's where the good
stuff is for you to you know that's
where some water is that's where some
some food is because that's what they do
naturally in the desert they say hey man
the water's here all life has to have
water and carbon and so what they'll do
is they'll be like okay it's time to
grow this way or it's time to grow
bigger or you know it's time to relax
because again these guys innately want
the best for the planet they're givers
they're they're all about improving the
environment making sure that the
sustainability of their species and
their children and future generations
has a healthy environment versus the
pathogens the package only take for
their short-term survival that type of
drought tolerance should be put into
food crops I know that there's a concern
rock tolerant horn and the types of corn
that can grow and so like sub-saharan
Africa that don't like I mean you know
the moisture that we have over here in
North America but you don't have to go
and see that much yeah there is dry
farming so all plant life is absolutely
connected to microbe life living in a
microbial world like it or not no matter
how much hand cleaner you think you
could use and no matter how much he you
know flora clean you there's still a
microbial mess in this world everywhere
you look at all forms the soluble carbon
will be you know viewed as food for any
kind of microbe and you know are winning
an evolution of microbes I mean I think
that there's more microbial mass on this
earth right now like by a factor of ten
then there are all other kinds of
biology combined so there's more in your
beard than there is humans on the planet
the plant that actually got roots in the
ground the plant
evolved I mean as opposed to in a
hydroponic system or in some flower pot
somewhere always thought that the actual
you know synergy that the plant has
enjoyed for a millennia in the microbial
world where the roots are which is down
in the ground in the earth than the
earth not a recreation of the earth but
they actual here--the itself puts a a
different type of pressure and I think
the kind of thing that you're you're
seeing I mean not only with secondary
metabolites but now using genomics and
this is would be great to get Kevin in
on this discussion you could actually
create an induced panel and look at all
the known genes in variety of different
pathways and look to see whether or not
thieves types of assaults or you know
environmental assaults lead into the up
expression of certain
means that our hallmarks for turning on
certain pathways sort of like in drought
tolerance I know that that's very well
studied in both soybean and corn what
happens and what makes a good drought
tolerant plant and I think it was just
straightforward plant breeding but
ultimately they're able to engineer
those pathways into the organisms itself
to make them drought tolerant what I
think the interesting you're doing if I
could just finish it up is that recently
there is a company looking for you know
registration with the EPA and Scott
Pruett just issued this two-page
response saying that you know cannabis
is illegal and you know the he's not
going to regulate on you know products
that can be used in cannabis cultivation
and so therefore I don't even know why
we're being asked this of course the
answer's no [ __ ] you and basically
turned around the document so once again
thank you to everyone who voted for
Donald Trump for putting this idiot in
charge of EPA who basically could be
making strides to help the cannabis
industry by being able to take the
initial steps to understand that
biological warfare and biological
control and as a level that you're
talking about is the safest way to
control diseases that could affect
cannabis because no company right now
has a data set to show that chemically
or applied chemical pesticides or
fungicides or herbicides or whatever
are going to have any type of bad effect
on humans because it's never been
studied and there's not likely going to
be any company that's going to do that
so these companies that are trying to do
this with biological control have the
exact you know this is the lever to turn
here and it's the weighted you could
control as you see how these things
affect what goes on in a plant not just
because humans like them terpenes are
there for a plant response to a defense
an environmental and saw whether it's
insects or whether it's fun to die or
bugs or most
microbes microbes are involved at every
level and everything that goes on my
insects rely on microbes because the
microbes start doing the chewing on the
the initial thing and then that rings
the dinner bell for a whole zoo of fungi
that just follows after that so very
intimate in the involve in any type of
fungal attack microbes are there and
bacteria are there from the very
beginning so just recognize that yeah
the plants need bacteria to live and I
think the approach that you and this
other company are taking to use a
microbiological way of enhancing the
soils own biome better control plant
disease is exactly what should be doing
and [ __ ] the EPA Administrator because
this guy and the administration needs to
go thank you greed so question oh yeah
sure I I recently have read some
research where a biofilm was the subject
of it that companies were looking to
coat fruits and vegetables with a
biofilm to increase the longevity and
while they accomplished that the other
thing they noticed was if this biofilm
was applied to the base and the bottom
part of the plants that insects that
crawl up on these plants didn't
recognize it as food any longer and so
therefore did not attack it mmm are you
familiar with that at all I'll put a URL
with mark for you to go yeah throw the
throw the URL up did you want to finish
what you were saying there before mark
yeah it's a little bit about water
because I think it's such an important
issue for for our species and our planet
so one of the things that our microbes
are is they're saprophytic so what that
means is a saprophyte is a type of
organism that will actually live on and
and decompose carbon or organic matter
so what's interesting is is and this is
kind of a unique content curator
disclosed here but so we all understand
that carbon sequestration you know is
done through plants right plants
sequester carbon as they do so they
create different sugars and
carbohydrates out of their roots that's
what they turn the the carbon into now
as the root does this are microorganisms
and and most soil microorganisms do this
we're just introducing them in larger
numbers but these soil organisms are
soil organisms specifically our
saprophytic so all of our strains are
saprophyte so what that means is they
will they will create a layer of
insoluble hydrophilic houmous around the
the route around the within the
rhizosphere so what that means in lay
terms is that the the organisms will
actually use the different secondary
metabolites that I was disclosing to you
and decompose almost like a composting
effect all around the root so that way
it can it can create a substance called
humans now houmous can hold 80 percent
of its own weight in water so what we're
finding right now with a lot of our
growers is that they're able to grow
corn they're able to grow ten onions and
beets and and carrots in Arizona out of
season because what's happening is
there's a layer a hydrophilic layer of
water that's being held in within those
bioavailable nutrients that's also part
of the mineralization process there's a
mineralization process that happens when
you decompose carbon it makes the the
macro micro is available to the plant
like I was talking about the New York
you know big building thing and how it's
it's turned into a bio bioavailable form
well both of those process
is our able to create a sustainability
factor in the rhizosphere so you're
gonna have water when the plant needs it
in those fine rears that you were
talking about Sam which are protected by
our product because we're also that
biofilm that these microorganisms are
creating is a protective layer that
disallow certain health issues to to
encumber the plant so that's why one of
the things that we disclose is we are
able to keep the roots white and healthy
for the duration of the crop cycle so
yeah that's that's kind of it what we're
seeing is that these plants will have
water whenever they eat it so you can
use a lot less water to cultivate your
crops so like back to what Mark was
saying like if you go to a Home Depot or
Walmart or Target Garden Center look at
like what the masses have access to not
so much in California could walk into
any you could walk into an herb and
garden place and get you know any mix
that you want live soils compost things
but let's say the average American who
has access to plants and soils they get
they get Scott's
soil they get micro they get what's the
two most popular things we see is a
Scott soil and what's the other one
miracle-gro sorry and it's like it's
it's a turn-off right so what and and I
didn't know you had a product but you
like late to the show here but if
wouldn't you put it why wouldn't you
want to try to get what you're talking
about not just in the cannabis industry
but maybe you are or maybe maybe you've
come from a different industry but why
wouldn't you get it out to the masses so
that we could correct our farming across
America I was reminded by a marketing
guy that Miracle Grow is not a soil
miracle grow is a brand you kind of
schooled me on this yeah as well yeah it
started as a chemical as a like this
just for a miracle grow on your plants
and you don't have to ever feed it so it
started as like a didn't it start as a
nutrient and now it's just a brand that
has lots of [ __ ] you know but Scott's
got soil and miracle
grow are both think owned by the same
company so yeah yeah so Tony Kavita they
wanted controlling interesting UV the
lights too so those people are
definitely making a play into the
cannabis space right go ahead but but
it's it's it's it's not sustainable
because as we know this plant is very
interesting and the fact that it will
mutate around and like it's it's it
allows things to it you know it's
everyone thinks growing cannabis without
pesticides in a twenty percent THC or
CBD with two to three percent terpenes
is easy it's extremely hard in ninety
percent of everyone fails so cannabis is
the very tricky one because it's multi
complex multi-dimensional hundreds of
cannabinoids hundreds of terpenes but if
we talk about a tomato or a cucumber or
lavender or I've got experiment plants
and lemon plants and different herbs in
time wouldn't we get start there at the
foundation of our herbs in our and our
our foods that are being our herbs that
are being grown by by everyone that's at
home I'm not talking about the food you
access let's start at the home grower
because I'm growing ten herbs right here
on my on my balcony you know some
there's people that grow all of their
little like basil and sweet mints and
things like that but they're using Scots
and Miracle Grow so that would be for me
more of a start than cannabis even
though I appreciate everything you're
saying and doing for cannabis and we're
talking about species as humans and
we're talking about survival then it
would be implemented into the mainstream
first no absolutely that's that's where
we've we've been working for for the
last twenty years and it's my life's
work to to go back there so everything
that I've done has been to work with
organic farmers we we have hundreds of
thousands of acres that that were being
applied to with different forms of this
biology with organic cultivators and
that's and sustainable cultivators and
conventional cultivators so so the
product is getting out there but this
this industry right now is producing
something so sacred
for children with seizures for you know
for for mothers with tumors and we want
to help we want to be a part of that we
want to give to you guys we did it's
supposed to be medicine right are you
guys are the failures you know you guys
are the stewards of our of our lands and
our plants we're here to support you
we've come to the product brings up a
good point just in terms of for you Tony
it's gonna be it's gonna be put out at a
price point where you guys can use this
in abundance and you can really see the
epic of all the things that we're
talking about the sustainability in
environmental and the help of the plant
increase exponentially with it with the
correct application of life to the soil
so money made I'm here for a limited
time to to to work with these cannabis
cultivators because I believe that you
guys right now are are key to showing
the world that we can produce a
commodity in a safe environmentally
friendly and conscious way and nurturing
way you guys are to more tune in to your
plants than any grower that I've ever
met you guys you know there's there's
cultivators out there that still believe
that their granddaddy and the way they
was always done is the right way and
that's been a big battle for us to be
able to transition a lot of these guys
to more sustainable conscious ways of
growing it's it's it's it's so it's a
life's work for me and that's what I
will never stop doing crime is written
to actually help us get this message out
and and and I don't have to do it I
don't have to say it I don't have to I
just have to put the product out in you
guys will be the ones the light beings
that will take this product out to the
world and I believe that with all my
heart and that's why we're in the
cannabis space is because we need to do
we need to have this in our food
right and you know for me what I would
like to add is that I have kind of a way
when I meet people when I could when I
have a conversation with people and it's
sort of you know sometimes it's just all
read people and you know the when I met
Tony you know I knew him for about five
minutes before I was like holy [ __ ] like
I'm gonna like end up spending a lot of
time with this dude I have a feeling
it's like I'm gonna meet and so Peter
really resonated with me not only the
fact that he's highly intelligent and
articulate and his ability to share this
information but that he's so conscious
he's so like I believe him I believe
when he talks and he sounds like he
could almost break into tears because
you really believe the guy loves this
this is his life and so why we didn't
want to go about him saying oh hey
bubble man I'll send you this product
you can try it on your crop if it works
you can talk about it I I resonate it
with it in a way that I said well why
don't we just bring it to church why
don't we talk about it you've noticed we
haven't been dropping the name of the
company a ton we're just sharing the
information but you know I want my youth
my listeners our audience our audience
to be able to be in a situation where if
this is something they want to try they
can try it they can do it sort of along
with some of us that will end up trying
it and it's gonna be transparent it's
not gonna be some oh let's do this all
behind closed doors and once we see no
let's just make it transparent like it's
gonna work it's not gonna work we're
gonna see something we're not gonna see
something let's just let's just try it
out I love the idea of going down this
rabbit hole of knowledge because the
information that you're sharing Peter I
can tell you I know very little about
and I want to know more what interrupt
assembly but I really appreciate you
having you know us here for what we're
trying to do and we're not anything
special we're not like you know we we've
just been fortunate and lucky to find
the right biology that is really
conducive to help increase the efficacy
of this plan and I can't tell you how
grateful I am for the space that you
give it me to come
to talk about what agricultural crop is
is your product mostly used on besides
carapace everything I mean everything is
if they're a single crop that you find
uses it better than any other crop we
have different formulations of the
microbes for different plants but I'll
tell you what it's it's actually
unbelievable how well our product works
on cannabis it's almost mind-boggling
that was my next question which there
two microorganisms for different crops
for different species yeah yeah can we
buy some where can we buy some for our
strata we have a website set up called
soil balance procom so it's soil balance
procom and yeah you'll get a feel for
what we believe a little bit more about
the technology the science I don't like
to you know be a salesperson and you
know but but we're we've made it
affordable so $14.50 or I think it's
14.95 we'll give you five grams and that
creates 50 gallons of liquid solution
each gallon will have six point one
trillion microbes per gallon and sixty
two different varieties all of
beneficial bacteria so when you
inoculate your soil like or even in
hydroponics because these guys all live
on the root so the rise of confident
bacterias they they will just regenerate
and live on the roots for the duration
of the crop cycle and the more you put
them on the higher titor's you'll get
the higher microbial titor's and and and
then the terpene even in even in a
strain that's producing 5% protein
levels could go higher and more and more
diverse I I smoked some of this stuff
and I'd love to tell you guys one of
these days about the experience that I
had smoked in this with nine different
turkeys and we're listening okay
you don't understand that terpenes are
expressed by the ability of the plant to
to produce them which is controlled by
the terpene synthases so if the plant
doesn't have particular terpene synthase
it can't produce that terpene it's just
like cannabinoids it's if doesn't have
the CBD synthase it cannot produce CBD
we should sample show on on the syn face
I swear we should make a special panel
for just that conversation because that
is that's a serious [ __ ] deep rabbit
hole you're talking about right there
like that is like not an offshoot of
this conversation but it is the bottom
line it that's what I mean it's super
important it's really important and it's
not just about tea the cannabinoids it's
the terpenes it's synthase I mean I it's
another thing I don't understand
completely but that I would love to hear
us talk about more and I'm sure the
audience would as well
oh good no no go ahead Peter um okay so
so this this grower brought me some some
stuff and I've been smoking grass and so
this is nine star flower right just
joking gone I mean yeah I know what that
mean because it'd be a call flower 1
star cuz it doesn't melt but this is a
nine star flower flower what actually
melted into a liquid no I'm stopping go
ahead the grinder yeah literally poured
out I couldn't even tip it over so I put
it to my nose and it was like like so
pungent that it was like a wasabi or
like a like a horseradish right if I put
it really close I was like oh it's so I
could hold it about right here but if I
put it here it was too smelly to even
put that close so so I grinded it up
like I said I if poured out like it
wouldn't come out so I leaked out into
the bowl and then
and then when I smoked it it was kind of
like like my kids watch out Willy Wonka
and the Chocolate Factory and there's
like violet book polo Riga they're
bright Willy Wonka's gum and she's like
hey Dad here comes the the blueberry
here comes the turkey dinner right so
that's totally how it was it was like
like I tasted chocolate I tasted
blueberries I tasted lemon I taste it
and I tasted like so many different
flavors all your taste buds were going
bananas as it went in and as you exhale
just going bananas in every way yeah and
and what was crazy about it was it was
kind of like smoking a hookah like
instead of you know how when you smoke a
hookah it's like really light like air
like it's just you could like take a
huge rip and it's just like fills like
air when you're smoking a hookah well
that's how this stuff was I had I didn't
even have the slightest notion to calm
like I had no like or any of that it was
just like air like super light air and
um and it was kind of like hash like a
like kind of like an edible so it was
very conscious very clean you know not
not super where I was really stoned out
but but it but it worked like an edible
because after like ten minutes I really
peaked out I didn't pick her in the
beginning but after about 10 15 minutes
I was like really really feeling good
and it lasted forever it lasted like 4
hours here's a pretty good question from
someone in the chat room for you Peter
is there products to avoid using when
using your products then could
potentially wipe out these beneficials
yeah yeah there are so we've made this
product really durable the soil balance
will I mean it will really stand up to
pesticides and most fungicides any type
of fertilizer but systemic fungicides
kick our ass I mean if you use a
systemic it's gonna go into the plant
it's gonna go through the vascular
system of the plant and and in the root
zone and our guys live on the root so
anything else you can use we're friendly
to any you
we know a lot of you guys are protecting
your crops it's a big investment you got
money coming in so you can use your
pesticides with this product if you have
to to protect your investment please
don't
anybody who's using a fungicide systemic
fungicide on cannabis to be hung up and
dried for real real
that scares me yeah well and in you know
in CalPERS is the stomach or profit
people use sulfur yeah the one you you
know that that really that really not
castel know but what you'll find with
using this the soil balance is you're
gonna have comprehensive health that's
what we hope you find with using it you
know it's kind of like our bodies if
you've got a really good community and
you've got a really high level of the
biology in your own body it's not going
to be conducive to a bad ph or bad you
know is it susceptible to copper will
copper to take it out no no then none of
the organic you can use any any organic
pesticide or fungicide our art art
colonies or ask in any pesticide can
kill it which is cool so that's a first
in the industry as well there's there's
most of these products you know have
strains that when you put them into the
acidity of the soil environment a lot of
whom will die like for instance compost
tea microbe strains you got to think
about compost I love compost tea I'm a
big advocate of it the the heat makes in
it the full mix all the the macro
microbes are beautiful in that the
enzymes but think about the strains that
are coming in from a compost tea you've
got maybe strange that that live on the
plant tissue the biomass you've got
strains that are coming from animal
intestines so when you introduce those
to the root a lot of them will do a good
job but some of them may die you know
after a short amount of time so what
we're doing is introducing regenerative
soil microorganisms that exclusively
live on the root and so we have maybe
two of the
it's been tested with cannabis together
or in some sort of scientific study yeah
we will that we worked so hard to get it
to a point where we could make it
available for hydroponic and cannabis
yeah so that's that's been the
scientific feat right that's been the
big thing can we create a product that
will work without soil yes because we've
we've all 62 these are saprophytic which
means they're gonna live on the root
because the root produces sugars and
carbohydrates that that will sustain
them so so the the fact that there's
water there as well as that carbon on
the root we just grow like crazy all
over the guess what I was really asking
was if the 52 different microorganisms
were contributed at different ratios
might it be better for different
varieties of cannabis or not I guess
that's what I was really trying to say
you know we we've found that certain
strains will be conducive for certain
plants but they can't be SIA family
which includes hops we actually have
refined these strains to work with that
plant family so it doesn't matter the
strain I mean and maybe that's limited
thinking on my part maybe eventually we
can do some some deeper analytics and
those are things that our laboratory
once we you know get more sales and we
build we're still kind of a boutique
manufacturer you know we're coming out
trying to grow with with you guys we you
know we want to be a part of this this
industry and be a part of you and the
growers and support you guys and be your
servants that's that's the key so yeah
those types of questions I mean we we
would like to eventually have a
laboratory where we can evolve to study
that you know maybe really refine and
tune in for each strength and how
amazing would that be there's a lot of
law cannabis are either varieties or
cultivars bacteria are strains
so so he's selling a strain yeah that's
why I said that's why I said three
dollars a Grammy for buying tiny amounts
it was strange salesman I'm a microbe
cultivator and I try I try and whenever
we sell these things I always try and
tune into to giving like a good
gratitude and offering with these guys
because that's kind of what we're doing
to our plants you know and and working
with this technology has really tuned me
into how important that unseen world of
light of life is you know to be able to
give life to the roots of plants is an
amazing thing that I'm really grateful
for I try and just continually offer you
know abundance and and and gratitude for
that have you guys taken macroscopic
photographs and Thea root systems you
know we have it it's funny that you
mentioned that somebody was like hey you
got to start doing microscopic
photography okay we see it under than
sorry but we don't trust me trust me
should do that yeah yeah you said great
idea that's a great idea that's an
amazing idea I just get bubbleman to do
it cuz it sounds like he really wants to
you guys honestly Tony I'm up here I was
gonna introduce them to you or dog
where's Peter you're down in California
aren't you Peter I'm in Arizona okay
okay
closer still well people from Canada
think everything's close Arizona in
California Santa far away Thank You ver
yes yes definitely he's way closer to me
yes that's it I think that I've got a
buddy in the industry that that you've
seen me support before with vital and
they do a lot of different work in
California with a lot of the farmers and
what you're talking about would fit
really really really well with the
biodynamic sustainable farming and
practices that
that are going on in California because
they are doing greenhouses and
controlled greenhouses and you have to
you know you're dealing with you're not
growing indoor so you're dealing with
everything that's out there and so
everything can be a predator not just
not just bugs all kinds of conditions
whether you know the dynamic range
between the daytime temperature in the
night time temperature the way the plant
transpires all kinds of all kinds of
things so it sounds like you've you've
made almost eight like if I could kind
of summarize what I'm hearing it sounds
like you've made a water-soluble
probiotic for the root system like when
we go and get a kombucha you've made a
way to like create a water-soluble
colony that's that's in the trillions
that that's kind of like a probiotic for
humans is that yeah that's dialed in and
yeah that's exactly what we done okay
just a bit something that Tony had
pointed out before which is that you
know the majority of the growing public
needs to know about this because of you
know when they're going to buy groceries
and maybe if they live up in the woods
in Humboldt they only come down to
civilization like once they're gonna go
to a big-box retailer they're gonna go
to a Walmart to Lowe's they're gonna go
to a Home Depot and what are they gonna
find there
they're gonna find Miracle Grow and
Scots and all that other crap so it's
important to get the word out on these
kinds of things because until the EPA
regulates restorations for those things
they're never gonna find their way into
those retail channels and so you're
right
Scott's miracle-gro they own the retail
channel if you if it's sold in a Home
Depot today and if it's a plant insect
control product chances are it comes
from or you know in full of companies
that hate or that channel access to that
market
so they're people who live up in the
woods who need to commute once a week
down to go get through supplies they're
trapped because what store is available
the store that's available is the
Walmart or the whatever is so they're
gonna go there and they're gonna buy and
stock up on all of that crap do their
homework in advance reach out to you on
the web or whatever you channel you're
able to get your product out there to
let people know that there's an
alternative your other than those
supplies that are sold no no no I'm sure
it's easier said than what you're right
now this is just lighting up and I kind
of want to tune into it
what you're saying right now that's why
we're in and it answers your question to
Tony that's really why we're in this
cannabis space because there's no other
plant that we've ever worked with where
you can see the efficacy as prevalent
than this cannabis plant it's almost
like a magical plant for what we're
trying to do with our mission because of
the the quality enhancement the terpene
expression it is magical hmm thank you
for that energy I love the differences
of the of the panel like such different
personalities not to cut you off Tony
you're gonna go in three seconds but I
just had to say right on for all of you
guys thanks for spending your time here
every Sunday you know I was gonna say
that like you know when we think of the
plant and its evolution you have to also
think of the actual endocannabinoid
system and it did actually exist and
maybe mark wouldn't agree with me but
I've seen some literature out there that
the endocannabinoid system has evolved
even pre pre human so it's something
that's been around disagree with that
okay all right well I think that's
pretty well known that it is true all
right all right well we're all on the
same page then so yeah it's a so it's
something that's evolved in nature to
quality human rights created so that we
could fulfill our end okay
have annoyed into yeah
well that's I was gonna say so what heat
what heat what's happened here is the
plant has survived and the end the
system itself of these of these of how
we absorb it became part of our
fundamental DNA and it's part of life
and what's interesting is that the key
word that Mark is talking about is
probably why he's on hash search pushing
cannabis and not in the mainstream is
distribution so if we look at the look
at the soda industry we look at the
music industry you look at any kind of
industry those who controls the channels
in the in the way of distribution and
retail control the consumer so same
thing with music if you're if you're a
huge record label and you're buying up
airtime on the radio and and you're oh
great my computer's about to go to a
kazillion checking's oh my god hold on a
second guys this always happens there we
go and and they're able to control that
just like like somebody's like oh I'm
gonna create a new soda and I worked on
this project in 2004 2005 the first Net
Zero soda great idea helps you burn
calories instead of giving in calories
and it was this amazing type of thing
but guess who controls the distribution
of soda so you there's only two
companies and therefore you're gonna bow
down and with what this guy's taught
what Peter's talking about here is he's
like hey listen I made a made a trillion
parts per million or a trillion parts
probiotic for four plants that will do
all this amazing stuff that is a huge
need right now especially in the micro
world and the distribution channels and
the people that are actually making
money are making money off of crap
they're selling crap yeah and they're
like hey this is great
Wow with no cannabinoids yeah okay
basically that's the exacting is what I
was gonna say it's like CRC bucks a case
yeah they are
okay they sell roundup at Home Depot
like it's a [ __ ] like a pepsi-cola
talents everywhere everywhere it's like
yeah you're so right on well so there's
so with the rate yo that's why Sirius
Radio came out that's why satellite
radio no commercials because for a while
there and it's it's funny as you study
these like these generational changes
for a while there we only had radio and
I was I was reading up on people that
are born between 78 and 83 which is 77
and 83 which is myself where what's
called the micro generation right
we're not the Generation Xers the
millennium but we grew up in the stage
where as kids we had analog in college
we had digital and so there was a time
where there was no digital phones there
was no we took a picture and exposed it
right away on our camera we had to wait
two weeks you know and what's happened
is in that boom in that generation they
they found ways to make money they found
ways to cut tape and now what Marc's
talking about the EPA now it's like oh
let's cut down the tape let's let's make
this easier for us to sell more crap and
what that does is it keeps Brits it's
about money instead of about the human
relationship and the species so I could
see why you might have a tremendous hard
time getting this into the mainstream
but I could tell you in California
versus the rest of the country for for
farming and growing herbs in your in
your for the consumer I would put them
at the highest consciousness and I think
your markets California yeah it really
has been California has been great all
the states have been great you know it's
just isolated pockets I mean let me
expand the north the sorry the Northwest
so Washington Oregon California area of
the United States I don't want to leave
out my friends up north because that
they are all extremely conscious in
Oregon so what Mark was talking about is
is pretty pretty right on point because
you know what we're trying to do to get
the product on with regards to
distribution just to kind of give you a
very high-level overview of it we are
really in the belief that the the
product will speak and sell for its
so if I can put it in the hands of you
guys and put it in the hands of the
right people that can actually see for
their own eyes the power of of just
simply adding the right biodiversity to
their crop then you're you're gonna be
able to share this message and kind of a
grassroots movement and that's what
we're looking to do that's that's my
ideal marketing strategy that's what
I've been doing for the long run and
that's why I have so many sustainable
organic cultivators using this product
is not because I have a huge marketing
budget but I'm keeping the cost low I'm
working with the right light beings that
are able to get this out because they're
tuning into how important it is for
their own environment and in it and it
it almost like relates or it balances
out with the actual technology it's like
us it's like a relative synergy so I eat
them am I the only one that just saw the
light beam come over his right shoulder
over the last few minutes do you see the
light beam yeah I saw I'm sorry as you
were talking about that look to your
look on camera and look where your
children's pictures are there's a beam
of light is shining it's shining down as
you're talking that's why I ordered two
bags a bit beautiful you know what
you're probably right and what Mark was
talking about to shame because the epa's
like okay this is something that the mat
that's billions of dollars across the
united states of consumption of cannabis
whether it's adult use or quote unquote
medicine that people in humans in the
public are consuming it is our fiduciary
right and our duty to study the effects
of pesticides on plants and it's
interesting that now they are and by the
way the beams in front of you so I know
it's not on on the wall yes on your it's
right across you yeah look at that
um it's crazy a Peter let me paint a
different scenario
yes 280e goes away cannabis gets
delisted and you are bought hook line
and sinker by Scotts mirror
or another multinational corporation I'm
looking to get never gonna [ __ ] bro
never gonna happen
I'm just kind of like playing devil's
advocate that's all say the same thing
to me
dude they said they'd say hey but didn't
Marquis to work for one of those
companies those guys I really I really
would like to have them assimilate this
is this is something so important to me
that I'd love to kind of share with you
guys on on church well they're yes okay
listen to this idea so within the
balance of of the micro world right
there's there's a light and there's a
dark there's a shadow and there's a
light right the pathogens we see them as
shadow they take from our plants they
kill our plants if you extrapolate that
to humans right we all have within
ourselves in a shadow we have suffering
we have pain we have things that we're
trying to alleviate within a within
ourselves and so the idea that I've seen
with our product which resonates so
clearly with us because I feel like
we're so here to to take care of the of
the plants and nurture the plants that's
why we've been given all of these
abilities these abilities to love and
nurture and and want to be loved and
cared for these plants that's why we can
energetically tune into the plants so if
we're actually able to to reach Hanul a
lot of that shadow energy that's coming
into us you know a lot of that anger a
lot of that fear a lot of that pain
reach annal it into a compassionate
place a a consciousness and actually
come from a place of giving in a place
of gratitude and abundance that energy
will extrapolate and then just like our
microorganisms do it doesn't allow room
for a lot of those pathogens to gain
competency or gain traction or you know
there's just health
there's just abundance there's just you
know this high level energy of good good
love and and mostly compassion and
that's what I've seen this product work
it's like a compassionate product for
the clients it keeps them healthy and so
what you're talking about with regards
to distribution and you know the big
evil guys they're they're not they're
not evil none of the humans on this
earth are evil we're all just in a
certain place or a point of of suffering
they're just looking for a product to
push and that's the product they have
the push well yeah you know if we if we
can break through to where we're all on
a balance plane you'll then then you
know all these chemical companies could
help a technology like my bacon they
could they could embrace it and add it
as a part of what they're innately been
created as a human being to do that's
that's why we're here yeah and I think
with Mark Steyn anti greed pill first
because greed blinds everybody to
everything unfortunately when people
want to do stuff like that they just put
their blindfold on of greed and we end
up with a bunch of other crap instead we
end up with chemical companies like
Monsanto selling us Nigel passe and
telling us what a great thing it is well
it has to be great because now it's in
mother's milk wrecking their best
shuttle you have to recognize that
shadow and re channel it and allowed
them to be channel it into into
compassion and they will if they're
given the opportunity and they have the
right technology they may not ignore we
have to look at it openly and say look
these people are doing this you know I
agree with what you're doing in fact I
just ordered two bags of it I think it's
a wonderful idea and I've been looking
into living soil and plants for a long
time I've only grown in fresh rabbit poo
earthworm stuff like that and I always
felt like the bugs and animals were not
clearly the best biology for plants you
know like they were the micro engineers
and they were they would attract the
rest of the work crews along they would
make it and we always grew plants for 56
years between where we do really good
plants and never age
a lot of the things that seem to attack
a lot of the plants nowadays that I hear
friends have I'm just going based on
that we always try to make our soil
alive and it always seems to be the
right path for us but I love this stuff
I just ordered two bags of it and I'm
gonna use it this season on all of my
urge and skunk plants that I'm going
ordered a couple trillion a mark is
saying is that if your strategy if you
create something that's good and your
and your mission is is is good for
humans in the planet and you like you
said they're just put the you know the
distribution companies are just pushing
what they're told to push they're like
hey we've got product day with that
product B we're gonna set up 1,500 sales
people across the country and they're
gonna sell product a and they're gonna
sell product B but it's not a sellout if
you get a contract with this with a
distribution company or a record label
if you will that says okay I just
created something that's ten times
better than what you have on the shelf
and so you have to work on something
that would be like a repeal and replace
type of policy where you just you start
implementing repeal and replace your
products with my products and if you
could find a distributor that says we
currently have ninety five percent of
the market share were of crap that can
harm you know humans in the environment
you're like great I would like to see my
product over the next 10 20 and 30 years
repeal and replace that ninety five
percent down to zero well that's you
know that's literally what Paul Stamets
is doing right now like he is literally
producing all these incredible unique
products based on things that he's
learned from the mushroom and literally
like from pesticide and herbicide I mean
he's able to control insects with with
different funguses I mean you you're
aware of Paul's work I'm sure Peter I
mean the way you put that mushrooms
I've had a brief conversation with Paul
and he's doing some some amazing things
I'm really happy for him and his work
and it's very different than what we're
doing though you know we're different
but it's similar in the sense of what
Tony was just saying to be able to like
his work is the same in the sense that
everything he's doing is is beneficial
and it's about giving and it's about
producing this information that's like
right using nature instead of deadly
chemicals instead of like harsh poisons
it's that that's where the similarity I
think was yeah yeah I mean we're we
really believe that you know one of the
most advanced technologies on this earth
that we can learn and utilize is nature
I mean that's that's and retuning are
energetic into that beautiful secret
command working in there's what a lot of
you guys are already doing and you're
feeling that and that's such an
achievement for plants that you know it
went when when I talk about it I feel
like I really resonated with with a lot
of the mechanicus cultivators though
understanding that that energetic
connection that they have with their
plants and and and and giving it the
right things is just almost like this
this desire that you want to do you want
to give it the best so that these guys
their energy can just help and heal and
give to the to the people that you're
serving other humans and that resonance
is happening you know with or without me
or with or without what we're doing it's
already started and it's a beautiful
thing in my lifetime well it's just to
be a part of you know it's the stomach
worm what one of the things I was
talking to you about earlier was how our
product creates human right so an
earthworm as it's going through the soil
what it does is it eats carbon and it's
excrement is is actually human so it's
the most bioavailable nutrients it's
it's hydrophilic which means it retains
moisture so it's very good for the soil
all the nutrients in it are bioavailable
think about that process but doing it
exponentially faster with saprophytic
organisms that are found in soil balance
so our guys will attach to carbon
because saprophyte eat carbon just like
a worm does we decompose it on a
microscopic level around the roots so
figure you're getting a bunch of
earthworms around your roots if you if
you want to think about it that way and
then it's decomposing all of that carbon
making it bioavailable right on your
root right on your root with these small
little guys these little these little
micro organisms and do your
microorganisms live through the gut of
worm so when it poops out are they
microorganism still active yeah yeah
yeah yeah we actually increase on all
kinds of worms we increase beneficial
nematodes did you know that beneficial
nematodes eat human and plant parasitic
nematodes eat carbon yeah I've been
using nematodes for almost 40 years yeah
we're good houmous the beneficial
nematodes grow naturally in our soils
it's amazing so there was a little off
subject but it reminds me of when I was
2,000 maybe five back then I was a
general contractor and working with my
brother in Florida but we had started a
construction site and they generally
give you engineering scoop and site
plans that tell you like the last you
know 40 60 years of what they have
documented depending on the city and how
well the the documents are done but we
had started to drill the piles and stuff
and hit a like an unforeseen oil tank
that somebody just buried on this land
and there was no permit for it or
anything and we drilled right into it
and all of a sudden there was like you
know 40 feet deep you know this is in
Florida so you're hitting water and now
there's like a barrier very very small
between the top and then as the water
table and so maybe it was probably maybe
it wasn't 40 feet deep we were trying to
drill deeper and we I think it was it
might have been 10 feet under the soil
but it was buried we had to stop EPA had
to get involved and I'll never forget
this story because I was like man we are
[ __ ]
there's millions of dollars on the line
everybody you know you're building these
like projects and they had hired a
specialist and I was to meet him because
I was the project manager and that this
thing was shut down
EPA everything like how you gonna clean
up the environment well the number came
in around 55,000 for the specialist to
come in and he was my brother was like
yeah he's a bug specialist I'm like what
do you mean a bug specialist in well he
invented and he creates these bio bugs
and I'm like what are you talking about
he's like you'll see you'll see this
guy's this guy's known around the
country so he came in and we had a big
hole on the site I'm talking you know
you could walk around it it was probably
good 40 feet around this thing all
centered out and it was a guy was kind
of uh not a cowboy hat but like a
adventurer hat if you will and he had
just like a button up and just seemed
like a normal guy whatever and he said
yeah don't worry about it man he's like
I've got this he's got two containers
about this big and he just went around
throwing these bugs microorganisms
around around the dirt not even on where
the oil was and as as he went around
these things hit the dirt and went like
into the soil immediately they ate all
of the oil they pooped out like
phosphorous or something and then died
and then they decomposed into some other
natural element and it was like the
craziest [ __ ] I've ever seen they ate
all the oil in a course of five days he
put trillions of like these organism
bugs that he designed and created yeah
and I I was like I looked like came back
and I was like what the [ __ ] happened to
the oil and and then out then the next
question of course came to me which was
well why don't they use this on other
oil spills and different things like in
the water you know and I and I remember
saying that to him and he's like I don't
know he's like but you know I work with
the EPA EPA sometimes and it seemed like
it was a technology that was easy he
could make a lot of it but there was a
lot of control and different elements
and agencies between the source and you
know reality and and you know bio
products today it's it's kind of a
unique thing like there's a there's a
there's a fifth row law out there and
there's so many crazy different things
that you know for for the EPA and how
they do their system it's like you know
if you're if you're a chemical it's
really easy to get passed through right
if you're if you're a natural product
that's not true but it's still it can it
can be somewhat of a different process
so there's so many like Adi does try to
get rid of chemicals no quickly but not
I think he's referring to EPA
registration registration of an active
ingredient what you're saying is that
there's different through a chemical
than it is to read you're a biological
so I do have some experience in this one
what I can tell you is that they have a
candidate to worry I have pesticides and
bio pesticides are things like bacteria
probiotics things like that um and you
get those registered you still have to
go through the same straw but the the
difficult thing about a bio pesticide is
really the the production and the
consistency of it and being able to
categorize it because you have to sort
of register what the active ingredient
is and obviously I mean this is a
biological thing it's not necessarily
like a fungicide where there is like an
active ingredient that's formulated at a
certain percentage that's right that's
grass for them it's easier to kind of
understand because they know what the
toxicity of that one ingredient on us
other crap and starters that's in the
formulation really has nothing to do
with it and it's just that single active
ingredient and in that respect you're
right it's clear that they can that
active ingredient based on the safety
and the efficacy of that where with a
biological it's a little bit more
you know I used the analogy throwing
sand down at the beach
a biological additive into a
pre-existing biological system it's
really hard in a way to your your
efficacy in terms of like a active
ingredient level like you would if it
were a single active ingredient or let's
forget about agrochemicals just think
about aspirin right aspirins efficacy in
the human body is directly correlated to
the dose of aspirin you get right so the
dose of your product that's effective is
going to be really a it's just gonna be
a little bit more difficult to
characterize if it were a single
ingredient which were just happens to be
a chemical that's exactly right but I
think the thing with with biological
control and as far as I know we are
actually part of a team that registered
a insect repellent underneath the FIFRA
guidelines of oath what is a bio
pesticide so it was based on a plant oil
we chemically modified a plant oil and
we created this new insect repellent we
still had to get it tested for both
efficacy and human safety and it turns
out the human safety tests alone just to
warrant bringing that package to the
Environmental Protection Agency who then
is gonna look at it and say okay based
on your safety based on your use rate
based on how this is manufactured we
grant you a registration to sell that
product right and so that's the really
high expensive hurdle that you typically
need to have some big-ass company take
the expense on and be able to do all the
talk studies and be able to do like what
is the impact not just on the soil which
is where your product comes in contact
but what's the impact systemically on
other things that could be affected when
your products administered I mean I
think it's a great thing what you're
doing Peter and I think it's going to be
difficult for the EPA to get their arms
around
registering stuff for cannabis use and
especially for you know in light of this
latest thing from from the EPA from from
Scott Pruett where he basically is just
taking the the position of oh this is
going to enable the cannabis industry
which is federally illegal so BAM we're
not going to give anyone registrations
for anything having to do with this and
this doesn't help the industry it
doesn't really help to make that kind of
decision so but I'm just to go back to
your notion the bio
ethical means to control I think is
gonna be what we're gonna rely on it
it's what like if you look at the list
of what's a lot in Colorado and it's the
same list as what's allowed in
Washington and order you know it's
basically the minimum use rate sort of
pesticides minimum you know advocacy I
mean they don't really have a whole lot
of efficacy you know work very well some
of them are biological control agents I
think what your company is looking to do
is improve on that from the roots down
to me that's a much much better
application than say applying something
to the vascular system of the plant
itself one of the one of the things that
a lot of people microbots that point in
robot and is that if you're making
compost tea right so you are are you
have you've created an aerobic beautiful
houmous compost i know how to do it I've
made gorgeous composts there's still
gonna be pockets that are unaccompanied
create a tea there are some some very
small microscopic pockets that uh that
are gonna possess undecomposed pathogens
so as you as you create a compost tea
you have to be really careful that your
your good guys or higher than your bad
guys and that's really where where our
product comes in we got to get really
high amounts of good guys so that the
bad guys don't have a chance to you know
infect you so we're not a we're not a we
make no claims as any type of a bio
fungicide
a pesticide or any of that we we've
never even tested for that we we don't
know if our product works on that all we
do know is that the health is
exponentially enhanced when you know you
have just a ton of good guys I mean
that's what organic growers are finding
all over the country so we've done is
we've taken those same good guys that
are conducive ly found on the roots of
those soils and those healthy you know
plants that that just are healthy and
we've just increased them and we're
adding them to the cannabis plant and
larger number so they're the same
strains that you could just pull right
out of the soil you can eat them you
know and and and from that from the
EPA's standpoint you know they're okay
with that right now so mycorrhizae but
bacillus subtilis all these strains
they're getting out there and and people
are starting to really see the benefit
of adding probiotics to their plants
just like we do our own bodies and
believe it or not as you do that a lot
of the strains and what they'll create
will actually enhance the natural
strains that are found in that that
environment that you're cultivating in
you know it's almost like one talks to
the other and they all kind of come come
alive again and they're there they're
ready and so that's just a absolute lot
to do with the minimal capacity of a lot
more holding capacity and what you're
doing is you're populating the biome
down there that again creates as well as
it consumes and so now I totally believe
in the approach you're taking in you
know wish you all the best in trying to
get these products distributed real
quick in districts yeah so that's been
kind of the interesting thing I'm really
trying to keep the price low I mean
that's that's the goal with this thing
like I'm trying to stick to our roots
which is to be able to give this product
to the cannabis cultivator at an
affordable price we're not here to you
know rape the market or or like you know
take
Vantage of the margins that you guys are
making you know I studied the industry I
know that the margins aren't epic you
know so we're not here to you know but
we are here to utilize the connection
that you guys have and the fact that you
guys believe can believe in the biology
because you can see it so well within
your tripping profile and so so for us
we know we're gonna grow we're gonna be
able to get the product out on its own
accord because of the efficacy I mean in
30 days you can see what this product
will do I mean it'll be a parent and
with that being said once we once we're
able to get enough people and and good
growers and you know good energies
involved in this it'll just naturally
spread and and a lot of those
distribution channels and business and
economic models you know hopefully we'll
be able to circumvent a lot of that and
price low if I grow big I'm gonna try
and keep this price even lower you know
so that he gets out even more and more
and more because adding life to the soil
is is conducive to our long-term
sustainment so my job is to give and I
want to align with other givers it's how
I was raised maybe I was raised by an
Italian mother taught me to just give
you know but that's that's how I do it
and that's how I hope the people that I
align with will give will pay it forward
and and and there won't be just one
channel of energy it will be an
awareness where we all realize we are
that light and if we grasp onto it and
continue to give and take care of our
plants and virtue our environment will
be here forever for a long time and will
and we will have a light beacon shine in
this galaxy
you know if we're able to really heal
and nurture that environment with
compassion we all want to do that we
just need the tools to do it and the
tools that we have you know have been
involved right now and we're finding
that they're not working very well hey I
wanted to welcome chimera to the room he
popped in a little while ago and it's
been nice and quiet not to disturb him
how you doing there chimera not too bad
excellent conversation really great con
rebuke Peter thank you camera yeah
really cool so camera just got back from
the event out in what was at the ice ers
or the i-r-s see ers have annoyed
Research Society they have a conference
every year with all the top minds in the
from the neuroscience field that are
studying cannabinoid receptors and how
you know how the cannabinoid receptors
and all the different all the entire
endocannabinoid system really works and
so it's a lot of it's a lot of synthetic
compounds and my studies and all that
kind of everything but they also look at
you know cannabis a little bit or as
many really big talks on cannabis there
was a bunch of posters on cannabis and
then mark where and you know all those
folks did some presentations on all the
human studies that are being done so
it's it's really interesting
conference people don't typically they
ask you not to share the info because
it's such a small community what what it
is is people you know they all get
together in their shape they share their
data before it gets published and that
helps kind of self peer review the
community but you know they don't people
don't really like it when you share
their their info but I did get
permission from one of the groups to
share something awesome so yeah how you
guys all do it doing pretty good you
know it's been a pretty good
conversation about bacteria and terpenes
and Sam had a really good sort of point
talking about the sin face and you know
whether if the synthase isn't there you
you know you're not going to get that
particular production of that this
cannabinoid or that terpene maybe
another conversation for another day you
might want to be a part of y'all have to
review what he said so I know the
conversation absolutely so this one of
you guys can actually see the screen I'm
sharing at this point in time oh yeah
okay so we just try and make it nice and
big actually I'm gonna go about this
different
so there's a company called nae pro
research they're based down in
California and they do support for
cultivators and dispensaries and some
people might know of a company called
fight X which is Ethan Rio sales company
and they they approached this whole
terpene thing trying to figure out a
terpene classes it was it was mentioned
briefly on church last week so I just
wanted to put up the analytical method
that they used some people have an
understanding and they can go and look
it up and you know see that this is the
this is the method here that they use
that for all the all the work that's
going to follow hmm
it's called a development of about and
validation of a reliable and robust
method for the analysis of cannabinoids
and terpenoids I'm familiar with this
paper great yeah it's a great paper it's
really easy it's really the first paper
where they showed a very you know
laborious method for actually
quantifying terpenes the way that we
quantify cannabinoids a lot of the
previous works were I don't know mark
shall dawn might care to comment on this
but I think there are really more
approximations well we were doing pretty
much what they did and we were doing it
20 years earlier we were using the GCF
ID to determine terpene yes the
statistical robustness of this
particular paper is pretty solid and
yeah I guess my comment was predicated
on the fact that terpene analysis in
cannabis has been done for you know more
over than half a century now so I mean
the first people to look at it you know
where it was early on just to sort of do
it in a very descriptive way but then it
was actually you know isolated and
things were fractionated and Inter pians
were sort of you know became more
prevalent I guess when Ethan and others
started looking at the the so-called
entourage effect
right and I think what since this
analysis method apart is that it was the
really the first method to robustly
quantify terpenes you know per milligram
in a sample would you say that's true
mark mm-hmm yeah maybe yeah at that
would statistics statistically valid
yeah yeah because people have measured
again I go back to the papers from the
mid-70s where people did measure that
but you know this is just more
statistically robust on modern
fermentation and you reviewed by a more
knowledgeable peer I agree this is that
it'll have to agree also because 20
years ago this is basically the
methodology we were using but and the
reason we came to that conclusion was by
talking to the very top people in the
field of terpene analysis being done
with cannabis mmm-hmm
and when they carried it out to this end
and published in 2005 yeah they came to
a very similar conclusion absolutely
yeah I've seen this one too this this is
it does give you the quantified of like
milligrams it and everything interesting
so this page is good it's good we all
agree this paper is to help is this
going to be like the method that labs in
the future will will use to know it's
what they should use Yeah right that's
one method yeah these things always
develop over time but the one of the
interesting thing in headspace analysis
algorithms into the nut modern cannabis
instrumentation that's being sold these
are shimasu instruments but both shimasu
and Agilent instruments do make
basically the same the thing that
measured it's basically the volatile so
if you're gonna be measuring either a
sample if you're rejecting it or if
you're just measuring headspace I think
headspace is really cool if you can do a
temperature ramp especially with hash
because you can look look to see what
kind of volatilization of the terpenes
actually getting because you know that
you know everything that goes through a
GC is being heated up and so there is
some chemistry that could happen at
these temperatures with these fragile
molecules yeah and I've got something
else to talk about on that topic they
also tested headspace analysis and found
it appropriate for if you want to
determine what your terpene percentages
and profiles are yeah I was thinking
kind of like what what Marcus and I have
discussed in previous episodes with the
serfs so if you wanted to like multiple
eyes off of like a titanium versus a you
know ceramic versus the different types
of impact on what the headspace
molecules can be just because of the
different yeah you know clean services
whether or not it's there's a few
differences it would be interesting to
determine what those are yeah absolutely
absolutely you know just like when I
make water hash certain terpenes stay
present right till the end and they're
profound and they're loud and other ones
get washed away in the water
it would be interesting to see if there
are certain terpenes that are more
easily preserved from surface he markets
to to taste you know versus other ones
that go ahead ever so this is kind of
goes back to that cannabinoid water
thing has anyone tested their hash water
for you know what trace amounts of
cannabinoids or terpenes might be in
there and is there a product concept
around you know spent water from hashing
operations that could be I'm not
thinking about maybe for a human
consumable but we were talking about a
little bit on the facebook chat which
was maybe putting it into animal feed in
animal food because it's giving him some
sort of phytochemical extract fraction
god knows what the hell's in there but I
would say this much without being you
know even having a sign
degree without knowing much about much
any old human you know especially if you
have a fondness for cannabis if you
smell the cold bubble water and even
taste it
it's just good long conversation the
other day space and I'm just drinking
the water and just drink the water that
comes out of it it'll give you you know
different rinses the first rinse versus
the second have you ever tested to see
like how much cannabinoids I mean be
that cannabinoids are not water-soluble
but that's a matter of well it depends
if we're looking at ppb and ppm levels
can we find cannabinoids because this
cannabinoid water that is being sold for
60 bucks a case I you know again if you
do the calculation and try to figure out
they would have to drink of that water
to get like an efficacious dose for like
an epilepsy patient right it would be
like a train car full of water I mean
there's there's not enough cannabinoid
in some of those now the questions aside
on whether or not that actually has some
type of you know homeopathic biological
efficacy in the body when you're just
drinking water that has trace amounts of
well AB annoyed let me let me say this
mark now recently Tony sent me the
terpene sugars and the terpene syrups
and I guess I put a glass full of water
and tried the terpene syrup and put a
little of the the xylitol the turqu
sugar as he calls it in there and he's
like yeah I have a sip I'm like oh yeah
wow that's tasty well yeah it kind of
reminded me of bubble water to a degree
other than the fact it was totally clean
and the way it dispersed was alien like
it was like what [ __ ] it's just like I
dropped this syrup in and it just turned
into these little worms and then the
worms turned into blur and then all of a
sudden the water kind of was a little
foggy I was like that's [ __ ] trippy
anyway I tasted this [ __ ] I you know
he's talking to me on the phone
oh that's neat oh yeah it tastes really
good well I sit down at my desk and I'm
like hi okay
I'm hot I'm like what the [ __ ] I'm like
dude I almost feel like the way I feel
like when you heat mushrooms and you're
not quite sure you know but you know
you're about to get there like it was a
climbing sort of like what's crazy about
that as we as far as the terpenes are
conserved trying to find a way to get
them to go into water the right way but
without using as much to bring the price
way down and not have any THC or CBD but
then as we got to that pure level
something happens because it's like okay
well if terpenes are found in fruits and
vegetables and cannabis and they
definitely play a significant part in
our endocannabinoid system whatever
they're turning on whatever they're
doing I found water was a very water or
liquids was a really good way was a
really good way have you ever tried
before we get too deep into the
conversation I want to reiterate that
okay I'm not claiming the terpenes
themselves got me high I'm always
dabbing all day long so I had victim
tonight yeah I had dabbed fifteen or
twenty minutes prior but listen I
understand the feeling and the
difference from that dab and then 15
minutes later drinking this Turkey and
water especially without any like he
wasn't like oh how do you feel how do
you feel I told him I was like dude I
feel high and he's like well you know we
talked about modulation I mean you're
obviously your body is full of
cannabinoids right now don't you think
that there would and I didn't think that
there would be not the same way I smoke
and experience it yeah but maybe maybe
[ __ ] it was undeniable in your
particular case the water soluble
fraction unlocks something you know I
have no idea it's not that I did it go
ahead yeah I was just gonna say now the
water that we're talking about from the
hash there's a there's another market to
it you know there's a there's a ever
there's ever booming markets in
California what we're talking about
terpenes and fragrances and if he pulls
up that other chart
okay so you see so there was another
chart that chimera had that he didn't
want to show us it was like
color-coordinated maybe if you could
show us that one real quick yeah there
you go
well it's down a little bit oh he missed
it now there was another one there was a
different chart you had that you didn't
want to show us yet but this is good
enough this is fine so essentially
what's happening is like I you know it's
a Trader Joe's I got some water that had
like lemon and ginger natural flavoring
in water added the Jack Frost to it and
I tried the Jack Frost on its own in
water and then I tried it paired with
lemon and ginger okay which is you could
see the lemon that's on this chart and
there was another different it was
another slightly different feeling so
and I didn't do it right away I tried
them you know spaced out different
different days so I can tell you that
there is some something happening on a
level there it would be interesting to
pair it with probiotics and terpenes now
that we're talking about probiotics and
what what profound effects we could work
on in the gut for people that have leaky
gut IBS Crohn's poor digestive systems
not functioning properly enzymes but you
know ultimately these the the the water
that's coming from the hash water will
have a different lots of different
markets so there's there's people
selling rose water hydrosol sprays just
for your face like it's not it's not in
the men's industry as much but you know
somebody sprayed me with like a like a
rose water with some kind of cannabis
hydrosol in the face you know and I was
like oh that's really Pleasant you know
I was like a mist
so there's definitely when you're
talking about not just drinking it but
definitely something in the hash water
that's fragrance it's it's really
Pleasant it's nice it could be used as
maybe bong water it could be used as a
spray but I'm definitely going to the
next step that I'm going to do is test
the flower test the resin that's made
from the flower with all of the microns
that have been separated dry the flower
out test that dried flower and then take
that water like you just said and test
that for cannabinoids and test that for
terpenes and then I'm going to vac
freeze that and try to separate the
water out and it's it there are people
that are boiling that with a sill but
I'm gonna try to do without any
temperatures and then I could test
everything and then maybe we would have
something a little bit I don't make
let's make some space for Ryan for a
second so he can yeah I mean something
yeah go for it they tied back to that
but yes opening are you there Ryan he's
there he's opening opening well I think
it comes back to the lobby part I'll
call back and what the significance of
whether his first opening conversation
was the testing factors you know so we
have to get an accurate way to test
these things and and really be have a
standard you know so that like Aaron
says oh that's you're using this
equipment with this headspace with this
thing this is the standard these two the
two discussed in the paper the GCF ID
and the HPLC method that's a really good
start at that kind of a thing but it
would have to be widely used before it's
a standardized method so yeah I know it
was a little bit drawn-out and like we
can tend to get a little bit distracted
but I just I hope you guys can just kind
of follow with me cuz I'm trying to
paint like a long story picture so that
you can see the whole process of how
these guys went about this work so
anyway this is the analytical method we
talked about a little bit and they use
it to generate a lab report format
called the phyto fax okay so these here
are fight this is a spy no fax the phyto
fax layout okay and there's a webpage
that's called fight Oh fax dot info and
you can go and plug in like blue green
or P or you know some of these keywords
push and you'll start seeing all the
final Prats final prints come up okay
though the final print is a really
or the photo facts are really
interesting lab report format that
provides information on you know
obviously flour samples and hatch
samples or even terpene samples and so
it consists of this bar graph on top
which shows your quantified levels of
cannabinoids terpenoids moisture content
hmm say you got see you actually you can
see that like this one is a twelve point
three twelve point three six percent
total cannabinoids one point three four
percent total terpene complement and
it's just under seven percent moisture
the second part here is called what they
call the canna dial and it represents
the ratio of the top to terpene or the
top you cannabinoid sorry so in this
case it's the small sliver is CBG acid
and the big piece of the pie is THC acid
okay then we go down at the bottom and
we've got which is essentially a terpene
fingerprint that's done based on color
and it's a really interesting way to
look at it I know when you first look at
it you don't really it doesn't make it
doesn't make a whole lot of sense but
eventually what happens is you learn the
colors of the terpenes yeah and you
don't have to go back and read like you
know you'll know that limonene for
example is yellow right the Pennines are
green little all is this like purple
color and Meers through this lavender
kind of color and miR seen is this more
dark maroon kind of color dude I love it
they've taken a page out of the bubble
bag page but yeah you're right it's in
that same way that you know that the
color right the 73 is the yellow the 19
yeah you don't have to go and look it up
every time once you see the yellow bag
you just know that's the 73 exactly so
you know it's not like SC labs format
where they have you know they actually
demonstrate 34 or 32 or whatever it is
terpenes on a graph
these guys are limited to 17 because the
17 these 17 are all known to be
pharmacologically active for one but two
they're also the most prevalent ones
appear in like the majority of cannabis
samples okay and so they're the most
useful for discriminating a class system
you can use to separate you know what we
the wine analogy before it separates
like a merlot from a Pinot Noir from a
Shiraz right mm-hmm
so these this terpene data you see here
at the bottom is actually what the aroma
and the entre so you can see this left
side of this panel here is the aroma and
the flavor you can see there's two
different graphs laid over top of each
other and then the right panel is the
predicted entourage effect from the
flower that fascinates me right there
that's interesting all right this is
super coming this is it is gonna be the
way of the future you know because
people you can go into a dispensary I
really like that profile of the plant
and then you can say you know this is
the type of effect that it's gonna have
so it's super cool check out the web
page again it's phyto facts dot info
oops
phyto facts so you think most
laboratories would be able to adopt
something like like that type of
disclosure of information within their
license their methodology and they're
there they're fine oh packs you can
license a permit nice very user friendly
which is nice so for example I just
searched dream to pull up like blue
dreams but like tears there's a bunch of
different varieties that are all based
on different blue dream hybrids it looks
like but so we'll just look at blue
dream for a second so you can see again
mere scene is this purple one at the
bottom it's the dominant terpene which
is really City you know a sedative right
as I said a sedative terpene and then
this sample has more pineys than the
last one and actually very little lemony
so anyway go around and play with all
that kind of stuff
search whatever terms you want on the
search engine and I think I think you'll
find it interesting
so once the once they searched once they
did like you know hundreds or thousands
and
the tests where do they get their
biological data from their efficacy like
what's gonna you know you said that you
had one graph where they showed you know
a recommendation I I'm not not for a
disease or a therapeutic area but can
you go back to that one chart you're
asking how do they tie this data to
effect yeah what so so what is this
exactly I'm trying to okay well so see
realization right you can see this one
behind relaxations it's also high in
mere scene right so that's that sedative
property of how many how many stretch
cultivars they have in the database the
first 14 i typed in none came up until I
typed in Gorilla Glue okay but do
something like type in gorillas or glue
because a lot of times you get
variations on the name right it's like
god it didn't have granddaddy purp so it
didn't have true G you mean just like
type in Oh G type Turks type perps type
og okay like look for example I'll just
go to the top and type og oh there we go
alright size of the relaxation wedge
just a statistical correlation to how
much mersin is in a sample more or less
it's heavily weighted on near scene
right but again all the other terpenes
do have effects right okay so but what
are the other categories of effects so
they had relaxation was one that's the
mercy one wouldn't it be more I mean I
would say like I like the words I don't
know I get that's not a medical term but
I mean more of like a hypnotic or
medical remember duty in the late States
and you can't use I mean it's like yeah
you're right you're right yeah so what
is it focus energy inspiration right
inspiration is highly diverse we mean oh
cool really focus is isn't is is which
one again pining yeah it's time to
pining which is weird on this
because the paintings are actually all
there the third dominant terpene right
it's a small effect so they have a less
weighted score and the overall I'm not
again I'm not exactly sure the exact
algorithm but there's obviously not
rhythm behind it so how would I pull up
any sour DS on this or just try anything
type sour or diesel like let's go did
nothing came up
maybe I'm [ __ ] here so maybe they
just don't have it
there's no data on Saturday source hour
anything it's almost right chem see if
they're in the Kemp family no opening
Time Machine preferences oops
don't you just hate computer sometimes
they have crushes like classic public
pushes I like that I like the whole
layout and everything day where are they
located too so people can get things
tested or get their information I it's
not a public laboratory you can't okay
service laboratory they only work with
certain dispenser eating cultivated
clients their data really somebody gets
a better system theirs is the best
system for some time so let's go
downsize muji cushion what's unique
other than a nice color-coded graph
thing I mean we could finish yeah you
get bogged down in the in the in the
thing I was that was just a tool that I
was showing you to go and play with and
an experiment I'm not trying to present
idle backs okay I'm just trying to
present you something greater here which
is this so after running tons and tons
of tests they started to of these
terpene classes started to emerge which
is what Josh was talking about her sorry
what Alec was talking about last week
okay but this is really the work that
predated all of it and you can see like
for example let's look at limonene okay
right so this limonene class here these
are all different types of samples where
limonene is the highest terpene present
in the sample okay which is what we were
talking about what you
talking about a couple of weeks ago with
Tim's County Fair right you were basing
it on right the five dominant terpenes
right and I was saying I mean it's a
start but it doesn't really show you the
variation that can occur within that
within plants that are all alive and in
dominance so what this has done and
broken it down you can see that what we
cut was called the gold clasp or the
gold sub class in the limonene
superclass that is when limonene is
roughly equal to carry off lien and
roughly equal to mere seen okay very
cool and that's gonna have a different
effect when limonene is greater than
carry off lien and roughly equal to mere
seen and that's interesting because
Peter came in earlier and talked about
having some of the plants that they had
grown with his probiotics that bacteria
is that that a high or like instead of
two or three there was like eight or
nine classes of terpenes that had
similar amounts like you know what I
mean like we don't see that very often
like I haven't anyway one that I just
got let's see if I can show my screen
here this is a cool way to so at this
conference real quick this is what you
went to and there this is a really cool
way to start start the process of really
dialing it's like that it's like the
table of elements for cannabis and
terpene classifications this was the
first really comprehensive
classification system for terpenes and
so you can see if you count the classes
it's got 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 it's got eight
different terpene classes in this one
whereas the County Fair that they were
they're only using five different
classes right right they didn't have a
no sameen class they didn't have a
little little class well I didn't have a
human now look at what Peter's got see
this buddy see if you have anything that
matches this what he's got on this try
that did this chest he he was at 0.3
before he used the soil balance again
and out
Rick not a master grower like you guys
this is just a regular guy right
not a cannabis cup dude like you guys
are just a humble guy who's creating
medicine in his yard no co - op'
open-loop this is how we did it and and
so what in this laboratory only tests
for these particular ones this is all
they test for but this guy the
laboratory they said that they had three
others that were over 0.1 but these were
the only ones at that particular
laboratory just like it probably was up
for close few rounds percent they're all
relatively very close except one
one thing that is makes you know and I
it's really interesting to look at
individual results and I'm not trying to
talk smack about those results but what
one thing that we know that happens when
you go from cultivation - cultivation -
cultivation the environmental the
environmental conditions change and that
can actually impact the order of the
terpenes on the in the sample and this
was that look at this though he's got a
kosher Kush where his Mersin except the
li-ming's just a little bit higher but
he's almost fitting right into your Gold
Series I'm just looking at the chart
that's there there's a couple of them on
there that have three or four that equal
each other right so one of the things
that they did in this is that all the
all the plants were grown in the same
exact same conditions right and when you
do that you eliminate the environmental
effects mm-hmm and therefore you can get
a better representation of the actual
impact of the genetics on the flavor
profile right let's see so so so this is
coming in consistently for us you guys
we're getting like all balanced levels
but of eight nine of these of these
terpenes which is again most
laboratories have seen like what your
samples were the ones that you just
showed you have you know four that were
really high level maybe five but to get
that many like above seven or eight or
nine but
that's something that most laboratories
we've talked to have never seen before
so you know again you guys are
completely right each each strain and
each cultivation methodology is going to
vary within the amounts of terpenes like
a cannabis cup level guys gonna produce
a much higher terpene level because
there's a ability to understand the
correct macro micronutrients I mean you
need the physics to actually be able to
have something conducive so the client
can generate this this type of biomass
this term I mean so so if that's correct
if you're a good cultivator you know and
you know you're [ __ ] and you're putting
in the right macro micro the right
nutrients right carbon sources their
biology is going to come out in such
balanced expressions because it's it's
it's going to allow the plant to absorb
exactly what it needs so that it can
reach again what you guys say it's full
Jinhua and and to complement what you're
saying that what's skunkman and what
what come here saying here is if you're
if you're probiotic for the plant allows
the plant to reach potential expressions
of which genetically there and if you
look at this archive of cultivar your
and you say okay a kosher kush is in
this classic OG Kush gold where the
limonene equals the beta carotene equals
the mersin and you're able to and you
look at that particular test you show
that's a kosher cush so so what we were
asking earlier which was okay let's
apply your your probiotic to a o green
candy Riya or apply it to a proprietary
hybrid or these different these
different classifications were like a
mercy and classification and see what
that does to those levels so the it
would be interesting if you grow all of
the same and you have these
classifications he's showing us what the
what the probiotic what effects would
have on these terpene profiles now if
they all if every single classification
of genetics that was grown by the same
farmer and they all use this probiotic
and every single one of the
classifications evened out you would
have a phenomenal like weird
something you know what I mean like you
would have something that's just like
unbelievable that's not gonna happen
that's not gonna happen
I don't believe so either that's so I
don't think that would happen what it
would do is it's almost like a probiotic
in enhancement so you're being able to
like have the plant reach its maximum
terpene classification so I think that's
what your probiotic would do in each one
of these classifications agree we have a
grow right now it's the Central Coast
trees actually I just finished 18
different strains that have been
cultivated with the the soil balance and
so we're gonna you know maybe I can come
back on here and show those to you guys
once we have them in and SC Labs is
gonna do the analysis I love this
classification chart down tonight I just
wanna but this is you know I showed you
the close-up so that you could see the
actual terpene breakdown but this is
actually the really cool thing about it
and it relates to have the you know what
we were talking about with the
emerald-cut the the county fair and and
creating terpene classes and then
competing within the class so if you
look at the purple subclass right it's a
mere scene carry off lean and then
pining look look here all these
different plants right but whatever the
this is not the purple cush that we have
in canada but it was a sample in
california called purple cush the purple
girl the purple who do the GDP the rate
the granddaddy perps and the blue dream
they all have the same more or less
stripping profile at least with regard
to these major seventeen terpenes okay
and so this is how it fits in to what we
were talking about you know like the dog
the dog
what are they dog breeding competition
right it's like that's what they were
doing with with lining up terpene
classes is that you allow the plants
with the similar flavors to compete for
the same set of awards right yeah yeah
and so those are different for example
from the silver subclass right Bubba
cush Master cherry slider cherry cough
in the legend oh gee
right they all have limonene is greater
than carry off lean and then roughly the
same as nursing right so on that white
widow one I don't know the white widow
I've ever seen I haven't seen like it I
wouldn't classify it as a purple but
it's classified there because not of its
look but more of its terpene profiles
what you're saying it's classified
only bias terpene okay the repeat
classification system okay even though
the flowers look different the chemical
profiles are up juicing and there's
there's minor variations again it's only
based on the top seventeen most
predominant in most occuring terpenes
your minor Terps like you know alpha
Basava Lal and Y all and all these
things they can drastically change the
flavor yeah I was gonna say that was I
thought there might be a correlation
there but there's I mean for the
majority of what you have there's a
correlation of mersin being higher I
think that's what your chart shows in
that particular category I believe
mersin is the dominant one and each one
of those which would wonder if that has
a certain reaction when there's a the
phosphorus that's kind of slowing and I
guess quote-unquote bruising in the
plant creating the purple genetic look I
thought that maybe mercy and tied to but
then the white widow doesn't really grow
purple at all so it didn't that's all
the rest of those all have purple in
them and the purple kush is that's also
another very there could be one called
the perfect plan or aka the dirty perps
like Oregon dirty perps that's where
that purple pushes and I think all
purple and Ken's GDP is purple the
purple Voodoo's all purple blue dream
has some purple and blue and you know
hints of blue but a lot of purple in it
I thought maybe there was correlation
between the terpene and the no because
they're independent traits and you have
morphology in that chemistry this is all
based on camera yeah yeah one thing that
is interesting in that class Toni is
that I mean GDP and the the oracles and
that you know they're all they're really
popularly at least they work for a few
years in the Bay Area yeah right and
what other plant was also hugely popular
in the Bay Area with Blue Dream huge and
so I had wondered if that was like a
regional preference for a chemical
flavor mmm easy well if you look at the
Bay Area you need to be like a little
sedated and hypnotic then like I mean
there's a lot going on over here this is
ground zero for a lot of [ __ ]
so maybe just those particular varieties
just made everyone chill out you know it
could be but it's alright but I mean
like you know like in Spain for example
it's critical you know critical cluster
critical some ashanty sirens are really
popular there but many of you go to
Austria it's it's the chronic right like
mm-hmm
west coast of BC west coast BC it's like
pk the purple kush right at least it was
for a few years and we do develop these
like it's like it's like a local I are
call it a flavor preference but it's
like a local fashion right that develops
in an area that people like so pull out
on that chart real quick cuz that's also
like kind of I mean maybe it's maybe
it's a dialect if T if terpenes are the
con are the language like Peter was
saying earlier yeah that's one of those
I believe it's a silver is that chard
available online yet no well it is now
that we've got it on yeah what I meant
was that Ethan
sent me a copy but I was wondering if
somebody point to an internet site where
they could grab it like the hash Church
yeah like probably in the next 25
minutes this will be recreated in a
spreadsheet all color-coordinated in
someone else's - no one else's deck so
it also recreated it put it out there
and OB and Tuesday are Wednesday's
publication and then they'll claim it
yeah well it's I mean it's published it
was published with the ICRS and I like I
said mark dr. Lewis from from nay pro
gave me permission to put this up so
this is super cool this is their you
know this is their work when we you know
this they were the first to do the
terpene classic
isn't shout out shout out down it's Ryan
I have to show you something on my wall
did you protect the whole thing he's got
it right up on the wall I development
that's a pretty big oh [ __ ] you printed
it out in full as you go down this door
there you go down to the printer well
he's he's muted right now for some
reason he's probably talking and doesn't
realize it
he already trademarked it okay so let me
go into the next piece of the story then
okay
so what they've done is knowing that you
can have terpene profiles that are that
are replicatable and you know things fit
into the same flavor profile that meant
that there is a genetic component to it
so they started breeding plants and it's
unfortunate it's not easy to tell on
this variety but on this poster I can
you guys seen this poster I can see like
limonene superclass and you know for the
most part we could see it I thought you
said have we never seen it you can't see
like the the accurate graphs of which
each one is doing you'd have to zoom in
a little bit more on those ones but let
me zoom in on the terpene superclass
here so essentially what you have if you
look at the terpene fingerprints on the
bottom right 1 2 3
mm-hmm they're pretty much the same
right yeah there are small variations
but they are pretty much the same but
the interesting thing is if you look at
the canid i'll which is the ratio
between the top to terpenes this one
here on the left is a type 1 plant its
THC dominant with a little bit of CBD
wow look at that they're different the
middle one has is a type 2 plant with
the company Oct and CBD and then on the
right this is another hybrid that has
majority of the the cannabinoids are are
CBD with a little bit of THC so you have
been profile the inter pean profile was
varying cannabinoid Wow
and so now we're in a situation where
you can take these 3
and you can start using them for
clinical trials because what you've done
is you've stabilized the terpene
complement but you're varying the
cannabinoid content between treatment
groups how do we get those well you'd
have talked to dr. Lewis so and again
same thing in the pining superclass
right now these are both super cool I
mean they're knocking about pining
superclass limonene superclass this one
here the beta carry off mean superclass
is a little bit different the top the
first to the left one is again type one
pre THC predominant with a little bit of
CBD type two as a mixture of CBD and THC
but this one here on the right is a
really incredible plants and it's so
it's you can see the colors are a little
bit different on the canid aisle and
that's because the top two to the top
two cannabinoids in this variety are CBD
and CBD B Wow okay so CBD and CBD V or
cannabinoids that are really effective
for epilepsy okay that's where GW is
chasing them down for different for
different kinds of epilepsy as well
correct like CBD a acts differently than
CBD V is that correct I don't think we
know why I thought I saw Ethan Russo
talking a little bit about it and the
CBD V is for a frontal epilepsy he spoke
about it recently when he was here in
Vancouver you can we can catch up on
yeah for sure I would let Ethan be your
guide on that if you say that yeah but
this Co but what you're saying is
somebody specifically bred these what's
left letsa let me finish it's Evie and
CBD but if you look at the terpene cup
background it's high in beta-carotene
and high in little and both of those
terpenes are also anticonvulsant and
antispasmodic
so what it is is they take the
cannabinoids that are designed for a
specific condition in this case epilepsy
and they put it in the terpene
background
that also has an entourage that has the
same effect right so this is really a
case where it was a cultivar that was
designed well great you know a lot of
people that they look at we only need to
figure out what strains work for which
conditions where this is a totally
opposite approach this was let's create
a variety that is targeting and who bred
that who's doing this well this is work
that was done with a probe through one
of their clients Wow
that's killer man that's that's like the
coolest [ __ ] I've seen in a long time to
be honest with you yeah that's why I
wanted to lay out the whole story for
you guys from analytical method all the
way through people sure now we need to
get that into farmers to grow it so we
can extract it and get it into medicine
to people so no first we need to set up
a call with dr. what was it named dr.
Lewis dr. Lewis get it into the farmers
yeah you got to get these varieties out
there with the trillion probiotic
formula step up the growing game get
this stuff out in the masses yeah a
trillion I mean the amount of work that
went into these plants and these this
method I mean these you're not gonna
find these clones on the market no any
time school he's got a contract it
though you know they'll be yeah they
will find people you know people that
are serious partners will be licensed
the technology and all that kind of [ __ ]
right it's [ __ ] awesome this is this
is good progress yeah right people are
doing good work you know it's like just
because you don't know about it
necessarily doesn't mean it's not
happening out there and every once in a
while you get wowed awhile moment from
time era and the good people at Nate Pro
yeah you gotta gotta give credit to the
neighborhood folks of course yeah
absolutely we give all credit then it
was up but you came and shared it so I
give you a little bit of credit too no
it's very cool
the I had a question for you guys cuz
that kind of was something I was gonna
bring up today what and
skel don't we'll probably be all over
this one to answer it but we did some we
did some tests on converting th da to
THC and or to CBN and figured out some
different different methods of how to do
this but there was something while we
were doing doing this process we were
like in the Jack Frost example when we
used Jack Frost terpenes with Jack Frost
flower oil and and had it from a
originally tested which would be
probably I'd say under 3% active
applying no heat to it but just actually
soaking it in its own terpenes at a say
20 or 30% range we found over a course
of time organically with no heat that it
actually converted 60 70 percent of the
THC over to THC when I tested it later
what's your thoughts on the way that
other terpenes can play so converting
the THC a to THC basically just
activating it without any heat but
rather an organic just using terpenes
just a saturation of terpenes oh and you
and you think did that sped up the
decarboxylation rate of THC I just just
what you thought the potential was yeah
I mean there's all kinds of things that
can catalyze that heat is one thing but
also light and air and other things and
yeah I think that if it was in a solid
form and if its crystalline it's one
thing because you have the low energy
form of the crystalline lattice to break
up to overcome but once you do make a
solution can you increase this
degradation rate absolutely I could see
that happen how long did it take to do
that
so this was like just what we were just
what we were calling are like you know
when you were creating a high
terpene rosin this was over a period of
I'd say not that long maybe a couple
months to three months we tested it once
and then we tested again and I noticed
by the third time I was like wow there's
a 50% conversion here and it didn't it
didn't change the container or exposure
to light or change temperature it was
actually kept like 50 degrees yeah I
could see that it is exposed to light or
is it kept in the dark light no low
light yeah I don't know so I said these
are HPLC results obviously cuz you're
measuring acid right yeah we go through
se labs I have like a bulk account we're
always testing like everybody stuff that
comes to us for pesticides whatever you
have a small amount of the original
sample so you know that that first data
point is actually valid yeah I do
I was just curious what you thought
about it or what people thought because
it appears it would make sense kind of
on this topic of conversation where
people are breeding now that there's
people breeding like varieties out there
for specific terpene profiles with
specific ratios of those particular
cannabinoids what the chemical or with
that what that then would lead down into
an extraction process so that person has
now a CBD CB V with a certain terpene
expression and perhaps we can create an
organic chemical reaction with utilizing
the terpenes themselves as a catalyst
instead of heat or light because we came
up with something else now I can convert
I have figured out a way not with
terpenes but a different way to convert
our hash rosin or flour rosin to cbn
without losing any volume of weight but
rather convert yeah I thought your
eyebrows would go up on that so if I
start with a thousand grams of 70
percent of flour rosin or hash rosin or
an 80 percent distillate
I can convert that to CBN without any
without any of your traditional lighter
Heat in another way
that we developed without any chemicals
that will convert that thousand grams to
well some other things it's it's not
that it's it's it's not really my tech
to share but some other scientists that
I worked on with it for a while they
came up with it and obviously had me
sign some paperwork but I was looking
for it for our p4 because I wanted to
upscale it because we originally I
talked about it before and release that
in Toronto how we sift and then we use
heat and oxygen to break the SIF down so
we have like 250 milligrams of THC a
converged about 70 milligrams of CBN
it's just a really long tedious
laborious process and it's really like
kind of a degra gated nasty blood
looking oil at the end but it's just
people are individual so how do you
scale it up was converting converting
this without losing weight so now we
could take like a 70 or 80 percent THC a
rosin or hashish rosin or flour rosin or
distillate if you will even if it's THC
convert that to CBN without losing any
weight at a 50 percent so if I'm 70
percent flour rosin when I'm done I'm
350 milligrams of CBN with under the
point one THC without losing any volume
of the weight so in that process I
started thinking about how terpenes
could be catalyst for converting THC by
just having just these random little
experiments going along the side I just
didn't know what you thought about it I
thought maybe I was crazy there's no
nothing compelling in most cannabis
terpenes to promote decarboxylation if
they would why would they just
decarboxylate on the plants right they
could exist on the plant you know now
what you're saying is you're somehow
extracting them and combining them and
doing some kind of you know most that
would be catalytic as you're just
lowering the activation energy to
decarboxylation happens at room
temperature it happens quicker at
elevated temperature and everywhere in
between it's just as
you know the amount of decarboxylation
has to do with you know either thermal
history typically it's seen but I can't
think of anything off top my head why it
would be promoting decarboxylation but
um the dehydrogenation event is
interesting to to to CBN right so you
say that you have a method to convert
THC to CBN which is always yeah I mean
it's so Arnaz PhD dissertation you can
do that stoichiometrically using
selenium based oxidation or sulfur or
sofox I'd there's a lot of other ways
that I'm not saying it's there's that at
all the point is is that yeah when it's
oxidized all that those terpenes and all
of those other fragile thermally
sensitive molecules are are just going
to create just pollard aggravated
colored compounds and that's all the
crap because the Sam will attest to
CBN's a white colorless solid I don't
think it has any color to it at all
so I mean you know that's one thing I
was going to say that this is opaque
gray the cvn that we're getting in the
oil when I'm done with that you should
try recrystallizing it I think it's
recrystallized from methanol I think is
usually where it's okay because I was
going to say that on the crystallization
of CBN to get it into crystallization
and like terpenes being yeah nine
non-polar well everything I'm trying to
do is chemicals but that's what the
scientists I mean other people would say
yeah did it say you could recrystallized
right here oh the purity and then you
can analyze it and when you only find
one compound that it's CB n then you
know that all this [ __ ] that you
purified away if you do have a solid
coming out of that it probably is CB n u
s-- need to purify it you can flash it
down a little chromatography column or
do whatever you need to do to hang up
any of the other bodies because I think
and I think Sam has actually shown a
sample here on hash Church white
crystalline solid it's like white is as
THCA
I mean it's it's a white crystalline
solid I I do believe come on I've never
seen it myself but could you say suspend
the the oil and ethanol and bubble pure
oxygen through it to convert it
I would I would just not use oxygen I
would just use air right because I don't
like heating up oxygen because oxygen if
you have things that will do higher
oxidation yeah it could be really really
bad thank you really all you need is air
now can there's difference you can
accelerate that you can add basically I
I'm not going to give away anyone's IP
and I probably shouldn't talk about it
but the point is is that look in the
literature there are methods for the
stoichiometric conversion of THC the CBN
we'll just leave it at that
yeah I was just musing I was thinking
oxygen and I wouldn't yeah oxygen oxygen
under pressure with any kind of yeah
it's it could be explosive well I don't
even I mean I'm talking about bubbling
some yeah I tried I tried taking once
upon a time we tried taking like pump
just air through regulators through oil
tried to heat it I tried to take rosin
in the past and tortured it like 500 600
800 degrees none of that seemed to do
the trick and it's definitely something
that I was interested in and these two
other guys are discovered it they're
very techie scientists people I'm like I
think you guys fight
you know it's through their company I
was like think you guys might like have
a patentable thing here and they're like
what do you mean I'm like I don't know
anyone else doing this and
I've seen a lot of the different stuff
and I just put idea in their head and
you know I try to you know trying to
figure out things without chemicals but
yeah at the end the polarity plays a big
difference because THC a and it's a
polarity on like a hexane or a
hydrocarbon the non-polar effect allows
it to crystallize very easily but when
you get to CB n polarity plays a big
part in how you would crystallize that
at least naturally so the only viable
solution was probably a chemical like
you're saying just to just to get it
done just to say okay here it is let's
test it you know hey I got a quick point
another thing I wanted to bring up from
the ICR just kind of on topic and it's
something that dr. shel Doan has been
saying for a long time but these guys
who actually went through and the the
researchers name was Melissa Lewis
unrelated to mark and she's working in
Toronto with one of the universities
there are a few of the universities
there and anyway they did a bunch of
extracts using supercritical and ethanol
and a bunch of different extract types
and then they ran the extracts through
an MSO GCMs device and they noted that
there was a whole bunch of chemistry
that actually had gone on in the in the
process and they showed that some
compounds were created and some
compounds were removed from the from
matrix just just by the process of doing
the extraction so you know again what
Mark has been saying for for months and
months and months now probably longer
yeah when you're doing these extractions
there's chemistry that's going on and
it's not you're not just pulling it
pulling out what is in there right it's
all about optimizing the process so that
you're capturing what's in the flower
you know otherwise you are doing
chemistry and you're changing it into
something else
anyhow I asked her if I could take a
photo of her data to share it and she
said no because they're gonna be
publishing so they're gonna be
publishing it sometime hopefully in the
next six months and we'll be able to go
it over go over things a little more in
depth at that point in time did she see
the formation of a she
I'm just curious was that like a
degradation product that she found in
her in her work no but there was some
really interesting things that I'll tell
you offline well that's something we
could look at when I'm gonna do this
experiment again for you mark then and
for everyone that's listening and see if
there is I now that I'm gonna do it
specifically with Jack Frost again I'll
start with the flour or rosin get it
tested then I'll have the terpenes
tested then I'll combine the two then
I'll monitor it over one month to six
months get the degradation see the
conversion and see if it see if that
happens you know we'll do make sure -
room to make sure you're using lab that
has GCMs because most people are using f
ID and they don't know that is what does
SC labs use because that's what we've
been using they use GCF ID so they're
they've run like an algorithm
essentially has computers pull out the
known Peaks but hash oisin is not going
to be a Terp that they're looking for
who can I send that to well they might
have a mess I'm not sure but I believe
they probably do have a GCMs but you're
gonna have to go in and say hey I don't
want your standard turf test I want you
to look for the presence of hashing okay
okay right because if they're there
they're typical turf tests they run on
GCF ID won't pick it up yeah and and
that wasn't actually the the mechanism
that was implicated by the authors in
that paper was a photo lytic mechanism
where you got a recombination of the die
radical that's formed formed when Mir
seen is is irradiated with light so I
mean again some of these things happen
thermally as well as photo lytic ly but
that particular one it would be
interesting to do that on a mere scene
enriched variety like this data shows to
take someone that has a lot of Mir seen
those types of degradation components in
there and that was you know one there
are several thermal pathways that
terpenes
especially with the Marcin skeleton and
will either rearrange to give the
terpene turpentine
Sabbatini I mean there's a whole family
of them and they're just ice American
where the double bonds are and when
those things are formed thoroughly
they're usually formed a mixture of like
four or five compounds so uncommon turns
to four five like instantly just because
of these thermal degradation routes but
yeah thanks for pointing that in that
right I've shaded do you remember the
original paper what the conversion rate
was from mersin to hash machine I know
but they measured it I mean I'd have to
pull it up I don't have it off the top
my head yeah because he did was tested
it after the fact and not before maybe
but well I thought in that paper they
actually intentionally did it on mersin
itself to look for it and also I think
found literature precedent for this
reaction variously and it hadn't been
observed I guess on hash but and I guess
the the point maybe that you're trying
to raise him is that this is thought of
as sort of like the-- the thermodynamic
dead end of hash that's been shined the
light on for a long period of time it
was ultimately night will be versus but
maybe it's just been pressed with heat
and it's a little bit old and it's
present maybe I don't really know right
maybe the conversion was done in
planteth maybe was done when it was long
ago plan that's funny I have my doubts
but I could be wrong you know we don't I
mean it was because the tests were done
by French police one on seized samples
oh we have no idea where in the chain of
custody that conversion happened right
yeah I could do all those little
experiments we could run wash it to six
variety that's easy I mean that's we
could take a I mean we could there's
access to blue dream which is
honestly very very very high in mercy
that season no I tried look for Tony is
looking for athlete f qu e is like I've
got tons of that we got it out here if
you see the phenotype that's almost
exclusively mere scene there's one out
there that might okay that one's
absolutely prevalent and you know what's
interesting that one's usually from the
guys that I get that ones 25% plus THC -
you know okay that's pretty cool
everybody's got homework yeah we do damn
did he ever drop out fast after saying
that that was like I should end church
one day like that ah man oh yeah so
we're also like mark created in the same
type of process rosin distillate again
without winterizing with alcohol Wow
he's CEO he's back he's back but yeah
we're creating these different I was
just trying to create different products
because we've got public man and I got
some other projects in the horizon but
it was how do we create like you know a
distillate out of rosin without
winterizing and in that same process it
was like alright well we can do that but
we could also do a conversion in the CBN
so next week I should have some
hopefully and I'll show it to you and as
you tell tell me what was the chemical
you ever spoke cBAM I smoked our CBN but
that was a using heat and degra gated
this is this won't use it yeah yeah but
we have it in pill form in sublingual
form CBD and CBN for like four years now
is all from but it's a different process
it's it's a long process and then to
discover 64 and Fort Collins and we'll
run an NMR and HPLC okay the nth degree
of everything that you have in there
very cool what's the what was the
chemical you were saying
to crystallize that I'll try it no I
would say a good place to start would be
maybe methanol or ethanol I mean again
just try to make a saturated solution
material boil it up so it dissolves and
then just you know look to see if you
can crystallize it like you would grow a
piece of rock candy you know it is is a
polar molecule okay yeah that one would
work methanol yeah well methanol or
ethanol it's toxic you may want it what
about purified like 95% ethanol like a
organic what about an organic ethanol
like from great like it doesn't make a
difference just you're just trying to
crystallize I got something I have an
organic one yeah I know what to use for
that alright cool
we shall see so the the other thing I
wanted to get back to what Peter was
saying and that is that um you know you
were talking about sense and like human
sense of a big part of the human
effluent is actually you know there's
lactic gases a lot of lactic acid that's
actually given off by people and that
has to do with just islands of
biochemical processes that are happening
but turns out that's one of the things
that mosquitoes hold it on a goal marker
that mosquitoes actually use to identify
a blood meal so it's thought of that
deep and other insect repellents somehow
interfere with the insects ability to
detect lactic acids like they have a
particular sensor way of doing that sort
of chemo specifically and that some
humans have more lactic acid to the in
are more attractive to do to mosquitoes
and other I think like my wife will get
bit before I will like her system like
she's like more of mosquito target than
I am I don't know if it's like that with
other different people but lactic acid I
know is a
for a lot of people has a lot to do with
the biological you know biome that
actually lives on your skin right
are you meeting I was muted I was oh no
yeah actually it Peter isn't muted but I
can't hear him now that's weird
here no you might have mosquitoes in the
fact that my wife always got bit before
me and then after she had a serious
illness and took huge amounts of
medication they wouldn't bite her
anymore and instead they would bite me
huh that's what you say crazy
yeah certainly it has a lot to do with
live on your skin I think there's quite
a bit of bacteria to deal with on
people's skin naturally hello yes come
back burgers wait come back well we've
almost rocked three and a half hours so
far pastures today not bad not bad at
all and people were wondering if you
were standing the whole time yeah I like
to stand out but I feel like if I'm
sedentary if I'm just you know City my
body just starts to you know I'd like to
be up and I channel better that way
awesome three plus hours of standing
this morning well done a PITA and I'm
probably now gonna go do Despicable Me
with the little guys so nice oh you will
you stand in the theater as well yes I
will that's awesome well played well
played yes yes I'll be the guy in the
back stabby corner but yeah I really
enjoyed I can't thank you enough man for
having me all you guys I really thank
you for for hand of the year it's been a
it's been beautiful absolutely well
we'll continue the conversation for sure
I have one more question for Peter and
they do
manufacture your own microorganisms or
do you purchase them and mix them what
is it that your company actually does
yes so we actually around the world
I mean multiple countries multiple
environments and we actually isolated
each individual string we we we studied
and tried to find them so we do
manufacture them ourselves which is kind
of nice because you know if you if you
think about certain things or certain
products there can be such a diversity
of strains and you don't really know
what exactly is going in there I mean
biology is so diverse so what we've done
is we have 62 strains at the exact same
amounts every single time so where we
take great pride in the fact that our
product is consistent and and for what
you guys are talking about and how that
relates it's it's gonna be so nice to
actually quantify the the different
strains and what they're able to produce
you know those terpenes in combination
with with these microbial so there could
be a bitter effect if you use more we
could see a better effect if we use less
of certain types of terpene strains so
yeah so that's I guess the best way to
answer the question the the product is
consistent and we create them ourselves
well we don't create three strains
they're part of Mother Nature we've just
found them and we recreate that we grow
them at high numbers so I Oh affecting
by out you're a bio prospector right in
yeah exactly
that's what your bio mining hey thanks
for opening my eyes to some of this I
ordered some and very interested in it I
appreciate you coming and giving all
this information thank you for
purchasing I think we're very grateful
for that thank you so much yeah Peter
we're gonna give it a run here to it
sounds like a great product thank you
guys thank you so much that's that's
what we're really hoping so that's
that's why I'm your rank hey you know
I'd love to give you guys some product
so you can know
test it out and see what you think I'm
really excited for you to see it you
know it's one thing to talk about it
it's one thing to come in your but for
you to see it and to be able to smell it
and and the colors and the trichome
production is just gonna exceed your
expectations
I know that and I'm projecting that
energy out there because I know it you
know it's happened right now we've got a
92% repurchase rate on this product
after trial so the people that are
actually putting it in the ground are
rebind 92% of them that's pretty any
business that's been our biggest
challenge to be honest is you know
having these growers just to use it you
know if we humble everybody we have a
gentleman up there his name is ty ty
Israel I don't know if you know I'm up
in Humboldt you know ty Tony yeah after
that I've heard of him I think I might
have met him before - you'd probably be
upset if I've met him multiple times and
said I think but it's dead name sounds
extremely familiar he's he's put it on
his plans he sent me some pictures he
said the the ten grows you know said
they've never seen anything like it
before the the the plant leaves just
started coming up doing this so they
were really you know elevated with with
a different kind of energy and so once
he saw that he contacted me and said I'd
like to you know get this out Bulgaria
so now it's if it's spreading like
wildfire just just through use have you
tried you probably already working on it
but have you tried a any type of foliar
feeding yeah yeah you can you know not
on say the buds but I would say as a veg
product but if it's all-natural and
people don't have to use a pesticide you
know what I mean I've never said that
no you yeah well you don't have to use
pesticides on cannabis that's people's
choice so that's just their growing
methods it's about controlling
environment and and keeping a healthy
plant the plant will push off the pests
the bugs if they're healthy so if
they're what you're saying like if you
using a probiotic in the soil and the
plant does what it says it's supposed to
like you're saying then it should
naturally ward off those those things so
I was just curious if you guys have
developed anything in that same realm
that's a foliar that would also help as
a beneficial that doesn't you know the
people use tea compost and they spray
all kinds of stuff on their plants
during veg and stuff yeah so we're we're
hoping to get to a point down the road
where we can sell enough of this product
and begin you know with the quality to
to bring in more scientists to
continually develop those types of
foliar applications that would be
conducive to colonization that happens
when the soil borne pathogens such as
Pythium Fusarium verticillium
rhizoctonia guy oh man oh my sees
botrytis Pythium all of those guys that
you deal with especially the the para
nós pura like the the powdery and downy
mildew x' those are all incubating
within your soil and they get to a point
of confidence here where they actually
colonize the stem of the plant and
that's how you get your disease
topically and so to elicit an immune
response as well as add the correct
strains conducive to pathogen
suppression on the leaf biofilm
is something that we will be getting
into down the road once you know we get
to a place or a space where where we can
afford those types of people and
scientists so we're kind of like uh in
some ways we're couldn't like Tesla
right now or just starting now we have a
we have a regenerative sustainable
technology that can help the environment
and we need the support of all these
people that are tuned into their plants
to help us grow we want it rode with you
we're all we're all kind of in the same
boat right now you guys are doing
something that's federally illegal you
know and and we're doing something right
now that's off the charts as well we're
a joke what's your website again so we
get it out there for people yeah thank
you it's so it's soil balance procom I
would just say that my license is
federal I don't know what about what you
guys are up to but we're all we're all
doing something that is I really it's
light work you know it's it's it's
coming from a place of giving and it's
coming for a little and so it's coming
inside all of us it's coming from the
stem of human consciousness it is it is
it's a beautiful thing to be a part of
right now you look at I was just talking
about this with a friend of mine the
other day you look in the Dark Ages
you know where people were so inundated
with shadow you know pain and suffering
and killing each other and and we've
come through such a nice point of
evolution too now where we're actually
able to that have abundance and at being
able to hopefully elevate to a really
high level of consciousness and part of
that is going to be tuning back into
nature like like every every grower
feels as they tune into their plant they
resonate they understand that part of
our responsibility in my opinion as
organisms on this planet as human beings
is to take care of the predominant
species on this planet which is our
plants and if we tune in to them they'll
tune back into us they'll give us our
food they'll give us our medicine you
know they'll heal this whole environment
and with with what's going on and and
that's why I named the product soil
balance because you know the time for
balance is now you know you know no
nothing happens without a response like
I think probably before we started
wearing shoes athletes but it wasn't a
thing you know so our bodies responded
by allowing a funghi to go in them
because we're wearing shoes which isn't
really the norm although it's become the
norm yeah so so yeah if you guys have
any questions about the biology how the
mode of action works I'd love to go into
that a little bit if you have any
questions on stop going to arrest
without any shoes on hey we call an
Italian restaurant right yeah there you
go Andi Bravo I will probably do a
little soil balance wake-and-bake
giveaway in the near future I can
picture it
good old wake-and-bake I gave away
Dana's book yesterday green buds and
hash remember good old green buds and
hash everybody write great book I'm
telling you I read it on my
wake-and-bake the other day and it's
surprisingly educational I have to say
he did a great job on that parody shout
out to Dana Larson for that big did I
miss a question right now I think you're
I think I didn't hear somebody first
there's just just answer it oh I heard
something about shoes right now no I
mean if you thought you heard a question
just answer it regardless and we'll go
with it but ever you do take care of
your shoes yes that's that's how I sign
all my emails from my cell phone
Kona's that's true it's the truth what
happens if you don't wear shoes all she
ever wears flip-flops you don't live in
island where see that [ __ ]
well that's because you are uninitiated
my grasshopper Oh Sam's talking about
the Illuminati I think he's on the
Illuminati one now that's the one I want
to join so I am again I'm probably gonna
get the despicable me cuz it's it's
about 12:30 but I've really enjoyed my
space here you guys thank you and all
your work I'm so grateful to you guys
yes thanks for coming out Peter we'll be
in touch
off-camera and I'm gonna call it as well
it's been such a great show unless
chimeras damn mark Sheldon Tony if you
guys have anything else to say
Indra by all means we can continue on I
don't want to cut anyone off but if you
guys
maybe end it with a little mark Jim and
he's got a little guitar in his hand I
see I just want to say happy Canada Day
belated to everybody in Canada yesterday
it was the sesquicentennial yes yeah
Centennial and armor and happy 4th of
July coming up happy fourth of July tell
our American friends to the said yes 150
years men sort of cut you off chimera up
great what now just have a great
celebration be safe out there and have
fun
PUF much melt puff much melt fourth of
July and enjoy Despicable Me 3 with your
child's Peter I'm sure it will be a
wonderful makes me want to go do that
today except I'm going out on the boat
with my friends from Whistler and gonna
pull them on the wakeboard in the
wakeskate so I may go live later on for
a little bit of that but in the meantime
chimera thanks for the knowledge drop in
the sharing of all that great
information
Scott man Sam is always an Indra thank
you guys for making it mark shelled own
dr. mark and Peter I'm sort of balance
pro Tony for szura in the room and for
our fellows Dana or Soria Darren Massey
and Johnny Burr fellow thanks for coming
in earlier and for those that didn't
make it today talk McCormack and at TF
on 10 well we missed you guys but I'm
sure we'll see you sooner than later
thanks for watching hash Church
everybody see you next week peace thanks
guys have a great day
ah that's convenient
are we still alive I just live I think
he didn't end it before we should all
just hang out and I'll meet you at the
other spot I sent you an email
adios now guys
okay bye
you