hey everybody welcome to hash Church 2.0
the past present and future of
vaporisation today we're going to do a
little vaporization dialogue I got some
good folks that I'm gonna invite in and
I guess I should get them in right away
with the email unfortunately my friend
Kevin from Team steamed Jamaica is
having a hard time getting in on his
phone but I'm hoping that Gary from up
tech and Linus vaporbrothers and Steve
from seventh floor and sable from vape
exhale will all be able to come in we'll
all be able to have a little bit of
conversation I did also send out an
invitation to Everett from verdamper to
jurgen from volcano and as well as task
Rock from from highly-educated so I
guess I wanted to start out before
everyone comes in I have sent out that
email I wanted to send my regards to the
family of Dennis Peron and all the
people that he supported over the years
for those of you that don't know Dennis
was a huge cannabis advocate just passed
away at 72 legendary cannabis activists
who kindled America's medical marijuana
revolution in the 1980s there's a great
article on Leafly
about his passing and a little bit about
what he done so we wanted to shout him
out and john entwistle his husband sorry
for your loss
and yeah we appreciate all the amazing
work that you did Dennis it was it was
the real deal for sure California and
the rest of the world will not soon be
forgetting Dennis Peron hey welcome mr.
Mcoy how's it going bro it's going great
dude look at you sorry I just missed the
Peron tribute but yeah I had to show
Dennis oh good yeah I had to shout out
Dennis I'm sure you've got your stories
as well mark McCoy from rip Tech
old-time friends jeez we go back a good
solid close to 20 years don't we we do
we do
he's amazing it's amazing and we got
Gary in the room who just
showed up from uptick in w-9 he is the
creator of the omnicons and the hercules
pan as well as the bubbleman Trinity Pen
so welcome to you Gary hey how's it
going can you guys hear me we can hear
you perfect there we go
yes I'm looking forward to the dialogue
today boys I think actually you know
between the two of you right now you
might be two of the people that take
this [ __ ] the most serious when it comes
to love vaporization and sort of the
ability to not lower your integrity to
acquire the thing that might be easier
rather than fight through those
obstacles with the high integrity anyone
with high integrity knows you just come
up with more obstacles when you can't
lower your integrity to make it work you
guys know what I mean yeah
well I hope I can explain this correctly
in order to actually get something of
high integrity you have to go against
the wave right here is where it the low
integrity is if you're going up against
the waiver you're doing something
different you're doing something how do
I put this you're doing something that
is a lot different than what everybody
else is the one and I a few a lot
different than what it thought it was
doing you're actually being seen
hopefully people take a take notice of
that but at the same time you were
getting drowned as well so yes look into
it yeah it's there's a whole situation
of well David Suzuki put it beautifully
when he told me about his show and he
was like you know when I got the nature
of things show I really thought that I
was gonna be this gem on television and
then I quickly realized when you when
you get tossed into a cesspool even if
you are a diamond but you quickly take
on the appearance of what is in the
cesspool so I was like a really good
metaphor dude yeah because you tie
yourself next to the doggy go there not
to be a dog one day you know it's it's
it's basically the same thing you take
on the appearance or wherever you are at
just like a person having the same
accent if
they live in the south for a long time
or in Europe for a long time it's just
just the same thing yeah absolutely
someone's laughing that I brought up
David Suzuki hey man David Suzuki was
awesome in his time the nature of things
that show was wicked
I think he's jaded through I think that
it was not just taking on the appearance
of the cesspool but hey welcome to sabo
from vape exhale who just made it in
with the beautiful rainbow colored wall
behind them hey what's up guys Marc
what's up Sabo good to see you
let's uh brethren let's up yeah yeah is
that who we got coming in now that's
Linus - their creators MIDI and it yeah
we got it we got a good little group
here I don't know how many more we're
gonna have I did invite my friend Kevin
from steamteam Jamaica I thought it
would be kind of a fun thing to have the
almost you know not the original as
McCoy reminded me the other day of the
Sith ian's which I'll probably start
envision and I'll go through a small
history of vaporization and this is just
an article I found online that I figured
I would read to everyone once I read the
history of vaporization anyone in the
room that wants this sort of toss in
their history and where they fit in or
if they feel that something's a little
bit different it's not the word of God
this is just an article that I found
online that I thought had a nice kind of
little history that I fit into pretty
well because I you know I was in
Amsterdam in 1994-95 when bill was there
with the with his vaporizer and I met
mark McCoy at a fairly early on in the
game and so I've been I've met volcano
people the year they released the
volcano at the can of business in
Germany I met Jurgen and his daughter so
I have a fairly my own version of the
history of vaporization so why don't I
go right to that I have it open here
I'll probably share it on the page as
well so people can see what I'm what I'm
reading and this will be quick and then
once we do this what we'll do is we'll
go through and each of you can
introduce yourself and sort of talk
about you know your passions of cannabis
and how it led into vaporization and
here I'm gonna just keep your mic muted
Gary if you guys notice I'll probably
mute your mics when they're unmuted that
way if you go to talk again just
remember you got to unmute your mic as
often we get some sort of feedback noise
here alright so let me change the screen
saver to show everyone what this is
going on here yeah application window
there we go the history of vaping so
this is from herb and I believe it was
the gentleman herb who wrote it it was
it's a couple years old now so the
history of vaporization herbs for
inhalation is a practice that can be
traced back far back and across many
different civilizations so the history
of vaporization herbs for insulation out
we got that what exactly is vaporizing
or vaping alright so if you've been
living under a rock and aren't sure with
vaping is here some explanation the
basic techniques since the inception of
vaping either old or the new age battery
supported vaporizers is the same
vaporizing heats the ingredients to an
optimum heat to the optimal temperature
range from cannabis is between 180 and
210 Celsius for the perfect vape
compared to joints bongs or a pipe that
burns the ingredients the blend is
whether they be oils wax or dry herbs
are heated to a level allowing the
release of the materials but allow the
temperature that would burn them as
there is no combustion during the
process of heating a vapor is released
this is quite cool and non irritating to
the users throat yeah unless you hit
like 17 volcano bags in a row without
drinking tea and then you quickly
realize how dry it really is 15 what do
we got here sorry the 5th century 5th
century BC so this is the this is the
one mark was talking about the other day
vaporizing to humans has been known to
date back in Egypt from the book the
history of Herodotus 1928 dial press
during the 5th century BC her Herodotus
who was often called the father of
history recorded his accounts of the
ancient practice enjoyed by Citians the
Citians takes some of this hemp seed and
throw it upon the red-hot stones
immediately at vaporizes and gives us
such a vapor as no Bree she
paper baths can exceed the Scythian
delighted shout for joy the steady heat
from the baking stones would produce a
pleasant smelling vapor so 1500 years
ago Afghanistan technically speaking the
first real vaporizer was event invented
by Iran sheikh of the moguls present-day
afghanistan Safa Safavid dynasty knows
to us as hookah or as water pipe
narghile argh Allah kaylynn shisha about
1400 years ago moguls Mughals then
rulers of India introduced hookah to
India which was then more used to a
Chilam the controversy over the
invention there is quite a big
controversy over the invention of the
first vaporizer here's a patent from
1927 USA the first one who came up with
the idea of the electronic cigarette is
Joseph Robinson he did it in 1927 in
which he felt filed a patent to the
USPTO for the first mechanical butane
ignition vaporizer Robinson's patent was
approved and published by the USPTO
little to his credit that he deserves he
still owns the patent of the first
nicotine vaporizer and so that one's
from 1960 was the dawn of the modern day
inventor of e-cigarette Korean veteran
herbart a Gilbert the modern-day
vaporizers until this day are claimed to
be built on the blueprint of mr.
Gilbert's original design mr. Gilbert to
this date works for the emperor east
cigarettes who bought his technology
1992-1994 amsterdam father of cannabis
vaporizer eagle bill has a cannabis
community called following known to
discover the popularizing of the
cannabis vaporizer he turned his device
safe and effective alternative to
smoking for over a decade he was a
favorite exhibit at the sensi see banks
hash Museum in Amsterdam that's
definitely where I met him as well as at
the PAC's party house and as well as
that lucky mother's in both 94 95 the
museum attracts visitors from around the
world and build in joint bill enjoyed
sharing his new technologies to any
willing inhalers a resident of Amsterdam
for 12 years this was soon before the
1994 cannabis cup sensi seeds gave bill
space and he blew away the crowd with
his new technology truly if anyone was
at the early cannabis cups it was really
really hard to miss Eagle bill the guy
was an incredible energy and an
incredible advocate for vaporization
it remained the most popular exhibit at
the cannabis cup for 10 years earning
bill and since he seeds numerous
first-place cups soon he set up shop on
a daily basis and the hash Museum and
used that platform to turn the world on
to vaporization Eagle bill was
introduced to vaporizing in 1993 by a
California grower who used the heat gun
to vaporize aromatic blends just in case
you didn't know everything in the
cannabis industry always started with a
California grower I'm just gonna say
that now whether its water hash whether
it's like it's just everything came from
a California you follow the history back
it's always the unknown California
grower it's amazing that we made
everything man we made everything what
can I say I'm just I'm not gonna die
deny it bro so in an effort to design a
more affordable means of vaporizing were
simultaneously raising public awareness
Eagle Bill invented the shake and vape
based on sorry based on the very same
ancient Egyptian methods Eagle Bill's
glass pipe vaporizer that heat at the
bottom of a glass bowl with instead
light lighting the cannabis itself
pioneered by a Native American the
shaken vape was nicknamed the peace pipe
of the future Eagles bill invention
would be the catalyst for rapid
technology and product developments in
the vaporizer industry and a big
inspiration bill passed away on 22nd of
May 2005 in Georgia USA in 1994 BC
vaporizer
Canada claims to have invented the first
electrically charged vaporizer inspired
on Bill's Amato design BC vaporizer
still is running in business today and
our inventors of solar power charger
charge vaporizer it was however Storz
and Bickel company in 2000 that invented
the new era of desktop vaporizers and
named it volcano just like its work
around the history of vaporizers as
controversial as it sound still holds
the timeline benchmark and technically
makes hookah the oldest vaporizer
modern-day vaporizers credit no doubt
boasts to everyone involved in the
process but still credited to late bill
Amato Amato for his pioneering endeavor
to the cannabis world so that was a
little article written by herb I know
that everyone's not present and that
really kind of stops in 2000 where it
really sort of picks up
and all of these different companies
started to come into play but kind of a
neat little timeline if any of you guys
have anything you want to fix on that
timeline by all means add it I can
imagine maybe mark McCoy has something
to say I don't know I thought that was I
thought that was pretty well done I mean
there was a number of different
iterations that came off the Eagle bill
including myself very much so inspired
by we Eagle was doing with the heat gun
and kind of got got keyed in by Doug
Minneola an old childhood friend of mine
from Foster City that also ended up in
Amsterdam and for me just coming from
that one hit snapped through school of
water-pipe smoking West Coast our you
know if you over packed the bowl and you
couldn't app it through yourself and
enjoy the fresh he will you you were
punished by snapping through that a she
so you packed a freshie for your bro and
I just was looking to emulate that same
sort of ritual and philosophy with vapor
when I took the heat guns and developed
the the chamber bull concept
additionally just a big fan of the water
pipe and the moisture conditioning
component I think you know it's
important to note that especially with
cannabis the the heat and the dryness is
really what does the damage so hot and
dry vapor will still dry your throat out
and irritate it and in fact I remember a
long afternoon
pulling off that volcano with you in BC
and waking up the next morning realizing
man we should have ran that through the
water pipe a little bit more than we did
absolutely yeah that's that's going back
for sure that must be 2001 or 2002 that
you're talking about right now we
definitely have been at it for a while
now mark was one of the first people to
show me I guess simultaneously between
mark and Everett from the verdamper
yeah whoo I also invited onto the show
today I'm not sure if he got the message
it went through his website and they
were checking emails for 48 hours and I
sent it a little bit late but he would
have been also great to have on the
conversation the first time I ever hit
the the verdamper I think it was at
tsoumas place although maybe they also
had one at lucky
others when I with it with the with
instead of the heat gun the strange
little sort of element that ever it made
but yeah between mark and Everett back
then this is you know early 2000s I
guess what I had seen I had seen evil
bill and Eagle was hitting out of this
huge giant so it was very hard to get
the vapors super super concentrated and
so from the connoisseur from the
hardcore like chronic you know we were
always looking like office volcanoes
really cool if only we could make it
still a hundred bags we're in one bag
that was always kind of like the
mentality like how can we get this
perfect constant rated to the point
where I'm actually you know cuz
obviously it was it was a beautiful
thing to be able to hit the the vapor
and have it just the taste of it and the
smoothness of it it and the subtle
nuances of it it was very very different
for anyone that ever went from straight
burning joints 90s we were all just
burning joints and then all of a sudden
someone was trying to show you oh you
can vaporize it it was right up there
with putting water and ice and pot in a
bag and trying to tell people don't
worry we're not gonna ruin this we're
just making hash right now they were
like what like people throwing that herb
away like big big bags of the vaped
herb it's like yeah that we're done with
this and people were like no I can I
could sell that it's like listen you
don't want to sell that that is pretty
much the worst thing that you could
possibly do what about vaporbrothers
when did you guys come online Linus oh
you're muted and you definitely you're
muted right now I muted your mic and you
want to you want to be as close to your
mic as possible because when you turn
away a little bit the mic is cutting out
slightly so as long as you're close your
voice will pick up real nice so yeah
when did vaporbrothers come along no
muted unmuted there's usually a little
button oh there you go you got it
oh you mute it again hit that one more
and wake up in the delay there you go
okay good all right thanks well ed about
1998 winter of 98 we were really doing
it can you hear me at the moment we can
hear you perfect my history was a lot of
going to college and a lot of trying to
cut down a lot of trying to help friends
cut down on smoking and and so I was
making very tiny pipes with very small
holes and it was also trying to stretch
supply because in 90s la it wasn't you
know it's super easy to get good weed so
trying to smoke these tiny bowls
suddenly I realized that I got way more
effect for way longer using less and I
was doing that at the same time as my
friend was investigating vaporizers
because the BC vaporizer was out and
there were a little there handhelds one
was called Terra and we had just
discovered V rip tech maybe a year later
we discovered and we actually talked to
mark we ran into him in Malibu once got
a great lecture he has a lot of info to
give but what we hated about the name
risers that we had was that vapor went
into a glass bowl and it got stale there
and when you went to take your hit the
vapor just went around in circles and we
really wanted to make something that
created the vapor and put it into you
right away my friend was tinkering he
took apart some parts they put him back
together with like a nugget floated in a
piece of pipe that we connected to and
heating iron and he got a hit and I
recognized because I was in physics
classes and stuff at the time that he
was drawing hot air out of a heating
element and through the herb and when we
realized very quickly that the best way
to vaporize was pure convection
basically heat air and pass it through
herb don't touch the herb to hot metal
or anything and basically that's what
Mark McCoy was doing
on a large scale big diameter big
airflow and what this e terre vaporizer
little handheld vaporizer was doing but
it would burn your lips and stuff we
came up with basically here's the
diameter that we ended up with which is
about 11 millimeters on the inside and
that was the perfect bowl for me little
big little SMO for us but it ended up
being like our standard and what we
think we came up with was the good sharp
strong moist hit from the smallest
amount of herbs but still big enough for
a few people and this thing would get
people too high which basically once my
co inventor called me and said that he
was in the fetal position I was like wow
we're on to something we need to do
something with this it that's important
because the world was smoking and we
needed to impress smokers and just like
you know trying to get onto vegetarian
food or something when you try it and
you really just want a burger afterwards
because it maybe ate something that was
not heavy enough once you you can get
this heavy enough and get this strong
sharp thick vapor you think you can go
back to smoking and you can't because
you're affected and of course the effect
was longer it was great because like if
it wears off you can vaporize more and
you get you get right back up again
whereas smoking is more like coffee to
me like it goes way high and then
crashes and you smoke more you get more
more sober you know what's up at that
but yeah that was our start I mean I can
talk forever about this but basically
where we think we came in was well quiet
small could be in your house
this one's beautifully painted but it
the main model will I'll bring one out
little later is a wooden box this is
painted by my girlfriend Lindsey's heart
work she's doing a project with them
with visionary artists on her vaporizer
but basically just connecting and
drawing a big breath of fresh air but
yeah I could go into it forever because
we we got really Micro with you know
what
we were doing what we thought we had to
do was popularize the notion of
vaporizing though because it was really
unheard of and before volcano came out
and went on 60 minutes it was totally
uncool and we were trying to convince
people once you get three hits into them
their proselytize they proselytize
others they're there they're in the
religion almost so we spread kind of
exponentially in it eventually we tried
to just become the most common vaporizer
in the world through our knock-offs
we got knocked off immediately and over
again somewhere improvements most were
we're just cheapens this angled wooden
box that I drew one night on an
all-nighter
I'd like this your knockoffs have no go
so you know that right Hydra - all right
great analogy - with the vegetarian and
just the few things that you said there
I also have to mention the BC vaporizer
because I'm sure nobody wants to throw
that thing under the bus but I'll do it
it was pretty much the worst vaporizer
on the planet yet it was like the one
that's sold so many back in the day like
I know the guy who invented it he sold
thousands of them thousands upon
thousands upon thousands of those
vaporizers were sold and they were the
ones with the little pan and the dome
and you know we got to give them their
place because they almost popularized
the notion of vaporizing
without really vaporizing and I'll give
them another props because it was Shona
Banda who was basically wasting away
from Crohn's disease getting arrested in
the Midwest having her threats of her
child taken and when she came on hash
Church and she talked about the oil that
she was using to help save her life from
Crohn's she wasn't doing mzt she wasn't
doing coconut oil she wasn't doing Rick
Simpsons she wasn't doing any of these
oils or bubble hashes or anything what
she was doing was she was collecting the
condensed cannabinoids and terpenoids
from inside one of those dome vaporizers
and she was collecting that oil and that
oil damn near saved her life if not did
save her life so once again it's always
easy to judge things it's always to be
easy to be like oh yeah that thing's a
piece of [ __ ] there's no place for well
you know what I'll say this there is a
place for it it was a very important
thing for people to see close full-page
ads in cannabis culture and High Times
magazines back in the day and and and
just start putting their money into
vaporizers now some could say it was a
bit of a step back when they ended up
getting it and all it did was really
brown your herb and kind of not really
give you many many rips and I'll
definitely say it was probably in the
late 90s that I started hearing a lot
about vaporbrothers and when I looked at
it I was like okay this is a much better
design like so and I'm sure that that BC
vaporizer helped you guys come up with
what not to do well if I could admit our
first model number one was a BC
vaporizer that had been taken apart the
heating element exposed and my co
inventor basically stuck a piece of
pipes or a direct straight on it and
sucked air through it he was wanting to
draw the heat out of it more and I was
recognizing the the convection going on
and they launched us so did the e terror
that's the other BC vaporizer a neat era
both both got us into it
interesting well we all have to stand on
the shoulders of giants all the people
that come before us all the people that
come after us you know we get stuck in
our egos sometimes and we think that
we're this individual and that were
worthy innovators we're doing this we're
doing that but there's no innovating I
mean ball bags would have never existed
without isolator bags it was first
seeing the isolator bags that gave me
the idea to add screens and to actually
innovate and it's not copying when you
make a product better and you innovate
and you stand on the shoulders of said
giant to move things over to that next
level that's kind of how we've gotten to
where we are today with so many
different incredible vaporizers on the
market last week go ahead I was going to
say you it is not copying but I
understand about that but you give
acknowledgment to where your product
came from you give the abolishment to
where you got this
raishin for your product a lot of these
companies will just take right now
you're designing just Rebecca or we just
we we were the ones who do the first
where they don't even give
acknowledgement to the companies before
them that actually pioneered the way
well you're a difference today you're
you're in a difficult situation because
you're in the pen market and you're like
the only person in the pen market with
high integrity so you're like you have
you are in the biggest cesspool of them
all I know that when you first went to
China to try and develop your designs
and you threw all your terrible designs
into the garbage that we're that we're
not going to pass Gary's integrity test
what happened to those those those plans
that got thrown into the garbage
well you gotta understand China is a
communist nation the IP belongs to
everybody even though that the designs
are there they're not being used but
they are being shared so somebody from
an engineer from another company has
access to the designs that I had that
was being given to our previous
manufacturers this is the whole story is
almost ninety 90 to 95 percent of the
designs are out there are basically
based on what I have done since the year
2008 I'll have to I'll tell you the
story in 2012 I was at age a a show and
my original oil tank that we had coming
out we had that came out in 2011 and I
was at a show and I'm looking at this
guy that this company sell the tank and
knockoff of our tank and he's tall and I
approached him in the I asked him a
what's good about this tank and what's
the difference between this and that and
he's telling me he's giving me his
ourselves a pitch and he's the saying
what we did this we do that
I go you understand that I'm the guy who
designed this right you're telling me
that it's doing things that it's never
intended to do usually and he looked at
me like oh [ __ ] you know I'm just I was
just trying to climb a hill calm the guy
who actually designed the tank
and and I'm looking at them like you
guys even understand what you guys are
doing and uh you know you you're taking
a design that's not even yours and just
marketing it as yours and you're like oh
boo we changed the mouthpiece on it well
that doesn't make it a different design
just because you change the mouthpiece
on it you know so it's companies like
that that are out there right now that
are just causing a lot of problems for
companies that are actually in it for
the purposes that were in it for that
client has said he was there for you
know just to bring a better device to
the market to allow people to not you
know not to allow people to get away
from combustion I got in it because I a
lot of people that I've met couldn't
smoke and and eating was a option for
them so we have to deliver the fastest
way possible
for THC and CBD to hit there they hit
their system and the only way to do that
is the pulmonary you know get it through
the lungs and how do I put this it it's
it's a little bit difficult see in the
world you know the way it revolves and
how how people are attracted to
marketing [ __ ] marketing that's all
I can say right now yeah not only
[ __ ] marketing but like pricing you
know you could just copy someone's
product make it a fraction of the price
because it's a fraction of the product
it's a piece of [ __ ] and people are
gravitate towards that I can't tell you
how many people have bought really bad
knockoff bags and then contacting him in
like these bags fell apart material fell
into my hash the screens blew out and
I'm like oh I'm sorry to hear that it's
like yeah yours we're so expensive and I
didn't really want to you know jump into
it it's like yeah but mine are
warrantied for life and I like I'll take
care of you with customer service like
that's what you have to look at
generally for a quality product that
might be a little bit more expensive
you're going to get really good customer
service you're going to get incredible
warranty and you're not going to be
bummed out if something happens it's on
a fluke because the company's going to
take
you you buy a piece of [ __ ] you won't
even be able to get back in touch with
that company unless you push like one
for sales
if you push two for customer service it
just rings and rings and rings and rings
and rings go you got to pretend you're
buying more [ __ ] from those
[ __ ] understand person - go
ahead I said it's usually the same
person - that picks up the phone for
support and sales yeah yeah yeah that's
always a good sign you gotta understand
it's not only it's not only that the
aspect of it is the original company
take for instance like let's say company
who came up with a design they have to
spend research and they have to spend
money on research and development it's
in the thousands they have to spend
money on molds and there and all of that
now we can't produce it in the United
States because if because of cost it
just the cost are outrageous when you
actually produce something in the United
States and first to protect our IP even
if you produce it in the United States
China can still copy it and as Linus
knows he's you know the taking companies
to Cork taking yeah other companies to
court for IP infringement is a lot of
work and a lot of money being spent on
ridiculous lawsuits now if you produce
it in China okay so now China has your
IP they can literally copy it and sell
it to somebody else does that make sense
so the original company that has spent
the money on research and development
gets shafted because now their product
is gonna has to be priced at let's say
$100 while the knockoff comes in doesn't
have the overhead now they can price the
same product for 50 bucks and still you
know to walk away with profit yeah it's
for sure a problem it's just like
anything right that you have the
innovators you have the passionately
fueled innovators who without them the
it would just never the products would
never come to be because these are the
people who are spending their time and
their energy focusing on how can I make
this concept work
how can we make you know and so it's not
really about like I just want to make
millions of dollars it's not about that
at all and you can kind of tell in the
product and in the integrity of the
person who's releasing that product they
really love their product it's important
to them but once again it's business
right it's a cesspool of business so you
slowly take on the appearance that
metaphor of jumping into the pool full
of [ __ ] and trying to not look like [ __ ]
at the end of the day is a tough gig
there's one other facet to that guys you
know you have the people that have
integrity and are more business oriented
but they have the intent they have the
integrity license from the innovators
license from that impassioned group or
individual that sought the intellectual
property did what they're supposed to do
to get their protections and then they
put their product out there paying a
licensing fee back to a royalty back to
that innovator and then their product
has to be a couple bucks more and then
they get beat up because they're
Proctor's a couple bucks more and the
aah coughs benefited that same
impassioned innovators technology and
they're not paying the royalty so I
think it's important for just consumers
out there to recognize that there is
some value in spending a few bucks extra
supporting the company that actually is
loyalty to the innovators to keep
supporting the innovators to keep
innovating I am one of the very few
people who do that very thing I paid I
have paid royalty fees for bubble bags
from 1999 all the way up into the future
so I've leased Rinehart delp's patent
for water extraction wrist and piece I'm
I'm like one of I'm like one of four
people who have did you just say rest in
peace he passed away
that was my understanding ya know too
long ago bro jeez I was that's insane I
wondered why I hadn't heard from
supporting the family though man so
you're doing the right thing no no
the right thing and I was very happy to
do it and there was a very few handfuls
of us that pay loads bags did it triple
extractor from out east and Canada did
it those are the only companies that
paid him royalties on clearly when you
follow that history I'm not going to get
into the whole thing right right now but
it because it but it does kind of play
into the conversation that were
happening that we're having right now
about you know you're just the
innovators just want to innovate we just
want to like just create and and and do
new things with what the product that we
have is we want to make it better in
some way which often the problem with
that is a lot of people think well what
would really be better is if it was
cheaper and that's um that's not really
better well you don't understand what
one mark was talking about paying
royalties and all and all that when we
came out with the very first cotton this
oil cartridge we were approached by a
massive distributor who was in the
vaporizer industry and literally told me
if I cannot distribute this product I'm
gonna knock it off either you either
sell it only to me or I'm gonna knock it
off it was literally like okay you you
you know and I and I told them go how
are you gonna knock off my patent he
goes it's very easy to circumvent a
patent I just have to change something
on it you know it doesn't have to be big
I just have to change something and and
I will bury you in lawyer fees and after
that I said you know what I'm not even
going after patents anymore because to
even patent something in the cannabis
industries it was nearly impossible in
2011 2012 and to this day it's still
very very hard to patent something in
the industry
paraphernalia itself cannot be patented
a few of them have patents but you got
to look at it this way even when they do
have patents they're still knockoffs it
just doesn't save anything
so royalties it takes it takes the
individual who wants to license it to
say you know what I'm the
pay royalties for this guy even if he
doesn't have patent but but he developed
the technology you know it takes the
individual person takes but in this
industry in 99.99% of the people are not
like that they will literally use you in
Tashia they'll claim over here you know
we got to work together [ __ ] they
turn on the study in the back which is
crazy because what they're really saying
is can you put your hands together and
give me a little boost and you're like
sure and as you bend down they step on
the back here in agony well so why don't
we go through I mean we have in a way
already but why don't we go through our
histories of how we've gotten you know
each of you guys how you really got into
the passion of cannabis and then how
that led you however many years later
that's what I really want is the
timeline back to vaporization or to
start Gary sure in the early 2000s I
started working in the laboratory it was
a medical laboratory what we didn't love
tests and all that I worked my way up
until I ended up owning the laboratory
itself where I've met a lot of people
that would come in we would do we would
draw their blood for the testing and all
that and meeting a lot of these patients
you know you helped me understand
because at that time I was not for
cannabis as a medicine I was totally
against it actually the to me was just
another drug because I've brought I was
brought up in a conservative family so
meeting these general trainee what
happened I said Joe straight II okay you
were at Joe sweetie that's okay you were
a Joe strating and then you started to
learn yeah so in mid-2000 when I started
you know talking to these people they
helped me understand that they actually
started helping me learn how to grow
because we became friends with a lot of
them
and in 2007 they approached me about
opening up a dispensary 2008 2008 is
when we were able to open up the
dispensary when we were opening up the
dispensary I was if I saw one of the
people using an electronic cigarette and
when I saw it I'm like how cool it would
it be if we can put a teacher in there
you know the the only app the only thing
at the time was literally glycerin
cannabis infused glycerin and our like
how cool would it be and the gentleman
that was smoking it was a very good
friend of mine and he said well I tried
it just doesn't work because you take
the cartridge apart everything falls
apart and just can't put it in there and
if I can it doesn't absorb too much
because there's cotton in there and all
of that we set out on a journey and in
the 2009-2010 era we met a gentleman we
met a gentleman that was actually in on
the same path as we were and he almost
figured out how to put the glycerin
inside the you know inside the
electronic cigarette and we we worked
hard then it was still difficult because
of the cotton inside then we met up with
Michael Backus from cornerstone Research
Center in an Eagle Rock California
that's when he said I will put this on
my shelf if you can get rid of the
cotton inside the oil tank which is
basically which was based on electronic
cigarette technology back then
you had to have cotton to be the medium
tool hold the the glycerin no and at
that time I said well it's impossible he
goes well I'll put it on my shelf if you
actually can't get rid of the cotton so
I went back and I back to the drawing
board and I went through maybe about 50
prototypes and a lot of a lot of fees
doing a molding in the research and
designs on them and in 2011 we
introduced the first oil tank that had
no cotton inside so that was that that's
what revolutionized industry because
you look at it every other tank had had
the cotton and had the the heating
element wrapped around it or inside of
the cotton so after a few years you
would actually start getting that burnt
taste and in 2011 when we introduced
that we we sat back a little bit we're
like you know
patting ourselves in the back because we
did something where nobody else was able
to do but before the two thousand eleven
we were also able to get pure oils into
the cotton cartridges which nobody else
was able to do as well so fast forward
after 2011 2012 2013 now we had another
design that had the ceramic this is
where we're we're talking about where
you said all your designs were in the
trash and nobody was using him and all
of a sudden just became popular well in
2000 in the late 2012/2013 era we came
out with the the essential oil tank that
had the ceramic wicks and all of that
well we only did a small production run
of a hundred to get a feedback of people
and how it's used it it had issues and
it just didn't work right so we shelved
that whole design and we decided to go
to different route with the kiss
cartridge where it slowed as you go lake
systems and when we shelve that idea we
we actually totally forgot it that we
shelve the ideal with a manufacturer
that we don't work with anyone because
after 2013 we decided to open up a long
manufacturing because our most of our
ideas and you know designs were being
literally licensed out to other
companies where we had no control over
so when when we shoved that idea and we
will concentrate on the Hercules and the
kiss cartridges in 2013 early 2013
afterwards we went we started working on
the Triton series and which has yet to
come out and all our design is where we
enforce reinforce the kiss cartridge
made it even
better every year with every iteration
of it coming out now the last two years
I was looking at it and and all of these
cartridges seem to come out and had
prefilled the prefilled market within
the past two years worse bulla started
booming and I'm looking at the
cartridges I'm looking at it I'm elected
this is my design
you know everything that I've done in
the essential oil tanks since 2008 up
until 2012 is now being used in the
refill market and when I came out of
like a dude that's my design and people
are like no that's not your design man
you're just acting stupid it's not your
design I go listen man this I even have
forum conversations by now showing
images of a ceramic core back in
2012-2013 you know on the on on tanks
and guess what these new tanks are using
the same design
yeah it's changed but it is based on
that design because it's still you know
so fast forward until now we
reintroduced the pure titanium grade
heaters inside the cartridges and we
introduced the silicon carbide wicks
check this out in 2013 when we started
using the silicon carbide wakes we
started calling them black ceramics we
call them black ceramics just for fun
because we we were pretty sure that the
companies out there would start calling
him black ceramic without knowing what
it was so well fast forward in 2016 2017
and 2018 one company started putting
black ceramics into their oil vaporizers
we started calling our silicon carbide
okay
and being silicon carbide because it was
silicon carbide we just called it black
ceramic well now companies are like oh
well well now we're offering black
ceramics I mean a silicon carbide - whoa
for two years you didn't know what was
inside your cartridges you know you're
calling on plastics you
so so when we started calling a silicon
carbide there all of a sudden you know
left and right there coming out what
cartridges that have now silicon
carbides in them well if they now have
silicon carbide in and what do they have
before it was just ceramic painted black
yeah also so fast forward until now how
do I put this our main goal was in 2008
was for the patients and by the patients
because I was financed by patients by
old hippies by old grandmothers
literally the people who helped me build
the dispensary are the people that
helped me finance the ideas that I had
and until this day you know I will never
give up on that word if I if my company
is gonna go down fine I'll go down
swinging
but I'm not gonna I'm not gonna market
[ __ ] I'm not gonna use butchers
marketing tactics I'm not gonna [ __ ]
anybody and you know the that's the
whole story of how we came into play is
because I saw an electronic cigarette
and because I said because Michael
Backus said you know you can't I'll put
it on my shelf once you can do this and
because of a couple of people along the
way said you can't do it and I did you
know I guess invention is the necessity
of the of the time where if you're not
put into a place where you have to get
out
you're not going to invent that's how I
think with well there's no doubt about
that the pen market sure blew up in a
big huge way and it's kind of like you
know not until I met your your old
employee they're samurais Sam when he
came up and took all these pens apart
showed me how terrible they were and how
everything was super close to the
elements and how solder was getting
baked and he's caught and like all these
different things and sort of started
explaining to me about your company I
was like oh okay yeah I can't like just
be using these things not that I use
them a lot I'd take them up on the
mountain where I didn't want to have a
dab ring or whatnot
but it definitely feels better when it's
this niche like for me there's so like
every vaporizer company
in here right now every vaporizer I have
like 20 or 25 vaporizers I have a whole
variety because I find the best one to
be the one that suits me at the time
that I need it well you gotta understand
I totally understand but the market
right now do you have to I'm laughing
myself and I'm sometimes even like
pulling my hair out is why would people
why would people say it's okay to use
stainless steel as a heating element why
would people say it's okay to use Teflon
like a millimeter away from the heating
element you know but right now that is
the thing it's people literally don't
care it's how cheap you can make it and
how fast you can make it you know finish
now the market itself there's a lot of
dubious players in it where they've good
already gone in and you know they give
out 50 free samples and all of a sudden
all blah blah blah you know this is just
the greatest thing well when you like
point out oh well it has this inside the
heater how's it better what is just
better it's just better you you you you
know it's just that it's better than
your product it's just better but how I
have an uptick right here oh we have the
Omicron yeah I think that that moves us
perfectly sorry I muted myself by
accident that moves us perfectly into
Mark McCoy and the for a company because
when I first met mark
he was like yeah you gotta have the sty
nail gun you gotta have the ceramic core
I'm like ceramic core tell me more what
what do you speak up so why don't you
give us your lowdown mark on how you
came to be passionate about vaporization
I mean again I was just coming from that
woman hit snapped through school of
water pipe smoke in the West Coast style
I mean admittedly I perhaps started a
little more on the recreational tint but
a long time I subscribed to Dennis
perón's perspective that it's really all
medical because whether you're taking
that rip to chill and watch a movie or
skating create you're still
medical benefit whether you like it or
not as as I got a little bit older and
some of the aches and pains kicked in I
realized I'd actually broken my back as
a teenager and had some pretty severe
muscle spasticity coming from something
that wasn't gonna easily heal I realized
that the cannabis literally just made
those spasms disappears so freaking fast
without the side effects of the
pharmaceuticals that the doctors who in
all their wisdom were prescribing and I
wasn't as active at the time because I
was a little bit laid up and you know I
kind of transitioned from water pipe
smoking with the lighters to uncoated
wood matches to vaporizing with heat
guns and it just made the really an
organic transition and at the time I'd
been studying medical aromatherapy the
work of the Swiss and the French and was
very interested in natural cosmetics and
essential oils and yeah I want to say
that was late 90s and 95 96 and it's you
know I've gotten turned on to the to the
to the Eagle bill vape by Doug Mineola
and Adam Dunn that that sort of changed
everything for me I was working on a
shower apparatus for putting essential
oils into your shower water flow and I
woke up in the middle of the night one
night after playing with the heat gun
for I don't know maybe three or four
months and I realized the fluid
mechanics and the gas mechanics were
exactly the same and the only way I was
going to emulate that real fulfilling
full-spectrum rip I was able to get out
of a small glass bowl with very careful
slow lighting with the wood match was
with the venturi effect Bernoulli's
principle realizable she's been right
here in front of the whole time so I
developed the concept of the two-piece
vaporization chamber bull wrote some
notes middle the night went back to
sleep and the next day I was in Berkeley
California at R&amp;D glass basically
groveling to get them to make some
pieces for me and I told myself at the
time I was not going to enjoy any
cannabis until I figured it out I
thought it might just be a couple of
iterations
well actually I thought naively I might
nail it right out of the gate and the
flow form physics lo and behold a little
more complicated than one might think
took me about took me about three months
my bros were all very happy to be the
guinea pigs but I'll never forget when
we finally figured it out and we created
a chamber bowl that worked really well
with the old-style guns and I'd already
looked at some of these heat guns you
know they've been in the history of some
of the cannabis pioneers playing with
them for a while
figured out that the the Stein L German
design Swiss manufactured ones had a
stainless nozzle and a non alumina
ceramic encapsulated nichrome element so
your air was actually going past the
ceramic and the stainless and although
far from perfect it worked pretty
freakin well rigged up with a nice sized
water pipe and we were able to dial in
the technique to get a really full
profile of vapor right to the edge of
smoke or just barely beyond if you
wanted that hybrid experience or even
lower temp and just just vaping on the
terpenes if that was your thing and led
to all kinds of experimentation with
other herbs and botanicals mixed and on
their own and of course eventually with
the inside of my beekeeper brownie boo
our beekeeper brownie boo we start
playing with propolis and really
vaporizing the same way the recipients
did because they always had propolis on
their rocks and those steam tents they
were throwing their their cannabis seeds
there by the article in herb but
remember where the seeds come from seeds
are in the flowers so the Citians also
get credit for being the first to really
vaporize specifically flower material
and yeah here we are today we took a few
iterations on the bowls ultimately
glassblower Steve they're inspired Jason
King with some of his inside-out pieces
on soldering irons and I paid Steve to
make some iterations for us that we
played with for years Sabo was one of
the one of the early adaptors got to
play with it and I remember just not
thinking the world was ready for a hot
piece of glass but
in fact I'll give sable a lot of credit
is the one of the bros who really was
like man you got to just turn people on
to this it's time and yeah you know we
we took a few iterations getting the
elements right and getting you know the
glass sorted so that we could make in a
production environment it's still the
hardest piece we make but when you yeah
when you dial into it if you like the
ritual of water pipe smoking to it milk
it up take a rip you know to your taste
you can dial it to the way you like to
session it's hard to beat man it's uh
you know I still get a lot of emails
from folks just saying you know I love
the system but I I got it you know you
kind of ruined everything else for me
surprise was that was that the based on
the hot glass yeah the hot glass that's
right yeah Brian's brother that's right
well Brian's brother cuz Brian was the
one that turned me on to it but he was
he told me really it was his brother
that kind of designed it and I guess he
would blow the glass for it but yeah
that's great that you guys are still
doing those since I thought it was
lightweight and easy it went in and out
of the bowl nice and it definitely was
glass on glass on glass yeah we now have
glass screens we have custom tool joints
so you can pretty much plug and play on
any water pipe or bubbler out there and
yeah all all glass heating extraction
and delivery and what I've found is even
relative to many of the technical
ceramics that I've played with you
simply can't get a better terpene
expression then with all glass or quartz
that neutral polarity of those materials
really does make a difference you know
people are talking terms quite a bit
these days but you know the the it's not
just about the chemistry it's about the
polarity the energetic component and if
you're using a metal element or metal
chambers or even metal screens to some
extent you're you're changing the
expression from what you would have got
just in those first couple pulls off a
proper cone agreed a hundred percent
particularly having a terpene company
and having access to terpene profiles
derived from cannabis
and and having access to all these
different vaporizers it leads us
beautifully into Sabo from VAP exhale
because the vape exhale was the first
unit that I found I could legitimately
preserve the terpene profile from pure
Terps because I was hitting them on like
a d-mail like a sick dish or a sapphire
dish or quartz banger and they were they
were delicious don't get me wrong but it
wasn't until I hit it through the vamp
exhale a super low temp in the quartz
rod dropped into the glass tube with the
heated like just the preservation that's
the word I use constantly I'm like it
preserves the [ __ ] profile this is
almost what it smells like when you
smell it in the jar rather than it just
it made me realize how different it was
you know convection versus conduction I
guess you would say like putting it
right on that dish and having it just
explode is not as gentle as having it go
into the vape exhale tube and just like
gently volatize into into my bubbler so
why don't you go ahead Sabo introduce
yourself tell us tell us about the
vaping sale and how you came to be I
know it's relatively new but your
history might go back further I don't
know give us a go yeah so we talked
about standing on the shoulders of
giants and well there's one I'm staring
at him right now mark McCoy so I give a
lot of credit actually pretty much
everything I know I owe to mark I was
lucky enough when I started consuming
cannabis as a 21 year old I I was really
late to the game just because I felt
that as a health conscious person I
didn't want to put any smoke in my body
but I had been a stunt man putting
myself through college and the injuries
were building up and finally I started
utilizing some cannabis and I bought the
first vaporizer I bought was the BC vape
it wasn't very good and then ultimately
I bought the Brit tech system and I
noticed that the return address was in
the same hometown that I grew up and
ultimately I emailed Marky allowed me to
come over
I'd only been consuming cannabis for a
few months at that time and so he was
really educating not just it's not just
the at the vaporization aspects of
cannabis but just cannabis in general
very holistically how it was grown how
it was cured how you make hash how you
how you trim it properly so I feel very
very lucky from the get-go that I was
learning from my Yoda Jedi Master and he
kind of introduced me to a bunch of
different people like you know I
remembered the bubble bags you know like
he was telling me all about hash I at
that point I was just getting into flour
so this hash thing was like way beyond
me and ultimately you know like he
showed me all these different systems I
love the heat gun system it was one of
my favorites I introduced so many of my
friends in college to it and then when
he moved to the to the glass wand style
it was just amazing and as he mentioned
you know I was really encouraging him to
really get the word out and to really
promote this this type of ingestion
methodology and I just love vaporization
in general I bought the vapor brothers
I'm a customer of the w-9 up tech
products as well
his sales rep used to come over and show
me the ins and outs of how to use the
pen so I just feel really really blessed
to be here to be able to talk about you
know vaporization in general and also
kind of what what inspired me and
ultimately mark is also a well he not
only influenced me on healthy cannabis
consumption but you know mark is a very
active person he also eats a very you
know healthy diet so I try to emulate a
lot of those things and really try to be
a healthy person holistically you know
not just with my cannabis consumption
but with how I treated my body with
exercise what I put into my body even
some you know spiritual type of
development as well and ultimately you
know I've had bought over 150 different
vaporizers from 1997 to 2011 at that
time I had been working at a start-up
actually the startup was really
- to Mark's house and my boss after we
had sold our company in the Salesforce
my boss was asking me what I was doing
and I told him I had been helping mark
sell vaporizers and ultimately he asked
if um you know if he gave me some
capital if we could design one ourselves
and that was the impetus for creating
the device I called my good buddy mark I
told him I had this opportunity to
create a vaporizer and if he be okay
with it he gave me his blessing so you
know as a I think we were talking about
at the beginning I mean Dennis Peron
just passed away yesterday there's a lot
of people here that influenced us that
gave us this opportunity to be here and
you know I think it's important to let
mark know and I think he knows I mean
he's been to my wedding we were on an
airplane together we got a chance to
catch up recently but if I've never told
him this you know he is he is the guy
that taught me everything and the reason
I'm I'm sitting here so thank you Mark
and and that's my story hopefully it
didn't put people to sleep nice say well
very nice shout out tomorrow you come
out absolutely I think it was pretty
accurate - I've known you a long time I
would agree with pretty much everything
he just said I was stoked
I actually remember the stories John was
Tommy's are like yeah I'm actually gonna
go meet save where I play Patel and talk
about his VAP Excel that I think the
evil that at that time was coming out in
2012 caroused the model stable yeah so
he actually was meeting with you to talk
about the Evo and all of that and he
told me that you guys were actually
using the Omicron - older versions of
the old crones where you you guys had
your sessions together and hopefully we
can meet up because I even told him back
then as I wish I was up there with you
guys you know get to meet sit down on
top but hopefully after this so we can
you know all exchange contact
information you know talk to each other
about the industry and all of that you
know something good should come out of
this I hope I think it will and I think
this is the beauty of what bubbleman is
doing here with this Pro
bringing a lot of people together I mean
I kind of feel it's weird that mark and
I are are speaking more now over the
show then we have you know we just live
a couple miles away from each other but
we'll make it happen
I'm now actually mark with you I was
actually talking to a bald man mark
Marcus and I was all like hey Marcus I
got this project I'm doing and I don't
want to promote it and he's oh like Paul
you know Mark from Veera protecting he's
he's already got that and I'm like
really yeah he goes he's already got
that okay let's find out and at that
time I knew your company I just didn't
know was a full glass air path that when
you just set it right now this full
glass air path now I'm thinking I should
go back to the drawing board again
because I need to make it different now
and it is a different design we are
working on something that's our desktop
that's full glass air path but the only
difference I think between ours and
yours is you use a ceramic feeder we
don't and ours is designed to look like
a spaceship because all everything in
our company is named after sci-fi stuff
we were I'm a Star Trek fan and the
Futurama fan because as you can see we
we have our deserve vaporizers named
Omicron Persei 8 you know and that was
that that idea was given to us through
another friend that is a like a you know
why just if you have your Omicron once
you call the second one Percy and the
third one Nate I go well let's do it
since I like Futurama but after that
after we named all our products Futurama
did an episode about us that you know
that Marcus yeah Futurama did an episode
about as T the terrestrial that's what
it's called the episode I think it's
season seven there Teta terrestrial
that's what it is but either way you
know the I'm looking at going back
retrospectively there's a lot of
companies that are here even
you showed me that Seiko the bubbler
that you have there was a lot of talk in
2013-2014 with people knocking off
because I think you own the patent for
the joint on the bottom of the bubbler
don't you correct yeah there's a lot of
talk of the on the forums of people
knocking that off and how that's not
going to be you know doable and all of
that but either till this day you know
people are still knocking it off and
it's pretty difficult for you to go
after yeah I mean I I I look at the
patents the same way as you which is
kind of like nuclear nuclear bombs you
never use them you just threaten them
and if people decide they're gonna play
chicken with you then you guys could
have a legal battle but the clear winner
is typically just the attorneys that are
getting paid all those billable hours
and it is such a thing it is such a
tough thing that is the honorary truth
right there go ahead Linus I think for
all the work that you put into a patent
and we got patents too and I think for
all the work you put in there's some
good that comes out of it because it
deters large businesses from knocking
you off so you'll deal with all these
small things that you can't whack them
all or whatever and it would cost more
money than designing new vaporizers so
you don't do it you know and just for
the the kind of the hippie ethic of it's
better to put money into developing your
next thing and staying relevant rather
than trying to fight people but anyway
it it the deterrent value I think is
there I hope we've all been helped for
all of us who have spent time and money
on a patent and paid the lawyers so much
someone like volcano or a giant company
well maybe they would knock you off but
my theory is that they don't and it it
if people with pockets won't rip you off
straight off when you have a good patent
and maybe that's prevented a lot of us
from being knocked off by actual serious
competitors
well you gotta understand people with
pockets won't knock you off but they
will bury you in legal fees just to make
sure you don't your patent is
invalidated just look at JPMorgan Chase
and Tesla you know that's that's
basically what happened you know that he
made sure that Edison got the patents
for the four got his patents and Tesla
was basically invalidated after that
dilemma yeah yeah indeed why don't I
think we've gotta now after Sabo to
Linus I just I know you kind of told
your story a little bit but you know
give us the full sort of like
vaporbrothers
but before the passion that led you to
want to do this and and I'll kind of get
deep into you know wanting the vapor
brothers to be the the most sold
vaporizer the passion that goes way back
the memory doesn't always go that far
back but I remember that it seemed like
pot was a good thing it seemed like
people around it were good people many
it seemed like it helped people to be
good people back when I learned about
acid that's such a time commitment and
it's a little scary too it seemed like
weed was a good substitute for it was
kind of a poor man's acid and now that I
realized how hard life is for a lot of
people I realized I was kind of a
privileged kid because I was able to go
college and stuff at the same time when
I proposed to you know my parents would
be pretty conservative what I wanted to
do in life maybe they would come back
with well what what's that going to do
good for the world and that kind of
invalidated a lot of things that I might
want to do with my life that were just
like fun or neat or or ego-driven or
something and that stuck with me and I
was like okay I'd better use my my tools
I wasn't doing that well in college I
was in I was like a
permanent student but it allowed me to
take a lot of different things and so I
thought I should bring together the
things I've been taught from the
engineering or interest in physics
anything from computers and the world
history and now health of course so that
kind of led to me trying to make these
tiny bowls because I was actually kind
of looking for less body impact because
smoking really does well you smoke as
much as you can until your coffee if
you're going for that vaporization once
we discovered our way to do it was
really well less body impact doesn't
just mean you vaporize and feel better
but you can vaporize more and feel bit
fine and as soon as marijuana started
becoming clear medicine this isn't just
recreational this isn't just for fun
these aren't just kids trying to get
high and and you know call it medicine
there are actual patients needing it it
became an important thing and kind of a
kind of a coincidence with us wanted to
impress smokers our device was great for
taking of medicine because it created
some high temperatures that we believe
brings out converts the THC into very
pain relieving components actually I'm
stating that wrong but the higher
temperatures that we were getting on
this which is basically you're riding
the fine line between vaporizing and
smoking we're not a pure vaporizer
unless you turn it down but it's normal
setting when you're drawing it you're
kind of riding this fine line between
getting it too hot and not hot enough
and at that point you're impressing the
smokers because I think you're creating
a lot of the same components that they
are used to kind of that quick effect
plus the body effect to it but
moving ahead I was also as I mentioned
before I was trying to cut down I also
wanted to be a better student and it
wasn't helping it was helping with
creativity but math not not so good and
I wasn't that great at math so but my
attempts to cut down created this kind
of stronger more efficient alternative
and I never felt like people quitting
cold turkey anything is a great thing
because the thing is not necessarily bad
they just want to cut it down and so to
cut something down it's nice to find
something that is stronger in its own
way and so vapor became that stronger
alternative and some people were
surprised to know that we still smoked
but whatever do both that's one thing
that we told people who were not
impressed by vapor overly the vapors not
doing it that much for you sure you want
to smoke smoke also and they they got an
effect that was way beyond what they
could have if they had just smoke and
some of those people went to vapor or
full-time we started getting reports
back from people that had changed their
life or saved their life this thing
about less body impact also allows
people as I said to smoke more and for
some people who really need the medicine
like some people were simply depressed
and marijuana would make them less
depressed and with that little kind of
substitute for acid effect it kind of
would help them come into a more perfect
like personhood like you can think
certain things through and you can get
somewhere sometimes in your mind on it
and then with these people able to take
more they couldn't take enough smoking
their lungs were done some people were a
lot older than us and we're like I can't
smoke on I haven't smoked in years but
with your vaporizer I do it every day
and this thing has saved my life once we
hear that a few times we realize we're
on to we need to do this and it's good
for the world but uh yeah there's so
many things I could get into there I
mean there were a lot of people
who helped us along the way and who
really became the vaporbrothers
vaporbrothers is not just two brothers I
have a brother but my partners were like
our bros and a lot of some people well
for us to start spreading faster we
lived in Venice at the time we wanted to
get to woody harrelson as fast as
possible because he had helped another
hemp company called Hempstead they were
the first like really good-looking hemp
clothes in LA you could be fashionable
and wear hemp it wasn't all like rough
this isn't him and partly done it this
is though they weren't just like rough
and bubbly that was kind of shiny and
and finally made fabric and whatever
that kind of blew up and made would he
not want to invest in companies anymore
but through his friends who actually
took our company and made it into a
thing they were so into it this one guy
his name now is hippie Steve and another
guy named dr. D dr. Richard Deandra in
D'Andrea they hosted me they hosted the
vaporizer and they introduced it to
everybody who came through and one of
these guys had a music studio in the
back he used to he called it smoking
totes his his band he is to do something
similar to smoking totes I hope they
weren't actually harvesting from toads
but they would make music to go along
with that and you could listen to this
music when you did DMT and it was like
you can't really listen to normal
contrived radio friendly music or going
on such a trip he vaporized everybody
who came through there there were people
recording their jazz bands they were
like oh we only smoke joints well and
smoke bombs and he'd like well try this
and they were converted basically and it
was helping them we also we were very
kind of hippie-dippie like wanting to
reject the world of toxins toxic food
was extremely popular things like
vegetarians
we're just becoming really palatable and
good and thick and heavy and greasy and
and lovable and we hope to do that with
vapor turn it from something that might
be a little too light or stale or have
other reasons why people would not want
to do it let me fast-forward again we
also wanted to make a device that was
very simple with this this toxic world
thing we wanted to get all the toxins
out of the vaporizer and with me knowing
that our formula was a very hot heating
element inside it's it's almost a
thousand degrees on the surface of the
heater it has to be that way to heat the
air quickly and give you the four
hundred three hundred degrees air that
you need to flow through the herb and
vaporize the herb just right something
that hot is going to smell and when it
smells you're inhaling particles of that
thing so if it's a hot heating element
you you smell hot metal you're smelling
a little bit of hot hot ions so that's
why we convert it over to ceramic as
soon as we could hot ceramic smells like
hot stone it's there there's barely
anything in it ceramic can handle what
three thousand degrees before melting or
breaking down and this sits here at
1,000 so that was very safe for us
there's glass around it at the bottom is
medical grade silicone which can handle
the the 400 degrees that it needs to
touch everything in the box is meant to
more than handle what temperature it
gets to even if the box is upside down
and and the air vents are blocked it the
point was we didn't want people inhaling
parts of the vaporizer and a lot of
vapor ice can do that I know with Marc's
vaporizers he used the best heating heat
guns that he could get the Stine L with
when Sabo came came along one of the
things that stuck with me when Sabo gave
us some advice once was that he was
wanting to position his vaporizers like
the iPhone of vaporizers and with the
all glass air path all the way through
to where the air is inhaled into the
vaporizer it stays within
glass and never picks up anything our
vaporizer inhales from kind of the
inside in the bottom but what we did to
every part in the ball is to remake it
to be knock exhaling smell when it gets
warm we would even redesign the LED
board the controller board to be correct
no parts get hot that's what makes cheap
devices to by the way cheap devices when
they put it in they don't do all the
work to make sure that every component
doesn't overload itself some resistors
can get hot and start smelling like
burnt plastic and that's just the smell
of Chinese stuff sometimes but what we
did was try to let free solder all the
stuff that we wanted to do to assure
ourselves that we could inhale from this
thing the rest of our lives and and not
have trouble we also inhaled air into
vacuum cylinders that were sent to
industrial hygiene labs which would test
the the vapor or test the whatever might
be coming off the vaporizer and so we
made sure that we got it good to wear
our vaporizer was safer than just
inhaling air like in your office and by
the way the air in your house and in
your office is not that not that great
especially after your your laser printer
has printed a paper another thing people
are very worried about metal ions the
industry doesn't know about metal ions
like the the the whole manufacturing
world around there doesn't care if the
material is not melting they think it's
great and something that could be really
hot could smell like metal and you're
inhaling those metal ions we got rid of
the metal but while we still have the
metal we had to realize we just simplify
it
don't pick like what up tech mentioned
stainless steel you don't want chromium
coming off of it
pick simple materials like iron and and
the nichrome wire that we had to have
that that that could off gas something
but make it small but what I realized
was your kitchen has
an electric range that has almost the
same materials running at almost the
same temperature at a much larger scale
and you're inhaling that forever so you
can't make anything like just perfect
we're always going to inhale something
but our point was to make it much better
than what you're inhaling every single
day
I think the point line is you're done
yours is we want to reduce what we're
the amounts were inhaling we don't want
to make it more with a you know by
adding a box vaporizer by adding any
type of a browser we don't want to
increase that we want to reduce it
forward basically most some of us
actually trying to reduce our carbon
carbon footprint so that I think that's
what you're trying to say correct yes
exactly and you know what call it a harm
reduction device from the very beginning
vaporizers have been haven't they been
called harm reduction devices like Mark
did you use that term absolutely I mean
it's it's through all three of our
utility patents we push the concept of
harm reduction for smoking of any
botannical not just cannabis but yeah I
mean what you said in the middle of -
really I think will stick with me I
think is a good way for for the the
viewers to think about it don't vaporize
your vaporizer and if you're using a
vaporizer that requires you to vaporize
your vaporizer even just trace amounts
of it's probably not the best vaporizer
for you yeah
and a harm reduction device is good term
because especially with a cigarette I'm
gonna just sidestep over two actually
cigarettes with juice propylene glycol
sounds horrible all the stuff that's in
them whatever it's a harm reduction
device you vape a bunch of these
cigarettes you're gonna live a whole lot
longer than if you burn cigarettes into
your lungs so with with harm reduction
devices it's not like there's zero harm
you're inhaling a moisture into your
lungs I don't know what lungs are meant
to take in but I don't know if they
evolved to inhale a whole bunch of of
particles and and and moisture but it is
so much better
it's hard with you know I don't know if
it's just Americans but we're very
all one way or the other way oh my god a
little bit of right now they're finding
out actually this is a whole nother
conversation they're finding out that
this little bit of benzene in marijuana
when it's cooked
especially at very very high
temperatures it's like a being on a very
very hot surface they're finding that
and but they're finding is less than
what you're inhaling all the time and
some people like oh my god I need to
stop and what are you gonna do go to
things that have more you know harm or
whatever but um I'd like to wrap up just
a few thoughts of where we were going
with this though the not tasting your
vaporizer there's a lot of practical
implications for that for one thing with
vaporizing you taste what you got purely
someone who produces material can use a
vaporizer to test how pure their
material is just by their taste buds
I mean your your your tasting your smell
can tell a lot of things that it even
takes test equipment to find out you
know the odor threshold certain
chemicals above the odor threshold are
well sorry I going circles sometimes
though I think you said something very
accurate there yeah the other practical
thing was this is getting back to the
well reliability of it and not inhaling
things we with not the biggest budget
ever we got a little bit of help from
Woody Harrelson's friend not from him
well little from him but more like the
heart help with not a lot of money to
make this thing work better we needed to
simplify it and we just have less parts
in it and simplifying it also meant no
fan no reliance on flowing air in this I
really respect the companies who do have
good electronics temperature controls
fans and things they really hold the
temperature right there where they say
they do this thing has no temperature
readout we just evolved our method to
not need it and what's really nice about
this device in the middle of the night
like at 1:00 a.m. and I'm not all into
acid or anything but just to bring back
that story let's say everybody is on
mushrooms or something in the house and
we're all kind of weird and it's it's
finally kind of gotten to its place and
people are kind of going deeper and
someone realizes they want to vaporize
you know smoke or oh no that's vaporize
hey pull out your thing we we had a
volcano actually I very much respect
volcano for being um it a lot I'm member
one anyway we had a volcano no vapor
brothers on the bar in this guy's house
and just the thought of turning the
volcano on in the middle of the night a
complete crackle II you know back
everybody use this because the only
sound it makes is the the correct
whistle that you should hear when you're
pulling the air at the right speed it's
psychedelic friendly you know yeah I
mean yeah and it's something you did and
the thing is absolutely quiet and that
became part of it and that also I think
helped it get into a lot of people's
houses because people were not ready to
have anything that they would call
paraphernalia being out in the open
especially when their parents came home
or friends came over or or something it
was kind of scary to have this so we
tried to make it very beautiful so they
could stay on their counter and not look
like anything this thing actually rode
around in the automobile and no one
would even want someone actually broke
into a car to steal one we're pretty
proud of that but uh for a long time no
one recognized this as anything else a
pencil sharpener but yet bait that
that's a good beginner of like how we
how we spread eventually we became okay
we need to become a company and we
became a corporation you know and
corporate izing caused me to have to
split up with my main partner which
really sucked he was a co-owner and I
had to buy a mountain and that that
sucked heavy but he couldn't hang with
the corporate culture and a lot of
corporations have to do is totally
antithetical stat the right word to a
lot of our kind of hippie ethics but we
continued with ethics as being our
strong suit also without a lot of money
if you're a good person and you're
ethical and you're helping people you
spread you don't need money to do it we
never spent money on marketing we
eventually figured out how to do ads and
they were always so so odd but you had
to do it to get out to to stores and to
go to the the trade shows and stuff but
really we rode on trying to be good
people have good product keep improving
it and not do the things that seemed
wrong to us and that's basically where
we still are though
I'm actually really it's awesome just
someone new came on it's awesome to see
all five now six of us oh man you really
got the the innovators here yeah I try
to put that you know once I built the
traction of the channel it was kind of
like oh what should I do with the
traction of this channel should I turn
my channel into a cheesy bubble bag
advertisement center where I just sell
all my products shamelessly or do I
invite all the other innovators that I
know that are some of them many of them
are even more inspiring than the things
I've done and sort of share that
traction and then have them help grow it
and build it even more it brings us
thanks for sharing Linus that was great
story I just really important not just
to us but I think for the the movement
because even all those knockoffs they
still rely on us to come up with stuff
we create we all here created an
industry that they see as money and
they're raising their kids on it and our
employees raised a bunch of kids you
know and and they do even though
knockoffs seem like like a pest they
aren't gonna keep going and vaporizing
is not going to keep going unless
innovators like us keep trying to do
what we do that's it it just pushes you
to
to go to the next level and it's perfect
timing because it brings us to tasks who
just came into the room welcome dude
totally stoked to have you here I was
you know I just only have seven days to
organize and curate this show for each
week it's like Sunday's over and then
tomorrow Monday I'm like I got seven
days before I got to have the next show
ready so I'm sorry I didn't put the
invitation out earlier to you but I
think that you know one of the things
that task did with the electric nail and
the highly-educated products is you
really took this whole like vaporization
thing made it even more made it the
ultimate for convenience for for the
dabbing world and I mean maybe even was
I don't know I you're gonna share your
history right now with us once I shut my
mouth but I'm not sure if like it was
even the start of the dabbing culture
obviously we were doing hot knives and
the mayor existed for doing the hot
spoon dabs but dabbing really dabbing
like heating up a dish with the electric
nail like that pretty much coincided
with the release of your product that it
not
oh you're muted sorry I can't unmute you
got to push the mute button on your
screen there I mute everyone's there you
go perfect
I can hear you perfect good all right
well first off don't worry about the
late imitation I always say if you wait
until the last minute it only takes a
minute though we're all good on that but
uh as far as highly-educated goes you
know there were nails before we started
in fact look you talked about building
on the shoulders of giants I have just
purchased my first titanium nail back in
2010 off of Aqualab you know they were
sold out immediately after so I couldn't
buy another one I couldn't my friends
couldn't buy one I had a friend who was
a machinist and so I just took the nail
over to the machine shop we made a few
modifications and just started making
them for ourselves after several weeks I
looked at Aqualab saw they were still
out of stock and realized that there was
a potential business opportunity there
so I sent him an email just said hey you
know we
these available if I'm stepping on
anybody's toes if I'm violating a patent
or or someone's design or intellectual
property let me know and it turned out
that the person who was manufacturing at
the time was a gentleman named kab Lee I
don't know if you guys are familiar with
the Cavallino but it was the titanium
now that existed before highly educated
and he had taken and from my
understanding so this is all allegedly
but from one side of the story
Kappa Lee had taken money for an order
and just kind of disappeared and so he
created this vacuum that we stepped into
started innovating I owe a lot of highly
educated success to the people that I've
surrounded myself with I've been kind of
I would describe myself as a lucky lucky
fool you know my machinist Dave who you
know helped me first replica he is such
a very left brain individual he's always
building his own servers he's basically
built his own Netflix platform that's
private where he rips all his own DVDs
he gives me access to just this weird
genius guy and so I have I had the idea
of doing an electronic mill because I
knew that the torch for dabbing was seen
as sort of a negative connotation people
associated it with you know smoking meth
or doing weird hardcore drugs like that
and we wanted to try and try and remove
the torch from the equation if possible
to make it more socially acceptable we
didn't really understand what we were
doing in the product or what we were
going to get and as the outcome of the
product but I just had the idea anybody
can have an idea you know it's easy to
have an idea the genius that did the
email is a gentleman by the name of Dave
Jensen and I just told him what I wanted
I knew that other people were gonna be
working on it I figured that it was
important for us to get to market first
and so I just put a lot of pressure on
him
to to come up with a design and our
first problem was back then the domeless
design didn't exist it was just all dome
and nails and so the hardest thing for
us to figure out was how are we gonna
get wires inside of this dome
contraption and not compromise you know
the integrity of the airflow or getting
the wires all gunked up and reclaim just
certain things around that so we we were
trying to figure that out and during
this time we ended up coming out with
the v3 adjustable now I don't know if
you guys know what that is but it was a
an adjustable nail for the domes that
could make it adjust to certain Heights
because not all glass contraptions came
to the same standard sizes some people
had larger domes other people had
smaller domes and so the v3 now could
adjust up and down and again you know
that wasn't even my design either that
could be attributed to the genius of
Chad from health Stone class who you
know another person in this industry who
helped pioneer some different
vaporization essential products and he
actually pitched that idea to me
in an online chat like this and so you
know all praise to Chad for that that
idea but after that came out we started
thinking okay so what's next for for the
nail like it what's after what else can
you do to these things and we thought
well what if the what if the shaft was
hollow what could you do then and I
started thinking well the hollow shaft
doesn't make any sense
and then I was like whoa it doesn't she
take the dome away but we were working
on a prototype and right at that time
the first domeless nail came on to
market that I'm aware of was called the
ko domeless nail and I believe it was
developed by a guy named Kevin nail if
I'm if I remember correctly Gary might
know some more about that because I
remember he was around in that that time
frame as well anyways once I saw the
domeless now and once we had our first
prototype of our homeless nail out I
immediately realized
you know we've we've unlocked the
solution for getting the cables into the
to the nail now without having by
removing the dome we can now just get a
heating element wrapped right around it
I pitched the idea to my machinist and
he spent you know a week or two
researching components found you know a
PID found a heating coil from a heating
manufacturer who would go on to end up
you know [ __ ] us over later on but
that's a whole other story and he you
know got the the sheet metal lasered out
the sheet metal to cut and Bend the
housings for the electronic units you
know some of these components like the
PID came from overseas but as far as
everything else it was fully cut built
assembled here in the United States and
he built four prototypes I took one of
them with me to the San Francisco
cannabis cup in I think it was in 2010
it might have been 2011 actually and
that's where we showed it off for the
first time and it was a major hit and
with the release of the email we we
started to kind of discover you know low
lower temperature dabs when the email
first came out there weren't carb caps
and so in order to put a DAB on that
would fully cook off within your breath
you it had to be set at 1085 Fahrenheit
on the coil and that everybody hearing
that now would probably be like wow
that's that's incredibly hot but with
without a carb cap back then that was
almost the temperature you had to have
it set out to make the all the oil cook
away and so anyways that was how the
email came to be I don't mean I don't
want to ramble on too long so I'll start
tying my entire stories all together but
but that was the invention of the email
it was a guy named Dave Jetson who was a
machinist and
and I just pitched the idea to him and
he helped me make it come to life but in
the end you know we only ended up
selling a hundred and fifty units that
was kind of a sad story for us while we
birthed the email industry we never
really got to fully enjoy due to that
that email coil manufacturer that whole
other story which you know I could tell
you it and another time but we could do
a whole show on how we've all been
[ __ ] over and out in our business
trials and tribulations which is for
sharpness sorry to cut you off I
remember I remember tax coming out with
the email little area story back in 2012
he came over at the county connection
booth at the San Francisco High Times I
don't know if he remembers that or not
but he plugged the email and and in
retrospect it's hilarious right now but
it was a very very sad moment at that
time where he plugged the email and I
think half the host power just literally
went out remember that that you're
talking about I blame the show for that
they got it back up and then the network
I liked I like to add the email did work
for the rest of the show but yes it
definitely did cause a little power
outage there for a moment and that was
actually a prototype wasn't it yeah it
was one of the four prototypes right
there what year was that that might be
it that might be it I thought 2011 but
it might be 2012 you know my sense of
time just not good well to have the
different groups that to have the
different groups of you guys in here
from like you know Gary with the pen
aspect with mark from so many years ago
as well as vaporbrothers with these
different
you know produce your own air force
there and the first time I ever ripped
was definitely like a memorable
experience with tasks with highly
educated like definitely helping
popularize dabbing for certain that's
the first name I heard with the titanium
nails and the the carb caps so very cool
and now say bow out with the vape exhale
you know in an in my opinion one of the
kind of younger up-and-coming guys
that's just got the super flare and the
excitement and is able to articulate his
message in this intelligent and has has
a great little unit like in folks favor
inspire me before I ever got into it
before I ever saw highly educated I mean
you were he'll stone monkey or stoner
monkey or something like it is me and
and that is my gamertag on ps4 so if
anyone wants to find me still monkey 55
I remember I remember back in the day
before I even started highly-educated I
was I was using the heat gun to vaporize
weed I even made a song about it a heavy
duty heavy duty heat gun no that all
starts with Mark McCoy so it's that mark
how everything is a pain at war
yeah you know the first time I hit one
of those heat guns was probably with
from Eagle bill but the first time it
rocked me was definitely with Mark McCoy
he was like yeah that's because you just
got a rip yeah alright oh it's great to
have this conversation going you know I
guess at that point in time we're just
we're in the discussion we did the the
past we're in the current we're in the
present of vaporisation and I guess you
know if you guys wanted to get into a
particular type of conversation I don't
know if we want to flow naturally or if
we want to direct it into what we all
think the future of vaporization is
that's what's we're going to kind of
hammer out for the last hour of the show
but we still have a little bit of time
if we want to talk about the present
still what's going on today
I mean it's there's a lot going on up
there as the cannabis industry blows up
worldwide
I wonder if vaporizers will really ever
finally transfer over
when Mark met me back in the day you
must have been to the melting point and
seeing the inhalation station of
vaporization that was pretty early for
its time because because the law was
illegal but because the law was legal we
had exemption 56 s we had these sort of
MMAR licenses that people could have in
Canada so I just used the mentality that
well it's not up to me to police people
to see if they have a license to consume
cannabis medically I can just produce an
environment where they can come and I
had a table with a variety of these
vaporizers from you know the volatize er
the aromatic of thrip Tec the volcano I
think there was a couple of others on
there that I might be forgetting but
just to be able to have people come in
and test the units on their own was such
a nice thing we used a lot of other
herbs and it would be interesting to see
I've personally used herbs with bubble
banks and extracted hashes or oil
extracts with you know micro
encapsulated oils and trichome heads
with the bubble bags using water and ice
and I just wonder if you know the
popularity of vaporization clearly being
fueled and passioned by the cannabis
both patient and recreational
communities I wonder if the herbs will
finally ever break over and will start
vaporizing these different herbs through
all of these different units you know
more than just trying it and never doing
it again
well in reality all our devices are made
for herbs that are legal used yeah well
I'm in Canada we're federally it's legal
to use cannabis and soon we'll have a
federally legal recreational system here
this year we're supposed to get
federally legal rack so that changes the
game I think all of you guys should come
up here and make some videos for your
companies do it I think I think more
progressive formulation is going to be a
big part of the future for sure and
devices that are able to adapt to the
substances that you want to vaporize and
a much broader spectrum of terpenes
flavonoids and various active
constituents
be able to adapt to the users
preferences or and/or perhaps the
extraction artists as they like to be
called preferences - in other words
being able to adapt the device to
deliver you know how much of the oil to
the organoleptic experience the throat
and mouth feel the flavor and how much
of it - the pharmacokinetics the the
deep tissue smaller particle delivery
and you know to be able to tune that
either in a way that's fixed you know by
the manufacturer they can say this is
what I think is right or to the users of
separates and perhaps even be able to
adapt to the users preference by
artificial intelligence or machine
learning and looking at the way they're
dialing and tuning their device and the
types of rips they're taking well mark
no you go ahead
I was I was actually gonna state that
what you're saying is we are there's a
lot more to go from my understanding of
what the vaporizers can achieve because
we've barely hardly started scratching
the surface because at this moment we
don't fully understand the cannabis
plant itself once we understand what
cannabinoids and how terpenes affect THC
a and all and all the other different
compounds is where we can actually start
designing vaporizers that might be maybe
a three phase unit where it starts at
certain temperatures goes up and down
and back you know sideways whichever way
you want it to design the unit but what
I'm saying is until we finally
understand the plant itself we literally
cannot design a unit that is perfect
does that make sense or only makes sense
in my mind no it's a it's a very
complicated process I mean this is why
the pharmaceutical companies have been
fearful of cannabis for so long it's why
it's a tough subject for the regulatory
agencies that are used to reductionist
Western science absolutely one thing
though that is very clear and that is
that just like growing in the natural
Sun as opposed to growing under
artificial light we know that with
vaporizing we are creating very
sophisticated spectrums you know major
cannabinoids but
minor cannabinoids terpene expression
based upon thermal gradients the canna
Canada mimetic effects I mean yet no no
one no one has this understood black and
white to gospel but we do know it's more
sophisticated than then how many people
make it out to be I think that's where I
think really it's going to come into a
Linus hit on this earlier you know the
in my opinion the superiority of the
human sensor you can have all these
complicated sensors but at the end of
the day you know from my experience if
it tasted really good and it felt really
good it worked really good if it didn't
taste really good and it didn't feel
really good it didn't work so well and
that is scientific but you gotta
understand every person's chemistry is
different so that's why we have people
that like the vapor brothers that use
the vapor brothers then we have people
that use the V Reb we V reptak and we
have people that use you know the VAP
Excel it just a preference where one
unit might not work for everybody
where there's different units out there
does that make sense yeah I think as
bubble man said also uh I own all of
these vaporizers so I use them all
differently at different times depending
on the use case and my mood and and what
what type of user experience I want so I
would say it even gets more granular
than that and that you know just
depending on your circumstance you know
you will utilize different devices I
mean you know obviously mine is a
plug-in portable devices have advantages
there and then although both mark and
eyes have all glass air pads you know I
do find there is a distinct kind of
resonance to his device that is missing
in mine and you know and there are times
when I will utilize this device instead
of mine and it all depends on my
preference at the time but I think the
great news is we all have the option to
to have all these various options yeah
I've got what was like like go ahead
people asking exactly you know what do
you think is best I say what's best is
what is best for you at
that point in time you know it's your
ritual your session what's the best bit
well it goes back to what Linus said
earlier names like oh I I don't know if
it's an American thing but we always
like we're over this way or over that
way it's always one thing or the other
and I think it's said to be for not for
North America because Canadians happen
in them as well I've been fighting it
for the last ten years and it's why I'm
much more into having a quiver than
thinking that one thing is better like a
one-shot wonder just one arrow for every
shot I take I want to fit as many arrows
in my quiver as possible regardless of
whether it's in regards to hitting off
of a surface on an electric nail from
titanium to quartz to sapphire to
silicon carbide all these different
surfaces I like them because they they
preserve the terpene profile differently
when I hit a dab off each and every one
of them at the exact same temperature so
I know something's going on my bio assay
is pretty tuned for cannabis I would say
the way mark was mentioning earlier that
that and mine is saying that that is
science you know I remember running mint
through my bags the first time back in
99 or 2000 putting a little bit of the
mint into a bowl and puffing it
interesting and then I put a bunch of
bubble hash and a bunch of mint into a
bowl and I puffed that and I blew it out
and I was like wow like I didn't cough
at all and so I punched into Google mint
and cough and I came up with this like
multi-million dollar study that like
Phillips Morris did on designing the
mentholated cigarette they spent like 12
million dollars to come up with the fact
that mint is a good thing to add into
cigarettes to suppress cough I did it in
like 40 minutes with like a bomb some
matches and a set of bubbled eggs and a
little bit of mint so there is value in
these bio assays whether we're doing
them as experiments in front of us or
whether we're inhaling into our lungs to
taste these different profiles yeah it's
all about the quiver that's why I'm so
happy to see all of you guys in this
room go ahead task it's the same thing
with with you know foods and beverages
you know like some people mm-hmm
don't like coke out of a can but they
love it out of a glass bottle some
people don't like their their food
cooked on on certain materials or
certain materials may cook more evenly
and more better sometimes you just you
know where I find inspiration sometimes
is from spots like that when seeing how
something cooks or seeing how I mean
even our newest product shameless plug
here on our new product we just put out
a new quartz banger called the gavel and
we've got a textured surface on the
bottom which favors the creation of
nucleation sites which helps facilitate
vaporization exceedingly lower
temperatures and kind of learned that
from just you know watching beer glasses
and beer glasses that are designed to
have you know etched bottoms to help
facilitate the the carbonation
separation from from the beer
interesting how a simple process like
adding that texture to the bottom of the
the gavel it reminded me when you said
it of Indra talking about his
hydrocarbon extraction machine of his
extractor and how by putting these
little divots inside his his chamber
when he puts because he doesn't have a
column like most of these products are
made mainly he does gas goes in and it
starts channeling and creating highways
and it doesn't touch all the material
well he drilled all these holes into the
inside of his chamber and so when the
gas goes in it hits these walls and it
causes cavitation which sends bubbles
back into the material and moves all the
material fully a hundred percent at a
time consistently and that really
reminded me of what you simply did with
your quartz banger that's [ __ ]
awesome thanks it's awesome very cool
well I'm feeling pretty good about this
vaporization conversation so we're two
hours in where should we where should we
lead this Conroe
thrown at topic has anybody ever worked
with a fraction of vaporization and
define it well a couple of years ago we
were we used extra fractional
vaporization is just a term that we you
know the we made with the Hercules
because using urban oil at the same time
but using the oil to heat up the herb to
vaporize does that make sense so the
heat created by the oil would then heat
up the the flour the earth that the
flour were you would actually heat up
the oil to vaporize as the vapor is
passing through the earth the herb gets
slowly heated up and vaporize which
would act ad cannabinoids or other
terpenes that are not in the oil itself
does that make sense it sounds like the
perfect temperature for the oil and the
earth the herb likes a little less
temperature sometimes oil you need more
temperature to get that fast see that's
the thing
well back I said has anybody ever
experienced something like that or
something like that we use oil and earth
together in a device that predated our
our dab device just dab onto a ceramic
surface inside but we had a before this
came out we had it in the vaporizer in
our normal vaporizer we had a way into
the top directly down to the heater
which was the right temperature we
wanted the oil to be at and then when
you connected the connected the herb you
created oil vapor and passed it through
the herb the hard part was getting both
to the just the right temperature that
they should be at the oil at just the
right heater temperature we wanted it
dropped right down right onto the heater
surface in there and the herb to be but
when you got both though that was the
best that was a bet I've ever try how
about you mark have you tried anything
I've done with the vo-tech or
yeah I mean I've I've definitely you
know back in the day put a whole bunch
of patties of bubble hash on top of a
fresh pack flour and melted it all
together and yeah enjoyed a tea Bowl I
understand about the Patty part but have
you separated where you actually would
have vaporize the oil first and use the
old vapor from the oil to vaporize the
herb well I mean there was the
separation in another glass screen we
have experimented with that so it's kind
of like you got your flour on top of a
glass screen and another glass screen on
top of that with your with your
concentrate eventually they do sort of
meld together but you are technically
vaporizing the concentrate first I guess
um it's a little a little messy but it
can be fun and tasty whatever - it
sounds like they should be really close
but I mean Gary do you mean like are
they physically separated by a distance
or is is the is it almost similar to
putting wax right on top of your herb
well we experienced it with the Hercules
worry we would load up the Hercules
first and right up on top of the ceramic
rod we would put a metal screen and on
top of the metal screen we will put the
herb where the oil is saturated right
next to the the oil sits right next to
the ceramic rod where it gets vaporized
and that vapor itself gets pulled
through the herb which which warms up to
herb itself then after window when the
oil is done it becomes a convection wall
I would say hybrid convection conduction
for the herb itself does that make sense
yeah so do you get a different
subjectively better effect when when you
experience this well like I said was my
previous statement where we don't
understand the the herb the plant itself
hundred percent well we don't understand
what each compound effect how each
compound affects the other next compound
to me it basically if you let's say if
you have
Oh gol and you have an OG Kush in there
you get the taste of the oil but base
what happens is after that when the herb
kicks in it just intensifies it for me
does that make sense yeah because in the
because of the more compounds that are
found in the plant that's not in the oil
it actually intensifies the the high it
intensifies the effects that the oil
brings initially sets in it's a more
sophisticated spectrum that you're
extracting and delivering I mean this
goes and kind of speaks to you know some
of the research that was put out in 14
by the Israelis and you know a lot of us
old-time cultivators have said forever
that you know is why Sun grown cannabis
is a superior therapeutic agent because
you have more of the minor cannabinoids
you have more terpenes more
sophisticated profiles it's just like
you know it says this is the wine and
weed right you no comparison do you want
you know more flavor sophistication and
more layers there or less and yeah I
think that makes a lot of sense Gary you
also hit on a little nugget there about
kind of a thermal equilibrium you know
there's a lot of talk and vaporization
about the superiority of convection over
conduction from my experience in the way
that we vaporize I've always found that
really the magic is when you reach that
thermal equilibrium the important thing
from my experience has been the
materials so in other words if your
materials are glass or quartz especially
and your convective air flow heats those
materials up to where they reach that
thermal equilibrium that's where I find
you get the best most rapid
full-spectrum extractions enabling the
most rapid full-spectrum deliveries I
want to speak to that and it's something
that has very much to do what you just
mentioned Gary although we never used
the oil itself to vaporize the herb when
surfer a class Brian came up with his
brother with that the one that mark has
now innovated on and continues to push
they just weren't really producing it
like a product but it was the OG hot
glass like a little handle with this
Hawk
that you held into a bowl and so we
would put some Rene herb in there and at
one point I I was hitting a lot of full
melt Renee bubble hash and on a screen
but I would kind of use the match too so
it was just bubbling and never really
completely burning and I always wanted
to combine the two and so I asked Brian
if he could make something that would
combine the two and he came up with this
pipe that was basically two pipes melted
together and they go and they were
separate all the way up to the
mouthpiece where the two bomb stems
would spin and create one mouthpiece
just at the top so you would inhale I
saw at the vapor from the herb and on
the other side I would put a little full
melt like seventy-three micron up Renee
bubble hash and I would hit that with
the match so I would see the smoke kind
of go up but it was really more like a
vapor smoke it wasn't a harsh dirt smoke
you know like almost like a dad up prior
to dabbing and then the vapor would go
up and when those two joined right at
your mouth I swear to god you could
taste their separations in your mouth
like they were joining in your mouth and
to me to this day that is pretty much
one of the most incredible rips I've
ever had so if anyone wants to come up
with the pipe that is add a Brig but
also fits one of the V rip hot glass
wands that you should do that because
people don't know I'm telling you that
was like twelve years ago and people do
not know what that mean yeah I think it
would be some type of an email for four
dabs you know it could be it could be
this type of unit as well like you just
how to make it so you could do both at
once
well yeah markets have you tried dabbing
off a silicon nitride not unless you've
sent me one well take a look at what
Linus has I've been following this
product for two and a half years when
it's it's it's it's different it's a
it's a different ball field a ballpark
that when it comes to dabbing liners
show them the VB 2.50 the 2.5 yeah
I was gonna say I have the Omicron for
sure this is a silicon nitride ring yeah
that's what you know I was looking at
this is silicon carbide your unit yeah
that's really nice but uh this thing we
we put silicon nitride in there because
it was the ceramic surface that could
get extremely hot very fast and not
break because ceramic and glass at
really high temperatures if there's a
big thermal gradient like the edges are
very cold because they're being held in
the middle is very hot because that's
the heating element that just rips
ceramic apart so silicon nitride it
comes from kind of the industry the
heating elements that heat the that
light the gas on fire in your oven it's
a heating element ceramic that gets
red-hot in a few seconds and let's
lights the gas on fire we use the same
material because it's ceramic and we
only want to dab on on ceramic at the
moment that's our I mean it's kind of
the easy way to ensure the taste will be
great but yeah this unit gets up to 800
degree maximum in 30 seconds so right
here while I'm holding it it's gonna
tell me it's ready and the the vapor is
really good because it's a slightly
textured surface I don't know if that's
doing what um what did our email for I'm
sorry I forgot your name email hmm
task yes was talking about maybe on a
tiny scale the roughness in the surface
of the silicon nitride it does seem to
be mariah's quicker
we're running quite high temperatures in
here and that's that's a whole thing on
itself kind of so hot that the the
material doesn't actually the devs don't
actually touch the surface they they
bounce and evaporate in the air and you
get the entire hit in within a second
this is a very quick way to vaporize
even if it's a tiny little dot of dads
it'll it'll go completely and evaporate
but yeah this is very obviously
say you can't be dabbing that with the
lid off if it vaporizes in less than a
second you must have put it right
through the hole in the middle there
yeah it keeps it mostly contained our
first models really kept the vapor
contained because I'm I'm big into not
letting it go into big spaces and
learning from the dabbing guys because
when we made this emails were coming out
with those domes and those even with the
Domus nails they're keeping the the dab
smoke within a very small area this is
actually quite quite big but when this
started we were still doing bubble hash
and actual hash and it was the right
volume to keep the keep the vapor
contained but this hole is where you dab
through and it's the intake that's
double duty and the only reason the only
reason I brought up the VB 2.5 Marcus as
you're telling me as you're saying the
future of vaporization see with what
they're doing it's something different
they're doing silicon nitride we've done
silicon carbide and what the industry
standard is right now quartz and before
quartz it was the highest ceramics and
before that it was the titanium and
before that it was the the hot knives
and before that it was stones so right
now we have you know if we haven't gone
through the full spectrum of materials
available what we can actually do so
right now what the industry is looking
at is quartz but I think II we have a
long way to go before we can actually
make the perfect a vaporizer where there
it is the nail whether it's an email
whether it's a handheld portable desktop
or whatever there's a long way to go
before we even come to the perfect
vaporize I think I think that quartz is
gonna be the the preferred material for
a long time and let me tell you why I
think that glass is always you know been
the ideal thing for the consumer and
they started with metal pipes they moved
the glass pipes you see a noticeable
difference moving from a metal pipe to a
glass pipe and then you know it's just
kind of the same thing happening through
the dabbing culture now but now you
a material of glass the quartz that can
withstand the thermal shock that the
process dabbing undergoes and so you get
that glass flavor and it it's it's a
hard material to beat the reason why
it's not kind of favorable to to these
vaporization electronic production
scenarios is because it's just got such
a low or such a different thermal
expansion rate than all these other
materials so you try and you try and put
it with something like a heating element
or you like even consumers will wrap an
email coil around the Banger to try and
make you know a quartz email banger but
it'll end up breaking their banger
because the the coil expands and then it
shifts a little bit while they're using
it and it's not on the same way and then
when it cools down it's now pinching the
glass and and it breaks it and so quartz
is is not a very friendly material to to
manufacture with when you're trying to
turn it into a heating element but all
that being said you know with with the
community where it's at right now I
don't think that any of these other
materials might be great and they might
be suitable but I don't see any of them
surpassing quartz and we were talking
about silicon nitride you know I have
concerns about silicon nitride I mean I
guess it depends on the application that
it's going to be used in but I mean even
on the Wikipedia page that I pulled up
right here it says main hazards when
heated decomposition silicon nitride may
emit toxic fumes of ammonia and ozone
contact with acids may generate
flammable hydrogen gas so um we got to
kind of be careful which materials were
touting is as being superior I mean if
if someone's making an L out of this and
someone comes along and hits it with a
hydrogen torch or even a map gas torch
or even if the class blower decides
they're going to use their last one for
to heat it up you're going to have a
product issue and so I usually feel
comfortable if we're just a fraction of
that the decomposition temperature did
they name what it was degree right here
it says that the says that the melting
point is 1900 Celsius which is extremely
hot but that is probably not taking into
consideration that the stuff that's
going to be going on to it like if
you're burning contaminants on the
surface that could make it decompose
exceedingly lower temperatures so that's
interesting
I think quartz is a perfect material the
silicon carbide that Gary's using in the
up tech I see as necessary because it's
a very porous and bumpy material and the
whole point of these these little dab
pens is just kind of suck the oil up
into the coil by wicking and oil will
wick up a surface that is rough really
easily and fast and that will keep the
coil nice and moist
and and then the coil won't get hot if
when we through quartz into the bottom
and and gary has done it too and a lot
of people swear by it
when you put quartz as the core of the
heating element well it's slick and it
doesn't wick the oil so much and
actually not at all you have to often
with a quartz pipe you have to like do
this to it to get the oil to actually
flow under the heater I get what I think
is a harsh sharp over heated hit and I
believe it's because quartz on its own
can't be a wick it's so well so as much
as silicon carbide can but I think that
we I mean I think we should all test
this especially if we helped each other
we should pay for the testing for a lot
of these materials directly and come up
with what could be a meaningful test but
we all of us are cut are pretty much in
the safe zone when we're at just a
fraction like a third of the temperature
needed to like break the material down
or
melt it or to even make it move or to
make it short life with Gary I know with
up tech he's concerned about these
things lasting for a long time so it
kind of goes hand in hand that when you
make a product and you figure out how to
make it last a long time that's usually
figuring out how to make it don't break
down even a little bit during normal use
or even a lot of use these things should
be made for heavy dabbers to use them
forever and they shouldn't fail on them
or else we keep you know we keep working
on it let me clarify I was definitely
kind of speaking about materials that
are gonna be helping flare oh wow yeah
yeah so that's kind of where my product
specialty is right now as we've moved
away from electronic assemblies and
things of that nature we folk einde of
more of a material science I'll focus on
that over here now with between the
materials and anything now so oh you're
talking about flame because I would see
you as an electronics guy but it's funny
cuz uh we've been playing around with
flame because it's kind of a new to us
because we've been around electronics so
much and sometimes it's fun to hear the
sound of a torch I mean the point of
your email and all of our products is
you can't hear vaporizing happening in
the next room and that's kind of nice
sometimes when you don't want the whole
house to know about it these materials
guys you know will be I think the future
will hold the development of the
materials to where we find that there
truly are best of all worlds if anyone's
dove into the Technical Ceramics space
they're doing all kinds of crazy things
I mean combining quartz dust with
various ceramic components to creating
quartz ceramics
they're absolutely happy and middle
ground that that I think we will get to
just a matter of pushing the the
material science no I understand about
that mark well what task was talking
about it and I think where we got the
mix up is task was talking about an open
flame where you gotta heat it up to a
high temperature then when it that could
break it down but what
Linus and the vapor brothers are doing
with that silicon nitride is it's it's a
control temperature where it doesn't
reach you know 2,000 degrees Celsius is
no way and what he what he explained was
and that's the thing I love about the
via the VB 2.5 is is it doesn't paper
ice on the heating element it vaporized
like maybe what was it a half a
millimeter you said above it right in
the air that's my theory I mean this is
the heating element but that helps us to
not have such a hot heating element if
you separate the heating element in
space between the helmet and what you're
vaporizing you have to deal with a very
high temperature that's like what task
was talking about with he's he you need
a really good heater to heat an email
because there's a little distance it it
needs to run at a very high temperature
so the email can run at the temperature
you want but as you're as you mentioned
it's a fraction of a millimeter the
distance between the the heating surface
and the dabs so I'm I'm so that's a very
small distance but at least the dabs
aren't settling down into the heater and
and and settling down into the material
and then turning black and and smoking
they're they're evaporating
theoretically in the air right above
it's the same effect as when you turn a
skillet on your oven up so high that
when you throw water in it it bounces
because it's being held up by its own
evaporating but its own vapor and that
effect they call it like Leidenfrost
effect they need a more catchy name for
that by the way the Leidenfrost effect
is what we were going for with this
device see that's what I was trying to
say is there's right now the industries
set on quartz we don't know what the
industry is gonna be said on five years
from now it's just gonna is its fluidic
right now because right we don't have
the perfect answer to any of this no she
says nobody comes most how it happens
it's just people like what they like and
whatever blows up blows up because
that's what people like and you hope
that what they
is actually the thing that is actually
you know better for them more along the
lines of preserving terpene and
cannabinoid profiles rather than
absolutely destroying them and yeah
there's more information go ahead yeah I
was just saying I mean I'm obviously a
big believer in science and technology
and I I love all the things that it's
done for us not just for the cannabis
consumption side but for everything in
general but you know like my good ol
buddy mark likes to tell me Whole Foods
are always better than eating EAS
metrics or any of those meal replacement
protein shakes that I used to scarf down
at his place all the time and you know
sometimes I always think back man
are we over complicating this because
the plant in its natural form sun-grown
it's just so awesome and I think bubble
man said it best you know if it feels
good if it feels right then maybe that
is the right way and I don't want to get
too much into hippie dippie territory
but you know it does feel that way like
as I started making all these technical
improvements to our device you know and
then I just thought about you know the
first vaporizer I use the heat gun and I
really thought man the heat gun you know
I haven't used it for ten years but I do
feel like if I use that right now I
think it would be comparable to a lot of
the unit's out on the market still you
know so I think there is maybe going
back to basics and it does seem like the
world is kind of going back to basics
again and maybe that is the best way to
ingest the can of cannabinoids and I
hate to eat and run or not eat and run
but it's time for me to take my kids to
go eat so I have to go run now and I
appreciate being on the show Marcus
tasks Mark Gary Linus thank you very
much for all of your contributions to
the cannabis world I I really feel it is
important to to give credit where credit
is due and all of you guys have
influenced me in one way or another and
I'm glad that I was able to do the same
so thank you guys and well I'll continue
watching on my cell phone while you guys
continue educating me I appreciate you
being yourself have a good one thank you
yeah awesome always good to have Sabo in
the house and sharing his his passion
he's just one of those guys that he's
ignited with it you know he's deadly my
words think for his vaporizer now
yeah I've been hitting it the whole time
he has these little quartz rods that you
failure your concentrate with and then
you just slide it right into the tube of
the of the piece the bomb goes right
over top but yeah these little quartz
rods give I mean they dab delicious one
of them I think the ones before I tell
you about this which is crazy I'll tell
you one thing about this when I put like
a drop of pure cannabis drive terpenes
into this thing with nothing else right
and turn the unit down and drop the
quartz rod into the glass tube that's
been heating the air up just the way it
seems to heat is one of the most
preserved pure terpene drips I've ever
taken and I've done like 20 30 in a row
like done some gauntlets with it it's
actually astounding how how much it
preserves the rip it definitely hits
table and we envision really really
efficient Annina ya know it's I mean I
have both my electric nail I got a mr.
hotbox going right now and I've got my
fav exhale going I usually have like two
or three different things going that I
can that I can rip at a time just
because I love a little bit of variety
in my life do you uh you use torture
dollar that are you comply hard use
torture I use torch I have a torch right
here it's just not it's not show
friendly notes you know what I have used
the during the show in fact for a while
there I didn't I have a dab inator I
have a Dean a love mr. hot box they're
all just sitting here I used them at
different times but for a while like
maybe a month or two I was just torching
I got into torching I came way late to
the torch game and I definitely am NOT a
fan of like knocking it over and burning
my car seat or burning my friends arm or
all the sort of like non like the torch
etiquette that is that not yet exactly
dudes back
I know and those burns we were talking
about it the other day with a friend the
burns that you get on the inside of your
arm they look like like like you're a
mess junkie or something I mean they
never go away they just are there for
like years
very good they don't hurt right when
it's hot enough you can't feel it I
tried I tried to fight the torch you
know I tried to do the whole email thing
but then the torch just came back full
swing then like you know for being my
market it did ya know the torch is
definitely popular like I said I'm a
quiver guy I'm definitely not trying to
be all like anti any particular one
thing I'll just you know I might not
smoke BHO or co2 oils but at the same
time I don't make it my mission in life
to make sure that nobody else does
either maybe a little bit more more like
that when you met me at oh hey Mark yeah
Compassion's market do you time it you
set your timer and you know you won't
let anybody touch it on us it's gone the
well you know what that's sort of be
really super new [ __ ] eventually you
just know your nail and you know how
long to hit it for and you know how long
it cools but the risk is quite you know
you use your wrist to tell how hot it is
can also really for me I'm avoiding one
thing in one thing alone with the torch
jazzing my banger who burn and black in
my hit and it also tastes like ooh like
that's something completely different
from the beautiful tasting grip I would
have gotten had I just allowed it to
stay in an oil like when I'm when it's
still in an oil I feel it like I
vaporize it and when it's Chaz my banger
and I need to get the DC glass cleaner
out that I feel that it's either but I
got to get on the timer like thank you
say it's super-new [ __ ] well here's
super new number one right over here
then just because it's like you know I'm
I'm uh you know I'm waiting a minute for
a banger to cool down is a long time to
wait and I get distracted you know I
checked my phone I see a notification
and sooner or later I've missed my
window so I've got a timer with it with
the alarm so it always goes off I always
get it at the right time and that's
that's really kind of what it's about
it's more about a discipline than than
being a new no offense or anything but I
know none taken
I was using it more like as a joke but
in reality I don't heat up for for that
long I don't have to cool my nail for a
minute because I don't take monster dab
see I take many many many like smaller
dabs so when I put a dab on a nail
it's not cooling the nail down so much
that I have to like heat it up real hot
for a minute and bring it down or heat
it up for 20 seconds with the torch in
order to bring it down also I'm hitting
these giant [ __ ] you know these
things are big he's different I got a
bunch of these JP ones and I got like a
I think DC sent me a double XL they're
all the ones I have are big so I become
a noob instantly if I hit someone's
small little banger I mean that I need
the timer immediately great my own
banger I'm pretty good well then the
these new ones that we put out there
they're a little different to the the
quartz material has a different thermal
properties than traditional quartz so
you know a twenty second heat up would
result in about a sixty second cooldown
yeah that's generally what I see with
some of these larger ones I have now I'm
like more like heated for maybe ten
seconds and just with my wrist it's you
know not very long that I wait twenty
five seconds or something close to
thirty seconds and then I'm have my
little dab and it definitely doesn't
work as good as having your nail plugged
in or having your timer and doing it
exactly the same amount each time
alright just that's it's all what you
choose in the end for sure you guys
believe in carb caps
you do you believe in tight carb caps
and really pull in a vacuum I like the
opportunity to have that I got these
puke and Eagle ones that fit into quartz
bowls like similar to the one mr. hotbox
has it fits very tight and when I put my
finger on the hole
there's no pulling through it anymore
you know it's I like the ability to have
it so I can do that if I want it but I
definitely don't want to hit my hole rip
like that every time I'll tell you when
we first put out our first carb cap back
in I think it was some 2012 might've in
2013 again I'm bad with dates but I was
under the impression that you know the
vacuum pressure played a substantial
role in the carb cap but as I've kind of
moved along and grown to understand it
better I think that it's good to have a
good seal so that your carb caps
functioning the way it's supposed to
functioning like you don't want air to
be coming around the sides where it's
not supposed to be going so a good seal
is important but I don't think that the
vacuum pressure placed so much into the
functionality of it as much as just
having a constant flow of new air to mix
into the oil and having the air thin the
oil out and by thinning the puddle out
it vaporizes easily because the depths
of the puddle is less and when you have
when you have a deeper puddle it's under
more surface pressure at the bottom and
it requires more energy to you know to
create nucleating or boiling and so by
thinning out the oil it allows it to
vaporize at least that's where my
personal understanding of it is that
right now and and I may be wrong but I
don't take that the vacuum effect of the
carb cap has too much to play in the
functionality of it I wonder what mark
mark McCoy who has a lot of deep
understanding of certain physics here do
you have an opinion on do you think I
actually put quite a bit of effort into
this last went first the principal state
of the art dabbing gear kind of came
late to the game as well I've played
with torches I think that there is
something to be said about the thermal
gradient in your timing and that's one
thing that you know you don't have with
the emails at the present although I
think you may see some of that stuff in
the future and what I found is it's kind
of a combination it's
the vacuum and it's the cyclonic flow of
some carb caps that like TAS said
spreads it out it's just like when we're
vaporizing flowers you want to grind
them up so you have that surface area
you don't want to grind it up so fine so
that it cakes together and interferes
with the airflow but you want to grind
it up fine enough that you really are
exposing your your full bowl all those
particles to that nice convective flow
and eventually that that thermal
equilibrium when it's reached in there
so I think it's it's it's a combination
it's both the the vacuum and the the
airflow and what I've found is the
cyclonic flow that spins the oil around
in there is the most effective in terms
of being able to go to get a nice
fulfilling thick condensed vapor but at
the lowest tenth possible so you're
minimizing the denaturalization of the
important components really really
important with the terpenes you know the
terpenes he'll these are these are these
are solvents they're gonna vaporize
really quick they're very volatile and
if you want that full spectrum you want
to be at the lowest temperature you can
possibly be at and I find the cyclonic
vacuum is the way to do that I got
turned on to that actually as a pursuit
because we have had some customers use
our heat wands as cyclonic heated
cyclonic vacuum and we're just blown
away that they were dropping their heat
wand as a carb cap down on a banger and
able to go even lower temp because
they're getting vacuum that's spinning
the oil around that's already heated
because of course that vacuum is coming
from the air spinning around the hot
glass element of our wand and so we've
been playing with this we've got a
couple products in the R&amp;D pipe that
would allow people to go this route if
they already had a wand and also a carb
cap design that would would would really
help maximize this based upon the same
flow form physics we have in our in our
vaporization heat want that's
interesting it reminds me I had invited
Enrico today from the sublimator company
he also kind of tuned into the venturi
fact and he you know one of the things
that I came up with why his thing is so
ridiculous is because because it does
give just an insane like its it's a
little I don't mean ridiculous in a bad
way like I thought it was one of the
tastiest rips the first time I ever hit
it it was just kind of kind of blew me
away actually I couldn't really believe
it because it just was such a big
crazy-looking thing and I was like holy
[ __ ] I'm gonna burn my house down with
this thing he's like no no it's good
check it out and I I hit it and was
immediately blown away and then I
started hitting it when it wasn't when I
wasn't getting the hit and what I was
noticing was you can't take the heat
wand and put it on the bowl and have a
rip his bowl was like this big like
titanium bowl that you needed to heat up
with the wand so it was the same idea
when they were both heated up and I
spoke about this with the hotbox guys
recently who have this little this is an
electric nail vaporizer that you put the
coil over top of here it basically goes
like that
and then they have a little heated pan
here a little screen that fits right
into here and it sits on your on your
pipe it screws into like the base
electric nail this thing actually
[ __ ] works really good and I told
them right away I said you know if you
keep this warm inside the thing before
we hit it I bet you it gives away better
rip and he was like oh yeah we figured
that out right away
so there's definitely something
important to be said about that like
when you're coming up with these designs
if you're an innovator listening to the
guys on the panel right now and you're
trying to come up with these unique
designs at least for vaporizing that you
know you can't just bring a component
that's totally cold into the mix or even
on the smallest level it really affects
the temperature of the surface that
you're dabbing off of or using to vape
off of and that in turn you know affects
everything in the end and you might just
miss that magic and I don't understand
all of the things you know to the level
that task and mark and the guys on the
panel are talking about but I definitely
get a good idea and I'm glad there's
people that are this passionate about it
paying extra attention to those very
subtle things to you know create the
nuances that make a great product great
you can't have a symphony with just the
bass no you can't
marked a quick question when you were
talking about the venturi effect and all
that have you ever come across the
notion have you ever thought about that
the less oxygen produces more vapor yeah
I mean I think that's another component
that's important to consider the vacuum
consideration I mean if you look at our
water pipes you know we we have we you
know back in the day when we started our
water pipes and bombs you know a bit
controversial in fact still to this day
some of my family members will jokingly
asked me if I still have that high-tech
bond company but if you say oh that's
high-tech you asked me am I still
smoking I'm like no I'm a pricing what
the hell is that
and I'll just leave me alone I need to
work on something if you look at our
vaporization water tool design I used I
sketches not just because I like the
option of running ice through the whole
tube but you know it really reduces the
air volume in there so that once you're
pulling that vapor through there it's
it's really minimized any oxidation and
so the vapor is more it's it's it seems
to be more active it seems to be you
know a racy sativas a little more race
here
real heavy indicas a little less heavy
in fact if it's late at night you know
often intentionally mix some air with
the vapor I'm pulling off the off the
tube or even not run as much ice because
I want a little oxidation to create a
heavier effect so yeah there's
absolutely something to that back Gary
okay yeah because we came to that
conclusion when we were designing the
Hercules that we made the air path so
tight that you had to mouth too long it
instead of going straight too long but
the vapor production that the vapor that
it produced compared to let's say a open
coil design and then depends where it
was totally different and about the
venturi effect that you're talking about
that does play that does have a role in
vapor
in itself it actually adds a how do I
put this it adds to the effect of how
much vapor it creates the the quality of
the vapor and how fast it actually
entered a half hour how fast it actually
gets into a person's lung were how do I
put this I'm not that I'm not the best
articulate person I can visualize it in
my brain but whatever you're doing and
whatever you talked about is actually
what needs to happen in vapor what needs
to happen in portable vaporizers and
that's the direction I think we're going
on right now yet it's a huge difference
the flow form physics makes I mean to me
it's still kind of dumbfounding that
open-source math that's been around
since the 17th century is largely
ignored in this industry or it's just
accidental when it factors in for me you
know I studied medical aromatherapy long
before I got into vaporizing cannabis
and I really felt the terpenes the
symphony was ultimately going to be more
of the magic because cannabinoids would
be sort of commercial commodities and
you can only create these sophisticated
terpene profiles you know by growing the
particular cultivar in the particular
appellation a particular vintage and so
always wanted to preserve those besides
just sort of being a flavor flavor snob
I guess by nature and so with cannabis
of course those terpenes go at such a
lower temperature than the cannabinoids
so if you want to have any chance at
getting the full spectrum vapor that
cannabinoids and the terpenes in the
same inhalations like you do off those
first couple poles of a properly rolled
cone or proper uh you know low tamp just
waved in the the would match across the
top of the V Bowl long rip you really
had to have a small sample size and find
a way to extract fast and efficiently
and for me it was yeah Bernoulli's
principle and the venturi effect which
as I stated earlier I was actually
studying for a shower aromatherapy
apparatus and I woke up in the middle of
the night and just realized ugh
mechanics fluid mechanics same
principles that's the key to getting the
best fate and that was where the is
where the design concept came for our
chamber bull still works even with the
venturi effect what we're trying to
achieve when we came to the conclusion
at the venturi effect was with its I it
was called cyclone tech for us when we
tried to do the Erb cartridge for the
vaporizers where we you don't have to
stir it anymore because at that time in
2012 you have to literally stir the
herbs inside the personal portable
vaporizers where we introduced what we
didn't introduce it we were working on
the cyclone tech where the air would
circulate around and in the herb itself
before being extract before the vapor
being extracted that makes sense for
some reason I can't hear anyone also
about that guys I was muted yeah
absolutely that makes perfect sense and
I think you know this is you know this
is this is where you're splitting hairs
but it's these these these hairs being
split that are the difference between a
good vape and an exceptional bit
yeah but too bad we weren't not able to
perfect the technology but it is
something that needs to be looked at
again because like like you said the
venturi effect what what actually people
are doing with the Karkat carb caps
right now is they're spinning it to
create the venturi effect inside the
quartz bowl so that that's just coming
to light I don't know how long that's
been being done but I have begun to
notice that where if you go back to how
do I put this basically what we need to
do in order to make the vaporizers
either whether it's a desktop or a
portable perfect we have to look at the
mathematics and what was discovered
hundreds of years ago yeah if you look
at that face you look at the old hookahs
you know as the article that we started
this discussion with you know sort of
the the first ancient vaporizer they've
got their charcoal holder that is larger
than where you actually pack your
your your cannabis or your tobacco or
your hashish or whatever matrix you're
vaporizing and that air that sucked past
that charcoal is getting heated and then
it's being accelerated by venturi
through your substrate that you're
actually looking to vaporizer
really in the case of hookahs hybrid
vapor smoking and yeah I mean it's it's
really nothing new it's the same way
nature works if you look at the way
waves are created in nature and wind
gets funneled through the forest it's I
think that's you know for me that was
always where the inspiration came from
the physics of nature but you're
absolutely on to it love to huddle up
i'm i'm fairly burst in the venturi
effect and Bernoulli's principle let me
ask a question real quick because i'm
trying to catch up to speed with you
guys i mean i'm familiar with the
venturi effect but I'm familiar with how
you're applying it in your devices are
you putting your material like at the
choke point before or after like where
are you putting it well in in our device
we have a bowl that's literally below an
intake that opens up wider so your your
your hot air that's can your convective
hot air source is being accelerated and
condensed by venturi right you think
it's reaching its point of maximum
velocity and maximum pressure right as
it goes through your substrate and for
me that was the magic especially with
raw herb you know you've got such a
broad temperature range across which the
terpenes and the cannabinoids release if
you want to be able to have terpenes and
cannabinoids in the same inhalation
which I do I prefer it that way you
really have to find a way to make your
extraction as efficient as possible and
that was that's what the that's what the
venturi effect does for you are you
taking advantage of the low pressure
that happens at that moment to draw it
out of the herbs more yeah we all
difference in pressure absolutely
big-time I mean the it's it's it's it's
the flow form and the pressure lavaca we
didn't take advantage of venturi on
purpose at least in this but we did
definitely this little ceramic injection
molded piece
is made a little bit asymmetrical it's
meant to create a spin if there wasn't a
spin already we found that air goes
every which way super fast though oh we
wanted to make sure that the whole bowl
vaporize is not just the middle but
that's mostly what we're going through
but actual a real venturi I've only seen
in in your vaporizer so far well there's
the venturi of pipes that I've seen that
the handheld pipes it's not a vaporizer
but the pipe itself creates the venturi
effect where it looks cool I'm not sure
but I haven't tried it yet but that's
that's another one that's out there
currently hey Mark let me ask you a
question real quick what uh you said
that you I believe that the vacuum comes
into play and I used to think the same
thing too so can you just elaborate on
yeah I mean absolutely especially to put
it in the terms that you're probably
most familiar with again as I said last
winter when I sort of have more down
time for R&amp;D and playing with things on
the benchtop I really said hey I'm gonna
I'm gonna figure out this dabbing game
and test you know all the different
state-of-the-art devices I played with a
number of the different american-made
coils I found that my preference I liked
just wrapping a coil around a glass or a
quartz banger because of the simplicity
but like you said there are cords there
for sure
at the end of the day the the carb cap
was everything it determined how low of
a temp
I could vaporize my my rosin or my Mike
Mike cryo ethanol ik I could go
literally to temperatures just above
what I vaporized flowers at if I have a
strong cyclonic vacuum and so I'm both
spinning the oil around in there like
you were touching on earlier to maximize
the surface area exposure to the heat
and I'm creating vacuum which of course
lowers the boiling point in the
temperature at which the phase
transition takes place right and
obviously you know in order to create
that vacuum you have to create
restriction so it's it's kind of like a
give or take you you're gonna have a
really dragged hit then
if you're getting that suction vacuum
that you want or you're gonna have a
nice you know kind of free-flowing it so
I guess it's just gonna it's about the
balance I think you know so many people
came from the the bond ripping of
flowers world where the idea was I want
to snap it through so fast
I need the least amount of resistance
and I you know hey I get it
I understand that's what some people
prefer at the end of the day for
vaporizing you actually want to paste
draw anyway so you know if you want the
cleanest full of spectrum vapor you want
your medicine to go the farthest the
least amount of it being denatured and
and damaged in the process you know you
have to find ways to make lower temp
efficient and functional and he's not
losing the lower wave and there's no
better way than vacuum and flow form to
add on to that I think that are also
regulating you know that like how I
spoke of volume and depth you know
regulating your puddle depth goes into
play too if someone's gonna throw a gram
into one of my bangers it's not gonna
cook as efficiently if they would have
loaded in in ten stages of 0.1 well
that's that's the beautiful thing and I
think that's why bubble prefers doing
the small taste or dabs I mean
especially if you have access to high
quality materials to vaporize you don't
need to as they say waste it to taste it
I mean you know if you I've got a rosin
that I pressed out last year virgin
flour rosin was 7.75% turps I mean I've
seen guys with rosin as high as nine
percent Terps if you have if you've got
that kind of flavor you don't need a
half a gram in your bucket it makes more
sense to take little tasters and get
that full symphony effect anyway take a
whole bunch of them do you know how much
vacuum pressure has to be created to
lower the boiling point just a single
degree oh it's a good question I'm not
sure what that metric is but you can
look it up on Google there there's
there's there's there's curves that give
you an idea of where the boiling point
goes based upon the pressure for by the
way it's different with all materials
like with water it's gonna be different
than it will with oil so I was just
wondering if you knew by chance no and
then the terpene profile of course makes
it unique and specific to every single
gently you're putting in there so right
we tried to measure pressures in
different places for different reasons
we wanted the vaporizer to know if it
was being drawn from and and you know it
just its temperature whatever and the
just ordinary pressure sensors could not
tell that little difference at all
it's it's a small change the human
sensor reigned supreme you guys I'm
telling you the human sensor reigns
supreme yeah I agree in this particular
world though I've seen the same thing
and I don't know if it's just a paying
more attention or if there's something
to be said for the olfactory of
particular people who happen to be the
innovators in these different aspects of
Industry that are just almost like the
cannabis sommelier where they're just
there their nose is smelling things a
little bit deeper than someone who's
just like you know I'm often amazed when
someone post there but out of a bag and
it stinks like mold and I'm like ooh and
they'll be like what well you know some
turps that's musk I'm like no bro that's
like mold
actually it's that's not terroir I can
see it it's right there on the but it's
just like that's not so I think that
there's something to be said for that
bioassay the importance of trying
something for your own head and and
making those decisions which I'm sure
would be a good place to start tasks in
regards to trying to figure out what
vacuum works best
just through the bioassay I mean I I
have like one two three four five six
seven different carb caps here and I use
them all at different times it depends
on kind of what kind of a rip I'm
looking for like if I'm looking for that
high anxiety like sitting on the edge of
my chair I'm on the brink of highness
well I'm gonna use my really serious
vacuum carb cap the one that has like no
air flow almost at all and I'm just like
that seems too when I exhale a
heavy-duty rip of the where is my bike
longer flowering lean rich rosin it just
is quite different from if I'm looking
to hit something a little lighter like
the Juanita like mimosa very orange
flavor II you know kind of like a
dessert more than a heavy heavy rib I
like to hit this one because it's so
flavorful and I don't have to turn the
vacuum on full I can just hit it really
like boom like a big blast and that I
still when I smoke this hit anything
else on my pipe until I clean the pipe
because everything will taste right I
think it just kind of boils down to
personal preference with a lot of
people's you know is some people are
gonna like one thing others are gonna
like another I personally like I said
I've kind of come to the conclusion that
I think the vacuum is less a part of it
and it's more just about having fresh
air to mix in with the oil so that
there's molecules available for your oil
to you know interact with then and
keeping that puddle not too deep and I
think that those are the biggest things
for me and having a cap that creates a
suction I end up feeling like I'm
fighting the peace so my personal
preference is just having a cap that you
know has a nice flow to it but can also
give the oils washing around yeah I mean
I think a happy little ground yeah end
of the day it's about tuning in did not
just your preference but you'll figure
it out that each one of those caps they
create different vacuums and so
therefore you use a different different
temperature to get the results you want
absolutely I definitely like having a
quiver of caps we've got only she got a
new cap that we're gonna put out next
Friday to you guys by the way I wish I
could show it to you right now but I
can't little collabo with Gordo
scientific so score them yes stay on the
lookout nice
very cool I'm sure you guys have seen
the carb caps that people were actually
putting terpenes into that you were
caught yeah I'm not sure that ever took
off very very interesting though and
also the whole concept of just like
having cool air before you know it's
because it cools the air you're you're
cooling the air before it goes through
and there's also the eternal quartz guys
came up with what they're calling their
convection carb caps where they're made
out of quartz so you'll heat the tip of
the carb cap and get it nice and hot so
that the air that you're drawing through
is hot air and it you know helps
facilitate the vaporization process even
further there yeah that's what some of
our guys have been doing with the heat
one that's what really got me looking at
playing with the carb cap and you know
being able the idea of actually having
not just vacuum and flow form component
but a thermal component to the to the
carb cap that's right yeah
definitely something they're all about
the Trinity yes sir alright guys well
thanks for having me but uh I got a take
off I've got a family thing I got a gate
too and I haven't even showered yet
today so yeah we're just gonna wrap it
up right now task thanks a ton for
coming in and chatting with us and we'll
look forward to if you want to drop like
a website and that Instagram or
something where people can check you out
that's always helpful for sure um
highly-educated ti.com for our online
store my Instagram is tasks Rock the ASX
are okay I hardly ever post those so
don't get too excited and the Instagram
for highly-educated is just
highly-educated TI awesome dude well
thanks for coming out Linus from
vaporbrothers thanks for joining the
conversation and keeping it psychedelic
bro I really appreciated your
perspective and I'm sorry to hear that
your partner split because you went
corporate corporates just the word it's
not a mindset yeah yeah it's an
organization that's yet more done when
there's responsibility and a lot of
parts
yeah you can't wing it awesome well
thanks so much for coming in and
Gary from up tech and w9 who helped to
organize the show
thanks bro for being a part of the show
if you want to actually line us real
quick do you want to drop your Instagram
and your website as well sure we're
vaporbrothers comm we sell the vaporizer
there we had the vb2 for a while but we
might bring it back Gary seems very hip
to it - that's interesting and Instagram
is at vaporbrothers spelled out the APO
our brother and that's good I'm also
Linus Linus Larson on Facebook you can
search for vapor buzz on Facebook and
then I post on there find me that way
it's good way to message I love dancing
and you know it sorry one more it's not
a plug it's a website that we all have
been on at one point
it's called puck combustion comm if you
want to hear if you want to be a
manufacturer and hear people say what
about this material what about that oh I
took a hit and it felt burnt it all the
things all the hard questions all the
arguments you can it the the people are
very discerning on that website truck
combustion calm I'm on there as Linus
vaporbrothers you can search and if you
want to ask the hard questions that's
the forum to do it on you won't be like
rushed off because it's not you know
polite or something although I'm forced
to be polite back everybody and I'm not
supposed to say anything bad about any
other company but that keeps it clean
it's it's one good place to find awesome
very cool [ __ ] combustion absolutely
Gary from up tack and w9 give thanks for
helping me put on the show do you want
to drop your Instagram and your contact
info yeah I appreciate you having me on
the show I really appreciate the the
members on the panel were they've given
me a lot of insight a mark Lynas task
Sabo I appreciate you guys coming on
Instagram is up tech that's our
manufacturers instagrammed and we have
w-9 tech our
Instagram our website is w-9 calm that's
the letter W the number nine te CH calm
that's where you can find our vaporizers
that I want to point out that last week
I did meet up with Linus the omicron
that he has we had to refurbish his old
Omicron he had Omicron v3 we had to give
him the v5 he's been two generations out
and I am going to be receiving one of
the VB 2.5 to test out because like he
said we might bring it to market we
might be working together on that
project itself so thank you everybody
for coming on and thank you Marcus for
having son and if you have any questions
I'm on [ __ ] combustion too as Linus said
if you can make if you can pass for
combustion
questions your company is doing all
right you're doing okay yeah yeah and
yeah Garrett Gary's very precocious
what's the word for pearl if prolific
he's very prolific on it and it has
answered all the most tough and he has a
lot of heart in it and when he says
don't inhale off of this this that and
that and we don't do that by the way he
means it it's really reportable and I
think the world is really going portable
- maybe gary has the good chance at
taking a lot of what we've talked about
today and reproducing it in a portable
way because for a long time all these
years I Bank on plugins plug-in models
because I get the hit I want reproducing
that into a portable well oil made that
easy and possible but vapor someday
would be cool if there was a good herb
vaporizer that was portable maybe that's
subjective future future show
conversation absolutely well I also want
to thank Martin koi for coming out and
sharing his knowledge it's always great
to hear from you dude and see a man even
my wife walked into the room at one
point to bring me a lovely water which I
have not even had a sip huh and you were
on the screen here on the screen then
she said does he not age
haha too kind to you looks exactly the
same yeah dude so thank you so much for
coming out dude many many good memories
man I'm gonna I'm gonna get the family
up there and we'll hang out here at some
point in the not-too-distant future
thanks for putting this on an awesome
platform bubble I can't thank you enough
for the exposure I thinks is a great
subject I think it's really good for
people the vapor enthusiasts
I mean enthusiasts of anything to
understand the history of what it is
they're too enthusiastic about how they
got to where they they are today and you
know the the ability to add feedback to
help guys like us you know drive the
future lionís we've known each other for
a long time always a pleasure
Sabo definitely one of my favorite
humans in the world Gary great great to
meet you I'm Marcus or recently made me
sort of aware of you guys and what
you've been doing will have to
collaborate on something hell our
companies are only three letters apart
hey quick question
I got a I got a are you in Canada as
well no I'm not I'm in California I'm
here you're in the top you're super
lucky to have been able to cultivate
here in what I consider one of the Sean
poorer regions of the world for cannabis
and for grapes for that matter and I do
apologize you got cut off you're in
NorCal right
yeah I'm in NorCal Santa Cruz okay
perfect I used to make my trip up there
for the annual pickup but okay yeah we
really we really need to sit down
because I wanna I want to pick your
brain about the some of the research
you've done on the venturi effect and
collaborating on something that we think
should be the ultimate portable device
that should come out yeah let's session
bro I look forward to I appreciate it
guys thank you very much everybody
awesome guys I also want to thank Sabo
for coming out with the team vapor
exhale you can check him out on
Instagram at team vape exhale
I'm bubble man you can check me out
right here on YouTube on Bubba man's
and BC bubbleman on Instagram and yeah
just super super thankful to have these
guys come in and share their information
today thank you all for watching whether
we had about 700 live viewers it's just
down to 580 now at the end of the three
hours that's pretty awesome and
hopefully the show will get a solid
10,000 views in the next seven days like
the last three episodes of hash Church
2.0 I will be in Jamaica next week for
Bob Marley's birthday bash at 56 Hope
Road in Kingston Jamaica and I'll be
hanging out and having a good time with
skunk man Sam for a while on the other
side of the island so hopefully we'll
see you guys next week on hash Church
and thanks everyone for being a part of
it
may the full melt bless your bowl sooner
than later peace out everybody