just start the
recording okay welcome everybody special
episode here today wow hash Church uh
season 11 episode three the solvent
episode very very excited for this
episode I've uh got Dr Mark sheldone
who's really curated the room uh and
I've got a bunch of people who are
waiting to get in already but we're
going to change things up a little bit
here on hash church and we're going to
do some shoutouts for our sponsors so
give me just one second to bring them up
on the page here and we'll get that done
then I'll let everyone in so first off
and first foremost I want to be give a
big shout out to craft Greenery which is
one of Vancouver's Premier cannabis
dispensaries uh for sponsoring today's
event uh they're all about bringing the
highest quality and uh widest variety of
cannabis and extracts right to your
doorstep all across Canada uh whether
you're a connoisseur or a curious
newcomer craft Greenery has something
special for everyone making your
cannabis Journey uh both unique uh and
Unforgettable so check them out for an
unparalleled selection that's curated
with love and expertise uh keep up the
great work you can reach them at craft
Greenery dcom and shout out to uh Dennis
and uh oh I got a little alarm going off
that I don't know where it
is
huh interesting
here we go one second here
guys that was my son's iPad how about
that for a middle of uh the the the row
so shout out to craft craft Greenery and
uh Dennis and Mark uh I also would like
to shout out evolved extraction
Solutions uh really a massive shout out
to Adam Temple uh for his pioneering
work in solvent extraction of cannabis
and for being a sponsor of today's event
uh they're dedicated to Quality
Innovation and the Cannabis extraction
process brings unparalleled products to
the community uh so thanks to their
commitment to constant investment and
research at their genome Technology
Center which we'll be talking a little
bit about today uh evolved extraction is
setting new standards in the industry
just keep pushing the boundaries uh
evolved extraction Solutions in Adam
Temple uh you can see them on at evolved
extraction on Instagram and evolved
extraction. comom for their website Al
righty okay we'd also like to give a
shout out to the media Bros specializing
in advanced CRC filt Solutions designed
to elevate the Cannabis extraction
process they're based in Portland Oregon
and serving extractors across the US and
Canada the runr uh their run ready
filtration media delivers unmatched
Purity potency and efficiency
effectively removing impurities while
retaining what the the cannabinoids and
aromatic volatiles that matter most uh
with faster flow rates no clogging
consistent results mediab Bros owers
extractors to produce safer cleaner and
more effective products with ease uh
backed by Hands-On expertise and
commitment to Innovations media Bros
simplifies the process and helps
customers achieve Excellence every step
of the way you can check them out at
mediab bros. store uh and if you're in
Canada you can actually contact Adam at
evolved
extraction. all righty so and last but
certainly not least I'd like to shout
out horge and the good Folks at chemtech
uh this is a company that's
revolutionizing cannabis extraction with
cuttingedge technology and a commitment
to Quality and sustainability chemtech
is a leader in post Pro processing
equipment for solvent-based cannabis
extractions offering Advanced Solutions
like the
ct55 tarpine separation centrifuge
designed to enhance the Purity and
quality of cannabis concentrates uh you
can visit those guys at goem tech.com to
learn more about their Innovative
Equipment uh and dedication to
empowering extractors across the
industry uh with chemtech support
they're going to we're going to continue
to explore and celebrate the art of
science uh uh of cannabis the science of
cannabis extraction uh fostering educ
Innovation and Community Connection uh
which is what we do here at hash church
so let's Elevate the craft together
thank you to our four sponsors and uh I
think we got so many people in the room
right now it's time to get the show
started boom there's Ryan Hubble Max
Eiser Eric Ward Adam Temple hemp guy wax
plug Murphy Murray and wow welcome
everyone and thank you for taking the
time to showing up on half hash Church
you know I get that hash Church
especially because it's so connected to
me has always been very much I think a
lot of people just assume it's really uh
like a solventless show and that we're
all about solventless this and
solventless that and yes I've been
guilty over the years for being a biased
prick towards solventless extraction uh
but I love that you guys have been
pushing the boundaries uh and uh really
expanding what can and can't be done uh
with the use of solvent extractions and
I want to thank uh my co-host Dr Mark
shalone who's not actually here yet I'm
sure he's coming
mark uh for curating this show and for
bringing you all together Mark's been a
part of hash church almost since uh day
one we love his knowledge of chemistry
uh we love the depth of conversation
that Mark uh brings to the table on the
constant regular he's an absolutely
brilliant chemist and the fact that he
likes to trip balls and watch The
Grateful Dead and fish well that's just
kind of a uh a little bonus that uh that
I have uh in common uh with with the
good old Mark shelone so I think he just
popped into the room are you there
mark yes can you hear me there he is man
future so bright he got to wear shades
this sorry we're a little late no don't
be sorry we're trying to figure it out
yeah we're trying to get it projected
here on the big screen but hey everybody
how's everyone doing today good hey Adam
nice to meet you Max and Telly good to
see you Murphy let's see who else we got
in the room Eric it's been a minute holy
[ __ ] man how you doing man doing good
glad to be here thanks for inviting me
yeah yeah well thanks for coming we got
skunkman Sam in the room as well uh I
did invite of course skunkman Sam and I
also invited Wade laughter these are two
of our elders in the community they may
not be connected exactly to the to the
level of solvent extraction that a lot
of you guys are but I thought you know
what I still wanted them in the room Sam
always just has the most incredible
perspective and he's certainly uh you
know probably going to tell us a bunch
of stuff about solvent extraction that I
didn't even know that he was involved in
because I've never mentioned anything
that Sam wasn't involved in since the
actual beginning so uh welcome to you Mr
skunkman
Sam howdy howdy howdy howdy you know
what that is
definitely when I hear howdy howdy I
think skunkman Sam all right we're going
to let a few more folks into the room I
see horg is there from the wax plug from
chem Tech welcome horge hope you're
doing well welcome
Adam welcome Max and Eric and Ryan and
Murphy and uh the gentleman that just
came in M Liga that's Marshall yes sir
all right welcome Marshall okay that's
right I you know I've never had a show
where so many people
were able to come in and then more
people and then more people I'm sure you
guys saw the emails oh I'm just going to
add one more don't worry just one more
oh we got a couple more people that that
are going to come in I think we have
about 25 people that are going to come
in here today so um I'm not sure how
Mark wants to start it I would love to
get some introductions from some of you
guys I mean I'm familiar with uh with
some of your guys' work I obviously know
Murphy Murray and I know Adam Temple and
some some of you others I don't know so
what do you think Mark while you guys
are getting yourself organized over
there do you think we should maybe go
through a short little introduction of
everyone that's on the panel yeah
absolutely can you guys hear me I can't
tell if I'm M we can hear you perfect
yeah and see you it's see us too right
on okay yeah so we do a quick uh intro
and we can introduce everyone that's
here first so I'm Mark sheldone can you
guys see me I don't
we can see you we can see you we can
hear you man I can almost taste and feel
you like trust me you're here okay so to
my right here we have trainer we all
remember trainer from you our
solventless episode trainer is one of
the best hash makers here in the state
of Vermont and we got the one and only
kind Bill ah the kindest of bills the
kindest of bills yeah the kind kindest
of those maybe we'll see if we can cut
the lights a little bit but why don't we
start so immediately to my right I have
Eric Ward Eric you want to introduce
yourself yeah um I'm Eric Ward I uh I
guess I would be known for um starting
the liquid thca separation from back in
the day called uh used to call it the
Heisenberg so kind of called myself the
Heisenberg there for a second and then
uh we start holy water right yeah then
we started calling holy water uh we were
doing the Heisenberg thing on fish tour
and kind of just selling carts like the
coil carts before there were actually
carts and then kind of got known by that
and a little before that um and then
yeah holy water which was uh the first
liquid that we brought out to High Times
Cup in Denver that first legal one in
420 and um kind of had to have to have
to talk to their lawyers to get them to
change the packaging for the contest and
everything because no one had ever seen
like a thin liquid like that and uh
that's kind of where I started I'm up in
Washington now at a company called um uh
sungrown we do Brands called fullspec
and we do rosin and solventless stuff
called solar rare
and we have a lot of different lines uh
Lea Works would be another brand um it's
kind of where I'm at these days and just
do some Consulting and lab stuff um a
lot of R&amp;D so I'm working with a lot of
new stuff working with the resonator
guys and doing key runs of BHO and Shout
Out TJ yeah shout out to TJ and um so
I'm kind of proving the the methods of
that and have done quite an extensive
R&amp;D thing with that and now I'm doing we
have a machine that does solventless
turps so we're actually able to get
turps with no steam distillation or no
anything like that and we just are able
to do solventless turps and so I'm doing
R&amp;D with that right now which has been
pretty
interesting dude I love I love that I
listen I always thought the solventless
term was hilarious and shout out to Nick
for coming up with it because it was so
necessary and whatnot but solventless
turps I know got to be the most awesome
like that
is solventless hydrocarbons man we got
the solventless hydrocarbons but guess
it's a method yeah it's a method thing
where it's like we're not using solvents
to extract ter well I know exactly what
you mean dude I know exactly what you
mean and I'm just using water which is a
solv yeah yeah exactly oh man listen I
went into that argument a few times in
my uh career there for sure so uh Adam
Temple next up would you like to
introduce yourself good good friend I
met Adam actually we did a couple of
panels together over the years at
different events and uh he's local to me
as well so uh give us uh give it up
there Adam right on thanks bub man um
yeah so also from the Vancouver area
founded evolved extraction solutions
back in
2016 um we're now kind of the the
largest extraction equipment and
supplies distributor in Canada um more
recently though we launched uh the first
thca crystallization commercial system
called The genome um been
doing a uh a controlled crystallization
course actually at our genome Technology
Center sh out to Murphy Murray who
actually instructs that course um super
awesome way to learn about uh about how
to isolate THC at different kind of
scales um so uh yeah that kind of sums
it up we'll get into that later for sure
maybe uh head over to Murphy Murray as
you just mentioned her welcome
Murphy hey thanks for having me
appreciate it uh I think it's very
fitting to come back to be on hash
Church um the day the Tik Tok gets
turned off what a what a fun day for us
all um taking it back old school but
I've been
uh exactly exactly um a solventless
folks haven't never been able to post on
there our our drugs look exactly like
drugs so we've been affected the whole
time but um I've been in this industry
so long that I stopped like dropping the
years because it was starting to make me
sound old I started out uh doing solvent
list with Nic you know with Mila's
little uh you know washer and um quickly
I basically have just been trying to do
whatever is new as soon as it's new the
whole time I've been going and
fortunately for me it has gotten boring
yet so I keep doing it um I've worked on
the equipment side the most you know um
so I've worked with a lot of different
equipment manufacturers and even as a
consultant and an educator my focus has
always really been on like how do we
make this job easier for ourselves even
with solvent
list I started with a washer um and I
know that people out there love their
Wooden Spoons but I also just love um
spending my time consuming these
products
and I think that's why so many of us
were available today because you know
solvent-based extractions way faster so
we have more free time we can hang out
and uh consume each other so um I've
been doing education building equipment
and um you know my Consulting is more of
lab advisory roles um a little bit of
consultant for cool clients for you know
from time to time now but I love
learning and that's why I teach because
it opens up the greatest
opportunities awesome well we're happy
to have you here for sure and I got to
tell you Dr Mark you guys although it's
not
exact you guys kind of had a little bit
of a Horatio energy going on when you
had the back light lit and quite a few
people in chat even put up the rip to
Horatio so I felt like we got a little
visit from our good friend Horatio
Delbert who of course passed away a few
years ago and was an absolute Pioneer in
both solvent and solventless extraction
go ahead Mark if it wasn't if it wasn't
for her ratio we wouldn't know each
other Marcus right I I think I owe him a
whole debt of gratitude for bringing me
on to Hash church he wanted me to set
Tony straight yeah exactly exactly I'd
love to hear from Ryan Hubble who's also
in the rooms rocking it out how you
doing Ryan Hey guys uh thanks for having
me Mark and uh Mark and Mark um I uh my
name's Ryan Hubble um I've been making
hash at a professional level since uh
2012 uh moved out to California I helped
start a couple Brands out there um
elephant extracts and sweet uh Sweet
Leaf extractors and then um in 20 end of
2013 beginning of 2014 I ended up at
Incredibles um the edible and extracts
company and me along with my um my
colleague Max we helped um develop their
extract um solvent extraction systems
there butane system and um uh led the
lab and then in the last couple years
I've been uh been a free agent and just
been doing a little bit of Consulting
here and there so so back in 2012 you
were like three years old when you
started I'm just joking I'm I'm an old
mother I I got I was like damn this guy
is looking good he's like young he's
2012 damn that's like some Pioneer years
right there good to have you Ryan thanks
for thanks for coming on look young
right I've been told that a few times
but when I gray out the the the beard
then people are like ah you don't look
that young
actually uh Marshall would love to hear
from
you yeah hey thanks for having me on um
I'm the director of R&amp;D at vuka farms so
I work in a hemp farm and hemp
processing facility we have CO2 and
ethanol extraction um as much as I'm not
deep into the industry like you you
folks are I've never even been toing MJ
biscon uh at this point but I did go to
Humble state for undergraduates so kind
of seen a lot of the industry over the
years you know in in different areas and
and from different sides I guess but I
also worked in Hops uh prior to coming
on here at vuka farm so pretty much
everybody I work with uh has worked in
Hops and hop ex extracts product
development stuff like that um so we're
all kind of new to hemp and cannabis in
that way U and honestly I don't know
much about hydrocarbon extraction I have
a PhD and so my a lot of what I learn is
from literature and there's not a lot of
data out there on butane and and propane
things like that so I'm just excited to
uh to be here with you guys and learn
from you guys today honestly well you're
dialed in my friend you've got the
people here who were on The Cutting Edge
of this uh you came to me via Nick
zegler Nick zegler is one of the most
intelligent friends I have I absolutely
love and adore Nick when he comes on
hash church and shares his his knowledge
is so deep in V and when he hit me up
and said you got to have my friend
Marshall on he's brilliant I was like
Jesus Christ like if Nick's tell telling
me this guy is brilliant then I'm
looking forward to having him on the
show so you came with the uh highest of
regards from Nick and uh we're happy to
have you on here and uh hopefully you
can uh share some knowledge and you can
learn some knowledge as well so yeah
I've been uh using CO2 extraction for
what almost 10 years now I've built my
own I'm building more equipment right
now proprietary equipment uh for for CO2
extraction so awesome well I do I do
know Nick Nick mentioned you as well for
the aromatic volatile show that we've
been trying to do obviously Nick was
also involved in that at yaka Chief hops
when you I don't know if you worked at
Yak with him or not but um no no
according to them I came from the Dark
Side so I'm actually the company that
worked at hos which is the other larger
competitor um and so my boss is the
former CEO of yak ma Chief currently
okay me on I'm I'm working with a bunch
of folks from Yak ma Chief but yeah but
I did meet Nick through the Hop industry
uh and then through this job at vuka
just to give the panel a little bit of
background if you don't know Nick he's
was the sort of one of the main
extractors for yakam mief I can't even
remember the numbers it was absolutely
astonishing it's like 4,000 kilos an
hour or something that he was processing
through this giant machine that they had
created but the thing that really piqued
my interest was that he had some
colleagues that designed some analytical
equipment where they could perceive to
the trillionth instead of the billionth
like the proton NMR so we want to get
these guys on Marshall you'll be invited
to that show anyone who feels they have
a specialty in aromatic compounds uh
you'll be invited to that show we're
going to get Jeremy Plum on there we're
going to get Nick zegler we'll have
Marshall come on and what we're really
waiting for is his two colleagues who
put that equipment together because Nick
is not willing to speak on their work uh
instead of having them speak on their
work so I'll look forward to that show
uh kind of in the near future uh and
then we'll head on over to jar Yari Yari
how you doing Yari good how are you
thanks for having me on dude I kind of
thought it was cool jar you know jar
hashar Yari you whatever works a a Yari
of hash and you as well my friends so
please give us a little introduction let
us know where you're at and what you're
doing yeah so I've been growing for
close to like 17 years now um I got I
got I've been doing it in Colorado since
kind of like the first legalization we
all had like the med cards and all that
and then um once the extraction hit the
scene uh I was was just interested in it
and um the first system that I heard
about was the ETS machine so I actually
went down and met uh Murphy um at the
etss place but I couldn't get any clean
runs because of those Carvers it was
leeching oil into every one of my runs
that I did did and Murphy helped me as
much as she possibly could and uh it
just we just couldn't make it happen so
she was the one who actually suggested
that I go over and meet the guys at
Incredibles which is where I met Max and
Telly and AK and then I met Dr Mark so
um that's kind of like the background of
how I got going in in the scene and um I
used their system for years it was great
but then I needed to upgrade a little
bit so I started kind of piecing
together and building my own systems so
um that's that's where I'm at with the
with my background and
extraction beautiful well appreciate you
sharing with us uh we've got uh well
let's go over to
Max there he is welcome
Max you guys can you hear me okay yes I
made the mistake of speaking right while
you spoke and I cut you out but I won't
do that again I promise no worries at
all well thanks again it's cool to see
some old faces cool to see some new
faces what up Dr Mark thanks for putting
this on um so I guess quick little
origin story is I've been in legal
cannabis since about like 2008 give or
take so going on two decades now at this
point kind of crazy um and it started
out just wanting good weed you know I
was never much of a hustler I just
wanted to like secure The Chronic for
myself um I remember when I was younger
and I bought a bag from my dealer and he
had better weed
in his sack than what he sold me and
that was the day I realized I was like
oh I like need control over my Supply so
it started like that and then it started
just uh making some hash for fun in my
backyard with some trim you know open
blasting at one point uh Derek Cummings
and I got Linked UP many people know him
in the industry not everyone does but
um what's that I just said D Money D
money
so um you know we started making ice
hash with just a Home Depot washing
machine that had a metal drum you know
we tried to do what we could with what
we had at the time at least no plastic
in there um and so it just started with
big you know big large ice hash runs
where we had a pulley system on bolt
bags pulling bags so that was a lot of
fun um and then just you know I've got a
a scientifically inclined mind and
wanted to play with solvents and wanted
to make the elusive shatter at the time
time something that was holdable and not
sticky and you know things come full
circle and we realize that shatter is
not it used to be if it doesn't shatter
it doesn't matter hold it from the
bottom all these little things that we
used to have um but uh so then that
continued to evolve and became you know
solv and extraction became a real
industry and uh so we were already kind
of playing around in our backyard honing
in something uh unbeknownst that there
was going to be high demand for it so at
medically correct Incredibles uh dererk
and I Linked UP Telly Ryan Hubble came
on board at some point and we Dicky
don't forget Dicky oh oh yeah and Dicky
we got we got Dicky who's not in the
scene but he's a behind the scenes dude
who was a crucial component in machine
fabrication we ended up designing our
own extraction machine what Ryan did not
uh advertise for ourselves is that we're
inventors on record for a patent on that
piece of equipment and we never really
came out to to you know do anything
related to metal we were just hash
makers and we saw the end goal we wanted
and we saw that none of the equipment
that was available at the time was able
to you know deliver what we were looking
for we knew some basic things like you
know solvent exposure time and
temperature and all these components
that we wanted more control over and no
one had access and we would give people
feedback who were designing machines and
I don't know if it was ego if it was too
much work for them to change CH it but
we were giv boots on the ground feedback
as users on how they could improve their
Tech um and then it just became easier
to design our own so I don't know if it
was in
2017 I don't know when we got our patent
Telly do you know actually the year we
got that um you're muted right now by
the
way um I think it was awarded in
2019 but all the all the work was done
in 2014 14 yeah so that was something we
were working on for a while um and then
those of us who are in Colorado know
that the industry I'm sure everywhere
has been kind of tumultuous and so you
know the race to the bottom has happened
and at one point I was overseeing three
cultivation facilities as well as the
laboratory that Ryan was managing and we
had about I don't know uh maybe 20,000
square feet of grow space so it was you
know it was um you know more than a
small thing but they get bigger uh in
between then and now we ended up
relinquishing our cultivation licenses
because everything was just saturated
and you know there's internal drama we
had with the fire department one reason
or another we just had some friction so
my role has changed a lot and we're not
doing a ton of extraction anymore I'm
still at medically correct doing R&amp;D and
recipe formulation you know working out
some Nano some nanotech and stuff like
that um but for the most part that's
kind of the the elevator pitch of about
20 years ago to now um one thing I was
just thinking about while we were
sitting here is Murphy I can't remember
if it was you or not but when I first
came on had left pink house which was a
real fun gig we all were doing a good
thing there um but that wasn't being
operated very professionally so things
kind of disintegrated there when I first
came over to medically correct we were
using kind of a hybridized
obos maybe partial ETS thing and I
needed to swing by and get a a cares
saer replaced and I think it was you and
there was a bunch of little aloe vera
plants that were at the office and I I
had been given one and uh ended up
turning that one aloe vera plant into
like this psychotic Obsession of
propagation and turned it into thousands
if not multi of plants all under just
some little grow lights in our machine
shop Warehouse to the got excessive and
I'm like I can't transplant these things
anymore we had to start giving them away
uh but that same cutting of aloe vera Is
Still rocking probably a decade later
and has made thousands and thousands of
hours that have gone out I love that I'm
looking at five propagations of it up on
my window sill and the big one down here
in front of me like you need Aloe Vera
in Colorado it's it's dry out here I I
attribute that uh Army that I built to
you and the first one that I got when I
was picking up a a refurbed cares saer
yeah well that's perfect let's keep the
aloe going and stop using you know oiled
compressors you know it's just really
good position for us all to be in
finally absolutely that's me hey thanks
Max appreciate the breakdown and that's
a I couldn't tell if it was a real fish
tank or if it was like some digital
screen that you have but that's a real
fish tank oh yeah that's a 75 full H
yeah dude yeah I'm telling you anyone
that loves weed and like getting stoned
and staring at a fish tank it's got to
still be one of my favorite things to do
like 25 years later yeah 100% And my God
if you like growing weed there's so many
parallels because you got to make sure
the water levels are right and you know
look at everyone make sure they're
healthy they're talking listen listen at
one point in time years ago it was got
to be close to 30 years ago I remember I
went over to breeder Steve's place and
he had started this what he was calling
guppy ponics and he had these Egyptian
mouth breeder fish and he was there was
this whole cycle of like the fish pooped
and then the worms ate their poop and
then they pooped and that poop fed the
plants and this herb was so [ __ ] like
I I can't even explain it it was like
herb that felt like it was flushed like
a thousand X from any herb that I'd ever
seen before it was just just more
breeder Steve stuff and then he got a
kick out of uh you know feeding the fish
his uh like his hamburger to to bug out
the vegetarian and the and the vegans
you'd be like I'm just feeding him a
little bit of hamburger so yeah
hamburger fed sweet skunk guppy ponics
for the win uh shout out to breeder
Steve you [ __ ] Maniac hey um go ahead
I said I would love that that sounds BK
yeah yeah it's definitely something it's
definitely something I want to shout out
horge who's in the room he hasn't turned
on his camera yet I don't know if we're
getting horge oh there he is what's up
home me what up man how's it going it's
going good man it's going good you want
to give a little introduction to the to
the crew I'm sure many know you and may
not so my name is uh H if you can't roll
the r it's all good you can say George
um no better known as wax plug in the
industry so I started back in like uh
2016 open blasting like straight up just
glass tube in the backyard like everyone
else I'm sure and uh started doing my
research there in the background until I
developed uh or found a way to bleach
the oil which became what's known now as
CRC so my introduction into like the
main industry was around 2018 when I
introduced or shared some of the
techniques I was doing from there I was
able to uh gain more opportunities uh
eventually opened up chemtech which is a
company which distributes equipment and
like centrifuges stainless steel
components just about everything really
consumables but from there I was able to
then really focus on research and trying
out stuff so I was able to really
connect with a lot of labs and
eventually ended up uh forming wax plug
Academy which is now an educational
platform where we help others learn
through there and also uh through a
university in Argentina right now in
Buenos sidtis so we have two platforms
right now going and like I said having
all these tools at your disposal has
really just helped push everything
forward and I travel the world a lot
currently like I have been to a lot of
countries and helped uh push the
techniques over there forward get the
knowledge going and just prevent some of
the pitfalls that we saw in the
beginning uh what else I mean yeah
that's about it I've been mainly just
focusing on crystallization
lately and developing equipment I would
say those are like the main focuses
right now I've seen in the industry nice
well I I met Jorge and yes I can roll my
ARS
because so I absolutely know how to roll
my arm I just didn't I was like I didn't
want to sound like I was you know trying
to speak Spanish or whatnot but I'll
call you Jorge from now on my friend and
yeah we met in
Berlin uh gez it had to be a year or two
ago now through Alex Rogers ICBC the
international cannabis business
conference and Jorge was just
he was just rocking diamonds this guy
was walking around with big old diamonds
and just giving diamonds away to
everyone and uh it really created uh a
neat I I saw it create a really neat
like like excitement similar to the
excitement I've seen when I roll around
and and give out people full melt hash
and your diamonds were impressive you
gave me a couple and they were they were
they were 8 to 10 karat diamonds for
sure like they were not the little baby
one karat that's for sure and I also dug
your little uh your little Grabber that
you had your little custom chem Tech uh
triple prom grabbers for those with the
dab to it just keeps sliding off so you
got to gra those things yeah dude so
good looking out man we're glad to have
you here and we want to thank uh you
know thank you guys for uh being a
sponsor today as well so really really
cool now I have let me just make sure go
into Gallery I think everyone has
mentioned we've sort of gotten a little
introdu from everyone so I am going to
bring I said earlier in the chat I would
uh you know lost uh lost a lot of
friends in the last year we lost a lot
of good people um I'm not even going to
try and Shout them all out because it
was just so many and I hate the idea of
forgetting one but
um there is one that I want to bring
back from the grave to show up on our
show today because uh this guy has been
he's been a Pioneer in this solvent
extraction for a very long time and uh
I've just sent him the link we'll see if
he's going to make it in I'm kind of
excited actually uh to bring this guy
back
um yeah here he
is without further Ado I'm bringing
someone back to life today we're
bringing Indra back Indra was not dead
as many have been saying including
myself for the last like 6 months to a
year he wrote me the other day and he
said stop telling people I'm dead and I
said holy [ __ ] holy [ __ ] dude is this
really you I was all shaking I was
freaking out I was like I was like what
the what's going on how could I've never
in my life been a part of a rumor of a
good friend of mine being dead that
wasn't Dead But Here We Go John Davis
Indra In the Flesh old as [ __ ] but we're
happy to have you here dude so happy to
have you here how have you been
dude
well
879 start slowing your ass way down you
know for sure and then uh I got diabetes
and blood pressure but guess what I'm
still alive and I have no plans for
dying dude good it's it's really good to
hear your voice I'm not going to Li it's
good to hear your voice Indra holy [ __ ]
you're you're a big part of hash church
you've been a big part since day one and
yeah you're a wild Maniac of a person
it's part of the reason that I love you
and and appreciate you and I've always
uh sort of tried to maintain a good
friendship with you I don't know how we
had a little falling out but uh I'm
really glad that you're alive I'm really
glad that you're here for the solvent
episode I mean for those of you that
don't know Indra really was you know
kind of the grand grandfather of BHO he
released that process in back in
1999 on ero.org
and uh really kind of got the ball
rolling you know he was also one of the
first people that
um you know when things were going a
little bit the wrong way with the Ethel
martines and sort of you know open
blasting and and young people blowing up
he was immediately completely conscious
of it and he reached out to me of all
people which kind of fed into my bias of
of of BHO because you know he'd hit me
up and he'd be like look you got to warn
people about these mer capatin that are
in the oil they're not good they
concentrate you got to you got to warn
people that they can't be doing open
blasting and they can't that that that
that plugs spark inside the plug you
can't be like out on your deck like with
your bikini top like blasting BHO and so
he was really although he was the guy
that released this process he was also
very conscious and like I could tell
that it was hurting his soul a little
bit that something that he had released
that he really just meant for it to be
such a good thing uh had been taken in a
way sort of spread in a way that was a
little bit disconcerting and so I got to
give props to all of you on the panel
because really what you guys are are the
people who are pioneering this solvent
extraction far away from you know I mean
we can laugh about it now hor just said
oh I was open blasting like we all were
it's like God thank you that you're all
here that you're all safe that none of
you are have burn marks on your body for
the rest of your lives there's the right
way and the wrong way to do things uh
and obviously that particular process it
really I say it all the time and I don't
mean it as a pun but it is a pun it
spread like wildfire I mean when he
released that method it was within a
month of me releasing bubble bags and I
really remember kind of being like
really like really dude like cuz B was
more popular there just there's no like
can't deny that it was more popular now
I'd love to get into this conversation
with you guys because I know a lot of
you uh are like Max in the sense of just
trying to get the best heady stash in
your in your bag you just want the best
you're a lot of us were just have always
been looking for the best so it's nice
to see I I don't want to lose my train
of thought but it's it's nice to
see people taking things out of this
sort of sketchy situation and bringing
it into a much more hey maybe having a
little bit of chemistry understanding
having a class one div one room you know
all of these different things that many
of you guys have sort of pioneered in
this industry uh have been uh very very
important to to bring to to the
Forefront so that these products can
become made available I was terrified
back in the day and I know you guys
laugh about it but you guys must have
been a little like terrified too when it
was happening when people were just like
yeah Eric give give me me a story
actually you have burn marks all over me
oh this did happen to me and beginning
of 2013 in January uh 2013 because I was
um uh Greywolf was putting up his
terpinator up on the internet you know
first one of the first Clos loops and uh
so I made my own version of that because
it was all open blasting before that so
uh my whole goal was to make because I
I'm very um you know engineering
inclined I'm not formally educated but I
have definitely uh made closed Loops
myself and have adapted many and done a
lot of custom stuff on that and so my
very first one I made uh I started
making in 2010 so I had it going for
about a year and a half um and then I
did like some custom stuff to it and I
was doing like I had like a dip tube in
it and I was doing like different
batches into like U Teflon bags and then
I would just have like a a gelled ice
cube thing that I would warm up and put
in the bottom and I would evated out
like that and I was still keeping the
liquid in it so I could use dry ice
blocks to separate it later because
that's how I was doing holy water and
after about a year and a half there was
just a static a static problem that
definitely ignited it and ignited me in
the process uh but this was in the very
beginning this was before people came
out with clothes Loop machines um you
know this was very very beginning and so
um you know that was my lesson on that
was you do need a C1 D1 uh you know I
was gone I was given the liquid to
Addison for a long time at Steep Hill
because that's how I met a lot of people
in the beginning was doing testing uh
because nobody had any information on
any of this stuff so I was having to do
my own testing at that time and so I was
giving stuff to him and nobody had seen
liquid or anything like that and that's
what I prefer to smoke I just like the
tpin you know that's my main thing it's
really the flavor it's always been that
and and so I've been giving it to him
and then I just disappeared for nine
months because I was in the hospital for
a month uh you know I had three
surgeries skin graph stuff like really
gnarly almost died type of stuff um you
know and then I Liv parents for about
eight months uh who they had to take
care of me and then after that uh the
the whole thing like literally like the
word dab came out in 2013 like uh the
industry started getting big right
around there and people would be coming
to steep hill and I be like oh that's
good you know but my friend does this
thing makes this liquid and started
telling people about me and so by the
time I was healed and feeling better A
lot of people everywhere knew who I was
or at least knew the name you know holy
water and people were like looking for
me they're like does he exist there were
some articles written about it is just
some really interesting coming from just
being in bed for eight or nine months
thinking I'm never going to be in this
industry it's not even really an
industry yet I didn't even think it was
G to be possible but I came back and I
tried to teach uh people and it just
wasn't up to what I was trying to do so
I started doing it again myself
even though my parents was like they're
going to kill me you know but I believed
that this was the thing that I this is
the thing that I like to do the most so
I always had other jobs and things like
that until this started just coming out
and started literally you know blowing
up in the right way instead
of [ __ ] and then that's when I went out
to um you know I was with uh that
company nectar in the beginning and I
went out to that um you know High Times
thing in 2014 in Colorado and that's
when we officially kind of unveiled the
whole idea of liquid and the separation
thing and that was the very beginning of
all that um but yeah I live with those
scars every day and it is something to
think about and it's something that you
know as I've worked in Labs since and
done consultations and things like that
safety is a priority and it's one of
those things that I'm so glad to see
because you don't ever want it to happen
to anyone else and I train a lot of
people and it's very important to do
things the correct way and to do things
safely and I love that that's where this
business went because I never thought I
was going to do this for a living this
is something that I can't believe I am
lucky enough to have an industry around
something that was a illegal dangerous
hobby um that I had hurt myself and you
know actually had gotten in trouble for
in California in the very beginning you
know so I was like the second person
that they had busted for B back then so
for me to do this now you know is crazy
did they slap you with a manufacturing
charge I did I have one yep yeah back in
that was in 200 end 2008 so that was the
end of 2008 so they didn't bad when they
when they give you their its own name e
when they give it like let's call it
manufacturing and we make it even worse
like you're anything that you're making
is manufacturing so all the people back
then since there there was no
manufacturing for hash people really um
you know they thought I was like making
meth and so you know that that charge is
just for anything that is bad and so for
to be able to go through all of that and
go through all the you know house arrest
slash all the [ __ ] I had to go
through uh and that was you know and
then to burn myself like after that
things like oh my God so you know it's
like to to trip up a few times like that
because it's in the very beginning
you're doing things and Building Things
That No one's ever done and you're doing
things that you're just like okay you
know is this going to work and there are
consequences to being at things in the
beginning like that but it's also a
learning thing and you can teach people
who are younger and just be like this is
not what you do that's right the people
who will stand on the shoulders of
giants you being the next generational
giant it's it's that's what we mean when
we say standing on the shoulders of
giants we are learning from their
mistakes as much as we are learning uh
from their breakthroughs and their uh
epiphanies um yeah that's heavy dude for
sure that's heavy I want to get into
that a little bit more in a bit but I
think as we're going through history at
this episode it would be cool to hear
from John just out of his own words kind
of like how he discovered this process
and how he released this process on
eroid once he gets done that I do want
to talk a little bit of more uh from you
know from Adam and Murphy uh Eric uh
tell just in regards to the education
that you guys are doing now uh Jor as
well uh in regards to what you guys do
in order to make sure that we're inspire
iring people to do this the right way
now because sometimes like for instance
I can I can take complete and total you
know accountability for showing everyone
how to make water hash the wrong way
when I first came out I would take the
bubble I'd roll it up all wet everyone's
hash was M molding it it was totally my
fault I was responsible for that for
years and it's like here I am trying to
Pioneer and be a Pioneer and do some new
things and then you make this key
mistake that you wear uh sort of as this
you know for you Eric as a burn mark for
me just as this sort of conscious like
oh my God like all I wanted people to do
was have better hash and I'm probably
responsible for like a metric ton of it
molding like that weighed heavy on my
shoulders maybe not as heavy as a burn
but trust me man it weighed heavy on my
shoulders knowing that I was the reason
that people's hash was molding so that
took a very long time to kind of break
that down and and be you know 2002 to
2007 or8 I was absolutely obsessed with
teaching people about
um the desicant you know for me I found
pizza boxes it was a food grade
cardboard it was hard if I if I if I
seed the hash very very thin over the
cardboard uh it wouldn't stick to the
fibers it would come off beautifully and
the desicant action of the cardboard
would absorb the water which was also
being you know weighed down by gravity
and pulled into the cardboard the
corrugation of the cardboard would go
into one level and then it would dry go
into the next level and so it was a way
for us here in the Pacific Northwest to
to dry hash Nick around 2008 I want to
say or nine he started coming out well
he's in Colorado he's not in the Pacific
Northwest and he's saying I don't know
what this Bubble Man guy is talking
about but you don't need to put it on
[ __ ] cardboard like that's brutal
just put it on some parchment much
cleaner no fibers this that and the
other thing and Nick a and I really
taught each other something because we
were kind of banging heads I was like
what the [ __ ] is this guy talking about
he doesn't know what he's talking about
he's over in Colorado saying the exact
same thing [ __ ] bubble man does not
know what he's talking about we learned
together that yeah in
Colorado where you need all that aloe
you don't need the desicant action of
the cardboard it'll dry from the air if
you break it up small enough but if you
try to do that in the Pacific Northwest
it's not working you are getting
moisture trapped in your hash and it's
going to cause you problems down the
line so Indra if you wouldn't mind
giving us a historical context of how
you came to this like what the [ __ ] dude
you're just like sitting around one day
you're just like what what the [ __ ]
please no I was uh in Vietnam in
1967 and uh trying to get the locals to
bring us some pot to smoke was nearly
impossible they would bring it but it
would be these big wet heavy
Buds and you couldn't light them with a
[ __ ] blowtorch it just wasn't
happening but you could tell that it was
good cuz it looked
good so I uh I started thinking about
it and I
thought well maybe I should try a small
I had read about gasas extraction back
in
1898 and uh I thought well maybe this
will work so I took a big pen I shoved
the barrel out of it crammed it with wet
Buds turned it upside down took a Ronson
butane lighter refill thing and hammered
it and there on the dish in front of me
and a few other guys sitting was a red
puddle
bubbling and everybody's like what's
that Dave and I'm
like that might be the reason or the
answer to us getting high
so not a good thing to do but everybody
put it on
cigarettes and everybody smoked it
including myself and everybody got
hammered and and they're
wondering what it was and I said well
it's it's oil from the
plant that was in '
67 then I uh came back to the States
68 and uh I was shot all the pieces I
got shot through the
middle while I was there and
uh I came back and I was thinking about
it for the longest time and then uh
around
1988 or 89 I ran into this guy I went to
Switzerland and while I was in
Switzerland I
met a guy named Hans who offered me
space to work in his shop even though it
was totally illegal he saw something
else in he saw flowers and spices and
stuff like that so he wanted me to be
there and we did start that we worked
for
roberte one of the biggest perfume
companies on the
planet and we worked for them for a
number of years producing fine perfume
oils
spices and other things like that and
then I started to talk to Hans about
hey maybe we should uh
try some large extractions I had a a 38t
tall 4 in or 4ot wide pipe and we loaded
that we he introduced me to some Swiss
guys who had been growing pot for a long
time and they had a huge Warehouse that
was I don't know it was 600 ft long 200
ft wide it was filled with boxes of
dried pot that mice had come in and
pissed
on and so these guys were like can you
do anything about
that and I was like well yeah I can take
the oil out and it won't smell like M
mouse piss
anymore so we moved everything over
there and started to
work and we were filling this thing up
every other day
and we had gallons and gallons and
gallons of this beautiful red oil that
was just immaculate it tasted so good
you could
hardly not want to have it every day as
much as
possible and uh at that point in
time these guys
uh I I wanted to go back to the States
and so I wanted them to pay me
and they did pay me something but they
didn't pay me for all the work we did
well while that was all going
on they I noticed that after we
extracted there was a lot of uh Tri
chromes
available and so we wanted to try to
find out how to get the TR chromes the
most efficient way out of the
bud and so what I discovered was that if
you freeze the pot using liquid nitrogen
down to extreme low
levels you crunch it all up in a 55
gallon drum use a 4x4 to smash it while
it's cold and it turns it into a pattern
basically that leaves you about 2 Ines
or three Ines of crushed material at the
bottom of the
barrel so then I pulled the material out
and we constructed a silk screen with 26
in 26 per inch
threads and we took the uh pot that we
had crunched up in this and put it in
that and shook it then only the TR
chromes came out all the greens stayed
behind and the reason it did is because
the
green took up some uh moisture
and it wouldn't fit through the silk
screen but the tri chromes all fit
through it like there was no tomorrow so
we made these giant piles of golden Tri
chromes I still have a video of Johnny
shaking it out and scraping it up on a
black sheet that we used at the time and
so here we had these Tri chromes and we
had the
oil so then I thought what will happen
if we mix the oil and the Dr chromes
together to make extremely good
hash and I thought about it and uh what
I did was I poured liquid nitrogen into
a stainless steel bowl those big mixing
bowls you know and uh then I poured the
oil in and then the oil started
shattering immediately because of the
temperature different
differentiation it shattered and
shattered and then I stuck a baseball
bat in it made sure it was all finally
powdered you could it looked like
uh I don't know it it it looked like
maybe milk or something it was milky
looking so after I got that in then I
poured in the TR chromes in a ratio of
55 or 60 to
40 and after that was poured in I start
St it quite a bit and then just stuck
the bowl outside on the porch and liquid
nitrogen drained off and that was that
and you could just reach in and grab a
handful of this really soft hash that
was you could roll into a temple ball in
just a few seconds it would dry with
skin on the outside of it and every
where we were in California we couldn't
make it fast enough it was just uh
everybody wanted it no matter what we
that that was in the day when there was
dispensaries but they weren't really
legal but we would go to them and take
one suitcase full of oil in little one G
bottles we called it golden oil because
it was golden looking it didn't look red
until you heated it then it turned back
red and we took in a uh little suitcase
full of Temple
balls we never left any behind at any
head shop they all bought them all if we
took in two kilos of oil and two kilos
of hash balls they were sold that was it
they paid us cash money and we were out
the
door and so that was my way of making
good hash I tried to make it as safe as
possible liquid nitrogen
non-toxic you know the whole nine yards
and so and then so that just LED you
about 10 years later I would suggest
first of all for those of you that don't
know who Rob roberte is like this is
this is not just a perfume company this
is a company that's been around since
1850 they are like the world's leaders
in natural raw materials when it comes
to fragrance and flavors and extraction
and like any scientist that works at
roberte anyone on this panel would die
to speak to this person for for any
amount of time they really are serious
serious players so you know that's a big
part of of of of history I would also
add that you know when you hear kind of
the older guys talk oh it was the best
this and that back in the day you have
to imagine like imagine BHO like 20 or
30 years before anyone had BHO imagine
what an anomaly it would be to have
someone put that in your bowl I can tell
you before I met John I met a guy in
Amsterdam and I wish I could remember
this guy's name he was a little guy
glasses he was an older guy and he was
from Seattle and he was a real
character and I met him in a coffee shop
in Amsterdam and he said he had this
crazy hash oil that you know no one has
and it's stronger than anything in a
coffee shop and this would have been
like 97 or
98 and I was kind of like well whatever
you know I smoke pretty good man like I
you know okay I'll try your hash and he
he gave me a rip of this hash and I keep
in mind this is really before anyone had
tried BHO and I actually took a small
rip of it and got very very very high
off of it for sure like it was something
different it wasn't just your average
product um I got so high off of it I
actually bought a gram from the guy and
and funny enough and this is it's so
hard for me to even say this I couldn't
[ __ ] finish it I actually went to
Mila's pollinator shop on my way out of
the country and I gave it to her and I
swear to God it was still like a half a
gram so anyway I find out that the guy
got the hash from my buddy the nose and
the nose knows and the nose is Steve
dumac from Amsterdam anyone that's ever
been to Amsterdam and spent any amount
of time at the Cannabis Cup or you know
touring around in that City and if you
are a hash uh uh connoisseur or
afficionado you are going to know who
the nose is anyway lo and behold the
nose and John Davis Indra are old
friends right so he I go over to his and
he's like yeah my crazy buddy came over
and he stuck all this weed in a pen and
he blasted it with a little Ronson tube
and I was just like that's how you made
that [ __ ] I was like what the actual
[ __ ] so I actually got my gram off Steve
it was the last gram that he had I I
don't know how much you made uh there uh
John I I think he said he had like 10 or
20 grams of it it was just a couple of
you know like maybe 10 pen FS or
something but um it was one of the
strongest products I I had ever ever
smoked in my my life and that was the
small world right you know a year or two
later I would start doing Bubble Bags
Indra would release um the BHO method uh
and eventually we would you know kind of
link up to to together I my team
actually went out to his facility in
Kansas and saw his like thre story BHO
extractor like the biggest BHO extractor
you could possibly ever imagine and and
and ran some back is not of cannabis uh
for uh canabo and aromatic compounds but
actually for something completely
different but we did end up seeing that
equipment Mike West and a few other
people from my team went over there and
worked with Johnny and indr son and and
we saw that it was real we saw that this
thing actually existed I we'd never seen
a BHO machine that was metering the BHO
in it would meter it in and out of the
system so he was like we don't have to
worry about wondering how much is and
then he would also talk about how like I
would be like how much did you lose over
like the course of like some years and
he's like oh maybe like a cup full so
he's like reusing anyway cool story
Indra I appreciate uh the old school
this
1967 in Vietnam how [ __ ] crazy is it
that skunkman Sam discovered static Tech
in Africa and Indra discovered the BHO
method in Vietnam I'm just putting that
together right now whoa what country was
did you discover that in again um
Sam it was Gambia Gambia of course it
was of course it was West Africa joh I
have a question for you the material
that you were using that you had boxes
and boxes with mouse p on it in uh
Switzerland was it twiss Rod doe or was
it I because all the stuff that I saw
mass produced in Switzerland BR the
dope I don't know because the Swiss guys
took care of that I took care of the
production and I didn't speak Swiss
German or Swiss French or swiss anything
so I was just a listener at those things
I I saw a lot of people producing a lot
of cannabis in Switzerland when I was
visiting there but most of them were
using varieties that were half uh THC
High varieties mixed with Swiss rope doe
and uh yeah just it's it's not the best
but it it still got the THC in there but
it probably had a lot of CBD I suspect
actually right the plant that we used
for all this was a plant that these
Swiss guys had gotten from the Swiss
Institute of Technology of plants and it
was called queen of
happiness and you could take an 8 in Bud
and shake off about 3 to five grams of
trrs it was something that the Swiss
Institute invented and then these guys
were going there so they took full
advantage of it so that was the that was
the plant dour was what year what year
was the John in Switzerland like was was
this in the late 80s or the late 90s it
was in the late 80s when I went there
and I started producing
stuff and I could I stayed there as long
as I could but even finally the Swiss
people said hey no more visas for you
get the [ __ ]
out yeah yeah no I I did it about 10
years later saw much of what Sam saw as
well definitely saw fields of decent
weed as well Steve was growing really
good weed Shanti Baba was growing really
good weed down in bellan Zona green
houses of of of
spectacular you know proper cultivars
proper you know proper grown actually
some of the nicest flowers I'd ever seen
grown in Switzerland it was a a
greenhouse that that Shanti Baba Scott
Blakey had and it was uh it was 7 foot
tall Calo plants and it was like walking
into an orange orch California Orange
from from originally from me it was so
good Sam holy [ __ ] it was it was
mindbending walking into this room and I
remember asking him I was like whoa dude
like how did you do this like everyone
else was kind of having these problems
and there was and this is not anything
against sort of the people in our
industry or growers in generally and it
might be something to do with
prohibition but um I asked him his
secret and he said I don't hire smokers
and I was like what he's like well
really I don't hire Growers and I'm like
what he's like all my growers in that
Greenhouse are rose Growers I don't hire
weed growers because they already know
how to do everything better than me and
I don't want them doing that on my
dollar so I just hire Rose Growers I
tell them instead of Pricks you have to
be worried about resin that you can get
in your eyes and then it burns and other
than that they just listened to
everything he said and executed exactly
what he said and it was like a perfect
cannabis grow operation and this was
like back in 2001 that I saw this if I
was better organized than I had my old
hard drives plugged in I'd bring up the
pictures uh of I I hate to say this
Marcus but this the same thing with me I
would uh prefer to have Growers that did
not know how to grow pot already and
just did what I told them and uh it
would come out better than
all my friends who have been growing for
20 years sounds like you guys just
prefer using an sop somebody just like
standard operating
procedures it's almost like you wanted
employees in some kind of uh you know
work for pay scenario it's really you
know it's like so much has changed but
uh things stay the same but I I want to
say back to the mouse piss box because I
I felt that in my heart I think one
thing about working with solvents in the
Cannabis industry that is
unfair is that the better you get at
this craft the worse weed people want to
bring you to ask you to save them from
it's like you know we get a lot of
innovation out of cultivation
failures someone else has ruined product
for six months and now after it's been
in storage for another six months I I've
got to figure out how to make it work
and so what's tricky about that is that
we don't really get to
brag about some of the coolest parts of
what we do because it's gross right like
like hor has brought brought up his CRC
right like it it was so cool to be able
to pull that pigment
out even when we didn't know you know
what the function of having it there was
it was just cool and interesting to be
able ble to do and talk about but then
we get this like negative
connotation and no we now we don't get
to discuss our science with the same
excitement because a lot of times we
learn from some garbage boxes of mouse
piss weed and we find out we could do
some really cool [ __ ] no I'm glad you
brought that up Murphy it's a really
good conversation in the sense of you
know I had had the conversation with
media Bros I had had the conversation
with a few different people I've had the
conversation with the irradiation fol
FKS the the people that do you know when
you're failing microbials and it's you
know as a as a business
owner there's there's sort of two views
of sites and we'll get to you right
after this Mark um it's
that okay you've got your sort of
Instagram I hate to call them [ __ ] boys
but this sort of Instagram Bro Science
of like oh yeah like you can't be doing
that you can't be doing this and that's
[ __ ] and that's they're just doing
this to to you know polish a turd and
this that and the other thing from a
business perspective like running a big
facility investing a ton of money like
having employees having responsibilities
and and being accountable to a to a
large group of people you know you make
25 and I asked this question to many
people in regards to the irradiation
like I'm not looking to irradiate myself
I'd love to not have to radiate a single
product if I make 25 kilos of bubble
hash for a a customer and this happened
recently and it was wild because they
wanted to use their own lab for testing
and the the lab came back that it that
it had
failed um so it needed to go to IR
radiation which is what they wanted it
to do I did a huge lab investigation
because I I just was like that's
impossible I swab everything I've done
the math I've done the numbers I am I am
paying attention to my variables in my
lab and it took me three months and
after three months I realized down sorry
John I'll just mute you real quick
um I realized that they had made a
mistake in the lab and that it had not
failed
now that was three and a half months of
a problematic experience now would you
tell if you're a brand new company
you've invested all your money you've
mortgaged your house you've got your
buddies working for you this is a Roots
thing you're not the suits as people
like to you know you're the roots you're
you're doing this the best that you can
and you have a fail like that but you're
going to be righteous for your Instagram
audience and you're going to tell them
don't worry I threw that 25 ke kilos
away who the [ __ ] is throwing away 25
kilos of hash just to serve a group of
people on Instagram who are never going
to buy that hash whether you were
radiated it or not so it's this
double-edged sword and you have it with
CRC as well of course it's great if you
make a nice product but maybe it has a
little bit of a a slight look to it
because consumers are so bloody uh picky
and they're only going to buy something
based on the color and now what oh we
see our SE it but so it kind of becomes
are you the company that made that maybe
a fail happened at a lab that wasn't
even a real fail and you were required
to radiate for this particular reason or
are you the company and this is the part
that that that you're talking about
Murphy why you kind kind of can't talk
about it why you look bad because
there's brutal [ __ ] companies out
there that are doing nothing but growing
moldy schwag they're happy to do it
because they know they can irradiate it
at the end of the process so it actually
affects the so peas in the beginning and
juring because they know where they're
going is just like it doesn't matter
we're going to CRC and we're going to
irradiate and we're going to get great
product that's not really what those two
things were designed to do they were
designed to help people in certain
situations but they become a
double-edged sword you get people who
move in with low integrity and then they
go about doing their business in that
way and so I'll pass it over to Mark
that's all I wanted to say unless you
had something else to say Murphy Oh I
just want to add you know it's what's
tricky is we don't have a good way to
evaluate and compare you know the CRC
gets that complaint about Flavor um but
I always bring up removing the flavor
that was there might have been important
the flavor that was there might have
been gross you know like there's there's
fantastic flour that we can extract and
get fantastic flavor from and sometimes
when you get a box of mouse piss weed we
say in exchange for no mouse piss we're
going to have no other flavor either you
know and so for us to um
you know be blamed for the cut when
we're a Band-Aid is is unfair because we
should be able to promote you know the
individual components and we get better
at that as an industry but you know it's
like uh again I I love nicke too but
that that word solventless really took
us back years in
scientific conversation because we've
we've tried to create
separation in where we should have had a
lot more conversation and a lot more you
know Nuance between each other because
we all want the best of whatever's there
the only one who would say throw away 25
kilos of concentrate is someone who
doesn't have it to throw away who didn't
pay for it to be made um so you know I
believe in recovery you know I believe
in you know reclaiming what you can uh
but safely and it's it's a really um
it's a tricky conversation because when
someone makes green bubble hash and
everybody has done it like one time
it'll happen and then you
learn but they don't have to live with
that every day and they don't try to
sell that
because they can't hide it um and you
know so this is a conversation that we
all have together I think within the
solvent like based Community but it
doesn't really Escape us and it's uh
it's unfair I think to the consumers as
well so CRC has its place for sure but
unfortunately over the years it's
definitely ruined BHO because oh for
sure because we've been running mouse
piss weed you know we allowed Growers to
give us garbage weed because we could
fix it you know that standard was not
held yeah and um like I said see like uh
when I first made the the rosin ship
diamonds years and years ago CRC was a
big part of it and W1 was the best thing
to do that with so like I said it
definitely has its place but as far as
people doing BHO with quality m material
the CRC has trickled over to everyone
just thinks everything CRC so like honed
in on what color it is and people care
more about the color than the actual
quality of having good
hash you're not wrong we're at you know
I I would like to add on that because I
saw it from day one when I released the
bubble bags and started doing the bubble
hash right I I listen I got lucky guys
like me and and Nick and Matt rise we
had an old factory sense and a lucky
ability to be friends with guys like
subcool and people who were growing
spectacular like Second To None cannabis
that was our advantage and so in the
very early days I you know breeder
Steve's like hey you want some shish
Berry buddy and I'm making you know five
star hash with just two or three bags
like who this is crazy so I had access
to all this incredible hash it was a
very short period of time after I
started selling bags that I started
getting these questions hey how do I get
my hash to melt like yours I'd be like o
o h they are not going to like the
answer to this question well you just
need to learn about the symbiotic
relationship between the micro
rizosphere and The Roots and the fungi
intelligence that will help Express
plants and sequester compounds from your
plants you're just going to need to
learn about that it's going to be about
a 10 to 20 year Journey that's going to
take you through absolute insanity and
crop loss and failure and and epiphanies
and and and all of these things or or
you could smash a bunch of into a tube
and blast it with a Ronson can and that
is what 99% of that's why B was taking
off so fast in the early days because
people who had material with like the
Bubble Bags just weren't the same as BHO
in the in the early days the Bubble Bags
would give you a nice material even if
it wasn't melty it could still easily be
50 plus% THC a and be strong but it just
it was those melty photos that everyone
wanted to be a part of it was that melty
shiny hash that everyone wanted and so
they'd say how do I get my hashed amount
like yours and you know the next day
they'd be like [ __ ] it I can p i can
blast this and it will be a golden honey
oil and so it was the beginning of a way
to make something that wasn't very good
look good and Marcus yes go ahead please
uh if you'll recall when you started
Bubble Bas I called you and said hey I
don't want to crush your bubble bag
business you did you AB did you did and
I wanted
to reaffirm that and then one other
thing about roberte is Dr ju uh
Julian was the head scientist there and
when I wanted to get business with them
I asked him give me something to extract
so he gave me some fouryear
old uh lavender all dusty in a
box and I extract Ed it and I sent it
back to him the next thing I know three
days later I got this frantic phone call
from this french guy who can hardly
speak English and he's like how did you
do that what is happening this is better
than the fresh lavender we want to talk
with you so I went in roberte and I sat
down and I became friends with Dr Daniel
Julian who was the head
scientist he then was so enamored of the
process
that he got on a jet and flew to Kansas
and walked into the place to sit down
and see the whole setup and he was like
he kept shaking his head he was sitting
there shaking his head and I said Dr
Julian are you okay and he said yes he
goes but I want you to know that uh
you're about 200 years ahead of the
extraction
industry and I am so happy to be here
and see all this and can I see you
operate at once and I said sure you can
and we did and we became close friends
and we still are we still
talk but
uh that's awesome that's amazing I want
I want to I have a question for you was
that company bigger than Jadon
Rouge hey you couldn't tell me don't ask
me about comparisons bro I don't know
Julian was they were around the entire
world they sourced stuff and country
that there was so do Jo Rouge but I I
don't know
either I can uh I can find that out for
you I want to continue the thought
because I wanted to finish and not be
blaming BHO I feel the exact same thing
happened with Rosen when Rosen was
released uh that happened with and it's
kind of this double-edged sword that
we're talking about with CRC and with ir
radiation you know it's like where can I
find a place for my mediocre product and
so that was a big thing when BHO
happened obviously not everyone has
amazing product the majority of people
who were blasting had mediocre product
it was turning into a golden honey oil
and it looked spectacular but it wasn't
until some of you people on this panel
started showing people what actual bomb
product was and adding all these little
tricks and tips into your Sops to really
preserve and you know get all of that
goodness in the end result it it just
was a place for mediocre product to go
and it was the same thing with rosin to
this day I kind of say about rosin all
the time and don't get me wrong I love
rosin I have beautiful rosin here right
now I've got some honey bananas it's
spectacular it smells so loud and so
beautiful but I do feel I find that when
I ask someone if I can see the hash that
they made the Rosen from they never have
it they never want to show it they don't
want to flex it they don't show it on
Instagram so I say the majority of rosin
is where mediocre hash goes to die
there's a lot of white rosin with no
flavor out there and tons tons and the
thing is you get exactly what you ask
for the problem is that if if we have a
lot of tools available to us we can
deliver on more of those asks so if you
ask me for a white product a clear
product a blue product whatever you want
like I could make a
thing um and so you have to know what
you want and ask the right question and
that is a
pretty
significant ask of a consumer especially
you know in in a market where we went
from not being able to talk about it to
then not being able to see it smell it
touch it or interact with it when we buy
it so it used to be you know that you'd
at least be able to smell that jar
before you picked up a gram of that
rosin and now you do have to purchase it
visually so they're going to ask for a
visual cue that's a terrible situation
if I had to buy my avocados visually my
ability to deliver on good guac would be
diminished you know like sometimes we
just have to identify the real problem
if if you had to smell the product
before you bought it you'd make a
different choice but when we have to
purchase it visually a a dark orange BHO
extract isn't going to look as good as a
bright white one but I happen to know
that I have had some absolutely
delightful dark orange B you know like
and just talking about all of his red
oil like you know the the visual cues
didn't matter when we had others you
know a lot of people complain about the
THC argument but give me any other
number yeah you know no I'm GNA get to
mark because he's raised his hands twice
but yeah someone just mentioned in the
chat oh I agree dude but CRC is Criminal
and another guy's like it's feels sneaky
but it connects exactly to what you just
said people are purchasing based on
their eyes we haven't created that
system we would love people to be able
to test it touch it smell it feel it and
experience it but we can't it has to be
purchased a certain way now obviously
you know I'm not a a BHO guy but I I
just see that when you're and and it's
very similar for um rosin as well and
this is why people are like let's cut
the plant down a little early let's make
sure we liliz and keep it in cold chain
and make sure we pull like taffy to get
those air bubbles in there to lighten
that bubble these are forms of CRC these
are forms of manipulation and sneakiness
that we are you know we're not forced to
do but I say we're kind of business
people are somewhat forced to do if they
want to compete in the market and it's
funny because it's always the buyers the
people who are the buyers who are saying
oh I don't like this and that's sneaky
and that well then then start buying
differently you know pay pay attention
differently Mark please go ahead all
right well first I wanted to say hello
to my old friend John Davis hi Mark it's
great to hear your voice again for some
reason you have a Ken nordine twitch to
your voice that's just uh Irreplaceable
so it's great to hear you again uh
second I want to introduce my friend K
bill here who's kind of one of the OG's
in the room who knows a little bit about
extraction and I think he's got
something to say
hey guys how's it going so first of all
so stoked to see so many here who I
haven't seen in so long Nothing But Eric
then forever forever maybe first legal
Cannabis Cup in
Denver but obviously been around with
everyone um John thank thank you and uh
you know to some of the points
first um
when I first came into fully
regulated market making hash I I hash
was the only way I could get in right I
couldn't I I couldn't get a badge my
dear friend uh fellow cultivator you
know Phil Ha was like hey hey hey Billy
we can hire you as a consultant and you
come back here and make some some hash
for us and then you you get to come and
play right and
um when we first set the machine up I
was talking to gidy up the the founder
emotech and who who I kind of developed
L resin with and he was like you know
something you're G to find out
immediately bill is it's the Grower's
fault if it's good and it's your fault
if it's bad get used to that [ __ ] right
now this is your world and you know I I
I I consider myself to be
at least that good at at cultivating
cannabis as I have been at extracting it
and and and fortunate that I learned on
exceptional material so this was a like
a new world for me to come into the um
this meant trash in and we want gold out
right and then you know live
resin in those early days man we didn't
Harvest rooms for it we walked really
big exceptionally grown rooms and picked
the five six seven best plants of each
cultivar and myself and and like a a Ry
Pritchard or Phil he level of careful
harvested those plants very particularly
and and and it was taken care of that
way all the way through this was the top
cut it was only supposed to be that
within you
know maybe three weeks owners came to me
and were like hey we got a room full of
aens can we
freeze it's like [ __ ] and and I
knew this was mindful
yeah I knew that was coming from the
first run honestly when I opened the
first pot of live resin I had a few a
series of thoughts that weren't around
the quality my very first thought was
like wow I'm going to be able to figure
out never trim
again I was like we're freezing
everything I'm [ __ ] out of the trim
game right my my second thought was like
wow this is special and good people are
probably GNA fight about
this and then my my third thought I was
like wow I guarantee someone is gonna
figure out how to use this to to to make
something bad yeah know I mean because
it looks so amazing you can right away
out of the gate use this as as a tool of
Destruction and and and it happened you
know reliably fast as commercially
driven things
do um but hey everybody on this panel as
a capability of producing you know
ridiculous quality setting standards
refusing
material I I'm I'm that guy I don't see
as much trash people know I'm going to
ask them why the hell they think it's
good and they're going to have to
explain to me so uh you know Mark and I
were talking about this on the way over
here I was like I'm I I don't want to
reward that bad behavior on the flip
side all of these separation and
purification techniques open up a whole
bunch of cool new products and ability
to formulate and and do things with
product that couldn't be used and and
that that's why it's awesome uh same I'm
stoked that rosin blew up the solv on
the scene because the accessibility for
a small producer to single source and do
a craft thing went up but I do think
rousin CRC for Ms I ask everybody that's
why I got my buddy trainer here he came
to me with melts and rosin and fresh
breast the the day I met him and I was
like oh you give many shits you know and
uh I'm
smoking this product today you know I
don't know if you can see the jar but
shout out to you
jari jar thanks Dr
Mar but Bill tell them about your gig
here in Vermont so I'm out here in
Vermont um 802 strong which which ties
into this this conversation right I came
on a coner
and I was like wow this is a market that
has tolerance for Quality that where you
can actually get paid to do a good thing
and uh I ended up Landing here at Zen
bar music venue vertical Place really
beautiful family-owned not a Multistate
operator yeah familyowned business that
was a buyback from an MSO that failed in
the state so it's actually super cool
that uh Mom and Pop dispensory bought a
a cultivation
manufacturing thing um and we're doing
some really cool stuff both uh in Market
in Ros and and you know obviously if I'm
out here I'm going to be bringing
something we're building and uh yeah
it's super [ __ ] cool
uh I'm kind of overwhelmed with with joy
to see all all these folks on the call
yeah Eric it's been a minute and you've
been on TV
so yeah no it's been I usually don't do
anything like this so it's really nice
to be out and about and actually like
be shout out to Jenny for connecting
yeah yeah it's was very very very
awesome you contacted her to I app that
Jenny from Vermont yes all right yeah
shout out to shout out to Jenny indeed I
want to give uh Adam had his hand up I
just we were get it might have been
something that bill was talking about
before we get too far away Adam please
go ahead real quick yeah no worries I
just want to build on what you guys are
saying and ask a question for the group
like has solvent extraction actually
just found its niche in turning garbage
to Gold because I know like there's a
few of you guys that uh you know you
came into this game looking for like
that like that personal stash and trying
to trying to like figure out how you can
get the absolute best quality stuff but
there's also like stories in the group
of like hey you
know process process Innovation was done
through like you know we had this batch
that that just didn't work out and
that's actually how I started as well is
like I I was looking I was using bubble
bags to uh try and get hash out of out
of the trimmings for my grow and that's
how I found um how I found uh uh grey
wolf grey Wolf's work and um grey wolf
was hugely influential for me in uh in
kind of building those first cloth Loop
systems um but one of the like the
untapped potential at that time was
everybody was throwing their trim away
and nobody had anything that they could
do with their trim and BH was actually
something that you could do that you
could make you could make shatter out of
out of uh trimmings that people were
just throwing in the garbage and um but
you see this theme kind of continue and
carry through to today and people get
getting better and better at making
something that's marketable out of um
out of you know either a Grower's
mistake or something that maybe doesn't
have as much commercial value yeah I
feel like a lot of the things that
happened has happened out of mistakes
and learning from things like that but
it's like it's the more places I've been
the more you you need to be able to find
a place for everything that that is
grown everything you don't want to waste
anything exactly as a business
especially as it gets more competitive
part of what we have to be able to do is
be able to find a place for things that
you know because there's always you know
depending on the size of grow that
you're working with you know we work
with a really big one up here um you
know it just depends on what part of it
like the trim or you know I used to have
people trim wet so I could just get the
the trim you know do live resin with
trim because that was a much better
thing for me and it came out so nice you
know so much nicer than when you you
know have it dried and I used to do that
for a long time but yeah a lot of it
really just come came from mistakes
things like that you know like I said to
burn myself to all that stuff but you
know when I have to do consultations
things like that you you really need to
be able ble to work with what you have
so it's like you know or else you go out
of business and then all the people the
families and friends you bring in who
you want to take care of because it's
been you've been in business long enough
to where people have you know thrown
everything they have into it and you
really need to be able to come up with
options for when you know like let's say
the weather's bad or things freeze or
things happen you know especially
outdoor grows things like that you have
to be able to figure out something or
else you go out of business and so
failure failure's important but the rate
of failure I think is also pretty
relevant here and I think that's where
prohibition comes into play Because when
it was Prohibition everywhere everyone
kind of developed at a similar Pace like
there would be one or two people who
showed up to Amsterdam and [ __ ] [ __ ]
up but like it wasn't everyone showing
up with the new version of everything it
was a lot of people showing up with
their version of the same strain right
like even you know the the proliferation
um of the way we cultivate a lot of that
you know happened at at such a slower
Pace under prohibition but at such a
more consistent pace and what I have
found really interesting you know I've
been um you know training people on new
systems and Consulting for a very long
time now and every new market goes
through the exact same [ __ ] it we do
not
learn from our mistakes every new market
comes in with wax and shatter again
before they get live resin and diamonds
again and it's like we all have the same
extractors no there hasn't been much
Innovation on stainless steel tubes in a
long time um but you know what that
shows me is that we can only you know
innovate as fast as the
flower and so it's that rate of failure
their cultivators have to get better
fail more to improve and then the
extractors have to get that exposure you
know it's like almost that 10,000 hours
sort of perspective where it's like you
need 10
runs that came out the same and 10 that
came out un expected before you know you
know how the next 20 are going to go you
know with any real experience under your
belt and I think prohibition has made it
um you know this funny cycle where we're
going see the exact you know if if
France starts you know implementing new
facilities they're going to grow some
basic low potency swag and some really
average homogeneous lowf flavor
concentrates like we're they're going to
do the same things and they're going to
slowly go they're going to make a hard
candy like we don't you know like we
just do the same stuff over and over and
uh you know part of that I think is you
know not to put it all on the consumers
but the consumer consumers are in the
best position to say we don't have to
start over from the beginning give us
what they have start today you know I
love learning about the history of it
but um but I think the consumers should
demand the current
version well let's talk about the
consumer too right like there's a reason
why uh the demand for you know lower
lower and product is higher because
people have a budget and so if you can
provide that that uh you know a better
experience through using maybe CRC or
using some Advanced kind of techniques
to turn garbage to Gold you can present
an option for these consumers that you
know like maybe it's better value for
them and they're making a choice
consciously that you know that they they
just
want they know they know that that's why
they buy it look like I remember
thinking carts are never going to catch
on who would want that it's so expensive
it ruins the oil why would it work and I
was so wrong you know I'll never I'll
never be able you know to go back to the
days when carts weren't the only way you
could make a profit you know producing
oil in the regulated market and you know
that's the consumer saying we'd rather
have it be more convenient than be more
flavorful so some of it is we have to
listen they do tell us what they want
and we and we say but what if it could
be good in our you know margin of
production puts ourselves out of
business like maybe we do have to just
Embrace that some people like mids we're
not
just we're we're in a commodity Market
where where price and cost of goods sold
is going to always win and so the 800
pound gorilla in the room is that it's
cheaper to chemically convert CBD into
THC than it is to extract THC from
cannabis plants so with that being in
the room I mean all that hemp derived D9
that's out there is all from chemical
conversion not from fractionation of
mother liquor yeah so let's face it
we're in a commodity industry here where
price is always going to win and like
Bill said people drink Budweiser I bet
you on this crew here people would
rather prefer like a headyy IPA
something locally brewed and Artisan
product but yeah the bigger addressable
Market and you know look at moves that
the the msos have made all big msos are
now getting into the hemp space Wana now
has a hemp thing I think this hemp thing
is completely taken the market out and
maybe sucked the little wind out of the
high quality
end well it's that next it's that next
level right um okay so Ryan Telly had
his hand up I just I was gonna say one
thing prior but I think it might have oh
when Adam was talking about the early
days turning trash into stash I used the
exact same term that term has changed a
little bit I'm when I said trash to
stash back in the day like that trim was
amazing it made Five Star Plus bubble
hash um trash into stash doesn't have to
mean like Mouse soaked urine soaked you
know what I mean like that's a we need
to be careful with the language that we
speak of course what Adam is speaking of
when he does say trash to Gold yes you
can take material that's not not as good
as maybe you know that's lost a lot of
its margin that you can take you can
clean up a little M make it an
affordable product and this is this is
the difficulty look I'm sure the
majority of the people on this panel if
we could we'd make it so everyone was
smoking the greatest product in the
world but not everyone has the money or
wants to put their money towards that
the same way that we do so then it
becomes a market that if you want I'd
rather see all those extractors get
health insurance you know like we all
have a stake in this
and I think we you know what we need to
do is is really
embrace our position in you know in
these roles because like Mark said if if
the goal is cheapest D9 if customers say
I want the cheapest D9 that's what I
need that's what I'm going to spend 80%
of my money at the dispensary on then we
can scale that up in a way that puts
less people at risk so that the people
who want to do really cool flavorful
stuff can hold their Market you know a
crap Brewer doesn't try to compete with
Budweiser they don't have to compare
themselves to Budweiser it would be
weird to they're not the
same
right yeah that's one thing I want to
make sure is like while you know we may
have found the niche in in being able to
be the good Recyclers of the industry I
want to make sure we're not relegated to
that position because you know that's
something that that like has always been
my goal is to is to just get to the
middle of the Tricom you know like strip
away the cuticle the you know the
secretory cells I just want to get to
just the pure o as pure of the oil as I
can and and on my Journeys I've found
that to be butane extraction and uh and
I find it to be you know like when when
you have great weed and and you know I
consider a good hash maker a good hash
maker is only as good as their ability
to grow or curate good material to me
you know like if you want to talk about
like at the highest level you know of
like you know competition hashm when it
comes to like you know solventless or
solvent it really comes down to your
understanding of Canabis at that point
as just like an you know as as a
cultivator and you know at an intuitive
level um so I just want to make sure
that like that's that's put in this
conversation here because I know like
Yari and a couple other couple other
people probably probably want to make
sure he said that because Yari is a
hybrid living soil single Source all the
way to the end and he crushes it so yeah
I remember selling him commercial
equipment and it [ __ ] up his oil and
like like I remember that it was weird
to hear that story again today because
like I haven't thought about it in a
while but I think about that a lot where
people are ruining their own product you
know by trying to adapt to way that the
market wants us to do it you know and I
think there's so much opportunity to
innovate you know when we can we can
really focus on what our goal is if
every extraction is a
experiment then you know you can do good
science and not prove your hypothesis
but like have a goal before you start
and to make fire does not count that's
not a goal like that's not all of it's
going to catch on fire so that's not
really a you know the goal has to be
more specific than that if the goal is
make the cheapest D9 get your efficiency
numbers up I could be the most efficient
at extracting cannaboids I could be the
most efficient at extracting tpin I
could be the fastest you know but a lot
of people look at saying I have the
coldest solvent tank they measure things
that are weird and extraneous instead of
um you know their ability to achieve
their you know intended output
and Murphy I wasn't I wasn't uh using
that as like like knocking on you you
help me as much as I as you oh I know I
just remember not being able to solve it
and it's I still don't
like yeah so but I mean uh what Telly
brought up is a good point and like that
is the I am I'm on a much smaller scale
than I'd say probably most of you but me
doing everything on my own and being in
control of all of it I can see all the
variables when something works better
something doesn't work better all the
things that I've learned have been from
all of my own mistakes with all of my
own material so doing all those things
over the year has got me to the point
where there is no trash there is no mess
ups there is no bad stuff anymore
because I've already failed every way
that you possibly can so um but being
control of the Clones uh making a tissue
culture room growing everything and
living soil I'm on my 58th round of the
same soil so it's been 10 years in same
dirt um all those things contribute
to hunting the best tpping I've done
side by sides with people that grow rock
wall we've got the same cuts the turps
just come out better in living soil so
um not FL call to buy your stuff
buddy I appreciate it
yeah hey Yari can you talk about some of
the cuts what what are you running now
um I've got tons of cuts um there's a
lot of stuff that I've been growing for
like 15 years uh that I've that I've
just kept around and then there's always
new stuff that we're trying out and my
circle of friends is the same but um I
have an eight Lightroom and a nine
Lightroom and I try and do one new
strain not one new one but one strain
per table so that I just always have
like the the biggest variety of flavors
and some are Staples and then I'm always
peppering new ones but there's a lot and
what what I've been seeing that's pretty
interesting is that although I'd say
some of the newer Generations once the
candy and the gas and all the hype stuff
there's a lot of people that when I do
these old school ones they're gone as as
as soon as I tell somebody they're
available they're out the door
Strawberry Cough the four Collins cut
Super Lemon Hayes uh grape Cola that's
probably one of the oldest ones that
I've done like there's I probably have I
think 40 or 50 cultivars in the in the
grow room right now so there there's a
lot
um and and going going back to things um
it's interesting because we were talking
about colors of stuff and like it seems
like the consumers
dictating what they want and it's not
really like the the best outcome like
everyone's so hyped on this white rosin
when people are pulling it at six weeks
the plant isn't even close to getting to
its maturity to really produce the the
best that it can especially on the
turpine level so
it's pretty strange like like that that
is dictating people are more concerned
on like the color versus like the flavor
and the experience of the actual hash
itself that's always been a hard thing
as far as quality versus what people
want what I consider like what I like to
smoke versus what I find other people
care about tend to be different things
and it always surprised me as I went
through the business of like how is it
that you don't want the best flavor
thing whether it looks
yellow or not you know to me that was
always the thing was the flavor and like
the nose like what that's not what
people care about necessarily sometimes
it's
strength sometimes it's not even smell
because they have kids or they don't
want something that has a strong smell
you know so it there is a definitely a
market for everything it seems like but
yeah the super high quality stuff it's
um sometimes not as sought after in
certain markets well I think we just
lack the language forids
well you don't you
also you've negated the education as
well right in the sense that people go
and buy your product they don't
necessarily know what each product is
nor the extraction process that got it
there right and most people have waited
to see what the market dictates as
opposed to putting out the diversity
because of the cost right you can't run
a whole bunch of different SKS package
them and get them out the door right so
these are real world situ situations
where the market itself educated itself
as opposed to y'all educating the market
correct which is for the most part kind
of an opposite way of doing things but
the market followed but the
understanding of what quality is and the
different levels of production I think
is still something missing to the
average consumer because we at the
dispensaries are still Fielding lots of
questions they still don't understand
the extraction or they're still afraid
because it say BHO on it right and then
you've all dealt with the repercussions
of oh you're evil bad and pushing
petrochemical Bad Evil [ __ ] and they
don't understand this is the same
process that your coffee is decaffinated
with okay that you've been drinking for
decades so stop with the fear
mongering and understand the different
levels of process right because the
dispensaries don't have the Educational
Tools nor have we been given them it's
something we've had to self-educate to
take forward so
how do each one of you decide which
products SK you take forward in a new
market that's a challenge and a question
into itself and usually usually that's
not an extractor making that decision
unfortunately you know guys we wouldn't
have had live res sorry Kelly go ahead
nobody wanted that [ __ ] I I they were
like what the [ __ ] is this it looks
weird how come it doesn't shine it gets
my jar sticky yep nobody wanted it but
how do you use it
righte it but we I I was working at a
place that had nine stores we had a
vertical so we were able to train Bud
tenders to be like just close your eyes
and smell this and decide if you want
this or not and people wanted it when
they smelled it you know what I mean
when I showed when I met Mark I showed
him a pretty fat jar of dog's Walts I'm
kind of s eying him right now gave him a
sniff he grabbed a rat out of my hands
and stuck his fingers in there and stuck
it in his mouth because he was so
overwhelmed by how like and I was like
back and forth whether I hated or loved
him for being able to do that decided
love it was the soft serve ice cream of
weed come on now that's that's a
privilege of Colorado though I will say
is we have always maintained the ability
to have a Le product for people to smell
there are lots of places that it the bug
tender has never smelled it it is so
sealed up and individually packaged the
person who grew it has no idea what that
final nitrogen packed Tin Can smells
like so that you know that data point
consumers are using every piece of
information we give them and what we
give them is flashy packaging weight THC
and maybe a picture of it you know and
so it's like giving them the the
language to ask for what they want a lot
of them would say they want more flavor
a lot of them would you know make a a
sacrifice for you know a lower potency
and more broad flavor if the price point
fit but like we've got to use every
piece of data and and we give them so
few you know because what we say to each
other about it is like the strain name
because we intuitively know like oh you
have some papaya melt yes I do want to
see that every time you know like oh you
have honey banana melt yeah I'll take a
look at that every time I know that if
I'm looking for gas like every once in a
while I run into some people who always
have sour diesel wax and let me tell you
something that Sour Diesel wax is still
the fire and the fire is a useless
phrase but it it's the one that means a
lot to all of us you know we've all
learned and defined what that fire is
consumers you know don't have that same
recognition a lot of us who want that
fire will still smoke a like clean
sourced cart when we're on vacation at a
Thanksgiving family dinner because we
all
recognize you know that there's a time
and place for everything you know I we a
lot of us have our drawer like a wine
offish andado would have a seller of a
fancy bottle that we just have and I've
about this little half gram of some
special stuff that I take a little dab
of from time to time and save for
Nostalgia so you know the the language
of how we share that with consumers is
really lacking and within the solvent
space it's it's
usually a lot of us saying we want
education but then a marketing
department who is detached from both
cultivation and extraction the
enemy sales the enemy Marshall wanted to
chime in but before he did I you know we
were talking about color and I just it
was going on in my head and I thought
wasn't it Bob Marley who said until the
color of a man's hash is of no more
significance than the color of his eyes
had to had to drop that one because I
was feeling it and uh Marshall continue
the conversation oh I also wanted to
thank etan for coming in you know I was
really trying to keep the panel today
really sort of um you know oil and hash
oriented but I think atan brings a
really great persp perspective from that
dispensary perspective as we're talking
about the customer and I don't know if
you guys heard it as loud as I did but I
heard there's a great disconnect between
the processors and the dispensaries who
are selling their products and I think
Murphy made a good point that that is
that marketing department that steps in
and has no connectivity to either of
these uh uh processes so uh Marshall
please go ahead yeah thanks I know I
don't have the experience in this
industry like you guys do at all but I
just wanted to give you guys my personal
perspective on this because I have you
know had pieces of it here and there
anyway I grew up in Utah very
conservative right never thought i'
cannabis legal in any state let alone
many of them I'm living in Washington
now Washington's one of the states where
you cannot open any the packaging you
can't do anything with it but look at it
and uh I mean you can smell the whole
store right because it's smells good in
there but also then in between living in
Utah and now Washington I lived in
Humble for 6 years seven years roughly
on and off and so I knew people growing
and I could go get it from them or hang
out with them or whatever so I think
maybe I was spoiled from that experience
in comparison to what I have here in
Washington I do not go to the rec shops
anymore in fact I've actually almost
nearly stopped smoking because I can't
go to the store get something that I
want I throw it away I thrown away
thousands of dollars worth of products
because I smoke it once and I throw it
away because there something wrong with
it after seeing the way you know people
growing it personally and seeing what
their products come out from that I I
don't know what they're doing I don't
know why it's so different for me but I
can't I can'tjust it so this also comes
back to the uh synthetic right making D9
from from uh hemp I currently work at a
large hemp extraction facility we s
drones of ethanol and CO2 extract and it
hurts me person personally to know that
this is now what's going on is that we
could be selling this to somebody they
could then be making it into D9 that
could be then going into a distillate
with fake tpin added to it and then sold
literally as live resin carts right in
the shop and you don't know and you
can't even when you go to the website
they'll tell you they're doing something
else I can analytically very easily tell
you whether or not that's real I can
taste it and tell you whether not it's
real pretty immediately if anybody has
you know wants any help trying to help
battle this like to me I don't
understand where the market struggles
then these other synthetics become
cheaper people start using them how do
we deal with this like I said the the
idea of growing up in Utah where it was
so conservative right we're in this
place where it's now and all I see it is
destroying itself and uh anyway so if
there's anything I can do to help
analytically sensory anything any of
this stuff please reach out to me
because I believe in all this stuff
being medicine and also just personally
enjoyable from sensory and experience
everything else like that and I struggle
to see what's already happened to it
here in Washington so can you analyze
and quantify
flavonoids uh I cannot personally right
now but I do have a lab every single
person I have asked for 10 years says
that well I mean I have a lab couple
blocks from my work where I can for sure
I think that's a huge opportunity for us
that we're missing even when we started
being able to test for tpin it was good
info but all of us recognized that the
tpine number was too low based on our
experience like the volume of the flavor
part versus number that's the color the
color is not likely canono the color is
probably and if we name them and
quantify them yeah you got to remember
too in the plant there's two parts to a
flavonoid there's a glycoside there's a
sugar portion and then there's What's
called the aglycone so typically by the
time you've gotten to extraction or
you're getting to uh uh distillation
you're certainly only dealing with the
agly cones and those are really super um
colored so they're very high Extinction
coefficients so a very little bit will
color a whole big batch but the other
thing I wanted to go back to was the cat
piss you know think about it or mice
piss uh mice piss
or yeah mice urine right is water
soluble right so if it was oil soluble
it would still be inside the mouse so um
if you are extracting and you're using a
a non-polar hydrocarbon yeah you're not
going to get all the water soluble crap
that was in the mice piss right because
that's all water soluble right and if it
was fat soluble it would still be in the
mouse right John that's right and you
you know
before we uh travel off in another
Direction because I'm starting to run
out of
steam there's a
hash a turpan that nobody really has
been able to extract successfully in any
large amount called
hasine you heard of that I guess but
anyway people find it an extremely old
hash and they can meta out the hashen
name which is a very syrupy golden
liquid that tastes like the best hash
you've never had in your mouth ever but
I have discovered a way to make it
happen and what we did was we took uh
five pounds
of
uh a certain kind of oil uh train wreck
and we froze it in a nitrogen freezer
for maybe 3 years at the end of those
three years I pulled that out put it in
the uh vacuum oven and passed it into a
collection device which I got off of I
can't remember who now but
uh the this thing would collect in tiny
droplets as the rest of the oil was
going by and that would be hashen and I
found out that if you do five pounds of
the uh train wreck that you can end up
getting about a quarter pound of this
hasine and I didn't want to see that
disappear into the ether because I don't
know of anybody else that looked into it
or anything so I
wanted there was a paper published in
2011 by a group over in Switzerland I
think of all places and they they found
it only in the areas of hash that were
exposed to sunlight and so the same
group basically that identified hasinine
they did used all the analytical
chemistry you know Mass Spectrum and all
that kind of stuff identified the
molecule they also postulated how it was
being formed again in a photolytic
reaction of mine so mine can absorb a
photon and when it does it becomes an
excited state and rearranges into
hasinine and so yeah that paper was
published in 201 11 I
believe hey Mark are they now finding it
inh that that sees really deep vacuum
for extended periods of time as well I
don't know are they not because I
thought they were finding it in like
these like cold long cold shatters
too um perhaps yeah yeah that that I
could be totally wrong I S I read
something on that and maybe
2014 as as far as I know know hasinine
has never been proven to modulate or
potentiate
THC no you don't get high off smoking it
at all it just is an amazing flavor a
turpan Beyond Turpin that's all nobody
you you can smoke all of it you want you
won't get high I took it with me to uh
Emerald cup one of the first or second
ones and at one of the booths I ladled
some into a couple of pipes because
everybody was asking because at that
time I was being observed quite a lot so
I put some hasine in the pipes and the
next thing you know we had a group of a
hundred people follow us around and real
cup all one some guy named Chance was
pushing me in the chair that I was in
and he would go to a new booth and go
hey indra's here and then 100 people
gather around the we everybody wanted
some of that Hine even though they
weren't getting high on it it was a an
incredible
flavor something that's not to be missed
if you can I still have about a quarter
ounce of it in my freezer and in a jar
and I I take it out when I when I end up
buying crappy weed from a shop or
something I pull the hashen A out and
dose it with that dude that's
sneaky but if you keep if you keep
passing around for decades then it turns
into something
else well hear your voice I'm gonna
smoke some hay in your
honor res cart question uh so live
resent carts have hit the scene for a
hot minute now do any of you guys make
live resin carts and how much HT do you
actually use to call it a live resin
cart
like probably like a third to 40% I'd
say something like
that I do 70% HD for oh see that's what
I would prefer I like just straight just
like that straight I don't even like the
Melt mix for p my personal stuff I just
like the super turpy but you know that's
like I just use the GC and um dose it by
uh total turpine content and you use
just TS use HTE so it's HTE but um
because I fraction everything I can pull
you know lighter and heavier back
together and so you know to start with I
wouldn't call it
HTE if you've got you know anything over
I would say 20% at the most but you know
10% would be ideal of dissolved
cannaboids in it so you know a lot of
people call things HTE that are really
you know nearly 40% still other
cannaboid thca and stuff that's
dissolved um and so for it to be you
know clean enough and high enough Purity
you've still got flavonoids You' still
got Esters you know all kinds of oily
things compared to like the you know
really more volatile TPS and so when I
just aim for that specific tpping
content because my HT is all very watery
because of fractioned it I know that
it's you know going to be almost 40%
tping and then you know another 20% of
that other category um because a lot of
people are putting out even again now
back to the language issue we call it
high turpine extract but some people's
High turpine extract is 7%
tpes and so you know they could put that
100% in the cart and it still wouldn't
have the flavor profile you know and
some people's High turpine extract
they're decarbing and heating and so
they've changed that
profile in a ways that Mark would love
to nerd out about probably for us you
know and the rearrangement and you know
how some of those are going to change
and so you know the way we even Define
HTE is still really vague because high
should have a minimum threshold I would
think but what send me
some what's that I said send me some
send you some you gonna save it for
decades though because I heard we got to
smoke it fast is what I heard from Sam I
can you got smoke it fast
I do I do love I love that interaction
though of watching you know Sam bring up
is it you know biologically relevant and
for you to say no it's just for fun
that's probably one of the Big Marketing
issues we've run into is that because we
had to Market this legally as a medical
product to create an infrastructure and
then we were marketing literal medical
products and America markets Medical
Products better than any country in the
world and by better I
mean you know with deception and
efficacy um but you know we haven't been
able to say this is important because we
like it this is important because it
tastes good this is important because
it's fun we've had to say this is
important for your mood for your
inflammation for your medical whatever
you know and so marketing has been
Twisted into this you know need to
impose a medical value
on a feature of the product rather than
just
embracing value mcy you you do
understand that when you combust or vape
uh flavonoids you do that you deactivate
them oh of course yeah if you want the
medical benefit we're we're talking
about food and that's where you know
that marketing gets completely lost to
the consumer because now consumers are
trying to eat gummies that have tpin
added that's going to do you know I
don't know what and they're not getting
a flavonoid count or any kind of
nutritional you know there's so many
valuable parts of that oil that we throw
away you
know yeah let me just mute that sorry
about the sorry yeah I just muted the
the mic um I did want to talk about
something that also feeds into exactly
what we're talking about here in the
sense of
you know extracting these aromatic
volatiles you know we love them we love
a lot of people love this High turpine
extract they love the flavor profiles at
what point in time because we know what
the capabilities of these compounds are
especially in Purity at what point will
we saturate and hit the number that is
like you know what this might not be
good to be um volz or vaporizing and
inhaling into our lungs I remember when
Tony started doing the TPS uh with Blue
River extracts and Blue River extracts
Canada we were doing you know TP dips
and just dipping our our full Mount
bubble right into like just like a jar
of like water clear I mean we were
calling them turpins I would suspect
they were probably should be named more
accurately aromatic volatile compounds
uh because I'm sure there were other you
know files and thiolates and Esters and
other things present other than just
tpin we just didn't have the capability
of perceiving them uh with analytical
equipment so um what how much is too
much I mean I think we've all pasted a
cart that was too much before and the
issue is that you know we've allowed the
agricultural nature of the plant and the
way that every Harvest can be different
to cross over into the lab there's not a
good excuse for every batch to be
different in the lab we can control a
lot um and the amount of flexibility
that we give the bat should be limited
to those flavors to those volatiles to
those things that are actually unique
and you know we see that very plainly
when we look at the label on flour
because you can have a room of 15
different aromatic profiles and flavors
with one or two percentage points away
from each other in
potency and
so you know to recognize that margin of
variance you know would require imposing
that in our manufactured products too
and so you know the fact that most
people don't even put the tpping content
on the label and then if they do do they
have a standard for that you know is
someone because you can have flour at
1.8% turps and concentrate at 1.8% turps
that's common that's for sale today and
that doesn't make any [ __ ] sense yeah
no for real Adam Adam and Marshall both
have their H uh hands up uh I think it
was Marshall first and then Adam so go
go ahead Marshall how do you put a hand
up I'm not very text saavy well are you
on a phone or a computer computer okay
so it's down I believe next to
react like next to share there's a
little heart oh the heart and it's a
drop down or pop up cool awesome thanks
guys I'm not I'm not too too good with
this [ __ ] well I will say before
Marshall goes and before uh Tony goes to
or not Tony I was saying Tony because
Tony's the guy that's in the room
chatting just said Nate yar's carts are
the best thing out there little uh
little little little props for you there
buddy so go ahead Marshall and then Adam
yeah on that topic of uh how much is too
much I think also the delivery method
can be pretty important and how hot you
get the oil and how it's being
volatilized off of the material uh so
for instance if you're dabbing uh with
any amount of tpin you can create
acryline and other reactive alahh tides
that can actually really damage your
lungs there's definitely medical case
studies out there people dying from this
from dabbing for a certain period of
time they're using a hot nail right so I
don't know how you guys do it I've
actually never done that just because it
just looks like smoking crack um my body
started doing that humble I'm like I
just roll a joint it's how I deal with
it
um but oh we must bring you to the dab
side my brethren bring you to the dab
I'm sure it will happen but uh I I make
a lot of oils uh where I'm working so
we've
TS
um as well I've I've uh dosed some of
the hemp tpin into or or oil I like to
call it as well because you're correct
there's all kinds of other compounds in
there besides der beans into beer and I
overdosed myself one night uh kind of on
accident didn't have lab equipment to to
dilute it had a stainless steel um like
straw that I had in the in the kitchen
dipped that in some oil put that into
some Ever Clear so I diluted it out into
some alcohol and then took one drop of
the Ever Clear into a beer and kind of
swirled around the can smelled it I
could smelled it smelled pretty good
took what Sip and it was it either came
back to the top of the beer and was
concentrated or it was just too much in
there um and I I did this kind for hop
companies making flavorings and things
for beers for years so I tried this
before but first time with him uh it it
was like a pretty strong stimulant it
for sure dropped my blood pressure
increased my heart rate and it was
intense for about an hour so anyway
that's where I I did overdo it in a
beverage uh just that one time when I
didn't have lab equipment to actually
get the dilution right and it was too
much um smoking wise though I've never
hit that I I definitely do a lot of
sensor and the oils we're making and I
can just smell these things all day you
definitely get high for about a half
hour as you're doing it and it goes away
um but uh they're they're also you know
like we're talking about with solvents
right these are all solvents some of
them are better for than others mirene
is definitely carcinogenic so one of the
major components in there especially if
you're doing a good job uh extracting it
it's got two terminal double bonds that
are reactive potentially and and can
cause problems so just keep that in mind
and think too much is where you know
you're just
overindulging you at the Lev of
concentration of the plant that's the
right amount you go beyond that it may
taste great it may smell good but it's
probably not great for you especially
when you're removing it from the plant
Matrix that's how it was designed that's
how we evolved with it so that's how I
would consider it um and think about it
that way enjoy it if you want every once
in a while but I wouldn't go smoking
really high HD all the time
lead problems interesting perspective
for sure thanks Marshall go ahead Adam
and then hor after no I know that's uh
the feeling as well because I'm pretty
sensitive to tpin especially in a cart
super interesting though about like the
maybe the carts that I smoked were not
really vaporizing at the right
temperature but I was getting like just
really bad like kind of burning nose um
if it gets over probably about 5% TP
beans in a cart or like 5% like all
everything that's in the HTE really um
but really I think another kind of good
thing to bring up here is is that's good
opportunity for um some of the
crystallization processes as well where
you can separate I know Murphy you're
mentioning HTE but being able to
separate the HDA out from the from the
um THC then you can actually create like
a standardized product reformulating
those creating repeatable formulations
but I think the repeatability here is
like is a big factor as well as like um
a lot of what has been brought up is
really just missing standards in the
industry um like if you look at the wine
industry um you're not allowed to call
uh something um you know uh champagne
unless it's from a certain region and
produced in a certain way and so that's
missing from our industry and so you end
up with um I know someone mentioned that
uh you know buying a live resin cart but
it's just like D9 from hemp mixed with
like some like tpin that they bought and
uh what's missing there is is really
like the the standards um not just for
marketing but also for like how it was
produced and then getting everybody on
the same
language I feel like that is an
interesting perspective that we've
covered many times here on hash church
and whenever I go back to thinking about
it I feel that and it really feeds right
into What marshall just said that the
plant Matrix knows how to create the
safest way even though I've been chain
smoking concentrates for like 25 to 30
years uh hopefully I'll be okay I feel
pretty good um yeah it's uh what was I
gonna say I don't want to lose my train
of thought oh that we're not perceiving
everything that's present in a in a in a
cannabinoid and aromatic volatile
compound profile so those profiles have
a variety of things that never are
understood by us that we don't and this
is why I wanted to do this aromatic
profile show with with Nick zegler and
and Marshall and a bunch of others and
get these people his colleagues who who
designed this equipment that was able to
perceive these thols and thiolates at
such just unbelievably small uh
fractions so it's the my worry about
reformulation uh which I guess would
kind of echo a little bit about what
Marshall was just saying is that if
we're
missing too much of the picture and when
I say too much yes these compounds are
in way smaller um amounts but for anyone
that has ever had the exposure to THS uh
it they you don't need a lot like that
is that funk and that garlic and that it
it it's so strong that I I theorize I
don't think it's accurate I'm not a
chemist or anything but from the
conversations with Nick and Dr Mark and
different people that this giant tarpine
profile that we give all omage to is
balanced precariously on a much smaller
delicate profile of smaller lesser
percentages that can shift that thing
from rotten baby diapers to strawberries
in a very very very small percent so
well we know that we know that because
you can buy off the-shelf turpins that
are like if you were going to test the
tpine profile of a plant it looks
exactly the same as the formula from off
the shelf kind of Botanicals right but
it when you taste it you know it's
completely different something missing
please jge uh it's uh you're up you've
had your hand up thank you by the way
Adam so I just want to share like my
experience on on like with these uh
topics I've uh played with CRC a lot and
then a lot of testing and also with
HTE so to start from the beginning like
back when they were saying uh CRC is
removing turps I I did a lot of testing
on that and found that actually the
turpins at least look the footprint
looked uh identical the uh to the amount
of tpin in there like nothing was being
offset or extra maybe a few 1% I mean
like points of uh percent of a
conversion say but the flavor was still
there essentially so when I looked into
it further I used the UV light and found
that the flavonoids which uh will glow
in that once they're absorbed into the
media the absorbance they were showing
up in the uh Medias and that what was
that's the flavor that was was being
pulled out that was associated with the
flavor LW say but when I looked into it
further it's like a that's where you say
how much is too much all those compounds
are a little bit heavier so they're
going to give you more of a harsher
taste to the extract so CRC is actually
balancing it and giving it like a more
better
profile and then you know people thought
like okay the red was more like it
needed more CRC to remove that color but
that red is like we already remove the
color with CRC that's the
chlorophyll uh and the other like
flavonoids you know the other pigments
so uh the red was more from like the
carotenoids which are just basically
like a hydrocarbon chains that that were
breaking down they were oxygen atoms
were attaching to it and making them
Santo so now they're looking red and
that's the red we're seeing so we were
never going to pull out that red with
more CRC so that's where people used too
much of it and gave it a bad name but
but essentially once we went into uh
looking further into the HTE I started
looking into say the waxing theht and
that came from pushing it through a a
micron filter using
nitrogen and that would allow it to
basically dewax it and pull even more
heavier
compounds and started playing then with
like a making my own Vapes and found
that like I don't know if you guys dab
distill it before or just like pure
distillate or or diamonds but it doesn't
really just it doesn't give you that
full High you know it's like a little
bust that it gives you really
quick and I started noticing like okay
you don't really need that much D9 I
guess to get you that high where you're
comfortable you're satisfied that comes
more from going into
say when you go like to
a how do I say it like uh when you add
the other HTE components to it
so if
you add like a 90% cartridges which
unfortunately is what a lot of
dispensaries are going for they just
look at those numbers and if it's 90% or
higher that's what they're shopping for
to put on the shelves but in reality you
don't need that much because the flower
comes you know with very little and it
does the job so what that's telling me
is that you really just need about 40
50% say D9 in the cartridge and the rest
being HT and other stuff to uh basically
modify that high and give you that full
spectrum effect so just B basically
wanted to touch up on those things just
from my experiences that I tested I
agree with that sure I feel like the
more tping like that it does give you
the better effect and it's not about the
THC number and it is about the full
spectrum tpine effect with it the
Entourage effect that they call so I
totally agree with that I think we've
been able to lean on Full Spectrum
within the industry as like a catchall
because we also have these kind of you
know
intuitive we know what fire is because
we you know have seen the best and the
worst um you know just to shout out
abstracts I think you know to give us a
language that allows us to identify that
category that we've been calling
TPS um you know which is probably more
appropriate than tpin because t is a
real thing and TPS can be a madeup one
you know put a z on it maybe um but you
know if we could just start categorizing
you know and like Marcus brought up to
put the to put the number on there
wouldn't
necessarily communicate the influence of
that number but if we could even I
imagine just a pie chart of how much of
this is
volatile and you know so if we were to
instead of saying hi turpine extract we
were to say extremely highly volatile
turpine extract versus medium volatile
extracts like are your turps popping the
lid every time you open them at room
temperature or do they not you know um
are these turps that are weighted by
oily flavorant because to add that
flavor category that isn't a volatile
aromatic is also really important
because like what I was just saying you
ask us for no color we can give you no
color and if you ask us for no flavor
and no color we can give you that but if
you ask us for flavor and no color you
might be wrong about what you're asking
for because sometimes the flavor you
want has color you know and so to be
able to clarify what people are getting
out of it if we could give them a
representation of this this is a product
that
contains you know and agreed upon
we Define what's high you know because
no one's going to say this is a medium
level and no one's going to say low even
being able to say low THC you know is an
impressive achievement for the hemp
industry I think um because we've just
you know we've built ourselves up on
delivering high but if we could start
addressing it like volatile aromatic
flavor and then cannaboid potency as
extractors we could start really
innovating and our formulation could be
delivering for everybody it could be
delivering our own efficiency you know
like we started harvesting rooms for
extraction we started growing strains
for hash making now we could start
chasing resin for individual compounds
this [ __ ] could get better and better
and better um but we we do need the
language for what we're looking for
because we've been calling it some
pretty generic terms and I think we've
exhausted the turps no amount of mercine
is going to make a difference to me the
way a little bit of humulene does the
way a little bit of thle does the way
like those small numbers do and I think
there is a way for us to communicate
that to each other it does start with
the science we do need more people to
just add it up and it's tedious work and
investigating it and coming up with a
standard for it it's no good it's it's
it's effort you know um but that's
that's the work that on our end we have
to do and then when we get done with
that we can't stop we have to then
communicate it out to people in a way
they can understand it so that it's not
you know so that if you tell me 2% th
I'm like oo spicy that doesn't mean
anything to anybody else we got to
figure out how that message gets all the
way absolutely horay had his hand up and
then Max you're right after him I had a
question for you guys one observation I
made like touching up on the color
because the color's there obviously
because the chlorophyll is there once to
remove it this oil canot oxidize quickly
if there's say no Turpin to protect it
but some like side observation I've seen
on that I've had HTE that wasn't fully
purged that sat for like say a year or
two and it seems like the hydrocarbons
are protecting it from the oxygen
bonding to it and oxidizing it because
the color is and smell everything there
is just like when I extracted it you
know and it was just jars that were
sitting around waiting to get processed
you know and like I said they're for
sure like over a year old and it seems
like they were just fresh and I just
want to see if you guys have seen also a
similar
observation yeah that definitely can
happen I definitely feel like that that
is something that happens with it the
oxygen not being in there and it
preserves it for a long time if stuff
has sat around for like that and it's
already turke in the first place yeah
some of the ogs on the uh in the group
could speak to this but in a lot of like
perfume Industries you have some of
those um less odorous highly volatile
compounds in with your desirable odorous
volatile compound to help keep it in and
keep it from degrading and so the higher
volatility of it first of all kind of
like a nitrogen or an argon blank it
does it keeps the oxygen from getting in
um but it also because they repel water
it keeps water out um which reduces you
know additional reactions and um so a
lot of times you know like butane and
isobutane are preservatives sometimes in
aerosol products because they will just
keep everything from changing in there
it's it's a super effective system uh
that gets ignored by you know
regulations um you know because we just
start to get a little bit of tunnel
vision but I've absolutely seen that and
it's it's common in other Industries you
know that's why we know that butane was
food safe in the first place is because
it's put
into like dairy products and stuff as a
you know as a preservative and prop
also in the perfume industry they use uh
fixant like uh Amber griffs from
Wales yeah true uh Max you're you're
up cool so I want to go back to what we
were talking about just a moment ago
what um Murphy was talking about the
like quantitative versus qualitative
components and how there's not necessar
a direct correlation and uh what I've
got anecdotally to share with you is is
a little cannabis adjacent but it's a
new discovery that I thought was really
fascinating for me um we're working on
some R&amp;D at medically correct some stuff
I don't really want to talk about too
much yet but it's for an edible product
that's going to ultimately be a cinnamon
thing that's got capsacin in it so we're
playing around with capsacin and we've
got some pure capsacin isolate and uh
wow has really increased my respect for
what nature can produce and just
synthesize through a plant and um and
the reason I'm bringing it up is because
we were playing around with how much do
we put in here what is going to be like
uh palatable we want it to be fun not
too subtle but not too much and through
the R&amp;D where we landed at is the amount
of capsacin that is going into like a
single serving is 31 100,000 of a grand
and it's like really impressive how
spicy it is I like like spicy food and
wanted to push it a little bit more and
we did some internal R&amp;D within the
company and was just getting feedback
from people and I'm telling you at
three1 100,000s of a gram some people
were like this is maybe a little too
much and so you know just going back to
people who want to look at a potency
test and what do the numbers say and
what tpine is this and that and you know
the the difference between quantitative
and qualitative value is not a direct
correlation and so I just felt like that
was one where you just got immediate
feedback because the capsacin is so in
your face it's just such a Nots subtle
thing that that was uh just a recent
Revelation I had that's got for me
respecting peppers and just the Earth so
much more than I did before and uh so I
just wanted to throw that out there as
Food For Thought hey I think that's
really valid the Scoville uh you know
range was you know came up with for that
exact reason because you can't
communicate those tiny decimals the way
that pictures of a number of spicy
peppers
does right at my Factory in Kansas we
once extracted 2,000 pounds of fiery red
peppers and It produced about 25 gallons
of this incredibly red oil but when we
opened the Chamber up to have a look at
it all of a sudden we could not take a
breath in or out our our breath was
frozen we ran out the door opened the
door and ran out we're outside drooling
and spitting and while we were out there
two mice ran out of the building as fast
as we
did it turns out it was a great Mouse uh
remover but yeah that stuff is scary and
we had go through quite a process to get
it out of the chamber and pack it up and
send it off to the people who wanted it
but very very dangerous stuff uh and by
the way we only use uh analytical grade
ISO butane for all our
extractions just my prob good probably a
good idea thanks for sharing John also
too the vanilloid receptor and the
caspen receptor interplays with the CB1
and the
CB2 interesting just a little drop of
knowledge there very very interesting uh
I did want to welcome JM to the room and
etan etan obviously we heard from
already so it's always good to have him
he's a regular panelist in the room but
uh are you still around JM or did you
turn your phone off and oh there you are
just got to unmute yourself there you go
unmute yeah I'm still here what's up
guys I'm used to listening to has church
and uh not chiming in so I'm trying to
break the ice here thank you Marcus for
doing that for me um it's an interesting
conversation regarding you know the
total flavor we experience when we smoke
hash or you know dab hash St it and
Turpin how much is too much um and then
also
flavonoid and I've been of the mind that
the flavonoids as we ingest them in a
vapor are not really contributing to
flavor um I played around with you know
Wasing the media and trying to add that
back at minute amounts and it didn't
seem to help much it actually was
horrible but um I wonder if you look at
Citrus oils or just a lot of essential
oils that are you know refined for
flavoring is uh you know they will do
what they call folding you know you'll
see like a orange essential oil that'll
say fivefold or you know tfold and what
they're doing there is
actually um removing or reducing the
amount of actual tpes to increase the
ratio of
terpenoids um which I'm pretty sure are
generally a little more um volatile but
you know contain more of that
quintessential flavor of say a uh blood
orange versus a mandrian orange and I
wonder Murphy when you talk about
fractionating your HTE is are you
running that through a column um to kind
of split the different classes
or yeah I'm just copying uh you know
what any other analytical instrument
would be doing and so I'll just run
through um either a silica and T5 so
that I can get high pressure high
resistance or through alumina if I just
want um you know minimal separation and
I want it to go faster so the media is
doing a you know really inert job of
just being a stationary phase and then
just high pressure controlling the
temperature again just copying what you
know an hlc uh GC would do so that I can
then elute things based on you know and
what I do is again I I always call it
fractioning because I don't have to know
when it's going to come out I just have
to have a lot of jars you know a lot of
containers ready to go no big deal um
and I've got you know a falling film so
it's pretty continuous but then I'm just
collecting things as they come and if
they come overlapping I can do it again
make it longer make it slower but just
by controlling that pressure and feed
rate and so what I get is different jars
that sometimes need to be combined and
sometimes need to be
reprocessed right on yeah that's uh what
caught my eye and ear years ago when you
started doing that ban based
chromatography are you I'm sure you've
sent all your jws to the
lab yeah most of them can't be tested
though like I want to test for waxes
right so you brought up you know what's
the value in the flavonoids that's a
perfect point is can of Flavin
contributes a lot to a texture and a
viscosity and a color in your oil and
whether or not it has a a medical
benefit when you smoke it and at what
level it's got you know a
bioavailability when you eat it those
are a lot of you know very complicated
questions but if I want to communicate
to a consumer Why this color yellow is
okay and this
one isn't I want to have a thing to say
that counts and so in fractioning what I
have is a bunch of
jars and many of them I can't say what
they are lots of them smell horrible
some of them ferment rapidly I got jars
of weird [ __ ] it's not helpful you know
and and so what I do is I keep them and
so when I'm reformulating what I'm
actually doing is just removing
Things based on my own bias and the the
few things I can
quantify and those things are the safest
parts of the oil you know I can quantify
TC the only part that won't kill me heyn
what makes it difficult John can you can
you introduce yourself because the panel
hasn't met you yet and then we have some
we have some hands up um we have let me
just figure this out real quick yeah it
was Marshall again who would be first
after you introduce yourself and then uh
Yari uh has his hand up as well so go
ahead and introduce
yourself yeah long time listener first
time caller here um true story
for real I started sci-fi systems uh
gosh what 2016 or so I come out of the
broader natural product space um you
know working with isolating compounds
for the biomedical you know drug
Discovery Market but uh I've always
loved cannabis and I quickly found that
the Cannabis industry was a real chill
industry compared to dealing with uh you
know the more academic uh side of things
and you know that was uh really what
made me switch completely to start
sci-fi also at the time I had a lot of
business relationships with equipment
manufacturers you guys will remember
when uh some of these folks wouldn't
even you know associate with cannabis so
um it was a prime time back then to
bring those two worlds together and uh
since I'm just loving it it's a much
cooler more casual industry um and the
questions and unknowns are gosh this
plant is
so uh there's a lot to it we take for
granted that we just put utane in a tube
and get oil but there is a lot to it
especially as far as what we're talking
about here safety and all that so yeah
that's me awesome well welcome and we're
happy to have you here and Marshall
you're
up yeah just uh briefly on flavonoids
the T the ner the name comes from a
flavor from your tongue it's a bittering
component like the polyphenols so the
flavonoids are biochemically sort of the
is in between of the aromatic compounds
the tpes and the turpenoid formation and
the polyphenol formation so the
polyphenols are the water soluble bitter
components right and then the flavonoids
are kind of in this you know gray area
in between um when it comes to
analysis uh there's methods out there
it's a matter of having access to the
equipment if you guys want to start
doing analysis on flavonoids that's not
a problem we can make it happen um it's
just a matter of finding the equipment
uh I've also been picking up old
analytical equipment on auction sites so
hopefully one of these days I'll have
all these capabilities in my house it's
a matter again it costs a lot of money
even just to run them right it's like
$20,000 just to get the power hooked up
to my house to to uh to put one of these
instruments in even if it didn't cost me
half million dollars to buy outright so
anyway I'm working on those sorts of
things CU I'm a curious person that's
how I ended up here I love sensor I love
the effects and then I'm a reductionist
chemist in that way and so yeah we can
we can make that happen just a matter of
you know finding the equipment it is
expensive that's part of the problem
right is that it takes who cares about
it and then it takes the money to invest
in it um but there's equipment out there
I know you know I know a bunch of
professors at universities that less use
their their equipment if if it was a
good project well and and don't discount
the time a lot of analytical chemists
don't realize that everyone else doesn't
know that for you to turn it on and
calibrate it to get a baseline before
you can start testing a standard if you
already have a method and a standard
you're putting just days of effort you
know into some of this equipment and so
you know to give you one sample and say
tell me what's in it that could be three
months of work and calibration and
rerunning and development and Sample
prep and and then it doesn't always
translate directly over to that product
infused into something else it's a
tremendous amount of time that someone
has to investigate I started buying
analytical equipment and quickly learned
I don't have the patience to run a
GC right Yari you got your hand up yeah
Murphy I had a question for you how come
you run your HTE and fractionate it
through T5 which will muddle instead of
leaving it as it is when it comes off
the extract so I'll use T5 as um a
dehydrating process so if I'm just going
to fraction HTE if I have something
that's already liquid and I've got phca
out of the mix then that'll just go
through alumina um T5 just allows me to
go at much higher pressure because
otherwise I would have to go through a
super long
column which would just I don't want to
and so you know I get a ton of
resistance out of that T5 and it's just
blended with the silica and so it's just
there to slow everything down really is
T5 media it is it's a benite clay that's
um acidified
essentially um so that it's going to be
a little bit more similar to silica gel
in that pH and so it's um it can hold a
lot of water specifically and it's a
very fine powder um it's probably finer
particle size than the silica gel but
the silica gel is really doing the the
chromatography lifting and so with that
process what I'll be able to do is get
easy stuff out at high pressure and then
I have to heat it up and get the
everything else out and then that
everything else can get refiltered if we
want and if I skip that part then you
get a bunch of the water soluble water
missible water
adjacent stuff um and so you know T5
will help hold on to that and there will
be there'll be Turpin other things in
there that you can still fraction off
again it's just um sort of I always call
sorting my laundry just give me what's
easy and then I'll have you know an
accumulation of jars that are for later
that will come back to because I no
cannaboids left behind but um you know
but why do all that work to formulate
them back together again oh that work is
absolutely a function of getting shitty
weed and having to make the best product
you can from it if the weed is [ __ ]
old and gross see I'm sorry you can oh
your weed's all good the the living soil
guy the living soil guy is like what the
[ __ ] like what what could you
possibly no
man that's if that's why then okay L I
even loved your sound of
disappointment you get those degradation
components you know when you go from
like the wax that's the cuticle of the
turpine to like these degrad fatty acidy
oil things that are like I said
sometimes it's like truly for menting in
those final jars and so I'm going to get
I'm going to skim the
cream and then I'm going to go back in
for the the best of the rest later so so
I don't know a ton about the media I
really just kind of met the media Bros
recently and was talking to Adam about
them a little bit but is there a big
difference between these powdered and
granulated mediums like what this is
just for I guess it it quickens the
process or something or they all do a
different if you were to think of them
in the way that you think of your
different Bubble Bags can Target a
different triome size each media could
be designed to Target a different
chemical category particle
size um you know they could have a
different pH which is going to have a
different you know kind of reactivity
there's um they could each they're
individual Tools in a sense and
sometimes they're used together with
intention and sometimes not and
sometimes that intention is to you know
give a trash to gold and sometimes it's
to analyze or purify but they are you
know even when they are similar they're
extremely unique you know it's kind of
like uh someone brought up the W1
earlier which is not the same as you
know just an alumina or a clay that's
been ground to a specific size each of
them can be
really really uniquely applied okay
interesting or used frivolously you know
or used frivolously well that's what I
it was interesting to hear horge talking
about how it was like yeah when we
started using it we just used it like in
small amounts and he's like the kind of
problem was people came in and were like
you know just stripped everything out of
there kind of thing so like I said I
don't have a huge uh experience with
this it's definitely interesting to talk
about though Clays Clays are layered
silicates okay so unlike silica gel
which is just silica particles right
macroporous silica particles right which
are the same kinds of of things that are
in some hlc columns most hlc's are
running what's called reverse phase and
so they actually have a fat soluble Mo
that holds on to the compounds and
separates the compounds all based on
polarity but but silicates are just yeah
there's a variety of different kinds
there's actually Nano silicates called
halite but yeah banite Clays are just
they're layered silicates and so in
between the layers of silica you could
basically trap all kinds of compounds
it's typically based on the size of the
compound whether or not it could fit in
the interstitial space between the
layered silicates sometimes you'll hear
about exfoliated Clays what exfoliated
Clays are is when they peel away those
layers um to basically make you know
non-layered silicate but yeah so anyway
a little chemistry on silicates
appreciate it Mark I I ask a chemistry
question to a chemist you're gonna get a
chemistry answer right yeah I I played
the media Bros little video while you
were while you were doing it I'm like
getting all fancy over here with my uh
uh my hash church but no I appreciate
the conversation today you also have
your hand raised but I guess you've
already spoke so we'll go back to Jorge
who uh has his hand up again go ahead
hor okay yeah I just want to kind of
touch on the media too it's kind of like
I like to look at it like Photoshop so
you have all these tools on the left
side you know and each one of these
medias because they're different in PH
or structure like bentonites like a
guess like a generic word for claz there
like kalanit meti had a pull guide like
and all these are going to pull or have
like a stronger affinity for something
else than the other you know so once you
understand all these things and test
them and know how they work you can
basically have Like Your Arsenal of
tools like Murphy was saying and and
come in with a purpose so if you're
going to say crystallize the reason like
W1 would work is because it's acidic so
once you turn the solution acidic the
extract is going to crystallize a lot
better versus something that's say basic
or neutral and same thing so just
depends on your purpose if your purpose
is to bleach then and you have something
that's higher in in contamination then
you would go for something that's more
atic and vice versa you know what I mean
so the these are all just basically
tools and
we should get like more knowledgeable on
them to be able to uh basically perform
better like CRC extracts instead of just
coming in and stripping everything I
think there's a huge opportunity for
Education here because what I'm seeing
in the market is mostly people want like
the easy button and not a lot of
extractors want to learn or like really
have that much expertise in like what
are the use cases of each of these
different compounds and and how to kind
of use them with Precision so a lot of
the time it's just like the goal is just
to lighten the color or to have a
consistent marketable color for the
product and so they're just looking for
like Fast flow um so that it doesn't uh
slow down their extraction process and
they're just running everything through
CRC um as just kind of like the standard
operating procedure because a lot of
this is kind of like top down um you
know from management type of thing like
directives and not necessarily coming
from like where Murphy is coming from
with like precision like science yeah
absolutely I had to overly invest in
that too I think part of this comes from
if if I I might not see my potency
change at all only my yield going in and
out of a specific media and so if that's
the only number I can measure is potency
and turbines which we know aren't going
to be impacted by a specific Medias then
how do I measure that change in the
flavor positive or negative you know we
need a data point we all need to start
sending samples to Marshall I think
maybe you know something well well the
man with all the flavors has his hand up
so Yari what do you have to say about
that so um I just wanted to add and
point out a couple things so um like I
said before CRC is a good tool and you
really need to
know this this kind of goes back to the
grow things like if you know the strains
that you're growing incredibly well you
can adjust appropriately to what
individual powders that you're trying to
use to do like their individual job and
what I mean by that is like I've had
friends of mine that have come to me
where we've run their extract before and
it's it's strain specific but some of
them are so overwhelming with the tpin
and in their HT and everything that they
almost need a light CRC uh and finding
that right media which doesn't muddle
that the the big problem with the CRC
thing is that if like you guys were
saying if you strip it too much strip
everything away the taste is awful or
Bland or not there whatsoever so um
knowing the cultivar and knowing what
individual CRC powder does you can play
that to your advantage um I have gotten
to the point where I don't CRC anything
myself because I found the sweet spot on
where to take down the Plant where it
was at their their Peak within a couple
days um a friend of mine gave me a
little hint on that that you we did do
analytical testing to find when a
certain cambon oid dropped to a certain
percent was at the peak of the strain so
doing that and then like I said running
stuff for other people um when when the
the turps are overwhelming can still I
mean no one will know that it was CRC if
they've if they've done a good job and
used the appropriate amount of powders I
think they get misused and that's what
screwed everything up in the
industry just like everything right it's
just always the same thing you you know
you you start out in this sort of
ignorance and then you gain knowledge
and sometimes that can lead you into
bias and then as you gain your
experience you sort of realize oh maybe
staying more over in the center and
gaining information all around me is a
better idea than then uh well I mean I
was completely insane I was just like uh
I was convinced everyone just had to
have full Mount bubble I just was like
of course you have to have this this is
the best this is the best because that's
what I thought and then i' meet I'd meet
people and they were like no this is the
best and I'd be like how can you even
say that and you know you just get over
your own like narcissism dude like just
let people have what they want to have
and let people explore and and uh at
this point in time I so my Affinity for
cannabis and cannabis extractions I just
think it all has its place it's all a
journey it's all Pathways and the more
we explore and the more we uncover
because like Murphy said like we don't
really do new [ __ ] it takes a long time
we got to do it's kind of like fish when
they would say I think Paige was
interviewed and the lady was like why
would you jam for 42 M for 42 minutes
and he's like well because so I could
hear like the 43rd minute you can't get
to the 433d minute of jamming without
doing the other 42 minutes you don't get
to hop skip over the jam the jam is the
journey and so I guess that's true for
cannabis and it's interesting because I
see it with cannabis that she doesn't
necessarily want people to cut corners
and find tricks she's always just like
no it's going to be you just have to I
think the day we stop trying to get
cannabis to bend the knee to us will be
the day that we truly find success with
uh with our relationship with cannabis
because prohibition tried to uh get
cannabis to bend the knee and it did not
work out let me tell you money was spent
people were jailed lives were ruined uh
and here we are all these years later
thank God we have an industry room we
can talk about this go ahead Mark you
look like you're anxious to say
something on happy and purple I just
realized who JM is so is that John Mark
what up hey John how are you good to see
you so I don't know if our hash Church
audience will remember but when I went
to visit Indra in uh
2017 I think uh John got inspired and
came down to injures too so we actually
met I think uh through a hash Church
connection and you were the first PhD
that I had met that uh wakes up with a
bong
rip well that was fun and we have to
thank John for hosting us we we had a
nice session Danny uh Danny from corova
who I think has been on the show before
but I think Marcus didn't we do an
episode from John's Place there I think
maybe I think we did it's possible it's
all muddled in fuddled in my brain we've
got like hundreds of these episodes
under the belt at this point in time so
it's kind of hard to uh remember eight
years ago right yeah exactly Marcus yes
John I just want to mention one more
thing before I sign off because I'm
running out of gas here I was in the
hospital all day yesterday uh my blood
sugar spiked to 500 and it was a very
difficult time for me I only managed to
survive it by the hair of my chinny chin
chin but uh what I wanted to mention
that one of the ways
of choosing how your extraction happens
is I used to run a coil from the
isobutane and I would hover it in a
bucket so that I could get the overhead
of the liquid nitrogen to cool the gas
to various temperatures and by doing
thus I managed to extract the very
lightest things first and so anyway it's
just I don't know if anybody's going to
do it what what is the CRC the uh air
conditioning stuff the magic dirt it's
the magic dirt
chromatography oh okay yeah it's just
column chromatography that's all John
all right well anyway I just wanted to
mention that that was a method that I
had developed used hi Johnny and uh glad
you're
well yeah good
to say hi toan hello etan how are you my
brother long glad to see you Al live and
well I'm gonna visit your pot shop when
I come down to get my teeth fix by the
VA so I'll be there to wave at you in
person but anyway you guys I'm I'm worn
out so I'm going to sign off for the day
well thanks for being alive Indra and uh
sorry for telling people that you were
not alive and uh wow I didn't get to see
it but people were freaking out in the
chat when I said I'm gonna bring someone
back to life and you came
on well you got that rumor from my son
who's lost to Beth so well we we'll
we'll we'll we'll hope for the best for
Johnny star and and hopefully uh you
know what it's uh we say it the same as
with um oil and everything else in our
life [ __ ] sometimes we just got to make
big mistakes to learn to learn big
things and we'll we'll we'll pray that
Johnny star is going to learn from this
experience and come out of it but uh
we're really glad to see you dude and
we're glad that you're alive and uh
we'll be seeing you again sooner than
later thanks for coming on Indra it was
my pleasure and hello to everybody who I
didn't see say hello to and uh I love
you
allra this this is Sam
speaking hey car old friend this is Dr
Mark I'm doing my best I'm trying to
stay
alive aren't we all keep doing it
brother keep doing it awesome all right
well I feel like goodbye brother I F oh
Yari Yari had his hand up sorry Yari I'm
I'm trying to keep it all together here
hey JM uh does your company build those
membrane filtration
systems
yep you guys are in
Washington uh Oregon Oregon up here near
Portland have you guys uh have you guys
used those with still cyon
extract uh
unofficially I know someone who
has I was at [ __ ] Creek about that
because like that's the one bottle that
people are starting to see is the
solvent recovery oh well solvent
recovery yeah I mean that's like the one
thing that you know Nano filtration does
very easily across the board that you
can you know be fully confident plug-and
play no issues or challenges because you
know we're working with natural products
here so the composition can vary quite a
bit totally and the other interesting
thing with um the mushrooms you know
it's the the sugars right yeah and
getting a more
concentrated extract you know away from
those sugars and there's tricks that can
be done uh that the membranes also come
in handy with to remove those to a great
degree but you know that's nothing that
we've worked
on okay to say but well I might like to
talk to you uh outside of the the the
chat about that because I'm pretty
interested yeah
yeah I'll make sure that you guys all
have access to one another uh
particularly just you know if there's
one particular or two particular or
every whatever you need just email me
and I'll make sure that you have the
right uh email for the right person yeah
I will say yard there's um there's quite
a few membranes uh that are used even in
like Preparatory uh chemistry for like
analysis that are for like removing um
sugars and fat specifically and I've
used quite a few of those with mushroom
extract
in an effort to test them because it's
not great you know um like I just won't
even put a a chocolate bar in my hplc
column anymore like you can just [ __ ]
ask somebody else to do it because I'm
not gonna you know be the one um and so
there's quite a few membranes that you
can get for that what I like about that
is you can get those in like you know
almost shring size um or like little cup
size you know um so you can do little
samples
before you go and get the big system so
you can figure out where you really do
have to scale cuz some of the good ones
for solvent want you to have a pretty
clean product and there's a lot of oily
fats in some of these mushrooms too
which is and that's why I asked because
it's such a more difficult oil to work
with because like I've heard of people
doing falling films with them and them
CL it completely clogging their line
I've made a lot of cement you know
liquid cement and I don't know what you
know do you guys know Coleman Shapiro
yep yeah he seems to be having having a
lot of fun doing that all these days
Corps extracts but yeah a lot of people
are out there clogging the bottom of
their fil reactor you know just we're
you know trying our best and uh one
thing I'd love to know um and maybe you
know J could work on this is um maybe we
could make those membranes out of a
mushroom derived products so they could
be more affordable to [ __ ]
with help us out man it just grows like
the mushroom just grows on the the
permeate tube and uh I mean Harvest
that's how we got it we stripped it from
a membrane you could grow a more
intentional one that'd be that'd be
dope yeah probably grow it right in the
housing yeah that's what I'm saying
that'd be
sick well I think it's time for a dab
what's everyone puffing on I just
smashed some Event Horizon from my last
dab I think I'm going to hit a
masterpiece 90 Micron first wash melt
sounds decent I'm not I'm not even
trying to plug this but I don't know if
you guys have ever smoked out of an
indux it's probably oh yeah I have an
indux the big table one yeah you have
the Murphy do you have the bird the new
one I don't have a new I have like a
maybe one of the first like commcial
verions it's like a record player I have
like I went on Amazon and bought like a
whole roll of tubing so I could just
like throw them away
carelessly um because in science you
just you know disposable plastic is part
of the job somehow um but it's a killer
unit it really it's too much work you
know like I need it built into a whole
table for it's for sensory science
that's for having friends over to do
sensory science like that is exactly
what that is for I will say and nice to
see Sam lighting up the Carta and I'll
let everyone tell what they're going to
pop on but I got I got this Dr Dabber
switch to recently and I didn't realize
it's an induction unit this thing is
actually pretty ridiculous I was
surprised I mean it's heavy duty it's
not like a little small portable unit
even though I've literally carried like
Elite motherships around in pelican
cases onto the black ho home Mountain to
rip dabs while I'm snowboarding in the
middle of the day or take out on my sled
sled to the pton ice caps and do rips in
an ice cave that's like a you know
40,000 years old or whatever but I will
say that this thing is pretty [ __ ]
cool uh if you get a chance to rip one
and you're a big anyone that's into
flavor um
obviously uh induction heat is kind of
as long as it's delicate induction heat
I will say I don't know a ton about it
but I do know that I have probably nine
different units including uh Riley's um
indux Labs unit as well as I spire uh
the one Luna gave me in Berlin and and
and a variety of other units there are
some that are just too much they just
they their lowest tap when they start is
just way too high but like the indux
labs and as well as this unit I can turn
it down so low that I can take rips of
my dabs and have them taste different
like really different uh with the low to
the medium to the high I feel like
Marshall's like ready to say something
he's like turned his camera on he's like
what are we talking about s science here
I got some [ __ ] to say I got a PhD go
ahead
Marshall oh yeah just in general I mean
it's so all almost all the work I did in
the Hop industry was connecting the
sensory to the analytical work for beers
uh and hops and hop extracts and things
and so it's fun to be able to work in
the canos world as well I'm working with
mostly him so I can't even imagine you
know what we could do getting hands on
on good real uh material like you guys
have so
it's just a Messier output you know like
I thought I thought having a gcms would
be cool and it turns out it's just work
like you feel no progress ever you just
start you know you you stop running it
longer you're like if because it'll keep
[ __ ] will keep showing up you're never
done so you know it's um it's really
cool science but it is it is really hard
work to break those compounds all the
way down in a way to analyze them and
what's tough is that our ability to
perceive it you know is a lot more
sensitive so it's like these really
complex analytical instruments still
can't tell apart the like you know that
black pepper versus the white pepper in
a way that we can and I'm like damn you
know we really are still pretty far from
automating that oh yeah
and and to know with certainty too I
mean I would have an existential crisis
if I was an analytical chemist that's
what I've said for years because yeah
when you get into the weights with that
it's like wow how do we know anything is
anything you know and you could be wrong
for so long you could you could trick
yourself and make a peak out of anything
oh yeah you know and you're right about
you know the sensory aspect and that is
the most important actually I got what I
call
the
gustometer so when we're dabbing I call
that gustometer you know Gusto flavor
like the food stuff you know the
olda you know ometry so yeah everybody
there you've got a gustometer in your
house already the most sensitive
analytical instrument um and yeah you
got to test stuff for Quality it's
important because there's all flavors I
mean we all know the issue with like
possible contaminants that even Rec Labs
aren't able to test for or don't know to
test for but you might to taste it
before you know anything so important to
try your dabs I'm interested about this
indu though because
I've it it's not a cheap instrument you
know that's probably the most fancy guts
of tacometer out there um do you find
that the Dr Dabber that is Marcus uh is
it similar in giving you that lower temp
range if you want it this this the it's
not as broad but there's at least a nice
enough sliver that makes it so nice to
have at your TBL toop the indux is like
a invite PE that's like in high school
when you set up the dungeon and Dragons
table invited your buddies over this is
not a thing you just do on the random
this is some [ __ ] you prepare for this
is like Hey we're going to do sensory
science with my buddies uh we'll be able
to test it at such low temperatures that
you're you know you're kind of ripping
monos more so so than anything and then
you can go through into the
sesquiterpenoids and get into these
completely different flavor profiles and
they [ __ ] hide each other from one
another you know like there's a reason
why we cure the monos out in flour
because you get this kind of like oh it
doesn't smell that good sometimes and
then you cure that out and now this this
new bouquet has arisen underneath you
know the one that is volatized off so
that in itself is going to be an
absolute art form in
how people you know cure or preserve
their material listen fresh frozen that
was uh at least in the Cannabis world
and you guys could speak to the butane
world and tell's got his hand up so
he'll be next but in the Cannabis world
it was you know flavor rule uh sorry the
bubble has world it was just all about
that flavor profile and what you how how
well you could get the flavor from the
plant profile to be like the same but
just completely concentrated to a point
where it's uh you know mind-numbing tell
uh why don't you go ahead youe your hand
up yeah um so this is something I think
a lot of BHO people can notice just from
leaving um leaving products in a vacuum
and doing doing some tests with the
vacuum and just smoking it it's
something that you notice like every
once you know you've got some things
that are just really blowout you know
really top end sort of on on the
Spectrum and if you vacuum longer you do
you you lose some of that perceptual
masking and you open up some of some of
the heavier turpins that just get blown
out by these things that like kind of
blow out your senses but don't don't
translate one to one to like the tongue
and olfactory experience and I that's
something I've definitely noticed from
the vacuum and that sometimes like
especially if I'm entering something for
a contest you know I'm going to hit it
and maybe V it try vacing some it a
little bit longer to see what happens to
it and see you know like okay if we take
some of the top end off will it will it
open up and and can we get some more out
of this or is this just sort of a very
topend you know um high pitch kind of
spectrum hey Marshall I I wonder if you
had any insights on maybe some things
like the way you know Murphy M said like
we're all going to be doing the same
things well have PE like maybe we should
be following a little closer behind the
Hops industry because you got the the
amount of millions of dollars like we we
talk about how expensive this work is
and how cannabis has really only done a
fraction of the work that needs to be
done because we're still fighting
margins and racing to the bottom to to
create our industry but beer has a foot
in the door it has money to invest the
Hops industry is [ __ ] big and so do
you see any advantages to you know some
of that stuff that was done to Hops with
hops in the anal analytical labs being
able to translate over to cannabis and
help our industry yeah absolutely in
fact that's kind of how I ended up here
was we had all that analytical equipment
right I learned a lot about these
compounds there's a huge overlap between
Hops and cannabis I mean obviously when
you go and ferment beer there's another
gigantic range of things that come into
play uh for changing the flavor and the
aroma but uh yeah I mean it's it's it's
not that difficult but analytically our
noses are better for very specific
components right because uh sulfur
compounds THS are tens of thousands of
times more potent per molecule than
almost all of the monot Turpin or zesco
Turpin right and that's where you get
these really crazy Aromas like burnt
rubber or armpit right there those are
the THS over concentrated and the other
class compounds in here are the alahh
and these are ones unfortunately that
are a lot of the bad Aromas you don't
want that you want to remediate in fact
bentonite clay specifically binds
selectively binds alahh and that's part
of why it does some remediation on older
material um but analytically they're
difficult and that's where I've loved to
see what I you know what I've learned is
that you've got to trust your nose and
your equipment if you know how to do it
and you got to know the limitations of
your equipment and your nose right the
sulfur compounds will blow out your
ability to smell the rest of the stuff
that's there and this is where the aging
and all the curing really comes into and
how you're doing that CU they have
different oxidation time frames so they
break down or volatilization so pulling
vacuum or heating it again doing all
these things are going to adjust the
relative concentrations and then give
you that Aroma you know that that Aroma
profile that you want from it and that's
where honestly the making concentrates
and extracts and things can be tricky
you can actually take something that's
beautiful and turn it into burnt rubber
right because you've now overc
concentrated a bunch of stuff in there
that's great and now youve got a burn it
off a little bit to get it back to where
you want it so that's if nothing else
I've learned a ton from the work that I
did there because we had the equipment
and we had the uh you know the money and
the time to spend doing this and we had
25 25 person trained sensory panel to
compare the sensory with work with the
analytical results that we were getting
from the lab and then we had the lab
equipment where we could analyze all
these things so um I would love to be
able to do that same work uh in this
industry again it's about finding the
equipment finding uh the places where we
can do this stuff because it's been not
allowed for so long I think that's a
part of it for sure and I think we're
going to be able to help you with that
by having you back on the show and maybe
doing a specific show on and you know I
was thinking this would be part of the
aromatic volatile compound show but
perhaps it's focused more on what we the
Cannabis industry can learn from the
Hops industry that had a 25 team sensory
group to learn about those Sops on how
to run a proper sensory team on how to
first of all I mean Nix told me this
from day one look step one is you have
to find out what your blind spots are
you need to identify what your blind
spots are what can't you perceive right
it's not that easy to figure out but you
need to figure it out and then the other
one was sort of like what are you
perceiving in more of a hyper manner
than what the rest of the group is it's
a little above you know that middle bar
you're you're you're hyper perceiving
certain things where you're like oh my
God can you guys smell that and everyone
else is like no I don't smell it the way
you do so we kind of got into those two
things and I thought man this is a
really interesting conversation that I
think I haven't really heard a lot in
the Cannabis industry that seems ripe
for hash church so you know maybe if
you're down for that we can get some of
the people that are on the panel today
and some other new people and we can we
can do a sensory
you know discussion of in regards to I'd
love to get some people from other
Industries as well although hops just
does translate so well because really
it's another aromatic inebriant that
people love worldwide and it has these
different shared I mean God it's a
there's relations for goodness sake so
did should bring in Rob and Mojave
they've been writing articles on of
course on hops um which is been
absolutely fascinating because of course
we've seen you know diseases cross right
hop and vroid right comes from hops
which is fascinating because when I was
at the Cannabis germ plasm Institute
from the USDA in Geneva New York uh last
year they were there's a section in
between when there was the the huge
homogeneous um field that was growing
517 different ascensions plus female
plus their the males with it but there
was a row that we went through and they
were growing hops on purpose so that I
thought was rather fascinating so uh I I
plan to talk to Larry smart and them and
ask them more about that
crossover because uh they're already
looking at at the USDA
level John has his hand up you want to
go ahead John yeah I just wanted to say
one I envy the beer industry for you
know how how much further ahead they are
than our industry in terms of what we're
talking about here we've got a long way
ways to go and you know one critical
difference and this ties back into
discussions that were happening earlier
uh between the two industries right now
is there is a huge lack of public
consumption you know what I'm saying
like legal public consumption with beer
you can go to a bar and get served up
and try all sorts of beers that you
would never go buy just a sixpack of to
try right you can try singles nothing
like that really exists at least here in
Oregon and most the US for hash and
that's going to affect too you know what
the consumer the retail side is um you
know demanding and I find that there's a
lot of people that just have not
experienced a proper dab and aren't
going to go and throw a bunch of money
out of gram that they've never tried
before God forbid they can't even smell
it before they buy it and um I think
that's a going to be a critical piece
tooo to lifting all this
forward that's why we keep repeating the
cycle you know because no one in a new
state can do anything other than see it
on Instagram they don't know what
they're looking for they're using all
the data they have basically
none exactly well in California they've
just allowed food um in dispensaries
besides you know uh for the first time
ever so I would expect to see some
pairings starting to happen you know
some chefs and more of that starting to
happen because you know uh more
legitimacy to to take place as well as I
would anticipate a a rise in dad bars
but the problem with Dad bars is is the
um the individual who thinks they have
the tolerance to handle it and those are
the people who we have to call the
ambulance for because they literally
pass out from being too high this is
where that proper sop comes in for
sensory experience of of extracts this
is the importance of like creating this
voice of authority and it's you know
it's it's so important and it's kind of
uh yeah I just uh I I hate to hear
people having bad experiences please go
ahead with that indu are you able to you
know at the lower end of the heat range
are you able to generate a vapor that is
mostly flavor and less 100% 100% that's
the thing like that you know I Envision
you know the wine and a wine and cheese
level of Hashi someday where people who
aren't really you know cannabis users
are able to
appreciate the wide wide range of
flavors this plant can produce and if
you're not a Dabber and you take even a
small dab you're gonna you're not going
to be able to enjoy the second one so
you know wondering how do we you know
someday be able to allow people to enjoy
the pallet that have no tolerance um and
even myself shoot this is this is the
work that Doctor Mark Lewis and Chimera
did at Neo which was to go through and
produce type two plants that are not
high in
thca and to create all the flavor
profiles that are available in type 1
plants and make them available in CBD
Shanti Baba's been selling CBD like
cigarettes in like the grocery stores in
Switzerland for like I want to say 20
years but maybe it's been longer now um
so there there is a whole world out
there that just wants to enjoy this the
flavors of cannabis and I think Neo is
probably ahead of the game in regards to
producing you know cultivars that it it
goes to kind of speaking like you know
it's the same with Edibles right like if
you're going to have or or these dinner
pairings that etan just mentioned if
you're going to have these types of
dinner pairings you better be down in
the 1 mgram range of of dosing ability
and honestly like my wife at at 1
milligram she's like going to be
uncomfortable soon so this is the
delicate nature of people's different
endoc canabo systems and how the
signaling system and how it interacts
it's just it's a delicate game that
we're GNA have to figure out over time
Murphy had her hand up so I want to go
go to her yeah I just didn't want to
lose the the train of thought there on
like I always tell people I'm not a
grower right like I'm I'm an extractor
and it's not because I don't know how to
grow I grow a lot of stuff actually you
know well known for my aloe uh as you
guys have heard but um you know I uh I
always say I'm not a grower because the
the way that you know Growers have to
approach problems is longterm you know
I'm complaining about the time it takes
to run a GC it takes way longer to grow
a new strain to feno hunt something you
know worth having and so it's really
cool that people are trying to cultivate
the lower potency and deliver that
flavor profile but it's also exactly the
job that everyone on this call is
supposed to be capable of like every
single one of us could
just get the flavor out you know and so
you know it's easy to blame the consumer
for focusing too much on THC but none of
us sell our
byproducts how many people are out there
buying cocoa butter and winterizing
under the same roof throwing away waxes
and buying waxes and shipping it like
we're crazy we have so much byproduct
that we used to promote cannabis and
hemp for legalization and then forgot
about when we started
manufacturing every single one of us
could be producing those byproduct
flavors from our you know current Supply
and if we worked with hemp instead of
against it you know we could we could
deliver those you know breeding
experiences but we could also
manufacture that and I think that's
where you know if the market that
doesn't want to get too high could
dab they'd be on our team that's our
fault we gave
everyone too high a potency in order to
get that flavor that's oh no we did we
did exactly what I did with the bubble
and teaching everyone to roll it all up
wet and cause years of hot dabs and
night nightmares and also whatever the
male Macho bravado whatever that was was
like yeah let's destroy them with a 900
degree half gr dab it was just like oh
my God what were we doing just putting
ourselves back like 10 15 20 years it'll
be fine I agree I think the ability to
create a proper you know so like for me
I've created it for myself I give people
dabs all the time I give elderly people
dabs that have never dabbed like in
their 80s and 90s and what I do and the
only way I've been able to do it because
and I'm pretty articulate but even if
the Dabber is is even just like a
titanium Dabber Dabber like this it's
too big you need a PIN to pull a pin
head out and then you really at first
that little pin drop is really about
getting them over the fear of and also
you got to get rid of the blowtorch that
blowtorch is it's freaking people out
nobody wants to see it it it scares
people it's not cool so you know shout
out to companies like like puffco and
Carta and and Dr Dabber and indu for
creating products that allow us to try
these products to to try these extracts
in the first place cuz you know to make
an extract like that and then just be
like what how you smoking it I'm just
going to roll it up in a joint man it's
like oh my God like just stab me through
the heart how I always burn it in a
cartridge that's really my heart yeah
that's that's that's a hder one too so
it is what it is but yeah it's uh kind
of lost my train of thought there but um
Sam's got his hand waving please I
wanted to mention that uh when we did
the analysis in
200 uh with a a team of subjects we used
a organoleptic uh survey with about a
100 questions and that might be
interesting
the other thing is that uh I do have one
of those uh induction pipes and I'll
tell you that absolutely gives me the
best Taste of any hits I've ever had but
that's only the first half of the hits
the last half of the hits just taste
like any other
pipe yeah it's definitely for extracting
the flavor profile it's like a like to
me it's an incredible tool for breeders
if you want to get to know your flavors
and you want to get to know your
bouquets and how they sit on top of one
another it's a it's a rabbit hole that
is well worth going down and it's a tool
that I'm personally surprised hasn't
been more more tuned because you know
there there's amazing machines proton
NMR and gas chromatograph but there's
also this thing called the old factory
and uh it's quite an amazing uh piece of
equipment that really puts those other
pieces of equipment borderline to shame
uh so use yours bioassay it's important
it's valuable there's definite value in
bioassay and sharing your experiences
with people so uh I love the science
aspect of it I I don't necessarily treat
it as much like the word of God because
I also like the uh the personal
experience of what the person has gone
through and uh and whatnot so so what
you touched on is something that is a
problem that we deal with every single
day in dispensaries is they come across
this concentrates and they're like well
how do I use it right that is still a
huge learning curve for somebody because
I originally came to concentrates back
in
200 uh you know 10 or so I already using
water hash but I was seeing people
buying BHO and other things and using it
and I was asking well why are you using
this and Murphy it is medically you know
it still is medically useful and people
do use it as medicine so I was watching
older patients buying these expensive
little jars and those that knew how to
because originally people were just
dropping the hash butane oil onto a coal
right once the coal had a burn off right
and then the titanium swings came in and
then titanium you know you had the the
the female and male you know
basically uh steps in the direction of
easier usage but it hasn't been until
recently that there have been electronic
entry points but even then for somebody
who's new to concentrates oh now I have
to buy something to use this because yes
my my torch scares the living [ __ ] out
of everybody every time I use it and
they're terrify but now you've got
things I'm I'm using the denail heater
right which is just a strictly
convection heater that heats my you know
my my uh my tool exactly to how I want
it but that's not an easy or cheap
expense so as you your professionals
here how do you teach people the most an
easiest entry point as opposed to you
know telling them to roll it into a
snake is its own Challenge and then
putting it into a joint good luck with
that and crumbling it in they put too
much in and then they're overdosing so
how do you help
people dip their toe into the water puff
Co is usually the best way in my opinion
uh justess because like like like you
guys were saying before the torch scares
the [ __ ] out of a lot of people but you
can hand you know a puffco with the
right amount of of concentrate in it to
you know a your girlfriend's dad and he
can rip that and it's opens like a whole
new experience for him so that's what
I've seen personally at least yeah and
the fancy lights you know that people
are like o what's that you got there old
boy go ahead Murphy um I just think uh
it it's definitely an education thing
but we we need to follow suit with other
Industries and so you know when I think
about the type of glass you're supposed
to drink wine out of and the shape of it
and the length of it and the type of
glass you're supposed to drink Scotch
out of you know and so you can drink it
out of literally whatever cup you want
sure you don't have to buy a puff coat
you don't have to buy an induction
heater you don't have to stay plugged
into the wall um I have like a little
laser one I finally got one that I can
dab with a laser I'm delighted by it but
like all of this requires an investment
and so it is a barrier to entry um
however for a medical product I think
there's a good justification for that
which is that if you want accurate
dosing you need accurate temperature
control and you know there's a lot to it
when when we're dabbing we're distilling
and if the condensing arm on my
distillation unit is a different size a
different angle a different temperature
if the vacuum is operating at a
different depth or CFM you know I'm
going to get a different separation and
experience and the same would be true
for the way that you're dabbing and we
could talk about it in that
really burdensome complicated way that's
kind of like when I have a chemistry
question I take it to Mark the first
version is going to be too complicated
and then right after that gets out we
get into the one that I can jump on
board with we can find a way to
communicate that to Consumers which
might be as simple as naming a couple of
profiles in where they hit your nose
versus your eyes versus the back of your
tongue um or you know we we approach
them with the you know the consumption
perspective because we could come up
with more innovative
delivery methods um the cart really took
us by storm because you know we let the
the tobacco industry sort of infiltrate
you know it and it it didn't work
out either it was it was easy it wasn't
even affordable at first that's the
thing the original vape pens were
expensive I really didn't believe it was
going to work and I've never been more
wrong about anything in cannabis so I've
been working personally really hard on
infusing joints in a way that works
because pre-rolls are
gross um they don't have a shelf life
and the best way to improve them is to
fill them up with concentrate and so you
know if I can use the right type of
concentrate to insulate the flour and
preserve the flavor there's a chance and
that gives me the portability and the
potency that a cart could but I think
back to this conversation we've been
having all along about po potency if we
get away from trying to deliver the most
THC at a time we could make it more
affordable I don't know if you guys
remember the little ceramic things that
you could inject distillate into yeah
that wasn't the right solution but it
was a direction that like like why
didn't we deliver shatter in dab sizes
why did we make it in irregular sticky
shapes wded up in paper we're doing
ridiculous things sometimes for slab
dabs you couldn't have had slab dabs if
you did that even I was impressed with
slab dabs we we've uh so you know to
that end we we don't make it easy for us
to handle in the lab or for the consumer
it does require some investment but
technology has never been cheaper people
who are approaching dabs today it has
never been more accessible because the
cost for me to buy a titanium nail and
the blowtorch attachment for the big old
map gas can at Home Depot is the same as
what it cost me for a $200 little laser
device like I spent way I don't want to
know the amount of money I invested in
metal dabbing things that I dabbed out
of a lot of times in my life so you know
I think people are willing to make the
investment have to make the
ARG this is um so I forget the name of
the overall company but if you see like
it's got a laser
and um so you put a dab in it like you
would with a puff Co and it will create
the vapor I don't know if I can get it
really close but you can see who makes
that in the vapor laser
dabs but laser dabs I've got one of
those for herb and hash yeah see some
type of device like that is sort of key
I mean obviously I think the oil
Community is definitely grown like the
customer base from the cart like people
making carts has really like made oil
spread and become very oil spread pun
intended uh it's made it uh more more
mainstream like a lot of people have
tried the carts now the question was
from ET you know what are you guys doing
to sort of educate or to create your
customer base and if you're not liking
the carts I get it um it's kind of it it
is what it is it's definitely a way to
fund your company if you want to do R&amp;D
and find other Pathways if you can
Cs and make them available people are
always going to love them um what I was
going to say is though so what I did
though aten from from my brand in
regards to education I do product
knowledge sessions constantly with
stores and Bud tenders and people but
really before that because I'm in the
same boat I'm making like full melt
bubble six-star dry sift live hash rosin
these products are too strong for the
majority of the users and so I want to
really kind of know differently than how
I helped build this crew of water
extractors out in the world by just
selling bags to everyone before that
there was no water hash and so there was
no water hash industry uh and so it's
slowly built with great Growers become
you know finding the bags and building
this industry so what I did with my
brand bubbleman brand is I knew that you
know the majority of the industry in in
both the US and Canada are pre-rolled
joints that is like that's like like a
massive if you can pull from The
pre-roll Joint Group market that is like
the one of the biggest market shares in
cannabis and so I was like I want those
people to uh experience a dab however
they're not going to it's not like for
many reasons that have already been
mentioned on this panel it's just not
going to happen oh yeah just go buy a
$500 puffco and then uh yeah make sure
you buy the right rosin or bubble hash
and oh you better get like a proper
Dabber oh you don't have a Dabber well
you're going to need one you won't be
you won't be able to get it out of the
jar and suddenly they're just like
$118,000 in they've got a JP Toro Banger
and a banger bucket and all basket and
all of this stuff and it it's a lot of
stuff to have um I wanted to build a
bridge with a product that I could turn
people on who were smoking joints and
there was now infused joints were just
coming when I created this product but I
I created this little product called
hash hits and it's really like a simple
little little box I you know little box
with these little paper tubes and we use
ceramic bowls now but we originally had
stainless steel bowls and we would just
put like0 two of a gram of hash in there
and you'd get like 10 rips out of it and
when I was when I was first creating
this product like I was creating it for
a customer base I hadn't burned anything
in like over 20 years I had only
vaporized hash melty six-star hash for
like 20 years so imagine where my
palette is when I'm like okay I'm going
to try and smoke some hash so I the
first bit I smoked it was very I was
just like oh my God that was a little
bit much and as I got to know the
product I'd take it out on the mountain
and I'd give them away to people and I'd
go electric skateboarding around the
seaw wall and it was this it was the
first time in decades that I had been
stoned I had just been high for 20
[ __ ] years and I totally had turned
my back on the beauty of being stoned
and I think for me I discovered that
that's what I want to share with people
I want to show them a nice Stone
that doesn't come from Cannabis but is
from the hash and build a little bridge
for them to kind of come on over and see
well what else is over here oh you got
these pure hash joints and you got oh
you have some traditional hash and
what's this stuff bubble has well that's
the strong stuff maybe just take a
little bit and eventually you know just
like for me I didn't start with live
hash rosin like I started with like
shitty moldy weed you know from a
sketchy dude that I probably should
shouldn't have been communicating with
when I was in uh in uh junior high or
whatever so that's what I did with my
brand build the bridge create some
products that they can kind of come over
and visit and so I would say to anyone
that's on the panel with with oil it and
Yari before anyone answers my question
you can chime in because you've had your
hand up for a while but I I
wonder yeah yeah I'll get to you for
sure um I just wonder what uh what you
guys are doing in a similar way to
educate you're the the the people out
there to what a great product you know a
BHO or a a live resin or a whatever it
is that your SKS are from this solvent
based
Community what's the best way to get
into it what's the best way to lead
those you know are you doing similar
things creating products that are easier
to
access go ahead Yari everyone can answer
that question when you're done okay cool
um I was just gonna chime in on the on
the heart situation because we talked
about uh you know what an easy
transition it is for someone who's not
used to concentrates or Oils and um so
I'm not the hugest card fan but they're
a big necessity in everyday life going
to the airport going on trips vacations
where you can't get weed uh in in
between zones they're just it they're
they're a good thing to have now they've
been dog [ __ ] for years uh and I think
in the last like three four some
companies have really stepped it up and
like done the research on our type of
oils burning in the carts because
for I don't even know how many years it
was just China sending us EIG carts and
that we were just testing to see what
was best so um the fact that they have
no burn technology where the heat ramps
up on and off when you're pulling a draw
makes that really easy for people to not
be holding buttons and overb burning the
oil so the tech has gotten better so I
think that transition to people that
don't have dab rigs yet or you know
they're running around town and they
can't have like a whole thing with them
that that is like the good transition
for a lot of these people getting
into yeah absolutely you're not wrong
they're popular I definitely like I
people ask me what's your favorite
what's your favorite dude like if sure
there's your favorite but how about like
what are you willing not to smoke out of
if you need to get high and you don't
have any device at that point in time
like listen like I probably won't hit
the Coke can but I'm definitely making
an apple pipe like 100% that's no
problem I'll make a pipe out of out of a
piece of fruit all day long so there's
something to be said for
that one thing we used to do at
Incredibles um we um we had done um like
distillations like call it you know we
tpen distillations but um just sort of
like a a distillation of the volatiles
until um we we decided it was a good cut
off just sort of a single pass cut and
uh coming up with some pretty like
really pretty good oils and we would do
essentially like essential oil events
paired with like industry events where
we would have a room and we'd put it in
some Bowl we we would um spread out a
little little bit of our distilled tur
into a bowl and then you know pass that
around the room and give like a whole
education class on it and I know it's
not something that you can do all the
time but it's like a non-smoked entry
into it too where you don't even have to
like they don't even have to necessarily
ingest it but they can still get an
experience and everything and start
learning about it yeah it gets them
sometimes over a little fear that's what
the micro daab always did even if they
didn't get high they tasted it a little
bit and it got them over the fear of
like okay okay like I did it because
they right to be fearful it's like dude
I could give you a dab that would be an
absolutely nightmares terrible
experience you would not want to be here
or in your body for that matter and so
it's just best to avoid that at sort of
all costs so um yeah if anyone has any
uh answer to that question in regards to
you know things you're doing not just to
educate you know your customer base and
to feed your customer base but to also
educate new people who are enjoying like
pre-rolled joints right now and maybe
you know maybe they might have a better
experience if they knew about about
extracts go ahead Murphy yeah so one
thing I think that um the solvent less
Community has done you know really well
in comparison to the solvent-based
community and there's you know a lot of
reasons for it um you know and probably
just the uh you know the age of the
processes how new some of the things we
do in the solvent world are um is that
you know there is a big Detachment we've
talked about it a few times between what
happens in the lab and what happens you
know for the consumer and the consumer
doesn't really need to understand the
entirety of the process but I do think
there's a ton of value in showing your
lab showing the process and giving that
visual representation you know for
someone to understand the temperature of
decarbox or what decarbox silation is or
why it happens at a specific temperature
is unnecessary for them to still see Ros
and drip out of a press and look at the
color and smell it in the room and say
this is correct you know and so we can
give consumers that kind of level of
understanding if we show our facilities
and show our process a lot more and
rather than trying to describe why it's
better literally show up for it I come
to this a little more naturally because
I've worked so much on the equipment end
so I've been training people to operate
equipment for a long time so it's very
normal for me to have other people in
the lab with me and to be showing
pictures and videos of the lab but the
the secrecy and the intellectual
property of it
all and and the nature of operating with
butane and propane you know there's
there's a lot of business reasons why
people don't want a camera in the lab
but the marketing team could show real
stuff happening you know like a lot of
my job is lifting a jar and looking at
it I I do that a lot but there there's
better
content that we could have you know
consumers exposed to like I would love
for consumers to see the freezer storage
nicely packed and organized um and you
know start promoting some trends like
that where people show their facility
because you know a grow gets to show the
healthy plants you know someone who's
washing is showing this ice water is
showing the hash you know they get to
flex the visual images of it and get
people closer to it and I think if
people could feel a little bit more
connected to the process with that
information they don't even have to
understand it they just would have some
concept of why CO2 isn't butane even if
all they know is that it's looks
different when it comes out of the
machine because they've seen what it
looks like like when it comes out of the
machine you know there's a lot of these
visual cues that we all talk about and
know naturally that the consumer just
hasn't been able to see from us in the
same way and I think you know I do a lot
of that in just showing the lab which
goes a long way to build trust it's kind
of like having an open Kitchen in a
restaurant you know we can see what's
and it builds trust I love an open to no
Source you know open kitchen and I also
am terrified of an open kitchen it's a
good it's a good confidence to have when
you go to an open kitchen oh I've one
time in my life I was at a place that
had a beautiful open kitchen that I'd
eaten there many times and just right
before my food came out I saw one of the
people working back there do something
that was just not something I wanted to
see and it completely robbed me of my
appetite I couldn't eat the food and I
didn't really want to tell everyone else
at the table like oh don't eat that food
man like don't eat that food that guy
that just touched it like I'm telling
you don't eat that so I do love the
transparency it's why personally for
live hash Rosen when I'm buying it I
would love to see a small sample I'd
love to see a picture something I think
it would be great you buy a gram of live
hash rosin and you get like a gram of
the bubble that made it so you can
really get an idea because uh you know
the sensory let's see the flower it came
from too while we're well at that point
it's right you know why not be be a
pretty good thing for certain so that's
awesome everybody we had a pretty good
conversation here we still got about 14
minutes to go so you know we can kind of
I do want while I have you guys all here
as well if you guys can reply back to
that email with your Instagrams and
contact information I want to put it
into the description of the video
because there's tons of people in the
chat that want to reach out to to to
each of you so that would be really
wonderful if I didn't have to kind of
Chase you guys around and you could do
that
um otherwise yeah another 14 minutes I
definitely want to thank our sponsors uh
this is the first hash Church in 11
years I've said no to sponsors for 11
years so it's also kind of wild and neat
and and ironic that you know some of my
first sponsors are for the solvent world
including uh Adam at evolved extraction
Solutions yes I got your name right Adam
you you can check him out over at
evolved extraction like I said I'm going
to put everyone's cont uh contact
information that they are willing to
share of course Instagram is usually a
main one email uh probably won't be
putting phone numbers but certainly
emails uh so thank you uh to Adam and
evolved for uh sponsoring today as well
as uh the media Bros of which uh Adam is
their distributor here in Canada so they
made sure to say uh if if you guys
wanted to get a sample or a discount of
15% you can reach out to uh the mediab
bros. store use the the code hash Church
capital m capital B and you'll get uh
either a free sample there from those
guys so thank you media Bros for uh
supporting hash church and thank you to
my friend Jorge uh from chemtech you can
check them out at myem tech.com uh and
just uh like I said some of the nicest
diamonds I've ever seen was from uh the
homie for uh in Berlin a awesome that
you're out there doing that and then of
course I got to thank my friends uh Mark
and Dennis uh from the craft Greenery
it's a local dispensary here in town and
they're sort of uh you know they've just
got a good Consciousness they're really
into finding good variety and good
cultivars and uh yeah I've got some
favorite rosins that I get over from
them so thank you there anything else
anyone wants to cover in the 10 minutes
11 minutes that we have left and also
really before we get to that thank you
guys for being an awesome panel what a
great group of people that Mark shalone
has brought together definitely want to
stay in touch with you I don't want this
to be the solvent episode I want it to
be the first of a many parted solvent
episodes so we're definitely going to uh
get you guys back and H uh get deep into
these conversations uh but in the
meantime if anyone has anything they
want to share before we sign out it's
been almost 4 hours of hash Church on a
l lovely Sunday morning here here I
guess afternoon now in British Columbia
on the west coast just overlooking the
Pacific Ocean it's Bluebird day it's
sunny kind of makes me want to like
drive up to Whistler and smash uh well
there's no Powder up there right now
it's kind of East Coast icy nasty
terrible conditions but it's still epic
and awesome to be up there I'm not going
to sugarcoat it I'm not going to lie to
you whistler's rough right now but we're
doing what we can with it Adam and I are
going to be up there next weekend uh and
we're going to be uh smashing the Ice uh
Mounds right Adam
hopefully we get some snow between now
and then I think it's supposed to we we
will get get a system in we will
absolutely no Wade no Wade laughter this
no you know shout out to Wade he must be
having a rough day I know that he will
always make it to Hash church if and
when he can I certainly shared the um uh
the um link with him because I always
love really I can finish it off but no
one can finish off an episode like hash
church I always like have inter like I'm
looking inside my my being I'm trying to
become a better person it's just like
Wade literally touches my heart and soul
every time he speaks we love uh Wade and
just have a deep respect for everything
he's done I mean what a what a soldier
like just giving medicine away to
catastrophic
children house in a coup days I hope I
hope we can do maybe a little video
together where you guys are like you
know at least hear your voices in the
same room that would be a really cool
thing uh also wanted to mention what
else did I oh I wanted to mention that
horge had his hand up and uh what did
you have to say there my
friend uh just wanted to touch base a
little bit on like the solvents I feel
like we didn't cover the like uh what
solvent do you like to extract with for
example you know isobutane propane and N
butane all behave a little different the
extraction process yeah more turs some
feel more fat some more color and they
each pull a little bit of a different
flavor you know like from the each other
so just wanted to get like a some
feedback from everyone possible dude I
love this this this is going to be first
I'm going to let Murphy and maybe a few
others of you guys just give a cliffnote
answer but I think this will be the
conversation to start the next solvent
episode on uh what a great question
Jorge uh go ahead Murphy you put your
hand up
first um yeah there's there's so many
reasons to choose each one and it's such
a good question and it's one in our
industry specifically because it's so
young and new that we can all get really
hung up on because the first question
you have to ask yourself is about your
equipment and what it's capable of
because sometimes the best
solvent for a specific sop is not going
to be the best solvent for the
underpowered heater
and you
know low wattage Chiller that you have
to you know run that process sometimes
you have to think about you know at the
at the cost of the equipment you have
and at the cost of the scale that you
want to perform at you can also in the
way that you can choose a best solvent
you can
compromise in a really strategic way so
maybe you know because you have lower
pressure vessels you go colder and
longer with butane and you you know
change your surface area and you you
know you make decisions accordingly and
so you know as important as it is to
choose your solvent you really have to
choose your equipment with your solvent
in mind you know and in traditional
chemistry it's not you know unusual to
have a totally different piece of
glasswar if you change your solvent in
order for you to match an sop or you
change your sop to use the same
glassware in cannabis we sometimes try
to do everything with the same two
columns
and hope for the
best uh which is not even you know go
back to repeatability as you brought up
earlier the best solvent is the one you
can repeat with if you can't repeat a
process none of it is best and the
solvent is the first place to start you
know you mentioned earlier Indra was the
one of the first to bring up this gas
needs to be
clean we haven't learned that lesson and
we haven't tried we're using refill
cylinders which are designed for fuel
you know we need to be having direct
filled tanks that are stored on site you
know maybe buried underground if you're
in a tornado area or something you know
we need a we need an entirely different
process to facilitate what we want to do
but a lot of times we get real hung up
on what product we want to make what's
the best solvent for that and we don't
start with what is the best solvent for
the process that we're capable of um if
we've already bought equipment or want
to pursue like that that question can
put you in a real Circle um if you're
not careful and a lot of times people
will get bad results from a specific
solvent because of those ancillary
features and so it's it's a very
integrated question that you probably
need to ask every day every batch until
you have incredible repeatability it's
it's definitely two-dimensional you
definitely answered it from that sort of
corporate business owner perspective of
like well listen that's not I feel like
Jorge asked it more like yo what do you
guys like for your best solvent like for
your head but I don't know we'll let him
answer that but first uh John you had
your hand up first then horge uh Jorge
and then Yari you'll be up after that
and then uh we'll call it a day it's
okay if we go over five or 10 or 20
minutes so go go ahead John well yeah I
think definitely a good place to start
another episode on because we could go
pretty deep into the various reasons you
might you know Choose You Know neat
isobutane neat propane blends with
normal butane or whatever um because
although they're all non-polar solvent
and they're all
alkanes they pretty they do pretty
different things in terms of dissolving
different flavorant um as far as that
goes you know and I noticed that with
just straight inan certain flavors don't
get picked up almost at a wide range of
temperatures isobutane that Bond I guess
it's the bond angle Mark could come in
and explain that later you know may be
more capable of uh you know pulling some
more polar uh flavor inside of the mix
and everybody knows that propane does a
great job with you know tarping as a
whole there's a lot there um not to
mention temperature and the original
reason I had my hand up was just to give
a shout out to the solventless Community
because I have became a better hash
maker from learning the things and
following the solventless community as
they are having to look so closely at
all these different triome you know
characteristics morphology you know that
has educated me to be able to you know
select the style of extraction for a
given biomass and that gets into solvent
selection as
well absolutely uh Jorge I think you
were
next yeah so the question was basically
like Murphy got it like uh there she I
wanted to bring attention to that like
uh you know you guys use different
solvents for different purposes Bas on
the SOP for example I want to mention at
one time I was testing how much thca
each solving can be solved so I loaded
up a minor or you know two miners with
the same amount of isol and injected
same amount of solvent one was isobutane
one was and butane and heated them up to
the same temperature and got notice that
only ISO buttine can only dissolve about
half the amount that n buttine can so
that's why like your sop would I guess
matter for what what you're after uh to
extract and but in general to like what
you were saying is yes there is also
like to extract with like uh for example
you can get a with using a blend like
7030 uh being 7D uh uh
butane and that can bring benefits for
example it can help pull a lot of the
other compounds with the extract so you
have a more full profile and it can also
help with like recovery times because it
boils over a lot faster than uh
buttine nice very good Yi you had your
hand up in my personal opinion and doing
all the experiments with the the grow
and the flower and everything and butane
is the best solvent for weed in my
personal opinion um I know that they
explained all those other reasons if you
wouldn't get really like analytical with
it but all
around uh the effect the the HT that
comes off of it uh the thca that you
pull from it I personally think n butane
is the the way to go just my yeah I run
this neat I run neat normal utane mostly
yeah but I do Envision this like you
know super nitty-gritty future of like
oh okay this Ry has this flavor profile
so for this extraction I'm going to dial
this blend of co-solvents to make sure I
you know honored that bouquet but you
know I wish I was running living soil
top shelf every
day you gotta make it happen tella you
had your hand up uh yeah I also uh run
and butane to keep it keep it simple on
the recovery too to sure that like I'm
not having to do crazy math to try to
try to get um get my um my ratios back
to what I wanted after recovering so
that's part of the reason why at
Incredibles as a business we always kept
it and butane just to keep it simple so
we were always recovering just one gas
and the ratio of gas has never changed
in our recovery tanks and uh and just
sort of out of preference I guess too
over time probably a little bit of bias
in that
I'm just going to have to neag everybody
because I love propane so much you guys
you just have to run it such high
pressure if you're running low pressure
propane you ain't doing nothing but if
you're willing to blast it like really
blast it you can do it's it's everything
that CO2 should be able to do but
doesn't well it's actually kind of
similar to CO2 in some ways and a lot of
the chemical ways explain this yeah you
know it's a
tetrahedral um type three diens
structure but yeah right I like to
compare propane to like you know that's
like riding a bucking bull you know and
inan is like riding a a good
well-trained horse and um depends on
who's driving you know and like you're
saying for the business sense I think
inan is more popular for many reasons
and one of them being it's really nice
to
handle it's not propan is cheaper
awesome well that was an incredible
conversation everyone really thank you
for coming on today and just W in the
knowledge like I said first of many
episodes we're definitely going to go
deeper uh I want to hear more from both
Jorge and uh Adam and Murphy in regards
to the education that they're doing I
wanted to uh you know see a little bit
talk a little bit about the genome uh
project that you have going on there
with your education and just uh yeah I'd
love to you know obviously speak to all
of you uh again here in the very near
future so Dr Mark thank you so much for
bringing this great group of people
together and uh hopefully you guys had a
good time over there puffing bowls
ripping dabs what was really cool about
pulling this this group together is it
it brought back some relationships like
Eric and I haven't seen each other in oh
yeah such a long time it's so good to
see you good to reconnect and um you
know it's great to hear from some of the
younger folks in the room too because
yeah there are some OG's we we did have
U an invitation out the Boris at Busy B
and uh for Jason the emotech so you know
but hey we got kind bill in the room
here this is great yeah it's great I
mean this is a great community of people
Ryan and Max you know I love you guys we
did consider you know basically throwing
maybe an invite out to Derek but I think
having uh having Ryan and Telly here the
next next best thing and yeah Marcus
thank you so much for giving us this uh
opportunity to come together Murphy
you're always so impressive I could
always tell you that everything that you
say is spot-on chemical you know I mean
chemically correct and uh I think the
real difference between propane and
butane has nothing to do with the
polarity polarity is about the same it
has to do with the uh with the
thermodynamics has to do with the rate
rate of recovery and the fact that you
know it's a lot easier and quicker to
recover uh things like uh butane but um
Jorge thank you so much for sharing that
uh that result that result about the
fact that ISO uh propane uh dissolved
less than n propane you know you might I
want to mention real quick the TPS also
play a role there talking about just
clean ISO you know no no secondary
solvent right right but just side
secondary solvent yeah I mean just to be
able to do a side bys side comparison
and share that result with the world you
know what I envisioned as soon as you
said that result and Jorge I don't know
if you remember I came by your booth at
biscon and we had a really we had a
really nice chat that was a really
really great I remember you oh yeah oh
yeah and and I'll say the same thing I
said to to to uh to Murphy which is that
everything that you're saying is spot-on
correct I mean you're you're not a
chemist by training but you're kind of a
uh a a chemist by observation and that's
that's really great but sharing that
result again maybe that's a great way to
do a control crash you know the fact
that you can take advantage of different
solubility differences and these
different solvents there could be ways
of perhaps you know like if you wanted
to make like kind of like the micro
diamonds or if you wanted to sort of
speed up your process you could keep
that in mind that hey if we're rich in
in isopropane we might see a crash
happen sooner than later sooner than we
predicted
right Adam when we developed the uh the
genome crystallizer that's actually the
original um Insight that that drove that
Innovation was uh noticing that um if
you added cold propane um into like a
jar of of dissolved uh oil and oil
dissolved in in butane then it would
like immediately kind of like pop um and
that observation kind of just we kept at
that and and uh now we actually use uh
butane because like uh people were
mentioning like it's just a little bit
easier to control and kind of the
consistency and repeatability of it but
if there's a challenging crystallization
you can always add um it sounds like
isobutane would have a similar effect
but adding very cold propane into the
mixture um can drop the the solubility
and kind of like create like an instant
Cascade of
crystallization go ahead John yeah well
it's real interesting you know Mark
you're saying there's not much
difference in polarity between you know
these three light hydrocarbons uh jge
has shown us you know with pure thda a
you know clear solubility difference and
a lot of us have seen it between the
three um and then with the genome
crystallizer I've also wondered you know
is it acting as an anti-solvent or a
direct contact
refrigerant um and I think that's what's
keeping me involved with you know
playing with all these things is uh
there's a lot of questions to be
answered out here you know we know what
works but sometimes the how is gets into
the nitty-gritty
absolutely awesome everybody well we did
it we hit our 4our Mark 4 hours and six
minutes in fact so I'm going to
definitely keep I've got all of your
email contacts but I'd definitely love
for you guys to reply to the email or
hit me up in any way that you can
ideally through that email uh I'll also
put you in touch with anyone if there's
an email if there's someone you don't
know but you wanted to know but maybe
it's not their name or the email doesn't
really connect to them in any way you
can reach out to to me uh and I'll make
sure to connect anyone on the panel here
today who wants to uh have the link uh
and just really thank you know the 400
plus people that were watching the
entire time we had this episode there's
some hardcore cannabis nerds that just
love to hear this stuff and uh we love
to talk about it so it's a it's a
marriage made in heaven really so is not
dead right pH is not dead no it's right
here today and hash Church episode 3 and
uh we'll be talking about this some more
in the future hopefully we'll uh make a
bunch of wonderful uh new Pro uh
programs here it's hard to plan a show
so I once again I got to give you props
Dr Mark for pulling such an Eclectic
wonderful group of people that actually
answered the emails and actually uh it's
hard when you're planning a show and the
people you're reaching out to aren't uh
getting back to you so hopefully next
week we have another doozy I'm not sure
exactly what it's going to be but I'm
sure it'll be a banger and it'll start
coming together here sooner than later
in the meantime I would say May the full
Mount bless your bowl sooner than later
and thanks everyone for the time that
you spent with us here today on hash
church this is infinite this will just
be up forever and ever and ever or at
least a long time so peace out everybody
we'll talk to you next time