good morning everyone yes yes good
morning everyone good morning hash
Church 2.0 episode 5 sending out the
link right now to everyone get everyone
inside here see what's going on today
how's everyone feeling we're really
excited today to talk about greenhouses
it's been a really wonderful thing for
us to be able to grow and be greenhouses
and you know it's been it's a beautiful
environment to be in and its really
changed a lot of the way that we grow
and it offers us you know different
environments in our in our world to be
able to create beautiful spaces so looks
like we got Jonathan Baldwin in here
I'm forever flowering nice mornin
morning great to have you here great to
be here yes so how are you feeling today
we got farmer Tom coming in the house
here good morning good morning Tom
having me hey Jonathan what's up buddy
good to see you brother
good to see you too you owe me good
morning it's chlorine nice to see you
this morning
Eric so how are you feeling today here
in the greenhouse they're down in
California tell us what's going on where
are you sitting
I'm at the office here at forever
flowering and Grass Valley I'm just out
here at the greenhouses because the
weather is so nice I figured I'd sit
outside today morning Jason
dragonfly you guys are muted other yeah
okay so I was thinking um farmer Tom
maybe you can give us a minute and why
don't you tell us a little bit about
your story and what's going on within
your world
okay a little thanks my name is farmer
Tom and I'm out of lower man I'm
originally out of San Diego but I've
been up here in Vancouver Washington for
the past 14 years we've got a 5 acre
farm we we bought an old nursery
actually so it came with 500 foot
greenhouses little Quonset huts tiles
two wells two inch main lines up and
down the property is pretty much
everything yeah I wanted and so we've
been here ever since and and kind of
doing our thing originally from San
Diego was part of the 215 push back in
the day our collective shelter from the
storm in Hillcrest in San Diego got
raided in 99 where I got arrested with
Steve McWilliams for 448 plants and I
kind of kicked me into the you know the
advocate zone so like the worst thing
could happen to you and then and then
you're not afraid anymore so we've been
kind of pushing through over the years
we worked I couldn't take a different
route so I I worked a lot with the media
back in the day here in Vancouver and in
the early days of 502 and even back in
the medical days we're doing the farmers
markets up here I just thought it was a
push to a better way to play it by you
know being more accessible to them and
then trying to do my best to represent
cannabis as well as possible that's kind
of all led up to we did some education
over here over the years we worked with
Washington state to legalize
concentrates because when they first
came out with I 502 the legal system up
here they were gonna only concentrates
we're going to be amenable and so I was
asked by como news out of Seattle to do
an open blast everybody thought I was
crazy we did it anyways and within two
weeks base
their message was if you don't regulate
and don't tax it at the time here in
Washington state was like every ten days
to two weeks we're having another
explosion we're going if you don't
regulate it and tax it these kids will
blow themselves up it's a twenty to a
hundred dollar fix and you're gonna have
a lot of problems on your hands so
within two weeks they change the law
that kind of led into me being able
asked to work with the Department of
Health and Human Services on the federal
level and we got to educate seven agents
from the CDC on production of processing
in cannabis in 2015 when I first got on
the phone with ten agents they they knew
nothing about cannabis they were getting
all their information from YouTube
no offense to YouTube but I kind of
wasn't it unfair to come into a
valuation of our industry and not really
know what's going on so they agreed to
come to my farm that we were gonna take
him on a tour they didn't like that idea
but they made my farmers secure location
where federal agents can learn touch and
handle cannabis so I had him out here a
total of five days I had him out here
and August for a couple days my plants
were about you know six feet tall and we
were thinning them out at the time and I
showed them all my practices that I've
been using as far as you know the
nutrients and everything else we were
doing with the plants and we gave him
demos on hydrocarbons and I brought in
JD from scout farm to kind of tell him
about concentrates and Dana from goat
labs to kind of give him the lab
spectrum and we bought it you know we
did a hand trimming machine trimming and
then that was kind of the precursor to
when they came out for the actual health
hazard evaluation in October of 2015
that was like the glory year I mean it
was like the best year ever and I was
lucky that we didn't get earlier rains
and we didn't have any kind of issues
going at the time so we had him out
there three for three days and they were
there to collect scientific data for a
workplace health and safety so they
hooked us up with sniffers one that
collected mold ones that collect dust
particles and then they have stem
apparatuses around the property in the
greenhouses out in the open air and in
our trimming and drying room they
gathered all the data they went back and
and it was published in April of 2017
and in August of 2017 I got my own web
page on the CDC gov web page dedicated
to the scientific study OSHA is using
them on a national level to create
workplace Elkin safety standards for the
industry Cal OSHA is using the same
report and I believe Washington State's
use that also so now that the reports
out the latest thing is that my farm is
referred to as an organic cannabis bar
search studies that are being done on
the federal level so that's kind of what
I've been up to last few years yeah
that's a lot of thanks so much that's
really interesting sounds like so many
ways for us to count the good
information
well it takes it really takes all of us
you know and I'm just doing my part and
you know we've also this is our fourth
semester teaching that Clark Community
College cannabis and your health course
I've done the the agricultural part you
know we've done a you know cloning and
see popping and then you know the
mediums to use and taking your plant to
harvest for harvest highest yields and
harvesting and curing section so and
we're into our second year we're really
excited about it and you know just just
doing my part
that's excellent well thank you for that
I think maybe we should go to Marcus
down in Jamaica for a minute if you have
a minute to tell us what's going on down
there and and how you're feeling that
would be really great and Americans go
there alright can you guys hear me okay
yes sir Mike excellent little bit of a
delay but no problem awesome Tom that
was wonderful to hear everything you had
to say I don't even know you and I like
you
immediately so that was great thank you
guys all for showing up today to do this
episode thanks to fresh flower in
greenhouse Eric and Jonathan for helping
ma parade and of course to the Dragonfly
sounds like Marcus may become myself but
I am here plus years
he'll hopefully be able to add some
value to the conversation and just
really really stoked that everyone
showed up to share in this dialogue
today I think like Tom was saying you
know YouTube's not always the best
source for information but we're trying
to we're trying to change that every day
with at least our little slice and it's
because of people like all of the people
sitting on this panel that decide to
come and share their time with us that
we're we're able to put this caliber of
information out so I do thank all of you
greatly for that and I guess maybe I'll
have a little bong rip while we go over
to the next person down zaxon we got
this really nice pipe from the Snodgrass
family last night Bob Snodgrass so I
think we'll take a first you're gonna
hit the gundog pipe this is sweet
okay Eric and and let's lit so nice to
have you here this morning
tell us a little bit about what's going
on this is awesome
well I just you know the office today
we have good Wi-Fi here or better than
at my house it's a little bit better
background the weather is great it's
almost like spring-like that's whether
it's yeah the people that we have honors
I think in my opinion seems pretty cool
people and I'm excited to hear and talk
to them as well so I kind of wanted to
start off and try to do some brief
introduction in that way they can attend
in that way I think Tommy I think your
microphones on sir
okay at the top is the mute button top
of the screen there you go so yeah
basically why don't we just do a quick
introduction for everybody and we'll
start up with Micah why don't you tell
us who you are and your company and then
we'll get back to you for some
conversation can you guys hear me all
right it's the first time on a Google
hangout so I gotta make sure I'm finit
right yeah so my name is Mike Anderson
and I company called leaf organics in
California and operate and own a few
different forms in Humboldt in Mendocino
County and then have a couple projects
in Southern California and Riverside and
we are basically a brand that we'd you
would find in any of the dispensaries we
make all kinds of different products and
one of the main focus is that we are
doing right now is on CBD stuff so we
grow all of our owns DVDs genetics and
turn them into all kinds of different
products like top Cole's soaps and all
that kind of stuff so yeah I'm stoked to
be here I'm in Colorado right now I took
three days off and tried to go
snowboarding but this not very much snow
over here it's similar to California
right now so yeah so yeah I know I'm
stoked to be on thanks for the invite I
really appreciate it and I'm happy to uh
you know hear what you guys have to say
right on Mike in well thanks for coming
and I'm glad I'm glad you joined us
Jonathan wants you to give us a quick
little who you are real fast all right
good morning everybody can hear me first
of all I just wanted to get a big shout
to the bubble man down there in Jamaica
what's up my brother
so glad to be here with you I've been
using your bag since I lived in Arcata
in 2000 so you know I was talking with
my lady this morning and we were just
talking about how like that just changed
the game right there man and it really
made hash making accessible to the
people and really started the whole saw
solvent less movement I believe so Big
Ups brother and Big Ups on your light
DEP hat my name is Jonathan I founded
forever flowering in 2006 I've been
working with Eric since 2007 we've
really been working hard around the
clock year-round to in the beginning
educate people as to why you wanted to
block the light out of greenhouses
people would always laugh at us like why
are you trying to block the light out of
greenhouses
and so you know for the first many years
it was a lot of a lot of Education and
as we see the industry moving forward
and we're seeing the the vast majority
of licenses going especially in states
outside of California going towards
indoor cultivation we're really seeing
this massive carbon footprint that's
being created and you can see the
headlines in so many places that they're
saying cannabis is this massive energy
consuming industry and it's really not
necessary true it is today but it's
totally not necessary and so when you
can really dial in a greenhouse hemp guy
who came on has to mute that person has
to mute so anyway when you design a
greenhouse with the proper environment
you're able to get you know top quality
flowers and and still have the
efficiency of growing sun-grown and and
as we're seeing in most regulated states
full Sun grown is really all going to
extracts they're really oil fields at
this point and what we're really seeing
in the dispensaries are indoor or high
grade light depth
greenhouse groaning and unfortunately
that's that's my intro before I ramble
off too much just had a cup of coffee so
let's left you guys guy get me started
oh no you're good you're good we're
going there that's the direction we're
headed for sure intros Jason you want to
say hi and tell us who you are where
you're at real quick have to go closer
to your computer we can't hear you Jason
yeah
dinner for sure it's a little better but
you might want to get some ear buds if
you have some freer from your phone grab
some I'll jump to JD real quick and then
we'll come back to you okay cool JD why
don't you give us a quick intro and say
what you're all about unmute yourself
unmute yourself all right cool can you
hear me
all right this is great I'm right here
in Grass Valley
Ron Gold Country cannabis with my team
here we've been doing lots of doing the
last few years
yeah I don't know we've had a lot of
success just bring in the sauce Marcus
at the front of the camera and you hold
on
second lady you're gonna have to hold
sorry bro I don't know who the hit hey
him I don't know if dragonfly can mute
them or not the hemp the hemp fam what
hemp family yo ha ha ha
what's he smoking on our IG give it
another try
unmuted enemy should be unmuted
no all right cool yeah go country
cannabis is my brand
we've just been out here growing for
probably like the last 15 years I worked
my way from Sonoma County up into mindo
Humboldt Lake County and found my way to
Grass Valley in the Sierra Foothills and
there's a great climate for greenhouse
growing we've had a lot of success and
have a strong team just love love it the
industry and everything about it so it's
really exciting to be included here with
you guys and any wait to see where this
conversation goes awesome JD well thanks
for joining us and yeah I can't wait to
talk to you to the hemp person bounce so
we can just move along so we got farmer
Tom we already had bubbleman and dam
check-in and so let's talk some
greenhouses a little bit I know Mike has
got to kind of maybe leave early so I
was gonna maybe start with Mike a bubble
man you got something you want to say I
was just gonna say there's skunk Mans
here as well if you guys want to hear a
quick intro from him I know a lot of
people know a lot about him but it might
be a neat thing to hear a couple of
words from from the man himself yeah
definitely sorry about that I forgot
[Music]
no problem whatsoever here he is now
howdy howdy howdy everybody in hash
Church yeah my experience with green
houses was I built my own green house
about 40 years ago and then I moved to
the Netherlands where I ran many many
many professional green houses with
computerized darkening computerized
watering and and I my favorite way to
grow is greenhouses although there's
but IIIi I've been there I've seen most
of the changes we were one of the very
first in the world to use darkening for
to mature cannabis flowers in the when
we were in the northern environment in
the greenhouse and if anybody has any
questions I'll be happy to step up to
the box but except for that I am what I
am and I think pretty much everybody
knows me guys well yes I mean basically
you know we're here to talk about
greenhouses and everybody on the panel
here is using greenhouses in some
capacity whether it's you know whether
they're working with us or not
everybody's got a unique story and to
themselves and so mica I was just gonna
kick it off with you since in case you
have to bounce early at least we can get
some of the information from leaf
organics you know I'm I'm you know big
fan of your products as well just
because everything you have is so cool
and Sun grown and I use the pet CBDs you
know for my old dogs and even the CBD
shampoo and so you know not going into
the products as much I'm just curious
for your story is you know a grower in
Southern and Northern California have
the greenhouses or what you know what
achievements or breakthroughs have you
had in the greenhouse sector in the last
couple of years yeah I think for me that
we're where the you know greenhouses
come into play and especially light
deprivation greenhouses come into play
and that's like new era of regulation
and taxes and having to like really
focus on your cost of goods that's where
I see you know not only do I think
plants grow better in greenhouses but
for us it's a way for us to get our
costumers yeah we're able you know
constantly be harvesting over and over
and over again versus just getting one
two arrests a year and you know and then
we're you know seeing a big difference
between what we're getting an output in
Southern California versus
Northern California just due to weather
and you know most of the places in
envelope - you know we're all out the
grid and there's no power or nothin like
that so it's all ran off solar systems
which is awesome and or we're pullin
tarps you know which is still totally
good and works but I think if that I
don't know if that answers your question
I'd like for us I think it's a way for
us to constantly be getting fresh
product in the rotation and not be
sitting on just a bunch of you know
older inventory and and helps us get our
cost of goods down which is super
important well I mean that's the name of
the game these days keeping the cost of
goods down because there's so many
things I mean now with regulation eight
taxes have kicked in so I'm sure you
medically medical legal for a while now
the state taxes have kicked in and so
that's got to be a little bit of a new I
guess a new challenge for you to address
yeah
every day it's a we always talk about it
at the office it's like a Rubik's Cube
you know trying to figure out what
changes you're gonna have to deal with
next and right I think the laws aren't
even really set yet and they're gonna
change again so and so how do you feel
about I mean you guys run fairly
moderate size greenhouses or you can are
you guys working on any big projects or
anything coming up are you guys gonna
stay kind of the the you know mid-sized
greenhouses that you've been using now
and pulling tarps or where we where's
the future ahead now with trying to keep
cost of production down and state taxes
kicking in you know that's a good
question I think for now we have a bit a
bit of both you know as you know we have
a we have a synth rubber flower and
greenhouses and then we have some that
we're blowing tarps on and a lot of that
comes down to what city or county you're
in and has a lot to do with what your
local taxes are so we do have a bigger
project that we're working on in
Riverside County which we're going to be
doing a bunch of it's it'll be a bigger
project and it'll be a you know a fully
automated greenhouse setup I personally
like the idea
keeping greenhouses in a smaller
environment versus like this massive
Costco style thing I think it's a lot
easier to mitigate problems with all
kinds of stuff pests and not that you
don't need these massive HVAC systems
and sort of turn the thing into a
gigantic into a room which I see a lot
of people doing and so yeah I mean I
think in the future we're definitely
leaning towards building a couple a
couple of these bigger facilities but
there's still something to be said about
quality product being grown in a small
environment you know it's it's any time
we've ever scaled you know like we did
in the last couple years it's it's hard
to keep up and make sure that you're
putting out the same quality product
every single time so it's a bit of both
key that's that's always a tough thing
and about consistency you know a lot of
the flour these days I guess in
California in some places would end up
going to distillates and oils and
extracts which is a good thing in some
ways but I'm kind of wondering if we're
gonna see flowers you know on the
shelves top shelf flowers people want to
buy some flowers to go camping with to
roll a joint or do whatever I mean I
know that there's a lot of mids going
down but you know as California gonna be
hit with the shortage kind of like
Nevada was just in the top shelf flower
category I mean I think all the other
things are gonna fall into place but I
just worry about that good doobie
material and I was reading about some of
the other day saying something about
everybody's just gonna get used to mids
and not really remember what top shelf
looks like I was like wait a minute I
don't know about that but I know that
you guys are doing good in the top shelf
category but the gross sisters just
joined us and Sherman wants you saying
hello we all did an introduction before
you happy hash Church I got stung and
lost my weight on the Internet so sorry
I'm late
I am Siobhan danger Darvish and I own
and operate California's first permitted
cannabis location West Coast farms and
I'm also one of the five gross sisters
hi Micah we party in Vegas let em take
this con yeah so I guess I might just a
my telling you more is it still my stage
I might just introducing myself oh well
the different and is that your brand I
think you're muted yeah I had to mute
her cuz you were echoing sorry about
that okay we're back um yes those are my
brands the farm itself is blessed Coast
farms and gross sisters media production
is a little bit different we're a little
bit more of the education side and
initially it started because my sister
my actual sister Sloane Reed and I
wanted to we didn't have money to market
our farm and so we decided to set a
guerilla marketing style of
instructional videos and yeah they kind
of took off and so this year it's our
second year doing the gross sisters and
we've adopted five new sisters four new
sisters and some behind-the-scenes
sisters and so we're really able to
branch out from the farm and cultivate
cannabis and all its new facets and so
yeah it's all yeah yeah again you're
good mic muted will echo through someone
else's camera so just try to mute when
you don't talk and get ready to unmute
when you want to talk and welcome thanks
thanks for having me yeah that's awesome
well I met I met you at the golden tarp
Awards and that's where you're a host
for the live stream and so that was a
pretty cool event too and you guys did a
really good job of hosting and
live-streaming that whole thing
yeah what's it like to be the first
permitted farm in Humboldt County by the
way stressful a lot
we were the guinea pigs and it felt like
our heads were on the chopping block
to be completely honest but you know on
the flip side of that it was it's been
amazing it's been wonderful I mean what
a blessing too I'm a second-generation
farmer and to be able to carry the torch
for my father who lived in the hills for
years and years and years you know and
Here I am with the first fermented farm
it's an honor it's a blessing
hence blessed Coast but yeah it's been
crazy we've gotten some really beautiful
recognition for our farming techniques
due to being the first so we like to
tell people that we filled out the
application as simply as possible simple
farming methods simply organic and so
that's why we think we got it
got lucky well that's really cool I
appreciate you coming on and we'll talk
a little bit more JD are you still over
there up I see JD was walking around a
little bit we can yeah JD you know JD
lives in Grass Valley it's funny I don't
even really know JD I'm in Grass Valley
too and I happen to see him our kids go
to the same school and then I was in an
event and I saw he won an award last
year and even this year I'm like wait a
minute I'm at cannabis events and this
guy's winning all these cups and then
I'm dropping my kids off at school and
there he is in the parking lot walking
his kids and it's like this whoa like
right on so I you know wanted to meet
him over the course of time and so we
started linking up slowly and so I
thought JD has a good story or
interesting you know background with you
know the ability to you know enter these
events and win them and we were just you
know I'm curious on the style of growing
you're using are you a high tech grower
you know is it low tech what's the
secret to some of your success without
giving everything away
let's see that's a good question um I I
just love it you know we all love it so
much like our team works really hard
maybe we put in a little too much work
sometimes that makes sense we could
probably not be as perfection driven but
we take really good care of them you
know it's compost tea and it's organic
top dressings it's funny I feel like the
you know the plant really reflects what
you're putting into it so if everybody's
in a clear space and working together
then the seems like the round to really
show that we had to really hide terpene
levels the last couple of rounds and I
don't know maybe it was because the
industry's changing and I was stressed
out and so the plant was stressed out
and those terpenes are its natural
defense mechanism you know it's like as
the point gets more stressed it seems
like it pushes out more medicine I'm not
exactly sure we've just like I said
moving moving up the coast was great
growing in Lake County was great
moving into the Sierra Foothills was
absolutely amazing losing the coastal
influence and really having these hot
days seems to really trigger the plants
and swelling up at the right time and
just appreciating where we give it to
them I'll grow and everything from low
end car parts cart you know Costco card
canopies with grow we've all the way to
you know 2500 square foot on a depths
that are completely dialed in we've won
awards from both both directions so it's
like I haven't really been held at
Neyland got exactly what works it just
seems to be working across the board and
probably due to the level of love that
my team puts in and this climber that we
have how long have you lived in the
Grass Valley area you said you started
out maybe the Coast Lake County how long
have you been over here now to the
foothills see I was in a Lake County in
2001 and then I made it here probably
about five years ago
Smart's Ville Browns Valley or similan
yeah I've been kind of all over the
place
yeah but the last five years I've really
been all to dialing in and it's awesome
this is where my family wanted to land
we was about as close to the snow is
that could be because the rest of them
don't like the cold and so I didn't got
being a great mix so it's like close to
Tahoe and the winter got below the snow
line in something you know the rest of
the season and it just really makes our
job easy so everything that we put it
here seems to just go so much farther
yeah it's almost like you could start
pulling tarps today I mean this weather
has been unreal it's like at night we're
still like in the low 50s and so yeah
that's that's some good grown weather do
you use a passive style greenhouse or a
sealed greenhouse with venom mechanical
ventilation what's your style of
greenhouse operation unlike the canopies
if the ones we built ourselves you know
they're open all the way around I have
about a knee-high you know knee-high to
the ground it's just wide open all the
way around the greenhouse I have one end
of the canopy would be a seal I'm not
feeling but pulled down probably about
3/4 of the way and then the other end
wide open and that kind of creates like
a funnel and it like forces air from the
sides and the back and flushes it out
that open end of the hoop automatically
without using fans or anything my auto
death is definitely like you know closed
up I don't know how sealed it is but
it's definitely closed up and with
thermostats and can flush that air out
really fast when they hit the right
temperature okay cool so I mean do you
when you enter Awards so you enter them
out of any greenhouse it doesn't really
matter it's like you know you don't have
one greenhouse that's better for the
award maker than the other or Terp maker
let's say
unmute I was trying to figure it out you
know it's trying to figure out like
exactly what was the recipe and the
first one we won we got a second-place
hybrid and him Khan and that was with
harley soo CBD strain going up against
Indore and it ended up winning and
that's just out of a Costco car port
with no fans no supplemental lighting
and it just did great it's just like
kind of look around like you know you
can tell the plant that really does it
you can tell the round you know when the
round is just going off and that one was
really good the golden tarp winners and
then woke up winners have been out of
the auto death probably at about I think
it's like an 800 foot elevation that
one's pushing really high profiles
almost everything that came out of there
that round was like over five percent
terpenes the plants were a little more
stressed I didn't think it was gonna be
that good of a round but when it came to
test results they were just off the hook
it's funny how that that goes sometimes
you know like stress and plants out and
things like that can be stressful for
the grower as well but then you end up
you know trimming it up and maybe you
can get in those lab results and voila
you got something special it's hard
always kind of hard to tell you know
Jason are you back are you able to jump
on and introduce yourself now sorry we
kind of glazed over for a second yeah
that's that network um so um my name is
Jason hello everybody I am a I'm a
recreational driller up here in
Washington State started in medical and
long before that I'd say what got me
into greenhouse growing was just kind of
watching the prices just ratcheted down
and kind of really feeling like I needed
to look into a different growing method
and so kind of up the tail in the
medical I am I started in with talking
to Eric and getting together
plans to build a greenhouse and and then
you know as as it kind of progressed
getting license really seeing everything
just changed drastically it kind of
occurred to me that you know we grew
indoors to hide from the cops and so now
in this regulated market and an illegal
market in Washington it's like I just
don't get it why why everybody isn't
going this direction and I think the
future really is like that greenhouse
and it really is going that direction
but you know coming from an indoor
grower backed up for so many years I
really just took everything that I need
from indoor grilling and applied it in
the greenhouse and I think my quality
tariff levels I mean everything is just
as good if not better you know a lot of
cases not to mention a much more
enjoyable work environment being under
the Sun you know it's it's chock-full of
Divya's and fans and dehumidifiers yeah
pretty wet weather up here but I go
year-round and I I love growing in
greenhouses I've got I've got one of her
flowerings almost a thousand square foot
and then I've got a few hoop houses that
I run just as sort of old-school polo
type during the season and so far so
good
that's awesome I went to your place a
couple years ago and you up on the
islands of Washington and one of the
incredible things about your particular
property is that there's bald eagles
flying everywhere around the greenhouses
and like you know it's just this magical
space and I mean whether you're pulling
tarps or an automated greenhouse or
whatever I can't imagine that being a
tough place to live and grow I mean I
was you know mesmerized by the place
myself and look forward to coming back
and visiting again sometime but you know
how we met - is that all your videos on
Instagram was you going through a 50
thousand square foot indoor facility on
a skateboard going from room to room to
room you know and it was the build-out
it was the build-out of this big massive
indoor facility and basically you one
day just walked away and you know about
the eight or thousand square foot
greenhouse to kind of test this all out
and you know I mean I think you've
really become one of the bigger Sun
ground fanatics that I've seen out of
the industry just because you're
dramatic change from that huge build-out
to just literally walking away and and
starting fresh and so that's an awesome
awesome situation yeah
no thank you um I I was part of a Tier
three warehouse and you know we looked
for the right space and then we started
building it out and I was kind of sort
of looking at this whole idea and it's
kind of seeing the writing on the wall
that this is not really sustainable and
I ended up believing my percentage on
the table telling them good luck and
walking away they ended up getting known
here to license and basically converted
our medical facility you to horrify the
key facility which involved lot offenses
and cameras and all sorts of fun stuff
yeah they look really good well yeah
when the funny thing is when I visited
you it was recreational in Washington it
started but you were still medical and
so the medical people could still walk
around with their jars and you know it
was kind of chill but where you go into
the tear taboos and the regulated
recreational there's cameras and you
can't do the same thing so it was
definitely kind of a fun time and the
fun thing about John Jason's greenhouses
was built over his indoor grow room that
was underground there's an underground
vault and it was kind of like deal ghost
town when you pulled open the door to
look down in there at the old grow space
that was you know from the Prohibition
days and now there's this big green
house on top of it and it's funny how
times have changed how far we've all
come from you know people growing in
prohibition times too
medical to recreational it's just a
whole evolution and you definitely
showcase that at your place yeah we we
had a little 10 10 foot by 16 foot said
that we have we built essentially over
the top of a mountain footprint
underground and that was you know way
back in the day that was that was my
little spot walk into this nondescript
little shed pull open the trapdoor walk
down the ladder and then you know I
didn't want to lose that because such a
cool little room and so we ended up
building a greenhouse right over the top
of that and the entire structure sits on
a basically a floating platform and then
and for a while right before you know
needed to scale up the bed that was my
little bedroom before the greenhouse so
the holy classic it was all
self-contained
now we're kind of converting that into
more of like a little storage room but
but yeah it's it's a it's been an
interesting journey for sure
I held on with medical as long as I
possibly could right up until literally
the last the last day hold down my last
harvest and then went right into
Medicare ready to recreational so it
kind of fell asleep old days ago but
it's you know it also comes with
helicopters doing so I keep another
helicopter insurance for sure well right
on man I'm gonna jump over to Jonathan
real quick cuz Jonathan before you lose
your coffee buzz I want you get back on
that roll you had earlier and you know
if you think about it all the people
here this topic you know light
deprivation in general I know that
wasn't invented by forever flowering
because a lot of people online or like
you know II didn't invent it but I mean
you know I mean you've really brought a
technique in a sense that you made it a
company that people could access all
this gear and information to do lie
deprivation and so let's hear a little
bit about you know that story in your
background and coming up and right on
thanks Eric first of all I just want to
start out by giving props to all the
first-gen people you know ii ten people
all the people that really you know laid
this foundation and blazed the trail for
the rest of us to be doing what we do
right now you know a lot of people to
come into the game right now don't
realize that people went to jail
you know people went to jail people had
their properties taken away people have
their kids taken away from them and and
today we're just talking about taxes and
we're talking about how how do we go
about filling out applications and
regulations and such and so you know
really big up to all those people big up
to Dennis Peron that just passed
recently and all the people that really
pave the way for prop 215 you know it's
it's a different day and age right now
and so you know just really given thanks
and having gratitude for all those
people you know thankfully you know I've
been in this in this industry for about
25 years and thankfully never had any of
those knocks on the door that so many
people have woken up to in the middle of
the night but but as far as greenhouses
go before I get into that I just want to
point out one thing if you look behind
me right here that's a ruby red
grapefruit
that's citrus growing at 2,000 feet up
in the Sierras with no covering in Feb
on February third or fourth wherever we
are right now so even going beyond the
whole idea of the benefits of
greenhouses and how they you know
increased her profiles how they're you
know really give that bling of that
indoor look that so many people are
looking for we can just stop at crop
insurance we can just stop right there
you know you're talking about a plant
that's not gonna get dusted with sprays
going on from your neighbor or desk
coming on and when we're looking at all
the different microbial tests and you
look at people you know a green life
productions over in Nevada came down and
gave us a little schooling on the fact
that in their tests in Nevada just from
the test results you're able to tell if
the trimmer was wearing a face mask or
not and so when we're getting down the
levels like that we're really starting
to look at you know all these different
nuances that
we really got to protect our crop from
not to mention the fact that you know
it's 81 degrees in Browns Valley in the
beginning of February so what's going to
happen when your full Sun crop in late
September and those rains come you know
like all of a sudden you're a plus is
going to maybe an A or even into a B and
in this market the difference between an
A plus and an A is whether or not you're
blasting it or it's going into a jar and
that can make or break your business
right there you can be done right there
so where did it all where did the
inspiration can't come from really
living in Mendocino back in the day and
pulling tarps and you know looking at
where where everything was going and me
and all my friends you know we all ate
organic drive drove biodiesel wore hemp
we were you know really living that
lifestyle and talking that talk and and
then but when you looked at it like all
my friends had like 50,000 Watts blowing
up in their garage or their barn or
whatever and it was like okay we're
almost making it happen so how do we
really take that next step and really
the idea was how do we reduce that
carbon footprint how do we have an
income a crop that's coming in all the
time and not just that one crop and and
how do we be responsible you know how do
we be responsible not just for our own
bank accounts but for what we're doing
for the community that we live in and
for the planet that we're living on and
so really for me the idea came looking
at pulling tarps and you know it really
sucked having to wake up early and pull
in a tarp and then having to be back on
the farm to pull the tarp at night and
so you know it was like that's just for
the birds right there so so automation
was the next step and you know really
you know looking into commercial AG and
seeing what's already existed because as
we know like we didn't for the most part
we're not inventing anything new in this
industry a lot of what we're doing is
we're just borrowing things that have
already been successful in other
industries and we're making it work for
cannabis right because yes cannabis is a
plant but for all
those people that say it's just another
plant and you grow it just like the
others you know I feel those people
haven't really grown cannabis so that
was a that was back you know four and
then started the company in oh six and
as far as I know is the first cannabis
exclusive greenhouse company in the
world back in 2006 and again you know we
know people were pulling tarps that are
put in refrigerator boxes over plants
like it was happening but it was the
first time that it was really looked at
is how do we make this a commercial
viable product for a viably commercial
industry and and so really back in the
day was just you know working in the
quasi-legal medical scene and just taken
every penny and throwing it into
starting a company you know where so
many of my friends were just buying
property after property and trucks and
vacations and all these things I was
just dumping it all into into figuring
out how to how to move this move this
forward and here we are today you know
super grateful and grateful super great
everybody
never let me pay his salary one day late
so I'm super grateful for Eric man we
wouldn't be here today without all your
work and all your dedication and your
are you know give it up for free mr.
Branstad the OMB and so you know really
today it's it is the future of the
industry you know and I think it's
really up to us you know because on so
many levels you know I just really have
this this feeling you know there's a big
circle right of the cannabis industry
and within the cannabis industry is a
smaller circle of the cannabis community
those of us that have really you know
given everything to make this happen
and neither of us can exist without the
other at this point
you know it takes the industry to
provide the efficiencies the finances
the network's if you will to to really
bring this into not only a national but
a global market but it takes the
community in order to teach these folks
how we do things and bring the knowledge
of the plant and bring the knowledge of
the cannabis community into what we're
doing so that we can really have that
impact on the world and you know really
use business as the religion that it is
today because it is the religion that
rules the world today and I don't see
any problems with corporations I don't
see any problems with business but if we
can bring you know the the knowledge the
sacredness and the the community that
we've all built into it then we have the
opportunity to change this world in a
heartbeat you know and really bring
forth you know everything that's going
on because what we're really doing is
we're growing crystals right and
crystals carry knowledge and information
and intelligence and so if we can every
time we're growing a plant in bed those
crystals with the knowledge that we want
to go out that's going to go you know I
always used to love to think of late
whenever you harvested a crops of where
is this going to be smoked like I know
this one guy is bringing a half pound
over to Hawaii and these people are
bringing in an eighth with them over to
Jamaica or wherever it is and so we're
spreading that knowledge everywhere and
every time somebody intakes that then
then we've done our job of just
spreading that love just a little bit
further damn look at you guy go right on
well said
thank you yeah well uh man uh well I
mean I'm super grateful for this whole
light depp scene and these crystal
growers I'm a miner so you guys grow the
crystals and all mine the fangs and I I
appreciate the educational piece too and
I wanted to jump over to Farmer Tom real
quick because farmer Tom mentioned what
he was doing at the Community College
and the education level and I kind of
wanted you to tell us a little bit more
about that and I wanted to also ask you
about the feds one more time and so the
feds came to your house and came into
your green
somehow now with you at your place or
was this at an undisclosed location
no they came to my house holy [__] yeah
they came to my house in 2015 in August
for two days yeah okay so they came to
your house and saw your grow saw your
greenhouse saw your where you kept your
say I mean what didn't they see that no
they've pretty much ly saw you know
everything we've you know just been
medical growers for a long time now and
you know we were biding by all the rules
so I really didn't have much to hide and
you know I would have rather educated
them on kind of where the industry came
from and all of our roots and you know
we were all you know we grow organic
vegetables along with our cannabis and
for us it's more like a lifestyle a
health choice for my wife so you know
she can you know if she can't live in
the city she can't be around you know
petrochemical products perfumes any of
that kind of stuff so we created this
lifestyle and you know it's it's work
for us and having them them here they've
actually become pretty good friends I'm
in contact with them they're they're
scientists basically this is that agents
from the CDC and NIOSH in NIOSH stands
for National Institute of Occupational
Safety and Health and basically their
PhD scientists then and they wanted to
get ahead of the ball on a worldwide
platform before another group did it
these guys are the premier people on
workers safety and health and they
wanted to get a jump on cannabis and
this all really went back to Denver in
like 2011 and 12 when the police union
up there filed a complaint with OSHA
sand that they were afraid their
officers were in poisoned with molds and
stuff when they would go into these
grows the labs would be off for a couple
days and they'd be in there like
cleaning up that there would be powdery
mildews and you know black molds and
stuff like that so the Obama
administration allocated funds to do
this workplace health and safety
evaluation it's just basically
scientific study and so they came twice
we you know we and the first time was on
my it was my dime and you know I'm being
a advocate for so long I mean we showed
him we smoked around them and you know
showed him our lifestyle and the second
time was more business orientated and
they were collecting data for production
and processing so each day I did a
different task we had a total of like 70
plants that year and by the time they
came in the later part of October we had
10 left so the first day was all about
big leafing and harvesting so we
harvested the temp lamps and then big
leaved and then moved it into the dryer
and the second day was all about bucking
so we were taking the beds off of the
off of the stems form every different
way we could come from the hand to the
little tin can method to the scissors to
what which ever way we could to give
them data and then the third day was all
about trimming we had Madrid machine
trims hand trim that hooked us up with
the cyber glove that tracked repetitive
motion and collected the data and all
that data was compiled and yeah so now
it's it's a scientific study paid by the
paid for by the you know of the
government and the people so it's in the
Library of Congress and I guess you
could look it up under cannabis and
organic cannabis farm so so organic
cannabis is the keyword in that study or
what you showed them basically it was
you know coming from an organic place
and using greenhouses and things like
that it sounds like I mean it sounds
like you showed them the side that we
all kind of are all an advocate for oh
definitely I mean I wanted to show them
what we were all about and what we can
what we came from and really give them a
good perception of where we all came
from it who we really are as a community
how do I choose you again I forgot did
you say how did they actually come to
you like because you got busted a long
time ago
no no no we're in Washington State we we
did a news piece with como news they
asked me to do an open blast and I said
yes then everybody thought I was crazy
but I thought well this is a really good
opportunity to educate him on it because
they were coming to the farmers markets
at that time and their idea of hash was
one thing it was BHO and keep working on
themselves so I I go wow this is a
perfect opportunity it's like you know
it's January February and I can get like
my friends together and we'll give them
a four-hour symposium on everything
concentrates so Joe Winn did an open
blast forum outside under a tent
I had farmer Joe Parker doing a closed
loop system inside and we had samples of
bubble hash of course and co2 and fee CO
and and that kind of stuff to kind of
show him that wow there's a lot more
here than just BHO and when you when you
ban all concentrates all you're really
doing is you know these kids will
continue to blow themselves up so it's
better to tax it or regulate it and so
that that kind of led to me getting some
exposure up here on concentrates and
then a kid the kid blew themselves up
and a BHO explosion in New Mexico and
then the Union got in touch with me and
then we got in touch with OSHA and then
I took him over to JD's from skunk farm
research we spent afternoon educating
them about hydrocarbons and why these
kids were blowing themselves up and from
that they picked me and my wife because
we had already interacted with them to
do the health hazard evaluation it was
initiated by the Union and you see these
are punitive type things you know like
we're gonna come in and find out you
know what your industry is up to you but
after talking with them and we were the
first ones you know I figured man we
might as well just go in there and lay a
baseline I'd rather it be me than some
suit in a you know in some other
location so we we agreed to do it they
they made my farmers secure location and
I had to pretty much be vetted by the
DOJ to grow cannabis we went through a
lot of Hoops the Obama it was actually
finished in 2016 and at that point April
2016 and went up I guess online for a
few hours and then they pulled it down
because it was an election year and then
they kind of kicked the ball to August
and August said oh it's an election year
it's kicked the ball to November
November comes around they go we got a
new administration let's kick the ball
to February kicked it to February of
2017 and they go oh we've got a new
appointee for the Department of Health
and Human Services we're gonna kick it
till April
I contacted James couch who's the chief
scientist on it we were you know were in
contact I called him he said he was on
home and maternity leave that day and he
didn't have any updates on it but the
next morning the box showed up overnight
at button at my door it had I don't know
four or five reports and then posters
that we can hang in our workplace
basically of what they found and what
they suggested so and then like I said
on April 7th it went up on online again
and then in August I got my own website
and in between that we I've gotten
emails from them saying that cal/osha is
using this is their baseline for
workplace health and safety they're
using the report that you know our SOPs
that you know created the report so yeah
that's how we that's that's kind of what
we did with them that's pretty much the
whole story well it's amazing Tom I've
been wanted to kind of hear that story I
know I've seen you and known you for a
while but I never really get a chance
we're always so busy and then so to jump
back into the greenhouse talk a little
bit more I wanted to go over to Josh and
Kelly they've been patiently waiting as
our hosts and they're good at being
patient with some of these things and so
now I wanted to jump into some more
greenhouse talk on the wall apini side
of things and also you guys got a hoop
house this year too and so you know what
have we been seeing in the wall apini
what are we seeing in the
greenhouse you know especially up where
you guys are and your special climate
like tell us a little bit about the
closed-loop farm and your greenhouses um
first of all I'm Jonathan thank you so
much you know brother
love everything that you have to say and
really bringing it back to the fact that
you know we are growing crystals we're
growing sentient beings we're affecting
people's lives every single day with
every single smoke that we put out every
bud we could be affecting their lives as
a whole or just that minute so it's just
so important to you know thank you for
that so on on our land we have five
different greenhouses we live far up
north in the mountains we're in a big
mountain canyon and we don't get full
Sun exposure every day so we really have
to take advantage of our sons are of the
sunlight and when we light up we usually
are light to Epping right around the
time when the sun's hitting the mountain
even in the middle of the summer so
luckily we don't get a really a lot of
heat in there you know towards the
evening of stuff but we have five
different greenhouses a circular one
that's submerged into the earth about
nine feet and then a really long wall EP
knee that's forty by seventy that's dug
it's on a hillside and on the back wall
it's ten feet in the ground and in the
front walls around six feet to the to
the ground and it's got a big flat an
angled roof on it and we also have a
hoop house that we got from forever
flower and we've gotten lots of
equipment from forever flowering for our
other stuff but we also build
greenhouses from from wood and local
materials from our land what really
works for us best is a flow-through
style design for our greenhouse we do
get a lot of rain in the summer and also
we can get it really early in the fall
so we really like to use our greenhouses
and utilize it more as a roof without
ever tree you know our walls never come
down in the summer we only have the
summer walls come down in the spring yes
then in the spring as soon as our
temperatures change really drastically
you know in the evening I mean as soon
as it starts to become summertime and
we're having
the hot days and cold nights because
that's what happens up in the mountains
where we are you know it's absolutely
imperative that those sides and the end
boils never get closed you know and
that's something that we've been
learning you know through time and if we
want to be able to grow these really
beautiful varieties that are really
important to get out on the market in
our northern area we have to be able to
light up and we do it old-school work
for the birds don't we like birds we
like I mean I still pull some terms
myself I know how it goes
I wanted to know do you guys use any
fans or any kind of electricity in any
of your greenhouses we really don't we
used to and we just realized that it's
really not necessary we have enough
airflow on the mountainside that we're
on just open it up and the way that the
mountains breathe is that we have like
an uptake of air in the morning time and
then a down take of air in the evening
so it really blows through all of the
greenhouses and we really suggest to
people you know that before you do the
layout of your greenhouse as you stand
on your land you find out the airflow
you find out exactly what's going on
with your son and your Moon right point
you freeze points we have frost so where
does it frost first where does a frost
second where's the Sun in the winter
where's the Sun in the summer we have to
think about that pretty pretty seriously
and we also purposefully build our
greenhouses to have a natural flow
through design and we've worked really
hard at trying to make this design work
and now we've got to a point where we
don't have fans so we're walking into a
totally peaceful environment that has
beds that are attached to the earth we
have different pieces we have different
kinds of dirt on our land so we date we
take different parts of dirt from our
land and we make dirt and we've been
layering on over the years so we have a
unique style of dirt in our that's not
non-commercial ails number one focus I'm
non-commercial and then we build a
gravity-fed greenhouse
a teahouse to feed our teas into our
greenhouses and stuff so we like having
different environments and we grow the
plants differently based off different
different greenhouse styles and we
definitely realize that utilizing
geothermal along with our greenhouses
has been a tremendous step forward for
us you know we've been we started out in
big outdoor and gorilla growing and then
moved all the way into greenhouses and
we thought that we maybe needed to have
a lot of fans and lights and all this
stuff and we're pretty much down to just
the cover and light tapping and we
really feel like we've got it figured
out now
well you guys have consulted on
greenhouses other than just where you
are as well as help design some I think
we helped you get or just provided some
materials for in Colorado and so did the
Colorado wall apini and for everybody
that maybe doesn't know while apini
greenhouses are in the earth they're you
know mostly a roof sticking up and I
know you guys have done a few different
designs the one in Colorado how did that
go unbelievable they're just so
absolutely stoked with it they haven't
had any issues in it at all it's
definitely the one that they put their
number-one strains in and the ones that
were they're really looking towards to
you know produce maybe mother plants or
or possibly four cups and they also have
a high elevation with strong winds so
you know as long as the sides and the
roof are kind of you know batten down
pretty well the Wally Feeney offers a
really good break for the wind and stuff
like that so yeah they've had a really
good time they're expanding on their
farm and getting into hemp farming doing
other things so I think it's been
helpful to their expansion and also
their tremendous differences between the
day and the night in Colorado as well
and it just really helps to put it into
the ground because you're just not
having those extremes the geothermal
sort of you know aids and that the one
thing I just I was I think we would just
like to say is that in the time work
like places like Cape Town have run out
of water in California seen severe
droughts water-saving growing techniques
can potentially outweigh the need for
you know you know being able to get five
cycles in one year because
times people use pots and greenhouses in
order to get a fast turnover rate maybe
in California so they can get five
rounds in a year and maybe that's why
they shy away from using beds because
beds you might have to let them veg for
a week or two to kind of get their roots
into the ground but it's gonna save you
up to 50 to 70% water and it's also
gonna allow your micro organisms to feed
your terpenes and turkey levels and the
crystal content and that we think that's
really valuable and also tremendous
amount you know we need to look at every
single cost right now it's so important
how can we reduce our cost and still
grow the fire you know how can we get
out a highest-quality product and
sometimes we really do need to look at
our systems fully and figure out you
know what's gonna be best for us for
sure I don't know cause just sort of
talking about you know for years I
showed people how to make hash using
water and ice and you know it's very
simple for for extracting resin but the
real real trick is to drying it and the
drying it depending on where you are
becomes a different recipe and I'm sure
with greenhouses it's the same thing
where someone might be hearing dragonfly
talk about how we just leave the sides
of the greenhouses open we're in a
different place maybe in Holland or
wherever it might not be the same thing
so for those of you that are listening
understand that each person specifically
talking is talking about their specific
environment and it may be a little bit
different depending on where you're
growing and what type of greenhouse
you're using etc so I just wanted to
mention that and that's a good point one
of the things I've learned over the 11
years I've been doing this is that
cannabis does want to be free it doesn't
want to be always trapped and when we
trap things we have to deal with
trapping air for instance when we trap
air it heats up and so one of the things
about greenhouses in general greenhouses
were invented for wintertime there
wasn't anybody on a farm on a hot summer
day that went oh I need a greenhouse and
so when we have cannabis growers
cannabis growers love to grow in a super
hot sunny spot and so what do we have we
have kind of two things that don't make
sense we have a greenhouse and this
hot-ass spot in a grower that's trying
and to grow inside of a greenhouse in
this hot-ass spot and it just doesn't
work and that's why we see a lot of the
failure rates for people in the
discouragement of green houses sometimes
is because it's almost turned into this
hybrid indoor grow room it's this idea
that we get free Sun and then the green
house is you know this controlled
environment not everybody can control
their environment so to speak
controlling an environment is timp and
humidity for the most part and yeah we
can work on the temp and humidity in the
greenhouse but we can we what can we do
about the leaf surface temperature maybe
the ground temperature the soil
temperatures all these other services
heat up as well as the air temperature
and so when we have surfaces soils
things heating up we create these
hostile environments and we create
hostile environments cannabis just gives
up and basically sends out those
invitations for bugs p.m. molds and
whatever can happen and so what we found
over the last few years no matter what
state we're in for the most part in cut
in the United States you know we we do a
lot of our greenhouses especially this
one back here our northern latitude kind
of cookie cutter because I believe
greenhouses should be flexible in the
sense that they can have winter mode and
summer mode both together and that means
the ability to open up and to close up
most greenhouses you know for the most
part run on two ways of ventilation
mechanical ventilation that's sealed up
with exhaust fans and intakes and then
there's passive ventilation with the
greenhouse ability to open up and close
the side walls and the roof vent and so
basically what happens is that you know
the Flex stability comes with having the
advantages to open the greenhouse up or
close it should you need to what we
found is that sealed greenhouse is in
the most part that are trapping air and
heating up in these hot summer spots
really have to use mechanical
ventilation because there's no other way
to exchange that air at some points the
air can keep up for the exchange rate
you know when air exchange per minute is
national greenhouse manufacture
standards but if the fans can't keep up
we have trapped air that's heating up
and then what we have is plant
transpiration which turns into
condensation in greenhouses and so
condensation is everybody's biggest fear
and if people have condensation nine
times out of ten its from plants sweat
and so what we have to do is back up and
help avoid that plant sweat and the one
way we can do that is through
cooling the surfaces and cooling the
surfaces isn't just cooling the air in
order to do that to cool the surfaces we
try to open up the greenhouse use the
proper greenhouse covers like these
diffuse greenhouse cover greenhouse
covers you see behind me and also using
things like white ground cover and
things that avoid Sun or solar gain
black ground cover black grow bags all
these things encourage a lot more
surface temp than you'd want and so by
using 10 grow bags and a white ground
cover and even a little infrared
thermometer to shoot and point and shoot
the leaf surface temperature of a plant
can really tell you a lot more than the
typical temp and humidity thermostat
that a lot of people want to look at for
the word control I guess you could say
and so you know we really want to make
greenhouses flexible we want to keep
cannabis free and then if we need to
fight mother nature we can do that
closer to the season extending or the
winter time and I know that uh one of
the things that comes up with all this
is also the quality because we can't
just get a greenhouse and go okay I'm
gonna get the killer quality and win all
the cups like J JD and you know all
these other people it really takes these
you know the correct method to the
madness along with being in knowing how
to deal with the method to the madness
in these tip these specific areas these
specific areas need these pieces of
equipment to operate how the grower
needs to at certain times of the year so
that they can actually make it work for
themselves and granted there are some
exceptions to the rules but what we saw
this year with sealed greenhouses
mechanically ventilated greenhouses that
only had the way to move the years
through the exhaust fans and the intakes
whether it's a wet wall or not even
people with wet walls had air coming in
at 75 and leaving the greenhouse at 130
degrees and most of the sealed
greenhouses that we talked to this year
didn't have the fans calculated properly
so they did have solar gain which
created that hostile environment and the
last thing that happens is if you lose
electricity you're screwed and so a
passively ventilated greenhouse can help
avoid problems if you do lose
electricity and you know something maybe
everybody could answer on real quick is
is that you know I see a lot of people
talk about you know indoor being better
than sun-grown endure being better than
greenhouses I mean some of the
greenhouse material I've seen is is hard
to compare to Endor it's hard to know
the difference and so there are
consumers out there that don't really
know the difference they just want good
weed and then there's also the retailers
let's say that are really trying to
stick with indoors better than Sun
ground and then they change the price or
they make the price lower does anybody
see any this going on in their farms or
pricing or who they deal with as far as
Sun grown or greenhouse versus indoor
and prices wise well I just want to say
really quickly I think what happens on
the market is anytime anytime light to
ever green house is super good it'll get
marketed as indoor just because it get
if that's is that higher price all right
and so I think it's really doing a
disservice to the green house like that
sector of the market but at the same
time I mean you can't really blame
people for wanting to get a better price
or actually move their product you know
so it's it's kind of a conundrum and
that's where I think it comes down to
you know constantly comes back to to
education you know and and I think is we
still are getting more lab results and
more scientific studies are being done
you know we're really able to start
seeing you know what terpenes are
brought out by it by sunshine you know
where does UV come into the factor you
know and and so one thing I just wanted
to say about growing in the greenhouse
though going back is you know really
again comes back to having a proper
greenhouse design you know I've been
living up and growing in the Sierras
here for you know well over a decade and
decade and a half up here in the Sierras
and we get up into the hundreds pluses
and I've never had an exhaust fan on my
greenhouse I've never had a cooling
system on my greenhouse and I think a
lot of people are being steered into the
direction of thinking that they need to
have HVAC systems or wet walls to really
or even high-pressure fogging systems to
mitigate something that doesn't
necessarily need to be mitigated for
coming from an indoor environment people
are usually focused on
what's the temp and humidity what's the
temp in humidity and that's all that
they're looking at but once you get into
a greenhouse you really have the ability
to start looking at leaf surface
temperatures at root zone temperatures
and that's where we really start getting
into you know the true growing
environment for the plants and so the
ambiance of the greenhouse can be super
hot but if that if you get the cooler
temperature is down on the leaf and in
the root zone you can actually go around
having to have any sort of mechanical
cooling and such as but you know as long
as you've got that proper passive
cooling and you've got a high quality
material such a sun's coming through a
lot of people like to skimp on on their
greenhouse cover and put up some sort of
like visqueen or you know just a single
layer poly but really that's what the
sun's coming through right and so that
is that's your separation between your
source of the plant growth and the plant
and so really one of the best things
that a person can do and the the most
cost-effective to improve their
greenhouse is to just put a proper cover
on it if you have a poly weave cover
that's got a high diffusion level and
even blocks out of a minor amount of the
Sun to really soften the light you're
gonna have plants they get more blingy
because they're not in the harsh
environment of the Sun just beating down
on them and they're not in a visqueen
material which is actually focus are
magnifying the light and creating hot
spots within within the greenhouse
environment and as soon as you have that
hostile environment that's when molds
mildews pests and diseases are gonna
move in because your plants not healthy
so it's basically sending out this
message of I need to be decomposed right
and so nature's just coming in and like
oh we're just gonna take this one out
this one's not healthy and so it really
comes back to creating that beautiful
growing environment both in the air and
then in the soil but that's like a whole
nother rant right there anybody have any
comments on the using the greenhouse
shavon we haven't heard from you a
little bit tell us about your greenhouse
in style you guys Manuel Deb
well currently four blessed coasts
we're pretty lacking to be honest but my
background in greenhouses was my dad did
black box and I moved into greenhouses
as the market was still getting prices
for indoor for death for that
yeah you black box that was awesome yeah
so but but I mean that was dad you know
but I then moved into just falling in
love with the fact that it was outdoor
and I could be producing high-quality to
sell perfect but no we need greenhouses
for blush goes so so hopefully that'll
be happening this year but I missed my
days of plonk tarts I'll be completely
honest you know it was there was a
comment made about the trash and the
just get a proper green house
essentially that was the biggest thing
that really killed me about this
industry was the trash and so I'm happy
that we're moving into you know a better
slate for that but also Jonathan I
wanted to say thank you for bringing up
Dennis Peron honoring that and honoring
our forefathers in this in this yes
thank you all so I think that the
leaning towards the testing comment was
also really where we're going with this
we're really gonna have to step it up as
far as cleanliness and greenhouses and
hay crystals
black box each plant or was that just a
term that he used they dug theirs into
the ground and then covered it that's
awesome because my first experience in
humbo was in 92 93 and people were
actually using cardboard boxes to
individually black box each plant and so
that's where the term black box and kind
of came from yeah yeah I remember those
okay no this is in the ground also
called a pdh pretty dug hole just in
case
yeah when I was up there everybody was
calling it black boxing and black boxing
the weed actually sucked I mean it was
really terrible looking herb at the time
because the people that I was dealing
with were really young and we were all
just you know like what is this what are
we doing and everybody it wasn't very
organized at all and there was no elders
guiding anybody along the way we didn't
have our family up there for sure and so
I recall it going back to outdoor and
yeah it kind of converted it and then
the whole greenhouse and death I mean it
just the market you know changed
everything up that was so interesting
I missed the days of pulling tyre exciti
rattle snake snake stories and like I
would love an automatic green house
because first rattlesnakes book and
flying pretty early I don't think people
understand when you when you have a tarp
laying on the ground for a day in the
summertime snakes and all kinds of
things get into that tarp and then when
you go pull the tarp it the tension of
it makes everything spring out of the
tarp and so you can find rattlesnakes
and mice and all kinds of stuff and I
mean pulling tarps yeah it isn't just
the pain in the ass of actually pulling
the tarp it's like what's hiding in the
tarp it didn't get rained on as full of
puddles yeah I dunno you know I want to
complain about I miss it I miss it I
miss riding dirt bikes and having you
know a good time I'm I'm coming to you
guys now from my office because I'm so
fancy but yeah what it would a crazy
ride to to be on and what an interesting
topic the whole greenhouse effect so
yeah thanks for inviting me on yeah it's
good to have you and yeah I mean you've
been around it for a while so I mean the
history that you that I talk about you
definitely know and that was the thing I
talked to some people over the course of
the years and the people that went to
Humboldt in the 70s
were black boxing in order to sex plants
and so they would actually use boxes all
over the little plants to sex and before
they put them out into the field and so
like DEP greenhouse light DEP black box
lighten up in general has been part of
the history of cannabis you know for a
really long time longer than I know and
I've traced it back like I said into the
70s of Humboldt County and so it's
really you know great to be here in a
sense the you know all these years later
I'm in a company in a the presence of
all these people doing this light DEP
thing and it's really like you know part
of the culture now it's blunt yeah its
but it's blowing up and so does anybody
have any other points they want to bring
up yeah I wanted to say really quickly
Eric and and to everybody is that I feel
like and all of us probably could relate
to this too is that you know talking to
consumers in the market you know the Sun
grown and the light depth makes you feel
better it just does when you smoke
something that's from a light depth not
only is it beautiful and flavorful and
it has a lot of terpenes but it makes
you feel better it makes you be ready
for your day
you know it resembles more of where that
plant came from rather than coming from
an indoor space you know like you all
are saying earlier with a lot of the
lights and the buzz and the vibration
and the electricity so I really wanted
to say yeah and also moving over it is
the weather also the diffused light is
really important in California I think
of Southern Oregon I think the light the
sunlight gets too hot and it can blast
the the plants and the buds and the
terpenes are volatile on the plants even
when they're growing so sometimes I mean
people are exploring you know having
shade cloths in their greenhouse in the
middle of the day in Southern Oregon and
Northern California Southern where it's
super hot and there's even some misters
and stuff being used above it to
continue having the right type of
humidity that it takes to grow crystals
and and then you know there's all kinds
of different light spectrums and come in
but one thing we're exploring is uvd
which is putting a disco ball in our
greenhouse yeah and that really brings
on the fall you know just check into
that that's all they're gonna say
I'm gonna get a disco ball and hanging
in here just for you guys and see what
kind of Terps we we bring up Sam I don't
know you I would be interested to hear
about your progression of you know
greenhouse growing and some year maybe
you're like deprivation experience yes
where is it on it's on howdy howdy
uh I've been grown in greenhouses ever
since the first year I grew cannabis in
Santa Cruz that was in maybe 70 72 or
something route like that and that was
just a homemade primitive greenhouse
what's and friends of mine were doing
darkening for sexy not for flowering but
for sexy and that was in Northern
California but one of the problems with
the sexing was at that time they didn't
really understand what they were doing
so they would darken it for two weeks
until the plant showed sex
whereas well the research that I found
when we were doing the research in
Holland was that most indica varieties
you can darken for one day and then two
weeks later they will show sex they and
they were not staying long and with with
vege with a uh excuse me with sativa
varieties sometimes they need to be
darkened two or three days at the very
most but then two weeks later they show
the sex gist and so it's I mean I had a
friend who produced thousands and
thousands of seedlings and then darkened
them off just for sexing to sell early
known female plants to people and a few
times he because he darkened up for two
weeks
they would not come back so the
customers were rather irate that they
had these little plants that were you
know two feet tall and flowered off and
they would not return veg can you also
tell the story of how you discovered
like greenhouse light death in
greenhouse light death what happened was
I went into a court anthem of greenhouse
uh cuz I was interested in building my
greenhouse or or buying one or renting
one or whatever and so I saw the kiss
anthems were being darkened to induce
flowering and I a light went on in my
head and I let Jesus Christ I mean I had
seen people darken plants with a tarp in
the late seventies and early eighties
but I wasn't interested because I I
wanted a greenhouse that was multiple
acres and you you you can't hand Arkin
multiple acres well actually you can if
you have enough labor but it's so that's
I saw what darkening could do I
instantly understood what this was for
cannabis and so that was I don't know
maybe 86 or something like that and what
once I saw that yeah I never stepped
back for for the Netherlands you need
darkening because you you can you can
grow multiple crops a year or you can
grow one big good heavy crop and darken
it and get it out before the cold it
comes and your heating bills are ten
thousand not what it's a day a week and
can you also comment Sam on earlier Mick
was talking Michael was talking and he
mentioned how he kind of likes to keep
them a little bit smaller which might be
perfect for what he's doing and and
producing super high quality flowers but
you came in as a sort of like oh I'd
like to have really big greenhouses and
maybe just talk to wire that is well the
main reason is is I like big plants a
lot of the work I'm doing is not
commercial production its breeding work
and for breeding work I start seeds
thousands and thousands of seeds and
then what I do is I I want to pick the
best plants and 2bic the best plant from
seed it's very difficult to do with a
little 1 or 2 foot plant you grow at 12
feet tall you get a really good idea of
its positive and negative qualities
for for a breeder it's it's really
required so I that's why I had a very
high ceiling my ceiling was well maybe
20 feet or so and I could grow 15-foot
tall plants if I want get 3 4 or 5 kilos
of dried material let me ask you Sam
about the sexy one more time you know
for people that are you know maybe don't
have a lot of power still in Humboldt or
you know these craft farmers if they
were to sex their plants like you were
saying how long if it was it's depending
on strain you would say but if somebody
was to do it would you say to darken it
for a day or two instead of the two
weeks like your yeah because I
experienced the same thing I've seen
plants that didn't come back out of the
veg and it was a huge pain in the ass
could you talk a little bit more about
that like your recommendation is my mic
on
okay then the main thing is that
cannabis will take two weeks to express
its ex but one or two days of darkening
is enough to trip the expression two
weeks later that's the main thing you
have to understand with earlier
varieties only one day if it's a very
late late equatorial variety maybe it
takes two or three days at the very most
and then when you put them back on long
cycle two weeks later they sex but they
don't stay flowering base are totally
veg and you grow them really really big
and then fly them off and you know what
sex they are that's almost like at the
end of that you should also say you're
welcome because that was a gem right
there absolute change er thank you for
dropping that knowledge yeah that's all
I needed
talk to you guys later
no that was awesome Mike did you I saw
you were gonna chime in a little bit ago
were you about to drop some wisdom on us
well I don't know if I'd call it wisdom
but I was gonna say something it was
gonna follow Sam rule yeah Jesus him and
Jonathan are hard to follow y'all come
on you go now what was I gonna say him
it was about you were talking about and
Jonathan kind of commented on the
difference between indoor looking
quality and how you will be pricing
pricing and stuff like that right so I
think that that light deprivation when
done right can absolutely compete with
the indoor market both in the testing
results and also the way bag appeal the
way it looks and we did this kind of fun
little test with the friend of ours this
last year where we gave him some of the
same cuts we were running same nutrient
program everything that we were doing he
ran it indoors we ran it in a light
deprivation and we tested it at the end
of the year and we ended up being higher
on the THC test and you know everything
else that that we both tested for which
was basically the TAC thing was the with
the competition so sometimes when I hear
people talking about the indoor there's
no way you can compete with the indoor
market I think that's a false I think
that I've you know and I agree with what
the people at Dragonfly were saying is
that it everything about it's better
it's grown naturally in the Sun case
better better for you and and then when
it with pricing you know like with with
what um and this is just kind of my my
personal opinion or whatever I think
that you know in California which is
where I'm not you know I don't know if
everyone's in California or not but you
know there's a big hiccup in the market
right now with what's going on and we've
got this big change in regulation and
dispensaries and all this other stuff
that's going on and it's hard to compete
with the indoor market especially in
Southern California but I think that
what could end up being the savior to
what we're passionate about sun-grown
farming is I think that with pricing
going up the way that it is these people
that are going into dispensaries and all
the sudden see in there
the price tag being you know 80 90
dollars for
for the 8 that they used to get for 45
or 50 bucks
is definitely going to be a way that I'm
hoping some grown farmers can survive I
think it's going to be a positive for us
well yeah educate educate sorry you know
what I mean like Conan we can't we
quantify things with lab tests sometimes
because I know that I've talked to a few
lab companies that have said over the
course of time some of the greenhouse
material they've been testing has has
tested to higher and the THC CBD and
even the terpene percentages and I know
that the terpene companies bubble man
maybe you might know something about
that with greenhouse material and the
terpene production that you might have
heard about or known yeah okay yeah you
know right from Tony's mouth almost
always the light that the greenhouse is
going to produce like a way higher level
of Turkey in production you know not
just a smaller amount but like a
substantially larger amount and not to
change the subject completely but while
I have the mic one of the things Sam was
mentioning about greenhouse triggering
flowering as well particularly in I
guess it was in like close to the
equator countries where they have 12
hours and 12 hours of light and darkness
and often people are trying to grow with
added lights additional light they'll
maybe put it on for another five or six
hours Sam had an interesting bit of
information to share on that tropical
cannabis growing yeah that's basically
what we found is that but even in the
Netherlands when I would grow big giant
plants at 1012 feet tall over the winter
I could give as little as I was using
these little 60 watt blue incandescent
agricultural balls from Philips and so
they were geared towards but but they
were only 60 watts
I would use one of those for every ten
square meters so that's a hundred square
feet and it absolutely prevented
flowering not not only that but you
could use as little as just in the
instead of giving them six or eight
hours of light to keep them badge what
you could do is just in the middle of
the night give them two hours of light
that's all they needed I'll just yeah
I've been doing this for thirty years
that's a big one for people that have
been especially in countries where you
know he was mentioned like only having
one generator only being able to turn on
enough light in one section of the
greenhouse if you do a quarter here a
quarter there a quarter there and
instead of leaving it on I'll just tell
you how severe I've done it I actually
was storing plants under refrigeration
at about plus three four degrees so
they're in a frigerator with lights and
all's I gave them was 15 minutes of
light four times a day so every five
hours I'd give them four five or six
hours
I give them 15 minutes of light totally
prevent a flower and they stayed badge
they also weren't growing because it was
so cold all I was trying to do is keep
the plants alive as the library did you
see that there was any reduction in
actual growth growth practically they'd
under under three degrees there's
practically zero growth mmm I wasn't
trying to grow them I was trying to
maintain them yeah yeah but Mike I guess
my question is is you know I think some
people would argue will they keep all
these lights on because not only do they
want to keep the photo period going but
they're also trying to have the plant
grow at the same time so I'm just
curious if you saw any difference at any
point oh and your and your experiences
where there you could see like a
difference in growth growth rates the
more lumens and the more hours of course
you're going to get more growth of
course but that wasn't my goal my goal
was to I had big plants in the ground
which I conserved in my greenhouse
had a small collection on on Mpho tables
under under halides and just as a
library and I had a third collection in
I had specially made like a refrigerator
with lights built into it which and in
those I I gave them as little as an hour
a day it broken up in 15 minutes
so that they never received really long
periods of dark at any one time awesome
thanks for sharing that yeah I just met
a guy in Humboldt a lot of my research
comes from old old-school growers in
Humboldt County and they said the same
thing Sam was saying as far as keeping
the plants and veg the guy came here
recently and did a greenhouse tour and
he goes no I only have my light on in
the middle of the night for one hour in
the wintertime to keep him in veg and I
thought one hour and so yeah
to save on generator and power and all
these things that people deal with they
can't use all this electricity or access
to it maybe in the middle of the night
you know so when he told me that in the
veg period he that he only uses the
light for one hour in the middle of the
night I was just like holy crap and now
I'm starting to hear little bits and
pieces of it and then of course now Sam
is kind of confirming that whole thing
too so I mean I'm gonna try it you know
like I think it's pretty cool I want to
try the sexing stuff and play around
with all those things I like doing
experiments and less time less lumens
maybe two hours to prevent flowering
right so keep that in mind is your sort
of recipe as you get into it well yeah
because sorry so that I'm just I just
want to make sure I'm here and you're
right so the thought process is don't
don't give him a long period of no light
you're saying just break it up and
you're turning the light on for 15
minutes every hour I've heard that and I
know Sam was saying that for his library
and part of his experimentation was to
keep
these plants from growing but to keep
the library and so he said he'd dosed
him in a couple times 15 minutes at a
time if I heard you right Sam and then
two hours and what he were just
confirming was the two hours for a low
lumen light right exactly and that's
what I think up and humbled the guys
using like a thousand watt light just I
don't know how many or whatever but he
does this burst of light for one hour so
I'm imagining if it's one hour working
for him it's probably a higher powered
light I should ask him but that was how
he dealt with power concerns and
generators and all these things because
he was laughing at all the people that
run generators for a few hours in the
morning a few hours at night they're
getting fuel deliveries you know every
week out to their mountain and you know
this dudes using the light one time and
and his bro both rate seems to be fine
for what he's doing because again a lot
of people are trying to just keep their
plants in check and then the Sun does
the production yeah that's really
important to keep everything efficient
you know we're talking about water and
now we're talking about ways to save
electricity and that's the biggest thing
about the greenhouse is to try to become
more efficient so you know utilizing
less light within the greenhouse any way
we can is super super important thanks
for that Sam that was sweet and create
that conversation is important as far as
you know terpenes and stuff I mean
that's most definitely what we find and
we even try and really sell our urban El
possible and as greenhouse and we we
almost force it you know and people are
like well you know people are dead at
added I'm like well guess what people
can learn now that this is how sweet it
looks
we've even not sold it if somebody was
going to sell it as indoors yeah well
actually it's been important to us that
really beautiful amazing gorgeous smelly
flowers can be grown under the Sun and a
light depth situation even as far north
in British Columbia and it's not just a
California thing or Colorado or whatever
in Washington that happens in Oregon and
that we've even sent we had our and we
entered it into the High Times Cannabis
Cup in Denver the first legal one first
legal year and it was Green House wheat
from our place and we kind of like used
gnomes the Nome Express and and we got
in the top ten indoor-outdoor was just
the collar time and boom there we were
to size up on the big screen we didn't
even go to the to the thing decide you
know we'll see and when we told Danny
Danko that it was BC greenhouse he
almost fell over it was really uh
beautiful own and we were walking around
there for the weekend we were kind of
smoking a bunch of people speed we were
like you know there's not like actually
that much flavor and a bunch of this
stuff so I think that you know we might
actually do pretty good and so we did
but so I think hearing has a lot to do
with it - but the greenhouse effect is
an effect it means something flavors
important to people I mean let's let's
you know I mean that's that's the main
things being able to open the bag and
smell it is one of the first things that
everybody looks for if it doesn't have
any smell it's not gonna go much further
than that and so you know obviously
curing is a big part of the process for
everybody and you know you can see Jason
in the background there it looks like
you got some [__] drying right now and
yeah the whole curing process is really
crucial to retain those terpenes but you
know you're also growing up north on the
islands and kind of places that you know
most people would probably say that it
would be difficult it is and you know a
lot of people laughed at me when I
talked about getting the greenhouse in
western Washington I was I was
definitely the first customer of
northern ice gardening picking up a
greenhouse and just to just to add to
the terpene conversation you know we we
want a an award for you know highest
level of Turkey there's lime money in
our in do fish
terkoz and you know just you know with
the with the market being so focused on
THC and you know that like if it doesn't
test over 20 you know stores don't want
it
but now there's kind of a little bit of
a shift with people wanting to see
chirping results almost on the test on
the label and I think I think as
customers as people in general get more
educated you know that the terpene
levels are really in a lot of cases I
think more important than THC levels and
you don't really get that so much I mean
no strain and growing methods at all
plays into it no matter what buyer but
but when it comes down to it sunshine
it just gives higher levels of terpene
to feel the high everything the sunshine
just you know coming from so many years
of indoor growing and then really about
I've got maybe three four years of
greenhouse growing under my belt I just
I love smoking greenhouse weed more so
there's just there's just a different
level to I think I agree I mean I know
that also some of the things that I
learned from your project that other
people can probably help with is that
you know you bought your greenhouse
going into winter time so you
technically didn't need your light
deprivation system and so you save six
months and then then when I got enough
bread together
I bought the greenhouse light def system
separate and put that in for the summer
so yeah I think that's a great way to
look at things because I try to you know
in some ways help people when they're
buying their greenhouses because budgets
are always a concern and so I always
kind of reflect to your story of you
know applying the money when you needed
it and you know there is light pollution
plans or a process is going into place
so not everybody can do what you did but
you did have kind of a funny story about
when you lit up your greenhouse one of
the neighboring apartments I had I had
Sheriff Department I had the fire
department literally with the with the
bolt cutters ready to cut the chain on
the gate but the fire chief just
happened to have kids going at the same
school and you know we've always been
open with wherever our kids have gone to
school like hey look we grow weed we're
legal
but if our kid smells like it you'll
just know that it's not intentional well
yeah that saved our ass for sure and but
yeah I mean without the without the
cover in the early morning or the
evening with a bunch of PhDs run and
it's a yeah you quit the glowworm
yeah so so the light that curtain is a
good thing to have for sure and not
everybody can do that because of the
light pollution plans that are needed in
place but things like heat if people are
setting up their greenhouses and they're
gonna be running at springtime you
definitely probably won't need the
lights and the and the heating system as
much so you save a couple bucks they're
just just a comment on that specifically
on some of these you know dark days in
the Northwest winter raining sideways
gray skies for weeks on end you know
rather than running a heater I'll close
that curtain and you know it's also
known as an energy curtain so it keeps
it keeps the the warmth in the in the
greenhouse and you know with just you
know 15 Gavita is running with with that
cover closed I don't need I don't need a
heater and you know at night I've got
the be huge London so generally speaking
it it stays right where it needs to be
you know when I open up that curtain in
the same temperature you know it might
drop down to 60 whereas with the curtain
closed and the lights running along
right there at like 75 76 degrees so
it's there's a lot of advantages and a
lot of different things that you can do
curtain you know without without them we
could just block out light it's just
keeping that environment keeping keeping
the temperatures and humidity and
everything bad I just wanted to comment
on on the idea of light pollution
and you know just bringing it back to
being a responsible farmer you know is
we really do we really should consider
you know when we are running lights at
night the the type of light pollution
that we're creating you know and in some
counties and some municipalities it's
actually part of regulations that you
have to have a blackout system in order
to enclose that light because not only
do the curtains keep the light out but
they keep the light in as well and as
you said Jaso like there's so many more
uses you can you can utilize without
because a greenhouse itself isn't
necessarily it doesn't necessarily have
our value to it right you know but but
when you utilize that energy curtain now
not only are you cutting down the volume
of air that you need to to warm or take
some of the humidity out of but but but
you're creating this this this energy
conserving area right and so that brings
me to the conversation of you know
people that ask a lot like should I use
a dual poly system with air running
through it you know or some way to trap
the heat in the middle of it right and
and really what we see is again you know
you shouldn't really be looking at your
greenhouse skin as your as our value as
your as your ability to hold in heat
plus what's happening you know is as sun
lights coming through if you've got say
an 85% transmissive cover that then has
a gap of air and then another 85%
transmissive cover so you've got 85% of
the light coming through and then 85% of
that light coming through and now
there's a need to start turning on
lights because you're not getting the
type of lumens that you need and so it's
you know it can be a really fighting
against the the flow on that level plus
in the summer time if you have that that
dual system as well now you've got an
area that's trapping heat and all you're
trying to do is get rid of heat right so
yeah the the curtains can be used once
on so many levels I I tried the double
cover on a different system just a hoop
house and for the wintertime you know it
does it does trap
it does create you know a little bit
more efficient running at the expense of
needing to run more lights because yeah
you know you're down with like 70%
versus versus just 85% so yeah there's
pluses and minuses for you know all
these different systems for sure do you
use a lumen meter at all to to judge
whether your plants are getting the the
kind of growth rate that you're looking
for in your greenhouses um I do I do use
a lumen meter but not necessarily for
that in particular you know I take what
I can get the lumen meter though I would
I would run around and you know at zero
lumens there's there's enough light for
humans to see but no not necessarily for
plants so I would use that lumen meter
as kind of a you know a meter for when
do I pull my tarps at night you know and
that's a good point too and they have an
app on your phone now called light
editor yeah so the light meter apps
pretty handy and that's when I find out
if it's dark or not and a lot of people
wonder or try to say oh you got to be
there exactly the same time every day
you can't have a pinhole of light leak
you can't it's just oh my god and it's
so unforgiving and your plants are gonna
harm and all hell and it's like now you
can be late I skip five days one time
not in a row but five days over the
course of a whole round I had lots of
light leaks over time I made sure the
light meter set zero if it says zero
you're good I mean I'm not advocating
being lazy and having tons of light
leaks and that kind of [__] but I've
definitely pushed the limit to really
see you know where the variances are
sometimes and I mean I think the plants
are pretty dang forgiving and most of
the myths and the things that we are
afraid of in cannabis come from indoor
technology and that isn't a slight
indoor growing it's just when there's a
light leak we don't find it for a week
or three we don't fight you know it's
just it's a little different in light
DEP greenhouse as it gets dark
mother nature is on yourself
yeah and something that we noticed too
is that we never had any firming or
anything like that or even Fox tailing
any problems we always had like you know
light leaks and all different kinds of
things you know we maybe weren't always
on time just the way that the day was
going and then we started putting in
like some equatorial landraces and some
of the old school land races and then we
really started noticing that if there
was even a teeny tiny lightly in there
that those ones were really going to go
off and we were having Herning like
immediately yeah we we had an Acapulco
gold in particular that was just getting
towards the end of its flower and then
just totally revenged its
its flower bud and stuff and it was just
a little bit of light that really kind
of triggered it to make that happen it
was interesting we noticed that with all
of our land race trains so if you are
doing genetics you know it probably is
important we're really learning about
having it totally tight but most of the
time it doesn't really make a difference
you know got to be on it but no it does
help to have a black yeah oh for sure
that brings up a good point that you
know I've had my own experience but I
like to hear everybody else's feedback
is two different strains for different
cycles in the year you know we talk
about you know three cycles in the death
house or five cycles
I've had my own experience where I can
see a variance in what genetics to use
in each cycle anybody else like to
comment I'll not I I would I would have
to say coming from an indoor grower
background you know I I would never skip
a beat and it's like you pulled a room
down you clean it you stock it right
back up and if you've got a good if
you've got a good you know seven and a
half to eight week plant you know
there's really no reason in a more
indoor or greenhouse that you shouldn't
be able to get six crops a year you know
if you're if you're running something
that's you can pull down in forty-nine
days I mean you could technically
squeeze in seven so if you know if
you're on it there's no lag time you
know at least yeah so you say
we pull six a year right now
every year I mean I you know I look at
it I look at it like this if you have
you know if you have 56 days in a cycle
if you're gonna pull down you know let's
say you're pulling down $30,000 every
every 56 days
well 56 days divided by $30,000 is you
know whatever it is I cannot but but for
every day that you're down and you're
not up and running you know you you
could consider that a loss whereas if
you're if you're really efficient you
really stay on your on your cycle I mean
there's there's no reason to not get six
and when we're all looking at and all
these new regulations and taxes and
everything we have to be smart with our
money we have to be smart with our time
be efficient otherwise we're gonna get
kicked at it again and Jonathan to
answer your question you know I
absolutely feel like genetics is
paramount to running you know multiple
cycles you know really looking into what
works in a cold colder weather system
what works better in a damper cycle
because with greenhouses and you're
lowering your costs you know and you're
not putting up all those fans and
everything you really can work with your
genetics during the seasonal times and
you know the model of getting as many
out of a season I totally understand it
and it makes all the sense in the world
and there are some formats that you can
use to just take some time off you know
and get like really good seasons you
know throughout the year and then you
know utilize your crew and rejuvenate
yourself a little bit like that but I
mean I'm not saying I hate it I'm not
we're not at all saying that as I think
you know to what you said yeah I think
josh is saying that those because we
have one a dongsang consulting with with
a lot of farms and we have really run
those numbers and people are really
trying to push you know the five cycles
and then when you start running the
numbers and the outtake and the heat or
maybe the air conditioning that it takes
to run those it's almost better well it
is it actually has been better for some
of them to take off one of those
because they've just realized that their
output is a lot more than what they're
getting out of it and one other factor
and like different and like in the state
of Oregon it's just there's a huge over
for production so just utilizing your
time you know in a way that makes senses
is a big thing but I'd also be
interested to hear what people are doing
for their soils if they're testing their
soils are doing ways to find their
selves to keep their plants efficient
and their greenhouses efficient in their
dress anyone's soil test Thanks yes we
soil test it's probably one of the best
things we could have done for our farm
we worked the soil two years and we used
dirty business soil located in Arcata
California and it just the the knowledge
that came from us being on an alluvial
floodplain was incredible the the ground
is perfect and so when I hear you guys
talking about all of the bags or
whatever I think it's sufficient to
plant into the ground
Mika's not back yet so I guess I still
have the stage but while I'm here if
anyone would like to do a video with the
gross sisters we want to hang out with
you guys more I don't know how long the
church goes today but there's definitely
topics that I've been writing down and I
would love to pick your brains later
yeah I'm sure most people are available
one form or another and yeah I mean I
definitely would love to say hello when
I come up north on my next visit lots of
people up in Humble have guest quarters
because it's not the type of area you go
to back in the day and just you know
hotels weren't always easily accessible
unless you were in Arcata
Sam had another thing he wanted to share
about talking about humans but basically
what we found is that absolutely need
lots of illumines to produce biomass and
vegetation has flowered halfway or more
and pretty much all so it's going to do
then is fill out the flowers and maybe
add a lot of weight from resin and stuff
I found lower light levels I'm talking
about from the Sun or from artificial
lights actually produce superior product
also what I found is that the high
temperatures associated with flowering
really high temperatures it's not really
positive because it has a tendency to
vaporize terpenes right on the plant so
lower temperatures a little bit lower
lumens I found produced superior product
there you go yeah I mean that's one of
the reasons that we spend a lot of time
trying to lower plant temperatures
because lowering the air temperature is
a lot harder to do and so our work has
been you know in a hundred degree days
trying to get plant temperatures down
into the high 80s if possible and it
works and the soil temps stay down too
and so you know part of that is what
we're seeing we're at the higher terpene
production coming up because a lot of
these places like I said are really high
in the air temperature but luckily for
us plants
like people we sweat plant sweat so put
me in front of a fan I'm gonna cool down
and not sweat put a fan in front of a
plant and it's gonna avoid it from
sweating and they even start to cool it
down because it's evaporative itself and
so that's where I see a lot of the
terpene and even higher THC productions
is yes softer light like samozang cooler
especially leaf surface temperature over
time and what we saw at the soil class
or the the regenerative class I did up
noir seminar with dragonfly up in
Portland last week was a guy that during
one of the discussions talked about THC
because a lot of people in certain books
and things written about you know higher
THC s high associated with higher UV and
what we see is that greenhouse covers in
general and even with glass green you
know glass being a cover a UV s can be
blocked and that's why people end up
getting a lot of PM in their greenhouses
versus outdoor plants outdoor plants
won't get PM is easy but greenhouse does
and that has a lot to do with the UVB
and so if people try to associate higher
THC with UV I'm starting to see that
that's not necessarily true and what
brings it up also in that class or the
seminar was a guy was doing testing with
LED lights and there was an LED light he
said that put off a higher UVB and so it
encouraged a higher leaf surface
temperature and they actually lost two
percent THC through testing the lights
and having those UV bees tell him that
so it it kind of associates a lot with
the Sun and how we can soften the light
to encourage higher THC and terpene
profiles and these plants and it can be
done and going back to what Jonathan was
saying about picking the right genetics
and I don't know if this has to do with
you know shitty clones over the course
of time because I was in some massive
greenhouses down in Southern California
and there was an acre or two that had
just tons of different varieties and
when you walk through the greenhouse you
can clearly see that certain varieties
did really well versus the other
varieties so it was clear for me is like
why grow these if you can just grow
those and you know it solves the problem
for that area but then again maybe they
had shitty moms and the clowns were
shitty but it literally looked like it
had a lot to do with the selective
cultivars that they were trying to deal
with at that time in that particular
area because again people are getting
existing greenhouses now and so they
might not have all the options that we
talked about and so how can we work with
existing systems to make them work
smarter not harder and all you know I
was thinking that it's really important
for people to have a small area of their
farm or their greenhouse for reached
research and development you know
running numbers and and and looking at
how we need to save money running a
little area of research and development
for genetics is really becoming
absolutely imperative what works in your
area and what doesn't I totally agree
with that and shout out to bogside
botanicals in maine they've been running
a few greenhouses of ours and they do
what they called snow dips on their hash
tags and I know they've done a lot of
research with small hoops and even
garage tents and things that we'd heard
earlier from some panelists and so yeah
I mean you can do a lot in a short
amount of time if you just do a little
bit of testing and then you know
quantify that you can do it and then
make the leap and so like I said before
a lot of the greenhouses and the things
that we see a pretty cookie cutter from
state to state coast-to-coast it's just
having that flexibility to be able to
open or close these greenhouses to you
know turn them on or off basically for a
lack of better words and support
cannabis not fight mother nature to
support cannabis but truly support it
and always possible and if we do get a
fight mother nature because there's no
Sun and it's dark and it's freezing cold
outside of obviously we want to add heat
but you know we want to be practical in
all these aspects of how we apply these
systems and are you seeing people using
shade cloths and in the heat of the day
and like for two hours say or something
like that I do and I in some cases I see
people using them in inconsistent ways
or maybe not totally in the correct
manner there is a time there is a point
of no return you know you can pull such
a shade cloth where it's too late and
you're actually going to be retaining
energy rather than helping cool the the
the leaf surfaces and things like that
I've been working with a lot of the
shade
screener now they call climate screens
now because originally they were shade
screens and so the companies we work
with create a climate screen that can be
used in various capacities and different
you know there's a whole book of samples
that I have and so depending on where
you are and what you're doing you know
we can select the proper energy slash
shade curtain but you know again the
grower has to use all these things at
the right time and appropriately so that
these things work smarter for you not
harder basically and that's kind of the
name of the game you can easily take the
word green right out of green house I'm
was wondering if we if anyone wanted to
talk about like pests in the greenhouse
and stuff because we've utilized our
greenhouse to get rid of pests and has
anyone else use that and what do they do
for that because I think that's a really
big issue in growing these days is how
to you have a greenhouse or how to go
long-term with pests and pests and
fungal management
yeah JD why don't we hear from you a
little bit what do you have to deal with
since you enter all these events and all
the scrutinized testing that you've gone
through in California do you spray and
deal battle pests and things um we
spraying when we need to kind of as a
last resort I've used heat a lot I'll
turn off the vents and on the on the
sealed greenhouse and I could run the
heat up really hot and if I run it up
over maybe like a hundred and ten
hundred fifteen degrees it seems like
it'll like start eliminating all the lot
of the pathogens you know like I've got
rid of a lot of pests we here you know
in this area you know it'll be 110
degrees outside for three or four days
running and so if you use four or five
hours a day and let it spike up up into
the 120 I mean it we've had a really it
seems to purge everything I'm here like
a lot of commercial nurseries doing that
too is just like with some of their
indoor plants it's like a lot easier and
more efficient than spraying so that's
one of the things that the greenhouse
will help with
are you spray away I like to spray with
compost tea like doing foliar tease you
know and building up that like natural
barrier on the plants so that they have
the immunity to fight it off the idea is
to not have to get into a battle with
anything which is to try to keep it in
balance the most much as possible
I am also heating up the greenhouse I
agree with you it's awesome I'm we're
really finding we're doing a tremendous
amount of research right now on
pathogens of both fungal and also pests
and we're finding that that 123 degrees
at leak temperature not just 120 degrees
and what is like going on in the outside
you know really having a temperature
gauge is absolutely imperative being
inside of the greenhouses when you're
raising it to 120 and also absolutely
giving them just like when you go into
the sauna you bring all of your teas and
your water is with you you really have
to drench those soils and get a really
beautiful tea on there that's easy to
uptake maybe some nice natural plant
electrolytes and get it up to 120
degrees and we're noticing that
pathogens die at 120 degrees and a lot
of the a lot of the beneficials will
thrive and the plant thrives at 120
degrees and we are just so thankful you
know maybe over the last 10 years
realizing about pest and fungal
management the leaves really going up
and stuff and then we hit a threshold or
they started to peel a little bit like
it a little bit too hot so we open the
sides but you have to be really careful
with the opening in the sides when you
do a heat treatment because if a wind
hits it or a direct Sun it can almost
like burn the leaves it makes us are you
really sure just that high when you heat
your greenhouse up you really have to
kind of open it slow and just let them
just kind of react limit and rebreathe
and stuff but I just want to say a fins
are a new pest that are becoming a
really big deal and there's kind of like
they're kind of different and they went
away after many hours of super hot heat
you guys ever see the ants bring the
aphids on to your plants so they could
milk them for their little sugary juices
yeah definitely it's really interesting
you know if you look at you know we've
gone into the brain of the 8th did this
last year have really taken a lot of
time to learn about Athens and what they
do and and what is happening now on the
planet and if you really look at an
aphid it's an amazing macro food for
almost every single other species this
little body it is so scrumptious it has
delicious little sugars and
carbohydrates in there you know and I
even ate one I was like okay you know
I'm really gonna do this they're
delicious they taste just like cannabis
juice so we're realizing that there's a
homeopathic dose don't know but they're
really delicious so they really make an
amazing food for other animals and other
life-forms and maybe they're coming in a
logical reason Yellowjackets eat them
and stuff so yeah you know it's
important broad mites you know we just
want to really encourage predator might
from the nursery all the way through
because you know sprays are harder and
harder to use even compost sprays and
120 degrees definitely will kill your
predators as well
your predator mites will not kill
ladybugs they love it other you know
hard exoskeleton creatures have no
problem with that much of the heat but
the small mites definitely die that's
interesting about ice is there something
to say about that
I was just commenting that using ice
water sprays on the plants will you know
cuz you'll see you'll notice mics and
russets and Rob mites all that stuff as
they take off they really thrive with
those higher temperatures so especially
with outdoor growing and you know you've
been to people's greenhouses you'll see
that so start to spread but ice water
will slow the cycle down for like two or
three you know instead of it being like
a duplication every like three days or
you can stretch that out to like four or
five and really slow down their their
duplication to give you time to get back
on top of it bubbleman I had a question
for you I started out just kind of as a
joke right here on the side but have you
ever worked with the the water from your
bubble hash and sprayed without on your
plants or if you used that to water into
your plants and have you seen anything
from that he may have just actually
loved shits I can see so that would be
interesting I mean I wonder a skunk man
Sam had anything to say about that too
but we use our ice water hash for every
single feeding you know we actually are
realizing that we're making hash now or
more for the nutrients of our plants and
to get like the leftover material into
our soil yeah even the hash I mean the
hash is now a secondary product for us
we're putting together our nursery soil
right now so we want to spin some hash
up so that we can utilize the leaf and
our soil mix and then we have a hundred
and fifty gallon tank that has a hose
coming out of it so all the water comes
out of the mingoes into 150 gallon tank
and then grab we gravity feed all that
water into our different greenhouses so
we just accumulate the terpene water in
our beds and I love it's a great idea of
course if you're making ice water hash
it's not so great to do ice water hash
necessarily in the middle of summer but
if you are spinning something inside and
you can spray a truss it might
definitely do not like that cold water I
love that idea Jonathan mm-hmm just just
as another sort of cut with greenhouses
and pest control just keeping things
kind of cold in the winter you know
there's any sort of issues you see
anything you know just turning the
heater off and letting things kind of
get a little bit colder than normal at
least in bed I'm talking about more so
but and then it just gives you kind of a
chance to get really on top of things
and they just don't bug just don't
multiplies readily when it's a little
bit chillier you know yeah it's another
reason that we like promote the radiant
heating because when you heat the soil
and heat the roots and heat the plant
itself the air temp can stay kind of
lower and you experienced that with your
geothermal your prohibition vault is
actually your geothermal heating system
for your greenhouse inadvertently and
you're able to keep those air temps down
so I mean that's really a benefit in the
in the in the wintertime too so I mean
yeah using using the environment to do
things to mitigate bugs is definitely a
good way to make the green green in the
greenhouse you know bubbleman you
dropped off for a second there but I
wanted to ask you have you utilize the
spent water from making bubble with all
of the Terps and all of the everything
that's inside of that to use as an
effective foliar or drench we definitely
played around in the early days but
never really noticed anything you know
I've my experiments were more hash
focused then grow focused and I always
seem to be lucky
you know shout out to Ron Hickey my grow
mentor from back in the day who just
always made it seem like a simple thing
to produce pull melt resin so I never
grew on a huge huge scale you know 20
lights was about where I maxed out and I
mostly really did indoor with a little
bit of outdoor sort of on my deck and
whatnot still do have the dream of
getting the forever flowering green
house behind my house that'll be 2018 or
2019 for certain but not too much
experiments other than you know a little
bit of a foliar feed and putting it
right back into the plants and it
definitely doesn't seem to do- that's
for sure what are you guys smoking on
over there in Jamaica
I'm hitting some pure artesian rosin
from Quebec little Quebec rosin a Mac
and of course we're hitting some local
Jamaican flavors as well rosin I've
always come and made bubble hash over
the years but rosin is just such a quick
and easy thing especially when you have
the Sasquatch rosin press here in
Jamaica we can just crush out a half
found in no time and make some some nice
resin so we have some you know the the
pineapple skunk or whatever they call it
the classic everything skunk in Jamaica
that's so awesome what are you smoking
on dragonfly
we have this homesteader strain that
we've crossed our temple spiced with our
zelli's gift and it's just got this
really beautiful flavor to it that has
some of the Jack Herer super Lemon Haze
Matthew's some of that original laughs
goo it comes from a father of our f who
knows how many years many many many
years that we've been working with a
particular strain and we've got this one
that we're calling the homesteader
because it's so sweet and because we
used our hash water on it that's on our
homestead but you know the I just want
to say one thing is just that when we do
use our hash water on that water it
doesn't really last very long and also
the leaf doesn't last very long when it
gets pinned up stephane up because I
don't know spinned is a word but I spun
up it tends to have a little bit of a
you know the ability to break down quick
so you know we put it right into our
soil in fact our son and our family's up
at home right now doing that right now
shout out to the crew thanks guys Matt
yeah so we're putting it right into the
soil so that it doesn't create a
breakdown and it doesn't get anaerobic
because the water on the leaf you know
can create an anaerobic thing will make
Bokashi and it by adding dry material to
it to make sure that it doesn't get too
wet and stuff so anyway utilizing it
fresh is key in the water you know just
accumulates in the soil nicely but
anyway that's cool what are you smoking
on farmer Tom what's your what's your
go-to in the throughout the day
you
muted you're muted who I muted no it's
Tom is that not had been not able to
tell there there we go
okay we're smoking I'm smoking black
wreck which is a black Durban mixed with
train wreck and mix with some amnesia
haze so that's we're like in here
that sounds good right on what about you
Sean what are you smoking on og simply
simply og okay that sounds good what
about you JD let's see it
a little rolled up for the show I've got
a living banana sherbert and just came
out of our winter round just came out
really nice super sweet and creamy good
thing track and still stay focused on
the show not good two glasses or that
sounds good since you're in the area ha
ha ha
when I was at the golden tarp I was
lucky enough to do this um judging and
whatnot and I mean I was able to know
which flower was yours once they
announced the winners because they let
us know the number but it was definitely
I think a landslide at the judges area
it was clear like it was pretty easy to
choose your flower over some of the rest
I think a lot of people in those light
dip competitions
unfortunately enter a lot of premature
herb is what I saw I saw a lot more
premature weed than I normally used to
seeing
well Jason what are you smoking on over
there um my favorite is uh this cherry
pie dough got going but um so a couple
of cuts I got from some friends just
nice donkey beautiful love it let's kill
her what about you Jonathan
you smoke on anything over there super
Silver Haze all the time you know me you
don't have any LSD going on over there
cuz I was good for a while what about my
kid what do you got in Colorado there
the strain of course you know write the
strain LSD Jonathan come on man your
mind you're on pains in Colorado with
Flav is that a leaflet yeah it is it's a
CBD strain that we did Valentine acts
and this is what I managed to get my bag
before we took off so let's kill her
that make slopes much nicer Ron well uh
I'd like to bring
back to greenhouse cultivation if I can
for a second I got a couple questions
I'd like to just throw out to the group
you know because I think a lot of a lot
of methodologies of cultivation are
changing right now because of the
removal of the plant count right because
that ruled so much of what people were
doing for so long and people didn't want
to get above 99 plants on their property
but now that we remove that a lot of
people are going with smaller plants and
higher plant counts so you know when we
talk about efficiency and of course you
know there's so many ways to look at it
really you know a lot of people are just
focused on efficiency which have a lot
of you know you know it's very practical
in the regulated market and you know Sam
was talking about growing big plants
more for you know genetics and breeding
and such and so what I'm seeing too is a
you know a big movement into rolling
benches so that you can really utilize
your footprint and have as much of your
space being grown with this little
amount of walkways going on and so some
people are going with really small
plants like 5 to 7 gallon plants and
then just able to just grow really short
plants that are about you know 18 inches
2 feet tops you know at the end with a
whole lot less labor that goes into it a
whole lot less amount of time for you
know again any molds milites pasture
diseases to move in and so you know
wondering what everybody here on the
call is having success with in the sense
of are you moving to higher plant count
smaller plants are you growing larger
plants inside of a greenhouse and and
going in that direction and maybe
vegging them somewhere else and getting
them in yeah what's your guys's
experience out there
doing higher play higher plank counts
than we were in the past we're sure now
that we don't really have to worry about
the quote unquote 99 rule for a handful
of different reasons I think that
especially with their full term stuff so
we do you know we've got some gardens
out to the sides of the greenhouses and
you know tending to a you know 16 foot
tall
outdoor plant it's super labor-intensive
and so we're trying to keep everything
that's just same height as us it's a lot
easier we do more more plants than a
nice let's watch let's watch you hit
that thing we do more plants in the
garden and we did in the past and it's
mainly great law for two different
reasons the one thing being that it's
easier when it comes to labor I think
and then the other is just I personally
feel that younger plants when you have
these big gigantic tall plants we kind
of see that there's we run into more
problems with molds and stuff at the end
of the year than we do with smaller
plants that aren't so thick and you know
in the bud setting so that's the main
thing and then in our depots yeah we
definitely don't see a green still doing
we're doing beds and all of our depots
even in our overflowing greenhouses it's
just the way it's my personal I like I
don't like moving a bunch of pots around
and pulling soil in and out of that
greenhouse all the time that might
change as we expand if we do do one of
these big greenhouse facilities I might
you know change my thinking on that just
being about we'll see yeah so more plant
more more plants and smaller plants
that's definitely what we're doing Mike
it's cool you just touched on something
that's interesting you know I was
talking about earlier R&amp;D and you know
bigger plants do have more
susceptibility we're definitely noticing
that is really awesome to grow them out
because they are these beautiful amazing
sentient beings and who doesn't love to
grow big plants and we just for those
tall ones yeah and we use that for our
research and development so what grows
well around our areas we're going to
grow those plants all the way out and oh
/ and we're gonna find out how they're
doing in the environment - you know
really work with what plants we're gonna
run for the next year what we're gonna
see doubt so picking our genetics and
there is different expressions that come
from the bigger plans so I think that
you know for us we'll always keep a
greenhouse and you know for the big
plants and stuff I know that different
regulations make people grow differently
in California you know it makes sense to
have 20 pounds at a time you know for
testing and everything and when it comes
to testing that's a cost and everything
so sometimes that's why clones are doing
batches of you know different you know
you know smaller plants and big batches
can make a lot of sense for testing and
stuff and what we're also doing now is
we're actually swapping out our
greenhouses so one half of the
greenhouse is for these huge large
plants that were utilizing research and
development in one area and then we're
doing you know two different cycles in
the other side of the greenhouse and a
sea of green so that's been really fun
to sort of swap it around going back to
pests having the smaller plants we were
able to handle them more and keep them
cleaner and moved through them quicker
and so the DEP worked anyway
I think that has a lot to do with the
plants just being in a more vigorous
state you know and especially if you're
in beds you know and if you have pots
you know if you if your plants have been
in pots for a long time and their roots
are bound you know they're gonna be more
susceptible towards towards pests and
and there's a lot of soil tests that can
prove that and bigger people need bigger
more calories it's no different for
plants you know when you have larger
people larger plants they need more
calories they're definitely going to be
up taking so much more from your soil as
well so it's really Jen rade out are
your plants producing more flowers in
the end or is the sea of green producing
more flowers and the flat that's the
smaller plants though usually those
roots are in a more vigorous growth
state as they're growing so they're
there put their flowers are more healthy
in that way Sam just had mentioned
something off camera here when we were
on mute that would you want to mention
it's am just wanted to mention that when
I grew the extent achill clone big small
even in vitro so that the flower Dolf
plant was only maybe an inch or two tall
when it was completely flowered in agar
agar in vitro in a test tube the resin
is much smaller the resin individual
resin heads on that plant when you grow
it to 3 feet tall like you're talking
about 4 C green or something the the
resin is is quite a big a bit bigger but
when I grew my same clone and it was 12
feet tall the resin was again a little
bit
that's important it's important to me we
we missed that last that last little
part but
well the the last little part was that
if your plant is 12 feet tall and you
flour it off and then you collect the
resin from that it's again a little bit
bigger than the 3 foot plant the each
individual resin head is a little bit
bigger and for hash makers that's
important and that's where we you know
don't want to outsmart ourselves you
know and and and having a place for the
bigger plants and the bigger expression
really they're they're you know
depending on what you're you're you're
growing the plants for it can make a lot
of sense so and if you are gonna bring
in one particular strain from you know
somebody that's selling clones or
something we do do really suggest to
grow it out really big if it's gonna be
something that you're gonna run and
you're gonna do a whole lotta or a whole
greenhouse over several agreement
greenhouses up it's good to see its full
expression all the way through to see
what kind of pasts or what kind of fungi
that it gets so it's interesting
listening to it all the different
perspectives
especially the resin head size I've done
I've done rooms with 24 plants I've done
them with 240 plants and the yield wise
you know it can be very similar the only
difference being the time that you've
got to spend in bed and you know if
you're spending different or if you're
edging in a different area you know it
doesn't have to affect the flowering
area but it's you know the the
regulations the plant number is going
away and they appear in Washington they
said we could you know medical we could
grow 45 plants of another said how big
they can be so you know I always did
really big plants and you know filled a
thousand square feet or 200 square feet
was good you know that's a member but I
like growing big plants and up here in
Washington it's not the best but you
know like that it it works but you know
it the same results can be achieved you
know with different number of plants
different sizes but the whole resin head
size that is interesting but it's a cool
thing to think about this year
yeah was a good one and you know I mean
one of the things that we kind of went
by to create a metric that Jonathan you
know we kind of came up with I think
through collectively responses from our
our the people we worked with basically
was that in a thousand square feet we
would say the minimum average harvest
should be fifty pounds and so you know
we have people up north that are
exceeding that number and then we have
some people most people actually under
that number I mean I know in Colorado
there's a couple facilities that are
supposedly pretty good that are running
at thirty-eight pounds per thousand
square feet and so you know originally
people went by you know how many pounds
perlite things like that and I know
grams per square foot is kind of a
popular way I think now in the indoor
category but you know like the
greenhouse on our property here it's
kind of back there but it's a 24 by 60
and it's 1440 square feet so we say the
minimum average harvest out of that
would be 75 pounds per harvest and then
you know we've seen up to a hundred and
ten but it all does come down to variety
and now with this plant count and going
into rolling benches and smaller plants
and things like that I'm kind of anxious
to see where these numbers are gonna go
if they kind of stay the same if they
increase or what but you know we're
still trying to do some fact finding on
that
I got another question to throw out to
people because this is something yeah
beautiful bed up there and BC you guys
you guys are giving love to the be stirs
you know you're redeeming yourselves you
know I think all BC should give love to
Kelly and Josh because they're redeeming
the B stores up there thank you thank
you we'll take that there's a lot of
good family up in British Columbia doing
some good strains yeah we'll see this
about the B stirs the B he stirs came in
not far after the community of
Vietnamese people started growing
cannabis but it actually came in a
little bit before
we lost it commercially really good but
the real problem in the beginning from
BC was the integrity of the buyer the
integrity of the buyer is he who was
I really wish we could we could listen
to him Martin we we probably know what
he'll say would the integrity of the
buyer really affected the the grower so
as people moved indoors you know the
only constrain that they could grow was
the strain that the buyer was gonna buy
from them and there was no room for
creativity and there was no room for
anything that was organized crime at
that time so that was the reason why the
bestir started to become you know gave a
name for itself was really because you
know then the consumers didn't even
really realize what a real flower looked
like outside of what the buyer was
buying so we said we were getting a lot
of BC coming down and had been sprayed
with formaldehyde so they could ship it
wetter you know and when you asked why
it wasn't cured or dried the response
that I would get would be because you
get more weight when it's wet and so
yeah and then being in before they anand
dadadada you know there was a lot of
that but so you are getting formaldehyde
weed from the north and then paraquat
weed up from Mexico from right and give
thanks for the NorCal hills cuz they
saved the day and came in you know all
the Emerald triangle and up and Sierra's
came in and saved us at that point the
islands of British Columbia and out in
the Kootenays have you know really
really crucial family will give thanks
to them absolutely no enough love to all
the guns of farmers out there for sure
I'll have a question though about co2
because it's getting mentioned a lot
it's being brought up a lot right now
and getting introduced to greenhouses
and my biggest concern about in co2
injection into greenhouses is how much
of its getting utilized by the plants
and how much is just being blown into
the environment and yeah I just want to
throw that one out into the group again
as well
thought you were gonna talk about co2
oil or something for a second I did too
but I feel 2 injection into the air it's
now I'm seeing a lot of people messing
with that now and it seems like you
gotta apply it just at the right time
well you know I mean and and and have
the right tools to measure that to
quantify I guess you could say but yeah
that's a new that's a nice hot new topic
basically is running the and I've seen a
couple different systems out there that
people are pushing but yeah we've always
thought nature was enough but I guess
maybe if they want more yeah I've seen
that too lately a lot a bunch of friends
that are talking about and I don't even
know what the product is but they're
talking about how they've got this co2
product that where the the gas will
actually stay in the greenhouse even
though the greenhouse is rented which
makes I would I don't know to me it
makes no sense whatsoever but they're
claiming that that's what they're doing
and it took it's for the greenhouse
grower and the person trying to reduce
you know energy costs and all these
different things it seems
counterintuitive to me the plant does
just fine with with you know what nature
provides and it's your when I hear guys
want to do that and some of the guys
that I see building out these greenhouse
facilities right now it's like they're
trying to build their greenhouse it's
like an indoor room and they put they
want co2 injectors and huge HVAC systems
and to me it's the opposite direction of
which way you should be going if you are
you know gonna be doing greenhouse
warming the constant reduction
definitely went up we've gone one step
further as far as nature is concerned
and we're planting a lot of king
stropharia and as we all know you know
mushrooms breathe in oxygen and breathe
out co2 and when you have you know
forever beds that you're adding a
tremendous amount of you know compost to
or a different type of leaf material to
it's really imperative to have that
quick breaker downer
you know the composter which is the king
stropharia so you get three different
things out of it it breaks down your
soil it lets off Co
- and it's delicious to eat so it's a
cold co2 so it's not the kind of co2
that goes up into the atmosphere it's a
kind of co2 that stays more you know a
ground-level you can also even stay
right around the soil it's also really
smart to do log culture you know
underneath your your your ganja and you
can be like a mulch layer you can just
do a bunch of round logs right next to
each other right at the base and then
they'll grow medicinal mushrooms and
exhale co2 so I think if you're in a
greenhouse you know you're in nature and
I think you should just enhance nature
and I think if you're using a greenhouse
to you know it be an outdoor grow room
then it can happen secondary products is
so supportive you know we're all just
pushing a lot of cannabis but to mix
cannabis with different medicinal
mushrooms is absolutely key these
beautiful to adaptogen is coming
together you can have so many different
types of secondary products that you can
you know be growing and getting out to
market or even getting to your
dispensaries and mushrooms is one of
them we like mushrooms
how do you spell that that's a that's
super interesting I want to I want to
check that out little bit it's a it's a
king stropharia mushroom for sure I want
to try them in about regional growing
bubble man touched on it when we first
started talking and it's really
important because I came from San Diego
I'm regionally a landscaper so I've been
plant things since I was 12 years old
and each region's a little so much
different in a growing climate and like
in San Diego we were growing we grew
under shade cloth and that's that became
a shade cloth band up here in Washington
I still use it a light shade cloth
through the whole season
it's it benefits me with the passive
airflow that we get we get a really nice
breeze that starts at 3 o'clock and
stops at 11 o'clock it comes off the
mouth of the Columbia and we're in this
just this little sweet zone where it
just blows through this nice cool air
and it really makes for a really good
growing thing but it you know it took
years to you know develop the style and
get used to your place and what works
best you know in that environment we
like to use shade cloth we've been using
shade cloth pretty much ly not the whole
season we're out September we'll pull it
off so we get some extra light its I
travel a lot so I can't really light
them too much so we just you know as
soon as the first sign of any problems
that's when we pull really nothing you
know goes full fully full-term on our
farm and it was and sex go we're huge
fans of trap plants so we plant we have
continuous rounds of green beans and we
also have continuous rounds of eggplant
because what we find is the bugs will go
to the trap plants before though go up
into the plants and I think just getting
known to your in your region we're in
the Willamette Valley here in Vancouver
Washington the Portland area so we're
kind of like the north end of the
Willamette Valley and we have a really
great greenhouse growing environment
here and
those are some of the things that you
know I've learned over the years and
that's there we go
yeah that's useful I think that cover
crops can even become a trap on accident
you know for pests and if people leave
their cover crops too long or if it's
they have a pest outbreak maybe you know
it can go on to the to the cover crop so
just having biodiversity I think we
think of having biodiversity and that's
a big part of our peer certification and
the farms that we work with and people
can look up you know the farms that we
work with and we have a new website
called dem pure farms com we'll just say
that now because its brand new in the
last couple days and it's going to
highlight the farms that are doing
interesting work and tremendous amounts
of educational practices yeah and we
really encourage just going back to what
everybody's saying education yeah yeah
it's really important to us so but yeah
you know the just having diversity
around your greenhouse even if it's
flowers around your greenhouse maybe as
sunflowers maybe it's marigolds maybe
it's geraniums cuz geraniums never get
bugs on them you know it's it's just a
it's a whole bunch of things that you
know make it important and it's things
that we don't even know about because
we're just enhancing nature by having
diversity or and another thing to add is
that we're realizing you know different
types of terpenes if you've had a really
horrible outbreak of mites and you've
had many years of it you know there's
the jaren all you know lemony nits
another one and lynn Ahlul those are
terpenes that really you know pests do
not like to be around at all so really
trying to find varieties that contain
those high terpene levels will be also
really helpful and I'd like to also just
remind people this time of the year in
the wintertime if you are growing in the
in the wintertime to maintain higher
soil temps I've seen a couple people
noticing that their plants aren't where
they should be right now as far as like
flower production and and some people
try to discuss you know maybe it's the
UV maybe it's the temperature maybe it's
you know the air temperature and some of
these other factors and nine times out
of ten a six inch soil probe going into
your soil
we'll tell you how cold or warm your
soil is and you know the soil when
you're in grow bags I like to call
growing in 30 gallon or bigger grow bags
NorCal style because when there wasn't
when there was plant counts everybody
wanted to grow the biggest plant they
possibly could but they wanted to do
light DEP and so the 30 to 45 gallon
grow bag got pretty popular and when you
put that type of a grow bag on the earth
or even a grow bed for that matter the
temperature of the soil will fluctuate
with the weather even so when it's warm
temperatures like this our soil temps
obviously go up and when its rainy they
go down and when we have the cold snaps
they go down tremendously and so we've
seen that you know or you guys soil
people have taught us that anything
below 55 degrees we don't have nutrient
exchange and good mobility for life and
so what I find in the wintertime is most
soil temperatures are under fifty five
degrees whether they're a painter or a
or a bed and so if you don't have soil
temperatures above fifty five degrees
you're gonna have trouble getting the
same production or quality of flour that
you would normally get in the spring or
the summer time and so you know a six
inch soil probes really easy to get on
Amazon and have it sent to you I also
get the infrared thermometer so you can
point and shoot the surface temps to
find out in the summer time how hot the
surface of the plant is how hot the
ground is a bunch of different things
you know so you can really kind of get
in tune because again that temp and
humidity thermostat that we normally
would go to in a grow room or even a
greenhouse controller doesn't really
tell us everything and so I you know I
have some people that I'm working with
that do you have you know they're doing
really a great job but one of the things
that we were kind of noticing is for
they mentioned to me about the
wintertime growing in some soil temps
dripping dipping they have a radiant
heating system the soil temps are up to
the 70s but then watering with 55 degree
well water will shock the roots and
actually cause your system to have to
regenerate and heat back up again and so
you know it's kind of a minut thing you
know when you think about it or just
when you're speaking about it I guess
you say but when you really think about
it and what you're doing it it can make
quite a difference and so
you know that's why I really try to
differentiate the difference between
winter mode greenhouses and summer mode
greenhouses you know greenhouses were
invented and designed for wintertime and
when you try to use them in the summer
they can be difficult but they'll do
really well in the winter time so I mean
some to keep in mind is that you can
really change the winter mode greenhouse
to a summer mode whether you're in a
hoop midtech or a high-tech greenhouse
and it just takes some thinking and
understanding and looking at the
greenhouse to decide which is the best
method to go about doing that but again
greenhouses were invented for wintertime
and most greenhouse companies are
selling you a greenhouse that is gonna
do what it's supposed to do work well in
the wintertime and so when we talk you
know hey we're gonna be out in the hot
Summer Sun it might be the easy default
to say you need a wet wall cooling
system and a wet wall is an evaporative
cooler so it's basically based on water
trickling over a pad and then the
exhaust fans at the opposite end of the
greenhouse exchanging the air and
hopefully that air can be cooled passing
through the greenhouse but if you're in
a humid area it's not gonna work that
way so here in the Gold Country or the
foothills where we are they can work at
times but they're not 365 24/7 and when
you get into humid places like the
Emerald triangle and I'm not talking
terribly humid but you know over 47
percent relative humidity you're not
gonna see much reduction in temperature
and that's why we really try to talk
about cooling surfaces rather curling
the air to do that because most
greenhouse companies are gonna try to
sell you a winter mode greenhouse as
designed and then the default is that
evaporative cooler and that's just not
going to work for everybody everywhere
and so again if you understand the
cannabis plant - you can really work
well with a greenhouse in the summertime
knowing how cannabis wants to sweat and
as easily to keep cool without a cooling
system doing all these things in the
right manners and then paying attention
to that soil biology I mean some of the
I think the show goes till about 12:00
and some of the last things that I would
you know wrap up with is that don't
always pay attention to the environment
we in the cannabis community and
industry chase the environment so much
the
a lot of people forget what's going on
underground and it's easy to overwater
it's easy to let your soils get cold
it's easy to let things slide sometimes
and the biology is an important part of
the system and so if you want control in
your greenhouse make sure you understand
what's going on underground as well
because in the environments only half
the battle in my opinion totally agree I
also think that everyone should have a
microscope and get closer to their Leafs
then just the little handheld ones that
are common for spider mites I think it
takes a microscope or getting in there
60 you know or even thousand times and
even having one that goes to your
computer screen that has a video on it
that you can you can take them a lot a
log of your pictures or videos even you
can take a compost tea or tea and look
at our microscope as well I think that's
really important to add to what you said
Eric so yeah and your your every and
touching your soil after every run makes
a lot of sense and and we really
recommend that ya testing everything is
important I mean the inputs these days
you never know where you're getting it
for I mean you might know where you're
getting it from but how long has it been
in the bag how long has it been you know
sitting around or through these
processes and so we really want to make
sure we're testing all our ingredients
you know making sure that everything
that we're using is gonna work because
according to Nevada and it looks like
maybe California it'll be pretty easy to
fail a test if you don't follow a lot of
the proper guidelines and keep it things
clean the Department of pesticide
regulation release the allowable stuff
for cannabis and there isn't much
allowed huh as far as pesticides and
fungicides and herbicides that people
would want to use and and maybe even
fine to be organic in some cases but
it's not going to be okay for cannabis
and a lot of people try to you know
compare cannabis to other vegetables and
farming and I always try to say that you
know you can't take a flower and go wipe
it on your
shirt like you would an apple before you
eat it you can't wash it off you don't
you know blanch it or or pasteurized it
or any of these other things that you do
with food before it gets to people a lot
of people don't realize what their food
goes through before it reaches the
shelves as far as being sanitized you
know and so cannabis can go through some
of the same things but you know UV light
you know I think there's some weird
microwave things out there these days
but I mean at the end of the day you
know we can't always compare what
happens in regular AG to cannabis and I
see that happening a lot these days but
you know making sure you know what
you're using and making sure that your
soil is healthy so the e can grow clean
healthy plants and the environment that
you growing is is conducive to that but
I mean as we start to wrap up here
closer to 12 o'clock I think it's
important for everybody to let each all
of us know how to get a hold of each
other in case anybody wants to connect
so that we can share information or
maybe meet up down the road or help out
a friend if we need to and so mica can
we start off with you what's the best
way for people to understand or learn
about leaf organics and your website and
stuff yeah we've got our website it's a
leaf organics calm that's a leaf with
two e's there's not to be confused with
the other 9000 Leafs out there in the
cannabis world but yeah the leaf
organics is a good spot to get a hold of
us and then I mean my email is mica mich
at leaf organics comm if anyone has
questions or you know I'm pretty open to
sharing do you have any social medias
you want to shout out so people can
check you out yeah yeah we've got an
Instagram page and a Facebook page leaf
I think it's just leaf organics is is
the instant belief underscore organics
on Instagram and then we've got a pet
food company that is basically it's the
same same company but it's just a
division under leaf called paleo pop and
that websites paleo pal feed calm
and we kind of specialized we had we
actually had that before we had leave we
were doing kind of human grade organic
non-gmo pet food and we merged that into
leaf and so yeah people couldn't check
that out and feel free to reach out to
us open sure success isn't a failure so
yeah and I love the pet products I got
old dogs some yeah usin that kid they
got pep treats shampoo like all kinds of
cool stuff and my dogs my animals
definitely are thanking you cool right
on I'm gonna I'm gonna let you guys go I
got a get get Jam in here but I just
want to say thank you to all you guys
Eric and Jonathan you guys have
definitely helped me out with a green
nap greenhouse knowledge over the last
few years and dragonfly Earth medicine
you guys have an amazing product it's a
it's super super good everyone all the
employees that we have swear by it and
all that we have a ton of neighbors that
we've turned on to it so I just wanted
to give you guys a big thanks for thank
it was really we're gonna have to hook
up somewhere off off camera yeah for
sure yeah definitely it was nice meeting
you guys all over this and uh I'll see
you guys around bubble man thanks for
putting this thing on man this is
awesome so you man enjoy the slopes yeah
my girlfriend sitting here she's you
know I got a you got a good half day now
yeah sorry
guys later thanks man I appreciate it
right on brother see you guys later
Jonathan let's move on down the line
what do you want it what information do
you want people to know so they can get
a hold of year or linka I
yeah our website for forever flowering
is light calm light calm and I'm forever
flowering Jonathan on Instagram Jo Ann a
THM and come check out our demo houses
we have a beautiful site in Grass Valley
California we got a couple of greenhouse
demonstrations going on there fully
automated structure
and yeah so grateful to be part of this
thanks everybody
yeah man thanks for sharing and it's
been good it's been a good conversation
Jason what would you like to shout out
and let people know how to get a hold of
you
so where our company names the flower
but that sort of we've got the original
blue bastard so original blue bastard is
our brand up here in Washington and
original blue bastard on instagram if
anybody wants to say hi but thank you
good they invite and you're bringing us
on yeah sure yeah yeah that's awesome I
look forward to linking up with you
again definitely come on up
next time you up here you have to see
the new facility yeah I'm gonna find me
an eagle leaf of a feather one of these
times under one of those big old red
redwood trees and bald eagles
greenhouses it's like I mean I want to
move there but uh yeah I mean yeah
that's great
JD why don't you let us know how to get
a hold of you brother let's see the best
thing for me I guess is on my Instagram
it's a Gold Country cannabis on
Instagram and we've got a website going
up Gold Country cannabis farm another
really cool way to get your farm domain
and yeah that's the best bet I'm usually
on there somebody's on there that'll
respond and can find me oh definitely
stand twist you guys have been awesome
yeah man well thanks for coming on and I
look forward to coming out and visiting
your farm sometime and talking
yeah I'm gonna come track you down the
down yeah all right I'll be here this
I'm gonna be around just hit me up and
we'll make sure we connect
siobhan can you let us know how to get
what how do we track the gross sisters
and bless and we're pretty easy I'm sure
on danger darwish you can find me all
over Instagram I also
sisters they're easy as well so find us
say hi my friends are your friends let's
grow thank you for having us on this was
great to do some technical farm top
again it made my heart sing so thank you
guys it was nice meeting all of you and
yeah find me reach out yeah it's awesome
well thanks for joining the show and and
I like your YouTube videos by the way
they're kind of fun and you know what I
mean like you guys are like yeah it's
good I mean it's good to see people
trying to have some fun I mean this is a
job and stuff and it's not like
glamorous or anything it's just you know
work and people make fun out of it and
stuff it's just you know I see you guys
out in the dirt and the dogs and
everybody's having a good time so I mean
it definitely I'll come visit you when
I'm up there next time farmer Tom and I
really appreciate it it's so great you
know seeing other women in the
cultivating industry we really
appreciate you thanks so much we're
really looking forward to meeting you
off screen and hanging out and sharing a
hug and a smoke Thanks yeah definitely
farmer Tom where can we check you out
with wood events or things can we see
you
well here's my card I hope you can see
it you can find me at farmer Tom
organics calm you can find me on
Facebook Everman Instagram at farmer -
on Lehrman and look for our F THC
scoring system and well we're having
products in California Washington organ
and about by the end of the year so look
for us out there thank you we really
appreciate you coming on and all of your
input and you know putting it out there
to other people to learn you know who
are really needing it you know if we are
going to be having a federal new take
over we're really hoping that they're
learning from you and learn about the
right way so thank you so much for
giving out that information and being
open yes you guys for having me on yeah
that's that's really cool man brave [__]
I couldn't do it and for me I mean
dragonfly you're hosting the show so
that you guys finally wrap it up but me
I'm at forever flowering greenhouses all
one word on Instagram and Jonathan gave
you our website light DEP calm and
worried in Grass Valley California we're
one hour away from the Sacramento
Airport we're about an hour away from
Tahoe so if anybody wants to go skiing
we're only a couple hours from the bay
centrally located so come check us and
and thanks again dragonfly for hosting
the show while bubbleman's in Jamaica
and thanks to bubbleman for allowing us
to have the show while he's out of town
even and his dedication to continuing
the show for all these years we really
appreciate all that he does and and
thanks to you guys again dragonfly
thanks so much Eric you know you're one
of our favorite people for sure Jonathan
over the years I mean you know of course
our company when we first came out we
kind of met out in Denver initially and
that we even though it was on tour and
all that before but we've been working
together for a really long time that
we've always had a lot of love and
integrity from you guys so we just are
really appreciative of that and you know
we want to move forward you know in this
lifetime you know
and and thanks so much marcus vc
bubbleman we just have you know he was
doing this way long before it was even
cool you know he was getting a lot of
havoc and a lot of stress in his life
from continuing to get the education out
and he's just going more and more
forward and we appreciate his family and
his wife holding it down really
important yeah thanks sure and you can
reach us at dragonfly Earth medicine
comm or also on Instagram
we're totally available we spend like as
several hours a day just answering
random gardening questions to people
were totally dedicated to the plan and
the intention that she has and is giving
it out to us as a medicine and we've
recently finished a website called DM
pure farms calm which lists all of the
farms that are peer certified it also
has a whole entire page of closed loops
when people asked what is a closed loop
if it's not for you know it's one on the
on the land it's it's anything that one
system leads into the other system
whether it's alternative energy or
reusing your soils or growing your own
inputs check out DM pure farms that's
just it's just one example of
like-minded people
regenerative cannabis farmers joining
together and we do really encourage
people in the industry to join together
because that's the way that this craft
cannabis superhigh bom-bom fire is going
to make it out into the industry and
encouraging people to work together on
the dispensary front and on the
processing front to utilize their
medicine in their cannabis and in a in
an excellent way we're going to Jamaica
on March 1st for two weeks ourselves and
we're being invited by a Rastafarian
community there and we're gonna go
really dive into spiritual cannabis on
Jamaica and learn about their ways and
their ways of connecting with the earth
and midwives of spiritual healers so
we're really really excited to talk
about regenerative cannabis there and
growing and cultivating cannabis
off-the-grid in a spiritual way that's
really important to us and also we are
going to be at the living soil symposium
happening at the end of March which is
going to be a wonderful collection of
really beautiful people which can
help answer the question of how to move
regenerative cannabis forward and reget
generative cannabis is important because
the mainstream big AG crazy days are on
our honor honor our shelves now and are
coming at us so really it's our gonna be
our integrity and our love and our
stories and our better strains that we
have that's gonna really keep us going
forward so I'd like to thank bubbleman
as well and skunk man Sam for his lots
of years of dedication towards bringing
every you know all this technical stuff
forward so yeah big up skunk man Sam he
dropped some knowledge today that I
didn't really appreciate yeah and
there's other people that were not on
this panel that are really excellent a
growing in greenhouses and reach out to
them as well
you know we're one group we're sharing
our story we hope it inspires you we're
all available check us out thanks Eric
thanks Jonathan thanks everyone here Co
have a good one you know take one more
toke for the road yeah for Dennis Peron
thanks to our forefathers yeah thank
goodness for the forefathers have a
great day love you guys
Alisa