hey hey what's going on strangers it's
been a while I think over a hundred and
forty days welcome everyone to bubble
man's world and welcome to hash Church
2.0 episode six
wow that was a serious break for those
of you that don't know we basically took
a four-month hiatus there at the request
of YouTube I lost my ability to stream
I'm very very happy that they gave it
back I want to welcome everyone into the
room into the chat room I'm so stoked to
be here and so stoked to see all these
familiar names as they aren't faces they
are names on in a chat room I'm going to
get right to it and send off the link to
the people who are waiting this morning
for the link to come in and spend a
little bit of time with us today we're
just gonna do a couple of hours I think
depending on the conversation but I'm
very very very excited to be back at
hash Church I missed it I swear as much
as you guys did there's a special thing
that we have here and it's it was it was
kind of sad when I thought I was gonna
lose my ability to stream forever I was
in a 90-day probation on YouTube and
after 90 days I went to stream and they
did not let me stream after a hundred
days they did not let me stream and it
kept going on and on and on but I was
relentless and persistent and I kept
checking every single day to see if if
we could get if we could get back on and
there it is there's the most familiar
face ever
you can't hear me come on I can hear you
let's see a team's gonna figure it out
hopefully you guys can hear me I think
you can hear me otherwise I'd be hearing
people say we can't hear you bubble man
but there's a TA
funk tank in the room first time in over
a hundred and forty days it's really
good to see you even though you can't
hear me I can hear you oh you can hear
me dude it's so good to see you man I
feel like you're like my long-lost
brother that I haven't seen in forever
it's been a while is really a hundred
and forty days Hastert's was our
connection bro like I barely seen hide
nor hair of
I'm sure you've got all sorts of
wonderful things to share with us this
morning but I hope you've been well
above all else I have been well and I
hope the same to you I see you've been
traveling around the world and
definitely miss the opportunity to hang
and to see what's going on because it's
also been my connection as well because
I've been underwater I mean it's it's
been crazy it's been legal here in
California and it's been insanity
Pepper's to say the least
you know we've got a whole new set of
clientele and people who are coming
through the door so it's been you know
all kinds of craziness but it's been a
wonderful challenge and one that we've
been able to live up to and yeah it's
just yeah just trying to keep up with
all the craziness we still don't have
permanent regulations here in California
we're still dealing in the temporary
world but of course I see there's a lot
of changes happening up there in Canada
as well you know you've got a lot of
changes happening to your system you've
got a lot of consolidation happening
right now people buying each other up so
it's been an interesting 140 plus days
to say the least what do you have - oh
my gosh I've been I've been keeping busy
for sure you know we went and enjoyed
spannabis there for a little bit and
that was a wonderful event and I ended
up in my York after that with these
wonderful people Danny and grace who
were just gracious hosts that spent some
we spent four days there with my friend
Sean lost gardens on Instagram as well
as the maple butter boys
and then came home and have just been
one opportunity after the after another
I'm actually in Toronto right now for
the lift conference which has been going
really well it's a huge monstrous
conference there's all sorts of people
on both sides of the sort of invisible
fence that invisibly divides us I mean
for me we're all in this cannabis
industry together but there's a lot of
division you hear of course the people
who have licensed production facilities
not all of them but some of them are
feeling a little short-handed by the
investments they've had to make the
hoops they've had to draw jump through
and how of course dispensaries don't
have to jump through those hoops so
they're actually pretty
profits and selling products while you
know the other ones are not but in the
long run there's good people on both
sides and I'm pretty excited too to just
see the industry growing every day
welcome Wade how are you doing brother
hello Marcus hello it John dude it's so
good to see you
right back at you gentlemen how's
everything you got a haircut Marcus yes
I did I got a haircut recently I went
with my son and we both got haircuts
plus I'm not wearing a hat and I'm
always wearing a hat so today I was like
a bride for a concert oh look at you
look at that nice nice right yeah so I
sent the link out to forest as well
today so hopefully he'll be able to stop
in and share some some knowledge with us
about the khalad rias Network and what
what what have you been up to Wade in
the last hundred and forty days since
last we saw you yeah
Wow chol address network I have I have a
new empathy for people who are in pain I
destroyed my back this spring and had
emergency surgery seven weeks ago today
which I thought I would never do but the
pain stopped immediately the surgeon
took bone off of three vertebrae and
took material from two different disks
in my back and I have severe
restrictions on activity for the next
six months so I'm not a farmer this year
I'm a person who's going to be making
helping people understand how to use
cannabis as medicine and all the
different ways that can happen and
meantime in our area I'm gonna be
helping the farmers who are providing
for collateral network or trying to get
into the regulated marketplace here in
California any kind of help that I can
offer them about how to fit into the
regulated marketplace and succeed in it
well so many barriers have been put up
to especially small farm
having any chance at all in this new
marketplace in California it's really
crazy well you know what as crazy as it
is first go ahead that's yeah yes
frustration you know if we we embrace 64
in the change that happened and then the
state of course created a lot of rules
and one of the main reality is is they
allowed four counties and municipalities
to vote out cannabis altogether and that
has been extremely limiting across the
board so there's bills there's a bill
currently in the state trying to allow
for deliveries in areas where they're
barred from having any type of
distribution points in the sense of
retail outlets so it's been frustrating
to watch many a farmer have to go back
into the underground because of the
inability to afford to come into this
real world you know we had to bootstrap
it ourselves and we're one of the more
successful ones and it was still very
challenging so you know it's it's still
frustrating for us that are able to you
know move forward in this situation but
it's it's even more frustrating to see
all those that were in the system and
the were being successful now left on
the outside and we have to we have to
show the stuff and we have to fix this
well I have faith in you guys as being
the right people to do it I want to say
I'm very sorry to hear about your back
and your surgery Wade but I'm glad that
it worked out for you and that you're
pain-free and of course you're still
doing the good work of Ja I want to
welcome forest from the khalad rias
Network and I want to welcome Erik from
forever flowering greenhouses I don't
want to say I want to say guys you know
it wasn't too long ago that our lives
were being destroyed in a very different
way we were being jailed we were having
our dogs shot we were having our kids
taken away we were having all these
things that was at such a different
level that the obstacles we have now as
horrible as they are they are nothing
compared to what we've been dealing with
for the last 40-plus years and that I
know that we're strong enough to get
through it so you may hear us bitching a
little bit about these difficult
regulations and the way good people are
being sort of forced out but we're gonna
fight
for those people we're gonna continue
the fight and at least at least at least
were not being imprisoned for 10 and 20
years at a time so let's not forget it
wasn't that long ago that they were
doing that to us yes yes hey well most
good morning everybody boy it's good to
see everyone again yeah that's what I
said too for us that's what I said too
yeah just been that it's been a hole for
sure it's been a hole in the in the in
my world not having the church happened
what's it been 100 and 160 days or so
one forty days now almost yeah yeah no
for real it's been about that long it's
you know I was I was in YouTube prison I
had one of my videos struck down I guess
someone flagged my video of me smoking a
pure hash joint they struck the video
and when they struck the video they
simultaneously took away my ability to
stream I didn't want to complain I
didn't want to rock the boat I have a
huge appreciation for the YouTube
platform and for what they offer us and
I know there's all sorts of difficulties
with all sorts of different channels
right now and I'm personally not going
to get into that discussion today too
much but I definitely was very very very
happy when I and I was searching I was
checking every single day for the last
40 days 50 days if I could stream and
one day I just went on and I went to
stream and instead of saying no
streaming allowed on this channel it
opened up the page and it showed me that
I could write a title and start
streaming and I was so giddy and so
excited it was like oh my god oh my God
we're back like it's really it's really
quite frightening when you have a
platform like this you know suddenly not
allow you to do something that you you
know I don't want to say I took it for
granted because I absolutely don't first
of all take for granted all of you
amazing people that both come on the
panels and come and spend time in the
chat room I absolutely am honoured
beyond honored that for whatever reason
we've been able to build this together
and like for
said it was a real hole in my world as
well not being able to talk with all of
you every week on this Sunday morning
and I'm just so honored and and blessed
that it's that we've been given the
opportunity to do it again so thank you
all for coming
for coming in and it's amazing to see
how about that for timing as I'm giving
thanks and praises the dragonfly Earth
medicine crew comes in mica came in so
welcome to both of you as well this is
wonderful okay I gotta ask the put the
question the 800-pound gorilla in the
room then can we smoke or not uh
hopefully I've been doing videos where
I'm dabbing I've been doing videos I
mean this is cannabis education I would
never tell anyone particularly someone
who just had back surgery that they
couldn't use their medicine oh what's up
Shawn lost gardens in the house who just
stopped by have a seat bro
join us here for some hash Church well
if that's the case yes sir first off
before we do that I'm gonna say bong
ripp there you go there you go hey
welcome dragonfly earth medicine welcome
mica hey I'm not sure if you guys can
hear me or not how's it going we can
hear you which what's your question wait
no question actually it was an excellent
observation he'd shared at the beginning
of our meeting that he was taken down
because we were smart he was smoking and
here we are smoking again but I just
made an assumption we should be able to
smoke absolutely you know what I'm not
sure exactly why I have all sorts of
YouTube videos there's all been all
sorts of drama if you google it you can
you can look into it but I definitely am
NOT trying to rock the YouTube boat in
the sense that I'm very very happy with
them giving us permission to do this
chat again I don't take hash Church for
granted this is a very important
platform and I really realized how
important it is when I was not able to
do it for a hundred and forty days and
towards the end of that hundred and
forty days I thought I was never going
to be able to do it again and
so I'm just very happy to have all your
smiling faces on the panel and I'm
looking forward to hearing everything
about what everyone's been doing for the
last hundred and forty days and I
definitely want to hear Josh and Kelly's
voice right now I mean I'm just elated
thanks so much Marcus for getting this
up and rolling and we're feeling like
it's a regular Sunday we were like I
could barely sleep last night so excited
to see you and a lot of love to you Wade
you know big big healing you know vibes
to you that's a big deal to go through
that but you can do it we know you can
yeah many blessings on that continued
healing and Forrest matey and Mike and
Eric and everything bigger yeah I just
went to pass Sean my pen and he pulls
his own pan out I was like that's pretty
cool so yeah I don't know it's just
great to see everyone it's great to be
back in this chat room here everyone's
we've got 70s mama and woody woody and
melty heads and John Maddox and yeah a
JD ji dam who has tears in their eyes
I'm telling you this is an emotional I
have goosebumps no joke I have
goosebumps
this is importance yeah the work that
we've been doing on here is important go
ahead Forrest as I say it's really
important you know I think that one of
your points as far as how important this
platform is this is really critical and
it ties in to why it was sitting down to
begin with and one of the main things I
think programs like this do the work
that we do at local and federal and our
national levels is help to break down
that stigma that is tied with cannabis
is inherently wrong that there's
something just if you're involved with
it or something apparently bad or
dangerous with it and that is dissolving
a little more slowly than I would like
but it's still there
and it causes people to make decisions
that are bad and against their best
options for quality of life it causes
people to to ban and counties like
talked about here in California
everyone's like it's legal in California
but we have 85% of the counties still in
a ban and how do we change the community
perception how do we get to hearts and
minds right we were able to share the
work we're doing we're able to put that
into the communities we're able to
change the context of the conversation
and it's really that's what's where
we're at with cannabis is still we need
to put the work into the cultural shift
of understanding instead of holding on
to this false
you know dichotomy of sin that is
somehow attached to cannabis and really
anything that changes your mindset we
have this old dogmatic idea that that
equals sin and you know or something bad
in platforms like this and some of the
conversations I'm sure we'll get into
are critical I think the impact really
can't be understated or overstated that
you know it's by having these ability to
get to so many different people share
what we're working with have them
working and sharing and speaking in
their communities that we really see the
biggest chance for impact on that
cultural shift and it's that cultural
shift that is holding us back in the
places that were we're so struggling for
rights no yeah but it's people like you
that have been you know very much
congratulations to what you have been
doing in Sacramento to pass legislation
to actually help others I've been
working behind the scenes with the
veterans cannabis council and we've been
actually we've got the first bill out of
out of out of Congress there we got the
first bill actually voted out to allow
for research regarding veterans so
there's a lot of things that a lot of us
have been doing in the absence of being
here that are pushing forward for
positive change for all because you know
we can't just sit back and rest on our
laurels but it also it reminds us that
you know and seeing all these and
justices of how much work we still have
to continue to do even with your
successes there in Sacramento it's just
a drop in the water compared to the
watershed moments we need to have so the
ability for everybody who's
watching to still get active and get
involved is still in parallel and it's
so important it's so it to continue to
to make this momentum stronger and
stronger that we've been able to show at
least on the state national and federal
front but we still got you know 41 other
states as well as those with legal still
have things we all have to work out and
hopefully with this legislation coming
up federally which will supersede the
you know the veterans bill that we had
going through will hopefully I don't
take it out of scheduled one all
together in the United States and allow
for it to proliferate through all 50
states so that maybe we can catch up to
you wonderful people in Canada since
we're still so lagging behind yeah you
know I'm sure we'll get into that but
you know that's something that having a
platform offers is it's the ability to
share with people what's going on
nationally at the state level and here
in the States and in Canada as well
what's going on there so that we can
steer people in the right direction
because I know with stuff that we're
working on I meet people all the time it
man if I had a note about that I would
love to participate or get groups
together and you know well how do we do
that in social media the internet
connecting with with folks is the most
efficient and best way to do it so I'm
really happy to be here Marcus I
appreciate the invite and I'm excited
it's what we're gonna get into here
today well I just want to add that
although maybe in the government and in
the federal situation you guys are
behind in Canada's a little bit of ahead
but I've always looked to the American
activists as my point of inspiration and
the work that you guys have done I
certainly don't feel that you guys are
behind us and your activism in any way
shape or form you guys are the leading
world activists in my opinion and we've
always looked to you to for for guidance
and for direction so bless up and that's
true and then there's the the few
Americans that made it up to Canada that
are even like more wild because they're
just like
just want the best of everything but you
know it is kind of crazy with the way
that everything is right now because
we're all like the originators of
cannabis and and other people that are
out there to like the the as far as
cultivation goes in the culture and many
of us farmers are just kind of
struggling to find our place meanwhile
there's 2.5 billion dollar deals being
signed all over the place and 59
publicly traded companies here in Canada
and everywhere else you go in the world
you would just think it was totally
legal because the government and the
large-scale corporations are a hundred
percent you know acting as if you know
that they're publicly trading and making
deals without even barely having any
lead growing so I think that we've
always said this at recently I'd say in
the last year we really really need to
just stay in business whatever that
means to each individual because each
individual that means something
different and staying in business with
integrity you know all of these really
large it may seem like cannabis ahead
but what kind of ahead are we it's a
really interesting conversation because
all of these really large multinational
multi international businesses now are
totally joining forces with
pharmaceutical companies and they're
going all over the world and they're
making deals and they're going to be
getting cheaper flowers from Colombia
from Jamaica from other places all over
the world they're not even going to be
looking to Canadian growers for their
flowers or because maybe this isn't such
a great place to be able to grow the
flowers cheaply they want to go to areas
that they can grow it cheaply sun-grown
and it really is going to be cutting out
you know the small farmers they've been
having legislation and they've been able
to set up business but they haven't even
given us our our licenses and we don't
even know what's happening yet well the
beautiful the beautiful thing is is that
although it may cut out a lot of people
in the sense that now this is going to
be a legal business that the whole world
is and one thing I can say from being at
the lift conference there's all sorts of
different people from different walks of
life that I've been speaking to you know
people that I may have almost harshly
judged years ago through my own
potentiation of my own stereotype as a
as a as a whatever you want to call me I
was more of a hippie mentality and I
would call it kind of call them the Jo
stray tease you know as I'm sitting on
hash Turks looking like a Jo straight II
but I had some incredible conversations
over the last few days and one of the
things that really struck me whether or
not it was about money that was getting
people excited or not it really felt
like these people all of these people
that I met had had a passion for
cannabis had an excitement like they
were walking through their lives as
zombies before and now they were getting
into this cannabis and I just felt like
you know what this is just gonna be a
good thing like people are excited you
know they were working in construction
or they were doing you know mining or
they were doing like they were working
in agriculture but with cows and
chickens and they were doing all these
different things and from all these
different walks of life and as I speak
to each one of them individually and
spend time with them I realized that
they're just people that are just trying
to live their lives they're just trying
to do good and now they have this
cannabis plant and I feel like if you're
gonna have cannabis in your life you're
gonna be hard set not to have it in it
put in a positive influence into your
life you know I've used it personally as
a guiding light for for a couple of
decades now almost three decades and it
was neat to see people for the first
time turning on their cannabis
flashlights getting the batteries on and
flicking that switch because you can see
it in their eyes there's a real
excitement and I obviously hope that
everyone that wants to be involved gets
to be involved and at the same time no
one's ever going to be able to stop you
from growing your own cannabis the same
way you growing your own flowers you're
gonna be able to do it here in the very
near future for sure in Canada with
recreational right around the corner and
over 50 to 60,000 people already
federally exempt through the medical
programs I think America is really gonna
get on board in the next five years I
think we're gonna see federal
legalization down there the work that
people like at Terre and forest and all
of these different incredible activists
are doing it can't be ignored anymore it
just can't be well we were also forced
them that they can't ignore us that's
the other thing you know now we just
that rider I mean the bill that we had
we had 52 co-sponsors that's been
Cades worth of work to get those 52
co-sponsors to put that on so all this
time while people sit around bitching
and complaining we've been putting in
the work by going down there and
lobbying year in and year out and
putting in that time so that we not only
had one we had 52 and so now we have a
constituency so strong that if they go
against us we can now shame them okay
this is a total shift in dynamics that
we as veterans can shame them and it's
better it's Memorial Day this weekend so
shout out to all veterans including the
drug war veterans but especially those
that have lost their lives because
that's what Memorial Day is to remember
those who have lost their lives so don't
forget those you know my cousin was
killed in war but I've lost countless
other friends in this drug war and I
view them all equally because it's all
shameful what's actually happened to all
of us but it shows that and you know
gossiped reminders that we have more and
more work to do and if you don't do it
ourselves you know
no one else is gonna do it so why that
would look to be the one and only with
that neither the man himself most year
most years skunk how many people just
smiled when they saw that come on the
camera your mics officer yes I had to
meet you Sam I'm sorry but you can
unmute yourself and say hi because I
know lots of people want to hear your
voice like oh no not not only that is I
saw Nick Bradley earlier and a shout-out
to the you know 22 vets a day kill
themselves so you got to remember that
people you know the lot of stresses that
we go through and this is a very healing
herb for all including our soldiers yeah
you know so never forget and especially
the 22 because it's more than 22 that
will die today because of that you know
so that's why that's why things are
changing is that we I mean the reality
is is that we have the moral and ethical
high ground we have the science
back it up at this point saying we can
do more science is really just saying I
haven't read or looked at it at all
you know there's absolutely the science
there to back it up and what we have now
is the group of activists all over the
world that can articulate it in a
different way that kind of breaks down
again what we were talking about about
some of the social that ideological and
dogmatic arguments of cannabis being bad
because it makes you feel funny you know
so it's happening the the fight and in
18 hip is perfectly is where the urgency
comes from with with our group and with
the veterans groups we work with and I
really see those two some of those two
categories to some of the the most risk
is that we want the people to still be
around when that day comes we know it's
coming but we want as many people to
survive to see that day as possible and
I don't think that it is really
understood how the slow reactions how
the passivity of lawmakers really
equates death and lives and cost people
their lives so I want us hear from Sam -
is he gone is he still here but I want
to also get into ETS bill I want to hear
more about it before we go today for
sure and share the work I am here and I
want to pipe up about one subject which
was will the future of cannabis be
produced in places like Columbia and
other places well if you look at the cut
flower industry all of the flowers are
produced in Malaysia Kenya Colombia
places like this I mean they they sell
90% of the flowers produced in the
industry and there's a reason why it's
it's labor costs and nobody can compete
with that to be honest but have any of
you ever worried about where you cut
flowers come from I mean nobody cared
they
- cheap price I mean I see where they
come from because all the green houses
in California are all old cut flower
greenhouses that are now converted to
cannabis or converting to cannabis I
mean probably more cut flower
greenhouses in the last year than I ever
thought I would imagine and Santa
Barbara County has the most mixed light
licenses in California right now I don't
rind up my cut flower extract it and
feed it to my nine year old kid so
that's true - there's a different level
of expectation there's different ways
the cut flower industry also has a lot
of organic growers
you know so the stuff is totally clean
it's safe I think that we're gonna be in
a unique position kind of like in the
aromatherapy and essential oil world
where specific essential oils express
themselves uniquely depending on the
different regions that they're grown and
although it might not be the majority of
the marketplace I think there's always
going to be a place in the market for
cannabis grown in specific regions and
specific soils with specific Sun cycles
to express I agree Marcus and if you
think about it right now with beer
whiskey and wine none of which I take
but it is a big business and it's much
better to be a legal business and any
illegal business but you can buy it from
any country in the world
you can buy beer from any country you
can buy wine from any country you could
buy whiskey from any country and I look
forward to in the future of cannabis is
that way that you can buy cannabis
products from any country in any country
oh I would love to have the opportunity
to buy your gland cannabis or some of
the other countries that are now
starting to produce cannabis well I know
a lot of those countries would love to
have some of our California cannabis but
the reality is is those other countries
will be able to produce it for much
cheaper and a better quality than what
we'll be able to produce here in the
United States so imports will be
something that will be considered just
like anything else you know regionally
you know in in the winter we get our
our vegetables from you know South
America you know and all these types of
regionalism that has you know built
their industries to accommodate the type
of international food commerce and trade
that is there so eventually will be
available I mean here in the United
States you've got you know people like
Humboldt Mendocino that are trying to
you know start to label or constitute
their label to protect themselves like
champagne did for the Champagne region
you know that anything that comes that
has the name champagne has to be grown
in the Champagne region
you know same thing that's marked
Humboldt has to be marked humble and you
can't be outside of Humboldt and market
that so these are new challenges too you
know just small-time regional realities
that Sam come on we barely here much
less at that international level where
we could import export we can even get
it to where we can't even get it over
state lines I mean even County to County
it's challenging here in California were
considered this liberal Bastion when
we're still just in the muck right now
so I look forward to those days to Sam
because I would love to be able to you
know import Moroccan or Lebanese or you
know some of the other you know exotic
cannabis that you know especially those
genetics that are being found in Africa
currently you know there's a lot of
stuff that has a lot to do with our pure
certification that we started I mean if
you look at those industries like the
beer industry I mean Oregon was one of
the first like big microbrews States to
really promote microbrewing and have
micro brews as a thing and if you go
into the stores in Oregon I mean it's an
explosion of micro brews and some of
them are really really successful and
really amazing so pure farmers and pure
certified farmers are making a
difference they have their own unique
you know soils and brands their own you
they tell their story and it's more of
like a farm-to-table farm to seed soil
to table soil to Bowl whatever you want
to call it you know it's it's people
showing why they're not different and
when you go to those other countries it
sounds really exotic when you're here
with the minute you show up there you
find out that all the banned pesticides
from the US are there and who the hell
knows what they put in their soil so
honestly I
don't want to smoke that stuff from that
country because I know about paraquat
and [__] that's been sprayed all over
Mexico and until we go there or someone
else goes there with some some like some
values and morals and and says oh or
yeah no these people are totally growing
of nature then now I can take that
medicine and put it into my body for my
nine year old is the reason why we you
know as you all are saying we need to
join together more on an international
level you know we've been in the in the
black market and all of these really
large corporations are joining together
they are talking to major companies they
are buying huge land shares of these you
know greenhouses of cut flowers they've
already been doing this for years and
set up for it and I believe that it is
imperative that we all join together and
that we do have a louder voice because
our voice is the culture of cannabis and
we have to stay unique because that's
what they don't have is something unique
well you got a hope that people from all
different countries are being inspired
by conversations like the ones that
we're having and that there's going to
be people who do things on the highest
level possible in all of these different
countries and of course just like
everything there will be you know many
people who don't do it with the highest
of integrity that's just the way the
world works I compare it to you know
look at how many people wear non organic
cotton and eat non-organic food and buy
the cheapest beers and wine and the
cheapest cigarettes and the cheapest
everything so it's money is a big sort
of controlling factor in the world and
we're kind of in a first world where we
get to sort of be self righteous but
when people are working their fingers to
the bones for pennies it's a really big
deal to you know be able to save money
where they can and buy things that are
as inexpensive as possible of course
they want the highest caliber I'm
certain but some people is just not an
economic reality for them also to the
honest truth is that I mean products are
not grown organically in California when
they tested it 60% of it had
contamination from pesticides and
fungicides I mean Jesus
pointing at the foreign companies who
may or may not be more guilty
why don't we clean up our own act first
that's been a challenge I agree and one
that has been you know that's why we
started testing in the first place
that's why we we you know we had to
reinvent the wheel so that we could know
what's in there but yes it is still
frustrating when you know we test
everything and everything when I was on
my floor we hope to set those types of
examples to do things right but it has
also shown us over the last 19 years now
how many people won't do it right so
that also shows that we have to be the
stewards we have to foster the
environment we have to be the integrity
leaders that show people otherwise
you're just tossed in with the mess of
it we're not setting the example that
needs to be set and it's hard it's
expensive it's not [__] easy but if
you want to do it right you have to do
it right and it's well worth doing it
right you know I don't want somebody
something to affect somebody to kill
somebody you know somebody's son or
daughter because of you know a pesticide
that wasn't screened for it gets through
and becomes a toxic shock to their body
and next thing you know I've got another
death on my hands I got enough of that
from war I don't need any of that
further but how many people have our
type of integrity how many people like
you Sam went out there when you realize
that cannabis wasn't there that you
actually went out there and hunted down
those genetics and then created the
genetics that we all share and enjoy
today you know we need more people I
also try to help people have an
alternative with my pest and disease
book to try to show people you don't
have to use poisons there is a higher
road that's an amazing book by the way
for anyone that hasn't checked it out
that is definitely some you want to take
a course in cannabis pests and diseases
that book is the one some of its
education as well because you know we
had a problem it's a cloud-based network
with people who were trying to grow
clean but when we started making the
extracts we were seeing micro butanol
pop up and other things that was finally
tracked down the systemic pesticide
issues for
nurseries that they assumed were okay
you know so I think still I think we're
seeing a higher failure rate we had the
destroy 40% of what was donated to us
because of pesticide poisoning or
pesticide you know showing up in
contaminants but some of the people who
did that or donated those things so
there were people who were great in
spirit and doing everything clean and so
we had the trapper back to where it was
coming from and so it's the general
industry as a whole I think is their
understanding better how some of these
work I think we're gonna see really a
more separation from people with good
intentions but are still just have this
systemic problem and the people who just
don't care and they're still praying
it's raining and this is exactly what
we're talking about I mean you can't
trust the USDA or the federal government
of any countries to tell you that what
you're using is safe you have to go
beyond that and trust your gut and know
what's happening in nature so everything
that's happening on on farms that we
work with and pee and other people they
have to test every single thing that
comes on their property because the
whole point of cannabis is that it pulls
what's in the soil up into the plant and
also and also with rooms with with
clones and stuff michael--ah butanol is
almost like a radiating element you can
have a room not even used and then have
and then have people come back in and
use it again and there's still problems
with it you you have to be smarter than
the system you have to be able to to go
beyond and it's really really important
and and Eric's talking about the cut
flower things that in Santa Barbara and
Central California I think it would be
really really really difficult to grow a
really clean product no matter who you
are the whole environment is really
really taxed we're gonna be taking over
large land shares you know in other
countries or in California got those
land shares and and that soil is TOC
stout and remediation has to take you
know immediate precedents before
anything else you know when you go and
you buy a piece of land in order to be
integral the first thing that you're
thinking is how am I going to remediate
this yeah and the soils that don't just
remediate or
one cycle of composting or what it takes
like a year two years you know three
years a big work and that's why Humboldt
Mendocino in California or around Chico
or even Grass Valley are really
important for cannabis growing so what
do you think Eric
they've been dumped on though - I mean
surprisingly enough all my travels I'm
starting to meet a lot of old breeders
or people not old breeders but people
that have been around a long time we
would consider the pioneers in the
industry and unfortunately a good
portion of everybody I've met didn't
know Eagle 20 was bad back in the day
and so it's been used and it's in there
it's you know roundup when they when
they talk about the percentages of kids
that when they take a pee and they test
their pee for roundup it's it's in
everything basically they're saying and
so when I did the moderating at the
emerald-cut for the panel on the
pesticides you know one of the things
the labs and the Department of pesticide
regulation said is what is the metric
for clean because really everything is
contaminated so how do we find zero for
cleanliness and go from there because
everything ultimately is contaminated to
a certain level so I mean it might seems
kind of scary and saying that what you
can't you know in reality it is but at
the end of the day what's happening
right now is the cannabis industry
forced its own people out and so now we
have a whole new generation of people
and don't get me wrong there's a lot of
pioneers involved but a lot of those
pioneers are big names for other reasons
they weren't necessarily big growers
they were big companies for one week
maybe it was a type of genetic it was a
type of an extract or whatever and so
they weren't technically big large but
they get investors to throw this big
lump of money find a place in Salinas of
Santa Barbara and they want to set up
shop and then everybody grabs their
darts and starts throwing the darts at
the dartboard basically and they try to
figure it out and what I saw in Santa
Barbara in some of these places is you
know we're gonna move into some of those
old wooden greenhouses the greenhouse
megastructures are these big cut flower
farms are still operating their farms
but they've scaled down to barely one
greenhouse let's say on their meg
megha farm and so what they do is they
lease out the biggest pieces of [__]
left on the farm to the cannabis growers
and so the cannabis growers go to these
old wooden [__] basically and have
to fix them up because Santa Barbara
County won't let you build a new
greenhouse you have to fix up what's
already there and so then people go in
and spend a ton of money trying to fix
up a greenhouse and they go broke before
they even get a plant in the ground and
then the second person comes along and
leases that greenhouse and then they
continue working on it and put a ton of
money into it they go under and then the
third person gets to move in and the
third person's actually stoked because
the third person you know has all this
[__] done that the first two people ran
out of money trying to accomplish so I
mean it's really funny to see how much
money is going into everything to the
people throwing darts and the big names
that really might not be the people to
scale up but the investors want to run
on the big name they don't necessarily
know that the clean beautiful flower is
what's gonna make the make the win but
you know rather cling to the big names
and then all the other people that
couldn't get permits all the people that
know what they're doing that's been
educated are pioneering you know family
members so to speak or left without
permits and kind of in the dust and now
who are they well I think the soil is a
big part of it like dragonfly Earth
medicine crew was mentioning there and I
think on the other side if you look at
the majority of plants produced clonally
micropropagation and tissue culture is
an answer to being able to clean out
pathogens and fungi zand microbials from
plants that have been impregnated over
generations with just incredible amounts
of systemic problems you know including
things like micro butanol and and all
these horrible eagle 20s and and just
ridiculous pesticides it's definitely a
way you know if we start looking at that
to start sort of cleaning up and
renewing vigor on these plants and it
seems to be working for many other
different clonally produced plants
around the globe it's just gonna take
some time and our testing is levelling
up as we go with legalization so
technically right now there's medical
mixed in with recreational
um you know a lot of the rollout
California had anyway isn't going as
expected as far as how to deal with the
medical and the recreational that's left
over from last year and so I think
there's just a lot of gray areas and
yeah there are solutions and I agree
with you there are answers and we can
get to where we need to be but
unfortunately with this California the
way it is I guess you should say we're
gonna go through we're gonna be going
through some [__] for a couple years I
think in order to get this organized and
it really makes no sense at all because
my club butanol and small percentages
can be used on strawberries wellness
everywhere like eating that berry
growers so you know in Salinas area
their strawberries everywhere and
lettuce and you know in Mendocino and
other places there's tons of grapes and
wine and then when you go to Santa
Barbara there's tons of avocados so one
of the greenhouse facilities I was at
was you know a major greenhouse facility
with five different farms or four at
least on the same property and the
neighbor next door was about to spray
with the helicopter avid on his avocados
because that's what they do once a year
so you know over here you got the orchid
grow with their exhaust fans blowing out
this way towards the cannabis grower the
neighbor that literally has his branches
of trees hanging over the fence going
I'm about to spray avid on my avocados I
do it once a year and everybody's trying
to do these sealed greenhouses sucking
in all this air and blowing it all out
and I can't say that passive would solve
the problem either in some of those
situations but I mean everybody's kind
of in fear you know if you're not if you
don't have a permit and you're about to
jump off you know you got these people
that are permitted and they don't you
know it's like it's just the whole
coming unglued situation right now on
how to sort it all out with the speed of
lightning that needs to get done because
investors want to see returns now and
they want to see the money coming back
and everybody like I said with their
dart throwing capabilities of you know
resorted to two gallon pots or one
gallon pots you know kind of see a green
and maybe it's gonna be organic or not
but we all know that it's not gonna be
living soiler or you know no-till or
anything like that so I mean the organic
words
definitely like you guys know Kelly and
Josh the word organic is watered down
and you know organic produce from other
countries isn't organic even though it
says it is it's just not so I mean you
know what's the level of cleanliness
that we can go by I guess you could say
and it might just have to go for where
you are and your farm and your personal
situation in order to do that because
the conglomerates are gonna have a tough
time that's why it's all extracts anyway
but as Forrest was saying you know a lot
of the extracts get thrown out and I
heard some people up north are taking
the approach like the chemical company
dilution is the solution and you know
this isn't this is this is even it isn't
even a conversation about glyphosate you
know that that's that's a conversation
that nobody is even having we have to
test you know um all of our all of our
inputs you know for our products and
that's like a really long list of herbs
and we go to areas all over and try to
find small farmers and then we're
testing their glyphosate levels even
though you know and that's outside of
the realm because you know the USDA
feels like glyphosate can be put in a
baby bottle and babies can drink it they
don't see it as something that's totally
toxic yeah we know but we know over
prolonged use that it kills soil
microbiology and if we're killing soil
microbiology then we're killing all of
the microbes inside of our gut and then
that just takes away our intelligence
and I feel like you know the glyphosate
conversation is something that hasn't
even been talked about because it's not
something that they're testing for in
cannabis testing for in you know all of
our organic fruits and vegetable I
didn't really realize that they didn't
test for molds in Oregon or was it
Washington or Oregon I didn't really I
saw I was reading some stuff and there
was somebody that opened up a bud out of
a dispensary and it was covered in mold
and I guess you know it's not it's not
something they test for up there is that
true yeah they're not testing for any
kind of molds or fungi at this point
right now because they can't
differentiate the DNA between them so
you know whatever counts like say lactic
ass
bacteria there's 36 or even more
different types of species of lactic
acid that floats around in the
environment if it lands on your flower
it's really only a beneficial to us but
it's still going to come up as a
negative on the test they can't
differentiate the DNA species so they've
done away with it and actually that's
not true they can differentiate Kevin
McCarty can but they're not doing it is
what I'm saying it's a very yes they
definitely can and they aren't doing it
I think because of the cost of that test
and maybe you have something to say
about that Kevin curtains gonna come in
later on today as well Sam okay let him
deal with it yeah he said he should be
popping in in in a little bit here so
hopefully he'll be it will be able to
pick that up when he comes in and ask
him about that because that's definitely
very very important that they're testing
for these things I mean it's just the
level of cleanliness depends on you know
this farmers and the testing labs to
kind of do the due diligence and you
know from what you hear from a lot of
flower people or farmers that you know
testing labs aren't always the same from
one to another and that can be kind of
confusing as well for people to you know
make their path forward if one lab
saying one thing and another lab saying
another whether it's passed or fail or
percentages or these terpenes you know
people are trying to use the labs also
to brand their products with you know
what they do include in them you know
what's included is really important from
the lab but unfortunately we find out a
lot of things that you know there is an
easy solution for that which is they all
have to use the same testing protocol
and it gets checked by an independent
agency it doesn't matter which state or
whatever there is a proper protocol and
that should be used really we need that
in California in the sense there needs
to be some sort of a laboratory
regulation industry which is of course
now the BCC is supposed but they're
they've dragged their feet just getting
us certified with just these emergency
regulations which we have to
and get recertified every three months
until the permanent regs so yeah we're
trying to get there Sam which is time
well that's the challenge is like we
need regulation but we're being
regulated to death you know
and you know as cannabis and wait could
probably talk about maybe some of what
he's doing but getting in with the AG
commissions locally and some of the
farmers you know when you speak with
them they say you know one of the fears
they have is looking at cannabis is an
AG product they're already dying small
farmers are dying because they are over
regulated already and then cannabis adds
this whole other level to it that it's
just kind of has other industries
looking going oh if they can do it to
them they can do it to us too you know
which is why I think getting involved in
the in the AG committees and commissions
at the local level and beyond is really
important for cannabis work in the in
the future and the more people that test
the prices will come down because I'm
seeing people writing you know the
testing prices are high you goddamn
right they're high you should have seen
what it cost me when I was pioneering
this 11 years ago you wouldn't want to
see the expense but it is one of those
necessary evils I had to swallow and
deal with so that we could arrive at a
point where we actually have you know
ring testing and satellite testing so
that we could verify that these
laboratories were actually doing what
you know Sam was saying actually showing
proper protocol or you know the big
frustration I had was then people tried
to proprietor make their testing a
proprietary situation so that we
couldn't even see what the [__]
testing was you know so it's been a
fight all the way through in one that
has to be fought all the way to the end
well we don't want to see you know
lesion
go ahead Sam attend at least you had a
choice of lab or labs when I started
there were no labs
Dero well that's the same thing I had I
had zero labs I had to bring people from
around the world and create that first
lab now if that lab is spread to others
but yes I agree I was in the same boat
as you I had to reinvent the wheel
because the Research Triangle wouldn't
give us anything I had to buy the GC
by the HPLC and build a laboratory and
hire a scientist just for in-house use
well that's Martin dude that's your like
on the next level you're an inspiration
yeah you took the bullet so that all I
had to do is deal with people already
had the machines you know what I'm
saying so I agree I respect that I
didn't have to spend the quarter million
dollars of three quarters of a million
dollars on the type of machinery that is
really required to actually do that and
that's for real folks that's what those
machines cost that was ten years ago
which means they cost even more today I
just want to add that the photo I was
holding up while we were talking this is
a macro photograph of powdery mildew so
for those of you that have never seen
powdery mildew up close it looks like
little little little bug bodies they
just stack on top of one another and
they create these long sort of strings
and you can see the size of them versus
the size of the glandular trichomes
they're quite thin and quite small but
they get everywhere they wrap themselves
around the resin there's no escaping it
it's definitely a bad scene and in the
photograph does it penetrate the resin
or can they be separated I haven't seen
it penetrate the resin Sam but how is
that for timing Kevin mckernon is in the
room and we're talking about microbials
and being able to test to decipher the
difference between and we're showing a
macro photograph of powdery mildew right
now for my Instagram account while it
I'll send it to you if you like
absolutely mycelium ah that's it and
welcome back to hash Church first one in
a hundred and forty days yeah we don't
you grew a beard huh well you know I've
been busy Wow so you're not getting
kicked off YouTube like everyone else
huh is the church in the name yeah I
don't know I've just been really not
rocking the boat I haven't made any
videos talking about it I've heard
people making videos to talk about it
and getting their channels deleted so
I'm just praying that we make it through
you know I've just this more than
anything that my channel is great and
fun but really this particular show with
all of you
people being able to come in once every
Sunday to me is the most valuable thing
and I'll do anything to protect it d -
there's a decentralized version of this
and sitting in on the ipfs that's like
uncensored wall so could keep your
videos in case they yeah they trying
come back in them all up absolutely and
welcome d4 20k to the room dude what's
going on then let's go on everybody
that's what I'm saying right there so
there's a 400 people in the room waiting
for you to say that bone rep mother
lovers let's [__] do this there's the
book House of Harlequin or a house of
laughter hemp diseases and pests
management and biological control that's
the book you want to look up yet JM
McPartland RC Clarke and DP Watson the
serious serious book right there it's a
heavy book and it's an expensive book it
ain't cheap no but it's not worth
supporting it's the real deal yes but
that product I mean if you look at the
cost of the knowledge and the knowledge
that's in it it is priceless it is well
worth any expense that's there if you
want to do things naturally and properly
thank you Sam and thank you rob Clark
for showing us how to [__] do it
right and bless you I guess like hey
what are you reading and what's the book
and I think well it's 260 dollars and it
comes out of this University
a lot of people don't want to spend it
but you know if you really want to learn
those are the books with the information
or they're not cheap also Johnny
McPartland
John McPartlin contributed to that book
probably as much or more than me and Rob
Rob took the pictures I had the hands-on
practical knowledge and John had his
nose buried in libraries and research
things to find all the information that
I didn't know and Rob didn't know but it
together the three of us were an
unbeatable team
did any macro photos end up in that book
I don't
I don't remember to be honest I don't
have a copy with me yeah no I can't
remember either I think I sent some for
some reason but I can't keep up with
which ones get in and which ones don't
so it is a great book regardless of any
macro photographs the information that
it is I mean it's a resource that you
just if you're growing cannabis and
you're dealing with pests and diseases
which you are if you're growing cannabis
you're gonna want to have this
information in your library and it's
only in hardback as far as I know right
Sam I've never seen it soft back no
paper man you almost need to come out
with a ringed copy so that you could
easily turn the pages if it's just in
case you come up with another one there
is Sam in the future reference book then
a growers hands on manual in the
greenhouse but yeah we thought about it
but we just didn't do it I want to speak
about the testing thing again that was a
knee up I had to step out for a minute
but the other night I heard I was in a
conversation with a fellow who was one
of the pioneers in the organic food
movement who lives here in our area and
he had many things to say but one of the
things he pointed out is that there are
more than a thousand chemical compounds
that are certified for use on food
products in California and all of them
have to do with controlling pests or
diseases and meantime how will we ever
ask our labs to be able to test for that
many compounds in cannabis I really want
to suggest that dragonfly Earth you you
guys have nailed down to me the real
concept about how to do this which is to
know your sources know all the inputs to
your garden over time you can remediate
your soil and the environment you're in
and by making your own inputs you have a
fair sense of knowing that your product
the material you're producing will in
fact be free of contaminants
and then it's a matter of building a
back story behind you and your work and
what you're producing that makes it
worth it in the agricultural market
because if Tomatoes is a good example in
California there are people who grow
tomatoes they get paid 14 cents a pound
for their tomatoes of course they're
selling it in 40,000 pound trucks
there's other people who get paid $4 a
pound for their tomatoes and I suggest
that cannabis has a much wider
discretionary marketplace if you will
for what we call top shelf but when you
start talking about medical need for me
it's really about the producers have to
know what they're doing that's why that
book is so important to me Sam thank you
so that you know when you offer some oil
to one of these families you know that
it's going to be free of contaminants
even if it's been to the lab and it's
tested for what's there they're only
testing for 20-some different pesticides
I don't remember we can test for 39
currently but out of the thousand and
subject certified in California for you
direct but you know ten years ago we had
zero okay so this shows you the length
and time that science takes it's not
fast you know Kevin can speak to it very
very precisely you know science can't be
rushed you know it has to be done it has
to be replicated it has to be done
properly and so each year we're able to
add and add other pesticides as we get
them and then the laboratories can
quantify or they can get the actual
standards to actually quantify and then
it's then added to the list so then we
have 40 that we can test for but it
shows you and that should give you an
everybody an idea of the drop in the
water we're still dealing with and we're
supposedly doing it right I'd be
interested in an explorer in the world
of microbials too as far as testing and
you know you you you want to have the
alternative to the pesticides you know
you may be talking about you know
microbial growth and biological growth
from soils and also potentially your
foliar spray
if maybe Kevin you can you can went way
in on this you know is it hard to tell
the difference between probiotic
microbials and pathogenic microbes or or
trichoderma and botrytis yeah so that's
a good point in Kyle Boyer just did a
great webinar on this with the can group
last week I'll try and for that link
around on this but the attractive derma
is key for getting rid of Aspergillus I
mean the the the problem we have is the
well the probably not in California
where Calum or California put writes
down they're a very species specific so
that you're not getting penalized for
using beneficial microbes but in many
states that are still following the AHP
they have language in there that looks
like it forces you to use Petri films
which can't discern the two they try to
count things and colony forming units
and so you really can't discern
trichoderma from Aspergillus from these
other harmful ones and the other thing
that we ran into very recently we were
doing a lot of sequencing with digi path
labs in Nevada trying to figure out when
molecular techniques differ from yeah
from from the actual plating that
happens and what we were finding is
there's a lot of rust onea that shows up
and real Stoney a is a is a bacteria
that lives inside of a fungus so it's an
endo fungal bacterial so when you try
and plate this you don't you might get a
mold colony but you could have a
thousand you know of these pathogenic
bacteria in it you won't be counting
those when you start counting colonies
so this thing also makes what's known as
a rise of toxin and so it's both the
human pathogen it causes plant wilt and
it also makes a mycotoxin so it's a
pretty nasty thing and it's sometimes a
days a lot of the the culturing
techniques because it likes to hang
outside of other fungi and Kevin is the
bacteria as a clump a lot is the
bacterium itself damaging to humans yes
there's something there's something
called it has a disease name that's like
raus tinnitus or something where Estonia
gets into their lungs and so it can be
infected there are some cases of
of illness from this I don't know that
anything's been tied
cannabis derived illness but they have
seen in hospitals and so it's usually
with like cystic fibrosis patients or
canvas patients I'm sorry I cancer
patients so it can't have some human
health and it can form it can you know
make the plants have some wilt as well
so we've probably got to pick that one
up and make sure that we can discern it
from from fungi it does in fact ask for
gilles and there's a there's a list of
like twenty different fungi that that it
does in fact then when it infects them
it makes them clump and form these
chlamydia spores which is one of these
survival modes if the fungi go into and
that alone can make them really
difficult to quantitate because once the
fungi start to the clump when you put
them on plate you can't tell one colony
from a thousand they're there so good
things not that lands on them so i think
that's really key for the whole
pesticide things i'm not very well
versed on all the pesticide limits and
then put in place yet in california but
i do know people were debating on the
parts per million of the parts per
billion but one thing we do see is a lot
of fungicide use and we're worried that
people are being driven to use
fungicides because these plating systems
often give you false positives and tell
you that you have fungus when you don't
there's a lot of bacteria that grow on
these plates and you can't really
discern them from the fungi so you know
if you're using the simplest and
trichoderma those could end up giving
you false positives on these culturing
systems and that would signal the
growers hey you should use more
fungicides because you've gotta find
this problem when you really have just a
bacillus problem and you're in this is
actually probably your best thing to
fight against it so are they actually
using that in the soil or on the plant i
don't know how folks are using i'm
assuming it comes up from the roots
because it's i think it's meant to be
helpful for nitrogen fixation my next
question how does he get on the plant if
it's only applied in the soil that's how
we used yeah so a lot of these things
when they get into the roots they
actually vascular eyes like Fusarium
gets into the roots and vascular eyes is
all through the xylem and phloem and
we've been actually been doing biopsy
works throughout the plants figure out
the you know can we pick it up in the
leaves or do we have to do course core
preps
well you take a whole bunch out of the
stem to see if you can pick it up from
there but it does seem to be following
what you guys were writing about in that
book which is it comes in through the
through the roots and if you do stem
preps you can pick up Fusarium much more
of it than you can if you try and sample
it out the leaves
I think the still is slow to your point
Sam is that they are they tend to spray
that one on that's more like a foliar
spray for a lot of plants I see that at
like in products called serenade it's
something that you'll find the garden
source which is a facilitative brand
Lance so yeah they can be in different
places and sometimes I vascularized that
sometimes or not we had a few cancer
patients die in California do you
remember that ATM is last year I believe
from fungal infections was that asked
for Julis do you know it was to them
yeah so they were concerned about
Aspergillus
Nucor and there's a couple other in that
paper I think Thompson is the one who
published that paper I'll try to XD I
can get that one for everybody and
that's why we wanted to test for pestis
I mean not only pesticides and
herbicides but also for fungus because
remember back in 2006 when I got an
upper respiratory infection we used all
our organic lepak testing to you know
that for our visual standpoint and I
still got sick which means there was
something microbial there that we
couldn't see so that's why you know in
one of the reasons why it took takes so
long is because it takes 72 hours for
playtests people that means it has to
they have to take it they have to put it
on a plate and it's got to sit there for
72 hours incubating so then it can pop
up so just to have a quick 24 hour test
it Kevin doesn't Elle quick oh yeah I do
it and I'm just giving a layman's term
for people I yeah we're using DNA to try
and find those things and there was
another one in Bakersfield actually that
just came out this year there was an
outbreak for cryptococcal meningitis in
a Bakersfield dispensary the patient
didn't die but the patient got
hospitalized with a with a lung
infection that eventually ended up
getting to her brain
so that's one that we probably have to
add the list because it has been seen a
lot of HIV patients and it's one that
it's not currently being tested for but
in fact I think they did nine more
sampling to the dispensary and found
that almost all of them but this was a
patient who was going in and buying the
cheapest blunts that they should like it
the pre-rolls and they were more or less
that was their habit as it always went
there probably three joints a day and
they were constantly getting kind of the
bottom of the barrel pre-rolls so yeah
note to self you know the other thing is
I think that we're gonna be seeing way
more fungal infections and way more
bacterial infections of pathogens on
both humans and plants we're seeing it
in soils you know excuse me the more and
more soil tests that were that we're
getting back you know from all of these
farms all over is the aluminum rates are
going through the roof the iron rates
are going through the roof these heavy
metals that were dealing with are so
vast and all of the the phyto toxins and
chemicals that are happening are killing
our microbiome not only in our own body
but also on tent life and and in the in
the eco sphere so I think that it's
really important that while we're still
looking at and defining all of these
different pathogens we need to also be
looking at beneficials and defining
beneficials and how they can be helpful
because I don't think that no matter
what kind of science that we can throw
at it the most important thing is that
nature is going to take care of itself
and she has over and over again and I
believe that you know that's the real
solution and answer is there an L
quicker way to do the DNA testing
because that seems to be the most
effective way to discern between
pathogenic and non-pathogenic and with
bacillus itself I mean there's a
thousand difference just you know that's
just a number I'm throwing up about many
difference between a bacillus we know
the bacillus isn't in the soil we know
the bacillus is good in our intestines
and lower intestines and we have
bacillus in our natural mystic sprays
and and and we find it really beneficial
but it can turn out to be a positive so
in general I avoided using sprays
because
the false positives that were coming up
for beneficials I the last thing I was
using was BTI
again against caterpillars and luckily I
was only breeding I wasn't producing
medicine from people but I wondered what
was BT I would it pass the testing that
that is being done in the various states
now I don't know I'm not certain so
Lister oh I think that was well yeah
that one would probably trigger a total
of robic count it wouldn't trigger
anything in California because
California right now just has coli
Salmonella and 4s for jello species and
those we can do in a very targeted
manner we target weak right down to the
species level and that's important there
have been cases of Aspergillus failures
that are disputed in Alaska there's that
there's speed up there between I think
one lab was calling it resilience s when
it was really asked for jealous it was
actually asked for the resilience but
they failed that thinking was
Aspergillus Niger because they couldn't
speciate it on a film and the lab that
was using DNA techniques could actually
differentiated so it can get you can get
very very specific with a DNA test the
hard thing to do with the DNA test is to
go after these these categories like
total Grove accounts and total yeast and
mold we do have a way to do that but
it's very hard to get it to be
concordant with the platings because the
platings don't necessarily select for
like the mold plates can grow bacteria
and so it makes it really hard if you
get a test that has it comes out with a
tentacle see if used for gram as a plate
because the plates have so many pitfalls
I mean 99% microbes don't culture there
just know how to culture them yet so
we're missing the vast majority of
microbiome when we slowly start using
those culture systems but we have made
tests that try to address the HP the HP
has these guidelines that are written in
total aerobic counts and total yeast and
mold and those ones are very very vague
categories that we think actually do
more harm than good
[Music]
excellent conversation guys really
really enjoying the in-depth
conversation on testing and bacteria and
just the health of cannabis in general
it is definitely a fight or remediate of
plant it can pull things up out of the
soil there's no doubt about it so I'm
just gonna say quickly you know some of
the things that that were brought up by
a dragonfly folks here is you know I
think the cannabis community is we learn
more about it will hopefully be expect
higher expectations out of what they
purchase I mean it's hard when people
are if they want cheap if they want low
quality you're gonna get it and that
risk is gonna come along with it but as
we understand more about the gut in the
microbiome how that is so closely
intertwined with neurological function
and we're learning more about the debt
in the brain and how its tied together
we can start to realize that if we
especially if we're using cannabis to
treat something medicinally that these
things aren't you know something that
you can separate you have to be able to
know that what you're doing to your the
things that affect your gut and your
body are going to also impact whatever
neurological thing you might be treating
whether it be you know bipolar or
schizophrenic or mental health
conditions chronic migraine heaven
forbid seizure disorders you name them
all these things all these points are
important and I think if as people are
more educated as consumers hopefully
that expectation is translated into the
behavior of the people who are trying to
get their business and also you know
becoming more educated on better health
and well-being I believe that you know
healthy soil does have all of the
answers to a healthy mind and body you
know it has all of the components that
it needs to be able to grow something
healthy in the same way that we can
easily look at soil and be able to mimic
that you know bio structure that's
happening there and I believe that the
more that we look towards nature and the
more that we
have an understanding of what health
really looks like because it's been so
diminished over such a long period of
time then we really can grant gain that
intelligence I believe that we can't
even separate our intelligence from
Bennett from the beneficial microbiome
that's going on within ourselves as well
yeah there's a lot of work coming out
now showing that your your gut flora
have a big impact on things like
Parkinson's and Alzheimer's and all
these chronic diseases when they start
doing fecal transplants they see very
very striking results yeah the fecal
implants have been really important Ida
and I believe that you know we're really
trying to do the same thing I always go
back and forth from health to soil and
plants to health I can't really separate
them and I believe that you know what
they're doing with fecal implants is
sort of the same thing that we're doing
with remediation of soil when we're
adding a massive amount of beneficial
microbiology into a soil to remediate it
it's the same way that these fecal
implants are really gaining a great
momentum because you know Department of
Agriculture hasn't really given those
incredible studies they haven't looked
beyond you know necessarily the NPK you
know we're just learning about
dissecting DNA of fungi and bacteria and
I believe that you know once we're
starting to see it within human health
we're gonna really start to understand
it even more because more money is put
towards human health and understanding
the microbiome in there and the more
work and research that we do in that
area you know the more that we're going
to gain the intelligence that we need to
be able to overcome all of these
pathogens that we're talking about yeah
so there is a study out from CDC
recently in OSHA getting a little bit
concerned over the Canada's trimming
Environment posted up right here so they
evaluated the health hazards of that
that trimming grants might run into and
this is the results of this which is
that there's high exposure to I guess
powdery mildew which I think you were
just showing off some mycelium and and
also to botrytis I don't know why that's
gonna go but there was a case here in
Massachusetts where one of the employees
sued
I can't remember which company was the
one of the growers here is getting sued
by employee because they broke down
rashes the trimming room and problem we
have here is some of the testing labs
are using culturing which doesn't
actually culture botrytis or PM so they
can't really see the problem and help
guide that the dispensary or the grower
on this so it's a yeah bit of an issue
here
you tube sorry what about the use of
isopropyl alcohol and it's buildup on
the liver and is there alternatives that
people can use besides isopropyl alcohol
doesn't everyone you people will be
using in oils and in ethanol didn't
hazen camp paper shown in like olive oil
or probably some of the best things for
extracting and keeping all the terpenes
i agree with that in lipid extraction is
amazing i mean i think that yeah yeah i
won't let any of our kids or the
families to work with get anywhere near
isopropyl at all so i see some people
doing it once in a while but you know
it's kind of like when you know RSO was
first getting sort of some attention in
naphtha was used all the time you know
and it just started to trickle to
isopropyl and now the isopropyl is
thankfully dying off and don't see it
very much but I'd be careful with
naphtha it has rust and lead inhibitor
that's put into it it's kind of a
greenish bluish tinge and you really
have to run that through a still and and
and clean that up I obviously I'm not
using many solvents at all when I'm
extracting but definitely if you're
going to you should try to try to get
them as clean as possible and I just
wanted to add in the middle of this
great conversation that I do have
Hillary black stopping by really briefly
she's doing a old woman's panel today at
lift but she's gonna stop in just for 15
or 20 minutes and tell us a little bit
about her recent conversations she had
with the Senate here in Canada in
Ontario in Ottawa our capital city and
so she'll be here in a little bit so
unfortunately I won't want to be rude
but when she gets here wherever our
conversation is we're just gonna pause
let
say her piece and then get to what she
has to do because of course she's very
busy so I just wanted to add that
awesome yeah it should be good
should be good I'm always and what about
you Micah you have anything to add today
you've been very quiet but I see you
there sitting and listening and feeling
intrigued yeah another conversation is
good I was having Samara computer issues
there for a while so I missed the front
half of the conversation but uh can you
guys hear me already
absolutely okay yeah one of the things
you know Erik kind of touched down a
little bit and you know that I've
noticed a lot over the last couple years
when it comes to testing and pesticide
use and all that one of the things we've
got this distribution company we've been
working on out of Mendocino and we're
testing flower and trim all you know all
the time hundreds of test results off of
all these different forms and we thought
that you know as all these bigger farms
came on lawn down in Salinas and that we
you know maybe it would be a good idea
for us to get down in that area and
start testing some of that material what
we found is that most that material down
there was dirty and for that and it's
not so much that that the forms
themselves are that they're not you know
their practices are good but they've got
these neighbors that are down the road
that are contaminating all of their
product and so it got to the point where
you know I agree with what Eric was
saying it's like there there's something
to be said for these farms that are in
Humboldt - you know Grass Valley view's
like more out-of-the-way areas where
it's easier to keep your product clean
um yeah that's rough having your
neighbor jump in the helicopter and
spray a couple of metric gallons of a
vyd is just like my skin was crawling
when he was saying that I was just like
that's that's heinous there's more
greenhouses standing around when the I
guess there was a shipment of the
average showed up and it went to the
rock it went to the growers address and
it was
the neighbors and so all these growers
are standing around going whose palette
I have it is this there was like not me
not me but yeah sure enough it went to
the guy next door with the helicopter no
less of in everybody's there suffering
from avid shame that's one of the
concerns that we see in some of the
counties here in California's are really
trying to push it out of the hills right
they want to get it more to the flat
agricultural lands and you know idols
it did cabbage some other you know
commodity that you can put next to those
really know the Central Valley in
California has been sprayed for decades
you know there's like we've said there's
no clean place just with the wind alone
and this whole push to get it sort of
out of the hills one of the reasons that
can the cannabis is so clean just like
we've just said here in Nevada County
and up in Humboldt Mendocino is that
there isn't that sort of other
agricultural farmland that it just has a
culture of just spraying whatever you
know it's been it's been nasty so I hope
that people who are in those counties
when they start to hear that push
understand how that push to kind of
uproot the culture of cannabis in the
hills of Northern California is also
going to equal to a really difficult
time sourcing and finding the quality of
cannabis and clean canvas you need
because it's gonna take years to clean
up some of these places before I would
touch what's being grown yeah but do you
then you've got places like Calaveras
County that open up their doors and then
shut their doors so that's where do
these people go you're literally through
prohibition of local you know locality
is forcing these people into going into
Central Valley into going into the
regular agricultural areas because of
the you know the fear of prohibition or
whatever the hell happened in Calaveras
County which you know it should be a
wake-up call and a realistic focusing of
everybody no matter what [__] county
you in you need to stay on top of what's
actually going on and stay in tune and
plugged yourself in you know if you know
I'm I hear people say you know I'm so
tired of you know I I don't really think
about you know you know voting and doing
things like that well you know what you
know you may not think politics involves
you but you know your boss is involved
in politics your landlords involved in
politics your insurance companies are
involved in politics and all they're
doing is using their political will to
make their lives much more comfortable
so if you don't think that you have any
reason to be involved you better check
yourself because all kinds of people
wasted hundreds of thousands if not
millions of dollars investing in
Calaveras County only have their door
shut on them in the county said [__] off
I don't think people realize how much
influence they have if they're you know
there's just apathy that we just can't
do anything and that's just not true
I mean it is work though you know we
were in Nevada County we were all out
ban they were put it on the measure just
specifically to make it so that the
Future Board of Supervisors couldn't
change it right that's how much of a man
they wanted to implement here and you
know with a lot of activism and a lot of
work we were able to defeat it and can
didn't stop from there and now we're at
a point where you know we are having
ordinances coming up it's going to be
issuing commercial licenses you know
from the place with Placer County and
all around the Sierra County where were
everywhere is in the band and but it
went from work we would absolutely just
be in a band if we sat at home and said
hey this sucks it's not fair and the
same on the state level we started
applying that at the state level and you
know in the BCC we haven't gotten into
this too much but we're looking at and
helping develop new license types we're
looking to actually shape what cannabis
is going to look like you know and
that's you know what cannabis looks like
now in our communities it's not what it
should have or would look like if we
hadn't had prohibition what we have now
it's just like in the you know I'd like
to equate it is this this beautiful you
know girl who a child that was locked in
a basement for 40 years right
and we kind of opened the door and let
her out and she comes out so yeah I
can't see it's bright and we think that
that's we're just gonna make that legal
now and continue to do that you know we
are at a point now where we can
absolutely shake how cannabis is
integrated into our lives and into our
communities and we absolutely do have
influence I've been actually pretty
shocked about how much progress we've
been able to make just making time to go
to Sacramento to speak with lawmakers to
go to the meetings we have influence
it's just are we going to complain about
the way things are or are we going to be
the generation that shapes the way it is
in the future and you know I know what
side I face it's it's a beautiful segue
into what Hillary is here to talk to us
about actually Forrest so I want to
welcome Hillary
back into the first hash Church after a
hundred and forty days it's gonna tell
us a little bit early hi Heather a love
you baby oh I was thinking about this
community we had the opportunity to
speak to the Senate last week so our
legalization bill is being reviewed by
the Senate in Canada right now and they
are there's a lot of movement around
pushing back on some really key key
things some of the senators wanted to
repeal the home grow aspect of the bill
and they had been talking a lot about
putting a potency caps in there even
talking about like limiting the potency
of flowers that were allowed to
distribute not even yet really wrapping
their head around resins and other kinds
of concentrates and so there were many
many things that I wanted to speak to
them about but you only get seven
minutes and it's really hard to like
hone it all down into seven minutes so
the two things that I focused on was tax
and potency so on the tax side our
government already charges a sales tax
to medical patients and now they're
applying an excise tax act which is
basically a sin tax to cannabis for
recreational and they're proposing to
put it on patients and so that was sort
of a really big thing that we're
fighting back because so many patients
says you guys know can't afford the
amount of cannabis that they need
already and we should not be putting a
sin tax on medicine for patients but the
potency conversation was also really
interesting because you have to remember
that these senators are kind of in like
kindergarten around their cannabis
knowledge and it's really easy to be
angry and frustrated that they don't get
certain things or be patient and try to
meet them where they are in terms of
their level of understanding so one of
the things that I think is always
interesting to talk about around photos
be that so many people don't know it's
like my favorite fun fact these days is
around how we have very few cannabinoid
receptors in our brain stem and our
brain stem is responsible for cardiac
and respiratory function and that's why
unlike opiates and alcohol cannabis
can't actually kill you so I talked to
them about how using the word overdose
with cannabis is not
actually appropriate because the word
overdose insinuates that death is
possible because they had had like a lot
of the people that came to testify it
was kinda like in in your time machine
and go back to 1962 level of knowledge
and and prohibitionist rhetoric that
they are hearing from they even had a
visit from sam the like America's like
super conservative doesn't even really
get any traction anywhere in America
prohibitionists we had yeah a couple of
our conservative senators actually went
down and spent the afternoon with Jeff
Sessions so this kind of influence on
our process is infuriating to say the
least but so we had a lot of work to do
to address some of the misinformation
that they had received so the I was
gonna tell you talking about potency and
extracts talked about the brainstem and
also just you know explaining the super
basics that you all know that if you're
using like the Tri Chrome's by
themselves it can just mean that you
consume less plant matter and what that
means for patients and talking about the
difference between like smoking the
whole joint or if you want to like
having one inhalation off like an
elegant vape pen but I think that we
really got the messages across around
potency and the fact that what they are
wanting to achieve through potency
limits it's not gonna work
that they need to just regulate all of
the products all the potencies and then
we can deal with them in a responsible
way in the marketplace and so I kind of
felt like I had my like hash Church flag
with me when I was out there so I'm
happy to pop in and say hi and glad that
you're back on the air oh man we were
just going on about it for the first
half an hour how great it is to see all
the familiar happy faces and here Indy
420 case a bong ripp was like the
opening bell for church I see I watched
your um what you what you were talking
about and everything there and you guys
touched on levels of
being close in age like the under-17 and
getting the criminal record and stuff
like that and you guys did an incredible
job you guys look so professional up
there and it was cool them all hey you
guys did a good job I'm really proud of
you thank you yeah it was it was pretty
amazing to see like team legalization
get our chance up at that and we got the
last word because they start doing the
line by Luanne through the act and
proposing their amendments next week and
both of those panels from that day are
super worth watching and the Q&amp;A is
really interesting I mean not that
anybody here is really interested in
like cannabis politics and policies but
if you happen to be somebody who is
vaguely interested in that kind of stuff
the Q&amp;A is super interesting to watch
and I just I want us to get it right you
know and the way that we're legalizing
cannabis is really still with a
prohibitionist mentality and that's how
they had to sell it to the conservative
part of our government and people that
still are afraid of cannabis as the
whole idea of how they framed
legalization is that we're gonna get the
Wold organized-crime out and we're gonna
restrict access to kids so it's not like
we're legalizing cannabis and have
changed our mentality around this is a
wonderful beautiful plan that's a
solution to so many of our world's
problems like we're not there yet hmm
well it's just like Forrest said with
locking the little girl in the foot in
the basement and letting her out 40
years later and she's pale and pasty and
she's a little crooked and that's like
that's what we're trying to legalize
right now I kind of saw your vision
there for us when you said if
prohibition had never happened and would
never set this up the way we're setting
it up and thank God for people like
yourself and people like Hillary or who
are sort of on the front lines you
really have to go to these Senate
hearings you really have to go to these
lawmakers and these politicians I know
it has been doing it for a long long
time as well and it's just it's
important work that you know not
everyone wants to do but the people that
are doing it that's because you got a
suit up you got a suit up and that's no
joke right there you got a suit when it
goes back to where we were
about cultural change and the impact
that has on the laws we want to see
reflected you know Sam those grooves
propaganda awful organizations it's just
spread probably some of the worst
disinformation I've seen here in the
United States I did a panel on teen and
drug use and you know all the
information that the schools brought for
the drug education they're giving our
kids came from Sam and it was all wrong
easy was there was untrue you know if
you if you look at that if you want to
like super nerd out and look at the
panel that was uh in the afternoon on
the 23rd a dear friend of mine Rosie
monden has been doing some amazing
government relations on behalf of all of
us she spoke and she just gutted Sam's
credibility to the Senate like she just
fully tackled it she had also organized
to have like thirty of the country's
leading researchers to work together to
organize a rebuttal document to their
document but she fully gutted them and
then the next day they put out a press
release I wish I had it to put the link
out that he put out a press release
about like Losey monden slandering them
and they've she she produces extraction
equipment and they put a picture of her
extraction machine with this big red
arrow to these gummy bears and was like
this woman's personally responsible for
trying to get your kids high in a press
release it was like it was so it's just
high drama taking on Rose any luck Sam
before I do I just want to say one quick
thing to that beautiful angel of the
woman Kelly sitting there who has been
sent Kelly has been sending me medicine
for my dog and my dog has bone cancer
and is really sore and the medicine
Micheli is sending for my Ringo is like
transforming our life and letting me
have some quality time with him towards
the end and I just nobody's ever really
I've never really needed anybody to step
up for me or somebody in my family the
way that I do for Ringo right now and
those treats that you make we need to
get them to all of the canine nation
everywhere
the world they're like such potent
medicine so thank you it is absolutely
my honor because I feel like you just
touched on really the reason why we're
all here this plant has incredible
healing powers and not only does it have
incredible healing powers but it
connects us and it connects us in very
deep ways and no matter how much
politics that we talk about or
pesticides there's some kind of a love
flow that goes through this plant and
connects us all and everybody who's
watching this show and everybody who's
that connected to this plant and we all
hold such an important you know part of
this puzzle and we just want to give you
so much strength and so much love for
being on the front lines for us all you
know in that realm and being able to
suit up and do that and use your voice
in the way that you do it's being so
eloquent with it is tremendously
important to us we wouldn't it wouldn't
matter what kind of gardening we we
would do it all if it weren't for people
like you that we're really helping us
you know to be free with it also and
it's made to support ringo who supports
you who you support everyone else Tiger
so much love and hugs through hash
Church Hillary thank you so much for
being a leader and showing everybody how
it's done because it's people like you
that you know have guided people like me
and others along the way that have made
us realize that it is eternal vigilance
and that it is you can't just do it this
weekend and walk away from it it is a
constant eternal vigilance and thank you
for being such a wonderful leader that
you are humbled and honored to know you
thank you thanks for sharing
thanks for crying where she destroys Sam
I'll get her to send you the link
absolutely yeah it's one of the Senate's
and it's all definitely yeah Rosie's
pretty awesome I would I want to watch
that as well I I was hanging out with
her a little bit yesterday and she's
just got a real lively fiery passion for
cannabis as well like I said earlier a
lot of the people that I met yesterday
you know there are a lot of people who
are passionate about cannabis and it's
it's good to see and it's good to be a
part of it it's sometimes I think we get
lost because we've been fighting for so
long for this that you know for the
longest time we were literally being
jailed in prison having our lives
destroyed and you know we fought and
fought and fought and fought and
although that's still happening in some
states in a lot of different countries
and the fight is nowhere near over it's
over for so many of us who now have
federal exemptions and who have
legalization around the corner and huge
things in California and as it happens
you know obviously we get comfortable
with and and quickly forget about that
even happening and start bitching about
the next thing on the top of the list
and I just want everyone to remember
that the next thing on the top of the
list is way way way down the list from
being imprisoned and having our children
take away from us to me the next most
important thing on the list is is the
work that that Forrest and Hillary and
that Jan all these people are doing in
regards to the politics to really like
Hillary was not joking when she said
these guys are in kindergarten when it
comes to their cannabis knowledge so you
can't really be harsh and judgmental
they're just ignorant it just needed
education and this is what we need to do
and I was actually this is a fun one
going to what Forrest was saying I had
actually have school administrators for
high schools and middle schools reached
out to me and I'm actually gonna give
private seminars on Saturdays and
educate these people on cannabis because
they all they have is the knowledge from
Sam and all these other places and
they're like that doesn't work this is
not real we need to talk to the experts
so they actually reached out to me and
I'm actually in a couple weeks gonna
along with my HR director take education
and research and show these people
because as you said they are all
neophytes they are literally at ground
zero of no knowledge so I'm gonna start
with these teachers and administrators
on my day off and educate them so that
they can go back and then teach their
other teachers and then in the health
schools in next year they're going to be
teaching them what's really out there
for them for Canada's because they have
no knowledge the state of California
no bit of understanding about what these
kids should be taught besides all that
lies and misinformation that's out there
so again shows you that you know we have
to take upon our shoulders to do it
ourselves to actually educate these
people so I'm gonna educate your
teachers so that they can throw out this
Dare information and then you know it
just shows me that there's somebody
needs to start a business just to
educate these people so that they can
just go around and say hey this is
cannabis B this is medical camera just
start off with the simples because it's
as you know as you've seen when you go
to Sacramento you start talking cannabis
you say and you just can see their eyes
just glaze up so we literally have to
start at the beginning
yeah well that's great news at ten'
starting with the children and the
teachers and getting that information
out you know probably people don't
realize how much of the propaganda in
you know negative cannabis how much of
it really was promoted obviously through
the prohibition and the and the policing
that was a big part because that's very
scary having your door kicked in but the
next ones on the list in my opinion were
Hollywood constantly making derogatory
jokes in movies and TV and of course the
The Miseducation and the misinformation
of our children at schools with programs
like pride and dare and Sam these are
these are these are just straightforward
misinformation and when you're just you
know trying to teach children on one
side about certain truths and you're
just filling it in with lies about other
things this does nothing but confuse
confuse children and of course it's the
it's the birth of brainwashing well not
only confuse them but it's it's harmful
you know I think one of the biggest
impacts is that the schools these dare
programs these Sam programs are doing
what they're blaming cannabis for which
is typically this this false gateway
analogy where cannabis will become a
gateway drug but I believe that a lot of
these programs are what really
contributes to that misconception
because they teach kids from a very
young age that there's no difference
between heroin and cannabis and that
there's no difference between cocaine
and cannabis and meth and cannabis in
alcohol and can
so what happens you know kids grow up
they get in high school typically with a
experiment with what might be around
first you know a lot of times that is
cannabis and when you teach kids that
there's no difference between cannabis
and meth in
what they taught was a lie it puts the
door to believe that there was a lie
with these other drugs and I absolutely
believe it contributes to the abuse of
some of these other drugs through the
misinformation education so it's not a
victimless crime and it's really sad to
see some of the most conservative we
want to help the kids folks buy into a
treatment plan that actually teaches
kids to not believe what they've been
taught down the road about dangerous
drugs and opens the door to make it
easier for them to experiment with them
it's kind of been in California culture
for a while so it's a little bit
different story here when we go like I
was just in Massachusetts at a town hall
meeting for somebody petitioning for a
license and a lot of people there could
barely wrap their heads around medical
or just wrap their heads around medical
and then you have to throw the
recreational in now it's like a whole
different aspect to everybody like
medical was fine for a minute for most
people and then recreational I was super
surprised to hear how many people that
were you know for medical out there but
totally against recreational and it was
like reefer madness on the same plant
are the same thing I'm like what are we
talking about here I'm like you know
what's recreational on Saturday is
medical on Monday I don't know if that's
true or not but I mean it's just like
you know what is the difference between
medical and recreational besides taxes
and money well I mean they're nothing
Princeton in the application but you
know other than that it's all grown yeah
but when people want to smoke weed and
they go buy some flowers I mean one
person might say I use it for medical
and the guy next to him might say I use
this for recreational and so people are
torn in two different worlds now
especially in other states where
cannabis isn't a part of the culture
it's really this defining line of you
know is this medical is this
recreational how is it even right
because I just was in the dare class
last week or whatever like Forrest was
saying Sam California is kind of unique
into its own because of the culture but
these other states I've been going to
it's it's a serious controversy
on the medical versus recreational topic
alone and that's what was surprising to
me because I'm just used to being you
know cannabis period and everything
instant reefer madness but now the
argument for medical and recreational is
like even more absurd in some ways yeah
another way to divide yeah in the
beginning you know this it's a it's this
cultural sand that is applied to
recreational this comes back like this
whole you know it reminds me of this
this whole Christian you know don't
masturbate don't have sex don't feel
good anything that involves some sort of
pleasure the human body is inherently
evil and wrong so what we have here with
cannabis is just this inherent we don't
know why we believe it but it's been
ingrained in us from day one that it's
bad or anything that changes your state
of mind is bad and evil and we have to
grow out of it we absolutely have to
stop associating using things that make
us feel different to relieve stress or
just because we want to feel different
as inherently bad if it's not harmful to
the body into the community and was that
a pun intended when you said we have to
grow out of it
sure yeah you know the division between
recreation and medical obviously someone
mentioned it in chat that the difference
I guess could be construed as intense
but aren't they both really also
preventive like when you're using
cannabis as a medicine and you're
saturating your endocannabinoid system
and you're regulating your biological
functions the way they need to be
isn't there a form of prevention
involved whether you're using
medicinally for one specific element or
you're using recreationally to feel a
certain way I think that there's also a
preventive aspect to it and really I'm
not sure that we should be too worried I
mean that the real division to me
between recreational and medical isn't
in the intention of the person but it's
in the quality of the product because
when it is people use radioactive
tobacco as a recreational product and
they use poisonous alcohols and all
sorts of different things and they're
adults it's called a doll use they
should be allowed to do what they want
if you want to sort of endanger your own
health it shouldn't be anyone
issue but when your health is already
endangered when you have some serious
element you need to be knowing that the
myth the medicine that you're purchasing
is being produced on a level that may be
too the you know beyond and above what
what could be you know sold as as
recreational product so there needs to
be some distinction I mean just because
dosage limits alone make it a challenge
you know when we blur medicinal and
recreational uses and it is you know
Howard how we're using it I mean we were
working with the BCC in California we
actually got them to raise the limit up
to ten thousand milligrams but you know
when we have for example this perception
of recreational use or someone just
wants to change their state of mind as
opposed to treating you know a tumour
issue or an endocannabinoid deficiency
disorder you know we have what is it in
California eighteen five milligram doses
per serving is that what it is right now
I think there is a 10 it's 10 100 it's
100 maximum in a packaging so most
people are doing 10 or you're seeing
people also do those micro dosing pass
tools or you know things like that micro
definitely conditions that need six
seven eight hundred thirteen hundred
milligram a day dosing and they're
restricted through sort of that
intention right the intention of how
it's supposed to be used then you put
patients in a really tough position
there's a you can't really get a lot of
therapeutically dosed products still in
dispensaries because of some of these
restrictions so again I agree with
everything you say Marcus but we at the
same time have to be able to maybe draw
some in the legislature draw some sort
of distinction on how it's used and
intended to be used so that those
products can be available for patients
at needle preparation we strip the
recreational strip the medical abilities
in California quite a bit I mean I can't
believe that access people do not have
anymore and the expense people are
paying to try to get the same medicine
like I was at the height I decided to
give the Sacramento High Times cup kind
of cuz it was the first legal whatever
and I'm not that far away and so I went
down and really popular
means that I could buy at a farmers
market last summer and up north or
whatever you know we're a hundred
milligram box each gummy was ten
milligrams and it was $25 plus all the
tax so I mean I can't imagine somebody
that have to rely on seven or eight
hundred milligrams a day and have to go
buy it legally now I mean it would
bankrupt them I mean I'm hearing that
from other people but I guess I just
didn't realize it for myself till I did
a little shopping around ya know go buy
some flowers and the Jarrah flowers is
like this tax that tax and you know here
I was like wow this is fun for a second
but really crazy and how can we separate
you know the idea of recreational from
medical at all what was that like the
Industrial Revolution like nine-to-five
that all of a sudden said that there's
some kind of difference between our
well-being and our health and the way
that we recreation typically that you
know to be happy boosts your immune
system so if we're recreative like you
were saying earlier marcus that's only
prevention for the diseases that come
down the line for you know getting
tumors and everything being happy is the
most important thing that we can do and
if that means you know token on your
cannabis or eating your gummies for a
good price and and it's a healthy way of
living then that's just only gonna make
sense for i just don't see the
separation in any way shape or form I
feel like it's just a lot of political
rhetoric and taxes that just put it on
there I find it really interesting that
you know in the 1800s and all the
apothecaries of the world you know as
you stated before cannabis was the you
know main ingredient and all of what we
used from the apothecary that we went
for it
you know healing and then you know here
came the the prohibition and the
Anslinger and all the stuff that came in
the monkeys and now all the sudden we're
getting read brainwashed into being like
oh this is like this is a drug and then
and then here it comes to 1996 and
they're like actually it's a medicine
and then so we have all this opening up
of mindsets because it's medical and we
all
and you know as a culture we get excited
because oh my god this is the best news
in the world you know everything that we
were working for its medically good for
us and we all these studies come out and
then this big dark cloud of legalization
comes and recreational and then all of a
sudden it's like forget about the whole
medical thing this is a taxable item
we're in debt let's go go corporations
let's sell taxes let's sell shares and
it just feels like it insults to our
intelligence so that's what I have to
say about that and still have
differential testing rights like like I
thought I remember like in Washington
state they had testing regs for the
recreational market in none for the
medical market so the medical market
became the dumping ground for all the
stuff that failed the REC market does
that still go in honor today because
they finally like right that chip not in
college no big job and ethically
problematic completely yeah and that's
something we're all recreational yeah
we're really fighting that here in
California because you know
so the colliders network is a children's
agency for those who don't know we deal
with Pediatrics terminally and
catastrophic lis if though
you
[Music]
right where they don't have a lot of
progressive loss and it's because of the
merging of the adult use recreational
medical markets there is a big
difference between CBD gummies and what
is necessary for treating rare difficult
neurological conditions and what the
problem is is you're right we could just
say that if we're saying cannabis is
free and we can do what we want with it
well then there's no problem but
unfortunately we have the limits that
are being imposed or from a recreational
point of view and there are limits
because people aren't using cannabis
responsibly you know and this is where I
push back a little bit on the all use
this medicinal use because you know you
can go on YouTube in Google you know
college kids first dab in some of these
videos where you see kids completely
cannabis naive taking huge dabs that
cause paralysis in one kid and the
videos online he goes into a full panic
attack he's freaking out you know that's
not beneficial that can actually be
damaging for folks and that fear of that
happening you know is putting laws in
place that make medicinal not the
medicinal means for therapeutic levels
really difficult to to achieve so I you
know I agree but it's a complex
conversation that whatever is decided to
be done if we have to differentiate to
ensure access than we differentiate
until we get to a point where we can
realize the cannabis is safe and it can
just be open the problem is that we're
putting limits on medicinal cannabis to
prevent people ending up in the hospital
because they eat too many brownies that
are preventing cancer patients and
epileptics from getting what they need
to survive and their life depends on it
and that and that is a definitely
medicine and necessary so it's it's a
tough one but I totally agree I think
that it's really important but but I
feel like you know it really is being
caught up in politics and rhetoric and
you know getting back on that kid that
took the dab is it really the cannabis
that did that or was it the pesticides
you know
cause that in that child you know that's
a total side side comment but I believe
that it is really important but when
we're starting to separate out a plant
that's just totally good for you then it
becomes political then it becomes money
and then that's where we all get messed
up and that's why we're having all of
these conversations where these people
have been part of the culture from the
very beginning bringing it forward or no
longer able to be part of a culture and
now a pharmaceutical company is taking
it over but the pharmaceutical company
isn't getting rights in access it just
becomes a whole muddled problem which
really is representative of all of the
politics and I don't mean to brush it
off on all politics but here we are
cannabis now has become a political
discussion I saw a lot of 40s and 50
year olds laid out on the ground at high
times from taking their first too big of
a dab or whatever it was I mean I've
seen it in Amsterdam people eating too
many edibles and just collapsing on the
the cobblestone and it's you know
sometimes violent and and sometimes
actually involves you know pain so I
always love forests perspective he has a
very unique perspective in all of this
having a very sick child and coming to
this from-from Silas's perspective it's
it's not a perspective than any of us
could possibly have and I always find it
very just very important for and I love
his confidence and always like whether
it's creating a little bit of discomfort
and just saying what he has to say
because it's it's very important at the
same time I know I know Kelly and Josh
and I know how you know they've got
these great healthy people in their
lives healthy son they have seen him use
cannabis and it's so they have this
other unique perspective and it's just
neat to see the two perspectives
interact and talk about this this
importance because on you know from one
perspective you can see like oh why why
do we need to differentiate we shouldn't
have to and then you can see from
forests perspective it's like well yeah
I don't want to have to differentiate
but if that's the way I have to do it to
ensure that my son and other kids like
him
get a clean medicine and access then I
will jump through whatever hoop I have
to jump
to make that happen and that's exactly
it I mean I agree with everything Kelly
and josh has said but it's it goes back
to her you know this all circles back to
the general lack of real education and
understanding and in our lawmakers
that's what it comes back to and what
happens is when when they hear there's
no difference then they falsely assume
well that dispensaries open so you have
all the medicine you need right and in
everything it's good they don't
understand the nuance of what needs to
continue to be allowed so yeah I agree
with everything killing Josh said but
again as a parent and someone who works
with pediatrics and children it
definitely is highlighted to me where
some of those concepts actually are
causing harm because of the lack of
understanding in our lawmakers and I
totally agree with you as well of course
it's it's such a point it's such a good
point and it's so important for the work
that's being done for the children and
bringing it forward and and it's become
so taboo you know with the idea that
it's only recreational then if it's only
recreational then we can't give it to
our kids and that just isn't isn't the
case at all so it does it becomes real
muddled in the in the education of it
and how are we gonna bring this
education for that includes you know all
forms of the medicine as well as all
uses of the medicine and I guess it's
from a grower at the end and when it's
all said and done it doesn't really
matter it really just matters was it
grown properly and clean because whether
to the recreational or the medical I
think we should just try and you know
make it you know healthy let's say yeah
and and 40 percent of what it is that
you're getting you know is coming up
dirty just is really representative of
you know what's going on in the toxins
of the world and that's not something
that is acceptable or okay in any way so
that's a whole other force of Education
that needs to come forward so here's a
question for the panel someone asked it
earlier and they were asking about
irradiated cannabis and how that's
affecting cannabis and how that might be
affecting patients and so this is
something that's happening in Canada
where there's a federally regulated
marketplace and so does anyone know much
on the pan
about irradiated cannabis I mean Arno
did a study on it and showed that you
know it it definitely takes care of the
molds and mildews but it definitely
destroys the terpenes and it doesn't
destroy them all but it affected the
terpene profile affects them
significantly but now we need to see
what is that actual difference you know
what you know if you actually smoked it
compared to the other you know can you
actually taste a flavor difference was
there an on-set difference you know that
needs to be studied unfortunately you
know just because that one study come
out that leads to as you know I think
Kevin would say more studies need to
take place can we explain what
irradiated weed will be or what the
process is I think that's a good point
to make from what and from what I
understand it's a bean at the lift
expose it's an irradiating machine that
has a like a conveyor belt that goes
through it and it brings the buds
through and it radiates it to like take
to take away the responsibility of the
grower you they they just basically say
now grow what you want we'll clean it up
it's kind of like the distal thing in a
way this isn't a UV light they're
pushing it through yeah well what
wikipedia says is it's it's the process
of exposing food and food packaging to
ionization radiation ionizing radiation
such from gamma rays x-rays or electron
beams is energy that can be transmitted
without direct contact to the source of
the energy radiation capable of freeing
electrons from their atomic bonds in the
targeted food the radiation can be
emitted by a radioactive substance or
generated electrically and this
treatment is used to improve food safety
by extending product shelf-life
preservation reducing the risk of
foodborne illnesses and delaying or
eliminating sprouting or ripening by
sterilization of foods and as a means of
controlling insects and invasive pests
that's medical well that's I just read
that technically it's every potato you
eat or is irradiated yeah lots lots of
foods are actually irradiated so it's
it's just but like once again we could
say that putting food in our stomachs
might be a little bit different than
inhaling molecules into our lungs
and if the terpene profile itself is
being affected then how bad is it being
affected if we know that terpenes
modulate the effects of cannabinoids
those are probably fairly important to
be left alone the way they are but yeah
I just thought it would be an
interesting conversation maybe we can
get someone on here in the next couple
of weeks that knows a little bit more
about it and could share with us because
I I I would like to know more about it
myself it's one thing I really don't
know much when someone asks me about
cannabis irradiation arno would be the
man
yeah I know I know that it's really
expensive and whatever like products and
stuff that they have out there that
we've seen with in Canada you know
they're talking about it in the
pharmaceutical industry big time because
they Reiter irradiate all different
types of herbs for supplements that's
just immediately done if it involves any
type at the health industry in any way
then it's going to be irradiated you
know a lot of our teas are irradiated
celestial Seasonings all of these
different types of teas that we might be
drinking every day that utilize herbs is
being irradiated and it basically takes
away you know the entire life force of
the plant material you know I'd love to
learn more from art or anything or
anyone like that and also I would just
question you know the residue that it
leaves if we know micro butanol just for
example is the easiest one you know
continues to radiate why wouldn't that
happen in the ganja and what you know
cyanobacteria is in my Ino other's
smaller bacteria what kind of those
probiotic cultures are getting
irradiated out as well and once again
you know that's an input to our human
body and we want like a whole food as
much as possible that's why whole foods
not the company but what you know a
whole food is so important and growing
your own food is more alive so I mean
it's just another example of kind of
processed food it's like it's processed
weed so yeah you can get it and I don't
know the specific science on it but I
mean I don't trust it I wouldn't want to
have anything to do with it yeah I want
a pipe in here it seems to me I've read
in the science that microbiology
particularly bacteria
and I imagine fungus have an ability to
share their DNA and pick up resistance
from each other and it seems to me that
era dating microbiology is going to
explode all of that DNA into a mad soup
like you are just talking about Josh and
men time consuming it into the lungs it
sounds like a really terrible idea to me
and this just goes to what I was saying
and I agree with Josh 100% so this goes
back we can do a whole show on this that
you know all cannabis has the potential
for medicinal use but it's not safe or
good for medicinal use you know and in
how it's used ism is important and we
see in the deaths of immune-compromised
cancer patients and if the cannabis is
clean and prepared properly so it's it's
a it's a complex topic that we could do
a whole show on but I think that really
highlights that point well yeah we'll
have to get a little deeper into that
later on in the year here once we can
maybe get some more key players involved
with the conversation I just put our
nose paper up there on the chat group
that one's got some measurement of the
differential effects on the monoterpenes
and SS the terpenes when you do
gamma-irradiated with some of those but
you know that could probably be
compensated for with you know spike ends
of senses yeah I had read the paper I
didn't think that the I knew it was it
was a change I can't remember it was a
20 or 30% you know that's not overcome
with spike ins but bed row Canada's
considered the you know the
quote/unquote standard because they were
the first regulated sort of situation
but their cannabis is irradiated so you
know that's just an FYI you know more
than anything for people to realize that
you know that's where it is considered
as an international medicine it needed
to be that way but that's also as
everybody was saying a reflection on the
growers themselves you know the growers
of that flower there's a need for it to
be irradiated because it's not
of molds and mildews period you know
yeah to make that sloppily and then just
irradiated where are the mycotoxins and
then it takes away the responsibility
from you know possibly really large
corporations that are just coming in to
produce money and they're not really
into producing a you know a health
product and there's a real
differentiation with that and I know a
lot of people that are you know in
northern Cali and in Southern Oregon and
people who have brought this culture
forward you know they're producing a
culture they're producing you know
something of importance it's not
something that you know can just be put
out onto the market that's just dead
alright we actually could do a study
looking at irradiated samples just to
know what I suspect the DNA is still
there although it might be there might
be some finally being cross linkers
going on sometimes here a crime that
would be interesting to see whether or
not we can pick it up because my only
concern of using something like that is
that you masked all of these the fact
that you had tons of mold on the plant
and the fact that you've made it so it's
not viable doesn't mean you that you've
necessarily made it safe because those
are still a allergen you can still get
effects like allergies with powdery
mildew and botrytis and the few places
i've seen using this have powdery mildew
everywhere but they don't even bother to
deal with it or read around it they just
basically say it doesn't matter we're
gonna go and radiate it and it'll be
fine when a culture but it probably
still has mycotoxins and other allergens
that are on it that just are we're not
paying attention to you right now nobody
got into cannabis cuz they were farmers
in the first place they got into
cannabis because they wanted to grow
some weed so at the end of the day when
people don't give a [__] or have the
skills or the background or the support
I mean what happens what happens and a
lot of places PE that are legal not
necessarily in California and but other
states I mean it's not optimal growing
conditions I mean there's places in
Humboldt and on the coast where it's the
hardest places to grow ever like there's
not really much choice the mean you've
got a it's taken some people 2 to 3
years to refine their skills to be able
to grow something without p.m. and
without mold before legalization
these things because it's just not
optimal growing conditions or optimal
greenhouses or spaces to use because of
legalization puts them in all these
weird places and so at the end of the
day irradiation and these things are
gonna exist because they have no
potential to pump out good [__] in the
end of the day I mean it's gonna have
p.m. and it's gonna run through some
problems and they're not gonna throw
that [__] away that's just the way this
mentality goes right now only the craft
people have the ATS copyin let's throw
it away and start over let's test our
soil and figure it out let's you know
get to the bottom of these things and
figure out the health of the problem
because when you go to the business
trade shows for the most part
everybody's drinking alcohol and
cannabis isn't allowed and the one thing
that you see from booth to booth to
booth is what kind of spray what kind of
UV light what kind of technology they
have to kill mold to kill p.m. to get
rid of all these things so I mean again
we're almost like Big Pharma here's the
pill to fix this here's the pill to fix
that here's a side-effect take this pill
oh the hell don't worry about it we got
a pill you don't need to be healthy so
you know we're not gonna grow there's
only a fraction of people that are gonna
grow healthy and do this right in the
long run because again the places that
are legal have the odds against them
whether it's the whether it's the soil
and the neighbor spraying [__] and so I
mean at the end of the day the bubble is
gonna burst but unfortunately a lot of
people have thrown in the towel and
moved away and some things like that up
north I mean I try to get it past the
doom and the gloom stories all the time
and I know there's some cool
breakthroughs and I mean don't you have
one coming up here mica don't you have
something opening up or some cool things
for leaf expanding opening up or dealing
some new stuff because I know there's a
lot of problems and some things going on
but I know that you had a had shared
some stuff that you're getting ready to
do yeah you threw me off there I thought
as far as projects that we have going on
yeah we are working on some different
projects but you know building some new
facilities and whatnot but you guys are
organic you guys are like what we talk
about your craft farmer you're in
Southern California all the fans just
kicked on in the back for they go on for
a few seconds
you're an organic farmer in northern and
southern California you're legal you're
permitted you're testing all over the
place and you know you're still just you
don't I don't know if you have a big
investor behind you anything like that
but I mean you've always come from a
small Crafts style farm and not so far
with it's all on our own you know we
don't have a big investor behind us but
yeah our take on it is that you got to
get it right out of the gate you know so
your farming techniques have to be down
and and don't rely on all these new
things that are popping up with you know
sprays and I was actually gonna ask you
guys if someone brought this up to me
the other day if I had heard anything
about um the irradiation thing sounds to
me like it's some sort of pasteurization
process or something that you know it's
because of you you screwed up in the
back you know and your farming
techniques possibly so it's a way to not
throw away product that probably should
be thrown into the trash and someone
someone was in our in our office the
other day asking about there's something
in Colorado that they're introducing
where it's it's something similar but
it's a spray they have any of you guys
heard of that whether they're talking
about spraying down the flower and the
different product as a preservative and
actually turning it into a law they are
they're talking about doing putting
tracers on it so they want to spike it
with some type of molecule they can
trace I think they're talking about DNA
but I know it's not clear to me webelo
has a grant to try and figure this out
and it seems incredibly foolish to do
this because you could actually just
track the DNA itself from the plant you
know how to do that now and so if you
really want a barcode just read the
native DNA of the plant as opposed to
adding some other DNA to it I mean it
brings up all types of concerns and you
start doing that because generally when
you spray DNA on things it's not going
to integrate the genome but you know you
you can get viruses and other things
bacteria to package that stuff and and
there could be perhaps off-target
integration events you know I don't know
it seems really foolish what they're
trying to do because it's one more
compound but I'm not so much worried
about the DNA because that's fairly
probably fairly native it's more
what are they going to package it with
like what's the foliar spray they
soluble Iseman it's almost like the
adjuvant SAR oftentimes more dangerous
than the actual thing you're trying to
apply and it's they all they want to do
this to get taxes you know it's easy
sales tracking and right now the RFID
tags are getting ripped off and this is
only protecting they want to be able to
trace that they want to be find out
because we have the same access of
genetics as anyone else as dispensaries
they want to figure out if this is from
the illegal market or if it's from the
legal market and this is the problem of
prohibition and the problem of
reintegration from prohibition now is
that these straight prohibitionists want
to figure out any way shape or form to
[__] with us and a certain result that
seems to be the case here whereas again
it could be traced as you say by you
know actually doing genetic but the
problem is is that we can genetically
access the same genetics from the
illegal market through seeds etc clones
etc as opposed to what's in the legal
market so what they're trying to do is
find a separation between the legal
produce market in the illegal market
which I mean they could chase their
tails forever I mean correct I mean
trying to make up this sort of mess but
that's why we're they're doing this
people because they're just trying to
figure out how a police if they find a
type of cannabis and they test it they
say okay this is from the legal market
as opposed to oh you bought this
illegally so they're still trying to use
this to entrap and to put people in jail
god that just sounds like it's a
terrible idea like some sort of spray I
mean yeah but this yeah this is why you
have to be active this is why you have
to go out and meet you know who here
knows their actual representative who
has them on speed dial you know this is
how active you have to be you know only
two of us a couple of us raised our
hands here it should be every single one
of us you know you should know who your
representative is nunu here's stupidity
like this my representative is Hillary
and red she's doing something about it
right now bless I just text her and I'm
like you got to talk to these guys get
it figured out I know you have their
number see Hillary always comes out
smelling like a rose
even when she basically demolishes them
so like Hillary's done the same thing
Rosie's done over the years but somehow
Rosie gets like a rebuttal from Sam on
the web page like bashing her like in a
public forum that's pretty hardcore
that's a real honor I would be very
proud of that
if I was her oh I'm sure she is I'm sure
she loves it she's gonna chill it'll
probably you know this is this is what
some of these companies don't realize
and some of these just people that are
doing the wrong things out there that it
seems like this day and age is the day
and age of accountability you know it's
like you're not might maybe not going to
be getting away with the same old same
old [__] that you've been getting
away for the longest time because now
people are somewhat organized through
social media and they're able to gather
in a way that just makes it so easy that
suddenly you know you realize there's
hundreds of thousands or millions of
people against this particular way of
thinking and that's what we need and
guys I gotta get going
thank thanks for having me I got to take
off so yeah thanks thanks for talking to
you guys again I'm glad to have everyone
back here I'm also actually have to get
going the lift conference is over in a
couple hours and it's the last day but I
want to thank everyone for coming out
and making time and sharing your your
stories and your information and I will
absolutely be inviting you all back
again
very soon hopefully for next Sunday
we'll do another one
and in the meantime if anyone has any
ideas on specific conversations that
they want to discuss we can do specific
shows where we invite specific panelists
and I want to sort of do both the spur
of the moment hash search where whoever
can come can come and we'll make that
happen but also have some times where we
actually create and and produce a show
for a special Sunday where specific
people are coming in to talk about
specific things and they make sure that
they have the time and the space to do
that and in the meantime yeah we'll be
posting all the links in the hash Church
Facebook page in regards to things that
we talked about I know Kevin is probably
already doing it but he'll post some
things in that Facebook page as he often
does and just keep on keeping on
everybody y'all doing great jobs great
work and I'm want to thank Shawn for
hanging out and sitting with me Shawn's
a local organic farmer here who can be
found on Instagram at lost gardens and a
righteous brother from another mother
so we're we're gonna head off to lift
and and see if we can't talk some sense
into some of these cannabis parasites
and I'm not talking about mites or or
some of these other real sort of
cannabis parasites that are sort of
approaching the industry and well we got
a safe doesn't mean we can't just stop
going to be shows that's just another
way to create divisions so we're gonna
make sure we go to the shows and educate
the way we educate and thank the entire
audience in the chat room right now
who's you know your your dedication to
hash Church is is above and beyond and
we do appreciate you for doing that
coming in all the time sharing the
sharing the links and getting it so we
can have five or six hundred people
watching live and yeah just thanks
everyone thanks for us thanks Dee 420k
thanks dragon fire earth medicine thank
you Eric and it's yeah and Wayde and
Kevin and skunk man Sam who came and
went as well as mica just give thanks
everybody we'll see you next week on
hash Church nice love
peace out yes