okay let's see we're going live
here let's see let's see
all right looks like we are
live yes we are welcome everybody to
Hash Church
5.0 episode three I am just going to be
letting some folks in here real
quick see what we got
oh Mr Kevin W that's a beautiful shot
Marcus how you
doing how you doing Kevin good how about
yourself hello hello hello there can't
hear
you maybe that's my fault let me check
my audio real quick think think oh yeah
that's my fault
I have got my speaker set up to the
wrong thing give me one
second uh there we go there we go yes
good day sir how you doing how are you
I'm doing good man long time no see yeah
so how long was the asur Hiatus I didn't
uh you know it was just under a year a
all right it was just under a year you
know it's been uh it's it's hash church
when it started it was this unque sort
of timeline where we were all so excited
to to Really share everything we were
doing and then all of a sudden this
legal system came into play and people
became more protective of their IPs and
of the things they were sharing and it
just seemed like everyone was kind of
going their own separate ways it seemed
like a very natural Hiatus I kind of
thought someone would pick it up and
take it over and there would be still
places for people to gather and Kyle
kushman has has done a good job and
there's a few others that have that are
that are pretty impressive but I just
kind of felt like you know what I think
uh we need to be we need to be doing
this again time to get back together
yeah exactly so I think right now what's
happened is the zoom link changed and
now I've got to send it out again to
everyone I just sent an email ah there's
Colin wonderful well long time no see
dude what what have you been up to aside
from uh you know testifying in front of
the Senate and doing all this wild stuff
I've seen you've been doing oh yeah we
we've been active on the haven't taken
our eye off the Cannabis front but I've
just been a little less vocal lately so
uh it's good to get on here we'll share
you you know share everything we're
doing the co stuff was a was a you know
a big deep dive but had to be done I
appreciated it personally you know I um
I particularly appreciate it I had a
really good conversation with my mother
about it the other day in regards to I
just like the conversation to be open on
both ends that's all just a dialogue not
kind of stunting one side of the
conversation just let people have the
dialogue they're very good at polarizing
people so that is their art and uh it
unfortunately certainly hit our
field yeah I was goingon to say You must
have been feeling it for sure
yeah Hey Kevin how are you hey Mark how
you doing good so we might be seeing you
Puerto Rico huh yeah yeah yeah how crazy
that that's going to intersect right
yeah I didn't know you're down there so
you you're doing some work down in uh in
the Ireland yeah I I I uh I consult with
uh with prit biotech they're the largest
producer down there and you know it's
it's you know it's a limited market it's
only medical you know yeah a limited
market but
um uh you know I
it's you know what the say they you go
down there and say oh you guys want to
become a state and they're like no no no
no we like being a US Territory because
there's all kinds of tax incentive to do
manufacturing down there and the
pharmaceutical companies have been down
there uh for you know 60 or 80 years so
like you know there's huge manufacturing
facilities for everything from over to
counter to injectables to everything and
uh so there's these huge facilities
there and the facility that they're in
right there they used to make a leave or
something it was old J&amp;J facility but uh
it's it's huge it's the largest indoor
uh facility that I've I've ever seen um
but um yeah I mean all the challenges of
just being down there just like supply
chain issues and you know like they get
hit when the hurricane comes in it
basically knocks out like power to half
the island so they have their own
substation like right there because they
have so much power online and everything
but yeah our guy John car Yan Carlos
bile is down there as their Chief
Operating Officer and um we connected
Kevin with a guy named Sam
hinar okay is that his name oh Sam from
from
MDC yeah so he's gonna we're gonna
connect and make sure that there's you
know facility tours and maybe you know I
don't know it's all it's medical down
there and they do reciprocate so if you
have like a a patient license from a
state you can get stuff into Puerto Rico
uh dispensaries but
uh or what's there is there a w timeline
on the island or they uh I think there
is but there's kind of like wanting to I
you know I my buddy was telling me
before I went down to Puerto Rico goes
yeah it's just all Wise Guys and Pirates
down there it's man it's crazy I mean
there's kind of been kind of like a I
would say a legacy Market there for any
drug you could possibly imagine it's the
Caribbean man I mean it's like it's all
tourism dollars and San Juan is
beautiful and Old San Juan is just
absolutely just like you know just
beautiful I mean cobblestone streets
just Empanada stands on the corner I
mean just it rich with with that type of
Mediterranean history and you guys are
having your gig so what we're talking
about here is canmed
20125 Right am I right 2025 [ __ ] holy
[ __ ] we're a quarter of the way through
the century caned 2025 is going to be
down in Puerto Rico what's the name of
the resort it's the Windam Resort right
it is yeah yes it's Windam it's kind of
out on the Eastern end Northeastern end
of the Island right right so it's Mark I
think p is probably one of the best
events that no one in our industry
really focuses on and they should
because of the impact it can make in
terms of innovation and who's doing the
real work and I think that's one of the
biggest takeaways that I've I've learned
from what Kevin and his team's put
together and you know I I really need to
get down there Kevin to to participate
with you Rico's time baby come on down
you know I missed my opportunity to
create an abstract for you guys but I I
think I'd like to do that in the future
to to Really to par send one in for 25
I'm sure there's I'm sure the windows
still open it's just you know life is is
happening around me so only so much I
can only so many hours in a day but uh
but yeah I I I'd love to see Mark you
put together in abstract to be honest
and and speak on the work that you've
been doing um well I mean there's just
there's there's so much to talk about I
mean it's like and that audience I mean
Kevin you remember like I came and
talked there and you were at the first
one wen't you I think he walked
into it was 2017 right because you guys
did
2016 and Mulan came to that one right
was it yes rafy so rafy just phoned in
for mine because I don't think he was
feeling well or he wasn't traveling or
but you guys have had this connection
with rfie you should talk about that
Kevin because as you know I mean he
inspired me and everything that I I've
done since I've been doing chemistry in
cannabis is all just because being
acquainted with everything that Rafi and
all the researchers that came before
Rafi you know like Adams and and I just
everyone was fascinated in the chemistry
of this plan it just didn't happen when
Rafi came in but you know to have that
connection and for him to inspire new
generations of scientists to get in like
now when you go to the icr s it's mostly
not phyto canabo it's all Endo more
endoc canabo than phyto canabo but I
think the great thing about canmat is it
kind of brings the phyto and the Endo
communities together and looks for the
obvious intersection which is is there
therapeutic use and having people like
Bonnie and um all those other doctors
that you guys have signed up actually
show real world results I mean here is
the tumor before here's the tumor after
any questions I mean holy [ __ ] you guys
have had it at canmed and so I came
there in 2017 that's when you guys were
still doing this at um at Harvard
Medical School right and uh held up a
vial of
hhc and told a group of medical doctors
that I dabbed it oh my God this won't
trigger a piss test what the [ __ ] and
this was years before so this was
basically a year before the farm bill
right and a year before the whole Delta
8 yeah hhc alphabet soup of canono sort
of exploded onto the scene so man just
in a short period of time we've seen a
real big transition in the industry and
Canad you guys have been covering it all
along it's great man it's great venue
yeah rafie was if there's one word to
sum him up it's generous I mean he just
gave everyone time and uh he was not a
divisive individual you know he'd listen
to anybody and and and welcome anybody
so he was just very um unifying voice
that will be sorely
missed so very uh yeah we're saddened by
his uh his departure but um yeah those
were that was interesting times I mean I
I remember your your your talk
specifically because it was uh you
brought in that vial of hhc and showed
it to everyone in the
audience yes yeah and um only at Harvard
Med school with that fly
well I but I I think it it was kind of
like the writing on the wall and then
the the the uh you know this hemp thing
now is is taking over the regulated
cannabis markets right I mean I I don't
know do do you guys not see that I mean
it seems like all these big Multistate
operators now like even Moana now has a
has a has a has a hemp Drive play so I
mean I don't know I mean what you yeah
it's great I saved you something from a
uh a CBD dispensary let me see if you
can see it I thought you'd get a kick
out of
that yeah well I mean and is that stuff
safe to eat I don't know who the [ __ ]
knows right yeah don't know um I'm sure
it didn't come from the flower as Mark
will tell you but um someone's been
someone's been spraying it on but you
know so how do you compete with an $8
vape pen at the gas station when the
dispensary wants 40 or 50 bucks right
you just there's no I right I mean what
the [ __ ] how do we fix this yeah I think
it Mark I think it goes back to policy
and the lack of understanding as to what
these constituents and chemical
compounds are actually doing to you know
any single consumer at any given time
and based on the extraction method as
you've kind of BL blatantly and simply
pointed out we don't really have a
clean Fair way to to show transparency
through the whole process and if it is
transparency you're showing all the dirt
and you're showing all the bad that you
know in Disguise of good right people
are going in for wellness and coming out
with different problems based off of
chemistry that is bad chemistry you know
and is it clean and how are those
constituents going to affect a human in
10 years yeah let the plant do the
chemistry and harvest the heads I mean
my God if everybody could have Cubans
white sift hash we wouldn't need all
these other right I mean what the [ __ ]
right and it's kind of like you know
again I've said this a bunch of times
booting on hash church as long as
there's prohibition anywhere there'll be
a black market everywhere and so you
even look at just just I I I I don't
know I mean the compression of margins
along the supply chain has basically
weeded out like a lot of people who
cannot compete with uh THC that's made
an order of magnitude cheaper than you
can grow it for I mean you just there
there's no competition you cannot
compete it it's a race to the bottom and
in a commoditized market price will
always win so it's [ __ ] up I don't
know how we can get this changed it's an
interesting there's there's some
interesting studies in California about
you know pesticides that are that
they're finding right so I think the LA
Times study came out showing this I
spoke to the journalist there I think um
paig St John is her name uh and uh it's
interesting that there like they did
this study in Canada where they looked
at 327 pesticides that um which is a
large panel for pesticides they're
trying to capture pesticides that are
outside of the the demanded testing
regimen um and they found like 92% of
the black market Market Flower up there
was uh was Laden with pesticide
sometimes a thousand times over the
limits and then only like 6% positivity
in the tested Market prior to Canada
going legal that number was more like
30% um so it looks like what's happening
up there is the the the the actual legal
Market's going down because they're
testing in terms of pesticides but the
black Market's going up so it's like The
Dumping Ground for everything that fails
but when Paige was doing this work in in
California
um it was a it's a bit different outcome
they're finding pens that are in the
Black Market that don't have any
pesticides probably because they're
chemically
synthesized uh and so um it's it brings
in a whole another you know or they're
synthetic cannabinoids right so it
brings in a whole another set of tests
they got to look for on the black market
pens um to assess safety they're they're
sometimes finding thcp in them they're
finding all of these bizarre canabo and
of course since they're synthetic
they're not they're not necessarily
coming along with a a high a high
pesticide content I I have to agree um
I've just seen so much stuff in the
legal market and transitioning from the
black market and like stuff that I think
a lot of people even aware of it that
they even have it in there because it's
systemically in their plant when their
or clones when the Clones that they got
and it's a big problem I agree yeah
sometimes it'll rich in the extraction
too I think Ethan Russo um showed that
that some of these pesticides really um
you know you might go from 20 to 80% on
the cannabinoids but the pesticides can
go from parts per million to parts per
thousand uh so the the extraction
process from flow is is different you
know I was under the impression most of
the Delta eight out there was made from
almost Crystal at CBD which should be
fairly pure yeah but yeah that's right
so those those pens ironically uh some
of them are going to be cleaner than um
I shouldn't say cleaner they're they're
less pesticide Laden than what you might
find in the in the legal Market but God
knows what hell's in them they may not
be Delta may may not even be Delta eight
they could be you know some of these
well yeah chrisal was like laughing at
me he was like saying he goes yeah you
look at like all this stuff that's being
tested for pesticides and it came out of
a chemical reaction vessel where there
AR pesticides and hopefully you're using
yeah cheap CBD isolate that's pretty
pure and if there are any Trace Amounts
of pesticides in there you hope that in
the process of distillation or whatever
purification process they're using
they're able to to get rid of those
things well but I I I think that the the
the the problem I think is is bigger
which is that all this regulation that's
required you do licensed production of
cannabis so you have to have your your
in some cases even your business pro for
of vetted by all these Regulators in the
state who want to make sure that you
know how to run a profitable business
right you have to do all kinds of
community outreach you have to make sure
that your [ __ ] is Zone correctly you
have to do FBI background checks the
hemp industry doesn't have to do any of
this right they don't have to do any all
they have to do is basically take bulk
biomass produce ingredients or just have
like a warehouse that buys those
ingredients until you can pull in you
know all the the miners are all
available isolate form some of those are
chemical synthesized but Kevin the uh um
the high CBG a varieties that are out
there right now have basically cratered
the price of cbga isolate CBG isolates
you see a lot of you know just products
with CVG in it like seltzers sodas
gummies all kinds of stuff so the the
hemp Bill remember that they didn't they
didn't
contemplate what was going to happened
after the hemp was Harvest because that
should be regulated by the Food and Drug
Administration right and you can't just
put CBD into a
food because that's in violation of the
food drug and cosmetic act right so they
never contemplated the whole CBD
business let alone CBN CBG all the other
alphabet soup and now you all these
crazy molecules which don't come from
CBD or hemp at all that are just being
synthesized right like hhcp and all that
of [ __ ] and now they're finding that THC
acetate generates Keen when you heat it
up on the mail so just all kinds of
crazy I think all of this regulatory
overhead is theater at the moment
because they're not policing it right
right yeah yep not at all if they don't
police it then they're just putting
they're raising the price of the legal
Market next to the black market and um
and then and all the business that are
in the legal Arena have like two hands
tied behind their back they they can't
write off their business expenses due to
28e they have to build facilities in
every state because they can't move
product across state lines I mean it's
it's just a they can't get banking right
like it's just a disaster for them
economically but they're collecting all
of this tax stuff to to float that side
of the image of of the regulatory Market
um but they're not running around
policing any of the lab testing so like
if they the lab testing is what's
supposed to detect the stuff and
differentiate it um I think we all as a
community have to pound on them to to
get that data public and and let the
policing happen uh real time because
having the right now what's happening um
I so I've been diving into this a little
bit with lab shopping and and uh this is
because of a talk at canmet this year
from Yasha Khan he showed some data
showing all the THC lab shopping and
some data on on like Houston mold lab
shopping that's going on uh and it's
clear that a lot of states have this
data showing that there are labs and
states that like pass everything and
they've been doing it for years and they
don't they don't act
um and so all the grows get painted into
an economic corner and end up having to
test with the labs that pass everything
and give them higher THC numbers and
then all the legitimate Labs like
Chris's lab and others you know
financially struggle uh and get squeezed
out of the marketplace so it's h yeah
Alex has a taste on this I'm
sure speaking of lab morning everybody
um see yeah likewise likewise well thank
you yeah I just wanted to jump in you
know we were part of the LA Times Expose
and it's incredibly uh revealing
obviously and you know there's a bunch
of things to kind of hit on there I
won't uh kind of go deep on it but um
you know one thing I wanted to hit on
kind of part of this conversation is you
know when when a state
puts uh testing regulations in place
that kind of essentially makes testing
the final check in the Integrity of the
supply chain and if there's no Integrity
in that because the state's not overly
regulating and Audi Labs then yeah it
creates these holes where everything
goes through you know whether that's you
know I mean it's it's been really sad
like uh up until you know I mean
California sitting on their hand
effectively and not doing anything The
Regulators to actually enforce and
ensure integrity and testing over
fiveyear period of legalization it's all
but destroyed the entire market and led
to the extinction level event that a lot
of uh small craft farmers and people
have gone through you know um because at
a certain point you know there becomes
an economic disincentive for people to
want to work with a good lab that's
going to give them accurate quality
repeatable data because they can just
chase the 50% flower literally we see
that it's been a huge thing whenever
we're publishing something at 26 and
it's 48% from this other lab why work
with us right whenever you that same lab
can p will pass you and never fail a
test for ASP Gillis pesticides whatever
it is you know why chance it with us
right so there's there becomes this
disincentive to even want to work with a
good lab you know but you know thank Jah
um you know by the beginning of this
year you know the state you know there
was a big shift you know the state lab
came online they have one down SoCal
that we're working with the University
of San Diego one up in Hayward or in the
Bay
Area um and if you've been tracking the
news you know there's been more recalls
this year than there's been in the last
five years combined you know and if if
you've kind of tracked you know it's
really been around po labeling inflated
potency as well as for asper Gillis
right it hasn't been about pesticides
because they haven't had those
capabilities internally um but but you
know essentially now that this is kind
of you know because and I think that's
one of the big things that you know the
hope of California regulation was going
to help button up you know learning
lessons from previous States mistakes
you know to have a comprehensive lab
program to test the testers to do the
secret shopping pulling the products off
shelves testing the product you you know
and kind of making sure that there's
Integrity to the testing side of things
and so that wasn't a thing for you know
the last four years this year it's been
a thing you know and then when the LA
Times expose they dropped you know kind
of that was after California you know
Department of cannabis control kind of
had a $5 million campaign to you know
kind of propaganda around why the legal
Market's so great and everything's you
know clean compared to the black market
but then boom the LA Times expose
dropped and really kind of showed you
know because when Paige St John reached
out to us in February early year you
know she was kind of writing the story
about how um it was an expose on how uh
California Regulators failing to do
their job and enact what's in the what
was in the regulations to kind of create
a state run lab that's secret shopping
testing the testers uh but the fact that
they hadn't done that let um basically
LED um the point of the article was
around how failed Regulators not doing
their job um to enact this has led to a
compromise public health and consumer
safety at the retail level and so they
went and bought 70 something Products
off shelves they fully anonymized all
the products um you know took flower out
of packaging gummies out of packaging
cartridges out of packaging they
anonymized whatever logos on the
cartridges and then they split the
samples sent half to us half in Resco
and San Francisco on Resco and is is
often the lab that we get compared to
whenever people have questions to
confirm pesticide data we have very
comparable tests
um and so the only thing that they
published in the LA Times expose is what
was double blind confirmed between us
and en Resco and so you know it was
really in really fascinating because you
know flower had 30% fail rate or so you
know kind of it was really for you know
you saw chlorop fenip Pyon butoxide pyin
bifenthrin those are all bug bomb
aerosol pesticides insecticides yeah
yeah well and they're insecticides but
more so they're these total least
Foggers you know and there's been this
thing like because I used to be in the
Hydroponics industry before we opened
scabs 15 years
ago and um and whenever we whenever um
whenever uh I was in the hydro store
there was this very common practice in
cultivation where in between harvests
and indoor Farms people used to
basically sterilize their rooms you know
by they'd spray their walls scrub their
tables do whatever with service
sanitation agents but then they would
take these 10,000 ft Greenhouse Foggers
they would light them off in 500 to
th000 Ft rooms um that are made out of
sheetrock and drywall and they would
basically total release fog these bug
bombs that permeates every surface area
of that space and it sucks into and
absorbs into the drywall and sheetrock
and then it sits around and then the
next Harvest they do it and the next
Harvest they do it and essentially there
becomes this like contamination um hyper
contamination factor that builds into
the sheetrock and drywall you can test
the drywall in like huge part per
million levels and what happens is every
time that you know temperature humidity
differentials you know hit Peak you know
whatever levels there's this off gasing
that happens years after its original
use so whenever anytime we see like
because we do a lot of root cause
analysis forensic investigations when
people fail and you know um it's there's
a huge kind of correlation to you see
you see if you see like chlorop py oxide
pyin
banthine you know there there's are
three different bug bombs and there's a
you know when we see that you know you
could guarantee it's an indoor
cultivation where these bombs were
dropped and people might not even have
used them for the last year or so um but
it's still showing up you know so that
was one thing and then you know but the
more damning kind of I think realization
from it was around cartridges right and
uh and in some of the worst example the
cartridges had like a 65% fail rate and
in some of the cartridges there was 10
to 20 pesticides detectable
um quantifiable and 10 of those were in
failing levels a lot of them were 100 to
thousand time levels you know like uh
you know so was and and you don't see
that no Farmers spraying that many
pesticides those types of concentrations
you know that's 100% indicative of
closed loop extraction processes you
know whether it's butane extraction
whether it's CO2 whether it's
distillation you know like the people
that are most on it what we've learned
people that can kind of you know there's
a lot of uh clients that we work with in
state of California that have a non-
detect level uh standard across the
board and they screen material they
micro extract it before they even commit
to purchasing material so that they know
what's coming into their extraction
closed loop system you know so and and
if there is ever anything they they know
what's there so that they can very
effectively thoroughly flush their
systems compartmentalize the gas etc etc
but what that what happens is when
nobody cleaning their instruments in
between and they're just running
material from this farm and this farm
and this Farm you know one dude's herpes
comes in the next dude's syis the next
dud is garia the next dud you know so
next thing you know there's herp syphil
you know in the extraction machine and
even if you then run hundreds of pounds
of clean material you know all of that
load carries over and concentrates into
the material and it just keeps carrying
over concentrating and so whenever
people that are on the manfacturing side
of things are just getting clean non
detect results from some fraudulent lab
they you know they operate and move
forward with this false sense of
security that everything's good there's
no issues but little do they know
there's this super concentration
magnification factors happening you know
that then next thing you know there's 10
to 20 pesticides at Super concentrations
and so it's a really big thing but you
know for what it's worth it just like
smeared [ __ ] all over the spacee of the
DCC and it really showed kind of how big
of an issue this is you know not just um
around kind of loud fraudulence but just
about how hyper uh contaminated things
like cartridges and other things that
come from clothed loop extraction can be
and so you know I just so thankful
basically tossing we're tossing a big
fat softball to people like Alex Baron
uh who I love Twitter um but his you
know he's running around saying this
shit's all causing schizophrenia and
violence everything else and as everyone
in this audience knows those studies are
all done with like marijuana that no one
ever tests so we've got no idea what's
in that stuff and yet this pesticide
issue if you look up a lot of these
insecticides and pesticides they have
like psychosis listed right they there's
neurological artifacts that can occur so
yeah War nerve agents shifted to
pesticides of the future you neurology
is a major aspect of this you know I'm
living with a family member who has
Parkinson so I deeply understand the
neurology aspect of of what happens to a
human when when things start to go
sideways and you know it's it's really
you know it's concerning on multiple
levels and a couple things that you said
Alec really came to mind in my
experience in California with working
with several Farms across the state is
keeping everybody honest it's really
difficult you know um I I you know and
then here here's another side of your
story is the marketing aspect of product
you know I've been mandated as a product
developer to make a certain percentage
point before and that's troubling
because that's not how this work works
you don't just design a a you know a you
know 99 proof product that's going to be
amazing on all all the touch points that
we all love you're not going to just
create a
95% uh THC product and have it resonate
across every single you know segment and
everyone's going to love it there's
inherently something wrong with that
mentality I think that good product come
from comes from good genetics good
growing practices and good you know good
marketing of that particular product to
that person but it's not about a
percentage point it's not about you know
how it's going to make you feel because
again it goes back to the basics of what
we all understand is that it's all
individual and we're we all have to
learn about these products and how they
bind with us as as people um and how our
receptors you know bind with those those
constituents there but I think it's it's
a big problem because on two sides of
the coin you have people marketing and
then you have people shopping that idea
of marketing to create a narrative that
really is a false narrative because
that's not actually how the plant works
it's not how well you know so I think
that's another aspect of the
conversation I wanted to bring a bit
little bit of light because that's been
my experience with this is I've been
asked to lab shop and then I call these
Labs out being like guys this is not
what's in this this is way too high like
where are you getting 98% from this is
not the constituents of this were these
varietals that we made this formulation
and these percentage points and amounted
of this and sure from these these
initial COA points you can amount to a
general you know area of of high 80s but
to see like 96% 97 kind of made me
question everything and I IC Crystal
yeah I spent my life dealing with all
this in in developing high level
products for several several markets at
once and it was it just ripped open the
doors of of deception on me and I just I
was the one being saying no guys
actually this is what the constituents
were it should be here or generally
around here and then they went and
retest like oh yeah you're kind of right
it is this it is that but you do have a
dichotomy here so I wanted to kind of
bring that up because it's there's two
drivers you have Agriculture and then
you have marketing and sales or really
three because you have you have to mark
it and then sell it right so I think
those together make a really really
interesting cocktail that needs to be
addressed
AC I think that's I mean ultimately what
everyone's talking about here is
California because we're talking about
California and California is a big model
hyper model for cannabis globally really
um is California dropped the ball in all
in a lot of different ways right
California the fifth largest economy in
the world agriculture it's a big imp you
know it's they just didn't have the
foresight to really roll this out and
actually maybe
not just lacking foresight but lacking
desire lacking Integrity not treating it
like other crops I mean even today you
know the the California the the cdfa
puts out an annual crop statistics
report you know on all different crops
it's very comprehensive it's about it
talks about inputs it talks about
pesticide costs each County what each
County spends and everything California
is not even I mean cannabis isn't even
in that report it's not even there's not
even an honor mention that say hey we
can't talk about it because of federal
federal regulations it's not there so
like the it's the largest cash CR in the
state and it's not treated like a a crop
so the the the Divide between
Agriculture and the C the community the
culture the marketing everything was
just a a complete dropping of the ball
and the pesticide thing example I
remember like 2015 me and Rob were kind
of in a circle of people talking about
like hey what would you guys do if you
rolling out legal cannabis in California
and Alec the first thing I thought of
was my experience at hydro shops right
it's a dirty dirty world and everyone
thinks everyone in cannabis is all cool
and hey now we're all brothers and we're
all here and we're it's all about the
plant let's be honest in California
Cannabis was about money and people
flocked to this state from all over the
world to grow cannabis to make a bunch
of money it's a cool way to make money
but anyway the hydro shops were feeding
the industry with a lot of either
outlawed or non-accessible pesticides
and when and and to me I'm like wow you
can't let that happen you can't let that
be unregulated and then have agriculture
exist over here it just doesn't work
that way and anyway so when we got a
license down in LA and I have a friend
who had the local Hydro shop and I'd go
and walk in and say hey buddy and buy
some stuff I'd sit there and listen to
him time and time again say to people
are you licensed or not and the are not
part they walk them in the back and
they'd pull out they'd open up the door
the trapo you know the deal and they'd
pull out countless over and over again
pesticides that and with and then they'd
give it to him in a
unlabeled bottle with no instructions at
all on how to use it with maybe a
Sharpie on the side that says like 2.5
mil per gallon or something and I'm just
like and the people that they were
selling it to honestly let's be honest
were fairly large commercial Growers
growing throughout the state and they
they basically right at that transition
Point said no you don't have to worry
about that and to me the big thing the
the pesticide issue that was like
obvious like why do people do that but
the fact that there's still pack
utol that's testing hot showed that this
this whole mentality and this whole
Market hasn't stopped it only blew up it
only got bigger you know what I mean and
and and to me that's the state not
looking at cannabis like a crop not
thinking about I mean the way they
regulated the the the canopy the way
they regulated who got licenses all of
it they're not thinking about it the
same way they think about all the other
crops which is it's a commodity you have
to protect the farmer you have to
maintain a certain you know status quo
in terms of yield and what the price per
whatever is and anyway that that to me
is a big part of this and California now
is trying to kind of like backpedal and
figure out well but so it's over
regulated we know that it's it's not
regulated like another crop we know that
it's not regulated like tobacco or
alcohol right so to me it's just a big
dropping of the ball like no one really
would scary if it was regulated like um
tobacco like don't they grow tobacco
with radium
226 isn't that like r
but my point but real quick the point
there is that that I make is that if we
imagine prohibition never happened what
would it be what would the market look
like we all want to be a cleaner safer
better world but we also want TR
cannabis to be treated like other plants
so there's that to me is a big part of
this intersection with how do we
transition it it applies to hemp it
applies to the thca market it applies to
how we apply pesticides it applies to so
many different aspects that shop the the
the way we test and sell by THC
percentage it's like we need to get to
the point where from a higher level we
understand that this is a cash commodity
it's huge we need to protect the farmer
we need to protect all of those things
and at the same time it's nuanced
because cannabis is incredibly
complicated and there's a lot of weird
there and you know well and it's it's a
it's a it's become a cash commodity but
it's also a sacred plant Sacrament right
and and I don't think about stooping to
the low of Agriculture which is captured
and all but poisoned and led to all the
long-term chronic illness and cancer
that now we're faced with I think it's
cannabis is here one of the big great
gifts it's here to offer Beyond The
phytochemical Complex of what it brings
is through the testing that we've never
applied to any other crop on this level
and it being this great bio accumulator
of the century it's helping to uproot
the story and the legacy of the Green
Revolution and what we've done the land
what we've done to the neighborhoods
what we've done to the school districts
downwind of the drifting [ __ ] avocado
Farms you know and so for what it's
worth like you know I think kind of when
there is integrity testing I think that
creates the barrier of Entry that keeps
out big egg big tobacco big Pharma right
because you can't just flip a Thousand
Acre monocrop Mega Farm that's sprayed
glyphosate and all the Organo phosphates
from World War II that you know you you
could grow grow rope for 10 years maybe
clean up your land one day you could
grow some type one type two type three
drug cultivars but but until then go
grow rope you know because the thing is
is like you know cannabis I mean because
there's the potency thing and then
there's the public health and safety
thing right the pocy thing is a
marketing [ __ ] thing it doesn't
matter you blow out 80% of the the
canabo and turbs in the smoke you know
whenever you exhale nobody holds it in
their lungs like they used to when we
were growing up you know because it was
so cherished and you know rare or uh you
know scarce you know people are sipping
and ripping just taking a little puff
blowing it out right most of everything
goes out in the smoke so I think it's
labeling pure labeling right and or pure
pure marketing right and and deducing it
down to THC is kind of really blurred
the lines between the the most monocrop
uh biomass and the most craft champagne
qu T quality cannabis there is um and
then Labs just passing everything as
clean it's blurred lines between the
dirtiest most adjacent herb and the
cleanest most like you know kind of um
complete you know non-com compromised
herb right and so I think the testing
has a huge role you know to kind of help
to kind of create that division between
what we're talking about but you know
when it comes to you know the the whole
reality of the pesticides you know I
think it's you know because there's a
lot of national efforts on the hemp
lobby with a lot of big money people
trying to you know further turn this
into a commodity right and again because
you know this I think it's this plants a
lot of things right but but the thing is
is I think we have to be eternally
Vigilant to prevent this from ever
happening right because if we allow the
stripping of the regulations and
reduction of to be more like food then
you know everybody lost nobody ever had
a chance right everybody that's been
doing this all their life right um but
but the thing is is where cannabis is
planted it's kind of like a transparency
Beacon you know so in Santa Barbara
County where all the avocados all in
camill all the I mean rotational egg you
rotational crops planted throughout the
year different times sprayed with
different pesticides punch sides and
things right it's a constant moving
Target and so when a cannabis farm is
planted there boom bing you failed right
now that there's recourse because like
Farmers carrying crop insurance crop
insurance claims are skyrocketing in
California right now you know farmers
are getting sued because they're their
drift is affecting a neighboring
cannabis farm that's a high value crop
and now their crop insurance skyrockets
now kind of liability is there you know
there's all these PES use report
requests investigations leading to crop
insurance claims and so what is
happening is it's forcing reform in
agriculture aerial sprang out of
helicopters and and planes in Center
Barb county has decreased by like 80% in
the last few years because cannabis is
now in the neighborhood right and so
then not only does that clean up and
prevent kind of cannabis Farms from kind
of just having this constant failing
situation that they can't do anything
about but it's also pre it's lowering
the overall exposure of school districts
and the water sheds and streams and you
know because people spraying in the
middle of the day without without any
like consideration of fif R wind
conditions and like time of day right
people are just spraying out of you know
economic convenience right out of
helicopters and just dive bombing where
people are just driving down the freeway
next to it right and so I think kind of
Dr really incredible to see what's
happening in this way of the forced
reform that's happening in
agriculture I want to pull on that
thread a little bit Alec and that I I
think what would really help the
industry and put it above this whole a
market which is fairly non-transparent
um is if we can get the states to put
their testing data from metric public um
right now we have to foyet this stuff
from a lot of the states which is a big
pain in the ass and and hats off to
Yasha con and Jeff Roston a lot of
people have gone and done that um Jim
mcgrey also did a lot of this early on
in Washington um I don't can you guys
see this screen that I put up all right
so what what we've done is we've gotten
data foa data Supply by Yasha and others
Whoever has it and put it into a SQL
database so that we can look at in this
case we're not doing THC although we
have that data uh we can do that next
we've been looking at just microbial
failure rates right and so we can chart
the fail rate per lab uh and this gives
us all types of information in regards
to like which labs are you know over or
under failing things um but more
importantly you can also see some
strange Behavior Uh in certain Labs okay
okay so we can actually chart let's say
let's take this lab I happen to know um
very very well respected lab in Mass um
so this is their total yeast and mold
levels across time for every test in
Mass this has been going on for several
years uh as many know the action limit
mass is 10,000 cfus per gram and this is
red line here so they have an even
distribution of past fails you know
samples Above and Beyond in terms of
cfus per gram their data is thinning out
over time because they're honest uh uh
people are leaving this lab because this
lab is in the
state
and that's
shocking this has been going on since
2022 and the CCC has done nothing except
when Labs raised this the labs that rais
the fact that this is fake data or at
least you know severely conflicted data
um they got visited by they got they
call it raided inspected by the CCC so
the whistleblowers got attacked
uh and uh and this particular lab we
know is operating like in 10 states at
least and they're vacuuming up the
volume in all the
states uh so for those who not familiar
with this somehow the yeast and mold
know to stop growing at 10,000 in
Massachusetts and if you go to other
states where it's at 100,000 the same
thing got they got the memo yes the the
yeast and mole got the memo um so the
other benefit of this is that this is
Massachusetts data but um what could be
really helpful uh in in this arena for a
lot of these Regulators because they
have their own you they have their own
tranches of data which they're drowning
in but they don't know how they compare
to other states um like this would have
like really helped Oregon because Oregon
um blew out Astro jillis testing um
because a few Labs there this is this
was not Apparent at the time so um you
know not not not anyone's fault but
Growers were getting screwed and that
some Labs had 100% fail rate yeah but a
couple labs had the same fail rate as uh
sorry this is taking a little bit time
to load um take it off log scale uh some
other labs had a fail rate that was
um I can find the right Labs here that
was in line with Michigan and Nevada why
nilous oh sorry it might need to
be fooled
uh and
um gotta find the right oh sorry I'm in
the wrong graph uh that's why
my
bad sorry so if you look at this there
there's some Labs here that are giving
like a 4% fail rate that's that's what
we see in Michigan in in Nevada so that
would have been there shouldn't have
been any alarm Bells however if you look
at some of the lower volume Labs you
move this minimum test down more Labs
should show up some of these Labs were
failing
everything and they had very few very
few sample B volume to do this most of
them were under 100 tests um so this
created a panic and the grower sued and
got the the regs removed uh so now
there's no ASP jillis testing in in in
Michigan now uh obviously I'm conflicted
we so you know CRI a river or sorry
Oregon yeah um but if the if the states
had the capacity to measure state to
state The Regulators would known oh wait
a minute we're dealing with an anomaly
here there's a couple Labs that are out
of spec but the largest volume lab in
the state was in line with Michigan and
Nevada all right we know where to focus
um uh but instead they kind of folded
not being able to handle the onslaught
that was uh was occurring and The
Growers rightfully would like [ __ ] we're
going to all go out of business if if
they were testing at any of these Labs
that had 100 you know really high fail
rates um well do this with pesticides as
well there's a host of ways to kind of
parse the data but I think getting this
public so that um a lot of people in the
field um Can attack the data help the
regulator The Regulators don't have
anyone on staff to do this type of data
analysis not
that and it's always better to have more
eyes and of course there are you know
Labs that are vested in understanding
this data there are um consumers that
are vested but very rarely do the labs
or the consumers have the lobbying power
to go and change the regulations uh the
grows have a lot of money and a lot of
tax uh um receipts and and you know so
be it there you know I think the market
if you look at the lab markets like for
400 million a year is what it's been
estimated at um whereas the the grow
Market is you know the whole cannabis
industry is north of 20 billion so uh
the regulations are going to get written
by the people with the most tax money
going into the state coffers and so um
they'll they'll continue to to probably
do what tobacco did which is to rip out
all the regulations possible uh if uh
and while the consumers and the labs
kind of sit on this different economic
chess for um now the same thing can
probably be done with pesticides we have
some pesticide data in here Oregon you
can see the pesticide data in Oregon
didn't radically change during the the
time frame of um uh of putting in any of
that asil
Tes anyway I think that's my that's my
soapbox is is that um I think if we get
this data public we can help The
Regulators police the market kind of
like what happened in Washington yeah
like because whenever whenever the
public kind of was able to do the free
moov Information Act request and look at
the data it was kind of pretty
transparent which Labs were never
failing any body and and deviating from
actually the average but but I Kevin and
this is a huge thing I I'd love to talk
with you at like length about this I'm
and I'm actively in like
multiple um pretty large aspir Gillis
contamination rout cause analyses which
I've uh you know because really early on
when legalization happen you know um
fails started popping up a fail is
consequential you have to remediate or
destroy product thousands tens of
thousands potentially hundreds of
thousand dollars product really early at
SC Labs we learned like you can't just
Auto email somebody a fail that's the
end of the relationship you know um and
so so and that and you know and a lot of
labs that opened kind of within a year
of legalization that thought it was just
a get-rich quick guaranteed testing kind
of thing because it's mandat mandatory
you know they like were compromised from
the very beginning because it's like a
fail means the loss of the business you
know and so a lot of labs that had no
understanding of the plant no kind of
experience no ability to even engage
with clients to help them figure figure
it out you know just it's easier to pass
people so they people would just pass
people and and that's again where this
disincentive occurred with us so you
know we almost went out of business
towards the end of last year because
nobody even wanted to work with us
because of how fraudulent the testing
space was but on the topic of as Gillis
you know it's it's really fascinating
because you know what we see it's about
about two and a half 3% fail rate across
all testing so most people don't fail
most of the time but whenever somebody
has legitimate spores detected and
present that's an indication that spores
are present somewhere in your facility
and unless they're attended to
methodically to like eradicate them from
the facility then what you can see is
like this overtime you know intermittent
fail rate from like one out of 40
batches to one out of 20 batches to one
out of 10 batches so you start seeing
this like exponential increase in fail
rates to where like worst case scenario
examples you know we've had groups have
a 50 to 60% fail rate for fuma Godus or
flavis on any sample they sent in right
and that's what happens whenever an
issue arises with aspergillis that is
not even addressed right or like
somebody works with a lab to just give
them clean results and brush it under
the rug but that doesn't mean it goes
away and this kind of really I think in
a big way kind of correlates to that
Oregon conversation as well because
Oregon didn't do any micr testing for
six seven plus years of legalization so
all of a sudden now like aspir Gillis
kicks in all of a sudden fail rates are
kind of way higher than people think
sure there's probably a bunch on
Labs not having their [ __ ] together not
having the you know positive day
controls all the things in place to
ensure that they're producing quality
data but I'm not I wouldn't be surprised
if certain groups actually legitimately
had a really high fail rate right
because what happens what we've seen is
you know Prat like so so these species
of asilas they're not native to Canabis
microbiome they're placed there through
some type of a vector Source those
Vector sources could be something like
like contaminated trichoderma who would
have ever thought that right people are
buying from arbore Organics prodcts I
won't name where they're inoculate you
got like beneficial fungus trma
inoculated on like a green clay that
turns out the green Clay is contaminated
with aspila fum Godus right so you're
buying thousands of dollars of
beneficial fungus inadvertently
inoculating human pathogenic fungus all
over your entire crop watering it into
the root zones right people are taking
predatory bug sources right that are on
a media right vermiculite mix a
vermiculite brand mix right and they're
spreading it over the root balls of
their plants to deploy the bugs well
guess what that's a vector like we've
seen like a couple of the biggest cases
like an ongoing one we're working with
right now we just kind of you know and
because that's what's crazy it's like we
were never the lab that was going to
just stroke somebody's ego like tell
them everything is okay and just
fraudulently like let them get passes we
fail if it fails a real fail we fail
them and then somebody like myself and
now we have a technical services team to
engage immediately as a fail happens to
both demonstrate the quality and
reproducibility of our work and how
seriously take a fail and and all the
lqc checks that we have in place to
ensure the quality of the batch and the
data and then from there disarming
because everybody was want to put it on
the lab like the lab screwed up right um
but then after we do this process of
demonstrating quality and precision of
our work then we shift it into a root
cause analysis and over hundreds of
these root cause analyses we've gotten
to the exact who who what were why when
how and uh a contaminant might have
entered a supply chain and and we've
been able to you know turn because
originally it was like total [ __ ]
sandwiches you know just engaging with
groups worst conversation I've ever had
with an owner screaming at me you know
kind of but but now it's like you know
we've developed a pallet for these [ __ ]
sandwiches because we've have we have so
many example use cases root cause cases
where we' figured this out and so now
it's like within a few questions we can
actually help somebody genuinely figure
out where's coming from because what
happens is there's a vector that
introduces it once it's introduced then
if you you know say say you introdu it
through predatory bug Source or
introduce it through inoculating
green yeah exactly we've seen it certain
instances of like like there's pinu like
that's like a cocoa fiber Pete Moss
peite right we've seen like instances
you know so they can be batched to batch
like media issues but um but whenever we
see the widespread outbreaks in
contamination it's usually we're seeing
it from like something like taking
trichoderma putting it in your Reservoir
watering it into every single plant in
your room right into the root Zone and
then it like proliferates and then
spores will like linger but then you har
what happens is you harvest the room you
go bring it into a dry room you hang all
the material in this big dense kind of
smashed together area you know where
humidity spikes you got DFI is working
to pull out the humidity you have tons
of air flow circulating the air around
and so what happens is you have the
proliferation of the spores that then
spread in the air systems and so so the
the the amplification multiplication
factor for the fail rate happen in the
air systems you know the HVAC lines the
air ducts the air handlers the
dehumidifier filters right and so when
we go out and do swabbing you know it's
like those spaces specifically that
yield the most positive results of
detection right and so so whenever we do
these types of uh analyses root cause
analyses it's about engaging to help
identify the root Chase it out of the
facility like remove that Source from
ever being introduced and then
simultaneously leveling up uh microbial
reduction strategies for how somebody's
approaching air system decontamination
because most Farmers they that don't
fail most of the time you know they they
have some semi you know solid process of
surface sanitation and spraying walls
and cleaning trays but very few Farmers
ever use some type of chlorine dioxide
or other type of gas um type of solution
where they actually intentionally Target
air systems because air systems are the
biggest place where we see the Spore
counts kind of grow rise and then carry
over to the next batch and the next
batch and then all of a sudden it's it's
an amplification issue that that's where
we see the fail rates go from like you
know 2% up to 15 30 40 plus percent
within a facility but whenever but it's
a very contained with in a specific
facility issue most people don't fail
most of the time but again once it's
present if you don't like very
methodically like address the issue it
can become like you got to like burn
your facility down kind of
situation Che packets Garden clean you
know compared to or a lot cheaper than
the radsource machine that you use to
Nuke all your weed yeah 100% so Al you
know last week we we kind of brushed
over like for maybe two minutes
remediation and you know we're talking
about ASO jalis a little bit and you
know we've talked a lot about the data
we've talked a lot about what we see
wrong you know what we see a lot in a
lot of new markets is just it goes
straight to remediation and then that
goes to a jar some reason right and then
someone's like someone's buying that
being like yeah I just bought a black
cherry or just bought powdered donuts
and they go home and they're smoking
remediated herb that is just Laden with
dead cells now how healthy is that you
know and what what are we doing in the
in in the industry or the community to
to bring awareness has has a good paper
on this looking at bio aerosols like so
if you zap your way out of this problem
you end up with high Moto toxins and
high endotoxins and a variety of other
stuff that are just not well studied
unfortunately so um the the paper I
threw up here speaking of powdered
Donuts this is a really good paper from
zamir puner where he's noticed that the
total yeast and mold levels in his
plants are very genotype specific he's
got some that are 50-fold less tym than
others consistently powder Donuts being
one of the worst ones uh because uh
maybe that powder isn't the powder you
want it's it's exactly I think that's
the what I you know the thing I think
about a lot is you know we all talk
about this we're coming in for wellness
and we're leaving with what you know
another problem um and then we are doing
our best as as community members and
constituents and and you know just good
good practices all the way through and
then at the end you're getting tested
for this and it's not calling out the
specific strain of of what this is and
there's really no it's just a blanket
past fail and is that the right way
Kevin um Mark you know do you feel you
know Alec I guess you know even going
deeper is there a way for us to call out
these specific constituents that are
problematic versus the ones that are are
perhaps
benign if if I real quick go ahead Al
you first cool yeah just real quick you
know like as so although California's
triple [ __ ] up in all kinds of ways
you know um around kind of how this
whole system is rolled out you know one
thing I think that they did really well
and um and you know we actually were a
big Lobby part with a lot of the organic
farmers in California to kind of block
the implementation of total East mold
total Rob bacteria levels right because
you know what we've seen from states
that have implemented these incredibly
restrictive Easter mold count levels and
and bacteria levels you know is that's
the biggest fail rate there's 30 40 50%
fail rate it forces people into having
to kill step to having to you know
ozonate or pasteurize or gamma radiate
everything before it's even sold at
retail and that in a big way in my
opinion that kind of Dooms the legal
Market because then everything is TP
zaps prior to being sold so then you're
guaranteed to be able to find any
everything terier and fresher and more
aromatic and terpenic from the black
market or traditional Market than you
are from anything on a dispensary shelf
you know and and and in those States
people are full hix like like clean suit
like it's snarly you know obviously
anybody that's operating those spaces no
and it's like and you know the thing is
is canab is an agriculture crop if
you're going to regulate so strictly on
EPA regulated like anti-life chemicals
from Bayer and Dupont senta and all
these chemical companies you know it's
like the way is like organic IPM
practices using benficial microorganisms
compost te's kind of like other
ways TM in place yeah that stuff
basically is a deao ban on all on all
biocontrol agents right right right
there are no EPA approved pdes tot for
use on cannabis and and all all the
state regulatory bodies that have tried
to make select lists you'll see like
most of the bio pesticides on there you
know low you know efficacy High use rate
kind of materials but the onus is on so
what what is a p pesticide pesticides a
active ingredient that kills bugs it's
sold in different product formulations
and places like Lowe's and own Depot and
yeah the onus is on the company that
registers so those products are
regulated under the Environmental
Protection Agency not the US Department
of Agriculture the EPA grants licenses
for use on pesticides and nothing is
registered for use on cannabis now they
do have some stuff registered on on hemp
which I thought is interesting right
again I think they're caught in that
whole
differentiation based on canono profile
but until the company shows that owns
the registration for the active
ingredient shows that at commercial
application use rates that there's no
effect to the environment no effect to
the crop in terms of toxic and you know
for that they'd have to basically enroll
human subjects which is going to take
years and millions of dollars to show
that we could apply this pesticide to
cannabis during this stage of production
at this use rate and here are the
metabolites and we've done safety
assessments on the levels of metabolites
that are in the final cannabis products
and guess what they're they're safe but
we've done Clinic basically clinical
studies in humans to show that you know
when they apply a typical insecticide or
fungicide to a crop first of all a lot
of those crops oh most of those crops
aren't smoked right and a lot of those
crops are washed and a lot of those
crops and I I really love your comment
here Alec because growing indoors you
know a lot of these pesticides are
basically photolytically leile so
they're meant to basically elicit their
mode of action and then the
photolytically degrade within days with
u UV andc Spectrum which isn't there in
indoor either right somehow right and
you may not be getting that light in
your indoor grow but the other thing you
said which is really you know again
disturbing to hear is that these things
are environmentally persistent in indoor
cavities and especially when you have
things like drywall which you know is
great for hanging pictures on your wall
but not the you want to clad the inside
of your cannabis production facility
with right there's certainly better
cladding options but maybe Kevin I guess
the interesting aspect I saw in your
data is yeah again that bifurcation
where it's like okay now everything's
all of a sudden below and those labs are
getting the business and you know that
again in in testing
Labs it's all about the numbers right
Alec it's all about how many
how many test samples can you get out
how many customers can you keep so the
samples that you're testing this week
are people going to get those results
and be like oh [ __ ] we're not going to
go to SC anymore we're going to go to
some other place that's going to give us
better results so maintaining customers
I mean it's an incredible Challenge and
I remember when looking at profor as the
testing Labs you think oh yeah these
companies probably worth hundreds of
millions of dollars like [ __ ] no it's
like they're operating at a razor thin
margin where basically you're trying to
you're trying to beat the other 10
testing labs in your neighborhood so I
mean there's incredible pressures on
these labs to produce and to try to you
know create bottom line impacts so it's
a it's a tough place to be man like I I
don't know what Mar that's why the
marketing is a problem man it's like
it's just there's no there's
nearly there's no factual evidence
behind a lot of the marketing it's just
all it's all the highest point and then
they go out and shop that right so it
creates that competition because they
have a mandate as a business if you're
trying to hit a product at 92% every
single time with eight% turps so it
tastes good and hits the the high
90s I mean you'll shop that all day long
if you can make make one printed design
and send it around to 200 shops like it
just saves you money across the board so
sorry
I I just wanted to finish the point I
was trying to make real quick you know
just about kind of like what Kevin was
talking about with the Oregon stuff you
know because and in California and how
California did testing you know like
very happy that they didn't they focus
specifically on the human pathogenic
organisms yes I think this is actually
really important point that and I think
this yeah and I think this could evolve
right because it's like I think they
took a more sophisticated approach not
regulating just the benign arbitrary
colonies total yeast of mold total
aerobic bacteria this focus more on the
human pathogens I think there's a lot
more microtox producing type of compound
right the type of
fungi those so I think I think that's
the evolution of it but but the fact is
I think it was a great success that
specific asperilla species that are
human pathogenic organisms were what are
targeted right it's only a presence or
absence right any any DNA detected in
you know one gram of material right um
so it's not like a quantification how
much is there it's just presence or
absence right we haven't really ever
failed anybody for microt toxins right
so it's not like peanuts or coffee beans
where it's like widespread outbreak
producing micro toxins but it's more
intermittently spread right particularly
compounded through air systems but
that's one of the big things that I want
to make point of is like um you know
like focusing specifically on public
health and safety and what can Farm
people right is what I think the way
forward is right and with it's gonna end
up in court right eventually it's gonna
end up in court and and the clinical
lature is not written in the language of
11,000 total yeast and mold colonies
hurt somebody they just don't write
papers that way because they're forced
to to basically satisfy C's postulates
which is you you isolate the pathogenic
organism and you reintroduce it to to a
model organism and see that it creates
harm and if you haven't created that
Loop you can't publish like the clinical
literature is not going to let you
publish something saying I had 56,000
total aerobic count and maybe that hurt
somebody they're going to say no go back
and tell us if it was Eola if it was
salmon if it was staff if it was pomonis
like you have to isolate the organism so
all the clinical literature is written
in species specific language so let's
say it grows like happens in Oregon and
they were to go to court they would
probably lose against ASP regillus
because there's in fact clinical
literature you know tying harm to real
patients if they applied that case
against total ye and mold they would win
uh because the reality cannot defend uh
you do not know which level harmful uh
and it's meant to be just a bioburden
check it's not meant to actually predict
clinical outcomes right but the reality
of aspergillis though in Oregon right
because all the because in Oregon you
got all the headyy organic people you
know deploying organic IPM practices
spreading predatory bugs deploying
trichoderma it wouldn't surprise me if a
pretty high fail rate existed
individually within certain facilities
because of how much we've seen the
introduction of it lead to you know
because most people again fail most of
the time for aspir Gillis but once
you've introduced it and sports are
genuinely present in your facility and
you're in a closed loop system and it
compounds and Carries over and like you
know kind of replicates in the air
systems you start compounding the issue
to where you have no idea how big and
how gnarly of an issue it can become and
so that's one of the things where I
think like you know Oregon you know
didn't have any microbiology testing in
place they started like by leading the
way
because test but didn't do this thing
with aspir Gillis and then they fought
it and you know prevented it from coming
in that doesn't mean the problem doesn't
exist you know and so I think the
reality is is you know kind of a more
sophisticated approach in how kind of
it's dealt with and how it's understood
because you know a lot of
well-intentioned organic farmers that
are using organic IPM products
inadvertently unknowingly are
introducing it and then kind of Might
very well have 3040 plus percent fail
rates internally because they've never
because until somebody genuinely starts
failing for ASP Gillis
nobody is even paying attention to
cleaning out their air systems in some
semi-routine way nobody's like gassing
chlorine dioxide to kind of Ensure like
they're chasing out any remaining spores
right and so I think it's a it's
definitely a big issue you know and uh
and I think kind of too A lot of the
work you've done Kevin it's like it's
you know there there are things besides
you know kind of asulis right like there
are ferium producing microt toxin
there's certain other types of things
that could be producing things that are
gnarly
so I think instead of kind of just test
you know that's why I appreciated
California they didn't it's it wasn't
just testing all microbes for the sake
of testing microbes it was focusing on
the human pathogens and I think as long
as we do that you know we can kind of
actually as a whole community help kind
of you know really Advance the the plant
and the safety and efficacy of now the
the flip side of of the asilis testing
has been that um people are complaining
that there's there's visible mold on
some cannabis that gets through that
aspil it's not aspis right and and
somehow we we probably have to button
that up with figuring out what that is
and and and either have a visual screen
or or finding what other pathogenic
organisms we're cared about if it's not
pathogenic we you know throw it out if
you can see it like a strawberry but if
it's pathogenic maybe maybe we got to
keep maybe you got to add something to
the list but and that's what the f and
for material test is supposed to pick up
by so there's um I think the species
specific stuff will also reduce a lot of
the lab shopping because the fail rates
go down so people don't have a
motivation to lab shop as much um and
then you know on top of that the labs
are are um they're much easier tests to
perform in that the labto laab they
won't be as discordant than the total
use and mold tests uh and so you'll
probably have less of this capacity for
people to find a lab that's got a 2%
failure rate versus a 15% failure rate
it's you know everyone's going to
probably be floating around three to 5%
uh independent of which which test
provider they're using so it'll probably
Wipe Out the motivation for folks to be
lab shopping off of microbials if we we
get those things done right
can I um can I mention something else
about I'm not sure if we wanted to talk
about this today Wade had his hand up
I'm sorry I hate I always got to defend
Wade get in there
Wade thank you
Marcus
I oh I think it's mut you're muted
Wade can you hear me now
Absolut okay um patient of many many
years cultivator of many years a lot of
this conversation this morning has
really been focused around solving
problems that come with indoor
cultivation Andor extensive Greenhouse
cultivation and I could be naive and I
would ask anyone on the panel to call me
out for being naive but when I was a
cultivator and engaged in what we call
regenerative practices where I was
creating any of the inputs that I wanted
for my crop on my farm so I knew what
was in it um all of these issues around
asilis yes it's in the atmosphere here
but it's a non-issue in a su grown
regenerative Garden is my experience and
again totally anyone on the on the group
calling me out as [ __ ] here but I
got to say that part of the silo that
has happened in States across this
country is forcing this conversation
upon us and I really want to remind
people that if you grow your own in the
sun take care of your plants they'll
take care of
you that's all I got I'm gonna go back
to listening fascinating conversation
and again thank you Marcus love you
brother I I have some data actually at
hand that can try to address this so
thank you for bringing it up Wade um so
there there is uh a lot of discussion
about ASP regillus out there and you
have to keep in mind that aspis has got
280 different species and we only give a
[ __ ] about four of them all right so
this is um now I don't have this split
by outdoor and indoor but it's a very
important Point uh that I'll have to see
if our if we have that information and
we can maybe dissect it and get to that
but what you're seeing on these on these
top lines up here that are kind of
cratering to the right are all aspila
species in in leaves so so let me back
up we've got about a thousand whole
genome sequin when we do whole genome
sequencing we get the microbiome picture
with it and so we can then ask what
tissue type did the sequencing come from
and and look at the microbiome per
tissue type so when you look at uh when
you're looking on the on the x-axis here
are the number of reads per million okay
so when you're sequencing the fungal
microbiome we're just counting how many
reads are ASP regillus versus all other
fungal [ __ ] that's there uh and it's
it's they're at you can see 100% of the
samples will have aspergillus of some
sort at 100 reads per million still a
very very low amount but all all of the
samples that we collected this is 943
samples uh that are that are in there
however when you start going down to the
four that we care about in the
regulations this drops down to like the
9% range that have 100 reads per million
we think the PCR tests are kind of
picking things up somewhere around the
three or 400 reads per million range so
the number this is this kind of lines up
with the Alex number around 3 to 4%
failure rate but I just want to show
this because it's often thrown out there
that asilis is every everywhere which is
true as a Genus but as a species of
these four pathogenic ones there's a
huge gap between all of them in just
these four so the ubiquity stuff is is
um you got to keep in mind there's a
major reduction when you just focus on
on the few that are there um but we now
have this kind of information um from
basically a thousand different uh
cannabis genomes from all over the world
so we know like what pathogens are there
uh so we can better inform Regulators
that okay these ones we don't need to
care about these ones do based on the
frequency of what we found um from
sequencing data because what they've
really done is just taken most of the
food industry and just lobbed it on top
of cannabis like they're putting leria
in place we've never found leria we
don't see leria in this type of
sequencing data but they want to put it
in there because the food people use it
and the food people have a test for it
and they can slap that onto our field
and start you know harvesting uh some
food testing revenue from us um you know
arguably a Coline cell they're very very
low in frequency um they're they're
there and it's like probably one in a
thousand samples or something might be
positive for them so yeah maybe you do
want to grab those if it's going to end
up in in you know oral or end up
ingested in some way but uh I don't
think anyone is lab shopping off of the
coli cell numbers they're just the
frequency of failure is just too low for
anyone to give a [ __ ] about uh that it
wouldn't it wouldn't create that kind of
economic motivation so what we got to do
wait is I got to see if we have that
information in this database if we can
split it by outdoor indoor because I do
think what Alec is bringing up the
indoor systems are recirc C ating a lot
of the air if the spores are in the
facility they're just recycling those uh
and outdoor systems may have all types
of natural mechanisms to keep asilis at
Bay like all these other gram positive
bacteria that flush it out of out of um
competition one thing I think's
important to keep in mind is how like
with the data coming from a lot of the
product that's in the market is not what
the
test actually represents you know
there's a lot of product that just gets
slapped a label on it so to speak um in
every Market where people are just
taking you know part of some other batch
and making it a part of a batch that has
a different sample or test on it and
that's I I think that the problem is
probably a lot more widespread than even
the data would
show it's really good point you know
there's a lot of that going on
especially nowadays because of the times
that we're in you you know making things
go further test results last longer um
batching large batches over time and
testing them week after week or every
bi-weekly is a really expensive Endeavor
um you know so I think that's that's a
good call out I I've thought about that
often it's funny that you bring that up
because it's it's yeah I mean metric
data is is just about as reliable as the
person that's inputting it so change ey
right you know yeah it's definitely it's
definitely true in the sense that you
know it it's not just like and I saw
this in Jamaica a lot it's not just like
bad evil people who are like oh I'm just
going to put these chemicals in because
I'm nefarious it's like you see these
situations occur where it's like I will
either feed my family or I won't feed my
family and it's sort of this mentality
where you're it's like the ultimate
trial where you're like okay like are
you going to have the high integ and
bankrupt your life or are you going to
get that 100 pound s you know fig lot
figured out and tested and passed in any
way shape or form that you can so I
think it's a very good point uh in what
uh Fletch just said in the sense that uh
it's just so easy to fall victim to
circumstance um I want to keep on the on
the conversation but I also want to like
first of all thank everyone from Fletch
I see etan is in the room for the first
time on 5.0 Brian's back Alec has also
showed up here which has been awesome
dude listening to you great to have
Mojave in the house Grandmaster LED
Thomas is here Colin and Wade we got Dr
Mark and of course Kevin McCaron sharing
sharing the data and it's just a real
interesting conversation so I wanted to
recognize and thank you all for showing
up I'm here with my homie Merlin my
other friend just rolled up Lincoln
who's kind of off camera but he left the
room so I'll just thank everyone there's
255 people watching right now and let's
uh you know keep this conversation going
it's awesome thank you
guys yeah I was going to say I I met re
at the emerald cup I met someone who's a
farmer in Central Valley and he grows in
the state legal Market at scale grows
thca Farm Bill hemp at scale and also
grows traditional Legacy at
scale and plays all three paths and I
was just like I'm like wow the logistics
of that that's insane like like wow that
you clearly can handle a lot but think
about how much you know there's a lot of
diversion in the state obviously and
everything goes everywhere if it can
that's and I am hearing that in other
states too I hear in other states where
people are like you know I would buy
from from the state Market but their
flower sucks so I'm buying imported thca
flour and then I'm selling it on our
Shelf as Delta 9
and getting new coo coas on it and it's
just like man it's just nuts you know
and there's a lot of that going on um
and and lab shopping is is kind of at
the heart of all that because diversion
and you know working with burner dros
and all that stuff it's all about having
a piece of paper you know and it's a
it's a dirty supply chain and it's now a
national dirty supply chain and this
whole 80 farms in one batch of
distillate those that distillate that go
that went in those Vape pin in La it
also goes to products all over the
country there's there's you know
Missouri just had the big recall
recently last week again because they
couldn't validate the supply chain and
that's just validating what where it
came from not what's even in it you know
so it's it's nuts man it's totally
totally nuts and to me it's because we
never you know it's a real big picture
issue it's like you like Al Alec you
know I mean it's a sacred plant right
it's like you need to bring you need to
bring the spirit with it but you also
need to bring philosophers and
ethnobotanists and agtech guys and
everybody gets to get and maybe a
comedian or two you know get in there
and actually like really approach it
from a comprehensive kind of panel like
approach and we didn't do that and this
is what we do you know and and anyway um
yeah so the the T you're striking a
court on the THC flower thing for me
because i' I've had several I have like
a partner in mind it was in another
state and he was walked into a shop and
they had like just everything lined up
it like every jili Bean they had sour
they had you know OG Kush said it all
just lined up he's like what's the deal
here talk to me about it and he's like
this is legal he's like well how is it
legal and he walked him through the
process of how he buys his pounds and W
you know gets it through and puts it in
the jar and then they basically have a a
BEDA style set up where they weigh it in
front of you and sell it to you as if
you're in a dispo and I think that's the
other aspect of it and those pounds what
maybe go for 200 300
bucks right so I think that's to Dr
Mark's point on the commodity side
there's there's a huge influx of this
and there's really no one grabbing on to
where any of it came from there is no
COA on most of this stuff and if it is
it's made up right
so yeah got a question I've got a
question kind of for everybody in here
um
what percentage of the black market weed
that exists today is coming from legal
Farms do you think in my estimation it's
more than 80% of the black market weed
is backdoored product I mean because now
that everybody knows the like the deal
on grows you can't put up an illegal 100
lighter easily anymore at all everybody
knows why you're installing air
conditioners you need a [ __ ] power
upgrade everything that goes with it the
black market is small little guys mostly
little hash guys and stuff like that
maybe a few you know Greenhouse outdoor
Growers and whatever but the vast
majority especially when you're talking
about indoor flowers all backdoor legal
product I mean like the the market is
not even close like the data isn't even
close to what the actual Market looks
like you know I think there's also some
you know there's there's the Big C's as
I call them um I think everyone can fill
in the blanks is the the rest of that
word is that are really running the
larger ones but yeah I think you're
right Fletch like it's mainly smaller
guys but it's coming it's falling out
the back door because it's it's got to
go somewhere right so that's where it's
going and when and when you're talking
uh extracts and stuff it's probably you
know it's even more than flour probably
well sadly sadly from kind of my
observation you know I think some a lot
of the dirtiest material that wouldn't
pass testing California goes east you
know and I think that happens in a lot
of States um you know where they can't
pass a state established quality
standard it diverts wherever it has to
go you know and and um and you know I
think there's a lot there you know
um you cannabis is you know Mojave you
were saying it's a like dirtiest you
know the supply chain kind of I I think
I think there's it's exposing the the
potential of how dirty the Agriculture
and uh landscape is but it's so it's it
has the potential to be the dirtiest
supply chain but the regulations the
testing requirements have established it
to be cleaner than water and food in
most areas of the country you know when
there's actually Integrity in that and I
think that's something really profound
there's a lot of farmers in California
like really pridefully kind of
establishing themselves you know and
branding around how can our cannabis is
cleaner than your food you know and and
I think that's a really profound kind of
uh thing that the plant is here to also
bring in kind of exposing the you know
contradictions in our lives of what what
we put in our on our body you know but
yet we smoked cannabis cleaner than food
and water you know and and so I think
kind of uh you know the um you know it
was interesting because when before we
opened up SC labs in uh in
2007 N I was working hydro store and and
and I I saw that there were two types of
people that were serving this plant you
know kind of through the lens of this
whole conversation around IPM you know
and people would come in like week five
or six of flour you know webbed spider
mites millions of spider mites kind of
just go you know going RoR and they're
come in in a super Panic moment because
they're like I [ __ ] up I didn't do the
proper prevention game you know to
prevent this from being a thing I now
have this really big problem what can I
do you know and and uh it's like always
like dude you don't you can't really do
anything you know it's this
like exactly vacuum you know takes like
bronners and like like sponges you know
like strip every leaf off the plant that
is fan leaf or anything kind of that you
can do to kind of remove as much of the
physical kind of material where eggs and
such are you got a lot of work ahead of
you get after it you know and you know
you can't even really spray things like
organic oils because those are also
going to be concentrating into your
material you know um and and and so so
it's like there's this very Integrity
Way of like not compromising the sacred
Integrity of spirit of of the spirit of
this plant and the healing is to offer
and then you know there was this other
approach right this other approach is
like well cool like so there were people
that were like all right I'm going to go
get to work this is sounds like a lot of
work I'm gonna go do this right because
they would never even consider
compromising this this plant you know
that was going towards in so many ways
compassion and how much it was helping
heal right and like this like act of
like you know gener of Charity and
generosity that you know like those
serving would kind of like take
seriously with their relationship with
the plant know but then there's this
other type of person that was in the
peer pursuit of profit that's like dude
[ __ ] that give me the UN you know give
me the vials with the little like two m
per [ __ ] gallon thing on the side
everyone you got you know and they would
take they would just out of like their
own Panic that they are now faced with
kind of carop loss they would kind of go
above and beyond the need and they would
like take Avid abamectin floramite by F
is8 Eagle 20 right Michelob betinol they
do this like Trinity like maybe even a
little forbid forf spinos or spicin you
know and they would kind of mix them all
together and they would spray that on
their plant in week five or six of
flower right that's like akin to like I
mean the reality of like the what the
act of poisoning everybody that touches
it from their on that's akin to like
what's happening currently in
agriculture with the desiccation of all
the grain crops with [ __ ] up you know
and glyphosate to spray you know a week
before Harvest yeah to if you dudea
boards if you you mix all of it and any
of those might stay you will have those
will be resistant to that application
now I've seen it with forbid too I've
I've seen people I've been called in to
consult for several people over my time
that have said they've done this crazy
cocktail this number one mistake and
then they went back in again with them
as individual
constituents and yeah balloons are
popping up like it's nuts because it's
the truth it's it's insane that that is
a in their mind and well that's ignorant
unmindful use of these anti-life
petrochemical World War II nerve agent
type you know that's like without
awareness doing something that's
actually really like gnarly towards what
the
plants just just to wrap the point
though I'm sorry just to get back to
what archive was bringing up you know I
just wanted to kind of bring this up
because you know the I think the reality
is um see it's like you know cannabis is
re being reduced to this like commodity
supply chain for Pure pursuit of profit
capitalization that's being like
expressed through all kinds of things
with you know the legal Market
intentionally diverting 80% of what's
out there to the traditional market
right passing a contamination Buck
outward there's it's happening kind of
in in many different ways and flavor but
I think a lot of it is kind of the dirty
stuff because because the reality is is
what we've seen in California you know
it's like if you look at Prime Agland
across the state and all the green zones
that agriculture practice those are red
zones for cannabis those those are the
zones that are AG adjacent and you're
probably going to be having this ongoing
kind of like issue popping up right
oh and you know but I think but the
point I think I'm getting to there is
like you know like whenever I I think
you know and I'm not saying that's just
because I'm part of a testing laboratory
I'm a culture Anthropologist and
ethnobotanist and kind of my passion is
people and plants and kind of just
seeing through the lens of testing you
know what this plant is doing and
bringing to the world you know I think I
think those that are in Integrity with
the spirit of the plant I mean because
you know it like legalization is just a
stupid like structure you know people
have been kind of in service this plant
forever and you know go you know
medicine's been going where it needs to
go and healing the world it's is it is
is it clean and in Integrity with the
spirit of the plant or is it toxic right
like all the dirty ass cartridges like
that are could never pass a test here
going east and that's where I think
cartridges is the worst topic to on this
idea of what is moving out of legal
markets into the these other spaces and
just also flooding that market you know
but it's with a hyper toxified product
and so you know I think kind of testing
just and then just our global
perspective on
what it brings I think it brings a
barrier of Entry I think it keeps the
integrity and spirit of the plant strong
and I think those that are in Integrity
with it were always going to find their
way with the plant you know um and and
and and yeah that was a very long-winded
thought but you know I think um it's the
biggest issue and and it's like you know
it's all but it's also the biggest
competitive Advantage you know it's like
those that you know have have operated
by the code of conduct with this plant
and work and solid with their word and
Sol with how they cultivate solid with
like the relations that that you know
that you have with people you know kind
of in in in growing together you know
it's like it I think it's you know I
think a big thing of the LA Times expose
really exposed this and one of my great
prayers and hopes around this is I feel
like whenever the state of California is
now on a hyper alert about how big this
is an issue and it's going to become
just a steady it's a it's a thing now
it's finally going to become fixed you
know and I think um the real value of
clean quality bomb material and extracts
is way undervalued because it's been
driven to Extinction in price with all
this dirtiest like you know most
contaminated most bulk biomass you know
to where craft is explode or
extinguished almost you know but I think
the reality is is you know people have
been operating on the idea that cannabis
is a commodity crop like you know just
like price
to that and but the reality is it's a
scarce resource and I think the scarce
resource you know whenever there's
actual testing and transparency and
integrity in the system that scarce
resource is I think what's going to like
become yeah seems like can the DCC be
successful in policing this if the hemp
Market is outside of it right it seems
like they've got to get uh an equal
footing on the hemp Market I'm sorry to
even talk anymore too but the reality
too I think Kevin that's that's the
biggest thing like there I think the
definition of industrial hemp is is a is
a curse on the plant you know because
nobody's growing Industrial Hemp for
fiber 99% of people growing Industrial
Hemp are growing type three cannabis you
know and and without with a completely
separate world that it has to apply to
or participate in you know where it's
just around this funny game around 3% as
the definition you know there there's
it's it and HCA that
right% all game and it's and and and I
think until there's a federal kind of re
like a conversation around kind of being
cannaboid if if you know regulating type
one type two type three cannabis that's
Dr grown for drug or medicine
cultivation that's within the same Zone
actual industrial fiber for growing
fiber is you know sure that doesn't need
that that that's relaxed you know but
but anyway I totally talked way too much
and so I'll kind of just we'd love when
when you talk too much come on spit this
well that's why we that's why we started
testing in the first place is because
Growers were inherently
untrustworthy there I said it you know
uh so so many of them failed when we
started testing and um what did they do
they took it elsewhere and sold it
because nobody else was testing so the
market showed me early and often
070809 that that you know Alec as much
as I want to believe in the Kumbaya
wonderful grower they were fewer and far
between and unfortunately they still are
from time to you know even people who
are growing industrially realize they
have problems and that's even before we
were talking you know how blading
viroids you know so it's just
fascinating that the same conundrums the
same problems the same uh ethical issues
that we discussing back then such as how
do we release this information then what
is tested on humans versus what this is
still going on 15 years from now and
people are still being unethical with
their grows and it's G to be interesting
um moali and I we've been invited to go
check out the
usda's um germ plasm uh Harvest uh
they're doing some Field Days in New
York in September so we're going to go
check out they're grown over 500
different varietals uh and they're also
doing um density trials so it'll be
interesting to see uh what they're doing
because they've been collecting germ
plasm since um
2021 and yeah they're growing it out
they're growing it out at six different
um facilities around the us but the
majority is it uh they're growing up in
Upstate New York for their uh their own
trial so it's going to be interesting to
see how they hand it they actually
created and made their own
decorticator uh which is strictly per
plant so it's nothing large in
industrial but it'll be interesting to
see um what they're going to and towards
um because it's
yeah same issues nothing has has really
changed you know we've got these ethical
Growers and now that we've become legal
we've got the industrial problems you've
got as Wade was pointing out the indoor
versus outdoor versus the Green house
which um was very interesting to see as
we just saw with the emerald cup do with
its test we also saw the uh State Fair
in California finally do a person's test
as opposed to just relying on you know
Laboratory Testing so you know it's
exciting the boundaries are being pushed
and we're expanding but we're still
Contracting around these same issues and
problems especially with the you know
industrialization and our own little
10th Amendment little realities and uh
hi I'm I'm in New Finland right now I'm
way off on the uh the East Coast here so
uh hi and greetings everybody it's great
to be back
here I I think I think that that's an
important just just point is that and
and the reason that we're going to this
St trial and the reason that I'm FOC
I've been focused on the a side of
cannabis a lot lately is because I've I
spent my whole life with the plant it's
a sacred plant and it's my commity
literally my entire life right it's been
my entire Journey with one plant and but
to me that's about how we use the plant
how our bodies use the plant the complex
chemistry of the plant all the different
uses of the plant but how the plant
grows in the plant itself in terms of it
its morphology and the agronomics about
it to me that is just Agriculture and
increasingly more and more the people
who do cultivate that plant are just
people who are Growers so we have this
weird transition that we're having now
in the USDA is a perfect example of that
is that we're entering this new cannabis
agriculture phase and US custodians who
are feel very you know passionate about
you know all the
complexities we have to pass that on to
them you know because this just I mean
capitalism is a hell of a drug right
it's going to happen and and the biggest
contributors to the dirty Vape pin in
this in the country or in the in the
state probably are the big Commercial
Legal Growers honestly you know I know
plenty of guys who make extract who can
tell you that when they purchase trim
from Big commercial
Growers like they say they do the little
quick test and they go hey man this this
passes on flour it passes on trim it
doesn't pass
on on the extract right so capitalism
will be capitalism it'll do what it does
whether you're a small farmer or a big
farmer right but the plant is a plant
and it's a commodity to a lot of people
and it's now an international commodity
and all these testing standards and
stuff that we kind of established here
in California Alec you had a lot to do
with like being a Pioneer on testing
they're now being adopted by the entire
world cfu counts and stuff like that I
mean the whole world now wants all
cannabis to be irradiated
right right because they didn't see the
opportunity it's like you know or they
set the land the standard like
Australia's standard and Great Britain's
standard is 50 cfu that's it right
that's it man so it's like that's how is
their pesticide
testing because important yeah yeah
absolutely well it's it's odorous you
know and and that's the point is that
like we we have you know we have to
constantly navigate that intersection
between a and culture and our and our
community and honestly you know the way
I see it going is it is just going to be
it's a commercial crop now so we have
you know we got to think that way and at
the same time protect it and protect the
small farmer and create premium products
and stuff so we're not stuck in a weird
commodity world you know it's like $5
wine $50 wine $500 wine that's common in
the the grape growing world but cannabis
is just like a baseline that goes a
little bit over and below and that's
where there's a lot of
opportunity um but yeah know it's it's a
mess and and and ATN brought up hop and
vroid you know now lab shopping for
hopon vroid is the thing right where
it's like this kind of weird self-de
feus kind of thing where people are now
you know choosing the the most
beneficial COA for their their own needs
at that moment versus what does the
whole Community what does the entire
like a state of California need cannabis
to be I mean they could have got they
could have attacked hop late and five
years ago and eradicated it by now if
they approached it like they do other
crops you know it was a relatively
simple approach
so I wanted to raise my hand because
since Kevin's here you know I I had sent
him some samples through the years of of
hot Lane vroid and it honestly scared
the crap out of me and made me rethink
everything and you know Kevin you you
went pretty deep on it um with that
sample and then found other samples
around the country and world I believe
and
kind of went on a tear um you know do
you believe that viroids are playing a
role
in how we're getting a lot of these
products to market in terms of of
they're why they're getting you know
petrius is such a a big deal and powder
mil pow mil do and so on and so forth
you think their immune systems of these
plants are are being compromised and
therefore all these other things are
happening as a result is that
yeah there's definitely a genetic
component to this too in that there are
plants out there that seem to keep this
in the roots and it's unclear whether
they have a yield impact and that that's
what was shown in the Hop industry too
that they have plants that have marginal
5% impact on on volatiles and those that
have like 40% right so it it depending
on your cultivar it can it can it can
create a yield so if you got a plant
that's that suffers from it and it's in
the canopy um then you you you you
probably got to get rid of those but but
the I think the problem we've seen is a
lot everyone's running around testing
Roots um and you really got to test both
uh mainly because there if you do that
you'll Wipe Out the plants that keep it
in The Roots which are the ones that you
want to retain those are the ones that
are that are like tolerant of it um so
we've we've got a few lines that we've
been doing a lot of these experiments on
uh and we can see that you can bring it
completely into flower the only thing
that'll differ with the plant that's
infected versus not infected is it will
turn purple uh on on the ones that
infected but you won't you won't find it
in the canopy you only find it in the
roots um you might find it in some green
area of the canopy but anywhere the
anthos sinins are off it is undetectable
PCR um so we've been encouraging people
to like C that that particular line is
Jamaican line and it it's not
necessarily a commercial line it's it's
an outdoor um line that's a type two um
so people have been trying to cross that
into type ones to see if they can move
the trait into something that's more
relevant for like an indoor grow um but
uh there there is a risk there that if
you hyper test and you only test the
roots that you're going to weed out the
plants that you might want to breed with
so um you have to be a little bit
careful on on like how you go about
doing it there and there there was for a
while this period where everyone was
just testing Roots because it was always
it was more easy to find
there but uh that means that you're you
could be killing your moms that are
likely to survive this uh so the the
testing in the in the canopy and in The
Roots usually in veg and in flower is
the way to really figure it out um
because a lot of the plants it's
undetectable until you pop it into
flower and then and then that's then if
it's in the if it's in the leaves in the
canopy during flowering probably you're
going to have a yield issue uh and uh it
is very transmissible uh it is not just
from scissors people are finding this in
um in in the water now they've been
doing testing they can see it's in in in
fertigation systems there's some papers
suggesting hop stunt virid which is very
similar moves around in fusarium spores
um so that can go through you know
mycelium networks if you're in the same
like root Zone spores that can move it
around potentially we we have seen it in
pollen uh now interesting thing about
pollen is if we take hlate and vared
positive pollen and pop it onto these
plants that are known to keep it in The
Roots the seeds that come out of that
are clean uh like like there's like 2%
3% of them that are positive once you
germinate them but most of them come out
clean um so there there there's other
studies others have done I think in
Arizona
with plants that are more susceptible to
this and their seed ratios are much
hotter they're like 40 30 or 40% of the
seeds that they pop are end up positive
but those are plants that are known to
not suppress it in into just the roots
but they they're known for it to go into
the entire plant um there's nothing you
can do much to treat this so I don't
know that it's going to cause um a
pesticidal lab shopping issue may maybe
there's people running around trying to
get C ofas that show it's not there uh
like in a nursery setting or something
but and most people we interact with
they want the sensitivity dial so hot
that it finds you know single molecules
um which again is is something I I
caution in that if you have plants that
are keeping this suppressed at a really
late CT and PCR that that means it's
very low in copy number their immune
system may be functioning with it fine
you may have a yield loss it it it may
be a risk that it can move but um you
know there there's there's a big
difference between plants that are hot
at a CT of 20 versus plants that are hot
at a CT of 30 that's about a a 10 CTS is
is like uh what is that that's going to
be didn't we we saw that with the when
we went on the wild goose chases going
through all the moms that I had trying
to chase it and we we thought at one
point that a whole lot had been infected
and then we we kept on testing and all a
sudden it just wasn't there anymore went
away yeah you had some that are out at
past 30 and we're just like hold on
don't kill those your your plant might
just get rid of it yeah I went on it
guys I went on a bender it was yeah yeah
so and I think that's important you
quantitative test because you know
something has presence absence on this
you you're not going to have that level
of information yeah but the difference
between 20 and 30 is actually
thousandfold sorry uh so it's a
thousandfold difference in in the virid
concentration in the plant and so if
your plant's keeping it out at really
low
numbers uh I'm I'm curious about that
plant I want to breed with that plant
because it's suppressing it um as
opposed to taking this kind of you know
chop all your moms down and start over
thing because then then we lose all the
genetics up there uh and uh it it may
end up setting us back as opposed to
moving us forward yeah yeah I had a
plant Kevin that I tried I tried to
infect a plant that was just always
wouldn't test and I tried to infect it I
was actually grafting and I was like
pouring actually run off into the roots
and it still would test negative um and
then another friend that um has that
same plant just recently tested positive
I'm not sure what the count was but the
plant is healthy as can be and it's it's
it's one of those those Typhoid Mary
kind of you know really um asymptomatic
plants but what noticed is that the
slower rooting plants that have some
type of a fungal issue like every dted
plant that like really really heavy dted
flower when I rip open the crown the
crown there's always some type of a
fungal thing going on there yeah so that
relationship I'd really love to hear
more about how that hop latent and
fungal yeah when they're when they're
really hot with envir there's often
fusarium aium around so um we we try to
we try to scan for those too but the um
you know when we're when we're doing
these challenge studies um for a while
the field was just grinding up hop plate
and vroid positive plants and then
trying to you knowa you know put those
onto the leaves with some injury but
when you do that you don't know what
else you're introducing you could be
introducing the pythium and the ferium
and and so uh to solve that you really
have to isolate hop PL and viroids so we
went and actually synthesized a circular
form this thing so we're now like the
Wuhan of of uh the [ __ ] hot plon
viroid because we made the damn thing
but when you do that you can get rid of
all the other unknowns you can inject it
into plants at like you know 700 billion
copies on an injection and these plants
don't take it right so uh you're never
going to get that from a from a Mite or
an insect or or um any of these Leaf
Hoppers they're just not going to move
that much viate around but we we can
take some of these plants and really
Hammer them with direct injection of 700
billion of these molecules ules and they
don't end up getting positive uh so it's
um there are ones out there that are
tolerant to this thing if you ever and
you know they're positive in The Roots
like two weeks after flowering so it's
in there we can see it that the CT start
to creep a little bit South on us when
when it starts going into flowering but
it never ends up in the canopy so there
there's a there's a set of plants out
there that we've got to keep our eye on
that are going to get us breed us out of
this thing um and and the clear cutting
approach of any positivity any signal at
all I think it's going to be really
dangerous because we're going to end up
uh basically obliterating all of these
plants that you mentioned if you see any
one Speck of this anywhere in the plant
kill it is is like uh I I don't think
that's how this is going to work um
there's going to be some plants out
there that that that can dance around it
yeah we have we even saw like Mojave we
saw one of the Strawberry Cough plants
that I've had for like I don't know 18
19 years that that you would never think
that that would have anything if you
didn't test it so that's that's the
other part of this is it can be in the
canopy and you not know it until
flowering yep so um definitely some
instances there but we're counting on E
Fletch out there let's get it let's get
that je pool sorted we did see it with
some of your your Leaf Hoppers though
yeah that's true that was interesting so
I I I had a I had the the UK cheese
because I just kept it I just wanted to
keep studying what would happen with it
as it went through its life cycle
knowing that it had hot Laden so I stuck
it in a part of my property that is just
like super isolated and then I thought
well why don't I put like a small
Greenhouse here and put six plants in it
that aren't that I know are absolutely
clean because I saw Leaf Hoppers I was
smoking a joint one day back there and I
was just like watching these things just
go boing I was like huh wonder if those
are munching on that and then passing it
around to all these other plants around
here and so I decided to put the
greenhouse there and sure enough I sent
Kevin the samples after you know week
after week and we kept testing and all
of a sudden it was like nothing and then
boom it just hit for it um you know
there there are I mean it's you know
this isn't rocket science here but it it
was confirming and and really made me
feel you know like we needed to better
understand more about the vectors than
we thought because that's it's not just
touch feel human I smoked a cigarette or
I touched on the plan or or whatever you
know insert here it's a lot of things
that we're not paying attention to
around us in in the wild and that's as
as outdoor Growers as a lot of us are we
don't know what's in our garden until
it's far too late so it's it's um you
know it's it's just good to know ahead
of time that if you can test and use
what Kevin's developed to to help you I
know that at scale um I would have it
would have been devastating what I went
through to try to kind of go back and go
through all the moms like I did clean
everything and then isolate them and
then bring them back in and the amount
of downtime that took was nuts I mean it
just was really throwing everything out
cleaning it making sure I didn't touch
something that had it on it still oh and
that that's a good point that's
something I wanted to bring up earlier
is um you know some of these problems
we're talking about they may kind of
self-correct themselves due to the
economics of cannabis long term like a
lot of these really big Farms that
particularly like you're just saying
going through these things is too
expensive for them that's why they use
all these alternative methods you know
pesticides
Etc most of the reason those Farms still
exist to this day is because of the
export market right that's the only way
they're staying alive right because if
they had to sell all that oil in
California where they're growing it
they're out of business there's no
there's not enough consumers I mean most
it like even the Thousand light grows I
mean I know a lot of people that grow
most of the really big grows in
California indoor grows they're it's
only trap packs keeping everybody alive
right they can't sell all their flour
into the legal market and so a lot of
this just may be a you know a
self-correcting issue where essentially
the
when when all the different markets have
their own cultivation like ma places
like Massachusetts and Maryland and
Florida used to be great export markets
for from California not so I mean people
still do it but it's not like it used to
be it used to be 100% of the product
going there came from you know the
traditional market and now a big portion
of the consumers are buying from big
legal farms and and and then depending
on the state's laws you may continue to
have these issues but in places like
Washington and Oregon pretty much all
the most of the big grows are all
shutting down and it's happening in a
lot of other places too and um I think
Canada is a great example of it as well
like uh you I mean how many of those big
$300 million you know Hundred Acre
indoor grows that can be growth put up
are still
operational um they're not and that
because the market finally becomes
localized once the export exporting of
all this excess product dissipates and
um and and then now you have to to
satisfy local consumers which are much
more picky than people that don't have
access and Export markets
yeah no well
said and on that on that um
cdfa crop statistics report I mentioned
earlier there's about you know there's
10 or 15 or 20 crops that are 100%
produced in California for export to
either the rest of the country or even
considerable percentage to the world
right and like Alec mentioned all the
best Agland is in the red zone it's like
the reality is if this eventually turns
into agriculture and plants it's the
economy of Agriculture you grow the
plants that are best suited for a
particular region for because of climate
and input and infrastructure cleanliness
of the environment cleanliness of the
environment and all that and exactly and
that's that's kind of what California
was and what it will be and like I
consult with people in places where and
I say to them from the beginning I'm
like this is an opportunity for you guys
to be a part of cannabis right now but
in the future this all goes away because
for you to grow the way you do now where
it cost you $3 a gram $4 a gram to
produce it it won't happen in the future
when this is really grown as efficiently
as it can be in places like California
and can I ask you a question Mojave yeah
um with uh if if like let's let's just
say export markets don't exist right and
you're just a producer in California
what what percentage of the people
growing like uh without an export like
let's say the state was really good at
enforcing the law and making sure that
everything you grew in California had to
be sold in California how many outdoor
and Greenhouse grows would there even
need to be there there's so many indoor
lights in California there there'd be
almost nonone existing on a localized
consumer level absolutely and we grow
enough weed often we grow enough weed
for all our neighbors just in our own
backyards you know so it's it all goes
away and California is really good at
that they're actually really good at go
if you go to if you go to uh the cdfa
and you say hey look I want to grow this
crop next year they'll say hey whoa whoa
whoa whoa do you know we grow a lot of
that crop and you're probably not going
to make that much money and if you guys
grow 20% or more of that crop then the
commodity price goes down and they
protect that they protect the commodity
they protect the farmer and they even
have I believe they even have mechanisms
where they can even buy you out like hey
look you know you're going to tank the
raisin industry right now and we want to
keep the prices at a certain point and
they subsidize you they subsidize your
farm in order to keep things like don't
grow too much it's bad for everyone one
and they didn't do that with cat I mean
they just wild wild west right and and
they never really did the math the very
basic math of what is what is needed and
to me but that applies and that applies
to the whole world though because
eventually cannabis will be normalized
it will be regular it'll be everywhere
and all these markets will have to
adjust have to go like hey we did it for
a while but we don't do it anymore
because now Mexico's online or you know
California is back on interstate
commerce it's all this big transition
and it's just it's all temporary yeah
and there is this land somewhere else
that doesn't have the red zone issue Etc
I mean it's someone's going to find a
better solution to do it cheaper better
whatever and access the market better
and in a lot of cases it you know
California is really just not
competitive other than uh because you
know cost of power cost of land cost of
all these other things you know
pesticide everything else I mean I think
you know Canada's probably not the best
example because uh the out it's hard to
grow lots of outdoor relatively speaking
there but you know what percentage of
the Canadian Market uh legal Market is
outdoor and greenhous grown um flow I
bet it's I bet it's less than the indoor
whatever it
is
yeah Holland you have any idea of what
percentage in Canada it is I have no
idea but I know that if you I mean look
at Holland Holland still crushes it on
egg export they don't have the climate
for it but they said this is where we're
going to be we're going to be a
greenhouse controlled environment
agriculture country and they nailed it
so it's like you can be that but if
you're competing with a pound of flower
grown in Vermont versus a pound of
flower grown in California in 10 years
the costs are going to be very lopsided
but if you're talking about like a a
really beautifully grown bell pepper
from Holland versus a really beautifully
grown bell pepper from Canada they can
compete because they're both the same
model right because they're both but
neither neither of those business models
that they have exist without export as
well for all those bell peppers right
it's like they never have that business
if they're just selling locally and
that's kind of my point is once it once
everybody can grow indoor everywhere
legally to Supply their local market
most people are going to try to take
advantage of that for for the financial
reasons you don't have it that where's
where's all this weed supposed to go to
to third world countries that buy weed
for less than you can produce it for in
California no way it's not happening
it's going to go the other way what if
what if I mean hypothetically like what
if cannabis like is only $50 a pound for
beautiful sungrown outdoor cannabis and
then all a sudden all the indoor has to
rethink about like whoa whoa what kind
of brands are we supporting with this
high cost is that what hemp is you're
only focusing on your customer base at
that point that's it you've had you've
got your brand they like what you do
You' figured out a profit margin that
works for them and you as a as a
manufacturer and that's all you get
right Mojave it reminds me of
strawberries in the 80s late 70s early
80s how they had to figure out how to
chop California up and then export it
and figure out cold chain and do all
that there's actually a girl I met
that's got a uh he has a farm in in
Santa Barbara called farming first he he
runs it and he comes from that world and
he talked a lot about his cost per pound
to me when I first met him and I just
was blown away that he was thinking
about the minute details of of
everything that we're speaking about
along the the the supply chain and what
that cost structure was of that that
pound and how that fit within the larger
model and what she was creating and it
just literally was like a blow wind in
my my hair was flying behind I was like
wow you're you know you're you're
futurist thinking about this and he dris
and now driscolls is all over the world
they're growing in Australia they're
growing they're grow in green houses in
Japan so it's like they took that
they're like yeah we have to export this
model yeah but it's it's a really
interesting model in terms of
Agriculture because it's sort of our
dichotomy of like how do we how do we
grow enough but how do we get it to
people for so it's fresh and then how is
it clean because there strawberries are
some of the dirtiest you know in
dirtiest fruits in the world let's just
call that um and it
all for can I think we got one big issue
10% of the people smoke weed and 100% of
the people eat food the volume we need
to produce is a fraction tiny compared
to what the the a industry actually
looks like I mean we're most of most of
these business models that people think
are going to work are never going to
work in the future once the once
the the the playing field has been
leveled
worldwide yeah now I agree man I think
what you're alluding to is a very
simplistic thing that I've alluded I've
got I've landed on often which is we've
got it all wrong right and and we're
kind of um we're kind of in the middle
of of how do we go forward and how do we
do this be being mindful as we move
forward because we will get it wrong
again it's just a matter of what it's
just we have to figure out the the
things we can change and and and of what
can we change what what impact can we
make to make it better and I think
that's you know we're all throwing great
ideas around today as to do that but
it's going to take someone in policy I
think to really make sure that that
drives through so everyone follows the
same plan right everyone's got to walk
together so to speak right otherwise
it's like if one guy's over here
spraying Eagle 20 and the other guys you
know growing perfectly and then you know
they both go to market and they're
shopping to get their products and they
both get to Market somehow you know it's
a problem so that's might be alluded to
the control that every other industry
has figured out is subsidies and and and
uh um uh Growers unions right that's it
where they control their supply chain
that's it we we met we control how much
you grow what you can sell it for you
can't [ __ ] it up for all of us um that's
the only thing that that's worked for
everything else for the last hundred
years essentially without that farming
in America is done John Deer tractors in
America done all done without subsidies
and Growers unions yeah you're striking
Accord with me because I you know I come
from the you know I worked in film for a
number of years and that's you know
there's film unions for a reason because
when you call gaffer and you need
somebody to light your set they you know
you have reliable people that you can
call to come you need a reliable grower
that can come and grow um that really
makes a lot of sense to me but there is
you know there's a lot of conversation
in between that I don't know if it's as
simple as saying we need just a union
but I do think there's I like what you
said there because it we do need to we
need to have um checks and balances like
like we need to have people that if
we're going to bring in to pay them a
fee to consult or be on the team there
needs to be some sort of results or some
sort of uh you know checks and balances
Man Behind why they're there um so I
think you're yeah you're striking CES
with me on that man but I I just don't
know how we would put it
together if I could kind of weigh in
real quick um you know you know just
thinking about cannabis as like this
idea of this National and international
export you know eventually right
whenever there's been this you know
opening up of Interstate Commerce and
kind of like what's happening in Canada
Colombia and elsewhere where it's like
internationally sporting right but um
you know I
mean I think there's the the regional I
think move you're hitting on part of it
you know it's like this the Appalachian
region realities of kind of where
cannabis does grow best um and also
practices around understanding how to
care for it to the point of consumer
purchase to where you can actually
preserve the most precious aromatic
attributes that Define the quality of it
when it comes to the most sophisticated
understanding of the value of what it is
versus pure biomass right where all the
aromatics are gone right and it's
reduced then to a point of THC but it
could still be distilled it can still
you know be made into other types of
products right but you know I think kind
of the idea of like the leveling of
playing field you know I think it
happens within each state within and I
think it happens with this ongoing
dialogue and and and what we like in
each area where in I just proud of
understanding how the differentiator
really exists cuz you know like you
can't just I mean you know such a big
reason why in Oklahoma there's such a
high percentage of indoor Farms versus
outdoor Farms is because you can't grow
outdoor in C in Oklahoma because of how
toxified the environment is because of
the last you know multiple Decades of
Agriculture you know and and the amount
of erosion and the amount of heavy
metals that blown around in the wind you
couldn't even pass a test you know um
and I think that speaks for a lot of the
United States I think that speaks for a
lot of the the world where Agri culture
happens right what what you know
cannabis is helping to expose like what
you did to the land you know and so it's
like as if there is you know this actual
kind of like rallied for lobbied for
kind of you know I mean because just
speaking for California as an example
California help you know kind of
established at the time you know I me
because it's not about going so far just
like each state or each country building
on the next to make it even more and
more strict it's about testing for the
sake of public like maximizing public
health and safety you know but like not
putting such ridiculous regulations over
the top on it to where you have to
gammer radiate and sterilize all your
weed and TP zap everything so now you
are again reduced to a commodity you
know but it's like there are testing
regulations that are rallied for and
lobbied for that help kind of Ensure the
Integrity of this plant you know I think
that's one of the biggest things that
those closest to the plant have like
such a competitive Advantage you know of
knowledge and awareness around where to
find land you know so many people spent
millions of dollars you I feel like the
more hubis people come in with thinking
they're just going to make a bunch of
money is proportional to how quick they
face PL you know you see it on a
corporate level you see it on you know
kind of all these huge multi hundreds of
million dollar losses and face plants
that have happened because this isn't
just another agricultural commodity you
know and I think kind of you know
leaning into what you know I think
testing brings you know on a global
scale really helps I think solidify the
permanence of kind of those
culturally connected to this plant um in
the long term you know um because it's
like cannabis is it's it's it's like
agriculture it's a very perishable
product you know in in in 30 40 days of
it's sitting at or above 70 degrees
temperature or you know the higher you
get from there the quicker it happens
the whole incredible loss factor of all
volatile aromatics that Define the
quality you know it's like I feel like
in each state like no no individual
cultivator or manufacturer I think
that's working with the flower can you
know is even ready for interstate
commerce they haven't even in their own
State figured out how to preserve their
turps you know preserve what they have
in their possession you know it's like
keep the cabbage in the
fridge it's like what happens in two
weeks of just [ __ ] that off you know
and and just allowing kind of it to just
completely lose its value as a as a as a
vegetable you know and so I think kind
of just you know the the per you know P
the perseverance and the resilience the
plant brings I think on on the level of
working with it and how much it helps
you to like manage chaos and like figure
out and find the way and kind of learn
the lesson you know from the face PL
that happened before but um you know
there's so much like awareness there
that I don't think you know any Farm on
like big egg or big toac I mean I just
like there it's and this plant and
what's happening with it is the anthesis
of what they've done and what they what
they do and what they know you know and
so so I think kind of you know being
able to kind of you know on that idea of
like you know and once this opens up and
it's direct consumer kind of in ways
kind of like wine and the wine model I
mean it's like you know that across all
testing we've ever performed there's
like you know it's about
1.4% uh um turp total TP content in
dried flour and then all the other you
know non-tested Trace Evol volatile
aromatics that are even more volatile
than the TPS but the potential one is
most sticky chronic you can stick it to
a window is like 3 to 5 a half% like you
know and and you know it's also is there
in taking a Testing Lab a lot of testing
labs are like 9% turps every time you
know so it's about real taling the data
but but the reality is is 60 to 80% of
all turps and all volatile aromatics are
gone by the time most herb is on
dispensary shelves or retail shelves or
G you know gas station shelves with some
Delta you hhc you know but um you know
kind of like we've seen this like really
incredible thing happening in Oregon and
in California where people have figured
out like this continued cold supply
chain of custody where they like you
know have very actively Monitor and like
ensure like the rapidness to Market you
know because the average batch takes
like 30 45 days to make a dispensary
shelves that's a huge time for like loss
to set in and you're like what was 3%
now at 1% cu the average on dispensary
shelves it's like 1% or less the average
pre-roll on dispensary shelves is like
half a percent or less it's like
cardboard like you know and I think
that's a big reason why people are just
like there's a market for the juicing of
like all these butterscotch flavors and
all these other things because nobody
can everybody's like running around
there's no brand loyalty everybody's
just chasing their tails trying to buy
something that tastes or flavorful or
has any type of uniqueness to it you
know and so but the thing is is you know
we I think a lot of the Oregon farmers
you know kind of like made it through
the collapse and kind of the like now
rebuilding you know it's like they
they've they've begun to substantially
quickly be able to differentiate and you
know build brand loyalty and sell it
quicker than it's trimmed at the highest
price the market can be in the deepest
floods and California it's happening too
you know because those people they like
instead of continuously doubling down a
production double down a tur
preservation infrastructure and like you
know kind of maintaining super tight
temperature and humidity differentials
to treat the herb you know so that
there's very little to no loss you know
and they're they're like working within
the Kelvin cycle to harvest like before
sun rises and temperatures rise where
the off gassing of turf happen you know
so I think there's so much and like
ancestral awareness you know around
those working with the plant and they
give a [ __ ] you know that you know is
kind of um you know areas where in each
individual State people can really
figure out how to differentiate and how
to like bring their turps like hundreds
of percent more isn't you know than
anything else on the market you know if
you can figure that out you know I feel
like that that's what you know Oregon's
shown it's like and California it's like
it's that's how you build resilience
because at least what you have when it's
not selling as quick is super preserved
and you can always kind of be on that
highest end you know and then you know
and then kind of I think you know being
able to just like identify and work with
you know people you know because because
that's the thing it's like the the you
know now that testing Integrity is
coming back in California and
everybody's freaked out that they're
going to get caught up in recalls or uh
reputational damage scenarios because of
being associated with a [ __ ] lab you
know they're like it's shifting people's
priorities around like hey maybe if I'm
paying hundreds of thousands of dollars
a year to a lab maybe I should work with
a lab that's going to set me up for
Success you know and I think that's
really what testing and kind of you know
offers you know with you know being able
to help you know kind of Ure you don't
fail you know and then don't and don't
set up for massive fail scenarios by you
know making sure you're not introducing
hopl and viroid or aspir Gillis to
cultivation and being able to kind of
you know like identify if the land
you're working on or it before you
purchase like a cut flower Greenhouse
you know see what kind of problems are
they going to haunt you you know and and
choose like you know but I think a lot
of these things are the biggest
differentiating factors that as testing
regulations really set in you know and
and the Integrity in it is happening
because you're seeing just the the whole
like lab uh fraudulent thing it's like
it's a national top in every state and
it's huge news you know and it's I think
the more that there becomes Integrity in
that states kind of build their own
testing labs and test the testers it's
going to help really like um in the long
run help individual groups be able to
differentiate and survive in a state and
then as it goes National and even more
International like have the biggest you
know differentiating factors because
heavy metal testing in California
nobody's ever in the United States have
have had heavy metal testing in place
you know like in in Europe they have
really you know 10 years ago they put in
really strict uh heavy metal testing
requirements and the international caca
Market learned that cadmium and Cacao is
a really big issue you know and it's a
fighter remediate of cadmium and if it's
grown around areas where egg happens it
remediates out of the soil it pulls out
of the soil into the cacao and now you
have like super high levels of cacao in
the in the bean and so so International
chocolate makers had to learn this and
clean up their whole supply chain and
mix you know mountainous grown cacao
with other cacao to kind of make sure
that they don't fail just so they can
sell into the European Union you know
the only other people in the United
States that have ever figured that out
are cannabis farmers in California you
know it's like
because because heavy metal testing has
been implemented nothing in the United
States has been that way so I mean
that's I think a huge different you know
the ability to survive in a export
Market I think in areas where testing
and public health and safety is going to
be a thing
I think is going to be ultimately the
biggest thing that helps the culture and
those like that give a [ __ ] about the
plant survive and it's going to keep out
the cooks you know and the these like
you know hubristic dudes that are just
face planning left and
right Alec I want to go back to
something that you had said earlier you
know you were talking about um closed
loop extraction and
concentrating so like you you could you
could run a clean test on flower
material that that would look clean
would pass but then when you extract
that material you would actually see now
things failing because you're you're
concentrating you know the oily cuticle
off the plant so like like I'm looking
at some data here
so it it's I mean and and you're
probably more aware of this than anyone
else on this panel is that the level of
sophistication of our analytical
toolbox has in inreased exponentially in
like the last 10 to 15 years right like
like we we can see picograms now we
could see things that you know again I I
used to use the analogy of taking a lint
brush to a New York City sidewalk we're
gonna find everything like you're you're
gonna you you can't necessarily put the
spec at zero PPM right because you know
beond PPM there's there's what that's
ppb and then you go down to parts per
trillion but so the the the thing I
wanted to show you I wanted to pull up
some recent data for my of of of mine so
we're we're able to make we're able to
make a check this out dude because even
like a handful of years ago on hash
church we were talking about this and we
were still in like the low 90s but we
could routinely produce from clean
flowers that test clean for heavy metals
that test clean for pesticides we can
routinely produce a live resin where the
THC Total is is in the high 770s total
cannabinoids is about
91% total tpin in these live resin
sauces are like seven and a half per.
when you add up these percentages man
there ain't a whole lot left man that's
like like on hash Church like I think we
were on maybe like about four or five
years ago right Mark and we were talking
about you know what is that last little
bit like how can we find out like and
and you know Ian Oswald and those guys
down at abstracts basically now teasing
out all these volatile sulfur components
so if I add volatile sulfur components
on my live resin that I'm testing 99 99
plus so when I just take the tpes alone
add that to the cannabinoids and this is
from a third- party lab I'm at like 99
plus percentage so I've
characterized
99% of what's in my jar to me I mean
that's just right from where we were
just even like four five years ago C
extraction not live resin kind of you
yeah there's been that's [ __ ] huge
like there there's like no big unknown
in there I mean
again what what's that no sorry well
because I mean the if you look at the
anatomy of a bud you know primarily
canabo within the your glandular troms
and resin right primarily cannaboids
followed by the primary and secondary
TPS right there which really five to
nine of them really constitute a
majority of what is there you know that
could be in flour up to 3 to 5 and a
half% in life resin like yeah up to like
7 to % you know kind of from what we've
seen you know and like when you start
getting that all together and there's
this like remaining percentage which you
know it's it's not a lot but you know
that three plus percent whatever more
less you know kind of based on
extraction process based on Purity based
on kind of you know live reson versus
not you know there is all these other
yeah volatile Trace aromatics right that
really Define kind of so much of the
flavor and Aroma aspects right um flavor
Bas basically what the point I'm trying
to make here is that yeah I mean to me
we're real close to describing 100% of
everything that's in the jar like
there's no like Mystery Oil or weird
[ __ ] from like 10 years ago parts per
100 but you're looking at Parts some
some of these pesticides are down in
parts per thousand you know another
decimal place over or parts per million
which is even further right so we're
getting close though right Kevin I mean
we're it seems like again so what I'm
trying to what I'm trying to illustrate
which I don't think I'm doing a good job
at describing better quantitating yeah
not only has there been a a increase in
the level of precision and accuracy of
what we can test for in cannabis
products including down to the ppb and
EPT levels but extraction has really
become oh yeah you know really I think
has come a long way I mean to where
black oil crud
to open blasting with Mystery Oil and
God knows what else was in that crap I
remember when indur used to be on
remember Marcus when indur would would
come on hash church and we would try to
talk to him about testing and he was
always kind of really guarded because he
thought that his process was somehow
unique when really passing a hydrocarbon
solvent over you know cannabis and
extracting the oal resin wow that's
pretty pretty much like making drip
coffee I mean there's not's not L I
thought the one thing he did that was
novel was dimple the inside of his
reactor to create cavitation and
eliminate channeling that impressed
me yeah I guess I was never able to see
like a set of data that showed the
impact that that had either in
productivity or resin quality but from
what I remember because I used to always
have conversations about him about
testing and that's when this whole
Mystery Oil thing was coming into play
and it was always thought of that well
if you're multiply distilling your
solvent your constantly taking just the
vles off but could there be in your in
your early fractions if you don't do
multiple distillations could there be
that Mystery Oil the crap from the
lubrication of the couplings you know
when they're handling hydrocarbon
solvents and other [ __ ] you remember
that stuff Alec we were talking about
that years ago on hash church trying to
figure out like what that last little
few percent of some
aleric Florine polymer [ __ ] that
comes along with the ride and these
gases well on on the on the aromatic
side of things which is really cool
because Yeah you mentioned abstracts
definitely epic did some very pioneering
research helping to kind of really just
show kind of the some of these Realties
right which are you know because in the
aromatics you know the majority of
what's there are the primary and
secondary tpin that very well probably
have the most biologically active
effects you know Entourage canono stuff
but then there's all these other
part per billion part per TR you know
trillion part per you know thousand type
level compounds that are there in tiny
fraction the level of turpins but you
know clearly have substantial effects on
adding Aroma or flavor to you know bring
out the uniqueness of various aspects of
cannabis and and uh you know identifying
you know helping you know like the idea
of thols right the sufar compounds that
really bring the gas aspect you know
which seem to be very vola right like um
you know relative to TPS right and then
there's like these other types of
compounds that are the what you know
they describe is the Tropicana sulfur
compounds right and uh you know that I
wanted to bring up a story about the
emerald cup with that I thought was
really fascinating because we we
extended this year you know because you
know over the last few years we've been
we'll test chemotype canab turps um you
know of all the entrance you know help
to sort and by Aroma and flavor right
and this way um grouping like with like
right so Jack and Hayes Jack and Hayes
tropical floral tropical floral aamine
right gas desserts sweet and dream types
exotic right so we've we had that right
um you know but it was really
interesting because over last couple
years we started to see this really
fascinating Trend right because
historically Tangi right smell of Tangi
forbidden fruit uh Calo Agent Orange
right it's miring really really high
miring low every other tpping right um
very distinct smell right and it's
actually it's not a turp right it's trop
these tropican sulfur type compounds
that um that abstracts is describing you
know but what's actually interesting
about those is you know and this is just
a pure observation from my nose and just
smell of cannabis over the years I don't
think it's that volatile I think it
actually sticks I think it's one of the
ones that's like really heavy and it
sticks around like as all the atps go
away right it's super present smell um
across you you know these these these uh
these different profiles but the point I
wanted to make was you know so
historically right there's all these
Tangi forbidden fruit um you know Calo
and orange types that they were always
in the sweet and dream category but over
the last couple years in the emerald cup
we started observationally anecdotally
through our nose and through the judge's
nose be we started to see the um this
smell popping up in other primary
turpine categories so we'd see it
popping up in the dessert category over
the last couple years the dessert
category carry off Ling loning like
which is a lot of the gelato sedding
cakes Sunday driver type strains so
those um like all of a sudden there's
Mimosa right there's um um tropican uh
there's there's Sangria right and those
are and those are strains that wash
really well in hash making and that's
and those are The Carling lening strains
and that smell started showing up there
but then also like this year like we we
even saw
um in the Emeral cup data we even saw
like things like like is if you've ever
smelled um Clementine right or orange
creamsicle which just one one of the
awards in the emerald cup of farms
essencia um and it's h it it's got that
Tangy like citrus smell but it's in the
terpinolene category right like
Clementine there's like fenos that like
straddle the edge of being one of the
other you know but it's again the shared
kind of um aromatic that's a non- turp
and so this year in the Amal cup we
actually you know kind of where science
you know because a lot of these
compounds too like in flour like in
extract sure you might be able to start
testing them but in flour they're like
undetectable you know by most even most
sensitive instrumentation you know and
and even and for what it's worth a lot
of these aromatics they don't even make
it through Harvest because people are
harvesting in the middle of the day in
the hottest times outside of the Kelvin
cycle where the off gassing of the
aromatics happen in the early part of
the day and so so I think kind of you
know and and also how people dry you
know a lot of these really precious
aromatics don't make it through I think
some of them like the tangin notes they
make it through past when the turbines
go but um but my point is is uh this
year in the emerald cup you know
everything T sorted they gets anonymized
presented to the judges within its own
category um so like red stickers the
penene Jack and hay types um but you but
this year because we you know we noticed
that that smell of Tangi like that that
Citrus hint um it was it was it was
probably there was probably as many of
that smell entered as there were at like
OG and gas in the whole competition and
what was so funny was everybody was
entering it thinking it was exotic they
were entering it into what they were
calling the Exotic you know because we
get you know Amal cup opens for people
to be able to kind of uh put what they
think category it should be in and
everybody was entering Tangi and stuff
as and Mimosa as exotic and it you know
and so it turned out to be like
as much or more as the whole gas
category so so basically all the judges
after the anonymized sort presention
present of the data in our judges kits
when everybody was going through you
know all the judges were empowered to
take you know to with their nose you
know single out any that smelled citrusy
note it and single out any that smelled
truly exotic to them and and
market and um and and so yeah so we
created its own tarpine class you that
we're going to be presenting through the
data like that was you know the judge
you know the
um consensus of the data of like the
judge's picks of the smell you know kind
of correlating and those kind of being
going into their own category and um and
then judged within that category and
because because basically there was a
tremendous amount of the entries that
were in the Mir scene category there's a
tremendous amount of those entries that
were in the Kling line dessert category
and there was a couple that were in the
turpening category and so so yeah but
take take a look to to Mark's Point here
on the percentages um so the the
abstract folks presented a canat a
couple years now and it's what's really
cool about data is how low concentration
these things are and how pungent they
are right there this is H the vsc3 in
the the bosio
gelato which is the one that's got the
highest of factory score is micrograms
per Mig uh and that's so micrograms per
Mig that's about one in a thousand
micrograms are 10us 6 are 10us 3rr so
that's a 10 Theus um three effect there
and they're talking about 10us 2 of that
so that's like one part per 100,000
creating uh one of the highest all
Factory scores so just fascin these
sulfur compounds are really really
potent terms of the a human's nose to
pick them up like like orders of
magnitude like right two orders of
magnitude right several yeah I mean I
the turps are in the percentages which
are parts per 100 this we're talking
thousands like a thousand times
more uh more potent yeah no and that's
the beauty of the human nose and the old
fact yeah fact spectoscopy yeah it's the
most sensitive Mass spectrometer on the
planet you know and that's what's really
cool about kind of the thing the themo
cup is like to you know be able to you
know as science is kind of helping to
Define some of these things be able to
take and push the system based on our
own nose and ability to kind of sort
things these categories but that's
what's really fascinating too to me
Kevin and and uh and Dr Mark you know is
just how um some of these super Trace
part per billion whatever level
compounds that are there like in this
sulfur world you know there's the gas
which to me like from own anecdotes and
just data what I've seen the gas note
goes away Way quicker than the turps do
right as opposed to the tangin note
which observationally stays way longer
as the turps go away so I think type of
correlation there could could could
couldn't there be kind of like a like I
I always when I think about Turpin and
the odor of cannabis I always think of a
symphony right so if you think like
there could be a couple violins and
there could be you know a couple violas
and really I mean like if if you think
about it like so yeah you have the
lenine right which is not loning right
so so and the interesting thing about
venine venine if you open a bottle of it
smells just like Valencia oranges but
when you when you take so valencene is a
sesquiterpenoid and or it's a
sesquiterpene actually and when it
oxidizes up to the sesquiterpenoid
none it changes it to
grapefruit so it's so
[ __ ] cool thinking that again venine
can basically convert to a more
grapefruit note just on oxidation and
that might be happening say like in the
Cure of the flour so maybe like Valentin
is kind of like a a pre turpenoid
precursor that ultimately in the Cure
cures up to nud katone which again is
going to give a more grapefruit kind of
flavor and if I could just give a quick
shout out to uh
skunkman Sam and Rob Clark on their Roma
story here
um we always wanted to Define what skunk
was like for a long time like what does
the skunk smell because we knew it
wasn't a turp um and Rob and I wrote an
article for cannabis business times in
2018 where we pointed out that we
couldn't say it was in cannabis because
we don't have a lab and we didn't do any
of that but we found the literature in
hops that that THS were in Hops and the
junky odor in beer that goes off is a
thle so we we we we put that out there
but but one of the points that was
interesting is it was also a thle that
was being created through photo
decomposition so it was in it was in The
Hop it's in the Hops we know that it's
in the wart it's in the Brew but in
green beer green bottled beer like hinin
and beex and all these German Imports
that gets photo decomposition and that
creates even a more files when you crack
that top and you smell that skunky Aroma
that's that's photo decomposition so I
guess to Alex's point is that it is
actually possibly not only is it in
there but it's also continuing to be
created in the plant itself in the Cure
over time I don't know but that was just
an interesting and the way the where I
got that is when I moved to Amsterdam in
93 and the first time I opened up a
brown bottle Heineken and took a drink I
was like this isn't hinin this a totally
different beer and then I found out that
all hinin that goes export to the US
goes in a green bottle because it's a
thing and all hinin domestically goes
into a brown bottle because brown
bottles block out the light that causes
that skunky odor and so the the hop
world had studied that and researched it
knew all about it and it was kind of
like a little inside joke about the
skunkin in in beer and how it was a
green bottle thing um so anyway I I
think that's just that's interesting
it's it's there's the not nose and it's
just constantly changing is also the
problem right all I was going to point
out is the structure of these things um
some of you may be familiar with these
look like the precursors to the turpine
pathway that are getting
dilated yeah so there's a I I don't know
how you know maybe it's enatic maybe
it's maybe it's light but it's uh it's
definitely uh an interesting whole new
arena in the Cannabis
field no they're prenol sulfides and so
obviously isoprene is the is the um is
the starting material for that Kevin it
it might it might be um right yeah it
might be I right right a with a
phosphate on there but um yeah it's
super interesting to think about like
where does that sulfur come from because
biological sulfur is something that is a
you know atom of economy I mean mother
nature uses sulfur all the time right
it's in cysteine uh methionine
right and so I was thinking like because
if you look at one of those compounds if
you could pull up those structures again
Kevin one of those compounds is actually
a um it's got a C
C5 tho in it and it's actually optically
active uh okay now not it it was the
previous set of structures one of those
structures is actually optically active
and it could basically be again some
kind of cysteine or homosysteine kind of
pathway
uh yeah no those aren't the ones neither
might be from from their more recent
work okay yeah um but yeah that so again
just going back to the overall theme
though is that is that between
extraction and between analysis of
extracted product we're getting pretty
damn close right I mean we're getting
able to be able to measure you know
between the lines of like what are in
these products and that's where it's
like I don't know um Alec if you
participated with Josh schwier or that
group down there that they've tagged to
basically help them in this lawsuit
that's happening in California where um
I forget what the name of the
dispensaries but there's a group of
dispensaries down south that are
basically have a class action lawsuit
against hemp producers for bringing you
know hemp derived THC and thca products
into the state of California they're
claiming of you know losing market share
and just you know not proper testing you
know residual solvents you know THC
isomers that are in there I mean yeah so
in in one way in one way testing is
really kind of like the bad news in the
industry right it's the bad news it's
that there's unworthy you know basically
producers that are producing all kinds
of [ __ ] because people want to get
[ __ ] high and I don't ever think it
was the intention of the United States
Congress to sign the farm bill I believe
they were snookered on fiber and seeds
and oil they were like you said Alec you
hit the nail on the head they were not
thinking about drug variety
can cannaboids and they didn't even
contemplate how to bring CBD to Market
because CBD is the active ingredient of
epidex which is an FDA approved drug so
it's just lowkey legalized cannabis and
created two totally different regulating
platforms you know which is really
[ __ ] and needs to be buttoned up you
know but the you know I think it's it's
it's just really interesting to see how
clo how like to your extraction point
just how much kind of it it went from I
feel like the correlation of the nail
and the the the little buckets you know
kind of uh and how much you see the
sharp like increase in quality you know
from like the black hash oil knife hits
on stoves to kind of the live resin or
live rosin and you know getting to you
know the most preserved essence of the
plant you know and how volatile a lot of
these compounds are you know and um and
and you know I I have a lot of questions
around kind of you know the idea of like
effect you know and how Entourage and
you know kind of the uniqueness of
different highs comes about you know how
much Tarpin play a role and how much
these very Trace part per billion part
per trillion level flavorant or aromatic
agents kind of play a role but either
way it's like when they're gone you know
it's like the clo the further out the
canaba turp ratio goes you know kind of
you know whenever you when it's most
chronic and you got 3% turps and you got
15% flour THC or 20% or 25% or 30% you
know it's like a 10 to1 or closer canab
turp ratio you know the presence
influence effect is substantial the the
Pres obervation of these aromatics and
all these other Trace volatiles you know
all kind of are you know in their most
present form you know but when that is
compromised and goes to 100 to one canab
turp ratio like most of what is on the
dispensary shelves you know in retail
markets especially retail markets where
people have to gamut a radiate and zap
their turps just to be able to sell it
you know it's like that's herbal
distillate that's like there's no you
know there's no turps there's no
anything it's might as well you know I
mean so so I think uh you know kind of
ended start bunch of things I'm bringing
up but like uh I I think ultimately um
yeah no I totally just got lost in the
sauce there um but overall um yeah I
think I think effort for folks to close
that the this hemp loophole I mean
what's the uh I think that's the biggest
thing we need to do like because I feel
like the word Industrial Hemp is such a
misused word and and I think until we
get to the Crux of that you know then
we're not going to be able to Def ior
toine you know kind of the because right
now you have like hundreds hundreds of
liters call
CBD but sorry just call them CBD [ __ ]
that's all they are is CBD whes it's
it's no longer oil I will say this about
it we haded oil into the market cutting
all the THC in the market and like bring
it's just destroying the whole thing and
go ahead Marcus sorry uh just going to
say about the hemp Industrial Hemp thing
I mean we got that going here it must
have been 94 or 95 in Canada I think
commercial laws changed in 98 which is
when you saw like um um the companies
come out and start selling the dehaul
seed so it was really always a grain
play in Canada we never did like CBD
cultivars to try and but then again we
never had the market that you guys had I
mean I remember when CBD isolate started
getting produced in Colorado and my
buddy was selling it for like $60,000 a
kilo I think it's like $600 a kilo now
which speaks 300 okay so this speaks oh
look he's got the balloons this speaks
to what Mojave was saying earlier in
regards to um you know having a
regulatory body that's sort of says like
hey you know and and uh Fletch as well
was also speaking to this about saying
Hey listen we control it we tell people
how much they can grow and the price
that they can sell it at and to kind of
try and not implode the entire thing
definitely saw that in the US CBD um um
industry and then I guess part of that
implosion was also the Saving Grace for
them to convert and to create these
other canabo that they can then sell at
gas stations where people can get high
of which is what this whole
conversation's been about and I do
appreciate it it's been really good I
just wonder you know where it's going in
a sense I also would would would
recognize the fact that we are the
anomaly like we are the small percentage
like most people probably don't care if
they're pre-rolled joints or W have
Botanical turps and 20 different types
of pesticides they're smoking
radioactive cigarettes and actively
enjoying alcohol as their favorite
personal drug of choice maybe they're on
like a bunch of pharmaceuticals maybe
they're on their ninth booster I don't
know I'm not judging um we all have to
make our choices but um it is just a
strange thing to think I always I always
I always hear Debbie goldsbury you know
from years ago when when we were going
off about how it's got to be the best
and we got to have the best turps and
the this and the that and she's like
she's like guys I love your passion but
I'm telling you like in 30 years of
doing this people don't give a [ __ ]
about anything other than price and THC
percentage no so it leads me oh go go
ahead sorry I was just gonna say that's
the role of the regulator to kind of
Ensure it's not poisoned you know it's
like sure if somebody wants it like
there's the whole Jewel generation of
kids that are just puffing on those like
those flavor sticks you know that want
some butterscotch distillate sure that's
cool as long as it's not poisoned you
know it's like when you look at like you
know a lot of those botanically D turps
they have like huge amounts of benzene
in there anything with a cherry flavor
anything with a cherry like it's like I
don't know what it is but
man I would imagine almost all of those
those Botanical turps that I've ever
touched have serious problems with all
their
and a big reason yeah the because all
the pesticides super concentrate not
only in the extract but primarily in the
essential oils you know so it's
froms Colin everybody you're all experts
here so I mean has anybody come across
anybody who's been able to come even
close to replicating what the plant can
actually
do well here's another perspective I
would go as far to say even the plant
itself has problems with toxicology when
we extract it by itself and by Design
there's certain constituents and certain
levels that we shouldn't be ingesting
you know and that's that's another
problem right and and in the hemp world
for some reason that happens often um
and it's not so often in type one but
there's a lot of turpine extracted
varietals that are meant for that that
are being sold at scale that do have tox
problems with them so I want to just
call that out that I've learned over my
time that it is on both sides and and we
all have to just be really open about
that the path forward is about
recognizing hey maybe we shouldn't grow
super super Haze and extract it for TPS
because it has this type of you know
turpine in it that we can't have at 3%
or more and it's causing you know cell
damage at this rate and therefore from a
talk perspective it's it's unfit for for
consumption right so I
think yeah you you're exactly right on
the toxicology certain things being at
certain concentrations it like all of a
sudden becomes really gnarly but I think
I mean but if you grow cannabis hemp
type three cannabis on clean land with
clean water clean inputs it's it's clean
the turps are clean everything's clean
you know and so I think you know again
it's like I think cannabis has the the
potential to flip agriculture in the
long run you know in this becoming like
a a bought into to like reality and
issue and and you know seen kind of as
from the cultural side of thing I mean
because you can't just flip a Thousand
Acre Mega Farm you know you can't just
flip a a a a greenhouse that's been kind
of cut flowers for the last 10 years
because guess what you're inheriting so
many of the problems of the past and so
I think you know again it's like if
there can be this buttoned up loophole
between hemp what's called hemp and
cannabis I think it's kind it's the
greatest thing that could ever come for
anybody closest the plant that's in
Integrity with the plant and I think in
the long run those that are in Integrity
with the plant are going to succeed you
know and those that are out of Integrity
with the plant are might be making some
like short-term gain and profit but are
going to have a long-term not successful
path with the plant and I think whatever
path it takes it'll correct itself as
well I think that's important is that
that every this is all just transition
so like whether whether it goes back to
just being state-based license systems
and we have all these little Islands or
whether it goes the farm bill path and
they change the ruling on early Harvest
window or whether they all the things
that they're going to do we know it's
going to go back and forth but it will
correct itself and my hope my hope is
that in this all this turmoil we're
we're forced to pick a path which seems
like what's happening right now because
there's been a a a a sea change in terms
of you know Congressional support
there's it's now every region has
cannabis in it everyone wants the money
everybody wants it to go for it
everybody knows somebody body who's in
the business or uses it medically or you
know it's like there's no anyway we're
past that so now it's just like we're
all just waiting like you guys tell us
which path to take and that's why I
thought this guy this grower who's doing
the three different angles was a really
interesting conversation was like dude
and doing it well and you know like hey
like I don't know which way it's going
to go but I got my I got my over here
and I got it over here and over here and
it either way I'm pivot like we've all
pivoted many times and medical was a
pivot we all know medical was a pivot we
did that you know we wanted medical to
happen but really we're just all trying
to legalize cannabis hip laws in Canada
were a pivot everything is a pivot we're
all just trying to legalize Big C
cannabis genus cannabis so to me
whichever way we get there you know
eventually it'll become some Australia
is a perfect example Australia started
out Total Medical like regulated
federally regulated pharmaceutical thing
all cannabis cultivars had to be called
like a leave and refresh and now they're
just now every California brand all the
cultivars they want chronic they want
fire they want all the they want it just
the way everybody does even though they
call it Medical but guess what in
Australia now 4% of the population holds
a medical
C I'd like to know I'd like to know what
the butt is that Fletch held up uh just
a few minutes ago because that looked
pretty [ __ ]
delicious that is uh it's B basically
Oishi which is Japanese for
delicious no [ __ ] it's Skittles cross a
flavor
pack it's like breing line I think
Colin's probably seen that one when I
was back uh in New York yeah dude the
the stuff that you showed me and we
smoked on together like man I gotta get
some packs of that for sure definitely r
that stuff that stuff's amazing it just
lingered perfectly guys it was like
every everyone had a different
slightly different profile but ended up
the same place where it just lingered
and just taste just flavor cating so I
have a question for you Fletch why why
is it that you grow uh and breed such
incredible quality cannabis what what
what are you doing differently is it
your old factory is it your ability to
perceive volatile organic compounds is
it something you're doing in the grow is
it that you have access to incredible
starter genetics I I because I just I've
always known you've had great genetics
but but it's it seems to be even like an
another level like it's just like you're
just so focused on the exceptional what
how
why well I don't know if you guys have
seen how many joints I've already rolled
and
smoked so I think that helps contribute
to it and then man my passion is just I
like hunting through
populations and like giving all the
different hybrids the opportunity to
um Express whatever you're looking for I
mean I you know with breeding for me
it's like everybody always thinks oh I'm
going to cross this with this and I'm
going to get exactly what I imagined and
for me I'm more just shotgun approach to
see what hits and um I think it's just
enjoying that and uh that being exciting
that that just it doesn't matter what
you even start with necessarily you're
going to continue to improve what you
have through that process as long as you
continue to you know reinvest in that
process as what it is because it's just
expensive to to have bad runs or
whatever it is um or where you pick the
wrong parent this time and you need to
go back and rework a line or whatever it
is and um just enjoying that process and
then and then part of it was just uh
always knowing right when I started
growing at least just having collected a
really wide range of like the American
clone only genetics and making sure that
I that I knew what I had and why I had
it and at that time I only focused on
Flavor you know and smell but really
things that only transferred to flavor
or it had an exceptional smell that I
wanted to make into a good flavor and uh
that's you know continually been the
process yeah but the other thing that I
would add is that your [ __ ] produces
full melt bubble and that's also not
something that always translates there's
tons of cultivars out there that are
delicious and wonderful and I I love
love them as you know a vapor off of the
flower but when I try to turn them into
hash it's just the yields aren't there
or if the yields are there it's just not
translating the same way that what I
perceived in the flower would be as a
concentrate out of the flower so I I
think that that's sort of an you know
they're really full melt genetics like
full melt certified genetics a lot of
your genetics produce when grown
properly obviously just beautiful hash I
even I think a lot of that's just the
selection process too right and using
multiple or or even having lines made
from multiple different females and and
just making more selections and then
lots of people um grow my seeds out and
find great selections too and it's it's
awesome having you know high-end Growers
grow what we make and and uh and get
them to perform really well I was going
to comment on even the the secondary
line that you released that were just
like stuff didn't really test all that
much like we got a doc times original
diesel on dude we s we found some four
heaters in there and there was only six
seeds in the pack I think yeah well I
can prob take so much credit I mean the
original diesel was you know just making
sure I have the original legitimate
clone and held it for 20 years and then
Crossing it with a good selection I mean
and it you know it wasn't even the Dosey
18 wasn't necessarily like my favorite
Dosey dough plant for my flavor this or
that it was just the most resist um you
know highest hash yielding um yeah you
know type from that original like 30
seeds I popped it it's not even like it
was a big big hunt or anything it was
just the continual process of just
picking something better every time and
moving forward is that's the name of the
game to me it's not every like everybody
thinks that oh I'm just going to back
cross and it's like all you're doing is
doubling up tripling up
on the original plant that you were
trying to improve by going back to the
plant that has all the problems and so
to me it's it's about making the
selections and then moving moving
forward with the with those and trying
to increase the reoccurrence of the
trace that you do
want no that's R cool I think skunkman
Sam just popped into the
room howdy everybody yeah I'm a day late
in a dollar short again
but we're still here dude like three
hours later we're still here I know I
was really surprised to see you still
here and you came in right when Fletch
was talking about like selection and
breeding so I thought that that was very
uh
cool well you know me I always like to
grow out as many as I can a 100 is
nothing to me uh I've done grow out
where I did SPO hunting from 20,000
Jesus Christ yeah I've never had the the
privilege I go through about a thousand
to 2,000 a year indoor so yeah no it was
20,000 skunk number ones half male half
female so I selected the 10 best boys
and the 10 best
girls well and those have spawned
probably half of the best hash making
varieties in the last 40
years yeah congratulations skunkman Sam
on the emerald cup recognition and award
too be absolutely yeah dude for real
hoping to be uh to be able to see you
there well I'm I'm so worthy I
guess why don't you mention what his
award was there
Alec I was I was trying to remember off
the top of my head I think it was
Lifetime Achievement kind of uh no no
it's it was in into into the beers Hall
of Fame there we go there we go that's
what it was yeah thank you for your
service to humanity and the flavor of
the
ganja well I I think the biggest thing
that I did to be honest was I uh sold
seeds incredibly
cheap that's why they're that's why
those genetics are everywhere that's
absolutely
true it's I mean it's it's even if we
don't know it's in something it's a high
probability that it potentially is in
there
somewhere well between Haze and skunk
was the two that was used the most the
California Orange and deran poison were
also used really a lot and I had some
early tie that was used really a lot I
had a variety called bunk which was Tai
ha skunk which was really really
popular Foundation of most of what's out
there right I use that to read my lemon
cake literally it's the backbone of it I
selected a lemon leaner and just hit
that back to another skunk
NL I I I tried really hard to uh to get
varieties that were extremely high in
tpin and really loud you know
that's yeah that's what I what I
personally enjoy and that's what
I I also like dry sify better than water
house because it's kept a little bit
more of the tpin and some varieties are
very sensitive to water other ones just
ignore it yeah tur water from the after
yeah but you don't want turp water what
you want is you want TPS in the the
resins yes sir I got I've got a question
this the perfect group to ask in terms
of uh why certain uh um resin heads wash
and some don't just because you brought
it up too and I think this is the
perfect group to ask is th this is how I
my assumption I think we've all like
made plenty of rosin BHO
Etc some of that some of those resins
even if you put them in a freezer they
won't harden up right like they just
there's too too much tping sauce I think
there's too much tpping in them is
and so if it won't if it won't freeze
yeah if it won't freeze at let's say you
know uh 32 degrees or even a freezer
that's seven or negative seven or
whatever then and and the hash is
basically just a representation of the
triome
heads ratio of TH or canono to to other
compounds essentially if it's too turpy
like like you just said skunkman Sam it
won't freeze 32 therefore you can't wash
it they'll their heads will just burst
in the
water no I I don't think that they burst
as much as some of them seem to be the
turps are water soluble from the heads
like yeah you could tell really easy if
the water is turpy then you know there
were varieties that we did like
shitol uh water has and the water would
didn't smell very strong at all and uh
most of the flavors and The Taste was
the same whether you dry sied or water
hash it and uh yeah so well if if the
tur beans are water soluble the tur
beans were like some of them inside the
head right so then it it's not burst but
it's it's leaked it's it's inard let's
put it that way and then and then now
that it's ruptured you can't catch the
the triome head anymore because it's you
know that's one of the reasons I like
dry sift and when I would make dry sift
I would cheer it for three or four
months so it was more like a little
raisin than a fresh head because the
Fresh Heads smear it easy they uh you
know when you're trying to dry SI it
uh you don't want it smearing you want
it you know dry SI and and it's very
strain dependent there are varieties
like in fact one of the best dry sift
varieties I ever had which this was the
pictures
uh uh Marcus that you remember um shumy
420 posted those full melt photos on
your Forum back in the day that came
from me um yes anyways the the that was
a skunk number one times White Rhino
right just you
know you know skunk number one is one of
my favorite for dry safety that's that
was the most incredible
I mean I I popped those seeds in
2004 probably so um you know that was I
mean it
was I've always seen if you cured that
weed was it uh uh easier to dry shift it
would literally start dry sifting like
with if I just dried if you know 10day
hang let the room get to like 40%
humidity and it would just rain Keef
when you trim
it yeah we used to always trim on top of
uh silk screen yeah that's right always
have done too yeah yeah we've done I
read all your guys books I I took it all
to into
practice hey there's know zamir punjob
did a thing I think at actually at
canmed and it's a m micros microscopy or
whatever um on cannabis heads on
tricomes and he shows some ripe heads
and the secreting and actually coating
the outer layer and it's kind of far out
because it's not burst at all it's a
fully intact head but just it's slowly
oozing out and it's covering and it's
always one thing I've always wondered
like what makes fresh cannabis sticky
you know is like how does that head's so
sticky when the chemistry hasn't
happened until it ruptures but the
reality is it's happening on a ripe head
on the inside and on the outside and
that has a lot to do with you know is it
is it you going through through the wack
shell or is it
coming you know you'll have to I don't
want to say because I have such a poor
memory but check it out it's it's it's
really good image and I I actually sat
in it I didn't even see it when I sat in
on the conference but he's basically
showing fully intact ripe heads that are
slowly oozing out and coating the
outside surface cuticle but it's still
rip and the other the other source
that's really interesting right now is
this that photographer um Zoom Gardens
and he's peeling he's peeling the
cuticle layer off of the gland head and
it's far out because sometimes it stays
intact as the layer comes off and you
know because all the the the gland is
this hard structure and so it's it's not
as much of a water balloon as people
assume that you just poke it and it
oozes out sometimes it oozes out very
slowly and gradually sometimes it's
R ruptured but still
so like that freezing and that dry sing
still works to get it through I think
that's all just the turine ratio that's
left like how much and the in the
temperature that you're at you know if
it's like super turpy it'll it'll be
gelatinous and if it's like a really low
turpine you know Turing I mean just all
of those types of compounds uh
particularly in my imagination it' be
like alcohol type compounds Just Like
Liquor doesn't freeze in your freezer
right so THC it it's hard at like 60 or
70 degrees and the more TPS you add the
lower the freezing point gets you I
think goes down to varietal and what's
there if you're saying like of what that
100% of what class of chemical
constituents are there let's say it's
highpine or high beta chylene or what
whatever that might be I think that
spread what you're talking about
Fletcher I think it's sometimes inside
of that that wax cuticle and and
sometimes it's some of the constituents
are are actually on the outside so
you're you're but if it's on the outside
and it washes but the head still stays
intact we'll get half from it right
there's certain strains you justt wash
it and there's literally nothing in
backing forward right yeah totally yeah
exactly well and that's I wanted to real
quick jump in on you know and I really
appreciate you bringing that up Fletcher
um bigger respect to Archive as well um
yeah it's it's really awesome to kind of
you know and skunkman Sam joining of
this pretty Legend area but um it's very
fascinating because if you look at what
washes typically the things that wash
best are care offline liing they're in
that dessert Zone they have the highest
yields and dumps as opposed to trying to
wash terpinolene doesn't wash trying to
wash like a or like I mean all the T all
the turpins will have different freezing
points some lower and some higher and
then concentrations of those versus the
cannaboid types and those freezing point
I mean I mean that's makes to me in
terms of the main factor that makes
stuff wash or extractable and it's also
of course temperature dependent like I
think besides the wash if you could get
the water colder
theoretically and besides the freezing
point it's also different Turpin have
different solubility in water yep
hydrophobic or hydrophilic yeah and
that's kind of something exactly exactly
yeah and that because that's a you know
because in in that topic you know like
what happens to thec those ones that
watch well real quick real quick um just
to you know because just wanted to make
a make a point on on um what we've seen
with testing right so certain you know
terpinolene you watch you you BHO that
it's the most high dump like awesome
like high turp you know so I think
there's the right type of extraction for
right type of Turk you know certain
things that don't wash like Sam saying
dry seeve wow you know kind of things
that you you know unable to do otherwise
unless you do something like butane
extract right which is great if you get
the residual out it's super bomb you
know um but the but what what I want to
hit on too is like what is within the
plant right the biggest thing we've
learned about potency and variance from
top middle to bottom has less to do with
kind of uh you know bouncing around to
lab Lab and has more to do with uh
optimal canopy management processes and
Le removing Leaf at the right times
critical through the development of
flowers and the maturing of flowers and
people that like strip and remove such a
vast you know which is very contrary to
a lot of the old school belief but you
know like removing 75% of found Leaf
right at the start of flower uh keeping
that off on day 21 keeping that off on
day 56 like what happens is every Bud
doesn't get any difference in light and
all mature kind of at the same rate was
what a top Bud tests so whatever a top
Bud test s if you have this like Optimal
canopy management process removing all
of the leaf at the right times and
keeping it off then all the buds kind of
mature at that rate and overall not only
do we see the standardization of canabo
content across a plant to what a topw
tests plus or minus like a 5% relative
difference um so if you had like a 25 up
top plus or minus like one and a half%
or 1.7% or whatever that is so you could
have kind of this standardization for
when a compliance test happens and
representative sampling you're like
right at the number what a top a test
right but if you remove like a lot of
farmers remove way too much Leaf way too
late in the flower and those are all
immature developed Buds and so there's
you could have on the same plant you
know the 25 up here but like 12 or so
down here at the bottom and now the
average is like 18 right and so I think
part of it and you know because when
we've done this trial repeatedly across
cultivars and time with different
Farmers you know we've not only been
able to show not only can you
standardize what the canopy test what a
top Bud test and the genetic bring out
the genetic full potential the plant and
canavs and turps and other aromatics but
um you get a yield increased yield per
plant increased extraction efficiency of
what you're able to pull off that
material per plant you know because
because I think it's about optimization
of How It's cultivated for if it's going
to be extracted um and then further it's
about what is the extract what is the
appropriate extraction process for it to
be put through so you can even turn it
into hash
so dude you're you're touching on things
that I think is are are a must must have
topic because it's it's the most
important thing I think any of the
individuals that are listening that are
hash makers in the chat right now if
you're actual hash maker what Alec was
touching on with your defoliation and
your Sops that go back to your
cultivation
techniques if you know if you've
listened to any of the things that I've
ever said in any of the the the the
talks I've done it always starts with
defoliation and there's a reason Reon
why everything that Alex just said that
is going to exponentially help your
resin quality if you get in there early
enough and have a a really finite timing
in which you do that and where you do
that on the plant at what time so I'll
leave you to design that for yourselves
but that is the most that I've learned
over my time doing this from cultivation
to oil and there's there's a lot that
goes into that and it's not just about
being a great extractor it's about being
a great Steward of that plant from that
seed to oil and understanding all the
ways that you need to do the things you
need to do in your Sops and work
instructions as a team because it's not
singular especially when you're doing
things at scale it all has to work in
Harmony and that's a very difficult task
um so I think that's dude you just you
hit on all kinds of things that I that I
really think about on a daily basis
because it's not just one part of the
process that makes it great it's all
these things that amount to where you
end up and well
I think really I think totally I
appreciate that um and I and you know
and you know because I think hesting has
helped me in the huge raat realize so
much of what the passion people have for
the plant and for extraction have helped
them to learn already you know and and I
think they complement in an incredibly
big way and and I think a big part of
this too is you know um diversity right
because can cannabis has become
homogenized in the chase for THC strains
as well as in the chase for strains that
wash right and we now see in this
California State Fair in the emerald cup
you know 60 80% of Any Given category or
more in the solventless category are all
the same profile they're very slight
variations of the same thing and so the
only thing that people really enter that
are different or quote unquote exotic
have some unique Esther or turp or
something in there like the tropican
sulfur turps to make like Mimosa smell
unique which is why people are like oh
it's exotic it's not exotic it's
actually abundant and and strong man Sam
helped bring that to the world you know
but the thing is is uh it's about like
diverse cultivar covering the range of
what's possible and then finding and
fine-tuning both the pruning cany
management process as well as what is
the ideal extraction process to make
that most awesome representation of that
cultivar through hash question for you
now do you think that's due to and this
is no shade on clone houses that are
actually doing commercial cloning not
guys that are selling clones online do
you think that's problematic within that
system that we've developed that you buy
from a clone house they just have a menu
for That season that's all you get you
your pigeon hold into buying whatever
Kush cake or whatever Skittles they're
growing that at large or blue drain
whatever it is um what do you you know
how do we because you know it's it's
let's be honest it's scale um owning
moms and propagation is very expensive
and it's it's probably the the most
expensive aspect of of doing all this to
get yourself set up to grow it um so I
wonder you know I keep thinking about it
because feno hunts are tough when you're
dealing with dollars and cents and
people that are don't truly own their
businesses right they're they're really
just taking money from people and
they're working for a VC or or a bunch
of people that have funded it and
they're like they're just they're stuck
they've got to grow this that they know
sells and how do we break that mold too
you know because that's something we I
we talk about in our team is like we
don't want to be stuck like caught into
that ever you know well Rob said Rob
said at the emerald cup years ago it got
quoted by LA Times which which was seeds
are life and clones are death and he was
talking about the bottlenecking of the
genome right of the gene pool and I know
of a particular Nursery which I won't
mention but in California over 50% of
their sales over 50% last year were
gelato 41
at least that one's got a little gas on
it you know yeah I know but 50% of the
entire sales and these guys are selling
all over the states and everywhere we're
one cutting and that's the big
bottleneck and to me that's a sign of
the fast food era that we're in right
now where everyone's just like cheap and
easy and what sells and what's colorful
and what's also a big part of that I
think is actually what's funny is I
think CU you know what we've seen is
this continuous homogenization of Cal of
flavors California to only be like 60
80% of what's back it reminds me back in
the day like in LA 48 or 50 strains on
the Shelf would be OG Kush variations
you know and there was like no
difference right and that blew out and
then kind of now the rise of the
desserts but now it's the same thing you
know and what's a trip of what I'm
seeing is so much I I I I believe that
the bulk buying Market is very
disconnected with the consumer Demand
right because the bulk buying Market
largely isn't trying to curtail to the
unique consumer demand in any given
state they're like playing to the
traditional Market you know and so you
got 60 to 80% of Herb in California
desserts and that's not slowing down you
know and you know even though
terpinolene right strains like that sage
like that train wreck you know they
represent like less than 10% of what's
on dispensary shelves but BDS analytics
and Leafly data have shown in various
regions of a state in various counties
Across the Nation when turpine varieties
are around they move like five to eight
times as quick as anything else on the
Shelf till they're gone right and so
that's a different value right and and I
think like ultimately the idea of like
you know because I think every
cultivator has to make those types of
choices right are you g to grow nothing
but Skittles and gelato by Skittles
gelato crosses even though 80% of the
Market's that you know because unless
your herb is like twice as tped and
preserved as everything else you just
blend in with the mass of everything
else you know but by diversifying your
portfolio having all these other
cultivators sure you might grow gelato
41 50% or more of what you bulk grow but
as long as you have those like really
epic isolated fenos that you love that
cover like range of smell and flavor you
know you can always grow those in
smaller amounts keep them going and find
the niche markets and areas in where
you're at to be able to really start
building a grassroot demand for those
because you know what we're seeing when
people do that like a leap of faith
because it's like you're making huge
choices you know but it's like don't not
grow it just grow way less of it until
you can start justifying that you know
or the other thing the other thing that
can be done is people can cyrogenic
freeze cryogenically freeze and uh
clones and uh keep them for uh
forever I I think what we're going to
find like in the future Market when
everywhere has legal grows and there's
just you know it's available everywhere
is if you're not innovating your product
with your products you're G to be
commoditized or pushed into that market
because you and everybody else that
bought the same clones this year are all
in the market together it doesn't matter
how new they are you bring back
something from three years ago it it
won't matter and the the more
commercialized Growers are are playing
that game and buying from those places
and not finding something unique to
their business the quicker it's going to
continue to move in that direction well
to be honest what I I made a lot of
seeds in my life but the seeds I made
were I tried to think of other people
but really they were the ones that I
like well you have a dis pallet man
and we each do and that's what's so cool
about this plant you know it's like it
tickles our old factory senses in a way
that I mean some people can't eat
cilantro because it's soapy or don't
like chocolate or cacao because of the
bitterness you know and others love it
you know and that's where you know I
think it's really about you know what
we've been working with the emerald Cup
and the state faon and some really
Progressive dispensaries in the state
it's like when you present herb to
Consumers you know it's like do you have
80% of what's on your shelf is this one
thing because you're not really
providing a difference and there are all
the TPS gone right but it's like sorting
like kind of presenting it like when you
go because when you go into a wine store
or an alcohol store right like that
every cashier isn't a small EA nor
should they be expected to be that's a
lot to ask but whenever the average
consumer goes in you got your meros
merow Shard chardes Cabernet of Cabernet
roses right and so the average person
can make a choice based on what they
know flavor preference is and um
presenting it in such a way not only
kind of helps to kind of
really get deeper into like helping
people find what best you know
Associates with their endoc canab system
but it also shows where you're lacking
you know and and helps to reestablish
value it's like hey dude if I've got
unlimited access to gelato 41 and cush
cake um but I don't have any plugs that
have anything in the awesome IND
dominant like tropical sleigh ride or
pineapple tie pineapple anything or kind
of terpinolene right or you know sweet
tooth like you know I mean I think kind
of um the more and all so much of it
happens with the retail because I think
the whole conversation around turps and
preservation of turs is like almost uh
preaching of the choir for those closest
to the plant you know because TN doesn't
matter right but once you get to like
the average purchaser at a dispensary
that's buying off spreadsheets and
strain names with THC percentages often
blown out inflated and not even real it
commoditized it right brings it to a
point where it doesn't even it doesn't
mean anything and it it it Blends
biomass versus the most craft chronic
herb in the world you know I absolutely
agree agree and on the consumer level
because and because and the awareness
and I'm sorry to I'm just wrapping the
point but the awareness is and the
Epiphany around this turps matter
aromatics are the most important thing
and if they're there or not you know
that's not going to come from an
epiphany at the average consumer level
or the average buyer dispensary that's
buying off spreadsheets is going to come
from the top thought leaders in the
space helping to disseminate that out
you know and leading by example you know
when is somebody going to test if
files can contribute and modulate THC
the way tping do because files the
latest Cades but nobody knows that they
potentiate or modulate cannabis
everybody has guesses but nobody's
proven it or indol that's that's the one
I've been
chasing pretty exciting stuff you know
and and Sam Actually I brought this up
earlier but I'd love your kind of
thoughts on it and your observations
especially since the orange that you had
as well as the skunk um you know because
when it comes to these trace thols and
sulfur compounds like tropican sulfur
that makes that Tangy you know orange
Citrus Vibe um and then the the thols
that make the gas Vibe right like the
nose can pick them up at such levels
that push the capabilities of even the
most sophisticated analytical chemistry
equipment and when whenever you go to
concentrate it and they're there in the
biggest amounts you know they can be you
know at that point you know they're
they're you know we're we've been
working on methods to develop see what
of them are even possibly to be tested
for in flower versus kind of what can be
shown up and concentrated in extracts
but that's also where the human nose
takes it to a whole another level and I
think this the marriage between science
and the human old factory triple you
know Mass spectrometer um I think is
where kind of this all really is where
it it kind of evolves to help uh
celebrate the nuances because in the in
the emerald cup we we just launched a
new category and that's the the Citrus
category and because there are so many
examples entered that people were
entering as exotic but were there were
as numerous as gas in the whole
competition and they spanned across
tpine categories from the mirin category
to the Carl Ling category to the
turpening
category question guys we were breeding
for tping what we found was and this
blew Rob Clark and M mindes because we
crossed hay with a hemp variety and made
an grew out the f2s made a selection and
we found one that smelled exactly like P
but it had no
THC and we know how much you do not like
that that really [ __ ] with your
nose so Alec like with all that you just
said imagine owning that wine shop and
selling like the most rare grapes in the
world and then having this little tiny
section on the right that's just like
ever CLE and some other weird stuff and
your customers in they're like what do
you got and you're like well I got all
this amazing stuff and all these really
amazing flavors then I've got this stuff
over here 99 proof Yep they're like well
I'll take that stuff over there that's
sure you know 99 proof it's 200 proof
200 proof or whatever whatever the proof
is but it's it really it's it feels like
that's kind of where things have landed
in in a weird way maybe maybe I correct
me if I'm wrong anyway but it just seems
like that analogy feels real right now
and we as you said Alec like we we we
can only all as a community talk about
how that's problematic and we need we do
need to change it because there is more
to all of this than just a a
monomolecular substance and you know
those that are on here disagree okay but
um I I don't know I just wanted to spark
that conversation with everybody here is
like is that really the path you know
because there is many paths to
Therapeutics here um sometimes a
monomolecular compound is Right
sometimes not but well also too some
people want the most punch they can get
for their buck
and they think that it's THC but for
example my best skunk clone was only
177% THC but it was super rich in the
right turfing yeah like 3 to one T ratio
5% T and people preferred it over stuff
that was 22 and 25 THC
sure right so we haven't proved what we
haven't shown what potency is with
cannabis at all and that's a big issue
right we've all we all we like potent
candles we all like to get high but we
don't know what potency is and even in
the literature we use the attached THC
to potency and like we all know that
that that's not no one was measuring THC
in land race populations when they're
selecting for potency for a thousand
years they're selecting for potency one
thing right but um the market you know
and they want to pay for their they
that's what they want to do they want to
get the biggest bang for their Buck but
we we know that we can deliver a more
potent variety that's at a lower THC so
that's that's just about us being bold
like Alex said brands have to be bold
breeders have to be bold we have to put
the product on the shelf for them to
choose from but at the same time the
Market's been dumbed down so much that
they just choose dessert flavors so what
I think we should do Alec is take all
the hazes the sages the train wrecks the
Jacks the durans and rename them all
fruity flowery
names purple candy gas yeah yeah what we
could try and do is educate the consumer
yeah that's it that's the that's the
answer friend you were gonna say
something dude well it just thank you
just seems like it's kind of confusion
on both ends when I hear that where you
have like a high-end bottle of wine and
and then you have like the low-end
alcohol so it's kind of confused on the
Shelf already or in the same in that at
the store but then confusion on the
customer on the clientele end too where
if they're coming into that store you
know not sure where that begins or how
to where that would correct I'd almost
go back to Sam or someone in Amsterdam
right now where checking in to see if
there if there are any like really high
highend or organic you know organic
regenerative even soil grown you know as
the basis for for high-end cannabis or
hash in Amsterdam as you know like a are
there places where you could find any of
that because I haven't heard you can you
can you have to find it by word of mouth
but it's it it can be done but it's a
minority of the product I always Pro my
plants
organically in the soil in the ground in
a greenhouse yeah I would have grown It
Outdoors in California but you can't do
it Outdoors here it just don't work well
right in
Amsterdam I can't remember who said it
earlier but uh you were talking about
um with uh with the market difference
between uh or the demands of the
traditional Market versus what the
actual recreational consumer is
and that drives a lot of what people
grow in terms of like the like you know
just in that conversation of of what
strains people are choosing to grow and
why the market is like candy heavy and
it's because most Rec grows big big ones
especially are having a hard time moving
all their stuff through recck shops y so
they're still trying to manage all right
we're going to plant 80% runs and then
20% couple sativas and some [ __ ] and if
it sells on they don't even put any
energy into it and they're actually
growing more than the market really
demands of them for that product anyways
so and between those markets and then
and then businesses trying to fill both
at the same time right well and it's
keeping us in the Stone Age because in
any state where this the catering to the
east coast demand which is usually like
the fivey year ago Trend in like
California or another state you know
it's kind of leading to that's all you
can grow because that's all that bulk
buyers want to sell but again I think
that's where just like the you know the
leap of faith exists you know for people
that are in the wck market to kind of
again find the right ratios of what
you're growing but but don't give up and
like you know don't if you can't beat
them join them but not when it comes to
Growing nothing but that because it's
like that's going to be the collapse and
the commoditization of the market
whereas but then but then they have to
invest in breeding and finding their own
[ __ ] well isolating finding your right
finding the fenos that cover the range
but the people like I was mentioning
earlier like in Oregon and California
that are selling out quicker than is
Trimm to the heist priced Market G bear
in the deepest floods you know they've
started to be able to kind of create
markets for these rare unique cultivars
because of how much they invested in
turp preservation infrastructure and
treating cannabis like cabbage and like
ensuring that they can deliver to the
point of sale at a retail shelf herb
that is hundreds of percents more more
flavorful aromatic sticky than anything
else on the Shelf you know those that do
that like there comes a point when a
market because every it happens in every
Market the same thing there's this over
production that leads to price
compression that leads to potency
inflation and fraudulent lab practices
that blows out the market and then the
consumers at some point lose faith in
the entire system and they're just
bouncing from Brand to brand with no
loyalty because everything has a 40%
flow result and tastes like hay you know
and so what happens is whenever that
happen s in a market and the consumer
loses faith and there's no loyalty those
that double down on tur preservation
that have a diverse array of profiles
all of a sudden through the dispensary
Market when they're delivering like this
they're like the the the Savior you know
and like all of a sudden the they build
these relations where they're you know
selling out quicker than trim the
highest price and a lot of them are
getting cash on delivery because of how
chronic their herb is and how high their
consumer demand and loyalty for that
brand is yep I mean like I know guys and
you know that only grow three varietal
just don't won't change because they
know it sells it's already sold before
it's down
CED and it's three of the most popular
varial in the game and they they're just
like I can't dir deviate because I'm I'm
you know I can't risk it you know it's
too risky to risk the fact that I might
have a bad batch when everything's just
sold right so I think that's another
that's another problem right so I think
there's also that too hereo I think
looking at markets like Oregon and
Washington that are just super mature at
this point and there's not California
Oklahoma all these other states have
taken over the like bulk game you know
so there's grows here aren't really
trying to cater to that for the most
part there's there's I mean there's
still some people but it's less so than
probably anywhere else and um yeah I I
think I think you're right Alec that uh
the companies that focus on preserving
the product to the consumer just like
you with a gallon of milk um uh is is
the name of the game and it's but it's
really hard to do that because most the
retail stores have no idea what they're
doing with their product and aren't
willing infastructure to do it which is
why we've been vertically integrated for
the last like seven or eight years in
Oregon it's because there was no other
way to do it you know I was I've I'm
from Washington and we couldn't
vertically integrate here legally so I
didn't do it here that's that's it it's
it was like there's no point for me to
I'm going to be end up in a commoditized
market if I can't control the
presentation and the supply and demand
of my own product and um it's turned out
well for us um but you have but you have
to gauge in size your market and your
demand and your supply correctly you
can't just be like oh I'll do as much as
I like because you're still you have to
remember you're focusing on some uh uh
satisfying your local consumer at the
end of the day it's not about all these
other people everywhere where else that
are coming into buy packs and all this
other [ __ ] which is where I'd say still
80% of the legal most legal markets are
still at and so and then you look at
Oregon and you can't really grow um the
like known clones for that long before
it's that strains commoditized so most
growers in Oregon are popping their own
seeds finding their own stuff making
their own hybrids making little deals
with other breeders to get some stuff in
and and that's becoming more and more
commonplace and those are those same
brands that are selling their product
out and but but they're not 500 lights
they're 50 lights exactly for for a guy
with you know a 50 lighter in his
backyard like it used to be but selling
it all legally at 3,000 a pound is a
great business um and uh that I think
looking at markets like Oregon and
Washington and even Canada kind of at
this point those big models aren't even
working even with export even with
export available to these big operations
in Canada it's not working it's
unable as not enough demand yeah and and
I feel like the plant is at certain
certain fundamental level uncor iable in
this way of scaling
commoditizing yeah yes they bought runs
into its own roadblocks with the
consumer trying to do it trying you're
not wrong the big companies have have
definitely like stopped trying to
produce millions of AC uh millions of
feet of canopy it's just not a reality
for them right now but there are some
larger outdoor grows like my friend
Merlin who was here with me earlier uh
he invited me to go see one in October
that's 94 Acres which is Big that's a
big grow that's producing a fair amount
of cannabis I've been in a 77 acre one I
have a friend who has close to 200 acres
here in BC I'm sure there's right that's
for know I don't know if there I can't
imagine there's Canadians are buying all
that yeah but in the end with export
even it gets pretty strict and there's
most of like if it's European it's got
to be eug GMP if it's Australia you can
have some other regulations everyone's
definitely trying to get their their Mar
cannabis from Canada into those markets
because CA Canada doesn't have much of a
market it's a small that's my point
that's my point yeah it's a small Market
can't they destroy and just get full
value over Insurance up there because of
the structure no right they can't I
thought that they were allowed to other
other crops crop insurance but I don't
know about who's gonna insure
cannabis ins is really there is some
crop insurance but I think that like
right away that was probably abused or
used up it's like it's like when we
signed up with lighting there's so many
insurance policies that we did for
shipping and they'd be like after our
very first claim they' cut us
off what's the point well what's crazy
about crop insurance is it's like
because farmers and agriculture required
to create crop insurance not for if they
their crop [ __ ] and lost because their
practices but in case they get sued and
held liable because they're spraying and
overspray effects another Farm you know
so on that end with crop insurance and
agriculture that's on the high high
that's on the rise and premiums are on
the rise because cannabis farmers and
how valuable crop is whenever they get
drifted on there's hell to
pay well the government will pay you to
not grow in regular agriculture at least
sometimes yeah no it's the truth man
yeah it's I think the couple thing Alex
you said you know really resonated with
like what is too much and same with you
you know Fletch like what is too much
you know what is the canopy size that
makes it makes sense so everybody with
population you just do it with popul
consumer based X percentage smoke this
amount and then you look at it go this
is the amount of square foot not lights
not anything else this is how many
square feet we need how many people do
we think are going to try to be in this
business 5,000 people break the square
footage down to the square to the people
that's where you start everybody starts
there if you can if you can sell your
[ __ ] out you can get more licensing and
more licensing and keep growing your
business that's how I would do it I like
that I mean Massachusetts has a path
like that for for the 5,000 foot micro
business where you can resubmit if
you're you know if you need more um I
think it's Anor it also keeps corporate
investment out because the first stage
will be such a low bar that it won't
have millions and millions and millions
of dollars worth of of returns you know
it's going to be a small business until
you show that you're successful and
you're not flooding the market with
cheap [ __ ] that's Tain it with
pesticides and F them mold that doesn't
test you know just like that's are full
of MOT toxins that have been remediated
I mean all of that is just part of Comm
the commercialization of it instead of
affecting some sort of production
control
right yeah it's all
about method that's easier than that I'm
not saying it's the best method but it's
very simple right but it's about to me
it's about what piece of Pi is the
regional model as we are in this
transitional period so every wants a
slice of the pie right so we're creating
all these different Regional models and
Regional regulations for everyone to
figure out who can participate on
investment how much canopy can this
Corporation own all that those are all
temporary adjustments based off of the
current state of affairs and and that to
me is the biggest challenge that's where
all the investors like I get more people
asking me about like so what what what
do you guys in the US going to do about
the farm bill like we're not ready to
invest here because you haven't figured
out Farm F Bill hemp in the US you know
what I mean it's like well like it's
nuts right so everyone knows it's headed
towards an international commodity
everybody knows that the guys that are
planting those acreage in in Canada
they're doing it for a future Emerging
Market that's going to need it and
hoping that it happens at the right time
that they can get it there and you know
but it's anyway so I think we're all we
all understand that it's just in a big
transition and and we're all just going
to have to roll with the punches because
I don't think anyone's going to come up
with a solution you know one time I
actually sat down and I figured out with
mathematics how much cannabis is smoked
in Canada and in uh America uh totally
and I figured out that whether you smoke
in marijuana whether you smoke in
hashish uh rosin whatever it can all be
grown on 50 square miles in California
right in the perfect climate with all
the infrastructure and all the culture
and all the labor and all the great
genetics and all the great minds just
like they do with 20 other crops where
we're like look man we got this we can
handle it don't worry about it it'll
actually be better for everybody and I
do believe that and I'm not a California
exceptionalist but I just believe that's
the way we set up this state as an a
state California Selena say is the salid
of America right and there's a reason
why because of prohibition though we've
proliferated this ideal of cannabis to
be indoor grown indoor looking even for
even for the like cheap weed now it's
people want [ __ ] that looks like indoor
especially for flower at least the hash
is a whole different story and so now
all these new markets around the world
that may have historically just been
where California could just grow it all
and we just ort it all and everybody
thinks weeds like cigarettes we've got
40 years of this culture of
wanting the like indoor cannabis because
of prohibition so now all these states
and we're already seeing it in America I
mean the evidence is there everyone
wants to grow their own [ __ ] and sell it
to the rest of the world well that's
like being a grower in California who
are you gonna sell your weed to another
grower like what are you talking
about yeah but also at the same time
such I have to say
30 years ago outdoor weed looked very
different than it does today and with
the right selection and breeding we can
I think we can create we can select
cultivars that grow and Seed crops that
grow so well in the ideal climate that
it'll be close enough that that hole I
need it to be indoor and I need it to be
depth It'll be such a quick shift where
people go wow $50 an
ounce that it'll it'll win because of
price exactly but but here's a thing
where the um government should be smart
enough to not incentivize that because
people only smoke so much cannabis if
you take it from $300 an ounce to 50
bucks an ounce what everybody pays all
you did is turn A2 billion Doll Market
into a $400 million market and you got
more people you everybody shot for A2
billion Doll Market and now everybody's
trying to share 4 $400 million Market
it's happened in every single legal
state that this has occurred in what
used to be a $2 billion markets now
worth 500 million bucks who does that
help especially the state who's trying
to tax it right it's like that they're
shooting themselves in the foot by doing
so and so are all the Growers that push
that that mentality of the cultivation
because prohibition created this
ballooned market right and people are
happy with it as long as they're paying
whatever they feel like they're getting
their money's worth whatever that means
and once you fully industrialize the
production and bottom the the value of
the product the incentive for anyone to
do any of that all of it's gone and
everybody's sharing thinner and thinner
and thinner pieces of pie every year
someone grows an extra acre but that's
also will always be new people creating
new varieties For the Love of it because
not everybody's chasing money I never
did well California is a whole different
world nowadays but what and and that's
the thing California is going through it
own collapse like Oregon went through
you know that Oregon's kind of been
coming out of right it happens in every
state you know and and you know even the
biggest people I mean there's been like
some of these monoliths that lost 600
mil and like have left the state right
of California Oregon and Colorado the
three most competitive mature markets in
the nation you know all of them are are
disappearing from competitive
market yeah well that's the thing it's
like comp they're not competitive from I
read you know like when the prohibition
of because when the prohibition of
alcohol ended there was this 80-year
consolidation among a few families
before craft was even established in the
80s right and and the the big prayer
right is that doesn't happen with
cannabis because the prob cannabis
ending you got Budweiser and craft
running in the same sprint the same
field in a market where it's I feel like
the hyperfocus on THC is the only way to
distinguish quality is such a mark of
the ad Ence and the immaturity of a
market because we don't even know and
have the tools to establish what is
quality right but what happens
inevitably those that build resilience
and double down a tur preservation
infrastructure to have because when when
herb doesn't when the flood and over
production sets in herb isn't moving as
quick as it used to and so it sits
around and it's really exposed to
whatever infrastructure you have or
don't have to care for the herb and
turps in your possession and if you
don't have that and it goes bad you're
just racing to the bottom with the
commoditized Market as opposed to like
you know the long game of preservation
and how much that's
cnia what we haven't we haven't figured
out how to I mean we know how to
stabilize cannabis we know how to make
it if we actually injected it with you
know nitrogen and Argon gas to actually
stabilize it because of these large
Productions but the DCC has its head so
far up its ass it can't even realize
that you have to stabilize these quality
genetics because there's so much
production that's sitting on the shelf
for so long they can't even get past
that so I mean they don't even
understand quality much less how to
sustain quality so California is [ __ ]
and I'm just saying this so other states
could learn from [ __ ] up so that you can
learn how to do it right because we're
not big
time over prodction issue one I think
that's what also uh with Illustrated in
this LA Times expose you know the state
has to be overly restrictive and testing
and auditing of the Laboratories that
are the final check in the Integrity of
the supply chain if there is a robust
State program to ensure the quality of
what the standards are put in place that
combined with people doubling down tur
preservation infrastructure I mean
that's there's there's you know over
production is an inevitable but the
thing is is clean quality bomb input are
a resource they're a scarce resource and
unless you know the folks that have them
you know you don't inced to do that when
over production is happening though
that's the problem no one's incentivized
you have to get rid yeah
totally down the top but that's where
vertical like you're doing in Oregon is
is you know building resilience and I
know brands in California that are
focused specifically on cultivation that
have done very thing and have in the
most flooded space built their brand to
sell out Quicken this trimmed cash on
delivery as a result of you know they're
not having cash flow issues like with
the dispensar not paying can we agree
they're few and far between oh few and
far between for sure for sure and and
that's you know 100% And that's the
thing it's like we're because we're in
live a motion action you know working
through quality like it's like the the
the dirtiest and the cleanest in the
state competing at the same price point
the cleanest or the the most chronic and
most biomass in the state competely the
same price point you know so it's like
that we're we're I think as a culture
like working a power through that and be
build resilience in time where there
it's not looking good but the thing is
is there is hope and those that really
figure that side of it out build the
resilience needed to make it through the
deepest floods you know and build that
grassroot consumer loyalty around not
only the quality of their product
because there's such a huge shock in
consumer trust and confidence right now
because of this like Expose and LA Times
so it's like you you know you can't just
like trust you know like you got to
trust but verify and if you can find a
brand and like you know that are not
only full built with integrity and kind
of doubling down on the turps and like
it's the only thing you can find in a
five mile radius that's got any flavor
Aroma there's a point where that matters
in the collapse of every market and it's
just about making it through breaking
even like you know just getting to that
point because if you're doing that
you're crushing it you know because once
this opens up you know there's no one in
the world that will be able to compete
with Oregon kind of California type you
know I mean you
know if the state prevented the over
production of all that like the like
there's a ton of grows that wouldn't
survive without
backdooring the majority of their
product and for sure if the state just
regulated that well not even perfectly
but just even at all right yeah that
would basically get rid of all the fluff
well that's those people that we're
talking about right that that these
grows that we want to see do well that
can't afford to grow and put hand
manicure in time and everything into
$1,500 pounds um where the market will
actually uh reward them for that and the
retailers won't be able to bully them
because of the over production
availability of something quote unquote
comparable that then the customer now
pays the price for because they're
buying three-month old weave for half
the price because it's there and like
you know or give me one second like in
Colorado when they started their legal
it was the 7030 rule where you had to
grow 70% of the [ __ ] that you sold and
you had to have your own store created a
great market right and so I'm just
showing how it does we even have
evidence to no whereare does work even
that that's that's cool you that's
that's a great data point because what
I'm thinking of is what Alex said about
cood and terms and how that doesn't work
and how that catches up with everyone
and that's really there's a million
reasons and analogies you could bring up
in terms of food why you would pay for
your meal first and you're not going to
leave the restaurant without paying your
bill right so why would you leave a
dispo and why would the dispo not pay
you on delivery right and then
furthermore it's you know the dros are
forcing people into buying scenarios and
buying schemes that are very familiar to
the beverage markets where you want one
brand well you got to buy a thousand
other of this other brand and that's not
moving to liquidate this inventory for
me to give you actually what you're here
for and I think those types of tactics
Force retailers to buy things they don't
want them to then in turn kind of slow
roll things that they've bought that
they do want and then it overshadows it
and it's this weird deconomy of like
well take a thousand of these for 200 of
these and you're just in this weird
dichotomy of of forcing yourself with
the dro to buy certain things so I think
that's a deeper curtain that I'm pulling
on all of it but it is a problem that
I've seen overall you look at the cut
flow
industry Holland used to dominate it
America used to dominate it it's not
that way anymore it's all done in
Colombia Ecuador you know a on the
tropics because it's so much cheaper the
labor and you you can grow the same
quality and uh I honestly think that's
the way cannabis will be uh it'll be
produced where it's cheaper to produce
and this as high quality as the
craft yeah well I'd say cannabis is very
different than Wine but it's for
California it's a similar Dynamic and
that like the 50s and 60s it was a jug
wine crappy wine cheap wine you know get
drunk and there wasn't a lot of real
high-end California didn't have a name
for itself globally and while California
built a name for itself globally and
France and Italy and Spain took a hit
also Argentina took off and Australia
took off and South Africa took off and
Chile took off and now California
competes with the Global Wine Market but
we still crush it and California wine
still has a brand worldwide you know and
that's because it was done collectively
with Farmers with regulation with
Appalachians with UC Davis with the
state and they decided collectively we
want to make California wine a thing we
want it to be a player in the Global
Wine world and we still are but it took
a real concerted effort to do it and a
lot of luck you know also Geographic
dominance and a lack of an indoor Supply
like we know you know you can do with
green houses and everything else it's
why you know Canada can supply their
themselves they don't need California
weed you could never you could also
never pass a test if you grew a urb in
Napa Valley you know it's like a
absolute poisoned tainted region of the
state right but my point is how much
what what could the the impact of
California would have son's Prohibition
in cannabis in terms of a global market
you know and what what impact it will
have in the future you know so Canada
might not have happened the way it did
if they could buy California wine just
like they don't you know so they had to
they were forced to grow indoors just
like we're all forced to grow indoors I
think that like Canada going the way
that it has kind of proves that there's
not even enough International demand
really right because I mean like to to
sustain even that level of what they
were doing you know it's like California
can come online too and grow bazillion
pounds but it's going to have the same
effect it's just going to bottom the
price and then people go out of business
and shut down all the big farms and then
you end up with small high-end stuff
that's servicing the local consumers you
got a few big guys that are crushing it
on some weird export thing that they
figured out that's that's super
lucrative they they'll be out there
don't get me wrong but they're going to
be few and that's why all the the uh
canac Corps have all left California I
mean to me the craziest thing is this
like if I if I um am like in the movie
industry I moved to Hollywood to go sell
my movies
right if I'm in the wheed industry like
these Canada corporations and I can't go
to California and make money selling
weed how bad are you at what you do I
mean you gotta be horrible I mean like
California is like fifth biggest fifth
biggest economy in the world they spend
we money on weed like nobody's business
there the velocity of money in
California Dwarfs anywhere else and
you're telling me you can't make money
selling weed there I mean you're you
must suck at weed because that's that'd
be like me saying I went to Hollywood to
sell movies and I couldn't sell a movie
there it's like well I'm probably not
very good
then a lot of those people though that
what they do their reason why they're
successful is because they've found a
way to through the high cost barrier of
entry into a lot of markets that are
limited license essentially build their
own little Monopoly even though their
product couldn't even make the cut in
Oregon or California or Colorado let go
man that just means their days are
numbered though
right yeah until there's limit until
there's no more limited licensing States
they really because I see it all the
time man look at I get text messages
from like Kentucky oh this is gonna
fireing off right now it's it's nuts man
people are people are hungry for things
that they don't really understand and I
think that that is a problem in our
industry where other industry comes in
and they've got better ideas and they're
going to go do this because they can get
the investment into it but then what
happens when you spend all the
investment and there's nothing left and
there's no return they go to another
place to do it again right until
something either clicks or they just run
out of money but it just seems to me
that that's never going to stop just
like the hemp markets are never going to
stop unless there's real reform um you
know but we as you said Fletcher like
there's a real opportunity sitting in
front of everyone and I I get most both
sides of it I always say we all need to
go back to the basics and just grow
really good herb again and stop worrying
about the rest and the flip side of that
is that someone will say well I want it
cheaper right well what happens when we
stop saying that it's
cheaper I've got when we say it just
costs this much you know I've got I've
got a funny metaphor I've thought of
before and you know how we were talking
about subsidies earlier
um prohibition was a multi-billion
multi-trillion
overtime
dollar subsidy for cannabis
Growers they created a lack of
Supply which proliferated the the
culture the industry everything that we
all love
right why would we want anything other
than essentially the same
thing after
prohibition where we're cont basically
in one form or another
enforcing um keeping things small that's
what I mean look at the Hydroponics
industry it's basically done right it's
just you can't even find hydro shops on
the west coast
anymore you got to drive 50 miles in
between stores it's
insane so
um you know how's that good for the
economy and how does that how does that
even help the state after prohibition
like they want all they they looked at
weed and go look how much it's worth
they selling pound you remember the old
uh news articles of pounds worth $8,000
right and they tell you it's worth 50
pounds is four million bucks you know
it's like that's they were looking at it
like we're going to get our 25% and here
they are you just allow over production
and
well warehouses warehouses full of Super
Sacks full of hemp from last year right
just Chuck full of 400 to 500 pounds per
super sack right and know that [ __ ] was
all grown last year and it ain't moving
because the CBD Market's been stagnated
so what are people doing they're
spraying that [ __ ] with thca or THC
rather putting it into pre-rolls and
selling it at gas stations and bodegas
in New York City you know New York City
is just such an interesting thing we
don't need to have time to go into it
right Colin will tell you this that
every time they make some big
announcement about trying to shut down
the Trap Market in New York because the
Trap Market is just it's just there's
there's like 10 shops on every block in
Manhattan right and you could buy you
know a nice you know sandwich and get
get a u get a drink and then buy some
weat at the same store you know so it's
[ __ ] crazy man some of the
stuff another
state Alex said it earlier too you know
what's happening now because I think I
had said this earlier and hey Fletch
it's good to see you again man it's been
a while man but um uh it's it's it's an
order magnitude cheaper to make THC from
CBD
that it is to grow weed extract it and
distill it refine it into that same
molecule of THC you'll pay 10 times the
amount to get to that same molecule of
THC so I mean this is just yeah it's a
[ __ ] show it's being commoditized I
don't know how any cannabis companies
expect to make any money when the
competition can sell an $8 vape pen two
clicks after you said you're 21 on
website they're asking you for your
credit card information you know I mean
it's just there's no way that the
regular Canabis Market gotta sell The
Chronic you got sell The Chronic and and
service a specific consumer and that's
that's my op yeah you gotta make a brand
promise and they trust you and that's
why they do business with you I'm on
board with you but you know what the
majority of beer drinkers in this
country drink Budweiser Bud Light that
they Buy in cases at Walmart so when you
could buy
weed weed with spray Delta eight on it
and you could buy it at Walmart guess
what all those Walmart consumers are
gonna buy it by the ton it's gonna be
new Prevagen or new Kunal right you'll
see jelly
donuts I mean
crazy everybody and Budweiser also has a
lot of glyphosate in it and glyos one of
the biggest deseri of the
desertified to all like 80% of all
long-term chronic illness autoimmune
conditions of all types into all
different types of cancer and so you I
think we're entering into this world of
uh this time of radical transparency
because of how compromised the food
system is how compromised all these
systems are and captured by corporate
poisoning PE Industries it's like it's
leading in this era for those that are
trying to live a long healthy life and
not get Parkinson's or Dementia or ALS
or Alzheimer's in their late time it's
like you have to be radically aware of
what you're putting in or on your body
you know and I think that just really
helps us to kind of get into that zone
and uh and the reality is is like yeah
there's going to be Budweiser you know
and and um and you know it's I mean and
the more we can do to kind of you know
identify test you know because taxes are
destroying everything I mean there's so
much destroying everything the state not
regulating Labs but I think ultimately
the testing it's again the biggest
barrier of Entry to keep out the
poisonous people that are you know their
only game is to like monocrop f and you
know desiccate with glyphosate you know
like the whole reality and so but the
thing is is that's also poisoning
ourselves it's poisoning the planet it's
poisoning all life species and um I
don't think that's the long run that's
going to succeed um but those that are
like radically transparent and able to
kind of build long-term kind of loyalty
around that you know I think is how kind
of a lot of those that are in most
Integrity with the plant are going to
like find their path and don't you think
that the majority of the people in
America
eat heavily processed chemical grown
food I mean for sure and they're also
developing all these long-term chronic
of course they are but Al I'm saying
is they're still buying
it well marus I know you want to jump I
know you want to jump but I want to make
I want to make a point before you end
this episode this has been a great
episode guys we talked about a lot of
stuff but um you know Unilever the
multi-billion dollar consumer product
Corporation Unilever they they're the
people who make who bring us helman's
mayonnaise right I don't know if you
like mayonnaise on your BLT but it's
it's probably they own like 150 food
companies yeah well they're they're just
this huge mega consumer product well
they have a new uh advertising uh slogan
or a new advertising kind of gist where
they want to talk about sustainable
farming practices because they use
soybean oil in the manufacturer of
mayonnaise right so and they they talk
about it so they they they they show
customers walking into like a deli and
then getting like a sandwich that's got
nothing in the rapper so it's a pretty
provocative kind of you know consumer
campaign but it's it's it's really it's
not paying attention to Marcus what you
guys figured out in Canada which is that
the driver for cannabis and hemp
ultimately is not THC and it's not CBD
and it's really not medicine it's
[ __ ]
food Everybody Eats food not everyone
smokes weed like Alex said right so
there's a limited market when it comes
to you know how widespread can you
produce cannabis but ultimately if
you're trying to display soybean on
protein per acre now you're up against
the industrial agricultural food complex
of archers Daniel Midland Bungie Dupont
senta you know all those chemical
companies all of them without exception
bought seed companies so they could
genetically engineer their seed
to be resistant to their fungicides and
their insecticides and herbicides so
yeah all I I think the ultimate driver
here Alec I don't know I I I could be
wrong on this when it comes to protein
per acre I think with soybeans you can
get somewhere between 360 to
380 pounds of soluble protein per acre
with hem and Sam tell me if these
numbers are are are in line with what
what you know hemp with the high like
phola high oil variety strains they
think the estimates are somewhere like a
thousand pounds an acre so if you're a
farmer and you're looking to raise I
don't know uh protein for your you know
livestock feed because you need to make
more red meat hamburgers for Big Macs
and leather shoes and [ __ ] like that I
mean protein per acre it's going to
matter how how productive that acre of
land could be and if you could make a
th000 pounds on that acre versus just
360 pounds an acre it's a no-brainer but
now again you're up against the
industrial
agricultural complex of these huge
multinational corporations that need to
keep raising
soybeans right and if you look at
soybeans soy beans keep going up keep
going up keep going up but what what the
other thing that keeps going up is the
amount of chem chicals that are applied
to the land where the soybeans are grown
we know hemp doesn't need the chemical
applications so the chemical companies
that own the seed companies have a
vested interest to keep soybeans being
grown right because they're selling tons
of chemicals right guess what when hemp
takes over they don't need to sell those
chemicals anymore so yeah I mean I I
think food is going to be the ultimate
driver I really I don't I don't think
you're wrong for sure and and cannabis
protein is like the it's like the
Cannabis of food it is so complex and so
perfect and so incredible it's been
compared to breast milk you know in
regards to the essential amino acids all
of the ones that adults need omegas
babies need the the ratios of 3 to1 glna
to GLA all of that plays a factor as
well listen this has been [ __ ] an
incredible conversation I think I spoke
twice because I was really just enjoying
listening uh and I have felt bad for
people in the past who haven't spoken
much and now I can appreciate their
perspective when you're not speaking
much you're listening you're getting
more out of it than you probably get out
of it when you share I want to thank
Kevin mccurnin for coming on and sharing
his data thank you Colin for for
inviting him and getting them on here
thank you for coming on uh thanks Alec
Dixon dude you crushed it today like
dude I always want to have you on here
your perspective is so valid uh it's so
conscious so loving and empathetic and
true to the nature of what we all sort
of believe uh Grandmaster LED thanks for
sharing it on your channel and letting
everyone know about hash Church we've
had 300 people watching live for like
four hours right now always a pleasure
to see you and have you in the room Wade
laughter bring in laughter uh it just
with your presence really appreciate you
brother um of course Mojave Richmond I
really appreciate what you said today
man it was great to have your
perspective bouncing off with uh with
Fletch a super honor to have you come
out dude I know you're not always
available and you're busy I loved what
you wrote in the uh in the chat room
there if you want to send out an email
that uh to everyone to remind them that
maybe missed what you said uh in private
they can reach out to you through the
hash Church email I hope you're going to
come back again and share uh more
greatness with a skunkman Sam I'm so
glad you made it dude I was worried the
whole time for a couple hours I was like
he's going to miss it
as the conversation got better and
better I I felt like maybe he is going
to come in and at hour three uh you came
in and blessed us with an hour so we
really appreciate that at T Fon my
brother I'm so glad you made it one of
the OG hash Church panelists haven't
hasn't been able to make it out for the
last couple because he's uh been
traveling I believe to Greenland and now
New Finland and probably eventually back
to California so really nice to hear
from your perspective and hear your
passion today and Brian dude I'm glad
you came in and and shared your Vibes
with us uh I want to continue this
conversation um next week so you're all
invited back and let's crush this out I
think I'm seeing for the first time how
important this dialogue is for our
industry and it's it's it's great that
we're all doing our individual things on
our own but when we get together the the
synergistic gain that we produce with uh
bouncing off each other not always
agreeing with each other sharing
different perspectives
I loved the different perspectives from
Mojave and uh and Fletch today both so
valid no one getting upset with one
another but both just showing these
different perspectives and I think you
know the conversation that is happening
in hash church is an important one and
it helped steer the industry in the past
and I hope that we can help steer at
least the community uh in the future so
thank you all so much for coming May the
full melt bless your bowl sooner than
later
let's all see each other next Sunday
shall we thank you love you guys thanks
thanks to everyone watching thanks to
everyone watching supp we really
appreciate you guys