this microphone live yes you you are all
live my friends just give me a second
here I'm about to set up YouTube there
is a bit of a delay on YouTube but
that's okay
who is your guardian angel that's weird
Angela medium let's skip that
alright okay alright well I want to say
something because I haven't yet which is
welcome to house church holy smokes I
should have written 3.0 but I'll be
honest I wasn't ready to let go of 2.0
yet I think that we only did 19 to point
o episodes so I was like it's still
episode not a 2.0 we're in up episode 20
this is the new platform zoom so I want
to welcome all our OGIS into the room
hemp guy D for 20k Johnny B and Etienne
are all here welcome gentlemen welcome
welcome
my mornings going okay it looks like
they found us so all of the people are
in the room that we want them to be
which is great so I'm gonna just click
the hash Church link up here and share
it I don't know if you guys understand
but usually what I would do is I'd
create a page on on YouTube for the for
the live show because Google worked
through YouTube now I can't do that I
can create the show on YouTube but when
I start the show on zoom it creates it
in a totally different box so not quite
the same as before but that's okay I'm
just happy to
happy to be here got Douglas Kate Gordon
is going to come in today
he is the gentleman throwing mechanics
conference in Jamaica he's gonna come
talk a little bit about that we didn't
really have anything in particular to
talk about today so I just thought let's
just get a hash search under our belt I
missed these guys being able to come in
and and and do this with you guys to me
is I'll be honest I really really missed
it
well we missed you too
talking to you guys and shooting the
[ __ ] once a week and you know that the
talking about it with someone else the
other day that dialogue that we did at
hash Church over the years really had a
profound effect on the community and it
really helped it sort of steer some of
the things some of the dialogues and
conversations that we came up with from
you know different you know terpenes and
rosin vape carts and terpenes and rosin
itself both of those things were very
very rare to see in the world of
cannabis prior to our talking about it
on hash Church so that's that's pretty
good I'm gonna give hash Church some
props for that and all of you guys for
for being a part of that it's [ __ ]
great not sure where everyone else is
but hey I got my crew
you don't see youtube screen I'm looking
for God to
you out let me figure you out here maybe
I'm all by myself maybe I'm not let me
see you're right we need to figure this
out
there's Darren
okay but
you like that Johnny be where we can see
everyone
it's on YouTube Johnny
yeah I put it it's it's on YouTube so
thanks John for that I'd like to be able
to see everyone I probably don't
understand how I have everything set up
I thought when I set it up and I wonder
if I set it up like when you guys are up
top it's interesting that you don't show
up there but no worries I'll put it in a
gallery view welcome to Wade laughter
hahaha I got a you know a little pun
there for your name and of course Mike
West is in the room as well who just
showed up he is on mute so we won't be
able to hear him right away but jay-z
looks like he's just fishing or
something on that picture
yeah Johnny be there saying you need a
mic superior genetics loves the Hat this
was a gift from Ian Davidson apparently
they were the oh geez to do compost and
then Jonathan from
forever of flowering greenhouses that
came out with his version which was like
that and I have both of them so thank
you to Ian Davidson for these super nice
kick down on the compost pad it's funny
how many people think it says Compton
like it we've got four people wearing
hats today although one of us who's
wearing a hat is wearing a very
different type of hat and then Mike also
has his kind of on the side so I'm just
making like really obvious I like the
bar cat though bro
yeah one
mornin mornin
mute Johnny because he's talking to
himself and making noise and would it be
hashed Church if Johnny B wasn't making
random like sounds with his mind
bomb rip there we go let's start this
day off right I know I sent this out to
everyone so I'm hoping that there's not
people having problems with it we'll see
I invited some other folks but you know
what I'm liking the core group here guys
this is nice I don't see it playing on
YouTube it says waiting for bubble man's
world yeah same
it's playing for me I
was able to watch it on YouTube before I
hopped on yeah I mean if you want me to
send you the chat so you can see it I
don't have problem doing that it should
be
live on YouTube yep that is well but
he's probably looking at the old YouTube
link that I was trying to explain
earlier that we don't come in on that
link we heard a whole new one so most
most everyone's there it's definitely
playing live says oh oh gee brick so I'm
listening to I'm watching the the chat
hopefully some of the girls show up I
did invite Hillary black I invited Wendy
Turner I divided Debbie Goldsberry I
invited Callie Blackwell from the UK so
hopefully some of them show up as they
always have fun the last time I kind of
did a hash Church and I invited Callie
and Debbie
they both had showed up for the first
time and it didn't work if you guys
remember that we had
hey Mark shall dawn how are you buddy
hey what's happenin market area on what
level of extremely stoked were you at
when you saw the David truck that the
trucks and Trey last night then the
trucks no then the Trey and I can't even
pronounce the name of that berry dairy
truck two trucks two dusky bands right
oh no the other one Quang Quang Binh or
whatever because tre played well right
yeah last night they did they did very
well yeah well last night they did they
played with trucks band and he did Layla
and they did like Jimi Hendrix song
little wing yeah incredible incredible
weekend music there
honestly to the Warfield shows back like
however many years ago when when Phil
and friends with Trey and and Mike yeah
it was epic I mean I think
Derek is just next-level he's got you
know the Duane Allman thing just down
like playing slide dude watching Trey
watch Derek was like oh
yeah and Susan Tedeschi brings it I mean
she's like Bonnie Raitt she sings from
her soul it's just
good such good music
when I saw that
as her happy yeah and they had a loss
earlier in the year you know Oteil
brother Kofi burn bridge used to play
with them yeah the meskhi trucks band he
unfortunately passed away but um yeah I
see with the Tedeschi trucks band I've
seen them all play together yeah they
crushed it last night it was just it was
incredible I was like the one thing I
was like oh my god we watched it on
couch tour and we're like man we're only
like about four hours away we probably
should have went to that I mean it was
just really really incredible we've seen
both those bands play independently but
to see them mixed up like that two
nights no it was on point much welcome
to the young padawan Colton Turner in
the room in the house just got asked
actually do you ever invite patients
into hash Church and then but doing
welcome Colton I'm not sure if we can
hear you let's try something
we're all patient yeah yeah and he's not
muted he might have to come in and
restart a browser this is all new to us
Colton so have patience with us but we
definitely want to get this working
usually there's a I'm not sure where you
would go to find the Preferences I know
that you can oh it is on the bottom left
on the bottom left under mute if you
click over to the left there it gives
you
can select your camera as well what I
had done earlier Colton when I came in
is it it had chosen my microphone as I
seen hear me now I can hear you now
awesome that was just like a commercial
yeah
how are you doing buddy I'm doing good
how about you dude really good man
really good to have you here and I saw
that you and the fam went down to the
Seattle Hempfest and stopped at some
pretty cool little American what were
you guys at like Mount Rushmore or
something yeah we went to Mount Rushmore
we drove through the Badlands we had to
drive from Illinois to Seattle Slew we
took two days to drive all the way there
so we were able to see you know Mount
Rushmore we drove through the Badlands
but it was night so we didn't really get
to see it too much
but we also got to like go see the
geysers and we got to go see Old
Faithful and saw it go off
that's all I was really we've got the
drive through you know Yellowstone Park
so it was really fun and even when we
got to Seattle you know Hempfest was
just absolutely amazing everyone there
was absolutely incredible and I'm never
gonna forget it so that was your first
ham fest that was my first Hempfest so
tell us what it was like to be Colton
Turner at the Hempfest that you wrote
you roll in with your [ __ ] your with
your with your America family super
awesome crew and what people are like
holy [ __ ] I recognize that kid
well it was it was really great because
I had like I spoke every day during the
ahem fest so I was able to you know talk
to patients and talk to you know
everyone about my story and about other
people's stories and I was actually like
on uh on a panel you know talking about
you know why it's important for kids to
be able to use cannabis and why it can
help you know treat some of their
ailments and
you know it
part of me it was really important for
me because you know a lot of people you
know even in legal states are you know
also still having shovel you know
fighting the law you know just because
you legalize doesn't really mean that
you know the fight is over you know
that's just stepping into the ring
there's a lot of work left yeah like
just for example in Illinois
they accidentally banned RS they banned
smokeable for anyone under the age of 21
which they accidentally banned RSO along
with that because they classified that
or veeko oil because they classified
that as a smokeable so that way they can
get around the milligram limit and
so now that isn't also not allowed for
anyone under the age of 21 so that's
unacceptable
absolutely absolutely so I mean I think
it's absolutely unacceptable that the
milligram limit is that low in the first
place that we have to go around to
classifying things as smokeable just to
get around there hey honestly kudos to
you Colton you know I was you know I'm a
patient myself as goal for veteran I
found it very hard to go out there and
use my voice when I was in my early 20s
I got to give you mad props for being in
your teens and going out there and
representing like a madman your inner
strength your family support network
everything around you I just have to
give you major props for leading by
example and being the strong individual
that you are you've risen above your own
individual
condition are now using as a catalyst to
help others and that's a leader sir so I
just want to say thank you very much
you took the words right out of my mouth
I mean when did we meet Colton when he
was 14 or 15 years old maybe yeah you
know you've come a long way dude and
it's I think personally although I know
we've all done a lot of work in the
cannabis space but I've said it before
and I'll say it again like I really feel
the last leg of prohibition will be with
with children they're the ones that are
gonna be kind of up and coming you're no
longer a child now I saw you celebrated
your 18th birthday recently but you
definitely came into this as a child man
and you're very and you are still a
young man so it's super props these are
the people you're you're the people that
the next generation needs to hear from
not not some
not us old gray hairs so weighted way to
take the torch and and crush it it was
awesome to see on the stage in in
Seattle thank you so much you know I
definitely think that you know the Sigma
it a lot of the stigma is definitely
ending because you know before I started
cannabis you know the the talk about
marijuana was that it's bad and don't
use you know now people are actually
having conversations with their kids
about cannabis and there are you know
people who are actually educated in the
subject so people are getting the right
information and people are you know
using it making the right decisions
around cannabis and you know the kids
that are you know around today have so
much more information than the last
generation so just as time goes on those
kids are going to get smarter and
they're going to be more educated on
cannabis and eventually everyone's going
to have knowledge of it
well what's nice about it now is that
the kids are learning as before there
was no education for the kids there was
nothing there it was it's wrong it's
illegal don't touch it it's bad it's
gonna cause you psychosis
I grew up in the 80s were you know what
if you were smoking a joint you were
hiding you were putting mouse spray on
anywhere like making sure even smell
like weed so it's it's just fantastic to
see we are today in today's uh era that
you know the kids and when I was 16 are
being educated on cannabis are being
told any of this preventive medicine
there's all kinds of different things
and it's just great to see it kind of
like
speaking it like showing exactly how
cannabis save your life and like myself
I want to tell the world how much it
helped me just like yourself cool you
want to tell the world how much is
helping you and that's a thumbs up to it
I love that yeah the student has become
the teacher now
yeah well that's the best part about
cannabis is it it you becomes thing and
then you want to teach everybody and
that's what cannabis does you become the
teacher you become the professor and
over time you are the person that movies
looking at going wow look at how much
it's helped you and saved you and you're
able to touch the people that are
suffering from the same condition like I
know people then I look at them they're
like dude I miss like smoke one of these
are take some CBD or you know that's the
biggest thing is is it's there for us to
just take and learn them on
so many different levels - you know
there are the you know there's my level
I didn't come into it as a patient I
came into it as a recreational smoker I
was 14 years old puffs in the joint with
my buddy and we just grew to have that
experience with cannabis without really
the you know the more serious
kind of like you know the patient story
the Colton Turner's the John Breaux
fellows you know the at Tana fountains
that the patient stories are powerful
and those people when you have that
patient story well of course you're
gonna have to tell every single person
like I mean oh my goodness like you just
dealt with this element with this
particular herb in a way that is super
profound and now you're gonna hear
someone be like oh yeah I have that same
thing like but you could not tell that
person if your lips were stapled shut
you would have to tell them you would
make it a point of telling them and that
is that is very profound right like I
when I you know came out and said hey
I'm a Crohn's patient I use cannabis you
know I spoke out because Crohn's disease
is a very taboo disease people don't
like to talk about their poo so you know
it was really important for me to speak
out because I felt like you know there
was nobody else because when I first
started cannabis nobody was talking
about cannabis and Crohn's disease and
then after you know I started to get
more and more out there with my story
you know Crohn's patients would like
come out of the woodwork and go oh I've
been smoking for 10 years and you know
cannabis does great for me well where
were you why didn't you speak up
you know y'all said Colton well said
because I'll tell you when you came out
with your patient story it was a huge
relief to me because now all the people
with Crohn's that were coming to me I
was able to just direct over to you
because you actually you know I I don't
have Crohn's I didn't use cannabis for
Crohn's sure I've read stories and I've
heard information from people but you
have a first-hand experience you have
something that goes beyond
you know like well what about clinical
trials you know what about clay how do
we know it works what about clinical
trials you know tell that to Colton well
Colton is getting eight you've gone even
above that and actually set up a
foundation so there's a Colton Turner
foundation which I actually just sent a
friend of mine who has a young daughter
who has Crohn's and sent him your
directions so that he could talk to your
mom and talk to your support network and
have an understanding as a parent
because he's in an illegal state and
he's trying to figure out if he now has
to do what you did Colton and move to a
legal state with his and be the parent
and actually move his family there so he
can take care of you know his daughter
so that she can at least have a
semblance of a normal life via cannabis
she has she hasn't even tried cannabis
yet but he's exhausted everything going
the legal route that he needed access to
information thankfully Colton guru and
your parents have come up with your own
foundation so you can you know educate
people further so thanks again
absolutely because you know one of the
biggest issues in my opinion you know we
can talk about you know what kind of
what kind of method is the best way to
use cannabis or you know what strain you
know works better but we're not going to
know all of that without research
because really I think that we just hit
the tip of the iceberg when it comes to
this plant and I think that we need to
really learn more about it because we're
gonna be I feel like we're going to
over legislate it and make too many
regulations over it to the point where
we can't really use it to its full
potential so I think that well how can
we regulate something that we don't know
you know um also whenever I go to a
doctor or a politician or a lawyer or
anybody they the one thing that they
always tell me to completely discredit
my story is oh well there's no research
so I got tired and I said well I'm gonna
fund my own research
so that way we can actually prove that
cannabis does
help is is a safe natural alternative
well speaking of speaking of cannabis
research we look who just came into the
room we got dr. Ethan Rousseau popped in
with the dragonfly earth medicine Josh
and Kelly just came in so we should
welcome them to the show and Colin as
well just popped in from Massachusetts
from Happy Valley
everybody how you guys doing
nice to see you Colton so beautiful
seeing you here and talking about things
that are just really important we really
appreciate you on our side
totally
I love the sarcasm lady approaches it
with you know this sort of like you know
I'd rather be illegally alive than
legally dead like the first time I heard
that I was kinda like wow that's that's
kind of sharp I like it the first time
that I said it I was 14 which is you
know you'd think that you know an adult
would say that you know somebody who's
you know really cool and intimidating
and you know people who have like done
like done the time you know Colton you
did your time and it's okay you're a
hero you've lived through it you're a
survivor like the rest of us you're a
man now but you were a man surviving
through that entire time most kids never
have to live with the stigma much less
the trauma that you and your family had
to experience and that saying comes from
the heart from the soul of a survivor
mm-hmm at all right and your sarcasm you
know what I mean ours like to them to
the other side to the right like for us
we loved it but imagine being like in
law enforcement or something and hearing
that from a 14 year old boy
14 year old boy that had to move away
from his grandparents so that he could
know as a medicine
yeah I think you're mad cool dude thank
you so much
so we're all if it wasn't for you guys
then people who
people like me wouldn't be able to have
the information that they have today and
people wouldn't be as educated as they
you know as they would be today because
you guys are pushing the discussion you
guys are pushing the subject and I
really appreciate that and I know that
patients all around the world appreciate
it too we're more of shoving it than
pushing it
[Laughter]
we're done playing Sisyphus everybody
else can catch it going downhill man yes
right exactly yes someone on the cats
that sounds like something skunk man Sam
would say and it really does actually be
honest one of the big things pushing the
whole reality now is
big business big government taxing they
smell the money they walk it and I get
them who makes the money I just want
cannabis to be legal for every use by
everybody everywhere
true that you know Sam you've been
saying that for 20 years or more
and
finally came true about big business
they are driving it they're not paying
for as much research into cannabis for
beneficial reasons as he and I
that is incredible I mean if you go to
the icy RSS I mean Ethan you go to all
these events don't you think that you
can see this incredible growth in the
money that's coming into in for research
yeah I do that problem is a lot of it
it's not in the right direction let's
the situation in Canada you've got
something like 200 licensed producers
but the mean activity with mergers and
acquisitions rather than actual research
and that's true with two exceptions
additionally a lot of what their new
research is just observational studies
which
are not helpful from the standpoint of
really convincing the physicians or the
regulator's you know it it's nice
corroboration for those of us who
already understand the medical benefits
of cannabis but
you know for up to me a lot of this
money would be aimed in a different
direction that I think could advance the
cause much more effectively
like much more effectively than paying
like 147 million euros for the volcano
company or like 224 million foreign and
anita labs
like those are some pretty bit like I
was actually pretty surprised that some
of the Canadian mergers and acquisitions
that have occurred no more so than the
than the investment of constellation
putting five billion Canadian dollars in
I was like now they got to put some of
that into research that's a lot of money
it's also the same as any new big
business I mean when the automobile
industry started in America at the turn
of the century there were hundreds of
companies now
yeah it does seem to be the plan is to
try and be one of the big four the big
five or whatever the big number is going
to be for for the way it is for for so
many other things right it's the
financial posturing has begun
not worry about it you know they'll just
be folly you know here and then or maybe
someone say they had a question yes this
is wait laughter and dr. Russo would you
I imagine you saw the study that was
just published by Merrill and others in
Israel on whole plant preparations
decarboxylated and on decarboxylated and
their effects on cannabis
not sure maybe you could see what their
premise was of work
I'm not sure where the funding was I
think it was with Technion University
and they were looking at commercially
available products in the Israeli market
they got like a hundred and twenty
different products they tested all of
them for 89 cannabinoids there was
clearly a lot of money behind the study
but they picked 12 plant preparations
whole plant preparations with a whole
range of cannabinoids and tested them
for efficacy against I think it was 20
different cancer cell lines in vitro and
far and then of course they kept
controls of straight THC and straight
CBD and whatnot but they found some of
the more unusual cannabinoid mixes had
really profoundly good results at low
doses against a bunch of different cell
lines no I'm with you yeah a lot of this
work was done by David Maher II in
Israel at the Technion I
know cam I've seen and numerous times
and yeah this is a good advance but we
have to be careful in interpreting these
results what they're doing is testing
different concentrations of material
either hold cannabis extracts or
fractions there were specific molecules
in cell culture what we have to remember
is that a lot of substances will kill
cancer cells in cell culture but that
doesn't necessarily translate to do a an
effective treatment in humans in this
instance yes we know that cannabinoids
can kill cancer cells they promote
apoptosis
apoptosis is programmed cell death but
it sounds like a bad thing but cells are
supposed to have a normal lifespan what
happens in cancer is that they're not
heating the normal signals and they
become immortalized which is a way of
saying that they grow forever until
something stops up hopefully in medicine
but I think that that kind of research
can aim us towards what might be
effective agents to promote then through
selective breeding of various chemo bird
lines
but ultimately it's going to come down
to using these things in humans to see
if they really work well I was
fascinated by the study because it
seemed to suggest that the
the old-school traditional way of making
cannabis preparations actually
it was a study that confirmed our
experience which is the right
preparation seemed to have pretty
dramatic effect with some cancers a lot
of folks use really high doses but I
personally have seen some pretty good
results
at low doses in folks that don't really
like cannabis at all but have cancer and
it was it's just a nice confirmation of
what I personally have seen and many
other folks report that something's
going on with cannabis and cancer and
many other conditions and
we the problem is most of the research
in order to be randomized double-blind
etc et-cetera et-cetera you having to
use isolates and it misses the whole
picture of what the plant can do for us
that's what I was like I'm yeah that's
all I got that kind of sounds maybe even
if you agree with this like there's the
isolating of cannabinoids and isolating
of you know medicine for pharmaceutical
izing something and it has its
limitations and then you know petri dish
and each row
testing has its limitations and really
seems to keep coming back to that
whole plant medicine I mean that their
reaction with our neurological system
being you know it seems to be
I say regardless of what you choose make
it all available yeah because I don't
want my choice to hinder your choice and
also welcome me you weren't in the
picture earlier right now I want to say
you guys do look like an oil painting
and I think so much take a screen shot
and oil paint that picture right there
at the DM pier camera because that's uh
that's pretty amazing I'll second that
motion am I wrong
I'll let her explain
Bionic really yeah I
don't on my shelf
[Music]
people hear me yes John but
what were you gonna say John I'm sorry
he just said can people hear me
[Laughter]
thank you all for the great work that
you're doing you know I live in Austin
Texas where cannabis
basically illegal
you have a fairly wimpy CBD law that
serves a very small percentage of the
population
it's
glorified
warehouse hemp law really
you know while it's super frustrating
that we aren't making more progress in
my state we're making progress and it's
wonderful to see that through programs
like this and the work that all of us
are doing collectively we are making
progress even though it seems painfully
slow for us it is progress and what's
super interesting to me at the moment is
the fact that the general public is
finally catching up to where all of us
are the problem seems to be that
government isn't and you know I think
that they're slowly getting there and as
they sort of come on board with seeing
this is the truth medicine and that it's
very safe and effective first with
medicine hopefully we'll start to see
better laws around the world that
reflect that even though it's painful
and I think that all of us have to
continue to stay the course and keep
talking about it if Thanks when day is
clean when do you think things will
happen at the UN level we've seen the
World Health Organization and others
actually
start to go for cannabis medicine but we
thought of a potential vote was going to
happen in the spring or potentially in
the summer but that has not yet arrived
and now we're looking to 2020 at this
time what can the individual watching
here do to put pressure on so that we
can see the results in the end
basically because of the work the World
Health Organization they really should
have to make a vote this next winter
the trouble is there's always someone
willing to throw a wrench in the gears
and it looks like the Russians are
opposed
and it may be that they'll find a way to
put this off yet again but the
foundation is there they've already
recommended that that cannabidiol BD
schedule
there there be rescheduling of other
forms of cannabis and THC we'll have to
see I think that at whatever level
people need to pressure their
politicians particularly on a federal
level to try and get this resolved
can you understand that
ultimately I think it's economics money
is what talks
convince people that there's money to be
made through cannabis commerce and that
the prison industrial complex is not a
benefit to society then there may be
changes
yeah ain't that the truth right there I
have a question about Parkinson's for
dr. Ethan Rousseau if I could ask the
question here Marcus why not sure so
it's pleasure asking this question Ethan
I
had a family member my father's had
Parkinson's for 16 years today and you
know we found a regiment of
THC and CBD
slightly not quite a one-to-one with
specific terpenes that have helped his
neurological being and I wanted to know
if you'd had had ever seen any profound
effects in your time with Parkinson's
and cannabinoid based therapies I know
as our family it's been extremely
confusing and it's something that has
really been a guiding light for us so I
just wanted to simply ask the question
and see what your thoughts were yeah
yeah it's a good question and it's a
tough area it's not like some of the
other condition we rapidly can see a
benefit
various preparations have been tried in
Parkinson's and with mixed results my
feeling is that most often a small
amount of teets gonna be helpful with a
larger amount of CBD
actually the best results that we know
of to date have come in an entirely
different form in
about 15 years ago there was a very good
survey study that came out of the Czech
Republic on bender OVA
what happened there was there was a
fellow that was eating what appeared to
be raw cannabis um I honestly don't know
there is THC predominant or hemp oh that
would be CBB predominant THC predominant
and over the course of a long period of
time he improved his symptoms this
fellow was on check TV their equivalent
of 60 minutes and apparently a lot of
people started doing this we had some
200 odd patients that had done this and
what the findings were that almost all
aspects would improve but after
prolonged interval that people were
giving their best results after three
months of using raw cannabis
ingested rather than I'm healed
so what that suggests to me is probably
it was either a combination of TCA
possibly with CBD a but again something
is happening very slowly here so it's
quite different to someone treating
their pain acutely or treating their
spasticity acutely I unfortunately there
hasn't been real follow-up on that but
um like anything else but particularly
with Parkinson's
experimentation is going to be needed
and I would really wonder about
cannabinoid acids on against
TB G a and C right well I've gone
through hundreds of cultivars literally
and what I found is after a while
the effects of those said cultivars or
strains if you will start to taper off
and I have to to start looking again and
we keep trying and we keep trying
it's been a vicious cycle but but to
your point we have noticed that in acid
form THC a is more profound for him than
if we do carboxylate it so she it's just
the way he works his body responds
better to that for some reason so really
interesting and really solidifies a lot
of things we've been doing so thank you
very much for sharing that
dietary or
microbiome and endocannabinoid tone
building
supplementation program well that's a
good question I mean I hate my feeling
is that so many of the disorders we're
seeing in modern society are related to
inflammatory and autoimmune processes we
know that in the 21st century these
things are really whereas in the 19th
century they were exceptionally rare and
the difference is our diets
I'm a big proponent of
prebiotics and probiotics
getting that gut balance in my feeling
is that the gut microbiome is the master
regulator of the endocannabinoids system
so you can treat things that way
and
supplement with cannabinoids
subsequently and I think between the two
that we've got possible effective
treatments for a lot of manziel's and
I'm taking medicinal mushrooms fit in
there too as well with their
neurological aid with lion's mane and
the other nootropic regenerative so
you just said nootropics at the exact
same time I did but I was muted
it was awesome to hear your voice come
out of my
that was a trail
yeah cosmic I like it I like it you know
it's again we there's a lot of toxins in
this world you know nowadays and you
know they finding
10,000 plastic particles and one liter
of snow and in the Arctic right now and
you know there's just a lot of overload
in our body so you know even things like
activated charcoal you know it's not a
cannabis thing but it's a way of
detoxing our system and helping our
microbiome and I think it's a
combination of cannabinoids and turbines
but it's also a combination of other
herbal properties and I think it's just
touched on something that I think is
really important as well as
detoxification and I think that you know
we're always talking about what kind of
we can add to our body to help boost our
immune system and I think also it's
important to start looking at how we can
detoxify you know ourselves our
intestinal system
so that these other treatments that come
after that work better cleanser
Bashar I just wanted to add that boots
Parkinson's also the medication you take
I forget what it's called l-dopa or
whatever it causes severe nausea in some
patients and
that is a real problem and cannabis can
help with severe nausea
yeah sure
yeah you know so much for my father he
was a 101st airborne first the 506 he
was directly involved in Vietnam and out
on recon by himself with two other
gentlemen that were a sharpshooter and
the other guy was dismantling bombs so
they would just get rained on with deep
literally he would tell stories of just
walking through the jungle and all of a
sudden
boom and just get nailed with just this
toxic stuff and you know it's it's an
it's insane to me that it took so long
for his body to to basically was
spending all this stuff off for so long
and then it just it just overcame his
neurological being in the self and it
really took took our family for a storm
and it was very confusing every no one
wanted to admit that he had it no
doctors wanted to sign him off as that
and we were just left confused so it's
it's very interesting that is a question
how you taking
yeah I'm asking are you taking any amino
acids by any chance along with his
cavities he's doing like tyrosine or
as well
because I take a lot of amino acids and
of we there was a paper why amino acids
work that I worked on with
years ago and I just looked it up and it
looks on the carpet in Thailand it says
what we were just researching
falen that's par for the course the VA
will deny and
yeah they basically give some of the
worst health care possible that's why I
had my own health care because they told
me the blisters on my feet for nine
years were all in my head and all kinds
of other problems and it wasn't until
five years down the line that a brave
doctor actually told me that they were
told to lie to us and then two years
later I got a nine-page breakdown of
everything I was actually exposed to due
to over running positions and having all
these bunkers blown up around us so it's
actually modus operandi for the VA to
deny etc that's why it is diligent upon
you and your family to throw it back in
their face and be blunt honest and
capture as much as your anger to them as
possible and vitriol they did yes I mean
I'm in Philadelphia often I I do work
with the University of Pennsylvania
which is you know there's some smart
people and and great people over there
however it is still confusing so it's uh
it's nice to hear a lot of this stuff
from you all so it really helps better
understand we make copies of everything
they're gonna lose your paperwork make
sure you have your own copies I have had
my paperwork loss from da V American
Legion VFW it's it took me four or five
different filings just to get my Gulf
War Syndrome stuff
denial is always the thing so it's again
upon you and your family to be as
educated and throw it back in their face
as possible because majority of these
doctors remember eighty percent of
physicians go through the VA system
because it's immediate residency so you
get the good the bad and the ugly and
I've had more than my share of ugly but
there's some good ones out there don't
get me wrong redness I choose to use
regular physicians in the regular world
which is why I have a business and
insurance and I cover my insurance as
well as you know most of my employers as
well because health care in America
still sucks and it should be a right but
we still have to take care of our own no
don't no don't absolutely which is kind
of empowering me you know but not but
you know it kids using you know you kind
of like oh I can't rely on the system
sometimes I find here in Canada you
people rely on the system so much that
they turn off their self-reliance button
you know and they're like oh I don't
have to go to the top you know so I mean
that I'm not saying that you know
definitely medical cares is the way to
go but also just continue learning like
we're doing is really where we're gonna
in pain no doubt man oh yeah question
what is your dad's intake method
his delivery for cannabis is that what
you're asking uh so I make pills i well
now he buys them but we we started where
I would make pills for him and also
tinctures so that's really the delivery
method of his his preferred delivery
method
so we would do that three times a day
two to three times a day that's where we
started out and now we're just down to
once a day and
that's it that that was the
way that we found was the best way for
him to
in taken ingest cannabis for him so
that's that's what we we chose to do
thank you
so
they have
they were wildly out of control
you know at one point and now they are
are controlled and he's actually going
on a trip to Europe and he's feeling
like he's gonna go to Amsterdam he's
going to to Spain
so he's you know he's working out three
times a week which is great I'm really
on him about what she should be doing to
be proactive and it's it's a thing where
it's really it's tough because you want
to be you want to have all this energy
and you want him to have all this
excitement they that I share and having
all this belief and he it just he
doesn't have it because it's it's this
the this the disease it's it's causing
him to feel all these things from the
question all the way to lack of
motivation and all these things that you
have to remind him like hey you're here
we have a you know I'm here with you you
know you want to be here with us right I
want to be here with you and those are
the things that that allow him to
overcome those hard hard tasks so to
speak so he's you know three times a
week he gets out
and he walks every day which is great so
you know obviously some days are better
than others it's just the way that it's
it it's built the disease is really its
own it has its own mind it's really
fascinating how with just when you think
you got it you're like yeah I got this
it totally changes and morphs and and
does its thing on you and and it really
it's it's absolutely mind-bending I mean
it's it's it's really fascinating but it
makes me work harder it makes me it's
why I'm in mass and why I'm around all
these these universities and and minds
that I can collaborate with to try to
help better understand not only what I'm
going through but what they're trying to
do with cannabinoid research so we can
all together find a mote profound
understanding for to make a more
informative choice so that's something I
struggle with all the time but yeah the
the delivery method has been been
tinctures and and I think it's really
and and pills and those are the two
right now that we found really helpful
that's really fabulous you know we make
a medicinal mushroom hemp oil
combination oil and it's something
that's you know not really very common
and suddenly be used for long and I
would really love to sends one to you if
you're interested he can give it a try
it has has the lion's mane and the red
belted Konkan and chaga and a lot of the
other medicinal mushrooms and we just
feel very inspired with the mushroom
realm you know as much as the cannabis
and to bring them together I think you
know it sometimes it's just the fusion
and you don't know what it is but anyway
yeah we just be willing to love wood
what are the active ingredients in those
mushrooms I'm just curious it's
obviously not so Simon is it
so we're really would love for it to be
psilocybin but we're waiting yeah so we
are really actually really actively
looking for you know being able to
define exactly what's in it but so what
you know it's the polysaccharides and
the beta gluten
so it's a water-soluble extract from the
friends of mushroom oil it's an oil ex
trail oil
the mushrooms are steam extracted and
then it goes into a liquid extraction oh
cool we also use a combination of fungi
we use live
poly pores from the tree as well as dual
extracted Chagas and and different
[Music]
well in in the name of science guys
let's do a little analytical chemistry
and figure out what are the molecules in
there they're they're aromatic molecules
the the ones from lion's mane are known
as Harrison owns and Erina Singh's
diterpene compounds and they spur
production of ngf and nerve cells this
is what I know that's helping to
maintain cholinergic system and for
brain function but that's just me and
there's all sorts of nootropics and Paul
stam enormous amount of information on
these mushrooms on on his on so they're
not alkaloids right they're not the
compounds are alkaloids they're terpenes
well in this particular instance the bio
actives in Lions Mane's but there's a
whole bunch of nootropic mushrooms like
he just mentioned Chagga which is
another one you know this there's a
there's a schwack of them memory and
nerve support so we
know pulsed and nourish leading into it
it's the real deal
what's that Kelly um I was just saying
mark we were talking to you a little bit
earlier and we did want to you know get
to the bottom of this we use you know
we've never really separated cannabis
and mycology in medicine always mixed
the two and had tremendous results from
the patients who have been taking it but
really there's so much unknown because
we weren't able to test it in a regular
testing facility because it also had
cannabis in it so now we have this
ability to move forward and really find
out what is in this medicine that's been
working so well for people yeah I mean
now that there's plenty of labs around
that can do cannabis testing a lot of
them do have the analytical
instrumentation to figure out what some
of these other minor compounds might be
that is in there I was reading last week
and a week before the the flavonoids are
800 times more stronger than aspirin and
Tylenol the sir I think that researchers
just came up with there was a big
article on it I'd like to find it again
day but it read on
all right beautiful people I love you I
have to head out I want to say a happy
belated birthday d 4/20 as well as
congrats on your business
bubbleman and Ethan risotto thank you
for coming in man many blessings Colton
everybody I think thank you very much
I'm off I'm celebrating my 50th this
week as well so
Darrin you haven't said it for yeah
today yeah he said it three minutes ago
yeah you know what I will say it again
it was just such good conversation how
do I interrupt that [ __ ] honestly
you know so I'll give it I'll give it a
good one here
bong real oh and we got a we got a this
is in honor of Brandon vigil
that he's a big fan and if he could get
a shout out it would make his day and
I'm thinking well that's gonna make his
day then shout out to Brandon Bissell
hey bong rip Brandon let's do this let's
do it put a brand invisible I
yeah I'm only gonna do a two-hour hash
Church today so we got another hour left
of dialogue and
happy to take it in whatever direction
that it goes in just happen how can you
be joining on the Sunday morning with
with all of you wonderful people again
it's been it's been too long
could could I um try to steer this in a
little direction that's kind of off
topic what we're talking about before
but I would really like what would done
what would be the easy well not easy
start but how would a guy like myself
who hasn't done the living soil before
what would I get started on this
getting started on learning living soils
well you know that we did do a good hash
search on soils
and if you look back and resource that
it has a lot of information on it and
there are people that analyze soils like
Leighton Morrison and Scott Scott
granola online and there are people that
do help people with living soil systems
you can look them up but we also work
with people you can hit us up I think
you know we might be seeing you soon
there I wouldn't say that there's like a
book out there that says something on
living soils and this is exactly how to
do it I think it's more linking up with
farms and that they're doing the work
and doing it testing along with their
soils well what falls books are worth
checking out though his teaming books
Jeff Lowe and Phillips I was teaming
with microbes and I'm teaming with fungi
and teeming with nutrients when and all
of those are incredible scientific tools
another one new one by Michael Phillips
is really great on soil even I found it
a little technical but if you understand
very detailed it's not specific to
cannibals but it'll give you all the
background information that you need and
I think if we start transitioning the
mind work and what we've been already
taught by big AG is that you know it's
the soil that's feeding the plants
rather than the nutrients that you're
giving so everything that you're putting
into your soil you have to wonder how is
it affecting your soil what is your soil
eating and then all of the exudates from
the microbiology within the soil then
transfer over to the feeding of the
plant so just transferring your mind
over to let the soil feed the plant and
you're feeding the soil that's a super
helpful way to look at it and what kind
of things in nature like soil what kind
of things in nature are digesting soil
very rapidly and that's you know carbon
that's already happening so if we're
just transitioning our mind it's almost
like once you start getting into the
microbiology then the microbiology takes
over the education in your mind and then
you're actually being educated by the
microbiology it's the Josh seriously
just come into the room I know
hey George what your ears burning did
my headphones to work but I'm having
difficulties it's all good I think this
platform it works really good even
without headphones but seriously Darrin
was just like okay I got a question I
want to steer this in a different
direction how do I learn about living
soils and then literally they started
talking and I was just kind of looking
around then I looked down and I'm like
come into the room I was trippy welcome
I'm yours too because I kind of want to
start doing the same thing
so we're talking about living soil
you know living soils is is a term that
that describes an action and the action
of a living soil is decomposing and when
soil is decomposing it's advancing the
microbiology and it's advancing the
nutrients that's going in the roots so
traditionally in cannabis growing a lot
of people bought soil that was finished
you know it had this may be peat moss or
coca-cola and it was this finished
cooked down soil with all the nutrients
in it and you bought this finished soil
and then you added teased to it
throughout the cycle but and it wasn't
really alive in the same way so what
we're learning now with living soils is
using you know combinations of raw
materials in the beginning in the making
of the soil like different now Alfa's
and haze and and different carbon
sources along with certain parts of
biochar which is sort of a a charcoal in
the soil which allows microorganisms to
live but it's also somewhat of a filter
and then we you add in a nice mulch or
top layer to the soil to continue the
feeding of the microbiology and then you
can use you know fermented plant teas
really really easy from there every once
in a while every couple weeks or
whatever it is to add to your soil so
adding the and making a really rich soil
is is the really ticket and I think that
it's a lot like you know when you invite
friends over to dinners you usually
write them and say hey what are your
dietary restriction
what is it that my friends like to eat
it's really the same what kind of fungi
do you want in your soil and then you
ask the question oh well what is that
fungi want to eat so if you're going to
be inviting in all these different
beneficial microbiology they have to be
in in order to colonize they have to be
focused on which I like to eat in order
to stick around and colonize which will
bring more chirping some work can happen
the one thing that I sure noticed about
the stuff that was grown in living soil
was the taste and
the buzz the smell like the stuff and I
sit in my room the other day doing my
measurements on this and I don't do the
proper measurements as they say on the
label I do my own measurements as I feel
that the plants can take with my
nutrient levels and that sort of stuff
so I do my own little tweaking and that
not is like basically we can teach a
monkey to do that and he can run the
show no problem if that's what we're
doing and you know it's really nice to
open everything like that but then
there's that living soil where I tasted
in it and was just what the hell is that
that is unbelievable and like you can
almost taste the Earth that it's grown
in as well and and then the concentrates
from it to mind-blowing earth-moving
life-changing type situation and then
I'm like whoa you know I'm a pretty good
grower I guess with with with doing
measurements and pH of water and stuff
good for me but if I could take those
strains that I've the cultivars that I
have and make them better and and how
they are right now and they could be
better because that living soil next I
need to learn it I need to
one thing I wanted to bring up I get a
lot a lot of indoor growers talking to
me and asking questions on how to do you
know living soil beds indoors and we've
kind of all seen the model on Instagram
where it's you know fabric pots you know
8 8 12 inches deep you know these beds
and
as as I've just been learning and able
to talk with different folks and
experience growing outdoors and in a
greenhouse that is connected to the soil
you know because I used to do this
method for about 10 years and learning
with Leighton is is we've realized that
if you're not connected to the earth you
have problems number one you know
there's there's
electrical issues you know you know I
physically grounded to the earth but
also you know a lot of people miss the
mulch layer and Josh and Kelly you know
the way they do it they do lots of these
layers and the mulch is kind of like a
moisture cap
and it holds all the moisture in and
regulates the moisture and then the
other thing we're really getting into is
you know instead of just having this 12
inch of layer of what we're calling the
organic horizon you know that people are
making up this the peat Mik mixture you
know third Peter third aeration a third
compost that's really an organic horizon
in in a natural Earth's setting and
we're missing the a horizon the alluvial
layer that is made up of sand silt and
clay and the importance of that is it's
doing the same thing it's balancing the
moisture throughout so when you you
water you don't get all this runoff you
get this this balance of you know
moisture in the bed and that's where
we're seeing like really long-term
success in a Norn indoor platform
because then once you establish the
right biology you know vehicle a good
compost tea
those microbes will actually start
harvesting the nutrients from that
alluvial layer the sand silt and clay
and you won't need to be top dressing
after after a period you know and I just
want to kind of throw that into this
discussion I don't know you know if you
Josh and Kelly if you've experienced or
that any of that work with when you
consult with indoor grows but just
something we're seeing hang alluvial for
one that's a fun word
but yeah I mean you know having those
are essentially trace minerals too you
know and when it comes into sand and it
comes into clay layers and volcanic you
know ash layers and stuff like that and
I think that is really smart I think
that there's been like the I
was also another teaching was having the
soil drain out really fast you know and
then REE you know and then read aerate
it which is kind of almost like flood
and drain a little bit more so I think
you're you're totally right and it's
being able to contain the moisture keeps
the life alive otherwise the
microbiology has to sort of die out and
then regrow and then I think you get
more supple trichomes and in the end and
I think that's what you're seeing Darren
and and maybe in Mike and you know the
extract artists that are taking the
extraction from that you know healthy
sphere and and also I think that you
know you were saying that you're getting
a better flavor and taste when you put a
plant in its natural environment because
plants now environment is soil then
you're gonna bring out the ultimate
potential at that particular strain and
what we've seen is that we've been able
to take really old strains that have
been played out for lack of better term
and be able to put them in our deep rich
soil beds for a whole season and totally
regenerate that plant there's a lot of
regeneration talk with tissue culture
and I would like to really put in the
Hat regeneration of these strains
through deep soil living soil techniques
as well
yeah I would just add that I've seen
this work
these guys have documentation of plants
that are approaching three meters in
height now that were this high six weeks
ago just through these techniques and
it's just with water good soil and water
and a lot of sunshine and a lot of the
big Lisa you know we had that big leaf
picture on there I mean we have lots of
plants with big Leafs like that and
anyway it's and it's not strain
dependent so you know I really want to
encourage people that have a played-out
strain that they've really loved and
they've held on to for a whole long time
you know give it to somebody else or
start doing living soil techniques on
their own to rejuvenate this strain and
I think that that's going to be really
helpful in the industry into the future
I'd also add that when it when you carry
that out living soils give a structure
to the trichome that allows your the
plant better afterwards and it gives a
longevity to the Civic flowers there's a
you know another thing thanks John we
have you know this thing where you you
know you have to sell your your flowers
within two weeks of harvesting it you
know a lot of times a lot of people in
your there's a lot of people up here in
British Columbia and stuff they'll be
like two weeks later it's on the market
but you know you lose out on curing your
cannabinoids and we were talking about
this the other night and just CDN or
something newer cannabinoid that can
happen after time you know one year in
two years so I think that living soils
also allows you to have better medicine
and you can cure a longer which allows
you do different things with your
medicine and hopefully people like
Colton or other you know patients can
get different kinds of cures out of it
so about living soil is you have the
opportunity to control what things you
are actually in your soil and by finding
the inputs that you need on your
property
it's the biology that works on your
property and you buy by concentrating
and enhancing it in your soil you start
one not only increasing the quality of
the material you're producing but you
decrease your costs you're not having to
go buy things and meantime every time
you go and buy something you're trusting
that what the bag or bag or box or
whatever that packaging is is actually
what is in there what it says is
actually what's in the bag and nothing
else is in that bag all of that's a
trust that I don't know if especially if
you're making something you know if
you're growing your own or doing for
commercial production
if you want the highest quality you need
to know what's in the soil because it's
a bio accumulator it'll pull out
whatever it needs and wants in the soil
I'm not I love the idea of
live soil and water
it just really it's it's what it's what
nature does
and
and what's true is most soils are not
live anymore they've been killed off
with too many different things
everything from glyphosate to
yeah
it just seems really important to
recognize that especially for anyone
that's going to work with cannabis by
reducing your costs and increasing your
quality regenerative practices and
living soil is the way to go you're
going to get the best medicine at the
best result and meantime it's a form of
environmental stewardship because the
soil is the foundation of everything it
goes on when we are killing off our
soils all over the world we're killing
off our opportunity to survive in the in
the cold climate thing that's going on
which is a whole conversation I don't
even want to start but we all know
what's happening there and yes
regenerative agriculture and practices
is a way of healing your own little
garden and then maybe your community and
maybe someday our world mm-hmm no of
course it's amazing it's you know when
when Canadians accidentally discovered
that heme removes radioactive
nucleotides out of the soil when Joe
Strobel a tobacco farmer got the first
hemp license in Canada and grew hid grew
a crop and then of course because he's a
tobacco farmer he's actively spraying
radium-226 on his field and so they have
to monitor the radioactivity levels of
this of the soil and the soil was too
low after hemp and they were just like
what the heck and tested the hemp and
we're kind of like oh geez this has
actually been pulled into this plant
over here that's how that's how the
Chernobyl hemp growing project got
started but you know I like the way
Wayde put that you know you know it's a
good it's a good thing you see someone
was telling me yesterday in Kentucky all
these tobacco plots want to grow
cannabis now and I'm like well they're
gonna be growing like many many seasons
of just remediate of crops because the
soils in those tobacco regions are so
beyond contaminated with like really
really like forget about David and
Michael butanol and these guys are
taking it to a whole other level where
you have to wear full hazmat suits to to
spray that [ __ ] on the plants it's
frightening marcus do they um
take that material and combust it or
incinerate it or do they put it back
into the soil and remediate it through
time no no definitely back in the day
originally there was two methods there
was the archaic burning and classifying
of the ash and then there was the
Russian Elektron
scientist who was using electron
clusters to manipulate and basically
take apart radioactive molecules
they Reax tracked it that's valuable huh
I think that that would have to be
Neutron right if you're doing radio
chemistry you're dealing with neutrons
you're not doing necessarily with
electrons I'm not a radio chemist yeah
the hemp that they grew in Chernobyl
they just made it in a hempcrete just to
encase it but if they did save some of
it and look at it was sure a fair amount
of it found its way in the Eastern
Europe so was the company that did that
I don't know if you knew that but that
was our our company did that
all right I was gonna say I wouldn't be
surprised if any of that hemp was
actually used somewhere in Eastern
Europe for CBD oil production yeah it's
sold at gas stations in Florida now for
in pens
it's really all he bucks a pen happy B
forget Florida even in cannabis on
friendly states like Illinois and
Indiana
yeah you could the truck stop two bucks
the pen
it was very interesting Wow yeah so the
state trooper that pulls you over and
bust you for cannabis is all jacked up
on CBD from the gas station
I'll take that
radioactive CBD though wolf I don't know
they don't know what to do with it it's
uh it's kinda humorous like I have a
hemp license an ax and a th cannabis you
know recreational license and my
neighbor finally complained and my
enforcement officer for the RAC came not
to visit and he's like hey man how do
you tell the difference I was like you
don't do it until you test them you know
and brew that true that it's the same
plant oh yeah I mean that's what I you
know I'm ten explaining it to him and
he's just like going well how do we
regulate this when someone's driving
down the road and they got a bag full of
CBD buds you know and I'm like you don't
do it it's a plant like we're the way
we're doing it now doesn't make any
sense we got to go back to letting it be
a plant and and you know I actually am
very in in some twisted way I'm very
thankful to you know the AG companies
Monsanto and them for creating such
such freedoms it for it for farmers and
in the may and you know the us we have a
lot of freedoms and so under the hemp
bill we don't have to do any of the
regulatory [ __ ] that I've had to do
on the on the REC side and it's it's
amazing you know and so are they
worth noting Wade when you created the
Harlequin that you were grounding your
pots at the time is that correct with
copper wire into the grounds uh
yes yes that's true I was growing
indoors in those days and
all of the plants were in
shallow ten gallon pots that and were
bone side and whatnot I've done a lot of
work on making sure the water and the
soil they were in and the what nutrients
I was given them were things I liked and
had the best lighting I could find on
and on and on but in sitting with them
one evening asking them why they were
not I could tell it wasn't there they
weren't totally happy and they and what
I heard was they were lonely and I had
to think about what that meant and and
so I realized that plants evolved in the
ground and so I had a copper water pipe
in the room that I had installed and
knew it was good to ground and so I
hooked up some row max10 three so four
connectors put them into a grounding bar
that I strapped to the copper pipe and
then put the other into the romex into
four of the first seven plants that
became Harlequin it's part of how
Harlequin got the name it has
because the four plants that got ground
were identical to three other plants
that didn't get ground that had the
identical environmental conditions and
the four that had ground not only grew
much quicker had bigger leaves there
flowers two weeks into flowering were
fifty percent larger and at eight weeks
into flowering the plants that had
ground had four or five different colors
vegetation red purple orange a little
bit of green a little bit of yellow but
just they were fluorescent coloration in
this whole room of green plants and I
realized that yeah plants need ground so
after that I got busy running a bunch of
wires that were not connected to any
form of electricity other than the six
to seven cycles a second that the earth
actually produces that we call ground
and
and now working outdoors where I can put
plants in the ground you don't have to
do wires you don't have to do anything
and I really think it's a huge part of
the living soil thing when everything
else is right in your indoor room if you
haven't provided them a connection to
the earth give them earth do it a few at
a time just to check out to see how it
works I think you'll be amazed at the
difference in the sults you see the
plants love being in connection with the
mother if you will
you know neasha well I was just gonna
say that actually visited being here
with Josh and Kelly this is the first
time that I have actually toured an
outdoor grow and I have to tell you that
what they're doing is so phenomenal and
relieved when Ethan and I drove up it
was immediately obvious that this place
was so is so alive and producing
extraordinary medicine I think it makes
a tremendous difference not only for all
of us but most especially for those who
are trying to restore their bodies with
cannabis and
you know I would say for anybody that is
out there thinking about growing
cannabis please look at what Josh and
Kelly and all the other regenerative
farmers are doing because you know the
the soil I would argue is really our
greatest resource some people would
argue the point that water is but I
think that the soil is far more
important because if you don't have
living soil you can't use your water
properly and then you can lose nutrients
that go into the rivers and they can
contaminate waterways and you work with
you you know land Trust's and different
things in the world and so that's
something you're really interested in
right yeah it's been 10 years working in
the land trust community in Texas and
you know with without
well-managed soil even no matter what
we're talking about whether it's growing
medicine or food or just open pasture
the land should have the capacity to
capture and clean our water supply just
for cannabis users and growers but for
everyone and so healthy having healthy
soil is really kind of a gift to the
world that we can all participate in and
I think that it's interesting too if you
really look at what the main number one
of nature it's making soil that's
nature's number one job yeah and and
without
healthy soil we don't have clean water
in to drink mm-hmm and then with without
the healthy soil we don't have the
healthy microbiology that comes from the
soil to help boost our own microbiome
yep I would just add a last minute
statement to that which is hemp farming
is a really big deal right now and it's
alarming to me and it looks to me like
an environmental disaster is happening
with all of the plastic mulch please
stop using plastic mulch it's not okay
it's not biodegradable and I don't know
of a 100% plant-based plastic and and
even if there was a hundred percent
plant-based plastic I still wouldn't use
it because hey and and cover cropping is
essential to a regenerative hemp farm if
you have the ability to grow a cover
crop over the winter that's chest-high
and then you till in that whole thing
along with another batch of cover crop
and then mound that up you're having all
this microbiology being created with the
cover crop and then you layer in huge
amounts of hay and don't tell me it's
too much work because it's what you have
to do so maybe don't do twenty acres do
five and do it right and go get your
uncle Ted and all the other guys to go
through five acres to and just do it
right so they you're building your soil
over the course of the year and you're
creating it so I said aphids because
they're around and you can't control
aphids very well and people are realized
in that everywhere right now so
pollinators can take care of very well
wasps and different things so creating
habitat within your pharmacist seneschal
and living soils living soil
regenerative hem farms plastic mulch
environmental disaster you heard it here
for the first time on hash Church you
just do it right the title of the
forthcoming book on living soil from
dragonfly earth medicine we're not
impressed with all your acreage we're
impressed with the quality of what you
come out with
amen to that as honestly I'm constantly
having conversations with people all
over the world and they're like yeah
we're we're looking at ten thousand
acres in Manitoba we're doing 7700
hectares in in Columbia and I'm like I'm
like do you understand how much biomass
can be growing on an acre like with
cannabis you know like if you ship the
bed a couple thousand pounds but if you
do pretty good you're gonna probably get
four thousand pounds off an acre I mean
seven thousand hectares I did the math
for this guy without even multiplying
his field by four because he's easily
gonna get four crops and a yield and in
a year in columbia but just with one
year on this guy seventy seven hundred
hectares it ended up being like sixty
million pounds of biomass and if he was
able to extract a hundred thousand
pounds of that biomass a day which let's
be honest very few ER anywhere near that
it was gonna take him nine point seven
years to extract his first crop if he
only grew one crop so I know like I
thought in Switzerland in 2000 2001
everyone got greedy they start planting
big acreages and all the herb rotted in
barns there's nowhere that they didn't
understand the SOPs of cutting that much
cannabis down and curing it and you know
having a space to properly dry it in and
know anything enough to field just hang
it off the field
yeah I saw that in Kentucky in two
thousand nine and ten where I went out
to to a massive I mean six hundred acres
and for two thousand nine ten in the
United States owes a lot and I'd you
know they were just like how do we get
this off the field and you know we had
to we I had to design this this crazy
system for him and it was really
interesting and now fast forward today
there's I'm a part of the small farmers
Network in in New York State and it's
all organic and we're we're we're
forging and finding everything on the
land to the crops and it's just a
completely different way of doing things
and it's it's sustainable it's it's a
it's a much nicer way to be entire
shopping and bucking right on the field
like you're out in the field shucking
and bucking yeah yeah
that's what the Amish are doing here in
Pennsylvania that's very manual I can't
wait to see it
happen in just a few weeks here all the
Amish farms around us or growing have
and
it's just it's it's great if you ask me
I don't know I mean you were mentioning
the use of plastic mulch I know the
Amish don't use any mulch at all they do
cover crops and they do certainly rotate
their fields but I don't think there's
use of plastic mulch at all and I
believe it's all certified as organic
too so I can't wait to watch the Amish
do their hemp harvesters sure definitely
the exception I think he's talking about
like everyone else yeah
strawberries but nobody grows among
straw they all grow them underneath
black mulch
plastic mulch
and they taste like wood
well it depends I mean you can get that
strawberries grown that way but in
general I lead towards your direction
well one of all marks of the Amish is
that they do peacefully coexist in
today's a Greek ultra production and do
have a significant agricultural output
at least in this area of Pennsylvania
and certainly in other areas of the
country so be that as it may yeah
they're different and they have
different farming methods they're here
and they're producing and I think
they're gonna have a profound impact on
the hemp supply at least this season
that we hadn't seen in previous seasons
to your point they're very advanced in
farming I grew up around Amish and I've
learned quite a lot as a young guy
working on Armus farms being around it
and their varying too and they have a
much different head on their shoulders
in terms of how to accomplish something
in terms of tasks orientations it's very
interesting
you know we could look at the scaling of
Amish and the reason why it is so
successful in the way that the Amish are
doing agriculture is because it's many
families per large acreage it's not one
company that's running in 70,000 acres
you know a lot of people ask us can you
successfully scalp Annabeth's can you
successfully scale cannabis and my
question back to them is showing a big
scaling in big AG that's actually
successful because my you know my
feelings is is that the big scaling and
big AG is not successful but the way
that we can successfully scale in
cannabis is taking large acreage and
having many families or many growers or
you know many farmers take over that
a-and that's the way to successfully
scale
we have five acres not of straight
cannabis but five acres that we take
care of them probably about three acres
of it is crops and the reason because
we're still under medical license here
in Canada Canada trying to enter into
the CTLs and we have plant numbers so
that's really the reason why we we have
five acres that could be cultivated but
we're not utilizing the whole amount so
how many plants does that is that the
plant license know how many plants do
you grow
it's changes every year because it's you
know depending on what medical license
we have it at the time or whatnot so
yeah it's really we just like to stay
underneath any numbers that are licensed
to us so right now we're
definitely not no it's no we're looking
at more like two two thousand and our
plant license is for fifteen hundred so
by the time we call and we ruthlessly
call
because we are breeders so we go through
and do a ruthless call are not only
males but ones that you know maybe
aren't showing you know high immune
response I know we'll get
well so we start our seeds on April 20th
around there and then we'll do another
wave maybe a month later of seeds and I
mean it's definitely a variation but I'd
say about 8 feet to 10 feet tall well
yeah yeah 8 to 12 right now our family
are Himachal Pradesh plants that we have
that were not light tapping are probably
about 13 14 feet up and also we start
our seeds then and then they grow
naturally and we aren't worried don't
use any trellising or anything so the
plants are naturally just being able to
support
almost 50 years and
but I think
one of the biggest differences you see
is the amount of roots I mean you've got
fuzz over everything and roots on roots
on roots on roots you know from the big
ones to the little tiny ones and when
you pull the root out it it takes a
massive
with it it's really really plugged into
here
that's clones from seeds they are even a
bit more of a tap root with seeds but
clones
you know one of the coolest things I
ever did in our first Hempfield in 1995
is I we were collecting a few of the
plants they were tall I pulled it out
just the plant it pulled out pretty easy
it was just a hemp plant but it had a
nice long tap root on it and we ended up
pulling out like five or six of them and
when they were laying on this like
trailer I was looking at the roots and
on a couple of them the root it went
down it was twisty and then right at the
bottom of the root was the the Hass of
the the seed shell like you could see
the the whole plant coming out of it I'd
never seen that in my life prior to 1995
in all the plants that I had grown I had
never seen anything like that we start
we pulled up a few more and was like it
was fairly common we were like that's
incredible oh I'd love to let Ethan
maybe tell us some you know a brief
thing on how to use the roots because
it's an often-overlooked medicine and
beef just really quickly be flora one of
the coolest things I've seen with roots
is putting a crystal right underneath
the seed and then the whole entire plant
grows around the crystal and at the end
of the year you can pull the plant up
and it's like a staff and and all the
roots have grown around the crystal and
it's really beautiful and we had a
friend do that but what are some of the
properties in cannabis roots how do we
use that sure so I became interested in
this because a lot of the old literature
referred to medical use of the roots and
typically the indications were to treat
inflammation
things like granulomas fibrous tissues
and also for cancer interestingly the
chemical makeup of the roots is totally
different than what's in the tops and
although oftentimes their use for the
same things
so in the tops as everybody knows we
have cannabinoids and terpenoids in the
roots in
contrast what we've got hurt Reiter
pinoys which actually the most abundant
biochemical chemicals in plants and they
are well known for having a protective
effect on plant growth and for us again
anti-inflammatory and anti-cancer
properties and there are also alkaloids
in the roots which you don't find in the
tops at all so how you use them a lot of
people are
incorporating these into dermatological
preparations so very helpful for skin
conditions and some people are cooking
them and in eating the roots we really
know less
about what the effects are there but
I'll just finish by saying I was really
surprised
some months ago I was in Santiago Chile
and a guy was selling cannabis products
on the street and one of them was the
tincture of cannabis roots so the dis
nah llege is spreading Natacha risen I
have an article that's I believe
available online on cannabis roots it's
also available on DM peer farms comm
site we posted it on Reiter when you
sent it to us huh yeah
yeah so that's that's really super
interesting yeah I heard about this
before from the roots and triterpene no
it's not a whole lot but it always made
me realize that you knowed it wouldn't
surprise me if cannabis had some
powerful root systems particularly went
back in the day when we learned about
producing ayahuasca using like a like a
plant containing tryptamine and then to
try and find plants that had the harming
and the harm alene that would sort of
potentiate those those tryptamines and
we learned about Syrian room which was
sold at like Middle Eastern grocery
stores in North Vancouver and stuff you
could get this the seed that you could
consume with mushrooms and it was sort
of like an ayahuasca but then we
actually got like the rule of Rudess for
the leaf from the DMT and then we got
banisteriopsis caapi
root bark and for years my friend and my
friends and I had access to this root
bark and I remember when we first met a
card there of shaman from Peru from
Iquitos he came up he was also a medical
doctor brilliant man by the name of Jose
and he was tripping out that we had
access to the root bark he was like whoa
like the first 20 times you only use
like the smallest leaves and you said he
said there was sort of a buildup and
only that the hardcore shamans were
doing the the root bark with their
preparations he was actually kind of
like he was blown away and then actually
kind of pissed off about it too he was
like you guys shouldn't be shouldn't be
doing that like should be using a
lesser and and to his you know effect it
was
extremely powerful everyone that had
those concoctions were just like that is
something else in make you know root
tonics are really popular you know
fermented root tonic sir all over the
island and every Rasta makes a different
you know not everybody you know just to
say a lot of them make a lot of really
great root tonics and cannabis roots are
often a part of that and an herbal
Chinese herbal medicine traditional TCM
decoctions are made out of
roots alcohol decoction so like t-shirts
and stuff so I think you get different
properties out of
tincture extractions from roost and you
would get out and say a liquid
extraction or an oil extraction so it's
nice to learn some of those different
compounds and what know what your target
is yeah for sure got a welcome Alex
Rogers into the room I just popped in
you kind of tripped me out because from
the corner of my eye you reminded me of
Noll van shiok who we got at like send
our like love to the universe because
amazing cannabis activists from Holland
from Harlem Willie Warhol's and just
like did so much in Europe for for the
plant got arrested and escaped
authorities back in the day like super
awesome dude he he passed away just
recently so we'll have to send our
regards and our love to his name was
cracking bubble what's cracking well we
got a whole crew in here we got a new
platform we've been talking about coils
Ethan Russo just gave the drop on roots
and cannabis dragonfly earth medicines
in the house whole bunch of cool folks
in the house you know man what's what's
cracking with you where are you I'm back
in Oregon right now at home in Ashland
but where were you where was I I've been
in Europe the last couple months so I
was mainly in Slovenia where I stay at
my wife's Slovenian so were there
months out of the year but then I travel
all around Europe because the Congress
didn't big there so so I get to write
off a lot of my travel expenses
basically will you'll be writing off a
travel expense to Vancouver here in the
next couple of weeks and we'll be seeing
you there for sure dude for sure I'm
gonna wait right yeah me too it's gonna
be an awesome event in Vancouver really
proud of what we built there and it's
just a sweet most of my events are the
ICBC events are like in Germany it's
like 35% Germans right bringing
Vancouver it's like 80% of people come
from BC so it's become a real local
besieged oh this is gonna be packed it's
gonna be awesome I like it man it's a
little bit different for most of the
shows that I go to you know it's you
really just do it in a day it's like
let's just get this over with you don't
know is it five hotel nights and like
dude like let's just get this over with
exactly exactly I switched I started
doing that in Oregon the one days
because of everyone was like conference
duty and they're like oh another
conference I was like hmm why don't we
do a one-day and I know I would also add
after parties that you throw are
actually worth going to Damian Marley in
that like forty person room in Spain was
hey know every now blind hog finds ear
of corn you know what I'm saying so we
just keep pushing and these little
little dim
well I'm looking forward to it I'm sure
any of you that are gonna be in and
around Vancouver on the 16th of
September will will be holding it down I
guess we're at the West End Bay shores
huh
[Music]
it was just there for my daughter's
graduation
y'all Congrats man wait lovely papa
papa exactly so who's uh you got like a
mob from Cyprus still doing the
after-party on this EP giant yacht right
outside the hotel it's gonna be super
camp and
we also got
we got John Salley coming retired NBA
legend and we also got we got all the
Canadian
usual suspects all the badasses Jamie
Shaw John Connor a guy named Marcus
Richardson chief cannabinoid officer I
want that title man forgive my I'm
waiting for other people to use it I'm
like it's been a year since I since
since that title has been in existence
and now I'm like I've seen like TV news
I saw chief ganja officer in Jamaica
which made me smile
[Laughter]
Marcus what's that in Pinsky is that I
don't know I've never I've never maybe
maybe Pinsky is also a chief cannabinoid
officer I thought school
he surprised me in
theory yeah no no I I don't know what I
was at see you know what I just hate
this door titles it's just like man I
just want to like make hash it's not too
difficult like that's basically what I'm
looking forward to with since starting
embark it's been literally a year of
like jumping through hoops oh you
getting building permits and getting all
of this stuff lined up so that we can
literally just do what there's never
been an industry like this where it's
just like oh you want to do you want to
open up a business you want to do
something okay well here you go just
like binders of like hoops to jump
through some of them are like flaming
some of them are spinning with like acid
flying off of them every type of hoop
you need you could possibly [ __ ]
imagine jumping through I'll tell you
one thing it does show that only the
most hardcore
are willing to push through with with
with any of this because it is exactly I
will also say simultaneously it totally
beats them kicking our doors down and
arrest us in prison for 10 years at a
time shooting our dogs and breaking up
our families and taking our kids into
child Family Protective Services some
people have forgotten how shitty that
was everybody's forgotten bubble
everyone that was I'm telling you I can
put up with
it is right now happening in Northern
California it's happening in Mendocino I
just heard a horrible story of a farmers
in Santa Cruz that they put an 8 year
old and a 9 year old on their belly with
guns to their heads and they didn't just
take down there cannabis they took down
you know all of their greenhouses they
went in and ransacked their house they
took personal items they even took their
four-wheel drive machines that they had
and they drove them out into the woods
and threw away the keys this is
happening this is last week Jesus Christ
back it's a bigger problem that's not
even having to do cannabis that's just
the authoritarian federal government of
the United States and civil forfeiture
and all that all this added leeway there
they they want to take it they can do
whatever they want to do they don't have
to charge you and they can take all your
[ __ ] and that goes way beyond canvas man
that's just a straight-up civil liberty
issue and the feds coming in like that
it's always been a problem people know
it's a problem and or you know those who
know no but then the whole industry has
kind of become
anesthetized from from all that and and
I think a lot most people on this call
right now it's like we're kind of the
roots
crew that's still reminding people that
ain't we're here for a reason you know
you see the big Canadian finance guys
come into the room and how they talk and
whatever and I'm not dissing any one
group of all I'm saying is that we this
[ __ ] was built on the blood sweat and
tears on the backs of lives being ruined
and so it's always a great topic to
bring up and mention because because I
think most people are tripping that's
what we do in the ICBC that's the first
thing I said I said there's two [ __ ]
government's gonna [ __ ] everything up
administer the regulators gonna mess
everything up and so what's really
important is that all criminal penalties
are ended towards cannabis and that
everybody has the right to a home card
right so everything else doesn't really
matter you know as long as all come if
you go sell ten pounds the weeds not the
crime it's the you don't play your tax I
guess that's always going to be a crime
okay but that's a different crime people
could deal with that the weed all the
criminal things I don't like jack hair
you know he used to be like oh it's like
tomatoes and some people like Oh Jack
that's a little crazy you know but [ __ ]
no it's not but you know with so but
that's never gonna happen so what we can
do to mitigate that is just say oh let's
keep ending the criminal penalties you
know the battles just begun everyone's
gotta have their home guard you know
around the world I don't know how much
grow pretty good Tomatoes
let those [ __ ] start growing
some weed and watch what happens you
know
oh
yeah I've been doing it for decades man
masters of the game
Wow yeah that's right someone just
pointed out this is the first church
with 12 people we were always limited to
10 people 9 invitees and myself with the
Google platform but someone asked me the
other day they're like how many people
can you get in there and I'm like well
it says a hundred it says I can put a
hundred people in this live chat with
cameras how ridiculous is that
harm reduction Club
Alex were up here in DC we're doing
amazing regenerative agriculture and a
ton of Education we'd love to be
involved in the ICBC
will hit me up and we can we can talk
about it the schedule for Vancouver is
packed but maybe we could do some little
few minute like get up Rara and just
make everyone the [ __ ] aware of what the
hell is going on and why we're here just
hit me up and we'll do something okay
yeah we definitely will thank you sweet
I definitely have to get there too hey I
got a question for dr. Lisa I have a
question for dr. Russo if I could Ethan
do you know what the latest and greatest
is on the FDA's position on CBD do you
have any update on that at all yeah so
the situation is with the farm bill the
hemp bill
supposedly a lot of these preparations
with less than 0.2 percent THC are legal
however that is not the position of the
Food and Drug Administration or the DEA
okay so from the the position of the FDA
the
preperation epi dial which is 98% pure
CBD is a Schedule five substance that's
the lowest level of control but that
only applies to epi dialogues and it
does not apply to any other former
cannabidiol which remains in schedule
one and I point out that cannabidiol has
not been scheduled in most countries
extra USA with the DEA it's
again to them it's all illegal and they
will tell you they reserve the right to
arrest anybody engaged in this kind of
commerce so it's great that we've made
progress in the states however and no
one should suffer the illusion that it
could all disappear tomorrow if the
political will were there to do it now
it would be a stupid idea and contrary
to everything that we'd like to to have
happen but that is still possible
because of these discrepancies in the
law and what the
administration's feel the situation
still is couldn't there be an exception
an exception to that rule though if the
Department of the Secretary of the
Health and Human Services issues an
exception to the FD&amp;C
Act to put CBD into foods and whatnot so
is that there always that loophole that
it is just really up to one person in
the Trump administration right now his I
think person isn't acting
HHS secretary I don't even think it's a
fully you know Senate appointed one but
isn't it just true that there is a
loophole for an exception to that law uh
you know as far as that goes the truth
doesn't matter it's the semblance of
truth that you can create and they bury
anyone under a tangle of legalese to
make their point so I wouldn't count on
that at all the Attorney general could
do something if he were so inclined
don't hold your breath what we really
need is Congress to tackle this and
there are available bills they're just
not moving at the sign so the potential
is clearly there for this to be
rectified but it hasn't happened yet
and really to change the laws we really
need change in the Senate because I
think Mitch McConnell even though he's
so-called Pro hab is dead Santa pants
moving any cannabis legislation to the
floor for vote so he just needs to go
gotta go hey I have there was a question
that I missed like three times now from
Kenna Biss in the chat room and he
wanted to know if anyone knew anything
about cannabis hyperemesis syndrome
do we have another hour
okay
this is a real syndrome um this is not
someone's imagination
it is not related to me as you will hear
in in some quarters this only occurs in
people who do very heavy
chronic doses of THC
what is going on we don't know precisely
but my theories on this would be one of
two things all one is that we're seeing
an expression of the the
biphasic effect it's well known that
cannabinoids can do have opposite
effects at different dose ranges so it
may be that so it may be that what
usually treat nausea produces nausea and
vomiting at these elevated doses but at
the same time the THC is still lowering
the set point in the hypothalamus and
producing hypothermia which explains the
pot bathing phenomenon the other thing
that could be happening is because of
chronic exposure to THC
that we're getting a downregulation of
the cb1 receptors in the brain and this
will cause a change in the way that THC
acts it will become an antagonist at
that receptor instead of an agonist so
it will reverse the normal state of
affairs the solution to cannabinoid
hyperemesis which produces the vomiting
nausea abdominal pain and this bathing
behavior the solution is that stanchion
from cannabis for a period of time
and people will get better however most
will suffer recurrence if they go back
to their prior use patterns I think the
solution is twofold one is use the
lowest dose that produces a desired
effect I also think that cannabidiol may
be protected so certainly people should
be using type 2 or even type 3 cannabis
preparations with a good quota of
cannabidiol
even does this happen to people who eat
cannabis or only smoking
well there aren't there many people that
are ingesting Teague's seeing type
cannabis orally I'm not it's a good
question I'm just not sure that it
generally were seeing it with people
that are smoking and especially doing
vapes all day long
it's the cannabis concentrate seem to be
strongly associated with this
interesting there must be something else
going on obviously because you know
there's a lot of people who use a lot of
THC daily that don't get this it would
be interesting to find what needs to be
lined up for this to occur people are
saying oh why does he say it couldn't be
me my think it could be it could be neem
and I've heard the argument as well for
me it's not a huge leap of faith for me
to think that a substance like cannabis
that works through the endocannabinoid
system and creates all these different
effects and regulates all these
biological function but there there
couldn't be systems where it flips where
that you know where get we're just
something's happening in the system and
it's getting it wrong it's you know it's
like you said I've seen enough people
back in the day take a big hit a bubble
hash for the first time and literally
either go white and pass out or turn
green and throw up like it was it was
something that I saw a multitude of
times and for my own self - have I ever
taken a big enough rip that I felt like
I was going to puke definitely at skunk
man Sam's house I felt that a couple of
times
yeah unfortunately I'm guilty for being
but yeah I I have a theory on this I
really can't share at this point but I
think in the future we may be able to
identify people who were at risk of this
syndrome and
as they they say watch this space we
have to find a single person gets it
from orally eating too much candidate
that's possible again generally it's
been association with with high intake
of smoked high THC material and I think
there's actually a couple different
things that are creating this
hyperemesis and it being a hot topic you
have obviously on the previous hashed
churches we discussed potential risks
associated with pest amination there are
some labs or some products being
consumed in the Midwest and non non
regulated states that could that are
exhibiting signs that pesticide
poisoning but with cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome I think it's just a
supersaturation within the cb1 receptors
because a lot of the patients that are
exhibiting it are consuming more greater
amount of cannabinoids than previously
available in the market and
do you think in terms of the conversion
of delta-9 when you ingest something
there's something to that you know would
you also believe that we you know I
I say to myself all the time we need to
better understand what happens inside
the body to the coton the conversion and
I'd like to hear if anyone has actually
done any studies or looked into that ah
well I could address this again I mean
it's still a bit of a controversial
topic there were um experiments done by
Leo Hollister back in the 70s on him dad
alleged that eleven hydroxy THC which is
what THC gets converted to in the liver
on the first pass that that was four to
ten times more
psychoactive than THC however there was
a lot of work at GW on sativex um and a
lot of this was not published but the
bottom line was they looked at THC
levels in the blood
eleven hydroxy THC levels in the blood
and had patients talk about how high
they were on a hundred point scale and
there were just no good correlations
that showed that there seemed to be any
difference in the psychoactivity of THC
and 11 mode roxie THC
so it it's not a settled issue
unfortunately the experiments that you
need to do to prove this would involve
putting a radioactive label on the
molecules and injecting them
intravenously I think you're gonna have
trouble getting that through an ethics
committee so I'm not sure this is one we
can settle but bottom line is it's
unclear that there's a big difference in
the psychoactive effects of THC and 11
hydroxy and I just wanted one really
quick thing is that I'm seeing a lot of
misdiagnosis with this as well so
doctors who don't necessarily have the
education they'll ask the patient you
know are you smoking and then they'll
just give a diagnosis of that when the
person is actually having a Goldwater
attack or or something that is showing
the same symptoms so I believe that you
know pushing this education forward so
more clean and people and physicians
have been educated you know knowing of
what the symptoms are and how to test
for it we have a friend who has the
issue and when you know they smoke our
cannabis is she doesn't have it at all
so I mean I don't I'm not gonna say that
am I gonna make a statement on the other
nothing that that happens well it's
gotta be righteous right I I have a
friend who can smoke cannabis but if she
smokes hash she passes out unconscious
like very badly like to the point where
she knocked out teeth the last time we
don't even let her smoke it anymore you
know the like not even sitting down
she's fallen out of Tears like
I I just wanted to mention the ethernet
we have received approval to do a radio
labeled study of our hydrogenated
cannabinoids through international
delivery so it was an arduous process
but we fought were finally there and so
we're at the front end of basically
commissioning a study to look at
internal delivery using radioactivity
just as a way to follow how it goes into
the animals brain
on this one back on the psychoactive
levels and unless we've got a rodent
Whisperer out there I don't know that
we're gonna get fully answers
animals first rate
and the most first the bat phone is
going I'm not sure I didn't know Batman
was in the room but Batman
that's my new phone make it sorry about
that markets that's dr. Batman to you
yeah the bat to bat phone
and don't be sorry whatsoever we're
chill were chill past church was a
little intense in the beginning as we
were doing it every single Sunday from
wherever I was in the world and I built
this incredible like it was it was
stressful I'm not even saying I'm gonna
say how stressful it was but now it's
nice and loose you know we have a
dialogue we have our conversation it's
great that everyone was able to come in
I said I was going to do two hours today
and we are at two hours and one minute
so as always let me just change the
screen so everyone can be seen this is a
nice way to go through things I can
thank everyone for coming and yeah if
anyone wants to say anything oh there's
a really cool function not that we're
going to use it now but for future
references there's a there's a function
where you can like put your hand up like
it's it's it's a little like thing on
the box where it says like you know if
someone's saying something and you want
to chime in rather than for people all
talk at once you know you can put your
hands up and create an order so maybe
we'll try that next time thank everyone
for network you can forget about that
one bubble I
feel yeah thanks for coming out even
last minute Alex I'll see you at ICBC in
a couple of weeks
d 420k and Johnny B mr. Waide laughter
and Dutch blooms Colton Turner thank you
dude for coming and hanging out with us
as always we're definitely gonna have
you back Colin and Michael Mike West
yeah everyone that is there from the
dragonfly Earth Medicine Josh and Kelly
and me she and Ethan thank you all for
coming in chillin skunk man Sam as
always I'm bubble man we'll see you guys
next time on hash Church