go live on the old zo
Tu and I'm telling you I was in bed like
three minutes
ago this meeting is being live
streamed all right let's check it out I
don't even know where the old YouTube
video is where the chat is and where I
usually send the link so hopefully
people just uh figure it
out yep there we go we are live
Beautiful hey welcome everybody to Hash
Church 4.0 is it season 4 no not really
I think we're like seven or eight years
into this [ __ ] but uh it is 4.0 don't
ask me the madness behind my uh
decisions but yes 4.0 episode one is
here uh apologies for it being 18
minutes late I was totally crashed out
sleeping and I never sleep until 9:00
like ever uh I looked on my phone and
saw that Wade had entered the room and I
was like oh my god dude we got to hear
from Wade today I want to hear from
everyone so good morning everyone we got
a bunch of people that just came into
the room I think we got about 50 people
that just popped in we got best friend
farms in the house we got Colin in the
house we got ET in the house and of
course we have Wade in the house so how
how is everyone doing how are you doing
Wade um I'm doing good um given
everything that's going on
um I'm uh I've got my camera turned off
because I'm in bed and uh not not real
handsome to look at this morning but um
yeah learning about
um uh a new health Paradigm in my life
I've been
uh uh getting used to the idea of uh not
enjoying full health and um having to
learn how to ask for help as a man who's
spent most of his life being ready and
willing to help others uh I find myself
in a situation where now I I need help
with all kinds of things that I never
expected to be in that situation so it's
a real eye openening experience and uh
I'm actually uh feeling
um excited it's not really the right
word but uh for New Opportunities new
chances to learn about myself and about
how uh our minds work uh in the context
of health and relations with other
people so that's kind of where I'm at
it's not easy is it Wade I I you know I
I I destroyed myself about four years
ago and I I I was unable to walk um like
almost at all and uh I remember just
feeling that same way kind of like wow
like I I was ending up going to a lot of
doctors and Physio and stuff so I was
and in my neighborhood there's a lot of
elderly people and what I noticed was
that I was much slower than them and I
was unable to do things that they could
do and I had like I'd be walking into
the building and then you know like an
85y old guy would be like excuse me and
sort of Shuffle by me while I was you
know moving one inch at a time because I
just so badly damaged my lower spine and
it really got me thinking the same way
just kind of like wow like this is a
really it just gave me a glimpse into my
potential future if I you know if I can
get there if I can hey brother right on
dude good to see you man we we love we
got mad love for you Wade so yeah it's
uh you know I was even talking to my
wife about it the other day we have this
long driveway it snowed about 20 times
this year and the minute it snows we're
both out there shoveling like crazy and
I'm just kind of like you know there's
going to be a time where we can't can't
do this and I wonder if our brains are
going to accept the fact that we can't
do it or if we're just going to do it
until we are injured or hurt and then
maybe we'll listen to our bodies and be
like holy [ __ ] like I don't think I can
go out there and shovel the 4,000 pounds
of snow again so I feel for you I know
you have an incredible Community around
you I know that you yourself have been
helping people in similar situations
that are unable to do things for
themselves and you've been such um sort
of a leading energy in that in that help
and I I often you know say it to my wife
because she's very much a helper she's
she doesn't take at all but you have to
understand that sometimes the the
taking is allowing someone else to help
which is also giving and so don't don't
forget that and I see that you have an
amazing community of people around you
um I see that you've got there a little
Facebook group started for you
compassion for Wade and I just love
seeing all the people that are just like
I want to help I want to do this like
let's get I'll help with meal prep I'll
help so that's really awesome to see and
uh I would have expected it to go no
other way with a with a person of uh of
your
Vibe yeah thank you Marcus I
um one of
the yeah yeah it's really interesting to
me how
um we take for granted our health and
our opportunity to do the things that we
love to do and um and yeah this came up
out of nowhere for me um back in
September uh I broke I fractured a ribs
sitting up in bed and uh it was like how
does that
happen and then um
over time yeah over the last few months
I've broken a bunch of ribs I I broke a
my collar bone on the left side here
trying to open a childproof pill
bottle and just fractured it cleaning
too um and the the type of cancer that I
have is called multiple
Myoma and basically it's um certain type
of blood cells uh bone Mar n cells uh
they're called
plasmans uh and they make a specific
protein that um anyway um I I'm uh my
body is being very good at making lots
and lots and lots and lots of
plasmas and uh what ends up happening is
it it there's so many of them they blow
holes in the bones uh so um when I look
at I've seen xray photographs of my
skeleton and it's like someone I was
shot with a shotgun there's just
hundreds of little holes in the bones
throughout my rib cage and Spine and
even my skull
um always thought I'd end up being a
holy man you
know so anyway yeah that's that's what's
happening and um
probably the biggest drama at the moment
is I have this sort of crazy object here
I don't know if you can really see it
but every time I get out of bed I have
to strap myself into this thing because
my uh my my H spine several of the
vertebrae in my spine are
um are eroded to the point where the
X-ray you can see my spinal cord it's no
longer longer surrounded by bone and
they're concerned about um ended up
paralyzed from U bone intruding on the
spinal cord so I'm doing a lot of bed
rest getting up when I can eating well
trying to get lots of rest Pain's
probably the biggest
issue um pain is such an interesting
thing it's really a sensation from the
body to stop doing what you're doing if
you can and if you can't
stop uh learn how to live with it
um but I um I have a I have a really
strong sense in myself that that I will
come through this that this is a thing
that uh this is not my end game if you
will I have um a very clear sense of I'm
I'm I'm learning about what it's like
for people in my situation now like you
said I've I've spent years helping
people in this situation but now I'm in
this situation and it's really um I feel
like it's an opportunity for me to help
more people understand what this
Situation's like and how U those of us
who uh look to plants and mushrooms for
healing
opportunities uh can really explore
what's possible um in our Medical
uh profession and the things that they
offer
um but really for me a lot it comes back
to uh caring for oneself learning to uh
accept
gifts uh my beloved Monica pointed out
to me that she reminded me of all the
people who have accepted preparations
I've made over the
years
and and they never opened them they put
them on their bed bedside and just left
them there like never really used them
and I feel like I'm being given that
same opportunity I have people who are
offering gifts to me on a regular basis
but if I'm not willing to open those
gifts and take advantage of the offering
that's been made I'm I'm like having
that sitting on the on the counter next
to the bed instead of opening my heart
to the uh gifts that are being offered
and uh and that's a hard part that's the
hard part of of uh
acknowledging all the
love that's out
there and
uh that's all I
got well I appreciate you Wade I'm
stoked that you're here with us today
I'm stoked that you turned your camera
on I'm stoked that you're acknowledging
all the love that's coming your way and
uh if you have any problems accepting
any of that love I feel like etan's cat
is teaching us all a lesson on how to
fully accept love I mean holy [ __ ] did
you see that cat's face just now that
was
uh I I need to learn a few lessons from
your cat she loves Wade and needless to
say um Wade thank you for calling after
your diagnosis um it was both painful
and loving to speak with you to remind
you as healers now is your time to be
loved and to uh accept it and thank you
for uh accepting it because as we know
so many people we've tried to help as
you said don't open it and um my best to
Monica and all your support team uh we
love you we're sorry to see you go
through this but uh you know we're not
above you we're not below you we're
beside you so we we love you we're with
you if you need anytime you need to talk
[ __ ] complain you got my number so you
know or just share love and just to
share a smile I'm here for you there too
but you know um do your best take it
easy remember you're human and I know
you already immersed in that but you
know just continue to accept the love
and we love you and my cat sends her
love
too I see Dr Allison and Dr Mark are
both in the house we got Mr dragonfly
Earth medicine hey Dr
Allison hey good morning um I I just
want to send some love to Wade um some
healing Vibes to him um and uh just I
I'm just I was listening to him and I
was feeling so much love um and uh you
know hopefully he can accept um the love
that he's given to others that is is
coming back around to
him um and I'm actually I'm just gonna
pop in for a moment because I am getting
ready to go on tour with tulle for the
week yeah um I've been preparing for
this for a very long time and so uh I'm
going to be hitting
Eugene uh Tacoma Boise Sacramento and
San
Francisco and
um damn some tool some tool assisted uh
therapy is that what's going on oh yes
there's going to be some mushroom tool
assisted therapy as well as some
cannabis um assisted therapy going
on that is awesome tool as well like
come on are you kidding me right nothing
like a little Alex Gray and uh Adam
Jones artwork to uh you know feel like
you're in church literally different
kind of church than hash church but
Church nonetheless we're in full support
of tul church that's uh that is for
certain and anything Alex Gray we
Embrace 100% I got my first Alex Gray
calendar in
1991 the sacred mirrors calendar and
that's when I got turned on to Alex and
did a two foot double jump right into
his uh into all of it which was uh yeah
I I appreciate Alex I appreciate tulle
and of course I appreciate you and I
always appreciate you speaking of Alex
actually the first event I ever did was
the 50th anniversary of LSD in San
Francisco at the unarian church in 19 uh
993 and Alex brought all his artwork and
set it it up in the in the center of the
Unitarian Church and it was he set up
the sacred mirrors he set up all his
paintings not just sacred mirrors he set
up a whole bunch of his paintings and
that's the first time I one ever seen
his work two it was live three a lot of
that shit's [ __ ] large and I had no
idea so because I had been to Dolly and
if you ever been to the dolly Museum
shit's really small so you never know
what you're going to get when you see an
artist and to see his work on full
display
just yeah that that's an artist I've
followed ever since needless to say
because it touched my heart and my soul
and everybody who was there and a lot of
people were tripping 50th anniversary of
LSD and they were just in the center
with that art it was just that
connection never escaped my soul it was
so beautiful I hope the experience is
wonderful and transcending doctor
because uh yeah I love to I've see them
many a time and yeah they always put on
an amazing
show thanks I'm really excited just
watch the drum solos those are the best
Danny car's amazing amazing absolutely
amazing my best friend and I have been
going to se tool for the past 25 years
so when they um you know and actually
during covid March 12th we were at the
Portland show and we were supposed to go
to Eugene and Beyond and it got
cancelled so we decided to take a week
and just go on tour um as you know best
friends and it's and my step kid's gonna
go to the Tacoma show for her first rock
concert so it she's gonna be ruined I
mean having tul is her first
concert yeah that's completely insane
mine was Iron Maiden and Twisted Sister
and uh I was able to find some better
experiences down the road but I'll tell
you twisted sister in like 1986 was some
serious [ __ ] they don't want they
weren't going to take it they just
weren't anymore in
1985 but I just wanted to make sure I
said hi I miss you guys and um I've been
thinking of y'all I've been judging the
Washington craft cup I'm judging rosin
and um and I'm also judging BHO and I
just I'm so disappointed in C the the
fact that BHO people are using
CRC uh I I I don't know if y'all talked
about it at all but I know Oregon has
outlawed the use of
CRC um it has not happened in Washington
and nearly every entry that I'm smoking
is
CRC I see Mark looking through the top
of his glasses I feel like he's got
something to say about that how can they
outlaw CRC what the hell is that that's
[ __ ] right just a filtration stuff
right I mean you don't don't call it CRC
and then you could still do a filtration
through
some some some media I mean I don't know
I don't like the way it tastes at all I
mean you can taste it in the back of
your mouth um I don't know whether it's
the dious Earth that I'm tasting or any
of the other um you know chemicals or
bleaching agents or whatever it is that
they're using um in their columns but it
doesn't taste good it completely takes
away from the tpin
and I'll tell you B BHO never quite like
got back on its feet after that Rosen
knocked it down a little bit like I'm
I'm not saying that it's like you know
and I and I remember Johnny B did a
video called the death of BHO and I
remember being like holy [ __ ] like I'm
glad I didn't make that video because
that the BHO Community already kind of
hated me but um [ __ ] I'll say it was
certainly a partial death like it was a
blow like a blow I'll never forget like
giddy up being like
oh [ __ ] b b will always be better
than Ros and it's too hot and it's burnt
and it's like where did that [ __ ] guy
go now I got Nick is in uh Nick
Bradley's in there saying Oregon didn't
Outlaw CC they outlawed specific media
now I know like uh I was just in Hawaii
and you can't even get any type of BHO
extraction there however they have just
started doing Rosen and their Rosen was
[ __ ] fire uh I have to actually give
major props to Maui Gro and what they're
doing there uh for uh pressure and heat
but the quality of the rosin was first
rate uh still expensive it's like $76 a
gram retail it's
expensive um I may be wrong on that but
it's still expensive but at the same
time the quality is getting better and
being a veteran I got a discount but
still the prices are still outrageous
I like I like that an I got a
discount that's awesome well you know
rosin and bubble has as all of y'all
know are just are gonna always be
superior you know what to each its own I
love the idea of everything being
available I've always loved the idea of
you know even things that I'm not
interested in there's other people that
have a great interest in it in in that
and so I would fight for people's right
to have BHO if that's what they want
um I'm just uh I'm just pretty happy
with my full melts and my rosins but to
each their own for certain It's a
Wonderful Plan I think uh go
ahead I was just feeling like if it's a
sacramental you know sentient being
plant it should stay that way all the
way into the body and when you put a
toxic chemical into something to
transform it to make it somehow more
available to the market makes zero sense
on a spiritual level and on an herbal
level people can do what they want you
know and they will and that's fair fair
enough and I just like to point out that
cannabis is possible to be a sacred
sentient being and the medicine that
comes out of it can change lives and uh
you know the purer it is the better it
is on your microbiome and you're
yep well said Josh for sure at the same
time I used to always be amazed at like
how people could take
isopropanol or or another poison as you
call it create this ex extract and then
like cure cancer out of their body with
it like there's there's got to be
something going on there like regardless
like I I can't tell you how many people
I know that did that with like ISO and
and butane oil and just taking it and
and and ridding their body of disease I
got to think that
uh the power of cannabis is greater than
the power of the chemical extracting it
and it seems to hold over right right to
the end and I get that the Purity like
I'm I'm a pure guy I I love I very much
love the full Mount Bubbles and stuff
and I'm always like you know if my mom
got some cancer or something I'd want to
send her like my best full melt you know
I I probably wouldn't go buy her
BHO that being said you know it's hard
to buy 30 grams of full melt BHO or 60
grams or you know to have have that
stash whereas at one point in time
people really figured it out with BHO
and and that and ISO there was just you
could buy enough of it where it was like
oh some and so needs like 60 grams you
know to start their regimen you could
just access it and trying to find 60
grams of full Mount bubble would be like
I don't know $6,000
$110,000 really expensive so I love I
love the idea of people using what they
have access to and in the meantime let's
make sure they have access if you know
it's your vision to have the best
cleanest best for your biome product
well then we got to do it you know you
got to grow the weed I got to make the
hash and we got to make it available
dude so come on let's do
this let's do
it I think if you're trying to I think
if you're trying to correct disease like
maybe smoking it isn't the actual method
anyway maybe not probably move away from
that whole entire modality you know if
you're GNA like correct you know a
chronic illness and uh that's the beauty
of this fractal medicine is that we have
this ability to transform it into
different ways and you know there's
there's there's a lot of ways to to live
out there and stuff and and I I would
like to just give my love at this moment
to wait because I haven't yet and I just
really acknowledge your whole entire
path everything that you've always been
about has always been a breath of of
life to me and Kelly everything that
I've ever seen you say everything that
I've in your presence Monica as your
partner your whole entire way of being
the way of bringing Forest into it and
cagus and your support of his you know
that of that whole entire network is is
lifechanging and and life transforming
and I really
appr you
know you and I also want to be as as
Kelly too also there any minute of any
day it can't be there spiritually we can
do probably a lot so we're gonna do
everything we can to continue to send
life love and uh and courage and
strength to you and you know I just want
to I I can't words are not enough to
express the feelings that I have that we
all have in our body for
you thank you Josh it's
um yeah so much of
what I think so much of what we do and
it's not just me I think this whole
circle of people represent uh similar
flavors as what I think I bring in my
life and uh so much of what we do is um
you put it out there because it's an
expression of who you are not because
you think it's going to bring some sort
of fame or uh recognition or uh anything
like that it's just it's who we are and
um and I and so deep appreciation for
you you you and Kelly and the whole
dragonfly Earth family uh were really a
breath of fresh air when I first found
your work and what you were doing they
made so much sense to me
um and yeah yeah thank you and I and I
love the um the way in which you call
out the spirit of the plant and the
importance of
um the
Spirit the wholeness of that plant and
the various ethenogenes
some of the the CBD capsules you guys
are making and uh supplementing it with
cannabis of course and
um yeah I just deep appreciation for
this whole network of people yes right
there just what he's holding up exactly
that I got him right here next to the
bed it's it's nice to visualize that
there's old
growth intelligence in there because of
the polypores that are growing in that
intact environment one of the largest
intact environments of all of British
Colombia are infused into that oil along
with good
intentions and you know the power of
cannabis of course and other herbal
medicines there you go it looks like you
got me maybe an uh Fus F andus or some
kind of an artist con there potentially
Marcus yeah that's beautiful um and and
it does have an intelligence beyond our
current wisdom you know but I inside we
do understand it and then that's why it
works so well and stuff so yeah it is
it's all of us there is a red belted
conk that's the one that's the most uh
prolific in in in the northern
hemisphere a lot of the world has that
red belted conk and it grows on fur
trees pine trees birch
trees rarely but sometimes hemlock trees
and uh they call it you know this it's
just a powerful medicine there's even
stories lore about native peoples uh in
on the on the British Colombian
Coast uh you know trading with Chinese
you know for 2,000 years and Le Lee
Miracle is an amazing Storyteller native
woman from Canada everyone should know
about her and she's talking about Jens
sing coming from from the Chinese you
know 2,000 years ago and the and her
tribes and her native people never
changed the name they just call it Jin
sing because it came from them 2,000
years ago and parts of that remnants do
grow in the forest and you find Jens
sing around here and and I love the idea
that as long as there's been humans
there's been trading of medicine and you
know to me that's really powerful and I
like that we're keeping that happening
today in this modern world and when when
a person says I'm interested in plant
medicine I I think they're saying I'm
interested in spirit medicine as well
because the plant has a spirit and the
spirit comes from the environment and
the interaction between the human and
that environment and that's where the
magic comes from you know that's where
pyramids are built or things beyond the
human power so I to hold the space for
miraculous
healing and also just you know conscious
conscious living you know just being
conscious you know as best you can and
maybe in this moment I would like to
take take a a a moment of of Silence
because in the in our family in the last
week we had a death of not only a Dem
pure family
did he freeze oh yeah he he'll be back
he's got internet like me there he
[Music]
is Froman
Creek hello I'll you're back Daniel
you're back we missed most of it so you
gota from Lane Creek hemp there we go
Lane Creek hemp Southern Oregon his
sister runs the farm it's a family farm
amazing people they've been they won the
regenerative cannabis farm in
Oregon you know a few years back at the
cultivation classic um there you know
family members of of green Source
Gardens and Nick and Liz and and uh it
was you know the random sad death and
they found him in his in a in his boat
you know on the river and uh and so
we're putting our our our our emotions
and our our heart space to Daniel to the
family and uh to the farm to anything
you know that's guiding him in his trans
transformation uh our heart goes out to
Daniel and Lany
temp thanks for sharing that um cut out
for the first little bit but definitely
got clear towards the end shout out to
Daniel's family and the whole demem pure
family that's heavy duty for sure dying
on a boat floating on a river humans we
die everywhere we go it's true
everywhere we go speaking of I'd love to
spend a send a special rest in peace to
uh a longstanding hempy who passed this
week his name uh Steve LaVine um he was
on the hemp industry Association board
uh I do believe he actually planted hemp
Seas on the dea's lawn so he was a
badass one of the sweetest most loving
hempies uh started the Santa Barbara
hemp company was always out educating
people for the last three decades on
hemp just a a nonstop tireless awesome
person so Steve LaVine out of Santa
Barbara rest in peace brother I'll see
you on the other side but uh you were an
inspiration uh pride and your smile was
unrelenting and the world is a
little a little less brighter without
you in it I love
you well said tan thanks for sharing
that um randomly enough Steve was one
gentleman whose paths mine and his never
crossed in the 30 years that we were
both involved with the plant i' I knew
who he was but we had never interacted
which is just fairly rare for me in this
sort of community I usually bump into
most most folks like that that are
lifers that are that are 100% dedicated
to the plant so yeah another cannabis
Warrior has gone to the other
side puff a um puff really quickly on a
positive note I'd like to just shout up
Brian at best friend Farms all of it's
positive I would like to say but and
Brian from best friend farms in the last
week two weeks has become pure
certified and his farm is you know
really coming alive over the last few
years you know and the whole main
Community you know is is really doing
their work to to try and make the world
a better place and and uh just really
stoked about Brian and the intention
you're putting into your products and
your farm and and the transformation
of growing all you know the food and
bringing in diversity you know working
with hemp Farmers local organic you know
cultivation uh certification groups and
stuff you can tell us more but you know
I think it's really you know Main's you
know I don't want to call it a sleeper
State because every State's doing a lot
but Main's doing a lot of interesting
stuff over there so and I know Colin
you're doing a lot of stuff traveling
all over the place I think you're in
Maine now so big up Colin big up Johnny
be on the
pushups thank
you thank you glad to be part of
it definitely
medicine yeah the medicine food come
inherently for MERS here you know it's
one of those things like I grew up in
the home with both and um you know
people were quieter before now but it's
it's some of the one of those things
that this state here uh you know has the
the landscape for it too where we're not
you know we're cold but it it's not so
cold enough to kill off a lot of the
blights through the winter and create
you know good top soil Continuum for the
next year and then we just have a lot of
water here uh like Michigan and like you
guys have up the A and I think that's an
interesting thing I was actually
thinking on a lot lately when it comes
to uh perhaps a hash Terre or a TP Terre
when you're looking at ambient humidity
or moisture
um surrounding when you kind of maybe
isolate or look down to the resin or the
gland and how it would exist and what
would be maybe a moisture bath versus a
very dry climate which is more conducive
for a heavy flower density healthy
flower but I just wanted to bring that
up a little and I you know Main's doing
a lot of good things with the medicine
and with the hash and such and starting
to pay attention to some of that
happening wanted to just talk about a
little I want to talk about hashir and
the word that you just just
invented um can we please make sure that
doesn't go past us um that was awesome
dude holy [ __ ] you came up with hashire
that hashire I like the the role on that
on that phrasing I was
thinking TP hashw I've heard of the I've
SE I have a sticker from Northern
California
terrist oh the terar there's being a
terar and and and begging up your
hashar you know I like hashar I like
hashar because it it also could include
not only you know the Terre the outside
but the indoor sort of aspect of it
which you know maybe there's maybe
there's something to that but your
hashir and your terar person have to
work together absolutely they have to be
close friends they have to smoke
together you'd have to take an effect
the air
you know because the air that's
happening is crucial
so depends on your oxygen War you know
it has to B saturation level well it's
around the same latitude right isn't
isn't Maine like at the same latitude as
BC that's I'm trying
to you know it's it's
Coastal it it's right it's kind of like
the same thing over there right a little
bit right no I mean the bottom so like
Ontario Hamilton Ontario is 43 parallel
which is the same as Eugene Oregon you
would never guess that Hamilton Ontario
is the same latitude as Eugene Oregon
until you look it up and then you're
like oh weird so like that's why there's
like the on what is it um Niagara on the
Lake is a town south of you know on uh
Toronto and it's they have huge hectares
filled with with green houses and tons
of growing you know some of the
original Canadian LPS were in those
those areas but so much to look it up
where's
Maine dude some of that some of that
southern Ontario resin like some of the
best full melt I've ever seen Grown
outdoors in Canada comes from not too
far from that
area Maine has some extremely talented
Growers up here I I'm really impressed
with the not only the camaraderie but
also the selection um and the
individuality that everyone brings to
the table here in terms of their growing
you know it's it's it's rare to see so
much fire on the
Shelf so I just looked up Portland
Portland Maine is
43 so that's that's low yeah 42nd 43rd
parallel I've heard 42nd being in the
51st parallel is like
hardcore it's it's a different like step
of cold and hardc coreness I think it's
why we might be getting all this
snow got three feet on
my how much something to do with the the
moisture level right and the moisture
level might have something to do with
not necessarily the terroir for growing
but for for hash making I mean uh H hash
making could be very very different at
different levels of humidity so it
definitely is do you think that the do
you think that the the would it be that
the maybe a fuller tpine expression
perhaps if it has a more of a bath of
moisture around for it to express every
aspect of that end that fraction of the
resin anyone know I I would I've seen a
lot of weed over the years not like oh
I've seen a lot of weed not like that
it's just we we are up in British
Columbia we go down all over all kinds
of contests everywhere and definitely
found that and even in California and
Oregon people use shade cloth in the
middle of the day and and the intense
heat because the resin heads like they
get closer into the bud you might say oh
there's a lot more resin heads because
you have a bigger flower and in the end
you might even have higher yields in
California but you know for example
California I'll just say for example but
uh you know up in British Columbia or or
up in the farther north where the the
bulbs get more they're get more
identified the the the they the flower
isn't as tight and the way that the the
hash the heads knock off and the
or not it's just in these areas you can
get a a more full expression in certain
in certain it might be harder it's
harder to grow though because you don't
get in some ways it doesn't express the
same so you have to use a greenhouse so
there's a lot that's a huge story it's a
huge story so that's why in some cases
we use green houses right because we get
the best expression because we're
capturing the heat of our Northern
climate and finishing it off before the
cold nights if we try and play around
with cold nights around here there's not
a turp to be seen you know what I mean
the the the the plant stops growing of
course we have outdoor varietals that
that
the resin heads are big and uh make for
in some cases even more greasier style
hash I agree with that that's what we're
finding here actually and it's a funny
it's interesting because the hash game
has kind of changed a lot to where it
goes to you know full melt or rosin and
people are looking for that real true
turp expression like a lot about the
flavor we all know it's going to be
potent but yeah I it's interesting
conversation I mean the
outo outdoor main one the out the ego
clash in California this year and that
that says something says one thing or
two you could figure out what they are
yeah and I I find all right so I find on
the East Coast predominantly you know to
not not to put this versus anything just
in terms of difference in climate um
having that moisture during your cure or
your your drying
process um it really truly does help um
retain a lot of the the the volatiles
that are there it it and it seems that
there's almost a uh a more control that
you can bring over the the whole process
in itself um that produces a more uh
robust
profile and it's uh it's something that
I I've I've really noticed over the
years and and I truly believe that the
climate up in Maine up here is really
conducive to uh super turpy varietals
and it's it's really due to the
environment we're getting a lot of big
resin heads too like in the 120 range
like uh yeah what joshu was saying
really really greasy turpy greasy greasy
and then a big big extra big dump
especially in the greenhouse later
finish that can go to full maturity but
we're seeing on the 120 Micron like
almost overpowering the 90 by by two lat
what about the 160 on
that sometimes you do see one I haven't
been hitting
it yeah I've gotten full m out right up
to 190 when I went and years ago I went
to Lugano to run material and I'll never
forget it in fact I took a picture of
the hashes with their microns written
down to them and it was kind of a not a
very good picture at the time um but it
got printed in Redeye magazine um
because it was sort of like from the 25
micron to the 190 Micron every single
grade uh melted and bubbled and you know
substantially too not like one was was a
Sizzler and the other ones were melting
like ice cubes but they were all like
ice cubes it was uh I haven't really
seen anything like it since I have to be
honest we definitely don't get a lot of
160 in our off our farm for whatever
reason it is and but we'll put it in
there just to clean it up and make it
sweet for what's below you know so the
220 190 160 just to keep it like super
clean down below we'll we'll go through
that effort but we don't get a lot out
of the 160 we play around with
it I can't remember who was talking but
they were even talking about 190 and and
possibly using a 250 instead of a 220
because they thought the 220 was
capturing heads and I remember reading
this conversation and being like okay
that's those are like really big
heads yeah I think Marcus we talked
about that a bit where I was asking
would it make sense to to add another
bag there to C had 250 years ago I used
to have a 250 and not too many people
needed it but just recently there was
another conversation not me or you a
group of guys talking about how they
were capturing all these heads in their
190s and they thought that they were
losing some in their 220 and they they
ended up getting a 250 and finding heads
in their 220 and not saying it's
impossible but it's just uh it's neat to
see people are doing things that I've
never really you know seen I like that
yeah good day everybody I was GNA
mention even with the sift I've been
using your 304 screen and a lot of the
heads on finding on that and I had the
coas come back were actually quite high
in THC I was quite surprised so going
with those lower uh screens I just
that's 45 microns so that'll be like
should be if you purify them in the 40
to 60 maybe even 65 range got a 42
Micron
yesterday uh well I meant THC percent
but um the your 305 is about a 45 Micron
screen 50 maybe closer to 48 or what
what not happy belated birthday Johnny B
and great job on your 50 uh push-ups
there a day there sir outstanding job
your consistency was a thing to
appreciate hell
yeah I love it now I'm doing 100
push-ups a day I do now up to 28 was my
Max so I'm getting up there considering
before my fall I did 35 at the bus stop
and that would June 24th of June 22nd of
2025 2005 so my goal is to get to 50
push-ups by the end of my 50th birthday
so I got all of this year basically so
join me 100 push-ups 100 sit-ups 100
crunches a day Mark you were doing it I
love you for it a bunch of other guys
but even I started with two push-ups
guys like and and then you can do two an
hour then do five just keep doing it
it's like growing just keep growing
until you get there never stop that's it
just [ __ ] yeah love you guys thank you
it was good to do push-ups I was happy
to do it with you Johnny B I didn't uh
didn't promote it like you did but I I
think I sent you the odd video of Johnny
B I'm doing my push-ups oh there he goes
he's doing push-ups I have
to do your pushup Johnny B started
getting into uh keep going never
push-ups as well
and keep going Johnny gez we can see you
somehow we can see you taking those
push-ups right there cring it under the
Des I ended up hurting my elbows and I
hate to say it no but I end I ended up
hurting myself from doing doing the
push-ups after it wasn't just in the
last month I'm talking the last couple
years I've been kind of taking it on the
last couple months I was
starting
yeah
yeah thanks guys for the motivation
that's my second most push-ups I was
trying to get to 28 but I was like ah
don't want to hurt yourself never stop
never again as as Josh is telling us
about hurting himself doing push-ups I
hurt myself how about that
dude turn your fingers in a little bit I
realize I can get better push-ups with
that I do wider and it's the book that
I'm on how to help with chronic pain is
through push-ups sit-ups walking walk
backwards retrain your mind breathing
exercises what I do every
day walks every
day someone just named your [ __ ] Johnny
Johnny bees cush UPS cush
ups dude Johnny be's cush
UPS what's the Brea what are the
breathing exercises you're doing
so when I'm walking I Breathe Into the
nose I hold for four seconds and I real
nose I do that while I'm walking and I
do that every day and I've been doing
that since March
6th and well you know what I think
everybody can see the change it's really
easy just do it like I just made that I
just decided I'm like hey you know what
I'm gonna do this all I do is walk out
the
door you know and every day got a little
bit better and every day I felt a little
bit better
and now I'm with you guys feeling
fantastic it's time for a
cush 2022 I'm doing this for a 100 days
you can start any time you want I'm
doing 100 crunches 100 sit-ups and 100
push-ups a day for the next 100 days and
then that will lead in for the next 10
years then 25 years see once you start
getting going mine was 30 days then I
had a 90-day challenge I did my 50
push-ups now I'm going to just keep
doing it guys because the only way to
get through Co and everything is [ __ ]
yeah ice bass but uh be healthy for
yourself and your mind and that's how we
get through this
together as you can hear healthy be
healthy for
yourself um I was uh I'm super like
inspired by what you're doing Johnny
it's it's awesome and I and dude the
transformation insane you know and then
like there it's like the the song your
theme song is Ain't No Stopping Us Now
you know type thing look at you and you
can't even see him he's half
gone yeah I'm 150.2 pounds morning I've
been 150 pounds now for over three and a
half months and I've had my weight off
so I found that happy medium I didn't
try for a weight I didn't set any goals
I just went to where my body naturally
went and now that I've I've done the
research on my see my grandfathers and
my grandfather's opas and my great
ancestors were all between 135 and 150
so this is my natural weight through my
through my Heritage and stuff like that
my father was I posted a picture of him
in 1964 he was 145 pounds you know what
I mean so this is where I was supposed
to be so once you find your natural
weight you just kind of want to being
happy there I can eat whatever I want
but I I eat more water density foods and
I pay attention to my health I smoke a
lot of dabs too right I mean I did my
biggest dab and I did my most amount of
push-up was just 28 I did a huge dab and
then I proved I went down to 20 28
push-ups pushups pushups pushups yeah
come on Johnny B that that name was made
for you you got to take that cush ups
and Med One your medicine is a cush like
come
on it's it's now the 100 cush up
challenge the 100 cush up challenge I
challenge you guys do 100 cush ups for
100 till
420 well I'm doing Burpee so I'm past
just the push-up so I'm I'm I feel you I
worked my way up to a 100 you too on
September 2nd I did two push-ups and I
was I mean I mean and and it's being a
long haul I couldn't even do a push-up
everybody knows it broke my neck shot in
my arm everything like I they said I
would never do that again look at me
they said I would I'd be in a wheelchair
when I was 50 doctors lied to me I said
[ __ ] you I'm G to be that right no even
scarier they probably believed it dude
so you know the whole thing is is they
make you believe things so beli in your
yourself that's the most important part
when doctor you're going to die like you
know I was listening to One talk he goes
you know I'm sorry but uh uh you're
knock going die they should say I can no
longer help you anymore you might have
to go find some other help don't tell
you you're going to be in you know I can
only help you at this point you can help
some someone else might be to help you
live this better quality of life that
you're looking for you know and and you
can do it for yourself because that's
what I do every day I leave that's what
I need to do for
me don't listen to your doctors I mean
they gave me five years to live in 1991
got to use cannabis they said it would
[ __ ] addictive wow hey Sav my life
got me off a pharmaceutical drugs look
where I am today because I use cannabis
for a medicine and when I need to I use
it for relaxation and a little bit of
entertainment [ __ ] it does all those
needs for me isn't that awesome how it's
gives me all of those needs relaxation
entertainment fun joy [ __ ] Friendship
Community dude I want to try this [ __ ]
what is it
called what's it called Canabis oh [ __ ]
I'm puffing it right now no wonder I
feel so good and I'm mildly and slightly
entertained I started jump
roping because my arms were hurting a
little bit and then I started looking up
all this jump roping challenges and
stuff and then I started seeing this a
lot of stuff that was like oh if you do
like a thousand jumps a day you
completely transform your body and then
you start seeing all this beautiful
dancing Styles and all this like timing
things and stuff and all these different
kinds of ropes and everything and so was
been kind of enjoying it and I was and
then I and I heard this thing on the
radio and whether it's it's kind of
weird but like uh in China they said
that every child has to be able to jump
a hundred times in order to go to school
so that's weird right but then I was
like can I jump a hundred times in a row
in a minute I think it has to be in a
minute think of how many kids might not
make it like from different countries if
you just were like Hey we're going to
take you and go to school and now I
can't I know Well turns out the school
is just being
healthy and being able to jump and being
able to walk and then I started looking
at all these workouts and these like
military workouts and these these like
murf workouts and all these challenges
and I was like Jesus Christ do these
guys know about
farming because all the time that they
spend in the gym and all this time they
spend working out underneath bars and
sweaty gyms I'm like have you guys ever
heard of like hugle cultures because
like a shitload of effort could be used
on transforming your land and I'm
telling you what if you want to put that
much effort into being healthy you might
as well get some [ __ ] food out of it
yeah soil biome that you're breathing
that soil biome and that air dude you
hit a good one outdoor hugle hugle
culture gyms like come build my
farm oh man and then it's like oh wow
what just happened I just built a whole
goji berry bed next thing you know like
oh wow all these guys drink dogey Berry
drinks right like wow you could like
grow them and then drink
them and then you'd be stoked and I just
I just I love that flip so like I kind
of have a hard time in between shoveling
my
driveway fixing things it's a hard time
getting the workouts in but I'm you know
I still do it
because you know it's all part of the
life yoga that it takes to to be
well true story Man true
story um we should go back to talking
about the size of the Tricom heads and
the greasiness and the dryness and the
different environments because I don't
know if I was done with that
conversation there uh definitely was
inspired to hear Johnny B's story and
was stoked on that but uh yeah let's see
if we can someone is someone gonna make
a 420 Micron bag now is that what you're
saying yeah the 420 Micron bag
exactly it's amazing how little
Innovation there really is it's um
it's kind of crazy I mean even myself
all I did was add some bags it's like in
the long run I'm kind of waiting for the
next big thing here to happen rosin was
amazing that was huge that was [ __ ]
pretty gigantic for an and and it goes
to show you too like you know there's
Direction and I know there's people that
call [ __ ] on Phil's story I have no
reason not to believe Phil's story about
him just you know pressing out the the
hash in parchment to make dabs that was
you know definitely remember niik doing
that and that whole Colorado crew doing
that um jibs and and kenwall and whatnot
and so it's just neat that at one point
in time he ran out of hash and for some
reason was driven to put a bud into the
parchment paper and it's amazing too
that people knew that concept from years
past when they were you know pressing
hash and oil was was gooping out of the
the filter bags and whatnot and they
were collecting it and saving it for
their heads but not enough to actually
have the the the gear turn in their
brain to make that an available thing or
uh you know a process but you can see
how how this changes everything and the
people communicating and sharing
information through this so many people
were able to get eyes on that and I I
remember in the Cannabis industry and
community
that rosin was the first thing to spread
on Instagram like wild
fire I froze
bummer that's a
bummer last four years since it's been
created how many machines are actually
out there in companies that are actually
processing and making machines you know
yep how does even one go about figuring
out which machine to get nowadays
whereas four years ago they didn't even
exist now you have your choice of
selection depending on your production
model so I mean it is pretty
incredible
totally people watching that here
remember we were in in Barcelona and and
and you know Brian came out and actually
made it with us while we were in the
hash Museum and now here we are years
later and there's literally machines to
press your tonnage it's quite amazing
just the adaptability as well as where
legalization or um uh accepted adult
youth in various countries and states
have allowed industrial personnel as
well as chemical chemists to start
playing with this plant that we have
never had that opportunity prior and
that are taking it really seriously so I
could definitely see some other um
Horizon benchmarks on the way yeah
yeah the note oh go ahead Johnny be's
got the first rosin maker out
actually yeah I mean it went from hair
straighteners to Arbor to a hand press
Arbor press to hydraulic Arbor press and
then yeah because everybody ran out and
started pressing and and destroying
their girlfriend friends hair
straightener to where they're like you
better go get your [ __ ] own now dude
yeah yeah but yeah I mean you know now
it's not about throughput anymore just
about you know quality selection and you
know your personal intuition as to how
you want to make your hash and what you
want to select and there's just so much
you
know will always be connected to the
amount of people you want to touch so
it's easy to do small batch and you can
very comfortable in small batch but
trying to do large batch small batch
quality and caliber with the living
soils and the proper growing that is the
true challenge that in my opinion is why
we're
here yeah well you've also got the small
screens you've got the the pressure so
you've got a whole series of new
technology that we've never necessarily
played it with in the sense of you know
what Micron screen are you particularly
using for this type of genetic to
actually get this particular squish at
what temperature how long was your press
and again it's the lower the temperature
is still the uh the safety of the day
because if you go too high as you know
it every temperature affects flavor
correct absolutely yeah and not not
always not always bad and not always
good right like you know you could see
it in the good way whereas maybe you've
got a cultivar with some monot Turpin
that aren't like the most enjoyable
those are going to pop off probably
pretty quick in the process re re sort
of showing a new bouquet that is now
there the sesua and the heavier Tarpin
that didn't volatize off quite so
quickly um sometimes it works the other
way sometimes people are like o i i I
hear it all the time it smelt like burnt
popcorn this that and the other thing I
don't ever smoke rosin that smells like
burnt popcorn I'm not sure why people
think that's what all rosin is like it's
actually as nice as any extract that you
could do if it's done prop it's what
their experience was I think they had
access to some crappy stuff so they
think it's crappy if they had access to
the Quality rosin even the stuff that I
just recently saw in Hawaii you would be
thinking twice and you wouldn't even
utter those sort of things out of your
mouth because the quality is is at the
nasal and passes right across the pallet
now yeah and I think back to what Marcus
was saying supply chain is is really
important to note it's it's like if you
don't have your inputs down you're is
you're going to struggle to make quality
material and especially scale it's just
it's just it is impossible and and
that's that's the struggle I mean I yeah
that's what we really truly need right
now is is agricultural experience and
Horticultural experience to
merge uh ideologies to to try to to you
know if they're if that's going to
happen at scale it's that's that's the
way it has to go but also sort of you
know the people who run companies and
have an understanding on how to do that
that sort of corporate aspect and
whatever you want to call the rest of us
Legacy you know Roots the Roots and the
suits like you also need to kind of like
there are things that they're really
good at and if they stopped sort of
doing it in nefarious
ways um it could it it you know like I
said it's it's hard to touch that many
people I I I love the idea of being able
to help my friends and my local
community and growing and you know
getting more and more people involved
but I also love the idea of just being
able to say to anyone in my country you
can just go here and get that like it's
available like I I I hate the idea that
people have been feeling for so long
that when I share something nice and I'm
like oh look at this bubble hash it's
like a six-star it's super nice they
just can't go and get some you know CU
that's what when if I see anyone's
beautiful stash that's what I want to do
locked sorry I froze up there for a
second U but that's Thea that's the
beauty of you teaching everyone how to
do it because you know it is possible
for a lot of people to do even a four
you know plant thing in their house
which tons of people do now and and it
is true that more and more people are
beginning to make their own but I get
totally not to take away from have the
beauty of being able to go to the store
but now that's even a threat for
different reasons but yes hi everybody
Wade I love you just wanted to tell you
how much I loved you and hi everybody
happy Sunday so nice to be here we're so
we have so much snow it's been like such
a journey almost like couldn't find our
place right now because we're so snowed
in it's pretty wild isn't it this is the
most snow we've seen in the 26 years of
living in British
Columbia yeah definitely I feel like we
had one maybe like in 2002 or something
like that that was a really huge winter
but I think this one is surpassing it
because we're just still in early
January but it's awesome all of the
water that's happening in the mountains
and this kind of snow really seems to
reset soil too
probably be seeing different pests even
some pests will probably go away and uh
you know so the Cycles continue so we'll
be excited for spring and what these
heavy snows bring us I'm scared I live
in abfer [ __ ] I hope it doesn't oh yeah
wow you guys had the hellacious
floods yeah my
basement I I fought water for a while
but that's okay you know what like you
said we need the water and stuff like
that but that looks nice I know Mark's
Place he's got a beautiful view there at
least you hopefully you don't get like a
mud
slide
yeah that's the thing all the slides and
all the things that are happening with
all this weather and all these big
changes I mean we went
from water like crazy to the minus
weather to everything freezing to all
this snow then the melts and then in
Ontario I mean I was out there and it
was like plus seven it should be minus
40 you know what I mean like
it's going to be good out there I think
we just got everybody's got to
grow how to share the snow it's a great
time it's a great time to make hash it
is so like what what we've done is okay
so on the note of you know having large
large Tricom heads you know there's the
thing of like oh we're gonna harvest the
plant early to try and get the lighter
colored hash and then the buds aren't
going to be as full and then they you
know then that that's that's not cool I
don't you know I don't I don't agree
with that but it happens it happens some
Instagram
[ __ ] did you know I
know and then uh the one some of the
best hash we've ever made was upon ganja
Gill's recommendation um the the the
snow was coming in and we just washed
hash straight out of the greenhouse so
it was starting to freeze for the first
time the plants were really nice and we
just took plants and washed them right
in in the actual Greenhouse itself and
uh it was amazing the the tpping content
on that was amazing we did it at night
too and so I think that you know there's
there's definitely harvesting the plant
in in the evening you know the morning
hours before the sun comes up and
letting the the the the tricomes uh
mature as much as they can and then just
finding ways to wash them as fresh as
they can be
silence two and a half month hang dry to
see if I can make some really good uh
hash
today so today's the day a bunch of
different screens I'm go some buds on
some screen and make some hash I hope
everybody makes some hash
today do
you I don't know like so like I honestly
I think this idea of of something fresh
and interesting happened when when color
came into the mix and and I don't I I
think that it's good hash is good hash I
don't
I I don't think there's the education
yet around hash and color and pigment
and why it's a certain color um but I
think you know
nothing to do this meeting is being
recorded you know and it's that's that's
the thing I think it's really important
for people to understand is that quality
hash is um has a lot to do with how the
heads were grown and how that resin was
actually cared for before it became hash
um is we're we're really just filtering
the plant material to collect that
material we are the unveils of the flame
yeah exactly and that's that's exactly
right and that's you know as you've
always said Marcus it's it's Fire and
Fire out um and how you grew that that
varietal if you let it go longer you may
have Amber heads there and your hash
just may be Amber and that might not be
a bad thing
whatsoever um I think that's just
I'm curi like I just listen sorry to
interrupt you
but yeah do you think then fully mature
Colin and fresh frozen trapped then
would be the most the uh fullest tarpine
profile expression from the plant any
call on that or car versus fres I think
I would I believe at least maybe the the
canono Spectrum itself is is IM mature
at a more mature state so you might have
a larger spread of and a higher
percentage point of these miners um in
terms of these you know the volatile
chemicals there I mean I I don't I think
it depends on the variety I think
there's a lot to be studied there in
terms of when to actually take something
for the purpose of the turpion
production um I do think there is a
falloff point uh where Turpin do peak in
the the terpenoids itself and all those
those volatiles do start to fall off at
certain weaks so um but there's a lot to
to explore there in terms of
understanding
that did it say this meeting is being
recorded when I came in cuz that kind of
made me chuckle and I thought imagine
like 25 30 years ago if I came into a
room and a voice announced that the
meeting was being recorded that's uh oh
we would all
left an out I might have even got
stomped out I don't know but uh this
meeting is being
recorded yeah it's still the antithesis
of my thought and my upbringing from
anything I was taught from using pagers
and payones and being described on the
side streets and you know hustling and
meeting in bathroom stalls and [ __ ] like
that and here we are you know completely
comfortable and legal to the point talk
being recorded and we're talking to the
about the drugs and [ __ ] that we used to
deal deal with grow illegally Etc it's
I'll tell you we really did change our
reality didn't we we did we changed our
reality who and I know un lot of it
needs to be changed I know there's still
people in cages and all sorts of heinous
[ __ ] going around the world we're not
done but the fact that it could be done
even on a small scale means that it can
be done on a large one which is once
again why it's so important to do things
on a large scale so everyone gets to
enjoy the fruits of our labor wait not
only that Marcus you're were going to
cord your drug talk and you're going to
share it with the world yeah except
Russia they don't [ __ ] with my [ __ ] they
they don't let me play I don't I don't
think you can play Bubble man's world in
Russia
unfortunately
really for sure I get letters every once
in a while from like Russian government
saying that uh bubble man's world is not
welcome I guess China
would I wanted to say say that we're all
talking about us changing you know our
reality and the way that the industry is
going and the way that the community is
talking about it more in the way that
the world is incorporating cannabis more
but it really is just the Cannabis so
the more that cannabis spreads the more
ability that minds are open the more
Minds that are open the more heart
spaces that are open and all we are
doing is just stewarding her into more
and more ways to make this world a
better place and it's just so amazing
that plant medicine just keeps showing
itself as the Cure All for both mental
physical emotional communal everything
space so I think that this show and what
you've been doing for so long Marcus is
just continuing to allow the plant to go
through doors that it may have not
otherwise gone
through so so much gratitude for
everybody for continuing knocking at the
doors everybody that's everybody
listening you know we continue to push
this plant forward and show her out in a
good way and have healthy concentrates
and healthy conversations better soil
then it's only going to make the world a
better place because then the plant is
just doing what it's supposed to do
we'll have a better health Healthy Mind
Body and soil yeah and then hash yeah
and we always talk about you know all of
the
different uh ways to make hash and how
to decompose you know like break it all
down and I think that it really just
gets back to the most important thing
about hash is that we're ingesting it
and that uh we just continue to grow
through the ingestion of it so I'm G to
have a bong hit right now
love all y'all happy New Year bong rib
for
Wade is this the first
house yeah this is the first hash one of
the new year
yeah well here's the growing into
2022 looking at new Innovations new ways
of making hash and uh new ways of
growing guys the industry is changing so
much it's awesome with light and and and
and technology and and all these yeah
like wow I got to look at them a rolling
machine that rolls like 10,000 joints a
day or something it was at the lift
conference and seeing this [ __ ] that's
happening it's a the future is kind
of growing fast guys well it is growing
but at the same time we're still dealing
with prohibition I'm watching our
dragonfly people who are using a puff go
Peak
and if I am correct in my understanding
puffco Peak went out of business because
the vaporizing can no longer be mailed
so I mean even things like that even as
much as we take two steps forward we're
still taking a few steps back from time
to time so even those that have found a
way for ingestion for our methodology
that's different that's more portable
even they are still coming under attack
and persuasion and manipulations that's
still do not allow us to inbi our full
freedoms yet so it's a it's why we know
it's not ignorance it's why we know it's
not ignorance it's straight it's the
demons you know it's an agenda it's not
like we're ever G to open their minds
that's like not ever
happening but you know they control the
board and so it's like a game of chess
and you know Kelly kind of nailed it
we're just there kind of opening all
these doors like hey cannabis quick
through here you know still suffering
the whack-a-mole unfortunately you know
what I'm saying but it shows you the
persuasiveness of our persuasion that
we're actually making end roads through
different access and points through
society and that Society is still trying
to you know still put it into its own
pedestal or hide it away still as
opposed to giving it what we actually
crave which is the freedom and the
desire for others to start being able to
go beyond the puffco Peaks to go beyond
these electric attachments Etc to find
the next better ingestion methodology or
modality that is you know again we have
to fight to legalize even simple
modality access much less what we're
actually em bibing and putting in them
so it's just interesting the steps and
that we've had to continuously to take
as we make our progress so it just
reminders people Eternal vigilance still
have to uh get out speak voice write
your letters protest and do the things
that you know got us here we ain't done
yet people are still in
jail the best thing we can do is is is
all of what etan just
said and also I'd like to just point out
that the Snodgrass family and the glass
blowing industry from the very beginning
in the early 90s felt those exact same
pressures where you know they started
grow blowing glass teaching everyone one
all of a sudden epicenter out of
Eugene next thing you know there's
serious money being made and all of a
sudden the government gets excited so
you know they they all of a sudden
couldn't you know people couldn't send
glass state to state next thing you know
people are moving here and there so you
know I think
adaptability is the
actual thing that we need to learn how
to be good at we need to be learn how to
uh we need to learn how to be good
adapting yeah it's not it's not survival
of the fittest it's the survival of the
most adaptable it's don't get
whack yeah and if it's whacka then we're
whacking our own Creations that we lift
up whatever is powerful right now we
have given power to and if we step back
and we look at it and we would start
recognizing what we want to feed and
what we don't want to feed that's just a
really important question if we're
talking about health and vitality and
wellness of the earth of the globe of
the people of the residents of this
Earth then we need to talk about what it
is that we're feeding that's a pathogen
and what it is that we're feeding that's
beneficial and I think that you know as
a human race we've been feeding a lot of
pathogens and then we've been calling
them they and that is our own doing
whatever they is is because we've given
that power that money that energy to
something that is also you know beating
us down um and I think that now that
it's 2022 we really can set out our
intentions and put our energy and our
kindness and our love towards the
beneficials to colonize the beneficials
to to procreate to
repopulate so I just think that I'm
super on that notion of health and
vitality and what that means and I think
it starts with each individual and so
just sitting with ourselves I like the
term resonance because it's the
Resonance of the ways but it's also has
the the word resin in it and then that
brings you to hash and then you realize
the hash the hash is just a Resonance of
the plant M and then there's it's kind
of this beautiful thing because the the
tricomes are crystals and then there's
that Cosmic enery and I like that and we
talk a lot about you know you have to
have a good beautiful plant in order to
have amazing hash and concentrates well
I mean that's the way it is in life for
some reason humans expect six for
everything but they put one star into it
so let's start putting six stars into it
and of course you're gonna get six stars
out that's just like what happens
whatever you put in you get out so like
Johnny B in the place yeah Johnny B has
been putting in six stars so he gets out
six stars and it's obvious and it's
really awesome um right you don't get
what you want you get what you deserve
and you work hard for it then you get
what you deserve so work hard for what
you want in your garden in your life and
anything that you do and you'll get what
you deserve that's what you only get one
life so I'm I'm talking here and talking
here it's awesome sorry guys but thank
you that's guys just keep growing do it
every day I gotta get my garden today I
can't wait to get out there taking some
time off like
yeah it's important
growth Hey
guys you're all super inspiring to me
every single one of you I appreciate all
of you
and with that said I've got to jump um
Marcus thank you for holding space as
always um everyone thank you for being
you and Wade sending you all my
love I really wish you well and keep us
updated love you man thank you bye
col
yes so I had a power outage last week I
apologize to everyone but uh the no
power thing was a pretty big deal
breaker I have a generator but I was
like do I really want to get my computer
and my um you know starlink uh up and
running on a generator so we just passed
but uh I'm glad we did a one today I I
want to hang out for another 15 or 20
minutes so if anyone wants to end it
with some inspiration something positive
something good definitely sending love
to everyone yes please go
ahead I I wanted to add in kind of in
line with what um Kelly was saying too
and getting back to like the
restoration um I think you know I I love
what you're doing with this group and
how it goes out and resonates because
it's bringing a lot of heartbeat back to
the culture which is really needed so
much these days it seems like for folk
tale and folklore and and to restore
human faith and trust in each other is
to tell stor and report back from the
human so you know the portal being the
cannabis plant to connect us together
all ancient and wise but I really really
really uh am thankful feel blessed to be
part of um being able to share stories
from with the folks
here and
outward D thanks for sharing that was
very well
said thanks for having me and definitely
in line with all the things that Kelly
said which were just beyond
inspirational and extremely well said as
well just appreciate all of you guys and
gals it's uh I am very glad I don't put
a lot of time and energy into building
the channel per se these days or my
Instagram it got disabled for the first
time ever recently and I was kind of
like I was like ah do I even want an
Instagram and other people like oh my
God like I would die if my Instagram oh
I froze am I back there I'm back so yeah
my Instagram got disabled I was like who
cares you know YouTube I don't really
put a lot of videos up but I do like it
for this for for this group of people to
invite together what we have here is is
is special for sure great group of
people who who listen and watch and uh
yeah I just have a a deep appreciation
for all of it the hash church is still a
special little thing and and and I love
the way you put it man like bring in
some heartbeats uh to the community Dash
industry uh and you know that faith in
humanity thing is a big deal as well
where it's easy to be a pessimist
nowadays especially if you consume like
bad media
247 that's like just eating poison um
you know 247 it's not it's not good for
you and uh it's uh easily accessible so
what my message would be to everyone is
uh stay positive get out into nature
enjoy plants enjoy fungi and uh yeah try
not toh let the division happen because
there is a clear division kind of
constantly you know this tension and I
think it's okay for the tension to be
there but doesn't have to be as tight as
it is right now so let's loosen that
tension much love to Wade much love to
etan Josh and Kelly Dr Mark Brian Johnny
B and the folks folks that have left
that'll be enough for me but I'll keep
it going for another 15 minutes so you
guys can all have a chance to wrap up as
well Marcus Wade is there anything that
some wisdom or anything you would like
to impart to us as you've been uh in
your new head space and mind space is
there some wisdom you'd like to share
with
us um
question um one of the things that uh
occurred to me recently is
um all of the effort that over the years
I put into understanding what's
necessary to create highquality
cannabis uh in terms of practices in the
garden and uh the soils that we built
and um the cultiv ours that we worked
with and uh some of the benefits that we
saw from those things um I've come to
realize that I that I want to bring that
same attention to detail that same
desire to understand what was going on
uh in this discussion like with hash you
know why we see different types of hash
from different environments different
moisture levels etc etc that whole
exploration of what's possible I'm um
I'm really feeling a deep commitment to
myself to understand my body more fully
to understand how it is that I like to
think of myself as someone who has lived
a good life who has always eaten well
who has always uh pursued good works uh
you know walk in light if you will uh
that how I end up in a situation of
having a cancer like this is fascinating
to me and I want to understand
what's going on there I I look back to
one of Kelly's observations about
pathogens and allies and how we have put
so much effort into creating pathogens
in our in our
environment um and it feels
like adapt to what we've done to our
environment what we've done to our uh
Zeitgeist if you will the entire ire
um sum of all our experiences and I one
of the reasons that I really love the
hash
Church concept the thing that we're
doing here is bringing that light each
of us in our own way work hard to
manifest that light with within
ourselves and in our work and we have
done very good at getting that word out
into the world but it feels to me like
for me at least right now
it's important for me to turn inward and
to really explore what's happening for
me and to understand how what's
happening for me is really to a large
extent happening for many people around
the world many of us are struggling with
uh toxins of one sort or another be they
from the media from our food from
whatever excuse
me uh
anyway um
yeah it just feels like a a time for me
to focus within and really understand
more fully my process I love Johnny be's
observations about how he's going about
changing his life each of us in our own
way are um Pioneers if you will and our
work over the years has been really
focused on pioneering ending prohibition
helping people understand what this
plant and our various allies can do for
us and now I think it's at least for me
it feels like it's a time for me to
understand more
fully what I can derive from this for my
own benefit as well as those that I love
I don't know if that made any sense at
all but there you go
that's made all the sense in the world
my friend I love you brother thank you
for sharing and being a guid iness stage
with us we appreci appreciate your wise
words of wisdom and appreciate you
greatly and wish you nothing but healing
love and sustaining energy so that you
can get back to how you are and where
you want to
be and I feel like that path inward is
the path of the true warrior the path
inward is the
path that we're all afraid to go
to the path inward is the path that
we're forced to when we've done
everything
outward this is the work that you're
doing is the work that heals all of
us the work of you going inward heals
the collective
Consciousness to places that we all need
I honor you I love you my friend my
brother thank you for doing the work
that so many of us need to do doing the
work that so many of us can't
do I have so much love and so much honor
for you in all of the journeys that
you've shared and you sharing that
you're going inward with your work is is
the greatest gift that you can give all
of us and nourishing your own
spirit so much
love I love all of
you you guys are all just awesome and
way you you give us that that push and
that that spirit and that drive and and
and the stories that you've told and and
the messages that you have given us over
the house churches and over time like
just today you touched my heart and I
appreciate you so much and I'm so
grateful to be able to sit here and talk
to you and and everybody here and and
and and the power we have as as a
community as this inner Inner Circle
that we've created over time and and and
this this growth that we have in
different parts of the world and what we
do as a driving force and and you're so
much a big huge part of this and created
a big inspiration within this community
and I want to thank you so much Mark and
everybody here who's been just dedicated
to this plan to this to coming to these
house churches it's like family guys you
guys are family and we're family to so
many other people and I want to thank
you all and um 2022 man it's growth guys
it's like Freedom right it's like
freedom and that's how I feel right now
Freedom with you guys and freedom with
growth weight and and Mark and everybody
here you guys give me tears man because
I love you guys and let's just do this
together man because the power with this
community is so strong and and I look at
where legalizations came from and what's
happened and and I can feel the force
within us now is just coming out just
going [ __ ] yeah let's do this guys 2022
way we got you we love you mark
everybody here thank you man it's like
bong R right
like that's it that's me just saying
yeah this is how great I feel every day
you can do it we can all do it it's
called decide make a choice do it for
yourself and everybody here man [ __ ]
love you guys thank you just had to say
that I know we all got this little bit
of Tears because we all have it inside
of you we all have that force in you to
just do this every day and I see it with
every one of you man just yes yeah I
just I gotta I gotta do bong rip now
it's just tears of joy man thank you
guys just so good right now appreciate
you so much every one of you all you
guys chat everybody other there is going
to watch this over time you guys rock
thank
you what I love about that Johnny is
just saying that everything's an
opportunity you know hardships are an
opportunity you know success is an
opportunity division you know
togetherness it's all an opportunity
when when we make it that way you know
so let's let's just try and find the
things that build us up and let's try
and find that commonality and come
together try do don't try do and if you
say you can't you're lying to yourself I
got that written on my wall if I say I
can't I'm lying because you can and
never stop believing in yourself I know
that so I words are powerful guys look
at those key words and change your
vocabulary change your life and I just
wanted to say um you know before we all
ended it and you know this isn't it or
anything but so much love for Daniel uh
and making his transition out of his
body three days ago four days ago now so
much love to Lane Creek hemp and uh you
know what an
incredible soil lover medicine maker
purely dedicated to his family to Dem
pure we um you know have gained an angel
on the other side we have gained so much
uh in knowing him and uh I just wanted
to really put that love out into the
universal flow for the broken hearts
over at Lane Creek hemp uh in his
passing and yeah
2022 um for all those yeah it's also a
time of rebirth and there's a lot of
people pregnant right now and you know
we just want to really give thanks for
that new that new life you know and that
new potential and that new you know
opportunity to learn from this wisdom
you know bringing in this new life and a
brand new season that we've never
encountered before we're getting ready
to have a brand new season that of 2022
of spring that we've never ever
experienced before so we can put
whatever seeds in the ground that we
want we can grow whatever it is that we
want to so we're going to sew the seeds
of love this here and and and bring
bring in love you know thanks
everybody Dr Mark the man of few words
today fin close us
out I've been on
mute well you know people like Wade are
are unique because
um I mean you think just not even
through the collagist network but how
many people have taken the
words and knowledge that this one human
has and
um brought new genetics and new
understanding to what the plant can
do and you know Wade you're a living
manifestation of the plant
itself you know I mean it's hard to tell
where the plant ends and where Wade
begins um uh so I I think that you know
I mean hopefully all of this um
community that that has come to your
support um is part of the healing energy
that brings you back uh to where you
need to be uh you know the skeletal
system is underpinned by the endoc
canabo system I think there's been some
very important work done over in Israel
to show that so let's hope by nurturing
your endoc can avonoid system it'll
bring you back to health and uh as you
know if there's anything I can do or
anything that this extended Community
can do for you just uh feel free to
reach out there should be a low low
barrier to reaching
out thank you
everybody Wade last words you want to
say goodbye to
everyone I love you guys that's about
all I got it's uh pretty special thank
you Marcus thank you everyone appreciate
the love right back love
you peace out everybody thanks for
watching maybe we'll see you next week
thank you love you everybody