then unmetered i just wanted to welcome
the people into the room that came in
which was Remo and Jeff and Ramon and
Rick and is that correct that maybe even
the skunk man is off-camera in in the
house at hashed Church episode 52 if I
talk do you hear me hell yeah that's
awesome guys Wow Wow so can we ask can
we ask them the origin of Hays please
but I'm not sure you can ask me much
that you don't already know but you can
try I got a question I got a really good
question which is he can't tell us a
secret on how you mix this great dry sip
sure but you have to over to my house or
I could shoot you afterwards I hope you
a I hope you're doing well Sam sounds
like you're keeping busy
dude I am brother I am hey Sam let's for
sure could you for sure talk a little
about skunk won and the impact obviously
that it made on indoor growing for us
all I mean know some of us sitting in
the room obviously know the story and
but it would be really nice to hear you
talk about skunk number one I'm not sure
what people on here but it was one of
the first indica sativa hybrids but what
was more unusual about it was that it
was fairly stabilized so that when you
grew it and you made seeds from it then
you pretty much got what you wanted a
lot of the other indica sativa hybrids
and there weren't a lot of them around
back in the mid seventies one skunk was
created but yeah it helped change but
also
other people complain that it was too
stinky and what it was stinky for him of
course was terpene so you can't win you
the best stuff is stinky
we like the stinky we didn't do so that
was something you put together in the
mid-70s skunk won really started in the
mid 70s yeah yeah it started in the mid
seventies correct was already available
by I think 70
78 at the latest Africa when was it
introduced to the Dutch scene because
obviously there are no Scouts involved
until 84 and then 85 seriously Wow and
it became a staple in the breeding lines
of almost everybody doing seeds as soon
as you introduce it was one of the
easiest plants to hybridize and get
predictable results with and often the
hybrids were better than either parent
so yeah people liked it for that wait
when did you decide you didn't like that
dank Afghani part of the skunk and
pretty much pretty much from the
beginning Aeryn what I what I had was I
had phases at the time which I loved
that's really what I was smoking and I
would smoke the skunk it was strong it
was really interesting if good blood
structure and added of it but it also
had that kind of high which was what I
thought I'm a narcotic couch lock and
that's not really what I like so I found
out that the sweeter ones were more
turns I work so for almost 10 years are
selected away from the skunk ear ones
there I brought it to the Netherlands
and we really like to go out to 20,000
feet what that allowed is selection of
plants which were really super the best
of
best and I selected ten of those girls
ten boys from those grows then take the
routes of the progeny and was able to
consist determine which combine the best
best progeny really easy look easy after
I selected to another large group of
plants thousands well from all of us
seed breeders who are out of here in the
world senior senior Sam skunk man thank
you very much for your contribution into
making our industry what it is today to
grow absolutely I'm I'm I'm really happy
that I helped tip the balance to what it
is today which is really unstoppable the
world governments have not admitted that
they've been defeated but the truth of
it is of course that the war on cannabis
is is completely lost
they're just punching it out a few
places I would say ditto from the hash
makers mr. skunk man Sam and we also
appreciate all that you've done to
severely tip the scales I give you props
all the time and being one of the people
that 100% inspired me into water hash
and into dry sift for certain so you
know you never know what it would be
like without you but I appreciate that
we don't have to wonder I look forward
to the day when anybody who wants to
smoke a legal cannabis product can get
you know dry said that's 92 even better
99.9 percent resonates and of their
favorite varieties that days is already
reachable by a few of us and will soon
be reachable by anybody who wishes it
yeah could you please talk about others
and the strain haze and its origin
because it's it's it's one of my
favorites as well years was really
started by
a friend of mine up in the hills of
Santa Cruz and he also a friend of Rob
Clark's he's also involved in this well
helping the guy what it was was a
combination of Hunter Rojas so also a
green Colombian and a long Colombia
though those three will combine to
create what was called the original
phase then some South Indian and Thai
genetics that I gave was added a little
bit later but that was not really the
original age that was sort of they later
would what you're describing as the
later haze be what some of us become
known as like the stuff that Neville was
putting out the no.5 by Hayes was
obviously very sure if he thought stuff
that had tire and or South Indian
genetics in it or if he got stuff that
was just plain to him because the
Columbian expressed Greek I am goldish
purple and the silver blues those are
all coming from just Columbian genetics
so I can't say I'm not sure after five
those checks genetic materials we might
have some of these answers where they're
not there's tire South Indian genes and
or not how many distinctly different
varieties of cannabis David exam do you
think there are like I don't know by
traditional is what I would consider a
variety and there was hundreds because
just just in South America there might
have been a hundred just in India there
might have been a hundred but it a few
hundred
what it really is boils down to is most
of them have only THC so it's the
terpene plus the THC maybe a few other
cannabinoids but those aren't really
making it recreationally better but they
might be useful for some other purposes
so while people like medical varieties
with CBD in them for example are the
terpenes and cannabis unique to cannabis
no 140 terpenes identified in cannabis
so far are also found in all kinds of
other plants - but but we know that the
hundred and forty five hundred and forty
that have been identified he Canada so
far might potentially be modified THC in
the other two methods whereas other ones
found other places they're not finally
canvassed a much more less likely to be
having anything to do with modifying
never thanks hey anybody else I'm sorry
I keep being the one that asked
questions but I could ask Sam questions
mr. Bovard - Sam I've got a question for
Sam uh time and time again I always go
back to kind of thinking about how you
were able to select and thinking about
tissue culture is it critical for anyone
who really wants to break ground and
breeding to have that skill like would
you think like when I think about
selecting between twenty thousand I'm
like when you smell it you may be you
know really really far away from base
camp um is that a gift that you have for
being able to do that like I'm just
thinking about all the people who fail
and thinking about going through a field
of twenty thousand like outdoor it seems
insane unless you had an innate gift for
that ability well look luckily I also
did have a colleague Rob Clark who
helped me with the
my large field Brady or large scale
greenhouse breeding Robert helped me do
the selection processes so that right
there cuts the numbers in half but if
you want to evaluate cannabis I suggest
you you need to grow large plants not
they don't have to be in the ground but
it's easier and were those numbers
around 20,000 for you Sam or were you
planting more than 20,000 was the number
that I was able to grow at that moment
at that time but yeah I mean if you it
depends on the variety and what's going
on the larger the numbers you work with
the better your results are going to be
in I am Not sure of tissue culture or
molecular biology is an important
cannabis breeding at this moment but it
is the future and if you don't know how
to do it you may need to have a team
that you're working with that assists
you in those aspects that you aren't
able to do yourself so did you always
travel like during the known harvest
season so that when you went to India
you knew you know this is coming down on
so I'm gonna be able to smell we tried
to but there wasn't always possible
sometimes I had to take it from dried
buds sometimes I had to get seeds from
people and not even see the plants
themselves not with that preferred but I
mean if you're in the area and that's
all you can get other times I had to use
second parties like Rob from connecting
for me in Yunnan China or many other
places since we've had a very long
relationship what is that down is that
dried shift say it's some sleaze tag was
it dry sift
no it's actually some great water hash
and Sleestak that you like it I like it
just as much as the day we were smoking
we're sitting right there hey Sam you
got dry seft
well what can I say
my favorite is usually dry sis but you
would be all over this yet let me tell
you as long as it's not dink I'm sure
you yeah it's just like Turk City right
here dude I still have memories of that
Sleestak dry sift let me tell you that's
about to worry about to turn California
out on Sleestak be here in a minute do I
have to say when I first saw it was it a
Sleestak or was it a Sleestak skunk one
cross that was the dry cept I can't even
remember it was oh no it was Pierce
least a Karen the first 50 saw yeah my
question to you Erin is has any of that
Sleestak been analyzed for cannabinoid
interpreting contact because that stuff
really is unusual to it so as always you
smoke it want to keep you up and for
more periods of time it's creative
forget it you know what I mean I like
you know for me that's like the Sleestak
is what really brought us all together
you know we had in Amsterdam by the name
of Matt a shout out to him he's in the
Alabama I think right now I had some dry
sips Sleestak in it was just amazing
it was amazing and it was just it wasn't
even really cleaned up and then he's and
I have already met Sam the skunk man
years before this at at birth at our
mutual friend Adam Adam's birthday from
th seeds and you know
so I Matt's like I got to show this dry
sift to say I'm a skunk man you know
because he says he can clean it up and
make it like the best right so he takes
this JA this nice jar of Sleestak takes
it over to him and then we get a phone
calls I can't you got to come over to
Sam's house you know and Sam's like yeah
I really couldn't clean it up it was
really clean and to like to a hash maker
that's like music to your ears when when
when the legend can't do much to your
material you know and it's just as good
it's it's like it's like winning a
cannabis cup for your first time or
something it's like yeah you know you
recognized by legend and he fell in love
with the strain to even more impressive
you know like here we are that just a
little experiment you bred something and
you you did it and here's a little bit
of first dry sip that came out out of it
and you're sitting at a legends house
smoking your hard work at the legends I
mean it was like a dream it was a dream
come true and to have them like it so
much and to have them want to play with
it and use it and grow it and do
experiments with is is truly an honor
you know and and I'm sure I'm sure
really [ __ ] thankful that I created
Sleestak you know it's just a little
experiment away you know those little
experiments turn out to be very
something very special later on and hey
you know and thank you for enjoying my
work because I've enjoyed your work for
you know since I was 12 years old I
absolutely enjoy smoking Sleestak tricep
and Rob Clark might enjoy slightly
better than me because he's really you
know a creative writing person and that
stuff he swears is the greatest for
creative variety because
it keeps you up all day so you know it's
but I also think it's brilliant do you
have the terpene and cannabinoid profile
or is there anything in every such THC I
I haven't I
we haven't done anything with it yet but
I can tell you yes we have a yeah it's
going to be in the greenhouse buddy I'll
just tell you that so we're gonna get
the whole expression here in a minute
I was always blown away that when that
Sleestak dry sift showed up because I
was also a big fan of it and I was lucky
enough to get to smoke a good good
amount of it it was so beautiful it had
such a great high it could keep you up
till 4:00 in the morning no problem like
it was insane but I really thought that
it would be something we just saw from
that day on I thought it was so special
that it would and then it was always
sudden that Sleestak disappeared and it
was like pho pho pho for like the next
10 years I didn't see any like killer
amazing like off the chain door I sift
Todd would have been happy he's all over
it he's all over the VHL but man I've
missed the DNA I got you bro I've missed
it
yeah dude it is amazing for certain so
yeah question of Tara for Ramon and Rick
and Sam how how is that freeze-dried
hash tasting just back to the driver
right I really liked it which one is it
yeah I liked it and the effect to it to
me it seems that like the THC level
might be a little bit less than some of
the other ones but I like the effect in
the way better I wish it was even
stronger monitors surface it's very
interesting tasting and effective and
that's what I like about Heather this is
the different jerkings
i mean it's it's not hard to find strong
THC it's it's hard to find
tgd with the turkeys that you might for
a particular taster of 837 people
watching and I've decided I'm gonna
write a song called I'm in love with the
terpenes I'll say the chorus with you
you're on the main character in the
video are you kidding me I'm just
singing I'm glad that we've reached the
level of understanding that we have even
if we just scratched the surface you
know can I ask you know Sam what was
some of the original streams that were
being passed around in the 80s by the
first seed companies and what was the
first seed company you know that would
be a great question to start with and
what was some of the strains they
offered the first seed actually of
course was sacred seeds that was 1976 in
Santa Cruz California I know because I
started it when we have original
offerings we had Hayes
we had skunk I think was the next year
and then we had Afghani number one which
I got from Jim Dublin and I had Hindu
Kush which and South Indian Kerala and
Durban poison so a lot of land races but
most and they were all true breeding so
that's was my focus at the time for the
first few years I was in the seed
business which one are you talking about
Horacio are you asking about the unknown
American that showed yeah the unknown
American question that we always have I
think we have to ask Neville because Sam
can't remember his name is that no no me
and Rob saw Neville about I will maybe
five or ten days after the Ameri
who had been staying with Neville for
the weekend or something left
and Neville showed us what the guy
showed us that showed him which was
grinding it up in like in the coffee
bean grinder type device and then
putting water in it and stirring it
again and then letting it settle out so
it was that's what but I can't remember
the name maybe under hypnosis I could
well you know what one day we'll hit
open it he'll he'll appear again he'll
he'll show up I mean was with me but he
doesn't remember either maybe you guys
were smoking that amnesia sift now we
weren't no I don't think never mostly
smoked cannabis with tobacco I know dude
the one time I was all excited I had met
him before actually but one time I ended
up upstairs at our Ian's apartment above
the greenhouse and it Howard Marks was
there and Neville was there and I was
with breeder Steve and I was like yeah
man this is what I'm talking about going
to talk to the old school dudes and then
they all literally except Arion like
steve and neville and howard all rolled
up hash in tobacco and I literally was
just like ah it's just one of those
experiences where you think it's why I
tell people don't get excited about
meeting the the your favorite band
because they probably won't be who you
want them to be well I can honestly say
I've accidentally taken one or two puffs
of tobacco in my entire life really
that's nasty
you must have given though like I would
love to have seen the mean mug and you
gave the guy who passed you a choice
with tobacco in it one time it was a sim
see so it was a titty Simpson beatnik
Bill Keith but you see Keith in Morocco
right hashish is not that marihuana
flowers mixed
my tobacco yeah so that's that's not
really what we're looking for okay sorry
yeah I can't do the tobacco for sure I
even in India you know where we're
smoking chill ohms on the side of the
Ganges River and everyone's like no no
you must put tobacco in there and I'm
like you know I must not just with the
ganja instead of tobacco and hash and
then like that you know an interesting
note on the terpenes ratio is someone in
LA stopped me at an early cannabis
industry meeting and he thought I was
responsible for oh gee and I corrected
him but I he he had gotten a clone he
knew it was for me
back when I got out of prison pretty
much in the 405 Oh six and he basically
told me when he was doing terpene test
that it was coming back with a very wide
panel and he likened it to like a box of
Crayola crayons
he's like once you get your hands on a
box of 64 colors in the box you never
want to go back to eight and what he
thought was is that even though the
crayons weren't full like that wasn't
you know complete terpenes profiles like
if you will really rich ones of each he
goes there was a little of everything in
OG he says and what he thought the
reason why oh gee became so popular is
because there was a terpene for everyone
like if you look in a box of 64 colors
almost everyone's gonna find a color
that they really like but if they look
in a little box at 8 they'll be like me
you know and and and I thought that was
an interesting comparison for what it's
worth hey Doc I have a question for Josh
and this it's Sam Josh hi Sam my
question is okay you got the clone from
some folks in Florida I believe did they
breed it did they just grow some seeds
and find it did they get the clone from
somebody else story as I know it is they
got the seed out of a bag that they
purchased
was that the Grateful Dead thing it's a
thing that comes from these two guys in
Orlando in around 92 93 that are friends
with Bubba that are friends with I think
some of his buddies and that's how it
ended up in their hands and they were
breeding between 90 when they you know
they were already breeding at this point
and those seeds I believe you know
that's where there's a couple other
varieties that they've come up with that
even made it to Los Angeles and I'm not
sure where that variety is now but uh
you know do the original genetics is
something to be found out no that's it's
part of the reason I even came out and
started doing this is you know I have a
long story in history with this but
there is a history before it it's just
super interesting to find out what that
is right and maybe if we're lucky the
Philo's work might allow us to discover
it but there's no guarantee that we will
because if for example if you take an
Afghan and a Colombian and the Mexican
and then you breed it to itself from a
population level for ten generations
it's gonna come out with a lot of
different ratios depending on what seeds
you using at the end there you
understand what I mean absolutely so
some will be almost totally sativa some
will have more Afghan some will be more
like I mean it's just there's just no
predicting what 10 self generations will
do if anyone is interested in doing some
project with the cut that I have I mean
I'm I'm down for sure
set send me send me an email mark can
tell you how and what you can do also is
where are you on the east coast or the
west coast I'm in Washington up in the
Seattle area
so it's really easy you could turn it
into one of the labs of Washington who
will send a bread to Philo's for DNA
analysis that would be cool
what could okay that'd be really cool
III think it'd be really nice weren't
just really in landraces but anything
else is interesting also are you able to
maybe explain to the audience as well
what what that is you're talking about
because they don't know I don't think
they all know about the project and we
almost have 900 people listening right
now so okay I'll give it a real short
rundown I'm I'm not the greatest world
speaker but here basically what we're
doing is we're extracting the DNA from
either seeds or leaves which will allow
us to conduct or create a family tree
for cannabis that'll show both
relationships and evolution we might be
able to say that everything evolved from
this variety I doubt we will but that's
theoretically possible or we'll be able
to say that this variety is related to
this variety and this variety meaning
that all the cannabis in Africa
originally came from India or originally
came from Asia or it came from and the
same thing all the cannabis in Jamaica
it had to come from someplace Africa
India well in a few years we might be
able to answer most of these questions
with DNA analysis we're not trying to
grow the plants we're not trying to
making some sort of living DNA library
were the genetics to be stolen and we
have been interested and then a that
kind of GMO craft but I am interested in
in the relationships and the evolution
of cannabis
not a question for sad about the Durbin
someone's asking if he came to South
Africa to collect the Durban poison
not only today that good South Africa
but others been there but I've never
been there but where I got the seeds for
South African were from Jim Goodwin and
he got them from Edie Rosenthal who got
them from a coffee shop in Amsterdam
called the trance key seventies but when
I grew them my greenhouse in Santa Cruz
County that it gave were all
hermaphrodite so I had to select out the
one or two that were theast
hermaphrodite well it was interesting
though so what I did was I selected out
the team that were the least made seeds
from those grew those next year and I
did that for about four I maybe even
five years but at least four and then
what I had was a variety there was
hardly hermaphrodite at all and that was
my German poison South African so I did
get the seeds from somebody else but I
did all the work to clean them oh and
yeah at the time it was the earliest
thing that people could grow in Canada
for example outdoors awesome well they
appreciate the the answer the guy from
South Africa is giving you a shout out
saying that whether you know it or not
you change the game down there okay the
other thing about South African is I've
grown several other South Africa
varieties that were not as early as that
one that one really is early but
whatever I mean if there's ours it's
good that should be the goal everything
else is secondary to quality for me
true enough and I mean you've always
pretty much from I don't know if it's
been from day one or not but maybe you
could answer this when it became
prevalent or when you became aware that
you would be breeding for hashish not
for cannabis to be rolled into joints
and smoked you know we've we've done
this we've done it a bit but nowhere
near as much as we'd like because some
varieties like skunk and Sleestak also
it very much so when it's dried and
cured a little bit the resin can be
knocked off much much easier than many
varieties some varieties like Hays it's
difficult to knock it off I don't know
if the resin is stickier or if the
adhesion layer is different I I don't
know what the exact mechanics are but in
the future also - you don't want hashish
that that when you harvest it it falls
off and you don't want it when it's
hanging and drying it falls off so
there's a fine line between convenience
and stupidity that's for sure hey I had
another kind of good question I just
thought of in regards to whether you
think that you know oil whether it's
butane oil or propane oil or ether oil
or alcohol oil or even rosin whether you
consider those to be hash and then Part
B - that question would be what do you
think about this rosin thing that's
taking everyone by storm
I have zero against rosin rosin with a
however it's pronounced to me
it's hashish no solvents are being used
it's being heated that's true but in
fact that could have been done in the
60s or 70s if you wrapped fashion so
famous tweeted stick hot and hard enough
need to get a little bit of rosin but
nobody was manufacturing it by the large
amount but all but what makes its
difference is solvent when solvency and
waters not a solvent it's used in some
suspension agent so it's just like air
for dry safety but a solvent whether it
be you know petroleum ether or butane or
propane or ethyl alcohol or whatever
even co2 that's fundamentally different
I'm not saying they can't make a totally
clean safe product I'm saying it's not
really hash it's more in the direction
of an oil or a glassed or an absolute
whatever so to me it's fundamentally
different but I understand that
I'm arbitrarily drawing the line in the
sand but luckily I had people like you
to pretty much feel the same way I do I
can ask a question and it's about
polyploid and I thought I had one back
in 1997 I had a plant that when cannabis
froze it pops two stems out and then
grows a little higher hops two stems of
in the opposite direction and does it
again and this one went up pop four
stems up went up top four it stems up
when I opt for and I just posted a photo
of this privately in our little Facebook
message thing but I'll post it publicly
but I wanted to ask Sam what what what
was the plan I had and you know what and
then again what is a polyploid way to
you Todd what you're mixing EPS is what
what's called world pilot Oxnard's world
finest oxy means that the internodes do
what you're talking about
polyploid you can't tell if a plant is
polypoid
by physically looking at it it what you
have to do is test the chromosomes to
see whether it has two sets or three or
four or whatever you think it is
whether it's a triploid or Ted
played or whatever like Sam does it make
a difference when growing or breeding
like um we're both mean how are both
looking at this uh article where on this
guy's going on about different strains
being really tetraploid or diploid and
he has so much theory that it becomes
way too much to read it's not true and
you look in nature all you find is
diploid I mean maybe a few people have
made tetraploid varieties I did a little
bit of experiments with it but none of
the varieties are tetraploid unless
somebody's making one but then they'd
probably be advertising there's a guy up
in Canada what's his name Billy Budd or
that's exactly who we're talking about
ah push ok we'll test test it send a
leaf to Philo's I'd have to buy his
clones and they they have a bad
reputation
ok no I strongly suspect that I have not
tested it so I cannot say absolutely
that it's not tetraploid and can just to
clarify we hadn't had no one said it
what was the what was the effect that
the plant I had or I saw I had with four
stems instead of two at each
intersection taxi it just happened
read about it in with Wikipedia world
file a taxi yeah my 20 year old Jamaican
seed came up with that exact thing
producing the extra a third instead of a
tube yeah it could make two for three
whatever
just for the same time how do you spell
this wonderful new word to my vocabulary
well world we know how to spell world WH
o are LED horrible and filer toxic PHY
l.a.x
why I'm guessing but hey I'm the world's
worst speller what or maybe you'll find
it on that on that genetic subject
though I had a question for you learn
when you look at on the surface of a
leaf and you look very closely at the
formation on a grid level of the
trichome heads that are forming you
actually see them in a grid and those
strings tend to be really good pass
trains for obvious reasons because
they're spread out with bigger heads and
then sometimes in a very strange
variation or expression in the gene or
plant they you'll see that same surface
area and they're the stalks fight for
the surface the surface area that's
there creating a almost like a chaotic
expression of stalks trying to get in
every little space and they produce
heads as well maybe not as big but it
creates a very hard to wash or extract
type of plant so what what kind of
genetic expression would that be linked
to in this poly or truck I'm not sure it
has anything to do with polyploid I
think more likely it's just a different
variety of resin stem type because
there's so many different types but like
I'm sure you've seen it that there are
types of resin that quite literally even
after you've dried it for two weeks you
cannot touch it it'll just smear its
like oil and there's other resin which
says like Sleestak which after two weeks
I just I mean it falls off like golden
and it's beautiful
so yeah I we haven't gotten to that
level yet where we understand the DNA
and the genetics of this but eventually
I'm sure people well now that they'll
use it to
use DNA assisted breeding so that they
can screen thousands of little tiny
seedlings and only grow the plants that
have what it is that they're after so
I'm sure that in the future two or three
the Dutch police put out scratch and
sniff cards so that in torment
neighborhood police type people could
smell what cannabis smells like and
coffee smell number one no wood street
Sam what strain do you think they like
they I'm pretty sure candy crush they
got that [ __ ] I remember that day now I
don't know what variety it was but it
was terpenes commonly found in drug
cannabis that's what they used and it
was a scratch-and-sniff
they also send out this little card and
say hey if you see this on your
neighbor's building and in the
wintertime it snows but like there's
some rooftops that look like yeah well
there's for some reason the snow is
melted right in the certain spots and
there's like they had a little tiny
portable battery-operated helicopter
that they flew around with a sensor that
could sense terpenes and they looked for
cannabis terpenes from the air but only
at suspected houses they didn't do the
general entire city they would go to a
place that was under suspect and they
would sniff it and say yep it's there
dan that's like taking a good idea and
using it for bad
yeah I tell you I can tell you right now
that somebody's like back at their phone
or something got some of my which I
think what terpene it was I think it
might have been Lemon skunk but went
like went out of the country didn't have
any cannabis on him at all
nothing just had the presence of
terpenes and had another dog let it
basically come at him like the dog was
like across the airport as a paw whoa
like I could bolt it right for him like
it was just terpenes being on him they
trained dogs internationally with Terry
awfully and maybe other ones also but
Terry awfully and they used to train
since we got so many growers in the room
people asked me a lot of question and it
goes both ways now people have used on
teas like even you know blueberry tea on
two to feed their plants during the end
um Sam how much do you find nutrients
can sway or carry over into the plant
whether it be a fish hydrolysate which
has its own fish ash terpene or using um
flavored teas to impregnate the plant um
is it are we
is that real and how far does it go like
our people use the different nutrients
and their taste
you can totally affect the taste of your
cannabis with nutrients you ever tried
turbinator or we gets us Terminator
flavor doesn't you know it's weird
anybody else wanna chime in well would I
find effects cannabis taste the most is
growing your plants organically to their
full potential with lots of lots of tiny
roots and big plants but that said I'm
sure that some different organic foods
must have slightly different but I'm not
sure about you know feeding it molasses
to make it taste like molasses or
blueberry
to make it taste like blueberry that I
think that's go ahead a bit far but
never use too much no no but if you ever
use too much bat guano your weed gets a
bat whoa no taste to it like you can
overkill it with some of the stuff yes
olia playing effect oh no not in the
negative way I meant that as long as you
can organically grow great great fine
tiny roots lots of them then your
cannabis is probably going to taste
pretty good can we ask you sandy what's
your feeling on flushing cannabis in the
end of its cycle of flowering I
primarily grow in the ground and I grown
big you know ten feet tall you know
three kilos plus whatever so I don't
flush them I when I plow the ground in
the springtime before I plant I use
organic amendments and I time it so that
it'll be pretty much sucked dry by the
end of season that I try out again next
spring
have you seen like when you've done
flushing experiments do you find what
would be the difference in your case I
mean you're going at it organically so
from the start a lot of people will say
low men it should be fine
but does it affect the smoke does it
affect the sift or people depleting the
plants of something critical
I find that plants taste better when you
feed the soil so that the soil could be
the roots feed the players when you
force feed the plants I think you can
get higher yields but I don't think you
get a better taste I don't know anybody
who forced feeds tomatoes to get a
better tasting tomato than has grown
from heirloom varieties tomatoes grown
for tastes organically but that's you
know what
fertilizers definitely alter yields and
actually that's the whole thing about
modern technology was the advent of
fertilizer to get higher yields with
food crops for farmers that was the
whole point of fertilizer
yeah well higher yields is important but
higher quality is more important I don't
know I can get some pretty good high
quality off right actually what I do
isn't entirely organic I have a vegan
program actually uh I find giving my
plants vegan stuff actually gives it a
nice clean flavor and you get like at
the end nice ass at the end free burning
you know tastes great if if it works I'm
sure it must be as you know I don't
smoke marijuana at all alright I'm
strictly a reson smoker I like that
stuff so that's cool we do not I guess
tricep tricep rocks yeah I I probably
smoke less herbal cannabis than mark and
Mark pretty much avoids it I don't smoke
it at all or I tried to do less than
that no it's not that I am against
marijuana for people that like it that's
their choice but the main thing with me
is to me
marijuana's strictly the the messenger
and hashish is is the message we're
sport almost welcomes least actor well
whenever you do get at Sleestak analyze
for both cannabinoid and terpene content
preferably different mother
not just from seed seeds from it but the
original mother I am really curious
Aaron alright
it's gonna happen Sam I guess I got
another question while we've got another
gap when it comes to indoors is
obviously um even though you have the
lucky luxury of being able to perfect
the outdoor grow when it comes to
indoors how many dip how far does light
go in affecting cannabis like when
you've seen those I've seen these crazy
you know when the guy has 50 25 watt
fluorescent bulbs and he's wrapped the
plant in it like a mania
um and I look and I'm like he seems to
be getting a result it's not
commercially viable but how often do you
see lights playing a critical factor in
directing the wave the genetics express
themselves to be honest I might be the
wrong person to ask because I've grown
primarily outdoors and in greenhouses
with natural sunlight so I'm not the
real right guy to answer about lights I
I have little crop experience with
lights
I maintain plants with artificial lights
for long periods of times that cold
temperatures for suspended animation but
that's about it well but you get I I
assume everyone brings you there bud to
smell and then hopefully convert to hash
do you basically get anything make your
strains back and you're like and I'm
like when do you basically go this
indoor [ __ ] is there's a reason why you
don't [ __ ] with it and you know it in
your nose I would say indoor stuff
that's grown under lights that I would
like the clone of grown outdoors in the
ground organically is to be really good
the trouble is a lot of it's grown
chemically and it's force-fed to try to
maximize yield and they're really
interested in really fast results rather
than
the highest of the highest of the
highest quality like you would do want
to make for your own grandmother
oh wait Horatio people don't just bring
Sam stuff like that it doesn't usually
work work that way you know I'm saying I
don't know I assume you guys obviously
get to us a way mortar profiles then at
least I imagine that's kind of why I'm
like well if every year in Amsterdam for
your whole life is the best of the best
being brought out you do eventually get
a sense of like you'll see og over and
over and over again and then go man
nothing smells like 95 what was it about
that guy to be honest it's it's not
really true number one is i when people
would come and visit me I as a raw
didn't make cash out of their there
their way I mean that's a lot of work a
few times maybe Aaron might have brought
some pretty clean resin which I either
was able to clean up a little bit for or
in a few cases like he mentioned I
couldn't even clean it up for because it
was so good but you know they they got
clever and clever or so if nobody else
flushes in fruits and harvesting then
what are we really talking about in a
sense because the plant doesn't have
salts in the buzz when people
traditionally grew cannabis
hydroponically they pumped it up to get
very fast growth they would use carbon
dioxide they would use all kinds of
extra nitrogen they wanted to pump it up
and get it through wham bam thank you
ma'am
so it's then in that situation maybe you
do need to flush it at the end because
you've had it on such a high level in
the first place
whereas organic what you're doing is
you're feeding the soil and there were
some microorganisms are breaking down
and the roots are picking it up from
there so it's indirectly you and that
you you're not forced feeding them and
that unless you've got incredibly high
nitrogen levels but most organic farmers
are aware of that someone's asking about
Sam and if you've ever heard of the
black African was an old strain her and
some things of would take an old head -
no does that sound familiar well as as
far as I know black African was because
it was either compressed like a corn
cobs or buried under the ground and it
may or may not have been affected by
various microorganisms may or may not be
so healthy for you so true black African
there might also be weed that's black -
I've seen black I'd seen a Vietnamese it
was black and I've seen other sativas
almost black it could be either you're
talking about Sam then I was started to
these two Peter sitting here next to me
who were handed me some various assorted
there
Rosen's and I told them I was gonna
smoke without tonight you've always
known some pretty cool amigos haven't
you Sam it helps it helps like how many
years ago did you meet the infamous haze
brothers well the original haze brother
was doing work up in the hills in the
late sixties time--even in 72 but I one
of them lived across the street from me
and one of them lived down the street
from me so they were both there because
the first days brother did it alone for
a couple years then he was working with
the other A's brother who actually lived
close to me and yeah so what 72 72 and
all the was done by the first taste
brother but that was the second brother
who were not really brothers but just
friends who added South Indian and Thai
for me very cool
exotic flavours I'm a huge haze fan
myself it's no no secret that I my son's
middle name is haze I'm like super
stoked on the haze it always made me
happy like literally just the smell of
that sort of spicy exotic flavor that
the haze is often would give you in the
air but hey it was hard to beat it
really is right hell yeah
super awesome I'm giddy that you came on
Sam thanks Rick and Ramone for bringing
salmon to be yeah you're very welcome
our cute local you know that I love hash
Church and I love what you do I'm just
kind of a shy guy so hey off-camera
anytime you are welcome we really
appreciated hearing from you and your
stories and I know that this is going to
be the hash search that gets the most
views and the most people talking about
it and that's thanks to you know a big
thanks to you coming in for certain I
also want to thank Josh and Bubba for
coming in and Todd for setting that up
it was great to hear it was great to
hear your guys's history you know it was
great to hear your perspective and I
like the way you share it I think it's
positive and I appreciated you coming on
to hash Church I'm sure we'll have you
guys back on again one day as well my
pleasure having you having you both on
and of course thank Club zero
Club zero can do something on the
regular on Sundays and have a gathering
with people coming in make them a little
bit more of a part of what's going on
maybe it'll be a regular old people who
chants they speak on the panel to come
up to the camera and say you think so we
thanks for having you guys do something
weekly here there's a lot of people here
just kicking it if you check it out the
bar hey everybody say hi to hash Church
yeah we're trying to get it on the big
screen next time hear it thanks Jeff
posted it's awesome extract that right
there is the the inhalation station of
vaporization yeah good stuff it's that
the ratio always a pleasure brother
thanks for coming on and sharing your
questions and your knowledge with us we
do appreciate it and for for those that
are no longer with us we thank dred for
coming in Tony as always kinda hilarious
today with his Terp sauce that was just
absolutely absolutely ridiculous how
many flavors he dropped on there so we
thank you for your in your unique
perspective we had nurse Heather on with
us earlier and a whole variety of people
I think D 420k for being with me today
freshen up the rosin filling up dry sift
non-stop bringing me glasses of water a
true true friend D 420k the dry sift
general Sam you would love d 420k is
hash I can attest so everyone thanks for
coming out the hash Church 52 we really
appreciate it and we hope to see you
guys next week peace out peace everybody