all right looks like things went not
quite how I thought they would but here
we go welcome everybody to Hash Church
5.0 episode five GNA quickly let some
folks in
here quickly quickly let some folks in
here looks like we started in a new room
but that's 0
okay share that down hey guys how's it
going let's see oh Dr Ethan Russo in the
house nice and on time bro that is what
I'm talking about right
there yes David are we gonna see
you maybe we'll see his Dr Seuss little
stuffed animal there it is oh that's
that's really what I meant yes
absolutely Dave's always uh he's like me
he always has uh technical difficulties
this morning I um I had a few myself the
the episode didn't start where it should
have started but that's okay we are live
we got 55 people in the room checking us
out and uh yeah I'm excited to hear from
you today we got a bunch of cool people
coming in I don't know if you know Davis
Allen he's doing some research over at
the University of British Columbia with
Chris gasa who's I guess a Harvard
student who's also over at UBC uh doing
some work there and they're coming in to
talk about land races and a bunch of
other fun stuff so should be uh good to
catch up but it's nice to see you man
it's been a
while
gotta hello
etan hello
everybody uh Dr Russo thank you very
much for joining us sure uh want to
thank
you um for 16 years ago I reached out to
you after I reached out to the
University of Mississippi to get the
information on how to test cannabis and
uh they told me of course to in so many
words to um get lost and I contacted you
and you helped me put me in touch with
Dr haac comp so I want everybody to know
that you were help F and responsible in
the early days for making sure of
independent testing for cannabis back in
the dark days so I just want to
acknowledge you and thank you for that
because of course you set us
inadvertently down a path that changed
cannabis and I have to thank you
forever you're
welcome very nice very nice well good to
see everyone on this uh Beautiful Sunday
morning I've got my sling off so my arm
is still completely broken but it feels
amazing not to like be slinged up in my
uh on on my uh on my chest here hey good
morning Davis this is Davis Allen he's a
close close pal who just lives across
the way uh in uh on Bowen Island
actually or is from Bowen Island I'm not
sure if you're living there anymore but
you are tuning in from Bowen today
correct yeah I'm actually living on
Bowen Island right now but yeah okay
okay awesome very cool well good to have
you dude man I'm I'm looking forward to
uh to uh some of the conversations Davis
reached out uh oh geez it's probably
been a couple weeks ago now and he said
hey you know I'd like to come on hash
Church which lot lots of people do and I
was kind of like all right well Davis is
a smart guy he's doing some good things
I I asked him kind of well what you know
what kind of conversations are you
thinking that we that we might get into
you know just because I I like to have
an idea when when someone new is coming
on that uh we figure out what kind of
conversations we're having and he hits
me up with well you know there's four
areas I'm interested in um land race
strains collected from isolated regions
chemical profiles ratios observed in
specific region regions and theories
behind either biodiversity or selections
of traits done by local cultivars
morphology and traits of Interest
pathogen environmental resistance
observed from various regions and then
breeding development of new F1 lines
from inbred land race heirlooms true
breeding hyd hybrid lines selection from
environmental pressure and stress tests
the pharmacology research on major
cannabinoids potential therapeutic use
other than THC I.E CBD CBG cbdv Etc uh
potential isolated compounds from
cannabis for future medical use and then
organic cultivation yeah no no it's not
it's not actually all Dr Ethan Russo
then he goes into organic cultivation no
till soil sustainability operating costs
cover crops pest manag via mineral
content in soil and beneficial insects
and sub irrigation benefits versus top
water sounds like he a show of his song
dude I'm telling you he came up with
some pretty good uh things here and in
fact his colleague Chris is coming into
the room right now as well uh who's a
PhD researcher that he mentioned is
involved with genetics and biodiversity
at UBC and he's also interested in
chatting about genetics in depth uh so
welcome Chris good timing there dude you
came in right like at the perfect time
to uh give you an
introduction thanks margus yeah man good
to uh good to uh meet you and have you
here I feel like today's conversation is
going to be a doozy uh everyone's early
welcome Dr Mark shalone into the room we
got some Heavy Hitters in the room today
I like it man I like it I'm all about uh
promoting incredible dialogue that's
what hash church has always been about
uh pretty loose in the the sense but uh
you know we've got Dr Ethan Russo here
to begin with so I was figuring we would
start with with him and kind of let him
get into some of what he wants to talk
about Ethan uh clearly doesn't need uh
an introduction but I'll give him one
anyway it's just an awesome awesome guy
has always been so humble and kind and
helpful and facilitating and uh it's
just nice to have you here do Ethan
Russo so uh yeah let's get right into it
man what uh I I believe one of the first
topics you had mentioned was cbga THC
and lemon for anxiety did I get that
right yeah CBG so canab gereral anyway
it's a pleasure to be here on what I
call Ash Temple at least during my
appearances um but yeah you know we've
had uh two Publications this year the
first one that came out was uh with
Folks at John's
Hopkins um we've been trying for a long
time time
to do what I call a a deconstruction
reconstruction of cannabis components to
try and show Synergy so the idea was to
follow up on experiments that um Dave
Watson and I did more than 20 years ago
um basically to use uh different amounts
of THC and loning and show alteration of
THC effects so that's basically what was
done uh the clear result of this study
uh which lead author uh was Tori spindle
so this is available free for download
at Ethan russ. org at the library tab uh
it should be one of the top articles so
anybody can access it there without
going through a pay wall or anything
else but basically what happened was uh
a sufficient dose
people in the study um had anxiety
induced by THC which was vaporized and
this is all double blind um but with the
addition of lyine in a sufficient dose
there was a clear reduction in the
anxiety um and people can argue with the
amount that was in there um you know we
addressed uh this possible criticism in
the article because the top dose loning
was 15
milligrams uh which would be hard to
achieve in many types of cannabis but
there are kavars that are particularly
rich in loning and actually can equal or
exceed the amount of THC particularly in
type three plants um so what we did is
not Pure Fantasy also people may realize
that I've always been a proponent of
whole cannabis extracts but in this
instance again we had to separate
components um without using herbal
cannabis that uh would just have too
many other factors that would complicate
uh trying to interpret the results so
again I call this a deconstruction
reconstruction the other study um was
done with uh colleagues at Washington
State University krie C is the lead
author and again available at Ethan
russ. org at the library tab in this
study we wanted to show and really
highlight what canaberal CBG can
do um we done a previous survey same
team uh that was published a couple of
years ago um in cannabis and canabo
research and it was just a survey of
people using CBG predominant material
and the results were surprising because
uh all kinds of claims were made about
medical benefits um people saying that
it the CBG preparations were better than
conventional medicine um and very very
significantly help with anxiety so we
tested that
proposition and um we used uh tincture
uh that was supplied by sheno Los um it
was uh pretty pure um this was a CBG
without any significant amount of TC or
CBD um and the only turp of any
concentration was kopine but um really
not a very high Tighter and unlikely to
have psychoactive effects of its own in
any event CBG in a double blind study
that was done over zoom on tests of
induced anxiety like counting down from
13 from a high number and restarting
every time you made a mistake um showed
a very significant reduction of anxiety
this is a with a dose of 20 milligrams
of CBG as compared to
Placebo um surprising result was there
was actually Improvement in verbal
memory uh with CBG so certainly no
evidence of impairment uh there was no
particular drug liking uh so it's really
a unique result showing an anti-anxiety
effect without any
sedation um we already know that CBG has
no drug abuse liability there's no
withdrawal um so this is really a
spectacular agent that uh deserves a lot
more attention um particularly here in
the Northwest there are CBG only uh
flower preparations and
tinctures but additionally CBG and
higher
concentrations uh with THC seems to do a
really spectacular job in allaying uh
anxiety that's induced by THC so it's
possible to still be high and have all
the benefits there from uh without
simultaneously getting paranoid or
anything else um with right preparations
so anyway that was
long-winded interesting it's interesting
that something that is a precursor to
THC could be good for anxiety when not
everyone but there certainly could be
people to speak about the potential
anxiety induction that can happen from
taking
Inc um I I've always kind of not so much
felt it on wide Leaf uh drug cultivars
but that terpinolene rich narrow Leaf
drug cultivars is where I have
definitely felt um a little bit of that
anxiety I never felt it my whole life
until I broke my cix and when my cix was
broken and my whole core was just
shattered and I was just having a really
hard time I accidentally ended up taking
some dabs of I think it might have been
whereas my bike which was that biker
cush crossed with Amnesia Hayes from uh
Karma genetics and I'll tell you man
that was the first time first what it
did was it exasperated my pain instead
of taking it away and then after it did
that it gave me a full-blown anxiety
attack which I had never had before but
I certainly became um cognitive and sort
of empathetic uh to those that had told
me that they had had this happen before
um lately since I broke my uh clavicle
I've been taking quite a bit of THC um
gummies just you know maybe like 50 to
60 milligrams a day which is quite a bit
for me I take like 10 10 at a time and
I've had no anxiety and it's just been
the most incredible pain relief that I
have ever experienced clavicle is a
pretty shitty bone to break not that
there's good ones but it's a painful one
you don't realize how often you move
your shoulder and how often you you feel
it so I've uh it's always neat I Wade
was speaking to this last uh week in
regards to how he's able to use cannabis
for sort of really the first time in his
life to really feel the effects of it
for um you know for what he's been
suffering with which has uh been a a
form of cancer so shout out to Wade
hopefully he's doing okay today and
we'll see his smiley face in here uh
wanted to welcome uh Mojave into the
room and uh I believe it's etan's friend
and colleague Michael uh krowitz who's
also in the room I wanted to recognize
those guys as well as Colin Palmer snuck
in I see you there homie I see you there
so yeah awesome guys just uh interesting
if anyone else has anything they want to
uh ask or or speak to what Dr Ethan
Russo just shared feel free to uh to
chime
in I just want Tok you very much for
your work it has helped many people it
continues to help people of course
needless to say people are tuning in
because you know you're at the tip of
the spear usually and uh you know
curious about um where you're Spears
headed
currently well we're gonna do a lot more
with
CBG uh for sure Carrie Cutler uh my uh
collaborator on uh prior to CBG studies
we've got two more planned um one is
going to uh be with a higher dose I'd
point
and she's going to do this as an inlab
study um so uh they might be a little
more aggressive and trying to induce
anxiety and they'll be looking at things
like blood pressure and response to
what's called a cold pressor test how
long it takes you um to have pain when
your hand and arm are in uh really cold
water um and how much anxiety that
produces um so that one's coming up
additionally we're going to do a
clinical study of a um well it' be a
formulation of my design it definitely
has CBG in it and that will be to treat
menopausal symptoms
uh so those are
upcoming uh beyond that um we've
got uh study about uh educational needs
um in relation to
cannabis um we've got a another big
review on IM myotrophic lateral
sclerosis uh again we're doing a bunch
of formulation work and there's always
uh new stuff coming along on the uh
John's Hopkins side um we've done
additional studies with uh Alpha pining
at
THC and there's going to be one with uh
mercing in THC at UCLA with Zea Cooper
she's looking at uh beta caropine in THC
in relation to pain so always a lot
going
on incredible go
ahead I'd asked this question question
on the uh on the U um webcast that you
recently gave I forget I don't know it
was a webcast maybe about a month or so
ago sure this and uh first of all again
thank you for this wonderful work um so
uh it had to do and I think we actually
responded you responded by email and you
sent me a reference on a recent study
that looked at the pharmaco kinetics of
CBG
uh but I guess my other question is is
what is this hitting is this hitting 5hd
or do you know how it's anti-anxiety
mechanism yeah the anti- anxiety effect
it's probably complex it may have to do
with serotonin receptors but um I'll be
honest I've studied serotonin receptors
for decades um and it's ceaselessly
complicated because they do different
things different places um they can do
different things at the same uh receptor
site um so if I had to explain it I
couldn't I would just say that we know
that um CBG increases Gaba activity and
so the anti-anxiety effect May well be
mediated uh through Gaba which is an
inhibitory
neurotransmitter um so uh more work
needed there but the bottom line is that
this is really an amazing anti-anxiety
agent uh for people who are aware of
pharmacology just about every
anti-anxiety drug is simultaneously
sedating Andor addictive and that's just
not the case here so this really may be
what Society currently needs everybody's
been through the ringer the last several
years whether it's um economic stress
pandemic War you name it um so I think
personally that CBG is the answer uh to
a lot of PE what people might think of
if they need a little pharmacological
help with all that
stress and you think cbga too has its
place there I'm sure you saw this I was
fasinated by this and I'm surprised
actually this study didn't get more
light but about a year and a half ago um
a group reported that
cbga shuts down store operated calcium
entry which is part of the um
inflammatory sort of cascade if you will
and may actually be one of the
underlying mechanisms that canabo in
particular cannabinoid acids are are
anti-inflammatory so do you think cbga
just because that extra acidic group
there could be some additional and I
guess where I'm going after here Ethan
so if you were ingesting like cvga flour
so if you're ucing it or somehow getting
the whole flour is there a nature uh to
wanting to have both the acid and the
decarbox material I'd say yes often uh
these combinations of the acids and
neutral cannabinoids are really helpful
therapeutically
the problem is um as compared to the
other phyto canabo there's been
extremely little work done on
cbga uh so again if you ask me what are
the mechanisms of action um I'd have a
hard time saying very much um but
certainly that would be a really great
thing for some grad student out there to
do his do his a project um but uh you
know I can tell you that but uh my
friend Dustin sulac his healer products
um they they have a preparation that's
cbga and CBG and um seemingly have a lot
lot of good results in a variety of
conditions how it compares to CBG
predominant without any cbga couldn't
say at this point but often we do see
added
benefits um of combining like that
you play that instrument behind
you colen can you sample
this I literally was just thinking the
same thing I was like
that when people worked really hard to
do
that and now it just happens that that
was absolutely skunkman Sam asking uh
you if you played that instrument behind
you and while welcome to Chimera dude
that's awesome to see you man um since
this was brought up that's a Turkish oud
and um yeah I play it um it's 11 strings
and it's not in tune so I'm not going to
indulge now but uh yeah I picked that up
at an estate sale uh several months ago
and been having fun with it that's
pretty
cool down here but it I need to place
the bridge to make it uh
playable how do you'all nice to see you
guys I'm sitting here with
Sam good to see you kir I love you bud
been too long to see you
all
hey well that explains the feedback from
Sam
then you can't have two mics so close to
one
another yeah no I had it a couple weeks
ago my friend Merlin showed up here for
the show and I was like oh my God like I
put everything in my headphones if I
don't have headphones on so I just
didn't speak for the entire show but
luckily uh Alec Dixon spoke for the
almost the entire show that that week so
it was it was perfect shout out to uh
Alec for for coming in how are you doing
Ryan what's uh new and different in the
world of chimera you're producing some
pretty nice Str cultivars for uh for
kippen team there I've seen yeah they're
doing that's actually a few years old
that stuff yeah but they're they're
doing some grow ups and finding some
winners which is always
nice I'm uh I'm I'm doing some more lab
work um working with another doctor at
University here we're gonna be doing
some interesting stuff coming out
so very nice well it'll be two years
probably before you can talk about it
and we'll hear about it but uh we'll be
we'll be looking forward to it yeah it's
a little early to give the cat out of
the bag at this point in time it's more
along the lines of breeding
Technologies so and I was just over in
Europe and my mom passed not too long
ago so I was brought some of her ashes
home and uh you know it was just across
the channel from David so I figured I'd
stop in and say hello he's been kind
enough to give me a bit of rest fite
here so it's good sorry for your loss
Ryan since so you're on I can ask you
and any of the other breeders there is
anybody uh selectively breeding for
turpenoid
concentration breing for terpenoids is a
[ __ ] it's really
hard yeah even going back to the the
nebor work we had um a whole bunch of
lines that were higher in in turp
concentration as you know it's really
about having the analytical method
that's sensitive enough to be able to
selecting breeding almost yeah well
you're yeah I mean like any lot of it's
epigenetic related to environmental
influences but uh perhaps
concentration uh overall concentration
of turps um I mean a lot of this hasn't
been worked out but I I'm just wondering
if anybody out there is concentrating on
on this line of uh
research well even like I said even
going back to the napro days we were
doing that we had certain Trin lines
that were producing significantly more t
or tpes in within a given you know
within a given line so we would breed
those up and and you can definitely
create lines that are higher like
overall turpenoid production I I know
Mark Lewis uh he had one in particular
was really interested in it had 2% Alpha
pining alone out of 3.9% total turps uh
so that's
spectacular um you know considering that
most
totals are about 1% on things that I
look at um but I I'd sure encourage
people to think along these lines
and well Ethan I've always I mean all
the you know I'm not a breeder but all
the selection work that I've done and
all the the cultivars I've created over
all the years have been torpal dominant
that's been my my game always been a fan
that's California well yeah well it's
big part of the world too torpol is a
big you know is a it's kind of an
outlier in many ways um but
interestingly enough it if they are all
fairly high in CBG so I over the years
I've realized that most of the cultivars
I've selected have been 1.5 to 3%
CBG and about
1.5 1 to 1.5% terpinolene um which kind
of gives it this really you know a
mellowed effect like people have always
assumed that like wow this is a a lower
THC variety like this is a 18 to 20 it's
like well actually 28% but it really
mitigates a lot of that that um THC side
effect um but once Ryan I was at the the
facility and Steve um Steve habba had
showed me a a variety or a cultivar that
he had um selected or I'm not sure
exactly if it would maybe you bred that
one but it was he said it was 5%
turpening yeah that was that was line
that I was talking about previously yeah
it um it was five the highest testing
plant that we found initially was
5.7% and you know I had a lot of I had a
lot of faith in Matt ge's analytical
method he really was quite insane about
you know correct numbers not just
getting a reading out of a machine and
yeah the there was a subset of the
trinoline plants that had that really
high tur uh percentage also like you
just said we also realized at that point
in time as well that there was like 10
to 20% of the of the tpine plants do
overexpress CBG like for whatever reason
they don't just convert all the CBG into
THC so you end up with a little bit of a
buffer or what we would call as a buffer
right um he did say that was paid that
you was that it was unsm smokable that
the just because the the the high
terpinolene was just completely
aggressive on your respiratory system
just in holding godamn just you know
it's so funny sitting here with Sam but
these are all lessons that he taught us
so long ago right like I mean even when
he was growing the Haz and in Santa Cruz
he had that experience where that he
wouldn't he'd always let plants cure for
a month right or at least a month before
you you try to smoke them because there
was you know I think that subset of tpin
plants that are just too much it's too
chemically right it feels too
chemically um whether that's the same
thing for the use in the extract Market
I I really see us going to a place where
Turpin become and other
volatiles but you know it's such an
underappreciated at least from the
analytical the way the analytics are
pushed in the industry but you know when
you're concentrating plants into these
extracts and rosins and oils and things
like that live
resins you you don't need to be using
30% plants right because there's there's
kind of like a a biological Maxima that
the plant can have in terms of total
canabo and total terpenoids they share
the the
common precursor pathway right and so to
a degree one comes at the op at the
opportunity cost of the other and so
like I think that you'd have that you
can have plants that are even you know
in the 20s or 15% with a really special
turpan profile and when that's extracted
that's more of a a suitable plant for
the market unfortunately a lot of that
stuff can't make it in a regulated
system where everybody gets so focused
on THC right and all a lot of these
flavor class plants that only produce in
the 15 to 20% range kind of get pushed
to the
Wayside yeah they're probably unsalable
most places unfortunately it's the
reality right everybody's so driven by
THC you know I I even see dispensary not
dispensaries but you know retail shops
and British Columbia and you walk in and
they have plants literally rated on the
menu the top is the highest percentage
THC content so I wish it were more
experiential um you know my son some
years years ago was a runner up for best
bud tender in Seattle and he really
tried to disabuse people of the notion
that they wanted the highest THC
possible but he didn't always gain a lot
of traction with the folks buying um so
it's too bad uh well in the olden days
you didn't buy something before you did
a
bioassay and
um that model probably worked better um
I mean it's completely connected to
price right I mean this is I I can
remember having these conversations with
you guys five to eight years ago and I
remember I remember Debbie goldsbury was
in the room and she's like guys it's
great you know I love that you are
thinking the utopian ways and you want
to educate everyone but she's like after
selling weed to Californians for 30 plus
years all I can say is all they [ __ ]
care about is price and th see so I just
wonder how we'll ever escape that in and
maybe we won't maybe we're The Fringe
and again people need to try it uh if
they have an experience again you know
as I've been mentioning if you can be
high and have the
benefits without the downside of uh
paranoia stress
anxiety um it's just a totally different
experience um you know and I I think
people my age really wax prosaic about
the olden days and it's true you know
there were very high THC kavars
available then but they were much less
common however the experience was
different and it wasn't all THC and all
mercing and lot of people older people
miss those kind of experiences and don't
like a lot of what's out there currently
Ethan i' also also just say Al it's not
just it is older people and people have
had the opportunity but in the breeder
Community you know there's a lot of
people who breed and and and have smoke
flour that they don't sell there's a lot
of Growers who have flow at home that
they grow and smoke and and not what
they grow at work and it's it's really
the market dynamics to me that's really
taken over cannabis where people the
people I I remember at one point
um like distribution guys in California
were like oh we don't people don't want
that you know like they were making big
decisions for what people want and then
you know you've got this new really loud
overwhelming you know fruity gassy thing
that is so easy for them to sell on the
nose you know that it just takes over
the world and California I mean Lemon
Cherry gelato and all that stuff is just
so dominant in the market here and the
The Growers themselves are like I hate
this stuff you know like it's just what
the kids want to smoke it's what the dro
guys want and I I name it five different
things and sell it as five different
things but it's so easy for me to sell
this to me that's like a real Market
issue where it's like the ability as a
brand and as a grower and as a a a
company to say like we believe in our
product and we're going to actually put
out something that we think is special
not just following these weird market
trends and dummy down and just making it
easy that put us in this position where
now you know huge portions of the market
are just a few cultivars that are often
resold under four or five different
things just because they're the easiest
to move and people don't even
necessarily like them people have like a
lot of years experience don't
necessarily like smoking it they just
know it well I just wanted to say that
about turpine breeding canono breeding
is fairly straightforward I mean you you
have to have the background material you
have to do what has to be done takes
several years but it's fairly
straightforward uh whereas the the
breeding for tping it's not so simple I
I I suspect there's many tpine syntheses
which can express more than one kind of
tpine uh whereas with cannabinoids CBD
also makes 20 about 20% THC but most of
the other syntheses for the different
cannaboids they're
straightforward sure yeah it it Dave
what you said is true um a lot of the
enzymes the uh synthesis for the turps
are promiscuous can work on different
substrates and produce different uh
different turps down the line so it does
make it really
complicated um uh but again I'm hoping
that somebody out there is interested
enough to do the genetic work to try and
ascertain uh how these things are
controlled uh etan had his hand up so I
just want to sorry Colin I just want to
make sure etan gets his uh two cents in
before we stray too far away from what
he wanted to speak about go ahead etan
um well a couple of things that's also
why we carried grams earlier um for
people to try right because I work for
Berkeley Patients Group we're turning 25
years literally next month so 25 years
ago that's what we were doing because
initially the uh consumer one in
California very educated um so they knew
what they were looking at or looking for
or towards usually very tarpine
rich uh well-grown flower was their
preference because uh they had seen all
different types of cannabis and they
understood what worked for them but
early in our testing right when we were
starting to isolate THC and then when we
found
CBD um that's where we had the problem
because science wasn't there so we had
the problem converting what we were
missing from science from the effect
right because we knew that THC was
not the be all and all we knew it was
very important however we didn't realize
the symbiotic relationships that were
there or science wasn't able to convey
them at the time so that we could get a
handle on the misinformation of THC
content being the Beall and all as
opposed to realizing the other
cannaboids were at play as well um and
we're still struggling with that
unfortunately and I hope that we're able
to someday get an educational
uh Outreach to the consumer so that they
can stop this because of the alcohol
causation that seems to be the
predominant thinking that high THC is
now going to get me the best high and we
know that you know therapeutically Med
medically that is not the case in any
way shape or form in fact we find lower
THC and other spikes and cannaboids Etc
to be very most important but to Dr
Russo's Point yeah early on we had to go
small so that people didn't feel the
financial ability to commit to you know
the overprice that was of course
cannabis which is back then you know
$4,000 to $6,000 a pound which 25 years
later where thankfully is no longer the
case so sorry to be so long winded there
but I thought some perspective for the
viewers might matter well maybe medical
users can drive it because uh
recreational uniters they're going be
how much DC what's the
price yeah um I I just wanted to say I
was looking through some of my coas and
some of my my testing and Ethan I I've
always sort of since the beginning of
being able to see what's underneath the
hood in terms of of what constituents
are there making up these profiles I've
always tried my best to selectively
breed towards things that were the you
know we're looking at the COA and saying
like Okay well now this translate you
know for instance I have lemon G13 up I
always believed that it was high in
lemoning and then I started working with
the plant really deeply and I realized
it was just really beta mercine that was
driving it and 1.79% to 1% of you know
lemine or line was really driving those
flavor that that the essent that I
really loved of it right and you look at
it and it's 4.3% 32% in this COA of beta
mering right and that's that's
incredibly that's that's a that's really
notable if you're reading towards flavor
profiles because merin's not something
you're breeding for you know you're
typically trying to get away from that
that to be honest sure so it's it's
really interesting but again as as we've
all said the the more I started looking
towards breeding with that methodology
it dispelled whether or not that was
really the path right so I think markers
I think last week we really talked about
some crisper I think things like that
are getting us closer to understanding
the ideologies that we can kind of
dispel and kind of work through to
better understand the path um but
there's so much work to be done because
you know if you if you cross two
Offspring together it's very highly
unlikely that they'll even resemble the
mom or dad um so I think it's uh as Sam
said selective breeding and um going
towards your you know the human aspect
of things is still um a big part of it
today listen you don't need to go
crisper to do that kind of stuff yeah
right of the things that that people are
not doing in cannabis breeding and I
know because I've seen this and I've
done it both
ways the reason napro and Mark Lewis are
having and Steve you know habba they're
having that kind of results with the
breeding is because they take every
plant and it goes to a laboratory
whereas the vast majority of people that
are doing this and I would say 99.9% of
the people growing cannabis they select
the few plants that suit their goals and
they send those to the laboratory right
so if you if you try to like kind of
come to it from a bio prospecting kind
of thing that's like taking a square
kilometer and digging four holes and
then deciding what you know is in the
entire Square you know Square four
square kilometer space right you
literally have to take every single
plant and you're looking for those
things that maybe the human nose doesn't
quite detect um or or really maybe we
don't detect them in the same way
whereas when you do a chemical
analytical you know kind of high
throughput like Brute Force approach you
might see some chemicals that are hidden
in the mix that you would otherwise Miss
and then you can pair those plants
together or self them and and that way
you can actually start driving specific
turp synes you don't have and even you
know it would be great to understand the
genetic mechanisms of these things um so
that we can develop genetic markers but
we don't need that like the the
chemicals themselves are chemical
markers right and that was something
that Mark as a chemist he really hit
home like the the chemical the
chemosphere of the plant like the Cho if
you want to call it that is really a
reflection of the genome right is what
genes are are produced so all you have
to do is look for those outliers and one
of the things that we are doing as a
global Community is growing a lot of
plants and you know some of those plants
find their way kind of to the top of the
cream right like they rise to the cream
and then we get these little pictures of
you know oh this is what makes this
plant unique be it thought Bol or
whatever chemical other whatever
volatile we're looking for and
considering right um but yeah it's it's
an expensive thing to do to take a 100
plants or even 500 plants and send them
to a laboratory that's a big old
analytical Bill no nobody can do it and
that's why you know I applaud Mark's
approach he could only do it because he
had a lab on site uh yeah yeah and I
think that's the way forward if this is
a a goal for other people it's sure
would be for
me yeah Mark Mark convinced the investor
and you know we had some really deep
conversations with the investor and came
he came to understand that that was the
way it was right that was the the
approach that was going to win and he
you know handed us the keys to the car
so to speak and uh you know we got to
take that toy out for a ride it's having
done it that way you can't go back to
the other way right because you just
can't make the gains that you can with
full lab support so
yeah it's kind of The Way It Is Well
said man yeah it's it's uh and you know
the one thing that I I've found some of
my favorite cultivars as I get into the
hood of them they're completely
different which I what I constituents
that I thought were there and to your
point you can't go back you you have to
know now it's not like it's just part of
the process and as it should be well you
realize that you're blind right you're
you're you're kind of blinded if you're
not doing it that way and so once you've
seen the light it's hard to go back into
the dark you can sure you can still
screen plants for all sorts of other
things but you know even in now that
there's un legal systems around the
world with universities that are working
you know collaboratively with industry
we're starting to figure some stuff out
it's really the game has changed so much
in 25 years it's remarkable yeah well
speak speaking of that I would love to
hear from uh Chris brassa as well as
Davis Allen they're doing some work with
the University of British Colombia and
uh yeah if you want to maybe start Chris
introduce yourself and kind of give us a
little Lowdown on what what you're what
you're
doing oh you're
muted sure so um I spent about the past
five years um working on understanding
really kind of uh the demographic
history of uh cannabis so um uh how kind
of the land races and um really I think
different species are related to each
other um and um which kind of natural
populations um the land races were
domesticated from um and then just
recently over the past six months or so
um the UBC received um a permit although
no Grant yet um uh to start some
pre-breeding um to really take cannabis
production um Outdoors uh breed cannabis
um uh for outdoor cultivation um in uh
Canadian environment um and so um you
know in the Pacific Northwest we have
some um like Downey mildew uh uh
pressures uh for example um we also have
um you know a shorter growing season um
and so um yeah the idea is to kind of
use his knowledge of um uh land races
and also maybe wild plants um to breed
some of um plants that are are good uh
medicine also um so Davis has also been
helping out with that um acquiring um
different land race varieties and um
Davis has um quite a bit of uh you know
longtime uh medical patient and so he's
able to um speak on kind of the the
efficacy of of different varieties and
um you know some of the uh chemical
profiles that um might be good to to
include in our breeding program
interesting yeah i' love to hear from
you as well Davis yeah for sure so uh do
you want me to give my background as
well like where yeah give give us a
little little little cliff notes of who
you are and what you're up to for sure
so I've actually been a medical patient
since 2011 since I was 17 years old and
I got into the industry in 2013
ultimately because I noticed that um
just like a lot of you guys are discuss
discussing like there seemed to be an
emphasis just on t HC and not on the
full profiles of the plants what I found
really interesting is one time I had a
university lecture a few years after I
um received my medical card and I
noticed that uh there's like a different
effect to it like I really paid
attention in class all these other
things because I was actually thinking
about not even uh attending my course
because I was having some uh autoimmune
issues what was really interesting is we
had lab analysis done on that variety
and it had a low concentration of CBG
which is really interesting that this is
being talked about in this discussion as
well and it uh it really led me to look
into the chemical profiles of various
varieties and have a strong interest
into land races because what I noticed
after years of collecting land races is
that there's distinct effects that seem
to be standing out within different
varieties and it led me to want to
collect land races from various regions
for future medical use additionally for
research purposes which I'm fortunate
enough to be sharing now with UBC and
additionally on top of that I think that
uh while I agree with you guys that like
in the current market there's an
emphasis on THC I ultimately think over
time that's going to shift because
people are recognizing more and more at
least I believe that uh having these
kind of distinct profiles will allow for
different type of psychoactive profiles
and so in turn by having this different
effect people aren't necessarily just
looking for what's the strongest
ultimately I think the correlation is
because there's a lack of information on
uh these other uh compounds within
cannabis all people who don't really
have a strong educational background can
look at is the high THC in the best
price because ultimately you know we we
live in an economy we live in a world
where people have to be careful about
how much they spend so they're going to
be price con ious and ultimately when
they don't have that information those
are the two easiest things to look at
what's the lowest price and what's the
highest THC and so yeah I truly believe
that over time that's going to change
and it's interesting just a few things
that I heard from uh Ryan for example
there about
um the you know profiles that aren't
necessarily you know 30% THC that then
in turn if they're like at 15 to 20 have
these more like unique flavor profiles
and uh I also co-founded uh Island
genetics so like we're a health Canada
licensed um cultivation company I just
recently left the company but still
really close with everyone involved it's
friends of mine and um what we noticed
is that yeah there's there's definitely
some unique profiles that aren't
necessarily the highest THC but they
wash well and then in turn they have a
really interesting effect in
product nice thanks for Sharon Davis and
I believe we had Brian pop in snuck in
behind us from best friend Farms good to
see you dude good to see you heyy how
you doing nice to see you yeah very good
got a got a Powerhouse of a room today
it's really nice to see uh I haven't
seen Ryan in so long it was real really
nice to see him he's always
uh a great source of information and uh
what you said earlier the chemosphere of
the plant that might be my new favorite
quote you know I I was just thinking you
know it seems like the one thing that
could save the industry right now is low
THC
flour um just because we're we're we're
we're in a supply and demand um issue
with people overgrowing we heavily
saturated markets and you'd think that
what the bigger Brands would want is
people to smoke more flour of lower
potency you know make more sell five
grams instead of two you know and not
that not that we want people smoking all
day like cigarettes but the reality is
lower potency flour of certain profiles
is so much more applicable to various
situations different consumers just it's
a much broader you know approach you can
keep your TC levels at 20% and still
have more tpes than you know what to do
with so
it doesn't have to be extremely
low so mve I did a study for a year and
a half with um with a a toxicologist and
two other phds I don't know if I can say
the name of the company but I I'll talk
about the study and what we did was we
we tested varietals that were in the 30%
range and then below the 20s right and
we gave those patients over a year time
those two varietal and we asked them
what they thought was more potent in
every single time maybe two patients out
of the out of the the 20 that we we did
this
with every single time they were on the
on the the Lower Side of the THC and
they they thought it was it was a higher
The Higher One you know so I think what
the learnings that I walked away with
was we need to do more of this because
we need to dispel and better understand
what patients actually want and what
they actually believe through Placebo
and two
perception you know as we're all talking
about per ction of of of value is and
we've talked about this on the other on
another episode where for some reason
it's like the alcohol world is seeped
into into our world and for whatever
Rhyme or Reason we haven't found a great
reason to dispel why not so I think in
that way I think we have a real
opportunity here to to develop the path
forward for that um because you this is
the millionth time I've had this
conversation in the past probably three
months yeah you know and I think it's a
it's a constant um in terms of
everyone's Consciousness and what
they're thinking about on a daily basis
of what
what years ago when we first tested uh
THC levels and uh we we found the
entries into the High Times hand cup
that the 25% ones people didn't like
them as much or think they were as
strong as for example skun number one
that was 177%
and we knew we knew at that time that it
was the whole picture rather than just
the THC but it's it's not easy to
convince recreational smokers especially
younger ones I think that last part
really well potency I think potency is
really important and and the fact that
we can't because cannabis is so complex
so chemically complex we can't really
put our thumb on what potency is but
ultimately it really is important I
think and that's how people navigate
safety with consumption of substances
but is by knowing how potent it is and
how much I need to put in my body before
I feel unsafe and we can't do that we
need to do it cannabis needs that to
happen I mean you need to have a number
on the bottle of alcohol you need to
have a milligrams on the prescription
drugs it's just it's just common sense
but cannabis is elusive in that way that
we'll never I don't think we'll ever
really figure out potency because it's
so abstract and people are so different
but there is there is a potency scale
and we can get there and and it's just
it takes a concerted effort with
scientists and Industry and limiting
cultivars so that you people can learn
like this one is this strength well it
takes it takes us back to the
conversation we had with Alec on hash
Church 5.0 episode 3 which is how
accurate are those numbers because
that's a whole new you know Warp that
you're throwing into the game you've got
customers that are buying Things based
on numbers on a package you've got Labs
that are incentivized to give big
numbers because they know they're going
to get your your business if you do and
Alec was saying there's there's a sort
of desentized if you are giving accurate
numbers and they're not the numbers that
the companies want to see and so you you
know that to me is also playing like an
enormous role so now someone's like oh I
only smoke 25s but they're probably you
know substantially lower than that in in
the reality so that that really throws
things there's so many things going on
in this conversation there's the labs
there's interlab I mean Alec can talk
about you know within laab variability
but there's also interlab variability
right like people make mistakes in
method development and you mis quantify
or misidentify certain compounds and so
even when you have the numbers are
reported on a dry weight basis and the
plant is 90% water
right so even if you have two different
lab analytics or two different studies
you can't just put those studies
together and Compare the numbers as if
they're the same they were they were
derived through different analytical
methods different Growers you know
different varieties and one thing that I
I have a theory and it kind of makes
sense to me we developed or we we we
screened a lot of plants through the lab
okay and consumed a lot of those plants
in my opinion there's a sweet spot in
between like 8 and 12%
that people of a certain age group
prefer that type of high okay and then
younger kids they never really grew up
with those things and so they don't they
don't understand the head space that
creates they grew up in the Afghan world
where like 20 plus per plants punch you
in the face and that's how you know that
you're high right and so like I really
think that like the perception of what
is high is different between people in
say their 40s to 60s you know I was
laughing when bve said you know the
young kids it's like at one point in
time that was true right we're not
really the young kids anymore right um
there's a whole generation of kids that
grow up on pre-rolls that are like 25
30% mixed with THC diamonds right so
like to really study this you need a
whole bunch of uniform grown samples of
different THC concentration and
different cohort groups and you know not
just reference one study and say ah this
we figured it out you know there's a lot
of that that goes on the Cannabis
industry we take a little snapshot of
something that happens in the real world
and we make this generalization of the
way that it is right but I think that
there's so many variables and there's so
many differences between
consumers that it really is a hairball
that is is quite difficult to tease
apart well even even the way they sorry
go ahead no I was just going to say that
I think that there's plants in that 8 to
12% THC range it's not necessarily the
chemical profile of the plant it's just
how loud you're listening to the music
right and it creates a certain headspace
and there really is something to be said
I believe I really do believe that like
that 8 to 12% on a very clear like if
you haven't used anything else that day
that provides that clear kind of
euphoric effect that you hear a lot of
people of the 60s and 70s talking about
right and let's face it like the
majority of the weed they were smoking
back then the ties and the the
Colombians and the the you know the
Highland Mexicans that kind of stuff
it's not 25% THC right A lot of it comes
in at that 8 to 12 range yeah um so I I
think it has to do with this basic
effect right like with th you take a
little bit you kind of get up right but
if you take a whole bunch more it brings
you back
down I kind of think it's the difference
between getting high and getting stoned
you know like you these these these
extracts are a rocket ship to the moon
the first time I ever smoked Sam's dry
sift like I I I had never been that high
in my life off of a bong rip um but then
when I started doing the hash hits and
was kind of trying to like wrap my head
around oh I got to like get off my high
horse and produce products for people
that aren't so Rippling strong not not
everyone wants to take a rocket ship to
the Moon just because 90% of the people
around me do that doesn't really mean
it's an accurate description of what you
know Society kind of wants so you know I
started making these haset and I hadn't
really smoked in a long time I was like
I'm G to have to smoke these things and
I'd go out on my electric skateboard and
I'd pull out a hashit and have a couple
of rips of you know like a 30% T THC
hash and it was super mellow for me
because I was you know I'd spent the
last 25 years just ripping the strongest
possible you know 60 70 plus percent and
super concentrated 5 to 10% tpine
content and it what I really found was
it was just nice it was just relaxing it
put me into a completely different head
space and uh yeah I appreciate uh I
appreciate that head
space yeah and you know there's
something that happens I think with H2 I
just I posted something on Twitter
earlier today I saw this kid rolling up
a joint where the paper was like shatter
essentially it was a pliable shatter and
they just stuffed it like a cone and it
was not only a total waste you know they
weren't they were smoking it and half
the more of the THC was going off in the
side stream than Ed their lungs but it's
like it's kind of that frat boy
mentality of like you know how much beer
can we chug right and I just I don't
think that you get the same head space
it's almost like headro right it's like
it's it's when you listen to music
incredibly loud it's hard to hear all
the subtly yeah right
say like recording music you you that's
why we use compressors and outboard gear
right because audibly we're looking for
the harmonics right we're looking to
shape the frequen exactly right and
you're touching on some stuff that I
think about a lot is we have harmonics
are fleeting right much like these voc's
or these volatile compounds that we talk
about and to capture them in their
perfect state is almost like chasing
this like forever like it's forever
chasing your tail you're trying to get
that perfect moment whether it's an
extract or you're it's the perfect
moment when you're going to harvest it
and you're going to dry it for this set
amount of time and you're trying to
encapsulate that moment you know that
personal um what you think as a breeder
as a or as a grower at that point in
time what you're trying to that that
moment in time that you're trying to
capture and that's that's a forever
moment and and bringing it back to what
you're talking about it's it the
subtleties are it's almost like the
music's gotten so loud to your point
where it's just blaring Ing and I don't
hear anything but just noise and what
you're talking about is getting back to
the subtleties of harmonics in maybe an
F Shiner F minor or a a g sustained
chord you know or you know or something
like that that allows you to as a user
really get in touch with why you use
cannabis and um the things that draw you
into the plant and keep us all here
talking about it and those subtleties I
think you know more importantly or what
gets us all up in the day to think about
this you know and you know it's it's for
whatever reason we're not bottlenecking
I don't think I think we're just we're
not selectively thinking about the whole
gene pool as a as a as an industry in a
in a way we're trying to monetize so
much all the time that we're almost
losing sight of what's important so can
I can I comment on that um follow that a
little bit is and and tied into um
something that Ryan said and also
something maybe our in the land race
conversation that we could go down is
that that the subtleties in people were
were selecting plants for quite some
time and a lot of them were selecting
individual plants because they were
smoking
flower and or they're hand rubbing
individual plants you know and that that
created all these populations with all
this chemistry all around the world
these land race based populations let's
call them because I do believe once it
leaves the land the kind of the race is
over um but then the Afghan Ryan
mentioned Afghan like that Afghan
population to me there's such a big I
mean it's had such a huge impact on
Modern
cannabis but it was it wasn't selected
for individual plants or individual
traits as much as it was selected for
ability to yield lots of resin and then
what they did to that resin over time
and volatilizing all a lot of the aromat
and abusing it with heat and time and
they were consuming a very different
product than what they were selecting in
a way so like the fact that the thing
that be is the driver of modern
cannabis came from a a population that
wasn't selecting for all of these traits
that we're talking about individual like
the Nuance the the the harmony the I
mean the the the color and the the
resonance and all that stuff right
because it was lost they were selecting
literally for API they were selecting
for the bulk power of oomph of hashish
and on top of that they were consumers I
mean think about it they were the the
heads that you're talking about Marcus
afan hash smokers dude they smoked lots
of hash it was like a race you know like
you know smoking like Sam will say like
smoking the hubby bubbly only certain
people could do that so like it was
embedded in their culture also to like
produce this massive API resin product
and consume huge doses of it to get
large amounts of THC in your system
versus the guys that were handling
individual flow and like so it's like
what I'm getting at is like the
selective Pro process by the people that
were developing these was so different
and maybe there's some kind of weird
perverse Twisted you know prohibition
Story how that made it into our modern
gene pool that we weren't actually
selecting those traits it just got there
all the dry all the dry sifters were
definitely sifting they were breeding
for resin because they were dry sifting
whole Fields not smoking individual
plants yeah and uh if you smoke
individual plants like with ganja
smokers then uh it it becomes possible
to select the plants that you like the
best whether it's high THC or t
particular tpine taster smell and uh it
it it it's a much better way I mean if
you don't smoke the plants that you're
breeding for uh
individually how the hell can you breed
for what you want well and they were
also you got to remember they were also
kind of only doing selections on one
half of the Cross right because they're
we were selecting the females but the
males were all being nobody was doing
any select mes you were just getting
what was around in the population so
there was a real friction or drag in
that genetic selection right there
there's been some pretty significant
things that have
happened you know growing indoors and
allowing more controlled crosses and use
of clones for like back cross programs
stuff like that but moreover like STS
and you know breeding two females
together that kind of thing has really
changed the game because it allows us to
start making positive genetic selection
on both sides of the parents on both
sides of the cross right so also turning
males
female yeah yeah
yeah yeah Davis had his hand up yeah I
just had a comment about that comment
earlier about Afghan populations I think
the I think the situation is is that
Afghan populations and varieties from
Pakistan you're right about the uh
selecting for resin content over
individual plants but I think the
reality is that those populations are
very biodiverse and high in overall
resin uh content which is true but it's
actually the westerners selecting just
for the THC content which has kind of
like changed the uh changed from like a
diverse profile into like you know
chasing THC again so the reality is like
those type of populations like if you
actually go and collect wild um Afghan
and Pakistan populations you're going to
find a lot of CBD
actually like equal equal quantities so
the reality is that because we've
artificially selected in the West for
only THC we've actually bred out a lot
of the traits that naturally exist there
so it's not actually that it's like high
cannaboid content it's that we've only
selected one pathway from
it
yeah I have a question for Sam um you
know out of the all the you know
so-called land stuff that I've collected
over the years and decades I you know
the stuff out of Iran of of Iran has
been the
most hybrid like that I've ever seen
like every single thing I've gotten from
that
region what do you think that's due to
do you think that that region is
selecting first of all I first of all I
strongly suspect that a lot of the
Iranian population
that we see today are coming from
Afghanistan Pakistan because let me tell
you they were heavy and hardcore on
cannabis in in Iran in the 60s 70s 80s
90s so where did the big population land
races come from I think they were
imported got it well that makes a lot of
sense because I that's exactly what I
always thought I was like how is this
even possible how are these plant so
good like there hasn't really been an
ability to really grow these things the
way that we envision them in the Western
World um to laws right so Mojave said
something really interesting earlier
about you know once you take the plant
out of the country it's no longer a land
race it's not even that the definition
of a land race is like a biological type
that is maintained by a culture right as
soon as the culture is gone they're the
people yeah it's yeah exactly it's man
and it's it's human and environment and
so once that human use like for example
tie sticks right like they were selected
for all those traits because that's what
tied well to the stick yeah right um so
yeah once you take a plant population
away from its land and it's and the
culture that is responsible for ushering
that breeding system you really are
changing it yeah um and and like let's
face it as well Farmers cannabis farmers
are different than all other Farmers
they want to grow better crops every
year right so realistically if you're
thinking that you've gone to any of
these places in the last 20 years and
you're collecting land races you're not
collecting the plant that was there in
the 60s and 70s right like people have
been bringing in seeds and cannabis is a
prolific outcrosser like we all know um
so I I really I'd be remarkably
surprised if these things were as they
were back in time because there's been
so much money spent all over the world
World in crushing these populations and
crushing the cultures that produce
them and also Ryan um that another thing
happened is well not to mention all the
all the our influence in terms of put
bring sending genetics back around the
world you know so what is the land race
and how much have it stayed in that land
but if you really think about I mean my
my uh family history with like cannabis
in Mexico and South America was like you
know by the 60s Americans were going
down there and they were heavily
influencing the selection
process it was it was no longer just the
local guy in aapo who's just like this
is our family thing by the time they
came down and said yeah we'll take some
of this but can you plant another field
of that over there I'll be back next
year oh and this one was good how about
that one it's like it really became an
export product in the 60s and 70s so a
lot of the the original selection forces
had shifted towards export to a western
culture so getting back to like what was
that original selective force and why
did that people in that culture and that
geography and that genan pole genan pool
structure itself that way is really you
know it's it's it's so far it's such a
Prohibition story you know um about how
prohibition shifted all of that and land
how we landed where we are today and now
I see like people here in California and
you know I love the idea of bringing
diversity back back into the market but
people using the word land race to sell
cannabis and to say this is a land race
or I use this land race cross it's just
like it's I get it it's just
bastardization of the word but it also
to me there's a little bit of a cultural
appropriation thing there's some
protocols some International treaty
stuff it's like you get into a really
weird space Not only that M but how do
you maintain a land race with less than
thousands of males and thousands of
females you it changes every year well
they were even back then they weren't
one thing much slower basis yeah
yeah vers exitu I think is what what you
we if you like land race population
exitu means like we took this population
and now we are altering it yeah so
that's what brought this up ultimately
is like I wanted to hear from the group
because I out of everything I've grown
like none it's all hybrids like I don't
I mean let's be real like it's there's
nothing I've looked at was like oh yeah
like I haven't seen that trait before in
some form of a fashion or another you
know um it's just maybe um it that line
could be improved um but I've I don't
know I don't know if anyone on here has
seen things they have yet to truly see
but it seems to me like there's um a lot
of social appropriation there's a lot of
um
misinformation and a lot of you know
quite frankly hot air that's being blown
around and sure these regions have great
respective Gene poles and we should be
dipping into them and and working with
them in some respect but we also have to
recognize what they are and um what are
we actually after here you know and
there's a lot of Sam in there let's just
all be honest Sam say that like G is KH
okay so you know when you're around
that's right everybody knows that
everything is half skunk okay that's
what I'm saying okay now this
Sam all right this is where I want to
introduce uh a friend of mine who I had
come in who's my mentor who I've been
working with at the international level
um his name is Michael krowitz and of
course many of you on this panel know
him or uh know Ethan and Sam Etc because
uh he's an OG cannabis collector but one
of the things that has been worked on is
this thing called the grock treaty g r a
KT and it's a new treaty having to deal
with land racism those land races that
were stolen so I want to introduce
Michael because he's my mentor and also
a part of the veterans Action Council
which is a national and international
organization and uh have him speak on
the grock treaty and then uh I did bring
him on because he he's one of those
amazing collectors so he has some
amazing cannabis artifacts that I just
wanted him toh Show and Tell and bring
him on so Michael
welcome thanks itan I um put in the chat
the link to that treaty um a little
while ago
actually um I was answering
um
Colin uh so the um International
treaties have sort of slowly caught up
to the Past um I was very very uh
thrilled to have um a little bit of
input from our our Mentor inous here uh
Sam The skunkman Who U made an
appearance in Vienna um at the
international meetings to speak about
the need to work on on this um end of
of I don't know what you'd call it
sustainability paying back paying
forward U it's uh it's about respect
respect for indigenous peoples
communities uh stakeholders but also
small craft farmers and they're craft
and they're they're not just their
genetic resources but most especially
and importantly the knowledge base that
comes along with the genetic resources
on how to turn these genetic resources
into products and I I would go so far as
to say everything that you've said so
far uh has been remarkably cool but also
fits into that category you know these
these this is the traditional knowledge
that you're working on building a new
craft of traditional knowledge um the uh
this this particular um set of treaty
meetings culminated a
25-year
negotiation um to create a a first ever
International working document that
takes the conventional bi convention on
biological diversity
the ngoya protocol and other things that
have been designed to create u a u a
good working relationship between
industry and and uh stakeholders
um and and Nations and and their
citizens and stakeholders um and in
Industry um but to take it one step
further to actually come to some sort of
agreement quantifying you know exactly
what it is
that that um we're talking about um and
coming up with some concrete ways you
know they didn't go so far as to come up
with sort of uh real you know what we
would call real enforcement mechanisms
but at least there is now International
agreements that make it uh possible to
foreclose on those that commit fraud at
least and and and you know do some of
the more egregious things that we feel
like are being done in in that you know
genetic um land race community this is
about you know the seeds that we took
back in backpacks full of weed in the
60s um going all the way back to the
1860s to the 1960s so this is
generational many many many generations
of Damage Done by colonialism um I never
thought as a cannabis activist that at
some point I would be sort of butting
heads with colonialism and trying to
tear down some of the last
infrastructure that's built out of iron
and although Rusty is not going anywhere
too easily
um but that's exactly what that
was Michael let me interrupt for one
second did do you know of any Seed
Company in today's world that is
bringing land race seeds from various
countries which is obeying these
treaties and kicking back to the uh
original grow I don't know of
any not yet and and your sentiment in
that regard was well received at the
United Nations
I I can tell you um and this is planting
you know planting new seeds of of change
that hopefully will lead to those types
of relationships which are healthy and
sustainable but also give us access to
these special plants that give us these
special characteristics that are our
future well
unfortunately we have access right now
because people are just liberating them
for the Revolution and uh they but they
don't kick back anything of any
significance yeah yeah I I think that
you know there was one conversation I
had the Thai cannabis Corporation was
very concerned that the efforts to work
on uh these treaties and and
negotiations might actually stifle
progress stifle Innovation and that was
a very good question I thought about it
for quite a while did some research and
came back with a no it wouldn't and the
reason why is because it moves too fast
genetics you know you're only a couple
of years away from the next big
discovery of something that's very
specific to a particular place you know
a land race that hasn't been really
discovered yet and U created yet even so
I think the that's where the future is
we've we've disconnected ourselves
because of the drug war the drug war has
very adversely affected us as a people
and made us first smoke more weed we we
actually ate more C and things before
prohibition and also growing indoors
absolute aberration which will be
corrected the treaty you're talking
about in fact they want you to share
with the government and with the
original Growers and it the governments
that were suppressing the original grow
so it's a bit loyy Yeah well and the
other thing with any International
treaty it's kind of self voluntary if
you want to be part of it right like
North America United States and Canada
they're not part of the nego protocol
good let me let me speak to that because
that's a really interesting point that I
also did some really intense research on
not that long ago and uh this was in
communication with our US Government the
United States government uh was to say
an outlier in these negotiations in
Geneva would be putting it mildly they
were a thorn in everybody's side they
were a bur under the saddle of any
progress um so they're not you know
we're not talking about Old Colonial
damage we're talking about ongoing
damage from some these countries first
but second um the thing is they do apply
and the reason why they apply and this
is coming straight from the US
government's mouth basically I'm trying
to quote as best I can um the reason why
we have to comply is because the vast
majority of our stakeholders in our
International Community are applying
these treaties they're going into
Commerce rules and and U international
trade agreements that supersede you know
that are actually Financial based but
they're based on countries that are very
willing and very we had like 35 40
countries that immediately signed this
treaty and put it into Force at the
objection of and and over the body of
the United States the other countries
are setting these rules up in their
trade and if we can bolster that
activity as a cannabis uh you know um
industry that would be great but even if
we don't the world will have to conform
to these trade rules because otherwise
you have no one to trade
with yeah the other thing is the Growers
are not really necessar necessarily the
Breeders they are the uh Trustees of the
genan pool at the present time because
the history goes back hundreds of years
for many of the Afghan and Thai and
Colombian
varieties Chris Chris had his hand up he
he wanted to ask a question as well see
yeah so this ties into kind of what
Michael and Sam have been speaking on
and I was just wondering kind of what
what does this benefit sharing actually
look like you know Sam mentioned that
the Growers are not necessarily the
Breeders and also that the government
gets a cut is it solely Financial like
um the recommendation to give back how
do you identify who the kind of the
beneficiary of these of these benefits
uh actually are and um
yeah Michel
speak yeah that that was actually
something that uh that you got me
started on Sam uh thinking about this uh
very hard and we actually put a
committee together to think about this
to try to figure out exactly how um
there's a couple of things I'll say
about it just broadly one is that our
our our cannabis team for what it's
worth agreed that this was
forward-looking that this wasn't about
um you know coming up with sanctions to
correct the past um that this was you
know forward looking negotiations that
would affect ongoing and future
agreements so you know we're not talking
about you know what do you call it uh uh
corrective measures of the past you know
monies or something like that and uh as
far as the government um I don't see the
government getting money either like
let's say uh a big company goes down and
and comes up with some seeds for a
cannabis product um from you know a
country near the equator and comes back
with an agreement with the the actual
breeder
um and the and the Growers that is
financial and the community the local
community the the those who are in the
that
traditional knowledge Loop I'd say at
the local level would get financial
monies and and uh shares and you know uh
ongoing support uh product uh uh you
know uh connection you know with this
with this ongoing product the the
country would get things too though like
like from a let's say a large corporate
player like that could easily work with
their National museums their National
libraries and their National um uh
educational programs to create uh
structured programs of learning about
these peoples and these products it's a
a point of national pride National
Heritage and and it's important
academically as well as uh the country
itself benefits from the the being in
the loop so to speak and getting the you
know this uh type of support allows them
to better better support their citizens
so you can sort of look at a carer with
tourism you know the way a national
government brings in tourists but then
they put them into the local community
it gets the funds
essentially interesting
stuff I just want to also congratulate
the reason why Michael's been working at
in the United Nations since
1997 and uh he's been guiding me for the
past uh four years uh there specifically
but uh yeah he went there at the beest
of Jack herrer and others uh and Dennis
Peron and um he is the reason why
medical cannabis has been legal
worldwide since December 2020 him and
his team helped change the law at The
Who and at the United Nations level so
this is the caliber uh that we're we're
having today on and speaking we're not
just talking about changing the world
we're working toward it and the group uh
I'm am I'm he's mentoring me as I work
at the U we're trying to change the uh
international law by 2030 2029 2030 to
remove cannabis from the most dangerous
drug category so it will no longer no no
people will no longer be executed for
cannabis around the world so that is the
higher level work we're working toward
because last year while we were at the
UN three people were executed in
Singapore just for discussing they
didn't even handle the Cannabis people
so unfortunately um we're out there
countering our enemy which is Kevin sbet
who is uh the main liar who uh countries
like China and uh Pakistan uh Russia and
others are using his language to
continue to execute and kill people and
imprison them all over cannabis and I
just want to give a major thank thanks
to Michael crowz and his team for what
they have done and I'm humbled to just
to be a part and hope that we can
achieve what we're trying for by 2030 so
at the same time countries like Pakistan
are going to permit medical at least
just the way Morocco has
changed correct yeah and Morocco is
allowing for medical now too so it's
it's a it's a huge change and uh we we
all owe a gret of attitude and thanks to
Michael and others and that entire team
the battle is battle is not done until
every citizen everywhere can grow for
any reason as as long as it's safe for
consumers
yeah I I I support that I wanted to
welcome Wade because he popped in while
we were having our chat he got a
haircut looking
slick oh you're M you're I can't hear
you figure it out
nope can't hear
you your microphone might be where your
speaker is check your Zoom how are we
doing now can you hear me hey there he
is cheers
um yeah um decided to get my head
lightened a bit and it feels good and um
yeah was having having a rough day here
but uh I really wanted to join in I'll
get a chance to hear the first hour and
change uh in the recording so uh yeah
bless it be to all of you and good to be
here thank you yeah good to good to have
you man we're sending the best Vibes uh
that we can your
way yeah Wade is part of our veterans
Action Council crew uh we're working at
the national and international level so
he is part of our advisory team so it's
great to see him and Michael on here
today and thank you Marcus for having us
on to share with the hash Church uh the
work that they've been
doing absolutely absolutely I love
stacking the panel it's uh I find the
best conversations come from it when
there's just a lot of us and we can kind
of just you know flow into these
wonderful conversations that really
haven't uh I haven't been hearing you
know like we took this big long break
with hash church and I thought ah
someone will just do it you know and
there's some great podcasts don't get me
wrong but they mostly do kind of a
one-on-one thing and I just love the
idea of having a bunch of great minds
listening to One another bouncing off
one another so appreciate all of you
guys for showing up for sure hey uh
Michael has a history presentation since
he's a collector like Sam and like Rob
um if y'all are okay he would like to
show y'all some some cool things from
Cannabis history I like cool things from
Cannabis
history so I uh actually wrote myself
some notes which I see now we actually
talk quite a bit in the
chat but uh yeah um ATN had alluded to
my uh sort of prehistory back in the 90s
I I find it endlessly fascinating that
he and I came up in the Cannabis
movement completely parallel to each
other I mean at certain points very very
close we were actually working with uh
cannabis Action Network and both working
with Debbie goldsbury at the same time
in the same place and but just didn't
cross pass that's probably the closest
that we came um but um I came up and as
as ATN handing out flyers at an info
table and worked our way up to the
higher echelons of the sort of the
thought process of the Cannabis movement
um sort of the Special Forces if you
will of the Cannabis movement uh you
never heard about us I like to to say
I'm that guy you know when when you you
say uh the Veterans Affairs policy on
marijuana oh that that guy or the uh you
know International treaty and uh you
know removing cannabis from uh schedule
4 yeah that guy um but uh it's it's um
really my prehistory to my activist
history that comes out here and and that
really gives me so much uh joy and and
and feel so good in my heart because I
actually was a cannabis of fishion a and
and lover in the 70s and if it weren't
for just some turns of events of you
know the Cannabis movement sort of got
derailed by the cocaine experience of
the 70s um and at that moment that's
when I was coming up right at the moment
where the Cannabis movement had derailed
and the president's cannabis uh you know
program and legalization had been
derailed and there was all this Scandal
so I joined the military I joined the
machine instead
and try to get a bird's eyee view I
guess you'd say of the system from
inside which actually worked remarkably
well I'll have to say you know that the
work that I've done in the in the
Veterans Affairs and stuff like that
certainly could have never been done as
a cannabis activist without me being a
veteran um and having that experience as
tough as it was I got broken up pretty
bad in Guam USA uh have an artificial
hip I no spleen some of those things as
souvenirs of my military service
um but um no no combat or anything other
than just uh you know poorly constructed
roadways on my on my way home from
dinner and Guam but other than that but
I think it's it's interesting um my
childhood I grew up in the auction
business my father was a professional
Auctioneer the president of the
auctioneers Association that kind of
stuff and uh I always have looked at
things from a historical perspective and
into the junk boxes and finding um you
know Antiques and things like that um
you know that was very natural to me and
and coming up in the Cannabis movement
just gave me the information you know
this is one of my favorite little
bottles one of the first ones that I
found cannabis corn medicine rwi was had
like a truck and they come around and
sell you flavorings and medicines of all
kinds and this had it was cannabis for
corns alcohol ether and cannabis and if
you if it's had cannabis it was a
painfree corn relief and that makes
sense you
know and cannabis wow that's got to be a
potent mix yeah yeah yeah ether and but
that wasn't to be drunk that was to put
on your corns on your feet uh but it
worked evidently there was like maybe 50
different products that employed that
that same recipe and um I think you know
to our conversation to sort of tap into
the conversation that's existing here I
think there's two things that are
interesting um one is how they employed
the
Cannabis like with other herbal
medicines this is a cannabis and talu
and
Codine and these
are specific medicines this is a pain
relief as you can see a pharmacy siiz
jug um that used a low-level pain
reliever you could find Cannabis and
every level of pain relief and each
level pain relief would have a different
herbal mix and I think that's one of the
New Frontiers that we haven't reached
yet as a people as a cannabis tribe if
you will is integrating the other herbs
into our world and how does cannabis
interact if you think you're having fun
with tpin wait until you start bringing
the other herbs into the into the
picture um to get a desired effect but
they had almost you know I don't know if
they perfected it but they certainly had
a handle on it back then with 75
different you know uh kind of gradient
mixtures that they would apply for
anxiety or for pain or for whatever and
I think even more interesting our
conversation here is how they overcame I
guess you'd say the lack of knowledge of
the specific cannabinoids because they
didn't even have a reading on THC it's
fun in the historical record to look at
all the efforts to to try to isolate
THC our our University got 12 pounds of
cannabis we made extracts we did this
test this test this test you can see
them pulling their hair out in the lab
trying to to isolate THC which of course
Dr micham did in the 1960s it was a long
time coming I'm talking about artifacts
in the 18 you know 1910 1930 1950
1960 so anyway um what they did though
back then was they had specific Source
material and this is really cool because
it Taps into those land races it Taps
into those specific spefic genetic
variations and and specific outcomes
that are uh geographically specific and
what they did was they just used those
medicines from those places they had
cannabis indicia was from India cannabis
africanis was from Africa and the [ __ ]
pot cannabis Americana was uh up until
the 1920s when they figured out how to
grow it better was pretty straggly
looking from USA there was actually a a
discussion in the farm far pharmac
pharmacological Association Journal as
to whether they'd ever be able to grow a
medicinal quality cannabis in the United
States but uh Park Davis and Eli Lily
sent a team to India and learned how to
do it is a a good documentary record of
their test cases and and their efforts
to create a quality cannabis Americana
which evidently they they did do in the
20s and 30s before it all got shut down
by the marijon tax act but um yeah um
that's how they did it they
uh Donnie worter I don't know if he's
published anything yet but he was
looking at that you know during an essay
of the of the different products how
they were employed how these specific
Geographic varieties and and
geographically specific products were
employed in the end product um and and
you know sort of do a assessment of that
and I think when you do you'll see that
that's how they did it that's how they
employed you know CBD predominant or
whatever by just using the source
material very carefully um but anyway um
I think that the museum is particularly
powerful I've got a couple of little uh
sort of exhibits for you in what it can
do to show people their own history I'm
see if I can share screen here oh you
got a enable yes it's sorry it's a
default I don't know why they do that
what I'm gonna show you here is uh I
actually as a collector and as an
antique person I came in contact with
someone who great classic story went to
a garage sale and found lisst Dewey's
archive lisst Dewey's Diaries list Dey
was uh the point person for the US
Department of Agriculture from like 1890
to like 1930 1940 um on hemp he was
their hemp guy he wrote some of the most
important articles in the US Department
of Agriculture uh uh annual reports are
some of the most important hemp articles
ever written from my perspective in the
United States on him um and uh this
person found his handwritten diary
starting in leatherbound Diaries written
every day you know entries like the
Hindenburg crashed today I was late for
work you know I mean totally
mind-blowing like insight into the past
but particularly cool and I'll show you
here is um being able to show people in
this case the people of Washington DC
their own past and their own Collective
history so here's this is an article
that came out about those Diaries when
we sort of made them work we put them
into action to show people their own
history and to to make them real and and
have them do something this is an
article came out in the Washington Post
in
2010 and it's got um the the
essence of it is this headline here us
once studied weed at the site of the
Pentagon and this was something known to
some of our researchers like Michael
alich already knew this but the people
of Washington DC didn't know this and
what really helped them to know this um
since this header disappears here was
this picture that was in mixed with the
Diaries and this is list Dewey on the
site that is now the Pentagon standing
next to a stand of experimental US
Department of Agriculture hemp plants
and I love the Smile everybody that's
standing next to imp place has this sort
of I don't know it's a very interesting
sort of smile that they they have but
that's one example of sort of making
this history work showing people their
own history and I wanted to give you
another this is one more recent that
came about as a result of our historical
work that uh led to the landmark change
of the World Health Organization
position on medicinal cannabis this is
the international office on hygiene in
France
uh that they had were based in France at
the time I think for they moved back and
forth to Geneva the predecessor of the
World Health Organization and that's the
picture of those guys there and uh in
this
article um that's an international
Office of Public hygiene in this article
we talk about the actual history of the
prohibition of cannabis because it came
to our attention this is mostly work
done by members of our team that spoke
French because it was in the League of
Nations artifacts and they're all
written in French and uh um they found
what would have to be called the true
history of international cannabis
prohibition which started with patent
medicines from the United States
specific ones uh I'm scrolling down to
the photo here these are from my
collection and these are in the article
the journal article I sh share the link
um but neuralgic improved these are pain
medicines from Park Davis made in Detro
Detroit and um cazu Michigan um
neuralgic and it's got
hyosus quinine cannabis but also
morphine products um and and other you
know strict nine arsonate aconite you
know there's a variety of different
um you know materials that are in these
different products uh and again
including things like morphine and
Codine as I described earlier and um the
thing is that they were outlawing
cannabis but in fact a lot of their
complaints lined up more with the mix of
some of these you know rather strong
medicines which my own personal theory
is they were coming off of the market in
the United States sort of surplus and
being sold off on the street in Egypt um
and taken on the street and a heavy
patent medicine with morphine and
cannabis drinking it like you know an
Elixir not a cool uh thing the police in
Egypt were pretty freaked out about it
the Egyptian government went to the
international authorities and found a
very welcome greeting from you know
countries like the United States with
our Harry anslinger and others that had
a very Colonial View of such such
activity so anyway it's interesting the
article is uh the Cannabis parlay at the
League of Nations and I encourage you to
to check it out if you want but it shows
you how these artifacts can be brought
you know into life and and put into our
our our now and our future and that's
the for me that's the the most fun of it
I told ATN everybody the other day I
feel like I'm trying to put a mosaic in
people's minds I feel like I'm a mosaic
artist and I've got thousands of
artifacts in my mind and they fit
certain people certain groups certain
ways and when they all see what I see
then I'm then I'm done then my work my
life work is done so but uh anyway
that's that's the uh the cannabis Museum
uh a little taste of the Cannabis Museum
anyway and I can show you this is the
latest thing I just picked up at auction
it's uh Linden cough Balsam so this has
been a pretty good cough medicine you
still got the cough medicine
inside you can see the Cannabis indicia
product proudly sold by a producer
in United
States so is that under 3% considered
hemp and that's why you can mail that
[ __ ]
around um the antique medicines are
tricky and uh eBay for example will pull
your items and be very mean to you if
they find out that you're selling even
antique medicines um so It's Tricky U
but uh we found some our researchers
found what is the concentration of
cannabis in that does it say on the
front label yeah it's a very uh you know
typical uh 8% alcohol five grains to
each ounce of cannabis
indicia yeah I mean um I got a very
sensitive uh gas
chromatograph uh if you want to send me
a sample of that I I'll tell you how
much is left in there be really
interested so is that so that that the
liquid that's in there is the original
contents that was in the bottle you
think yeah more than likely I mean it's
it's uh it's been opened but it doesn't
look like much has been removed there
there have been cannabis extracts that
we found in you know basement ofes that
were in the dark for a hundred years
that were still active I you can still
take them today so have you had that
analyzed by a Cannabis Testing Lab
everything that's in my possession is
going to be uh processed in the archive
that's the next step for the Cannabis
Museum on my end uh Donnie has a museum
exhibit up in um Ohio that you can
actually go to it's a physical exhibit
also Ben jonkers has one in Amsterdam
and and Barcelona and then our friend
Richard has one up in up in the hills in
in Sonoma um at the moment those are the
the displays but as far as working on
the artifacts in that way we haven't
started that work yet th this has all
been pilot work that I've been doing
forever I'm just I have a lot of
medicinal bottles of cannabis also yeah
yeah
David probably the oldest artifact that
I know
a wooden cannabis container which would
have been you what what would you say I
was from Sam like 300 years ago it was
like uh 1450s or 1550s something like
that but I have older I have seeds from
the pear uh cynthian tomb and those are
2, 400 years old Jesus Christ those
those are the seeds you tossed at me
that day and I was like what are these
you're like oh those are just a couple
of Millennia old cannabis seeds yeah
they were in the little Leather Pouch
found in this cinti grave PE tombs
correct so Sam those are those are the
Siberian or the the more alai ancient
samples is that right with the the woman
I'd love to try to no not not from the
woman that work was done by uh Ethan oh
right with Hong and Jen right but I
I got seeds for helping the VIR the vavo
Institute St Petersburg who went visited
and they gave me eight of the cannabis
seeds from The Leather Pouch from the uh
archaeologist rosino who uh excavated
the Pez tombs in about I think
1949 would would you um maybe be
interested in sequencing the Genome of
those seeds that'd be um no I rather
keep them okay that's fine
too that's
F it's the that's insane like I'll tell
you when he threw them at me and I held
them in my hand and he told me what they
were I thought holy [ __ ] I've got maybe
10 different ones that are you know 500
thousand years old but these are in a
unique position 2400 years
old saying there's a chance we could pop
Sam
huh maybe some of the
500 with enough Bitcoin could we get
them from you or what I mean I'm I'm
just kidding no I I cannot be
bought I'm afraid that's the way it
works welcome to history Church ladies
and gentlemen yeah the way it should
be leave them in your will to be
uh to be explored
yes leave those to science if you if you
can there sir could those so here's a
question for the group could those what
could we learn from those um if there's
if they were I mean sure we could map
them but what what Ethan found out when
they analyzed the seeds which had been
frozen was that uh they were high THC
variety got it you're not GNA learn a
ton by High I I I I me I might mean 5 10
or whatever percent but they had more
THC than than CBN or CBD or anything
else so they were a drug variety they
were the highest THC for the lowest
dollar 2,400 years ago that you could
that you could get this has been this
has gone on longer than 30 years I'm
sorry
Debbie how many sexy shells does it take
back then to get a seed
there was something else that the um
this the seeds those seeds tell you from
their placement in the Tomb and you know
they in those old burial sites uh they
had you know
even their their slaves and and you know
some of their prize people you know in
the Tomb with them as well as some of
their prize possessions lining the walls
but then they'll have something right
next to their body which is of extreme
value to them and that's I where I
understand those cannabis seeds were
were found and it just reminds me of
something you I was talking to these
reporters years ago and I was trying to
sort of you know connect with them and
it just dawned on me that and this is
going back to my cannabis movement
experience and that sort of Grassroots
history lesson that I learned you know a
thousand Pages the handing out one at a
time of Jack harr's books or whatever um
you know that cannabis has been involved
in our lives as as humans in so many
ways over such such a continuous and
long period of time that by telling the
story of the artifacts you get a sort of
a lens into human history so it's more
about you know what the plant and and
its relationship with us can tell you
about us that this history tells us more
than then you know it it's own to me
it's amazing that there was no cannabis
in the Americas pre- Columbus I mean
that's just amazing to me but it's
apparently true yeah I thought it it
went all the way back to gondan land too
but there is no reference until you know
L later on um uh specifically but um
yeah I I can't thank you guys enough for
sharing that that history I mean it
helps us understand when I originally
came to cannabis when I went in ' 89
Jack herrer and de Debbie goldsbury were
at my University and when Debbie handed
out that piece of fabric and I literally
touched it and realized oh there was
more to can
those tangible really holding pieces of
history have such an impact that Michael
and skunkman Sam I mean when are you
guys gonna have this museum is there any
sort of fundraising that's happening to
make this Museum a reality as opposed to
all of y'all storing all houses I've
given up on my idea of opening the
museum probably the best cannabis Museum
from
both the medical and a uh recreational
point of view is Ben roers in
Barcelona that museum is pretty damn
cool yeah yeah Ben's done a fantastic
job with with both the displays in
Amsterdam and Barcelona really um you
know showcasing the history of cannabis
if you want to donate I the the couple
museums I talked about up in Richards up
in Sona I don't know if he's actually
accepting donations but I know Donnie is
for the Cannabis Museum in Ohio um
Michael and Michelle Aldrich and others
are working on a display in San
Francisco which hasn't really kicked off
yet but that'll be fundraising and then
I'm going to be fundraising pretty soon
here on the archive which I I'm G to
base unless something changes
drastically right here where I'm at um
in Virginia but that the archive is
where we'll be really preserving the
history more than anything because a lot
of the archives of our own cannabis
movement and stuff are being lost just
to entropy to to rain to water to bad
roofs but also to like storage units and
and airs that don't care about things
that are throwing stuff out and stuff so
we have a sort of a clock that we're up
against to get this stuff into
protective sleeves and and photographed
and up on archive uh once the archive is
up and running you'll at least know what
we have you'll be able to go online and
see what's available and from that you
can build build any number of displays
you know it's it this like hits really
hard for me you know I was thinking
about history and how we don't have
reference points for things and you know
imagine if science didn't have mum or or
something to look back on or art didn't
have Monae to look at at perspective or
you know Mike lano's work to look at in
terms of you know composition you know
like there's just you could just go on
and on I could just keep talking about
this but the one thing I look at with
breeding is like you know Sam you're
respectfully in my world that for me
like I look at your work I try to study
like what did you use to make these
things why did you I read a lot about it
and I think about a lot about that
because there's process there's there's
there's deep history that goes into what
you did and then the things that
influence that and it keeps going and
going and going and we seemingly have
little snapshots much like the you know
I think Ryan said it well like we have
little snapshots of like what
individually each individual person's
taste or what they're after is
contributing to that said fenan or
whatever it might be but it'd be really
great to understand um you know where we
came from you know and and what did
those individuals think about and what
were those
influences and why did they make those
choices you know because that's
ultimately we're arriving at a really
interesting inflection point with all of
this
where never before have more plants been
growing around the world we're all
researching racing towards lights and
different interesting Concepts but you
know we're forgetting you know like
Michael's work you know it's very it's
actually really important it's actually
so important that we understand these
reference points you know because that's
um you know why should you have to make
the same mistake someone else already
made you know maybe that's a better way
of saying it maybe there's things you
can learn from it that make your work
that much better you know Mark imagine
never reading Malcolm Mich right like
think you know like where would you be
you know so um you know I think it's
important that we take this seriously
and we really look at it from a a real
lens I mean you could laugh about it you
could say oh whatever man we're just
crossing stuff but there's a deeper
underbelly and under sense of of real
responsibility um I think we're all
getting at here that need that so um
really Michael like amazing you know
amazing work dude can can I comment on
that Colin um yeah please hoping others
will join me with this this idea yeah no
it's it's it's important because um I I
think that probably the biggest
selective pressure in the past for you
know land race populations and I'm sure
Brian and Sam could you know know more
about this than I do is um was was
climate and and geography right that was
like the big big one like did it did it
live or not did it survive here or not
that was probably a big Dynamic with you
know cannabis Americana in the beginning
as well growing it in the wrong climate
and I just thought I had a comment the
other day with with um Kevin mccaran had
posted some stuff on on um on LinkedIn
about aspergilus and aspergillosis and
all this stuff and all this mold and
total yeast and mold and it's just like
dude it's the same thing it's like okay
it's it's a real simple selective
pressure it's like does it grow or not
and it's like we collectively hybridized
all these bad genes that were for not
meant to be grown in certain places
because of their susceptibility to mold
and buildu and we just because because
we were in a you know a bubble of pre
pre uh you know pre- legalization we
[ __ ] we we [ __ ] up the gene pool
right we we introduced a bunch of bad
traits that are really dangerous like
any farmer would say why in the hell
would you introduce the susceptibility
to this thing that people all over the
world had moved away from because that's
what you do you know if it lives it
survives so anyway that one thing is
like how quickly we can screw things up
by not respecting history and not
approaching it like agriculture or
approaching it like the people who came
before us for hundreds of years you know
don't grow moldy weed don't grow weed in
indoor environment in high humidity that
is not supposed to be grown sort of like
the Potato Famine in Ireland
yeah exactly it's like just read the
understand the past and like it's just
amazing how prevalent that is now and
you see all these states that have
really low cfu numbers which is also you
know you know an is you see Delware 500
cfus how about Illinois 100 100 yeah
exactly how do you get something to
Market D Davis has his hand up so he
wanted to speak on that uh yeah I just
was going to say about the um like
pathogen resistance I think ultimately
what's happened is that there's just
been so many selections in a really
controlled environment we're having like
ridiculously low humidities and
someone's I mean this in any
condescending sense but like someone in
their basement with like 40% or lower
humidity in some cases so then in turn
there wasn't any biological reason
generation to generation to maintain
that pathogen resistance so what's
happened is we're losing the ability
because we've been in such controlled
environments ultimately because
prohibition was so limiting on what it
allowed people to grow and where to grow
you know you had to hide it you had to
make it you know um not smell as much as
well like all these kind of different
traits to try to hide it from from you
know getting in trouble for it so
essentially we've we've lost a lot of
the genetic
advantageous um traits that we used to
have from these various varieties in
various regions because like you guys
are saying there was generations of
survival needed for these things to
maintain and to propagate and to to
still be around today so yeah we we've
really been losing that unfortunately
and it's it's the same thing about like
I was saying earlier about um losing
diversity in terms of uh chemical
profiles it's it's very similar we
people don't have that much space so
ultimately they're going to only be
selecting for a small percentage of
traits generation to generation that
fits basically what what will fit in
that space you can't really have a you
know 15ot tall plant if you well in a in
a small place in your house you got to
you got to grow that Outdoors so we've
selected against what could have been
advantageous traits again in terms of
yield or in terms of uh quality of
product for what's going to fit the
environment that you know we we've been
selecting for so long it's not even that
we've left them out it's that we haven't
considered them right so
it's yeah if you can't if you don't
measure it in science if you don't
measure it you can't manage it yeah
right so it's just kind of like being
randomly selected or not and you know I
I kind of think of chromosomes I try to
give people the analogy of chromosomes
as like streets in a city or blocks of
streets on a city right so if you're
buying a house by the pictures you might
pick like a really nice house but the
one next door might be really ugly and
shitty right run down and like or a
crack house or something like that and
that's kind of what happens genetically
right you you select for one trait
heavily up until now we haven't really
known what the next door traits are
right or what other traits or bad
versions of traits are on that same city
block yeah for example if you look at
cannabis with mildew there's both
resistance and susceptibility genes
so you got to make sure you get the
right set you're we're getting to the
point now though where we can do all
these things with Canabis and it really
is just the will of the Breeders to
invest in that kind of Technology like
you know I I was speaking with a a Prof
at University the other day and they've
got genome sequencing down to five bucks
a sample so at five bucks a sample you
know complete run you can grow you know
you can grow 100 plants and it cost you
500 bucks to um to get your genomic data
but you know after four weeks you can
take that genomic data and select
against 90% of the plants right yeah
right so for not that big of an
investment we can start harvesting in
about these
plants kind of Upstream right of of us
having to take them through the the grow
cycle and um a lot of these technologies
that haven't been available to plant
breeders are now really like we're kind
of live like I said it the other day
we're living in the future right like we
you know it wasn't that long ago when
the first genetic markers came up it was
1995 when we had genetic markers that
would allow us to identify male cannabis
plants right and it's it's been 30 years
now and we we're way farther ahead and
we have a lot more data and we have a
lot more access to these tools so the
question becomes like you know like I
said with the chemical analysis and
analyzing every plant when do the
Cannabis
breeders you know the popular ones on
social media when do they start
investing in the plant because if they
don't the future is going to be owned by
corporations that do invest in that kind
of Technology right because if you
invest in the technology be able to um
harvest the gains of those Technologies
so you know it's kind of it's It's I
think we're coming up to kind of a make
make it or break at time some of these
people that are making a lot of money
selling seeds they should probably start
putting some of that money back into R&amp;D
and really stepping up their game and
that's really will be what allows them
to stay in the game or not you know yeah
I think what you're seeing now is is is
actually that I mean I've been talking
to a lot of guys that are like man I got
tractor trailer loads of seeds that are
not selling you know
and that's I think that's due to that I
think you're you're hitting it on the
head and you know moreover I think it's
the lack of the ability for a lot of
these larger facilities they get off
cycles that are nine to 10 weeks you
know um so they're looking for clones
they're looking for trays and proven
things that they don't have to really
invest in but to your point it's not
really the smartest thing to be doing
and look let's face it we're cannabis
breeders right like what we should be
doing is breeding the Next Generation
and evolving the plant not still growing
[ __ ] cookies and chamd right I was
just
thinking go look at anybody's menu right
like go look at anybody's menu if
they're just taking those same clothes
and Crossing them over they're doing it
and making money and they're not moving
the plantform I agree as long as there's
a lot of skunk number one in each of the
you well Sam it's already locked in
there in my opinion and and I would say
you know look KMD sour like we have no
historical references on that as to
where they came from truly what makes up
those profiles how those even came to be
and that's another aspect of like the
history I think that actually matters
like you know we're still talking about
where the skunk and the skunk went right
it's like really guys like this is this
is you know what I think R I can say
that I bred the skun out of
skunk answer I selected toward the sweet
side because I like the effects I like
the hide better yeah but listen I'm
sitting here smoking rosin with with Sam
as well and I will tell you there are
thols all up in this in the stuff that
we're smoking so that skunk it might
that chemical might not be there in that
variety sure but you know like to say
that these things are gone I think is
really like people just repeat eating
something they heard on the internet you
know yeah well that's what I'm doing
right now so I'm repeating that for a
reason because I wanted to bring that up
because I I like yourself I agree I
think the skunk still is here I think
GMO is a good example of it I think um
The Garlic is a good example of it I
think KMD is a good example of it I
think chem 91's a good example of it I
think there's sour first skunk I bred
the first few plants they were so loud
and tpping and like a dead skunk
smelling that if you have them double
zip locked in in your pocket I mean it
it stunk up the whole [ __ ] house like
a dead skunk and I bred away from it
because I found that the sweeter Higher
One were had more iy high and I like
strong but I like iy
strong I've also found like look
truthfully those we all know now that
the th as well these th uh whatever it
is one two3 MBT way more poke it's um
it's it's one of those chemicals that
just a very little bit can fill the room
right but again it's kind of like it
going back to that conversation with the
harmonics and the outboard gear um it
really is Headroom right it's like when
you stick your bag in a in a in a you're
sorry you stick your nose in a bag of
something that's heavily volatile often
you smell the turps but those those th s
they kind of get lost in the mix right
and you can you can smell it much better
when somebody just brings a bag into the
room and you get that little whiff of
that tiny little amount of volatile that
just takes it enough to set off your
receptors for whatever reason right so
dude this this jar I just found this jar
like the other day this is probably like
four years old this is garlic this stuff
reeks of skunk I mean it's the most
horrific stuff you'd ever see it looks
Brown as you could ever see it but I'd
like to get it tested to see what's in
there to be honest because it's some of
the loudest it's insane it's like I'm
like I don't even know how this is this
and it's not even been kept well it's
just been in a jar it reminds it reminds
me of the Renee from back in the day
which I called pot to get you busted
because it was literally problematic it
got people kicked out of hotel rooms and
I'm sure that was I mean you could speak
to it better than me Chimera but I
believe that there was some skunk going
on in that cultivar now listen have a
bunch of people are just so more
volatile they're really really volatile
but they're they're also in there in a
lot lower concentration so if you look
at what those guys from abstracts have
published those things are there in
parts per billion not parts per million
when you look at some of these tpin
they're there in singled digigit
percentages so it's app and orang
exactly they don't need to be there in
higher percentages not necessarily their
volatility it's how powerful they are at
much lower concentration I think it's
both
Mark well we got to get uh Nick zegler
on here to speak to that because he's
the one that you know put his multiple
analytical machines together and
discovered over 1,400 thol in hops when
he was working at yaka ma Chief hops um
we have a bunch of people with their
hands up so it was uh Davis was going to
go first and then Michael had something
to say and then uh Mojave had something
to say and once those three uh speak I
want to because we were getting into the
powdery Milos and these sort of
susceptible things I wanted to go to
Brian uh who wanted to talk a little bit
about this fungal blight that's wiping
out Gardens in the US so uh go ahead
Davis oh sorry I think uh Michael was
actually before me um he he was when he
put his hand up but you did the body
language and had your question before he
put his hand up so trust me I'm
perceiving all that's going on here I
just wanted to make respectfully um I
was just going to say two about when we
were talking about uh breeding that
ultimately what I think's happened as
well is that there's like a lack of
available germ plasm for a lot of these
uh seed developers or breeders and I
think the thing is too is that without
sounding insulting here like there are
breeders within the space that just want
to use other people's work I mean how
many companies have just been you know
developed essentially by taking skunk
number one and Crossing with something
rather than just trying to make it
something new and on one hand like I
think skunk is one of the best strains
in the entire world like I have nothing
but positive things to say but that
doesn't change the fact that you know
there's a lot of companies just
profiting off of that how many companies
just have you know cookies crosses that
ultimately they're using and with that
lack of germoplasm being available it's
it's also what's Limited a lot of these
people from producing new varieties or
producing new things but I completely
agree with you Ryan that nowadays I
think the future only is going to be and
I really see like a Renaissance within
the breeding um sector that we're going
to see more genotyping we're going to
see more advancement in terms of like
identifying all the markers rather than
just you know Crossing what you think's
going to sell and the other thing I
wanted to state with that as well is
that I think a lot of with again without
sounding insulting like some of the seed
producers out there they're not truly
developing new lines they're just
crossing together varieties that are
popular rather than trying to develop
something new or trying to develop and
improve in some way and it's it's more
about the marketability of having a name
rather than actually have a product
that's differentiated as
well go ahead
Michael yeah so um just sort of
interjecting I'm not uh totally confus
confusing things but there was one other
thing that came to mind that I wanted to
share with y'all this was a um 16-page
brochure that Park Davis
created
um I actually when I located this I was
very excited I brought it to the
attention of Dr mikaria for those who
don't know who Dr Todd mcre
was he was probably one of our Frontline
experts on medicinal cannabis um overall
in the in the medicinal cannabis
movement uh he was the point person for
the national in a mental health cannabis
team back in the 60s um when they were
look you know just beginning to look
into cannabis issues but anyway this was
a color this is black and white for our
um Journal article but this is a color
brochure in 16 Pages talking about uh
their cannabis product and uh that's
their lab that would be that's a nice
lab that would be cool if we had a lab
like that may I just wanted to share
that um with Todd Dr Todd we did this
article the marketing of cannabis
Americana we talked about basically re
republished the brochure in its entirety
and uh he and I talked about it but it
was a lot of fun I just wanted to share
that with you guys thank you for sharing
that and uh it's uh
Mojave uh I just wanted to point
something out because you guys were we
talking about Aroma and like a friend of
mine just told me a while ago it's like
are you on a war against Aroma because I
it's a it's a it's a topic that I think
we kind of gloss over a little bit too
quickly because cannabis to me is a drug
and it's a medic it's a medicinal plant
and it has a lot of value but when we
talk about when we put things in the
scope of Aroma um the way things smell
loud cannabis that word came up it's
such a marketable easy easy to Market um
strategy and we really don't know what
part like Ethan you know Ethan is known
for his work with with David on the
Entourage effect but we still don't know
really what is that what contributes and
there's been there's there's Ethan had a
i he's he did some work with um a
particular um paper called the nose nose
right and it's about how we use our nose
to drive our selective process and that
you know we know what we like we know
but David mentioned something or Sam you
mentioned something really good last
week I think it was last week when you
talked about your cross with hay and
hemp and you made a hemp iety that
smelled like haast right so what are we
what do we want from it do we want just
Aromas is the aroma the driving force
because breeder every breeder I talk to
just talks about Aroma right so that
Haze that Haze smelling hemp man that
did not get too high but it smelled like
it did it had all the right aroma so the
way we're looking at like breeding and
selection and marketing and the consumer
I kind of feel like it's a little bit
dangerous and maybe even a a little bit
Reckless to put this big conversation
that's cannabis chemistry solely into
the aroma class because that it triggers
a different part of your brain and the
consumer relationship with it is so
different than the medicinal drug effect
side and that's really important because
I see people
choosing selecting Aroma and skipping
over the effect in losing customers
losing consumers losing Pat patients
because they're not delivering they're
not even seeking what we really thought
what we sought out from Cannabis which
was a drug it's not just Jolly Ranchers
and flowers and soda pop it's the drug
behind those Aromas and how we connect
those two which is still like this big
science thols I mean the indle
discussion that that abstracts brought
up to me is the most compelling thing
I've heard in years in terms of
Entourage effect is that there's a
neurotransmitter precursors that are
ubiquitous in all of cannabis that also
have a really interesting Baseline Aroma
that mean it's like
whoa you know but it's not a pleasant
Aroma or it's not the one that is the
market Lemon Cherry gelato Aroma you
know what I mean anyway I think it's
from a lack of information being
accessible again because ultimately
there's what I've heard from um friends
of mine that own dispensaries and a lot
of uh friends of mine who are less
familiar with the industry is they'll
say how someone mentioned to them oh
well you know this smells this way so
it's going to have that kind of effect
rather than having more of like an
objective conversation about the
complexes of all the compounds in it and
again it's like it's easier to have that
be as part of an explanation than to say
about the chemical diversity and all the
different compounds that are in it so
it's just more simplistic and I mean
there is there is truth to the idea that
different cines will in turn you know
modulate the profile and effect to some
extent but I think I think what's
happened is that that's become the
dominant conversation and it's easier
for people who don't necessarily
understand the chemistry of cannabis to
use that as their like driving
conversation or their marketing tool and
it's ultimately too I think it's
especially uh like we were talking about
with younger people um they're they're
less aware of like you know diversity of
effects because again they've just been
led to this idea oh it smells this way
it's going to have a different effect
rather than the idea of the full
diversity of the profile and at the same
time I'm not trying to dismiss um like
Tes I'm just trying to say that I think
it's just easier to communicate that to
people it's easier to have that type of
understanding rather than to have the
idea that that's a very complex plan but
it's crazy and a little bit dangerous is
my point is that like we Market I mean
like and this is a joke and I've said it
before and it's just a but if we
marketed like opioids that way yeah oh
my God yeah I completely agree with you
easy hey dude these Vicodins are
strawberry flavored Vicodins and these
are
the want everyone's going to choose the
strawberry ones but that's really
dangerous and it takes everyone on a
different path and it takes our brains
and our relationships with products
because flavor and Aroma are so Primal
and they're about safety and about
security where a drug thing is very
esoteric and requires a deeper so to me
it's not the consumer the dispensary
it's kind of the Breeders and the big
brands that have to kind of get
responsible and like not just not just
not just about it's an opportunity to me
it's like a drugs are you know selling
drugs is the thing right so there's like
there's opportunity with aligning with
that type of strategy it's just
harder completely right it's very much
deeper than that especially with
cannabis because it's been shown again
beta caropine for example right uh uh
acts on CV2 but I think I think what
happens in general with with tpen is
that they increase the fluidity at the
lipid bilayer and so it's likely and
again I think this is just still
hypothetical although there's a couple
couple articles that have shown this is
that is that there's an outside in
signal that
upregulates receptor expression at the
cell surface right and and that's a it's
a very complicated mechanism because
what's happening is again tpes kind of
interpolate into the lipid by layer and
I've likened it to just opening up the
windows at your house right you're going
to start exchanging the air between the
outside of your house and the inside of
your house so when when that happens
again there's a lot of compounds that
are secondary Messengers that are coming
in that could potentially upregulate
canono expression so it's too bad Dr
Russo had to out because I think this is
the molecular basis that could explain
the Entourage or The Ensemble effect
which is that how do you H like Stam has
said for years here on hash church that
Turin can modulate the action and I
think Davis you you had just said this
too Tes can modulate the action of THC
at CB1 so how does that happened
well I also I also say that a few of
them can potentiate the effects of DC
correct potentially as opposed to
modulate so so what kind of mechanisms
just think simplistically how can that
potentially happen so there could be a
confirmational change in the receptor
active site that makes those THC
molecules work better but I think what
could certainly be at play here is again
a signal that we don't quite understand
but there's something coming into the
cell that's basically causing an
upregulation of receptors so now there's
more CB1 receptors with more CB1
receptors yeah that the the effect can
be more more pronounced and why uh a
full
spectrum you know medication with full
turpine Entourage all the thols alahh
eyeses Esters everything else that we
know you know we were kind of saying
this on hash Church a week or so ago
that we can a live resin analysis now
and
between the tpin and between the canono
we're accounting for
99.9% of the material that's in there so
there's yeah thol is in there at very
very low concentration but essentially
we've we've identified everything that's
coming out of the cannabis plant you
know just even like a handful of years
ago on hash church we were talking about
this and we were still kind of like in
the 90s so if you think about like what
those guys at abstracts have done which
is they've identified that very minor
component that's there in an order of
magnitude less than the Turpin right
Turpin are there in single percentages
these things don't have to be in there
in a whole lot to add a whole lot of
flavor and it's so cool because like I
think the thing when Ian talks about
this you know they'll they'll go after
things like lioning d dominance in like
a fruity or lemony kind of strain and
not find liony in there at all so it's
like man there's something else that's
creating a citrus kind of you know lemon
type fragrance that has nothing to do
with limine so if you were just focusing
just on Ling itself you'd kind of miss
the forest through the
trees yeah you know the one thing I was
thinking about the what you're saying
Mark and it's almost like the ozone
layer getting blown up for a second and
then slowly repairing itself and the
blood brain barrier and those
constituents going through um and when
when you know a lot of the the things
that I was doing in the last two years
when we were looking at a sleep
formulation we started
really spent a lot of time on canabo and
then I shifted and started spending a
lot of time on tpin and there was a very
clear reason why because it was very
clear that the modulating aspects of of
those formulations were actually more
important for sleep than the actual
canabo sure the constituent of it was
important to get there but it wasn't CBN
that got you there it was like yeah you
get to sleep with CBN but it actually
was like more of an antagonist when
you're sleeping to wake you up in the
middle of the night than it was to keep
you asleep the whole time so I think the
modulating what I learned was there's
just a whole lot to to learn in terms of
the modulation aspect and it truly keeps
you on your toes but we have a real
problem with our industry is like making
these formulations
there's a real Line in the Sand of like
you have the plant on the right and then
you have faeron and all this other
flavorant if you will we'll just call
them that that are not from the cannabis
plant and sure you can get these
profiles to mimic in some
respect but to your point of actually
the modulation and and getting through
the BL you know brain barrier and
actually doing what it's supposed to do
creating those formulations in the lab I
think are far more difficult than anyone
in their Wildest Dreams understands and
I think you know and there's also
toxicology problems with that major
major tox problem so yeah I'd love to
you know again I don't we don't want to
throw Ethan under the bus but I think is
doesn't he work or advise
the yeah he does right so there's this
huge business around you know cannabis
Turpin or are they cannabis derived are
they not cannabis D you know there's
there's this comp there's this um Farm
colon I don't know if you know them up
in um uh Oregon called tpine belt farms
and I think their business model is yeah
just to harvest steam to Ste the tpin
and then plow the Cannabis back into the
fields so they're not even going after
they're not even going after canono and
and you know again kind of like what
Davis was saying well I think what we've
all been saying which is that and I
think Mojave mentioned the nose paper
and the nose paper again I think was
like one of those it was interesting how
those papers kind of came out because
the nose paper came out while abstracts
was doing their work around thol and the
nose paper kind of like if you think
about it what they're saying is that
there's something more than just turpine
profile right so you can't just look at
oh taline dominant strains we were
talking about the Cali
turpine dominance and and and what what
that means to people and and the people
who like you know gassy kind of like
chem and sour d i mean there's a certain
kind of flavor arom in there that's
really not citrusy it's more gassy it's
more like tastes like a Sal kind of like
you know what what that does the
efficacy I think when you experience
like you're pulling a dab you're pulling
a vape pen
and you want that vape pen just to taste
like the Cannabis from which it's
derived well interesting to go back to
Ryan's earlier discussion you know when
you look at these fresh frozen profiles
and compare it to something that's been
dried and then cured for several months
not only is the tpping content
completely different right right because
you're losing a lot of those tpin and
drying and curing but now the whole
profile is changed right and I think
think like all that merine dominance
that you see in live resin and
everything I think what happens is not
only does the merine volatilize on
drying but I think it probably does
maybe chemistry and turns into other
tpes could they be oxidizing the Turpin
noids right so like the huge uh like in
fact that has hasinine hashen am am I
not saying the molecule right I think is
an oxidative degradated product
of merine right and they found that it
only happened in the the the outside
skin of the hash that was exposed to
light so there's probably a fair amount
of chemistry happening in the Cure that
you're not getting in fresh frozen or
live resin but uh I love it all I think
it's great that you can do kind of like
a a live resin profile that captures
exactly the turpine profiles in the
plant but also do what Sam had done for
years which is like you can't smoke that
stuff until six months from now after
you've had a wh sale dry and then a cure
for at least I don't know four or five
months then you could smoke it right
yeah I mean if you look at steam
distilled turps like the one thing I've
learned from working with people like
TBF and others and at scale is like
getting those really sulfur this real
sulfur compounds is nearly impossible
because you're burning them off during
that process and and that that's what
those compounds are essentially right or
those profiles have amount to um a
little bit is volatilizing right maybe a
little bit yeah maybe a little bit taste
when you taste good chem de or when you
taste Sour Diesel you're probably
getting a few ppb of those sulfur
compounds that you say 100 yeah yeah but
it's I guess what I'm getting is it's
very difficult um but there's also a
deconomy here like someone goes into a
store and someone said it like maybe
Mary said it the we have a problem with
marketing people are marketing these
profiles as such and an un UND
Discerning consumer goes in for Sour
Diesel and it's some lab concoction of
resemblance it of it you know that says
Sour Diesel but it's not nothing came
from the plant so therefore it doesn't
even resemble the profile but they walk
away saying like telling their friends
this is sour diesel so and themselves
right so I think that's also a problem
um within the actual um you know retail
side of the industry and marketing
aspect it's
like have you ever bought store bought
turps that taste any good I've only made
them right from fresh plants that we've
grown and you never bought like from a
tpine vendor no one no one has been able
to produce anything close to the plant
right ATN right amazing because like all
those flavorants are being used in vape
pens today because you know you know
those are food grade right you're what
you're talking as opposed to properly
extracted turs like Colin is talking
about yeah guys I I can tell you like
I've audited all these guys I looked at
all their SDS I had a really great team
around me of of great a brilliant
toxicologists and what we found is that
almost every single formulation
has ridiculous amounts of things that
from a talks perspective just shouldn't
even be in there at all and it's it's
really concerning I think it's really
something you know know these you know
people go in for wellness and they come
out with other things right and I think
that's the other deconomy we're in that
I think about and it's our job it's
literally our job to make great products
to serve those patients you know because
we are patients as well we need the
right medicine well col I I don't know
if you saw that the the couple very
interesting pieces of legislation this
week uh yesterday Gavin Newsome kind of
threw down the Gauntlet in California
outlawing all uh synthetic
intoxicating uh cannabinoids but um so a
few months ago there was a ruling uh
that Rod kite had kind of poked the DEA
bear and got the DEA to basically say
that
thco uh is schedule one and also uh the
THC the Delta 8 and Delta 9 from which
it's derived is also so schedule one and
then yesterday uh or I think the day
before uh the fourth Circuit Court just
turned that over and they
basically said that
thco which is the acetate of thca
qualifies as H hemp and this is kind of
like a step in the wrong direction
because man it's kind of like it's
basically giving these hemp folks now a
leg up saying that there's Court
precedent now that this is now hemp
and it's all synthetic the plant doesn't
make this stuff at all and this feeds
that whole Beast of uh you know why is
someone gonna go to ATN shop and buy a
$40 vape pen go down to the gas station
and get a $10 one right like
five that hemp industry is making big
money off of those little loopholes and
don't think that they're not spending
some of that money in in h Washington to
make sure Ryan Ryan it's it's
unbelievable so the Colorado task force
that was looking into this and there's
lawsuits estimates that market just
south of $60 billion so greater than 50
billion the combined cannabis markets in
the US combined they think is only about
29 million so this is like 2x greater
than the than the Cannabis markets it it
it's a it's a much larger addressable
Market they have no regulations and they
sell on the internet over state lines
two clicks after saying that you're 21
years old they're asking you for your
credit card information yeah I don't
know how the the US cannabis industry is
going to compete it's well they're
spending like I know that they're
spending big money with certain
candidates too so you know it's
obviously you don't want to hear it that
you think that that influ that money is
influencing uh Judicial Systems but it's
certainly influencing political systems
well you're absolutely right because
most big Multistate operators including
Wana including a lot of ones are now
making plays into this hemp space so
it's kind of like you can't beat them
while we're going to join them and and
again try to take some of that market
share away so it's a it is really a [ __ ]
show down here I mean I I I I don't know
how the regulated market is GNA survive
this I really don't go ahead Davis yeah
it's incredibly home growing
oh Sam was just saying that the best way
to fight it is to allow home growing and
I can't say dis agree with that you know
a lot of these things happen because
you've got one set of law for the
federal regulations on hemp and then you
have a bunch of different Island
regulations that have apply to the
different states and yeah man like I
don't know it's gonna it's G to change
things for sure when the federalized
federal legalization happens but you
know I also just want to say as a
Canadian and having done that you know
regulating cannabis or legalizing
cannabis effectively destroyed the seed
Market in Canada Canada right um it's
just not possible how so how did it what
do you what do you mean like for for the
m mostly for export like you know at the
same time the states has lightened up
and considered cannabis seed as hemp
seed right we we now have like a high
excise tax and you actually have to get
Federal um export license and import
licenses so it's really made created a
legal situation where we can't operate
whereas the opposite has happened in the
United States right
like that's going to change here in the
United States there's actually going to
be a hemp Bill we've talked to people
behind the scenes that's coming down the
pike in October that is going to close
the loopholes now of course what Dr
scalone was talking about which is that
Court setting around thco just kind of
put a little thorn in that side because
of that legal precedence there is kind
of upset the cart because a bunch pardon
my language the DA's got hard on waiting
for this to be changed so that they can
come bash in skulls they've been waiting
for so long to come in and to get with
people that that loophole is going to
close and it will be bipartisan and it's
coming and so we can act surprised but I
know people who have ramped up who are
just getting rid of their stock now
because the writing is on the wall it's
coming and when right after that comes
then comes the hammer and it's going to
come down hard and heavy and it's going
to be ugly
yeah
I the US is in Renaissance right now
it's really crazy there's a lot of drug
use going on and if you really I mean
and the farm bill hemp is perfect
example of that how it's being pushed
through so aggressively and with little
with Little Resistance but go to your
local head shops and see what's on the
Shelf now I mean I I ran head shops in
La 25 years ago I managed a couple head
shops and there things on the Shelf now
head shops are a
drugstore it's just insane nootropic is
a new thing in head shops no Tropic it's
a new way of selling psychedelics
somewhat legally there's a bunch of
stimulants that they're selling there's
lots of Cava there's lots of katum
there's lots of you know there's it's
but walls of it and the walls of weed
too thca flour and all every different
vape and every different you know canabo
everything is all on the Shelf at your
local corner store some of it is a
little bit fuzzy in terms of gray area
some of it's fully legal because it's
been tested in courts but the but the
far out part is it is on Main Street and
when I when I ran head shops in the in
the late 90s we couldn't even call it a
bong called it a water pipe it was a
tobacco store it was it was Prohibition
days now those head shops which are
everywhere now there's way more head
shops than ever and they sell Walls and
walls of drugs and I'm not against that
at all I think drugs are part of you
know human you know Evolution we like to
feel different you know but it does
require regulation and it does require
some Public Safety mechanisms to make
sure that it's done right but when I
talk to the guys at the head shop
because one of them is right next to my
local pizza place and I go in there and
just rap with the guy and he tells me
about all the drugs he's selling all day
long I mean it's like you can call it
whatever you want man but it's drugs and
they're not people aren't coming in for
rolling papers and Vapes they're coming
in for these weird different combo drugs
Michael Which is far out because it's
like these compounded you know things
where it's katum and some kind of other
stimulant and some kind of other weird
thing and it's and and they're selling
it like hot cakes all day long and
that's and these are and this is and
this is in La when you still have
dispensaries too so you can get the
legal weed you can get the trapper weed
you can get the head shop weed and you
can get mushrooms at the church up in
Oakland and you can get DMT at the other
place in in Santa Cruz and and then at
every thousands and thousands of head
shops all over the state you can buy all
these other
substances anyway something's going on
and the fact that like places like
Minnesota sell THC Beverages and THC
Vapes at almost every gas station now
it's not going back that's all I say
it's just they're not we're not going
back and whether it's a farm bill path
or whatever or whatever loophole or
whatever something's going on and it's
just speaking of that actually Michael
crowz is actually G to be testifying
specifically on katum uh part of our
International Group helped keep katum
legal uh a few years ago when uh other
countries wanted to make it Michael krow
you want to speak on that what you'll be
speaking toward I think it's the 20th in
DC well yeah
I guess just the the basics of this
hearing um there's going to be
considerable amount of scientific
support some very uh top subtop medical
experts including the head of naida
National Institutes of drug abuse which
is interesting um but um my aspect of it
is just to talk about veterans issues
the difficulty of uh dealing with plant
material in uh you know Veterans Affairs
hospitals are are kind of like prisons
in the regard that they really work on
label mostly uh They Don't Really Work
even off label let alone anything
outside the box so uh getting like plant
material inside the VA Pharmacy short of
an FDA approved medicine um is is really
a it's our challenge at our you know
veterans Action Council basically it's
one of our key challenges um but that's
that's what we're trying to do in in the
end of the day and katum like cannabis
is helping a lot of veterans and and
other people uh not hit rock bottom with
opiates and want up being one of the
statistics with opiate death or or or
suicide death as well for some of our
groups like like veterans you know
police First Responders Etc so having
cannabis and and katum sort of pushed
out of the system by drug testing is not
that doesn't lead you to the end you
want you know that's basically what I'm
going to be telling these guys
I was just going to comment on um
talking about like you know the
synthetic products and the other things
getting around I think part of that is
because there's still legislation
against cannabis in so many states of
course people are going to try to find
every single way to get around the laws
and regulations to get it through and so
ultimately what I do think's going to be
a shift is that once there's more
Federal recognition of it once at very
least that we have medical marijuana at
a federal level the United States we
will start to see a shift I believe in
terms of all these loopholes being
closed and that's part of the problem is
every time we try to you know try to
avoid the issue we're essentially making
it worse because we're getting all these
synthetic compounds rather than you know
natural cannabis derivatives into the
market and it's leading again to more
and misinformation oh it's a naturally
derived product or something like that
rather than actually being from Cannabis
and I I just wanted to comment on uh one
thing that was mentioned earlier when we
were talking about strain profiles and
the synthetic um synthetic ones I think
I think there's even more than just that
I mean when we were talking about Sour
Diesel there's people that I know that
will tell me that they have Sour Diesel
and I smell it I'm like this this is
definitely not Sour Diesel so there's
not even really a regulation if you will
in the legal Canadian Market here that
recognizes specific varieties and
specific profiles and that's part of
again the problem with all the
misinformation within the Canabis spaces
there's users who don't necessarily know
what's what I usually give this as an
example of um let's say pink Kush was
smelling really or selling really well
and has a specific smell to it has a
specific effect has a specific look well
if one companies having success with
that ultimately a bunch of other
companies there's nothing stopping them
from saying oh yeah we have pink Kush
and just renaming a variety that they
have that name and ultimately it leads
to more imiss information and then
additionally as well they you know let's
say someone sees that there's this pink
cush now at a more budget conscious
price they go and try it and they think
oh maybe I'm building up a tolerance to
this variety I didn't really like it as
much and it takes away from the market
share of someone who is actually
creating a real variety it's unfortunate
because it's again just leading to more
misinformation and more problems within
the industry yeah that's always been the
way it was the names travel faster on
the internet than the cuting do and I
mean this was happening back with skunk
and Northern Lights right that those
names would be in the magazine and
someone would take that name and put it
on a on a flower that they had that
wasn't selling and in that new market
people come to believe that that's the
skunk one or the northern lights or the
cookies or whatever the name is yeah um
and you know I know I I harp on this a
lot talk about plant registrations but
this is one of the things that plants
registration solves right because the
name is granted to the PBR holder upon
registration right so it's like you know
somebody in Holland one of the seed
companies years ago ran around and tried
to uh to register all these names as
commercial trademarks it's copyright
yeah as copyrights that with recently
like literally recently someone did this
with hay now this was like in the 90s
right yeah yeah in the 90s and they they
came and actually tried to enforce all
these things and Sam had actually put
some of these varieties through the PBR
process not with the intent to
profit from them but in in essence to
keep them in the public domain so that
nobody could do this yeah right and so
but yeah like in the registration
process when you get a registration is
granted to a plant breeder that's how a
plant gets its name right and how a
plant product gets his name so you can
walk into a gr grocery store in New York
City or LA or Washington DC or anywhere
in Canada or even anywhere in Europe and
get a granny smith apple and they're the
same plant
yeah right it's all the same
plant s up real quick but that those are
two different things of the plant
variety protection gives the name
assigned to
that um patent or or or plant variety
protection but it doesn't give it the
name in The Marketplace that's a
trademark no not for an apple no but the
trademark is not as high as a plant
breeders right yeah like if it went to
somebody if somebody tried to take a
trademark will lose yeah the trademark
lasts and the plan the the patent
patents expire trademarks don't so the
reason that that Granny Smith or the the
um the power behind the name with a uh
you know a um an apple variety is the
trademark name so the on the patent it
could be in the application is a name
and that name is defendable in court but
in the marketplace in terms of
Interstate Commerce and how it's treated
at least in the US with a patent that's
handled by the trademark office and
trademarks aren't allowed are aren't
granted to cannabis at all in the US
well they are but patents are granted to
cannabis in the US and you have to
remember Mojave as well that the US is
like the only place other than Australia
that recognizes plant patents this thing
is not done through these things are not
done through patents outside of the US
right they're done PBR and the PBR is
the dominant system yes the copyright
doesn't hold up nothing to a plant beers
right in the EU in Canada and in most of
the Civilized world yeah yeah you
couldn't you couldn't you couldn't take
um a a name of a plant of a sorry a PBR
protected variety and try to apply it to
a good you'd lose in court but my point
is that in the US right now anybody can
call any plant anything they want
legally and there's no protection
against that
whatsoever you know I think to the
speaker's point I'm sorry I forgot your
name
you know these these the you're exactly
right in the marketplace people go do go
out and do these things because these
varieties are not protected right
they're not registered varieties and so
essentially we take these plants and
give them a name and you release them
into the public domain and what happens
happens variety that I can't I can't
attach a name to so it has a name it has
a name in the application but I can't in
the marketplace I can't claim any name
to it legally so mve look at in the in
our chat I just post
exactly what Ryan just said this is
gives way to exactly what I posted here
this guy just took a haze plant was like
now it's Unique flower original Haze I
saw that yeah I've actually communicated
with the guy like really man yeah I mean
there there was never a Sam hay original
hay uh original hay was the name given
it to to it by the Breeders and that's
the name I stuck with but there's a a
Neville original Haze there's a a
greenhouse original Haze or Haze
whatever I don't think they use the word
original you got to remember too a
patent is granted but that's not the
final ruling on if you actually own that
piece of intellectual property it's kind
of of like a stake in the ground right
it's like someone saying hey I own this
thing that there is an entire process
for challenging patents and you know
essentially the court system that deals
with just that so I that although that
that guy has staked you know something
in the
ground and even and even like Min
concertive nobody has appealed it yet
yeah if I was to appeal it I bet you I
could knock it down but I have no
interest in it uh I you know let the
stupid people do what stupid people do
and so far yeah the import the important
thing is that they become talking points
and we use them for Education right yeah
because yeah you know when we did those
first patents with with
Neo or the bhc group or whatever you
want to call it that that everybody was
pretty upset about that whole thing but
it really spurred people to start
getting patents and don't get me wrong
Mojave like you know being in the United
States and having that P that plant
patent certificate is actually a pretty
impressive thing um because typically
even in you know in PBR countries
chemical profile is not enough to
register a variety is different it's
done on morphological traits so it
really allows that patent system in the
United States allows it kind of fits the
niche of what cannabis is right because
you can find these new plants that are
chemically unique you you Pro plant
breeders rights has not grown up to the
real world of the importance of tpin and
things like that you know they will it
it will happen and uh I just wanted to
mention too that I got my first uh uh
upup uh plant breeders rights in
97 I had applied maybe a year or two
earlier but uh in 97 they were granted
and uh I I was the first one in the
world to get a a drug variety with plant
breeders
rights and we we did it we didn't do it
because we thought I mean we did it just
as a as a process just to like be adult
about cannabis and see what it would be
like but we also got a you a variety
protected through upov as well and we
also Sam you probably were the one who
helped us do this but we got the
enforcement Division behind it as well
um so we got the Dutch group their name
fleets me right now but they basically
so we have a UPA protected plant and we
have a group that will enforce that
protection all around the world they
have offices in every agricultural
region around the world and yes I I'm
I'm the one that uh that showed the
these people I had worked with them for
a really long time and uh Ryan knows
them so does Rob I've taken both of them
to visit with them and uh they she her
office she was on the uh upupa board and
she's the one who kept saying they will
change they will add chemical profile
they will add Turing Etc but it still
hasn't broken through to youp yet
yeah whereas in patents it is all it
takes is someone with the money to apply
to to essentially do the process to have
them change the system right um it's
it's actually the type of thing that
would be really nice if everybody buy
them they all know it needs to change
but it hasn't changed yet so what does
everyone think of like a canopia prior
art registering
sequencing what is that helpful for for
the people out there that don't have
access
to you know filing their novel plants
and you know is that even helpful for
people in your opinion because I I go
back and forth and I I think it's
helpful to understand relationships
between things and it's it's neat to see
that um but there's just such a large
big picture being missed there at times
I'm for all cannabis science regardless
of their motivation regardless of
anything I want to know yeah I think the
question though is it a useful system to
be able to defend intellectual property
I think other than being able to say I
have a time a timestamp on this with
this genetic at this point in time is
helpful but even that doesn't tell the
St whole story right like that doesn't
prove development and it doesn't prove
ownership yep and I think it's again
it's something that happens in the
Canabis industry a lot yes feel that
they can't people feel that they can't
participate in the legal system and so
they run around and they try to come up
with reasons why they're going to
develop their own system and you know
everybody should do what they want to do
and it becomes essentially
like it's it becomes
optin right and an opin system when it
comes to enforcement is [ __ ] useless
excuse my do not work it's totally
useless right and that's that's why
having like like like Mojave said when
you get the registration and then you
sign a a a contract with a company that
is that takes on responsibility of
enforcement but like a patent patents
can cost a bloody Fortune to defend if
you get a lot of opposition with the
same thing with uh uh upov if you have a
reader rights to a particular variety
and you know other people have copies of
that variety and are growing it and
selling it let me tell you gr after them
ain't cheap yeah can I give you my poor
man's IP tip and and and uh I think this
really would work out of all the
different like plant registration
nonprotected plant registration
herbarium slash kind of send us in your
sample phos whatever this is the one
thing that I've done for about 10 years
that is I think
foolproof is freezing your
Calon yeah it's like mailing your uh
your songs to yourself right yeah but
it's even better though because it shows
that you were the person who handled
that seed that it's not brilliant I I
really think it's a smart idea I haven't
heard
that and that way sure you don't have IP
sure it's not enforcable but if anyone
like like Sam says enforcing a patent
like I have a patent but I don't have a
team of lawyers so if someone wanted to
challenge me and like and and just steal
my my plant what if they they would get
away with it they could outspin me
easily I've been outspent by before by
people who ripped me off you know but so
when you're in court and then you pull
out your little well okay well did you
plant the seed okay then do you have
these little leaf tissue things that
show it came off of a little seed L say
but so then say they reach into their
bag and they've developed the breeding
technology that allows them to have your
plant material in their seed how do you
prove that it came from yours right
like yeah yeah the trouble is that the
Sharks and Minnows were all minnow and
the sharks are out there yeah well it's
yeah in it's like the music industry
it's like the moment you show a song to
someone it's like it that chorus reverse
may end up in like 20 other songs in a
session right and before yours even gets
out you're like [ __ ] I showed that guy
that you know doesn't matter definitely
seems to be part of human
nature yeah certainly part of the
Cannabis industry's nature there's no
doubt about it well there was no other
nature it's not like there were
germplasm institutes and is doing it
right that you know Sam had to go around
and actually you know fund and support
them and make those reality as well as
others otherwise you know what would we
have if it you know you sure the grock
treaty is now the Treaty of the of and
the reality that we experienced but what
if it hadn't been for the Arians and
dronkers and others what would and to
tell you the truth when I collected
seeds starting in the 70s there weren't
none of these laws so I could legally go
collect land races bring them to
California reproduce them sell them do
whatever I wanted and there was no
regulations I think it's better that
there is a regulation and that the
caretakers and the Breeders and the
original Farmers should get some sort of
piece of the pie yeah that sounds right
so when you were collecting seeds so
you've said this a few times over the
years where they're literally I mean
basically what you're saying to me and
what I'm hearing I'll just steal it all
the way down is all the seeds that we
have we shouldn't technically have
because we've stolen them right as a
community no that's not
1,00% but uh I'd say so what is it
that's probably true look it's exactly
like colonialism I mean you were born in
America you're an American citizen but
your genetic Roots come from there you
you were essentially a seed of the evil
spawn of colonialism does that mean you
you're wrong or you can't
do you owe the blacks a bit bunch of
money because you're white do you owe
the American Indians a bunch of money
because you're white uh that's a hard
nut to crack here's an interesting thing
is that in in a lot of the
Cannabis so more I think more cannabis
germ plasm came from export than from
people sourcing it from location so they
exported illegal weed and US peasants
collected the seeds out of it that's
absolutely true I think that that forced
upon us is what you're saying sorry it
was forced upon us really exactly it
showed up in my back door and little
pellets fell out and I put them in the
ground I you know but but interestingly
enough I think a big narrative is that
we went out into the world and brought
these seeds back but I think fewer
that's Sam and there's very few Sams in
the world that actually went there and
got Seed where most of the ger PL came
in the form of flower or being shipped
to the US I I think there's more Sams
today than there was 30 40 years ago
because uh there's a lot of people out
there going and collecting land races
and trying to profit from them you know
I I really like the philosophy of the of
the of upov and that is yes the things
that you can
develop you have the right to
commercially profit from them but if you
use the upov system and you do get a
registration for example you have to
make that variety available for home use
you have to make it available for other
breeders right they can't just knock it
off and sell the same thing that you
created but they can use it in the
development of future plant varieties
and the reason is that that plant
genetic resources
are or should be available to all of
humanity right like plant genetic
resources themselves should not be owned
by a corporation or an individual right
so yeah you can benefit for a period of
time from from the developments that you
make from those resources in some
countries you have to give the original
breeder of a variety that is used to
create subsequent varieties you have to
give them a portion of the
profits other in other countries uh it's
not allowed without the breeder's rights
and and the breeder can say you can't do
it so there's a lot of different uh
iterations of that yeah and that's
that's one of the real differences about
the patent is that when you actually
have the patent you don't have to make
that those plants available to other
people they are the corporate property
of whatever entity registered them or
holds the patent
right important what it's a very
different fruit of the system is what it
is right well it's yeah it is right but
there's other systems around us like the
music industry that live and die by that
like you can't sample an artist without
them saying okay and going through
either their state or them personally
and do it if you get
caught yeah but I mean it's really easy
to do it you know to you know or you
have I've you know for me I've sampled
people and then I have to go into the
session and basically mimic it right um
and recreate it um so it's it goes both
ways but I like that because it holds
people to a standard it and it keeps our
you know we were talking about earlier
in the conversation history intact like
there's a historical reference here
where this began and why and here's
where it's going and that person and
that that Legacy is along with it
so I'd love to see Sam get res you know
in this you know in the same light
residuals right for no no I that's not
why I did it course not the reason I
produced millions and millions and
millions of seeds was because I wanted
to change the world and to do that there
needed to be seeds there needed to be
clones there needed to be artificial
lights and now that the world has
changed uh let's finish the job and make
it so everybody anywhere can grow for
any reason and uh you know the hell with
h the Nay there's another little lesson
in there as well about plan IP when you
sell seeds you've given weigh the rights
yeah right you haven't so it's you know
if people are really truly concerned
about owning these things they shouldn't
be selling the seeds and just be aware
that if you are selling the seeds you
can kiss your rights goodbye because you
you sell those rights when you sell the
seeds yeah right so it's an important
distinction to understand and it's you
want to jump in there Davis you had your
hand up for a while now I was just going
to comment on the idea about land races
again that like they were stolen I think
I I think there are situations where
people didn't have permission or
ultimately made you know through some
nefarious means to get um the
opportunity to take them but I mean like
I've got I've got five contacts three or
family friends of mine which is where
I've sourced and developed my germ plasm
library and I can speak for my family
friends that are preservationists and
like very much into you know
preservation of culture history all of
that not just into cannabis that they
want to make sure that you know the
information from those regions the type
of culture gets recognized and
ultimately like the hardships and
everything that's associated because in
a lot of these regions that are isolated
that there still is you know cannabis
cultivation that hasn't been alterated
adulterated and I want to State while
I'm saying that some of these areas
likely have had adulteration over
decades or even were those seeds from uh
imported into the United States or were
they coming from different countries
they're coming from different countries
originally and it was
illegal yeah I guess that's fair to say
I I more was just making the point that
the there's no if or buts about it uh if
you don't go through the UN treaty
biodiversity Nama treaties Etc and the
newer one it's
illegal okay
and that's the thing is that those those
reality that we have had We Exist under
and now it's going to be an interesting
fight currently that treaty the gro
treaty Michael I believe is being tested
by neem and India India is going after
people who extracted and took neem and
this is going to be the first kind of
world test case um specifically under
the new treaty am I correct on that
Michael oh you're following that more
than I am so
yeah so it's a new frontier people and
that's that's the thing what what what
has existed and what does exist is is
down a new pathway and this is the a of
responsibility that we're talking about
that has been deflected for Generations
now has to come home to roost and you
know it's it's a new day and we're
looking forward to seeing what happens
who Rises to the occasion and I stated
you know India's taking its first step
and it's around neem and neem is a type
of tree that you can express press the
oil out of the leaves and has been used
I know I have used it as a um you know a
natural disinfectant or cleaner of
plants in gardens so um it's going to be
interesting to see because no one's gone
this way with cannabis yet but now there
is precedence and somebody's gonna fly
and run with that
flag with neem too it's been used for
thousands of years as a toothbrush in
India just the stems hey just to say if
you're in if you're in Canada and those
seeds came into the Country Canada is
not a signatory to the ngoya protocol so
um again it comes down to enforcement
unless you were like advertising it
as directly
from uh you know a certain certain
population down in South America there's
no enforcement action to go after you
because Canada is not part of a
signatory to the party right and even
even within the neoya protocol it's more
about systems and less about enforcement
like there is no real enforcement arm to
the treaty so like if you violate the
rules there's nobody to come after you
yeah right so it's like these again
that's what I was saying like these
systems are kind of it to a degree
they're opt in now Holland is in a
different boat right because Holland is
a signator signatory to these treaties
yeah I think all the European nations
are so you know it sure maybe that could
affect
trade of of that Variety in Europe but
it won't in Canada yeah so you know
these things aren't so cut and dry just
because there's a treaty it doesn't mean
that people aren't going to still do
these things you know there's all sorts
Tre that North Americans and you know
principally Canada and the United States
which are really a lot of the offending
Nation in these cases the government
just said hell no we're not signing on
to that and and Holland's not so holy I
mean remember where the Tulip came from
it came from turkey or that general area
and uh Holland is the one who took Tulum
to its heights yeah I
have go ahead I I have a vision of
hopefully not too naive Vision that the
these large interests you know huge
corporate interests and individual you
know small societies of Growers uh uh
indigenous peoples craft Growers
traditional medicine people Etc can not
just sort of exist coexist but actually
really support each other um that I
would contend colonialism took great
products and drove them into the ground
and if you want to have sustainability
you need to maintain that conduit
between the source and the and product
um big corporations that have tried to
get away from that and create their own
Universe have really blisteringly failed
you know the Monsanto model is is not
doing too well in our Modern Age so no
it's more like do
fruit yeah it's funny because Europe has
all these rules about you're not allowed
to import plant products like products
of plant varieties that aren't
registered right but when it comes to
cannabis they're importing all sorts of
unregistered varieties and right nobody
even says anything about it so it's
really I don't know like it's that
should change hopefully that that's ATN
is saying hopefully that that's the new
frontier you know it's hard to say who
will put their first toe on that line
but the the emergence of international
regulated medicinal cannabis markets and
sales is a good first
step and there's and it's like the
United States it's like trying to tie a
tie together all these Patchwork rules
that are so different it becomes a quilt
right like if any seeds are found in the
legally imported International cannabis
uh The Growers here in America will use
them yeah I'm not sure it's legal but
they'll use them and I was just going to
say there's no guarantee that even if
you go through the legal pathway that
you're bringing the most benefit to the
people who should be getting that
benefit so so like right now you've got
all these companies which are you know
operating in a gray area in this land
race Pakistan Afghanistan Nepal India
seed exchange world that's happening
right now and it's really big it's great
and some of them are working with local
people to you know share the profit and
to help tell the story and you know it's
kind of a it's a part a social Equity
play it enrolled in there but so so is
that better you know to do it on the
Grassroots level working with the tribe
in the Amazon directly versus working
through all the proper channels you know
it it gets filtered out and and I think
that's a challenge and I I'm just
bringing that up because some of the
people that are doing this I feel are
ethical you know and they're going there
they're going like look I'm going to go
to Nepal I'm going to sour seeds I'm
going to sell them in the US I'm going
to give share profit with the people in
Nepal I'm going to tell their story and
GNA you know but they're doing it
they're totally violating the plant
protection act right you know so like
it's like which which rules are we
obeying okay so we we go by the ethical
rules of what we decide is right for the
the original peoples and we totally
ignore the cosmic brother law yeah we
totally ignore the rules of the
government you know that puts these laws
in place for for like protection of the
indust you know protection of the
industry I was saying this like in 2017
in Canada we were importing stuff um
into the Canadian system and everything
that we brought in had to go through
phytosanitary and then get these Cowboys
that are bringing stuff up from the
United States um because it's got It's a
clone with a hot name and by the way it
also has like Cam and Russen mites and
uh hop L and vroid right and all of a
sudden hop L and V viroids running like
a hot fire going through everybody's
grow room like what do you think that
cost right what do you think that cost
the industry um it's still costing the
industry cost in the industry today yeah
so unable the number what has been lost
due to that right yeah yeah so I'm not
saying that like you know all government
reg regulations should be followed to a
te but like they're they're put in for a
reason right and when we operate outside
of those systems there's
consequences so yeah you know these are
these are really complex discussions
with so many things to take into account
and it almost feels like we had these
discussions turn into oh it's a big
complicated thing let's just keep doing
what we're doing right
it's a it's a it's there's too much
friction there let's just keep going
along with the status quo and I think we
also can recognize that it's also not
the way to go you know we have to evolve
we have to be willing to
evolve we have to you know yeah it's a
complicated one I think I think it I
think this pivots very well into uh
Brian's conversation today which is this
blight uh and it kind of talks to the
other side of breeding right when you're
putting plants together like maybe make
a point on getting rid of some of these
things that are susceptible to viroids
and diseases and back you know all of
these things so Brian ever so patient my
friend you are definitely patient three
hours 12 minutes but you're up I'm
thankful there's so much information at
hand I'm taking notes over here just
listening kind of trying to saturate and
you know it's really a lot and it all so
much applies to like what we all do and
definitely what I'm doing here on the
field in Maine inside and out and and uh
follows along well with the other
episodes kind of chaining into this one
here too a good Rhythm but I was even
taking some notes of my own just kind of
mentioning for here in Maine like with
my breeding outside I've been breeding
outside for years now and kind of
sticking it to that realm so in Maine in
typical fashion I've usually paid
attention to like smell up front when
I'm breeding for for the turp showing
early so I'll go for what I call two we
turs but I've also followed it with like
a taste to effect and I'd look at the
look thereafter even and just more go
for smell up front really good taste
into the effect and then leaning into
other you know areas too but for outside
why I breed outside is because of the
health and resistance factor and I'm
looking for overall health in the past
years this year and then I'd say for I
guess about the past four years we've
had this septoria challenge is what I've
heard it's called I know Colin has ideas
or uh some information and I can kind of
report from the field so I'm seeing
results as far as like types that will
make it types that definitely aren't and
I have a list going I definitely have a
library uh happening I'm seeing about a
10% carry so from like my clones in the
library at 10% hold on what makes it and
continued resistance year to year as
well but I'm definitely seeing a lot of
damage and I'm seeing some new types
that are showing faces I'm even you know
for the the defense I've seen some stuff
kick into defense later on now like as
it switches to fungal in the root Zone
from the vegetative and it seems to
carry on uh a health fight a resistance
but I've also I'm learning a lot about I
don't know much about it but I'm
learning from the field about septoria
at least here in the Mana I'm hearing
it's hitting other areas like you know
New York Michigan I think it's not being
talked about yet enough and much so it's
kind of elephant in the room and this
stuff's a wipe out quicker damage and
I've seen anything um I've seen
different forms of it I'm talking to so
SC you know like not scientists but soil
Pros here and we're just discussing it
there's chats going on today locally
even and it's you it's pulling off a
good enough product at the end is
definitely affecting yield the hash is
coming out still really good even
through some of the like rip it off get
it right down to Bear the flower seems
to be kind of for some reason into the
the portion you know into flowering it
seems to fade off or not have as much of
a of a hold but it wants to kill the
plant leaf off and live again and I've
definitely seen it this year go for like
a drive down to the soil to a systemic
carry which seems to behave like a like
a micro risal or a form of fungal that
follows rout in the rizosphere so I
think this is where it would maybe open
up to some conversation
I have heard that
traderma is being applied to several
forms out of some people in New York
actually and I haven't dug into it but I
I mean it makes sense to me but I want
to kind of open it up to see what people
think in my opinion it's kind of looking
for perhaps like a fighter or an
isolated strain or strains of fungal
that are still beneficial or non-harming
to the plant that would actually perhaps
be able to inoculate into the compost
inoculate around but just to share it
from the field reporting back the I'm
definitely walking the woods and I see
this stuff changing our landscape it's
taking trees down in the wood certain
type you know like quick growing Alder
popler there's Maples or Oaks affected
and it's changing the landscape and I
just haven't heard that much about this
getting opened up yet so would hope to
open it up to some some people here for
knowledge or information sharing you
know um so yeah you I so on the East
Coast I've noticed on Oak on native tree
native plants all over the place and I
never saw that we you know you and I
both grew up on the east coast and gr
cannabis for close to 30 years out here
now and it's yeah septoria has been a
big issue um that is is just devastated
New York hemp farmers and I think a lot
of the people that I've spoken to at
scale were hemp farming first and
transitioned into drug cultivars and
then planting in those same fields
season after season um and not taking
the right precautions to amend their
soils and create a healthy um solo
Network for themselves so it's it's been
devastating on the East Coast but um
it's the biggest reason why New York's
Market um has so much terrible herb is
because those the the soil that these
individuals are growing in most not
everyone but a lot of them are um
contaminated so they have these viroids
and they're not testing or Fielding for
them and that's where
iics does come through and and help
better Insight is a plant uptaking the
this via the soil and that's how it's
becoming infected well I I calling me no
more but I heard at first the theory
being is that it's a splashback from the
top surface and when I had Disturbed the
top soil just through simple hand
cultivation of the soil I did some I've
been doing some trying some like more
simple and organic application or even
natural you know like disturb top soil
seems to break up a fungal web that
exists that lasts for about two weeks
and then it kicks up again fresh good
fungal Rich compost on top fights too
but I mean at this year at this point
year four I'm we're we're throwing
several different types of compos from
professionals our own that's beautiful
and you know different uh natural sulfur
being applied several times there's
other
oil to to a pH balance citric
application for spray that doesn't seem
to touch a kelp doesn't seem to do much
so I don't know if this is answer any of
your question but it's back to this
maybe Colin knows but U um it's kind of
like throwing all the natural form at it
seems to be driven kind of deep
systemically down into the soil at this
point um and also you know pythium is a
huge problem um and lettuce closis vroid
is is starting to become prevalent which
is not I think we can all agree has not
been a major
threat um but yeah I mean we've used um
you know micro risal top dressings to
help combat it we seem to think that um
you know disrupting the soil to like you
said to not allow those that Network to
to develop is is has really helped but
the honestly we just call the plants
like immediately when we see it um and
then we start soil testing send that to
new testing Labs look at the what's
going on what does it visually look like
so if somebody is watching do you have a
visual representation about what this
looks like potentially I don't have one
right off hand to show I should have
I'll try to get some together but got
brown spots yes it looks like rust right
Sam knows is it on the leaf or on the
stem is it on the leaves that I remember
on new old leaves or old leaves not on
new leaves it was on older and it's
actually hitting up high on the plant on
new leaves it's it's behaving
differently through the years it even
has different form which seems to me
just again from the field seems like
different species of that one type of
fungus I've kind of heard a little word
about that uh from a soil friend and
I've definitely seen like tight yellow
spotting that's really dense spotting on
the lower leaves seems to be where that
one lives and then you're going to see
some you know holes in the actual ual
Leaf you almost look like something's
eating it away seems like a different
form I mean this stuff sounds nasty
what's are spread by by insects but
they're also spread by soil so if you're
moving clones around or if you're
moving it's the problem is is it's
wiping out trees in nature I've got 78
plus acres and I'm walking the back 40
down for Miles back here driving by
where my parents live in the Hills I'm
hearing from friends in Midwest
different states and not denying that it
does carry the soil but I you know one
of the things I pride myself in is some
of the most beautiful living soil my
compost is so rich that it's actually
the newer compost is growing blight free
you know squash plants that don't seem
to get hit in the pure compost and
they're thriving but I'm also kind of
like what chance do they have as soon as
they take a little bit of a yellow off
they go to this quickly and the trees
out in nature literally some of them
I've seen last year even some 20 foot
trees that are younger falling right
they're they're gone you know so seems
to be really even if I could isolate
here change over soil diff I've tried
different strains and different parts of
the farm of the yard on about a 10 12
acre cleanout here in the middle and I'm
seeing it still pop different areas but
I'm also seeing the resistant type or
two or a few that do the best my gas Mas
I I I I'm afraid I can't quite remember
uh as well as I used to but uh is a
tricoderma uh valuable to fight this
that's what I've heard I I haven't
applied it yet I kind of I that's what
I've used in the past wonderful to hear
that that's that's what's coming in the
mail there's three different strains
that are being toyed with out of New
York and I'll connect with you on that
call in a bit after too talk about it
it's probably nearby with you yeah man
it makesense
so yeah it's it's a big problem we we
saw it even indoors um to be honest and
we uh we had to do a lot of soul
searching in the the facility um to
figure out what was going on and we um
you know for whatever reason because the
facility was near the coast um the water
had this weird film even when it was run
through our it was just the weirdest
thing we seen I haven't seen it inside
here it hasn't carried over for myself
or friends in the area yeah we we nipped
it in the bud but you know there's also
you know a little bit of um you know
good old Clorox bleach in in the res to
you know to kill
anything at the right rates what does
this do to the roots so what is this
brown so part the plant could be
completely healthy and then there's like
a huge Branch that's just like dead
you're like huh that's the weirdest
thing why is that whole Branch just
dying um and then there's signifiers
like Spight and spots that can happen as
well but that's further it seems like
that's further and then the leaves get
crispy and kind of acor and kind of like
the plants are almost you know deep into
fall you know finishing itself off with
lots of ethylene around NE I
think say that one more time is that a
leaf necrosis would it be called it does
like a a die off like you just said yeah
it like creates it it feels like the
plant wants to produce ethylene and it
just like signifies it all to do it and
then it affects the other if you have
like other plants in the room it starts
to affect them because of the ethylene
levels and it's really fascinating
seeing it happen um but uh I you know we
found again it's just like you have to
be really diligent about cleaning
everything yeah um you gota be really
tight on you on everything and just make
sure you're double backing on all your
Sops and cleaning and yeah I could share
a little info from the field on that
note which seems to help out actually is
like we're using hay local hay Mulch and
a thick cover local hay Mulch on the
bottom that's kept with a fresh change
over so like the 4x4 Square on the rais
bed gets where it actually almost acts
like a catch for the for the leaf fall
because what I've seen this this uh
blight work like it seems to it's it's
intelligence at least in its life cycle
seems to want to do a leaf kill off on
the plants just tracking it wise to let
them go back B to see it it does a drop
down of the leaves right to the base of
the plant and from what I've seen or
heard those are asexual reproduction
sites that look like rust spots on the
leaf when it dies those spots Sam was
talking about gray spots and it fluffs
off the Spore and it definitely seems
like it wants to kill those leaves right
off and behave where it wants to catch
water live right there and spread from
there to go systemic so like a fresh
turnover of of mulch under the plant
where you can actually you know keep the
plants as clean as you can um honestly
This lends so far into at least in Maine
where it's a more small batch type of
feel anyway and by numbers by medical
allowance and such truthfully it's
creating like a tendar plants better
thing when I when I kind of listen to
the plants they're going kick up the
stewardship you know don't have us like
con said take us out change it don't new
soil new area or don't do this so it's
becoming like less is more and that's
what we can handle it definitely seems
like healthy fungal
population um a good constant nutrient
availability to it whether organic or
not and not letting them you know go
without and be overboard over the
threshold so it's really kind of maybe
testing the the farmer and it seems to
me with just so many plants out there in
general of all types with colors and you
know these different rules to it in all
Realms it seems like this is just kind
of a almost natural thing no matter
where it comes from you know for this to
kind of call like you said call call the
plant and it's going to seemingly call
down the breeding at least to bring up
this conversation it's not just going to
be breeding gone wild and F1 H poly
hybrids everywhere you know selling his
hot cakes because this is like year five
in Maine that this stuff is taking a
serious hold and this year being a good
grow year but a high humid one you saw
good growth early start off for health
in places with people that that were
bragging you know raving about it and
then they quiet fall off and it's like
detriment to the point of having a
meeting over it you know and it's really
if you don't have it it seems like at
least East I don't know probably east
east coast it's G to come around it's
it's just one of those things cycling
it's eventually going to come and at
this point it's a more of how do we
resist this in my opinion and seeing
like the 10% hold from new faces from
breeding and from the library hold of
genetics at least where I'm hearing
small batch application not field trials
for thousands or Millions thousands of
plants I'm able to see that hold and
then try it out different zones through
the years and then protect my genetics
well hold it you know as close as I can
because it be it works well for here but
it's also kind of tear stripping away
like the candy shop approach of turpy
and exploration or you know of just into
hashing it washes it's becoming one of
those where where it's actually going to
have more boxes to check when it comes
to Sun grown out here you know where
whether it's personal grow or whether it
would be a production grow I feel
because you know both angles are
affected the H grower that that has this
blight run wild thing going on too you
know very crazy is going to have a
difficult time so I guess going back to
trying to find the plants at least from
the breeding from the field and simple
understanding perspective hold them well
then I'm obviously like working into the
year here with my breeding to be like
resistant males that show you know the
traits even a a kickback later for
health one up front I'm tracking them
and then coming back to the The Proven
females that either over the years you
know or a new type that's showing its
face to be the healthiest new girl and
the new lady in the yard is a strawberry
smoothie band that I'm calling it so
strawberry headband on a citrus smothie
and it just looks I mean it sticks out
even among some of the plants you know
and and any who that's kind of like from
the so somebody sorry I just wanted to
mention one thing at that Wade had his
hand up but he has turned his camera off
now so oh okay awesome yeah I don't know
if he's there now but uh when he comes
back and turns his camera on we'll uh
give him the
floor there he is oh
wonderful yeah I had to take a leak
um what to do huh um I got to jump in
here and rant for a minute I I'm loving
this
conversation but I keep thinking about
what Mojave brought up about
flavor and how he was really pointing to
what I think is kind of a central
problem in the whole cannabis space
where the very ious
operators try and provide product
ethical operators try and provide
product that the consumer wants because
the consumer has been educated if you
will um to call out for this specific
version of
cannabis and as a patient I got to keep
coming back to that as a
patient uh historically we we followed
flavor and smell and morphology
as a guide to the chemistry that we were
seeking and now we have analytical
chemistry and um that's a wonderful gift
to uh our our
search um but
I part of what I wanted to rant about is
we also talked about hemp and some of
the consequences of shall we say
unskillful legislation that has happened
in the United States around the cannabis
plant
and um on the one hand hemp has had the
effect of normalizing cannabis all
across the country people are used to it
now and that is a good
thing the the other side of it and to me
the biggest problem again as a patient
and as a
consumer uh there's no protections for
consumers
and
um I guess part of what I'm trying to do
here is I'm asking you all of you on
this panel and anyone who's listening to
this recording
to recognize that if you are if you view
yourself as an ethical
operator it's important to create
product
that
um satisfies the
consumer while ideally
preserving The Beneficial effects of
cannabis other
than the drug high and I as a drug user
myself I I love the high but I've also
become a fairly uh passionate user of
cannabis uh for its medicinal
benefits and to me the whole thing of
legalization we wouldn't have we
wouldn't be here if it wasn't for the
medicinal
benefit and yes flavor guided us for
many years to that medicinal benefit
that we were seeking but I'm calling on
again those of us who are ethical
operators to to preserve the the
genetics that you have to call out the
thing because that's been the other big
topic is these various pathogens that
threaten this plant and we all know the
global plant isn't really threatened
we're really talking about the
commercial
Market
um
anyway I'm going to stop there I just I
I feel it really strongly that if you
know what you're doing with this plant
do it with your heart and your
Consciousness at the Forefront and I'll
stop there thank
you awesome man who says little but when
he says things it
sticks Alex Hardy in the chat was also
suggesting kombucha and airflow for
septoria arborist who's in there so that
was his suggestion so thank you for that
Mr hardy air flow sure that's a new one
kombucha makes sense
though trying it
out yeah I had a I had a gentleman reach
out to me recently from Estonia uh and
he had a couple of interesting things to
share um the one is just another new
method of isolating Tricom heads I'm
sure we'll be speaking about it in the
very near future but the other one was
he had this product um I won't say the
name yet but we'll let you you know in
the near future here but he was talking
about uh maybe coming and visiting
Canada and the US and maybe getting some
of this product to people who had uh
hlvd uh and I was just talking to him
while we've had this conversation and he
was like oh septoria yeah if it's
bacteria and fungal problems it's it's
much easier to prevent and cure and so I
sent you that email uh Brian and uh
maybe we'll make it so you can get some
of that that uh product to see if you
can't uh combat that
wonderful trying some out thank you
awesome well we got 26 minutes left
before we hit the 4 Hour Mark what a
great conversation today I'm definitely
down to Freestyle for another 206
minutes and you know if I haven't said
it once already I appreciate all of you
for showing up the Heavy Hitters came
out today it's been great conversation
really nice and uh yeah it's just it's
good people are appreciating it 300
people watching live right now so we're
getting those numbers up each week this
being our fifth week people like
consistency gives them sort of uh I
don't know just makes you feel good it's
warm and fuzzy it's like uh comfort food
in the fall be consistent and let's go
ahead gotta thank you gotta thank you
Marcus because uh thank you for re
restarting what you started a decade ago
and you know it's I love coming here I
love learning I love hearing I mean
opening up with E and Ethan Russo and
Sam I mean I just makes my heart singing
happiness for cannabis because there's
just nothing like these discussions to
have Growers Farmers producers providers
from different countries all talking all
things cannabis in a very intelligent
logical uh yet passioned uh way that you
know is backed in a root of science
which I think is is most important and I
I celebrate all of you and thank you for
just being a small part of
this absolutely and I think uh you know
part of the important fact is listen
we're just we're spitball and always we
we try to be as accurate as we can of
course we make mistakes and get things
wrong uh sometimes as well I think to be
a thinking human being and share your
perspective you have to take the chance
that you might make a mistake and you
might even offend someone along the way
as well but uh I like that we're doing
it I like that for the most part you
guys are quite conscious really I felt
like when Wade said what he said about
you know leading with your heart I feel
that about most all of you you know
almost I I would say all of you really I
know all of you personally and you lead
with your heart and I think that's uh I
think authenticity has an important
place in all of this people appreciate
authenticity and that's what I feel a
lot of when uh I get together with you
guys on Sunday morning in chat go ahead
Sam
unfortunately the industry as a
whole I don't think I think there
there's a lot of blackhearted
individuals you know a lot of people
their focus is monetary return I've met
them you're not
wrong they're everywhere but you know
that's
why uh you know being patients and
providers has been important for all of
us because we're able to share our
experiences with others and this gives
us an area and a way to do so you know
you're a provider you you provide bubble
man you know to Canadian providers and
we have various scientists on here who
are actively doing in the science that
has been you know definitely neglected
for decades on end and we're at a unique
precipice in time yeah there's an
industry and it's all full of sharks but
you know the it's the sharks have always
been there they're just more prevalent
we can see them in the water now but
it's not going to stop the people who
were doing it for the right reasons for
doing it the only way to get rid of the
Sharks is probably to take the money out
of
cannabis yeah but the sharks are in the
ocean and uh they're not taking over the
ocean the ocean is flourishing just got
to figure out a way to
flourish but if the reason the sharks
are interested in cannabis is because
they see it as an income generator of
course listen that's the reason a lot of
of people were interested in cannabis
for a very long time and i'llbe it I'll
even say that some people who have a
much more leading with their heart
perspective today would admit that when
they got into cannabis it was to like
pay for their mortgage and and some
other things you know which is fine in
my opinion whatever way cannabis can
infect our souls and minds and get in
there and bore in there and get us
growing it I support it all and and to
be honest I'd rather
see for example people like ex judges ex
police officers ex prison officers I
rather see them being greedy and working
with cannabis than being what they were
and locking cannabis people up yeah yeah
Amen to that dude that's uh that's the
sermon of the day I I kind of want to
know uh what are Chimera and stunk man
Sam smoking on and what is everybody
else smoking on in chat let's I haven't
seen that in a while what are you else
smoking on
Chimera what it what we're smoking on is
white albino Rosen it's grown uh on
alligator feces in the sewers of New
York it's actually a pretty nice little
rosin I actually went down and meet
someone at a coffee shop today so I had
a uh a joint of the grin spoon or what
are they what used to be called the quaz
you know the one I'm talking about with
all the cix's and not real bud structure
oh yeah but man I I I I'm not a big
cannabis burner so it was weird sitting
there smoking this joint that kept going
out but I was reminded myself that I was
in
[Laughter]
Holland um you know speaking of I had a
thought earlier in the show when um when
someone put up the the medicine bottle
the old medicine bottle I guess that was
Michael and it had it listed the
ingredients and it was you know cannabis
with all these other things in it right
and it it made me think when we started
talking about these botanically derived
tpin that we have a little bit of
cannabis and a lot of other stuff in it
and it seems we keep doing that
different versions of that same thing
and uh you know I I can't help but
wonder if a good regulation would be
that the only thing allowed inside a
cannabis product was something derived
from the Cannabis
itself right yeah well when it comes to
in
right like obvious when you're talking
inhalables
well what they'll do is they'll take
cannabis products and with synthesis
convert them into different cannabis
products which I'm not so sure I mean as
long as they're safe for consumers but
that's not proven safe well and you know
Mark shelone like I mean he's developed
some some of these things that are
synthesis products with using cannabis
and I I don't think anything's wrong
with that but I think think that if
we're developing new things that stuff
should end up down the regulatory path
of you know having to show safety right
cannabis shouldn't just be some where
you can take and modify and start
developing new products with unknown
Health consequences and giving them to
people you know the reason we know that
cannabis is safe is because there's
thousands of years of us using it but
you know when we start totally whacking
out the ratios between those compounds
and the plant and adjusting it in
different ways and new forms so does
does pure dry sift and bubble has maybe
not fit into that category Ryan I guess
really I mean that's the most the
highest percentage of volatile organic
compounds we we've ever inhaled have
been in the last 25 to 30 years so I was
G and rosin you know well again I the
way I see it with a natural product is
how are you going to stop people from
doing it how are you going to remove
that right of them to use the plant as
they will right and I and that's why I
kind of you know like like I was going
down that road when we talked about it
earlier I'm right into like plants that
are 15%
THC because maybe when you make them
into a hash they have a different ratio
of the terpenoids to you know say you
take a high turp line like say we're
talking about that 6% tpine line that we
developed right you've got essentially
twice as much or more
terpenoids in ratio to cannabinoids and
so when you concentrate that down
naturally you have a different ratio
right and so I think that there's like
when you talk about headp
space and you know and how your head
actually feels after consuming these
products like I really am a believer
in not you know not everything has to be
30% plus THC in the flower right like I
I get the novelty of it um but it
doesn't mean that you have to make all
products out of that stuff right and I
kind of feel like with the way that the
regulations go and the the Distributors
like the Distributors want high THC
products because they know that in the
past those high THC products have sold
right and so they know that they can put
their money into a whole bunch of stock
on that and they're not going to lose
money um it's also you go we also I
think we also got to recognize I mean
maybe this isn't the same in the States
but definitely in Canada the flower
market is kind of going away and more
people are moving to pre-rolls right and
so when you're in a pre-roll environment
those consumers aren't interacting with
the flower in the same way that we
do right and so is that a generational
thing maybe change maybe it might take a
dry head off of it yeah but it's not the
same as rolling it smelling it
exactly transforming it from a from a
bud into a joint that whole experience
of getting it in your fingers more than
you would yeah it's wild that's
definitely a way of looking at it and
you're not wrong I go to my daughter's
uh the dispensary that she works at is
Happy Isle in Horseshoe Bay not too far
from my house and I'll just go visit her
sometimes and hang out for you know 10
or 15 minutes and every single person
comes in and they're like do you what do
you got for like uh the cheapest Indica
pre-roll one gram you know 20% like it's
very funny how they're ordering cannabis
uh and obviously this is what we fought
for right you know we you you just want
it to make it available and I suspect
that as much as we want and I think it's
important what we're doing stewarding
these volatile organic compound profiles
and all of the breeding work that guys
like Ryan and and skunkman Sam and many
other people have done these are super
important factors we're preserving
different aspects but that'll never
change the fact that 85% or more of the
industry gives like zero [ __ ] about any
of it they're happy with floor sweepings
with some distillate and Botanical turp
sprayed on it and they just love it and
I don't know uh if you could ever fight
that well and you know Marcus I mean
like you know you're such a purist and
you know David myself are also like that
I think a lot of people on the panel are
we're such purists that we want that
absolutely finest part of the market or
not part of the market part of the plant
and to deliver that to the market with
pride and say like hey this is something
that I love you should check it out
we're we are like an anomaly right like
most people don't want that stuff yeah
and even worse in Canada the people who
do want that
stuff like hate anything to do with
government weed any of the people that
have learned how to grow their own weed
and make their own hash they're like the
one group of people that might support
you and keep you from going bankrupt in
that Venture of trying to bring that to
Market are like specifically won't buy
weed from the legal government
stores like I don't know I've noticed
like the needs of the consumers because
Generations socially are different I
mean they interact differently they're
on their phone they're buying things
quickly they're you know they're looking
to put their cart together before they
even go to the dispensary and they pick
the thing up rather than even shop and I
think it's it's a lot of that you know
like so to Marcus's Point like that
drives a lot of the choices some of
these larger operators are making
because that's all their feedback is and
that's the narrative they're they're
okay with that narrative they're like
yeah whatever if that's what sells
that's what we're selling these guys are
just business they're just figuring out
how to sell product it's like you know I
I just I know that we some of us have
been doing this so long like for example
I was I think back with Marcus and
having these incredibly strong hashes
not that they were strong but incredibly
pure hashes and seeing people react to
those medicines through Hills dispensary
right and and you know the government
looks at us and we say hey we got this
product that's like 50 60 70%
TC they don't understand that we have
just refined the best parts of the plant
and removed the you know we've washed
away the green parts of the plant and
kept the important medicine part of the
plant right and when you give that to
people in real need they don't have to
consume all this Burning plant material
right and so you can do one lungful and
get a real dose and you know people like
ATN and everybody else on this panel
that's worked with people and that need
cannabis it's like the pure the stronger
the
medicine the more complete right like
you know when I talk like I'm talking
like P really nice hash rosin or super
refined bubble they can use a lot less
of it and it's less harmful to them yeah
and so the government comes along and
slaps an extra 20% tax on that and makes
it less competitive in the marketplace
right like it's just the whole way that
we've done this thing is completely
backwards and a lot of these lessons and
these beautiful things that we found out
about the plant I you know I it's it's
just you see the way that it's playing
out like Marcus said 80% of the people
are coming in looking for cheap potent
rolls it's bizarre yeah we're also
trying to mimic other industry which is
sad because we aren't those Industries
you know and I keep saying that to
everyone it's just like just because
there's a strawberry ferone product that
could say strawberry cough and you could
use 4% of that and it cost you 30 cents
to grab and put in your vape and you can
now call it Strawberry Cough doesn't
mean you should you know and then on the
flip side of that because you struck a
coin with me earlier on the The Vape
side like what I learned is from a talk
point point of view like there's tons of
turps like pones of just blow hanging
fruit like pgon really toxic like and
that can show up in you know very toxic
levels in certain cultivars and we have
to be very cognitive of that of that to
your point you know as we move forward
because there's more to is it a monot
turpine or is it a sesa turpine uh I
believe it's a sesa turp monot turpenoid
monot turpenoid yeah it's oxidized right
but then it'll go way quicker if you do
it yeah so we concentrations we learned
in the medical and medicinal end is
definitely all about harm reduction and
uh believe it or not one of the work
that you know we we've been doing at the
UN we just got harm reduction put into
the UN after 24 years it took 24 years
just to get two words inserted into a
goddamn treaty so just so you know how
long it takes some time to make change
but yes it's
key I just had another comment about the
um again I'm probably like a broken
record on this but when we were talking
about people going into stores and
asking for the stronger product again I
think it just comes down to the
information that's accessible I think
that and just like Ryan you're pointing
out about the lower THC varieties that
would be higher in tpin or higher in
other compounds I think as we progress
as an industry ultimately people will
understand that and go for it I think
it's just you know we're we're really
even though the industry's been around
for a while now like we still really are
in the juvenile stages of it all the
juvenile understanding of it it's just
going to take proper education and more
people understanding it to to get to
that length to get those kind of
products out there because yeah like
there's also as much as people might be
demanding it there's also a lot of
people around me that are saying how
strong it is and in terms of that being
kind of like a
undesirable thing for it just to have
that high potency but also again it
comes down to the price conscious idea
of what you're
buying well it's a proverbial race to
the bottom folks and when pre-rolls
become the number one thing the cheapest
way to make pre-rolls is to take hemp at
probably A1 or $200 a pound and spray it
with THC that's been synthesized because
you could synthesize THC 10 times
cheaper than you can growing it so I
mean that's just the reality that we
live in is that you know a lot of that
stuff that's at the smoke shops and even
in all the Bas in Manhattan you know a
lot of that stuff is just the cheapest
[ __ ] you could possibly find because you
know again why you know um I would just
say that you know like if you have if
you have high quality flour
and you're trying to get fair value for
that high quality flow certainly putting
it into pre-rolls is not is not the way
to go right because just you know the
overall value chain and where the grower
exists in that value chain is if you
look at where the margins are everyone
is pressured at the front end of that
value chain including the grower and the
processor and the people who really own
the distribution networks and the folks
who basically are able to
populate dispensary shelves with product
are able to take a little bit more
margin because the guys at the other end
you know again look at go to olc in
Oregon has got a uh a a daily tracker on
what usable marijuana goes for and right
now I mean that number always floats
around somewhere around uh it used to be
around 1100 1200 then it starts thinking
around covid below $ 800 now it's around
$600 a pound so I mean it is really
difficult to turn on the lights at you
grow for $600 a pound so everyone along
the way is trying to extract out as much
value as they possibly can and
unfortunately again we're in that
proverbial race to the bottom where the
people who can produce a quality product
at the lowest cost is going to win it's
a commodity market right that's that's
that's how we are with everything we do
food the same way you know there's
30,000 McDonald's but there's a very few
like actually incredible amazing
restaurants in comparison of any one
brand maybe even just a one or a two and
so it's done like that with beer and
they have the IPA group so we just have
to recognize that we're in a smaller
portion of the market much smaller but
even if it's well listen I'm in a super
small portion cuz I'm in like the 1% I'm
a
1center um but you know like there's
there's there's all these other
different markets that you can fit into
I mean I'm thinking thatth you know the
company that does some of uh Ryan's
cultivars here and I always mess up
their company name it's our friend Kips
a part of it what's the company name
again
Ryan Victoria cannabis company Victoria
cannabis company they're doing exactly
that like taking dank buds and rolling
them into pre-roll joints and so it's a
smaller um Market but it doesn't mean
they won't do well with it so when you
hear us talking and we sound like uh you
know we're upset and and in a negative
mindset about this you know all the
people who are watching realize that we
prefer the much much much smaller
percentage of the market that when it's
worldwide is actually still a pretty
substantial Market I mean if a billion
people were using cannabis and you were
a part of the the
1% that is still substantial that is
still a lot and uh I just kind of wanted
to add that we got five minutes left you
know Walmart Walmart is a big is like a
big retail in fact I think they're the
largest company on planet Earth today I
think maybe next to Jeff bezos's uh
Amazon and yeah if you think about it
Marcus you're absolutely right but like
I'm thinking about like those customers
that walked in to your uh daughter's
dispensary you know at some point isn't
it like again it's useful to think about
I guess maybe like the micro brew beer
model so like those of us who love Petty
hash yeah we're like the micro brw but
the majority of the market drinks swill
Budweiser and Bud Light and Miller Light
and so yeah so like wmart let me throw
something out you here Mark I'm as you
know I'm over in Europe here staying
with Sam and you know I'm walking the
streets around the neighborhood and I
know that you guys have both been here
there's all these little cheese shops
and there's all these little bakeries
and these little butchers and fruit
shops and vegetable shops that are
selling
high-end really special cultivars and
meat types and cheese types and
vegetable types it's a cultural thing
right like there there is this cultural
thing where you know North America and
it's I think it's probably
populationbased but there really is this
thing where North America has a lot of
industrial production and that kind of
stuff just doesn't fly over here right I
mean sure you have those products but
it's there's much it's much more normal
to
have really nice nice food and and you
know that kind of thing and I think that
cannabis will develop along those lines
here Wonder connoisseur level yeah and
but it's that The Connoisseur level is
more appreciated by the everyday person
yeah I think Brian's saying is is what
how I view New York is like I have a
very particular lens on New York that's
because I've lived there for so long and
I see a culture there that's unlike
anywhere in the world it's much like
Europe where sure there's a bunch of
crap that's going to be sold and it's
their bit egas and they're going to get
their coffee and their pre-roll but
there is a world where they do want
really high-end stuff and they're going
to want it every day day and it density
it's when it's when a town or a a city
gets to a certain size that that a
business like that can be supported by
the 1% right because very often the 1%
isn't big enough to keep a business like
that alive especially cannabis regulated
business it's a lot right so yeah it's a
challeng you bring that up so you're
saying so you're saying so right now
there's like there's there's varietals
that these shops are selling like along
with their oh for example if you go to
like you know we went grocery shopping
the other day and they have all these
fruit varieties are more like they have
these blackberries they're you know the
size of your thumb right all these
products that are the result of
specialty breeding that that would never
make it into the industrial supply chain
in North America right whereas where you
live in an area where there's enough
people that want a really high-end
cheese or a really like nice home B
bread or like super fine fruits [ __ ]
give us Pop-Tarts and Froot Loops that's
what we want in the United States and
wine in a
box and wine in a box exactly in a box
and diabetes to
go got the
diabetes for anybody's watching if
you're if you're developing those
specialty cannabis businesses you know
like Marcus you got to just keep doing
it eventually they'll they'll pay often
enough people will learn and if not you
export it to someone where they
appreciate it I I keep waiting for the
world to grow up and only smoke dry sift
like all civilized beings like myself
do one day wonderful man listen that's
it dude 12:59 we got one minute left
that's enough time for me to thank you
all for coming and uh really stoked that
you were at Sam's Ryan it's awesome to
see you I sort of stalk you on Twitter
and and had an idea that you were in the
UK really sorry to hear about your mom
but uh glad you got to visit with uh
with David and Diana that's pretty
awesome um thank you Wade for coming out
and sharing you know always profound
you've always got the good perspective
we sure appreciate you here at hash
church and uh was nice to have some new
folks with Chris gasa and and Davis
Allen that was really really sweet I'm
sure we'll get you back on here again
one day soon Davis uh Dr Ethan Russo
you're not here with us anymore but you
were at the start of the show and we
appreciate that always nice to see you
as well I'm always amazed at how young
Dr Ethan Russo looks like when you
actually figure out his age you're like
dude that guy is like doing something
right over there for sure uh thank you
Dr Markell Don and Colin and aier and
best friend Farms Brian totally
appreciate you as well and uh anyone
else that I may be forgetting all the
people that have watched we've had
almost 300 people watching for four
hours which is incredible I love the
fact that you know that's the 1% again
it's kind of like it'll grow we can get
it out there and once we hit the right
um sort of notes for people it'll more
people will relate to uh what it is that
we appreciate so thank you everybody for
coming on sharing hash Church thanks to
Michael crows for that history lesson
those bottles yes amazing dude Michael
I'd love to have him back on as well
love listening to him speak and he's
just got a sort of hypnotic voice and
you can tell he comes from a place of
passion as all of you guys do so may the
the full melt bless your bowl sooner
than later and uh Johnny B is in Italy
in the chat room right now so shout out
to you Johnny B in Italy I hope uh
you're uh inspiring people on a daily
yes yes and I'm sure he's gonna about to
do push-ups it's like 101 which means
it's 10:01 there he's probably doing
push-ups right as we speak peace out
everybody we'll talk soon thanks Marcus
take care thanks Mar