all right look at that boom boom boom
welcome everybody bye everybody i-it's
probably a small group as today is a
very spur-of-the-moment last-minute
hashed Church episode 16 of hashed
Church 2.0 I'm pretty darn excited to be
here I'm not gonna lie let me just close
this down real quick
turn that off boom boom boom I'm gonna
send out the link to the few people and
by few people I mean very few people
that have said they're gonna come in
today I am sending the link out to a lot
more than four but I kind of got about
four or five people that said yeah yeah
yeah we can we can do it so very excited
to uh just to see you guys all it's been
it's been a little bit of time since we
last gotten together and it's been
incredible how much news has occurred in
the cannabis world community since the
last hash search and that's really what
kind of got me this morning as I woke up
a little bit earlier than usual and had
some extra time I thought man it'd be
nice to just hear from a couple of
people I wanted to hear from Etta he's
on a cruise ship with shitty internet so
we won't be hearing from him but there's
[ __ ] Johnny be sup guys dude how are
you doing brother I'm fantastic it's
minus like 40 outside it's ridiculous oh
my god right now good old Edmonton good
old Edmonton I just had to cut my hash
right at the window it's perfect really
like it's so cold I'd put it on the
counter right here and it was like
buttering up so I just put it right on
the windowsill and my pipe like
literally is like so cold to like
everything is just like this is perfect
I wish I could make some sift in the
bathroom good to see your smiling face
brother it's been it's been a while
since we did a hash Church hasn't it
you know what everybody's busy it's like
wow I'm just here in Edmonton and it's
like there's an Ethan next weekend
you've been flying out people this
industry's moving so quickly like [ __ ]
since October when was the last time
stretch we done you know what
surprisingly I guess I haven't done many
videos on my youtube channel period so
when I went
back it was only like six videos back
but it was the one with Alex Rogers from
the promoting the ICBC that we are going
to be doing in Spain on March 14th in
Barcelona are you coming to Barcelona um
I can't make it this year oh [ __ ] well
that's okay brother you're fun you're
flying all over the place all the time
so you can only I mean I'll be strolling
down on the fly lately yeah you'd be
flying all over the place yeah I went
and flew to Calgary recently and met
with this brewery that has an interest
in cannabinoids and terpenoids so that
was kind of fun I went there with my
team at embark I don't even know how
many people even know about embark to be
honest I have I talked about embark much
my latest project I don't think he works
you really talked about it at all I mean
people need to be like ourselves and
your friends know what's going on and
what you're doing but really no one
knows what's going on with a barque what
we've talked about over the years and
and and where you're going with what
you're doing I think it's fantastic I'm
so stoked and proud of what what's going
on with the industry and what you're
doing with the industry you got to tell
people what's going on yeah yeah for
sure well I've got Mike West coming in
here later so he'll be able to to talk
about a little bit about that as well
but yeah Embarq has been moving forward
of course this is a new company that
I've helped found just in the last six
to seven months actually and got great
team of people super stoked on them
really professional and high caliber
which I've truly it's my first time
experiencing in the in the cannabis
industry working with a team of this
calibre and so we're pretty excited
about it obviously it's an extraction
lab we've got a facility here in Delta
BC that we're going to be doing 40,000
square feet of extraction and it's it
when I say extraction it's not just
bubbleman extraction it's much bigger
than me obviously I'm very focused on
solvent list extraction I love the
Rosslyn I love the full melt water hash
I love the back but also dry sifting you
know that the solvent list processes but
then I
the same time we've got we've got a
great team including Mike West who's
really gonna be focused on the co2 the
hydrocarbon the cryo ethanol which my
partner Anthony from Colorado will be
will be actively involved in so we're
really putting this this really cool
team together kind of before the laws
are even really allowing it so we've
done a lot of due diligence in the last
six months we're funded for Phase one
simultaneously actually while we're
building out the building that already
exists so it's a rebuild kind of well
you know we're just gonna be doing you
know building specific things in each
room that already exists simultaneously
we've now taken on a project in
Woodstock Ontario where we're actually
going to build it up from the ground up
so this this could be 40,000 50,000
60,000 upwards of 80,000 square feet of
extraction it's going to be sitting on
three acres that our partners already
own and it's going to have some serious
capabilities if embark and Delta can do
3.6 to 4 million pounds per year of
processing we're hoping on getting
double that out of the Woodstock
facility so it's it's something very
serious when you're talking millions of
pounds of cannabis being being extracted
into traditional hashes into oh there's
Mike now what's going on brother
my name is morning morning Johnny how
are you guys I was just talking about
him dark and breaking down all the
different types of processes that we're
gonna be rocking on and the facility in
Woodstock and the facility in Delta and
was talking about you in regards to kind
of you know being in charge of our co2
and our hydro carbon division and
helping with our cryo ethanol and post
production of isolates and boom you came
right in we're just talking about really
talking about four years it's happening
it's cool yeah I mean you know it's
funny because hash Church really
hey Bo hey good morning good morning
how's Italy doing dude what's a father's
as a father of three I appreciate you
taking time out from your family even if
it's 20 minutes we really do appreciate
it that you came by and hung out on a
hash Church with us hey you know it you
know hey it's a good morning
here I wanted to see some old friends
consume some cannabis before taking the
kids to go swimming and here we are
dude you're an inspiration to me one of
the I mean in many ways of course all of
you guys are but one way that you really
inspire me is that you and I've kind of
not jealous not envious inspired by the
conversation that you started about
parenting kids and cannabis I think it's
an extremely mature topic that you've
that you've taken on and it's just a
topic that more and more people parents
of kids who are cannabis users whether
recreational whether preventive whether
medicinal I think it's an important
conversation to have and I'm definitely
wanting to plant a hash Church in the
future when you have more time to get
into that conversation because I've
watched you have it with a multitude of
people now and it's it's the time is now
for that conversation brother so hats
off you thank you if I was wearing a hat
I would take it off myself and you know
I mean I felt like it was just one of
the last places are not one of the last
places but you know it was something
that I could speak from my own true
experience with it and you know having
kids that are right now four and eight
years old and just going to elementary
school and dealing with the PTA and
other parents you know what I realize is
there was just so much misinformation
out there and it was really an
opportunity to be able to initiate
people and you know the part is not even
though it's not report cramming it down
the throat they were just looking for
new information on cannabis the
different ways that we can utilize it
and what's the best way to talk about it
with our children it's super important
and you just nailed it right there
that's where the conversation starts
because there's two ways as a father to
go through this there's the way of this
conversation makes my wife very
uncomfortable so I'm just going to avoid
it completely or I'm gonna talk about
this I'm gonna let people know that I'm
not they're worried I'm not a worry for
them I'm not trying to take their young
kids behind the school and get them high
this is like you know this is a
different thing completely and and and I
think that it's as important for a
recreational user as it is for a
medicinal use
of course in the last 15 to 20 years
we've given a lot more sort of you know
we've accepted medical users more than
we've accepted recreational users you
know it's like oh oh okay it's a
medicine okay well then you know that's
different but we're getting to a point
now where it's like well you know
cannabis is a preventive medicine which
really makes recreational use preventive
and so there's also a value in using it
recreational and and preventatively
one does not have to wait to get sick
one does not have to wait to be
endocannabinoid deficient before kind of
taking taking you know taking
responsibility into your own hands so I
just think it's a great conversation and
I'm definitely super stoked to get into
it more maybe we could have a panel of
all parents you know when we have that
conversation and just really go deep
into and I'm sure if we had you know a
variety of parents as well from the
super deeply like full-blown you know
like Earth Mother
regenerative farming like organics right
up to the professional you know you know
person that has a career person that has
you know that's not in cannabis
whatsoever but how did how did those two
people perceive differently maybe and
just you know get into the conversation
because it is very important sidenote
shout out to los Gardens for the
absolute fire fire melt this is some
five point five to six star and I just
had to say thank you to Shawn from los
Gardens you guys puffing on today well
I'm you did you Mike I muted everyone
when Sabo was talking so I see what
you're showing I just don't hear what
you're showing what's going on PHP n
nice group of people in the chat room
right now usually it shows me how many
people are in the chat room but I can't
actually see that right now
yeah that's so strange usually it'll
it'll show us like I said there's a
certain amount of people in the room oh
there's 277 people watching well that's
not too shabby
that's a decent amount of folks watching
so we've got some really nice stuff here
called sly
for that I discussed with you and I'm
coming back to smoke this with you
because this is some epic rosin did that
come from Saskatchewan yes it did I know
where that came from exactly and I'm
like how do you like my little Johnny B
I already knew that's why I've told it I
was like wait a second here I have
because this is for us to smoke and I
already know listen the only reason I
know that that's is you have the same so
I have hundreds of these containers but
only one guy sends them with parchment
in the lid shout out to the sky - man
there's mine mine was full melt hash not
Rasta but I got some I clean that up it
still smells like grape I got some
wedding cake and ninety view from you
that it gave me to give to you so we can
puff down by the way sitting at my house
wonderful man I love this community I
got like four months to live waiting
till I cook it up coz you haven't been
able to see each other you know what I
mean so yeah well that's that's what
happens right I feel bad laughs four two
one who's always been the most kind and
generous friend he's he'll get something
beautiful and he'll want to share it
with me and then we won't see each other
for like two months and I'll see him and
I'll be like please tell me you don't
still have that you'll pull it out and
be like of course I have it brother we
save it even this until we're smoking
this and I have that hash - and you know
that's the best part of what we do in
this industry and the people the
comedians we did we save that epic and
even in real size you know we smoked the
schwag at home but you take the epic
buds and you give them away to your
friends Eric we want to show our best
and we take our best with us wherever we
going the first thing we want to do is
like here check this out man beautiful
hey I want to hear from Sabol one last
time because I know he has to balance
really soon can you tell us a little bit
about your new products your new
vaporizer the hot new labs oh yeah
absolutely absolutely thank you and did
I sent some uh hardware up your weight
as it arrived yet Marcus
okay sorry so rude of me to ask you a
question while you are taking a DAB so
this is basically our new device it's
the ha new ha nice tone vape XL is still
in existence it's just um I guess it's
growing up it's going through puberty
and ha new labs and essentially what we
wanted to do was we started off with a
desktop vaporizer to learn the science
and physics behind vaporization and
sublimating the cannabinoids from a
solid into a gas and then we wanted to
apply it into a very easy to use
portable and this is the device it
actually is all magnetic base and we
have a red Congo oil in here right now
red Congo is a great landrace sativa
strain my consumed it right before I
competed and jiu-jitsu tournament
yesterday has been nice little shiner
and got kneed in the face and well this
is why 42 year olds don't compete with
22 year olds but luckily I'm okay I'm
still lying in bed my kids actually just
brought me breakfast thank you so much
because they know daddy can't move today
so I am very much utilizing this as a
recovery tool but essentially this was
our version of a vape pen you know when
we were looking at the vape pens I
started researching and I noticed less
than 7% of cannabis users actually
smoked cigarettes and I thought well
we're always talking about health and
wellness so why do we have these things
looking like cancer sticks and things
that give you um carcinogen so we
thought just getting away from the shape
of something that looked like a
cigarette would be great the next thing
we wanted to do is just have something
that had a really cool tactile sensation
in your hand so that if you couldn't
consume it you could still rub it like a
worry stone and maybe just relieve some
anxiety without even having to consume
it and we also made it asymmetrical in
shape you know I live in San Francisco
which is the home of Technology and even
here I think we're sick of Technology
people are meditating more camping more
hiking more so we just wanted something
that would be asymmetrical that would
remind someone of the imperfections of
nature or maybe the perfect
imperfections
nature and the last thing was to really
make sure that it didn't just look cool
and feel good but that when you put it
to your mouth and you inhaled it those
would supersede the first two user
experiences and we all know how much you
know effort the extractors put into
creating all the oils today the live
rosin the shatters the the diamonds the
sauces so what we did was when we
created our own version of our atomizer
most of the atomizers you know are
really small and the oil will sit on top
of like the ceramic disc or the nichrome
wire and what we ended up doing was of
creating what we call a ceramic sponge
so just like sponges have nooks and
crannies to absorb more water by having
all these nooks and crannies in the
porous ceramic we have roughly three
times the surface area as your
traditional vape pen which allows us to
use lower temperatures to give you
headaches over and larger clouds so
hopefully we hit the mark but um
hopefully you get yours in a few days
and you could let me know um if we hit
the mark I already know you trust me on
that one I know because I've been
anxiously at first you're like oh I'm
gonna send you one of these I was like
okay whatever that's cool and then as I
started seeing people's experiences with
them I was kind of like wow like this is
crazy and then it got worse and worse
and worse to the point where now my
mouth water is when I see it so I just
at least have to try it and you know for
me there is a lot in what you said at
the towards the end by the way welcome
to Colin over on the east coast I don't
know if he's in New York or
Massachusetts no comment he sweat up
garish what I was gonna say was and it's
a big long conversation and we've had a
little bit of that conversation before
for me there is a real difference in the
preservation of terpene profiles through
any type of vaporizer or dab rig and
that almost always is in regards to how
the material that you're hitting off of
holds and releases heat and so that's
why Sapphire doesn't taste the same as
courts and courts doesn't taste the same
as titanium all when you do them all at
the exact same temperature which I've
done they don't taste the same with the
exact same it's
area and I was actually hitting a
vaporizer the other drift the other day
and I don't think I have it here it was
it was very much like Gary's from from
the Omicron he's talking about the torch
yeah yeah but I was actually pleasantly
surprised at how much that preserved the
taste because I've been dabbing off of I
think I'm hitting silicon carbide right
now and I've been dabbing off of it for
about a week to two weeks this hash and
I ended up putting a little bit in that
torch and I was just very surprised at
how different the tastes were and I
think that that's something that you
know vaporization companies should focus
on much the same way when I spoke with
the Remo years ago about his nutrient
company that he was thinking of starting
was to focus on the productions of the
phenols and the hydrocarbons within the
trichome had like if you want to
manipulate something with your food
learn to manipulate the actual
production of the building blocks of the
cannabinoids and terpenoids that produce
and create more vegetative yields of
plant matter and so I see vaporizers and
and food complex that's the focus if you
have a food company in my opinion you
know like figure out a way to produce
more medicinal components you know of a
higher quality of a higher expression
vaporized companies vaporization
companies is to preserve the profile so
when you when you hit it the taste is
just so good and III I'd hate to say it
because I loved a Briggs but I think the
nicest tasting hits that I've had come
from handheld vaporizers for
preservation of taste
to mark and really because of just the
way it heats and I and as you talked
about that because I've been doing a lot
of dabbing with the torch and then
before us on the email these that penzal
on and as you're talking about that the
Pens give it that nice smooth I like the
taste here it's right on par yeah I'll
agree I was using the the torch
yesterday and the Omni Kron as well and
you know just give you a different
prefer a ver profile all together but
the the thing that I've been talking to
a lot of manufacturers about is the the
reheating and the the heating of of you
know oils in and a half gram to a gram
it's you know that heating and reheating
really causes you know a lot of strain
on the material and overtime so when we
get you know you get a nice little dab
in there on the torch or the omicron
it's just unbelievably great you know so
if we can get closer to that with having
oil let's say we take solve unless we
put it into a car it's that heating and
reheating and that material that same
material staying in that element that
really causes it to degrade and really
lose its its its flavor profile you just
don't have you don't get that with the
Omni Kron good that that leads me to my
vape exhale which is the only unit I
have ever been able to take keer terpene
rips out of without it just being
horribly destructive on my throat
there's no other unit that I've ever
been able to hit pure Terps off of like
that one I mean I did a whole [ __ ]
terpene gauntlet I can't remember who I
did it with maybe Brett from you were
there to say well we big one
we did one as well I think we did like
nineteen continent okay because I
definitely have a fourteen as well and
it might have even been d4 20k I can't
remember but that's that's saying a lot
and that is I always mix the two up
convection conduction induction
induction yeah and you know I've I've
always been a fan of convection over
conduction but as time has gone on you
know I've seen that there it's how you
execute the methodology that matters
most in no I played around with so many
different temperature types so many
different surface areas you know one
thing that I was really playing around
with was being able to inductively hate
fretted laughs in a way where a dab
could just kind of melt into it and
really take advantage of the additional
surface area and the interesting thing
is you know it's it's
each type of material or each type of
technology has its own kind of flavor
signature as you were mentioning earlier
and as we all know flavor is subjective
so I just tell people you should
experiment with all the different kinds
that you could find and ultimately you
know you will arrive at your favorite
and the best part is um it's always fun
as you're doing R&amp;D so even if it's not
right you're still getting a good effect
the result and the terpenes all have
different each terpene each monoterpene
has a different you know combustion
point so that's part of it I think as
well I mean these in research and
talking with some people I don't know
somebody here from Colorado and stuff
we're talking about terpenes and inside
the containers because of the way that
pre-packaging here in Canada with
containers and stuff like that and and
looking at active water content and
terpenes and how they're in the
containers are looking at their moisture
content sure that's nothing we focus on
heavily is trying to retain all that
moisture content because once that's
lost your terpenes go with it man yeah I
mean I would like to do a half stretch
on this mark about moisture content
after water content and low humidity
because it's quite a thing fascinating
that I've been researching to the last
little bit and there's a lots of
possible and it's just I don't have time
today cuz I gotta catch a plane and I
like to kind of get deep into it about
it but there's there's all these little
factors with legalization we're looking
at and how they're actually distributing
all of this right now you know what I
mean like it's yeah I've been watching
your voice yeah i'm testing stuff that
like 29% active water now active water
content in bread crumbs is 30 past it is
50 so there's got to be a standard
there's there's more I want to talk
about so I'm just gonna kind of like
this right also well that goes back to
the man you like now we're talking about
like GM piece like manufacturing right
and we're like as artists and as
cultivators you you kind of you know we
have all these new steps we have to pay
attention to cuz it's not just going
into packs and then being quickly sold
it's now being you know the packages are
now going to be individuals into grams a
halves and there's a large
one month three months six months when
it was packaged all this act Li is this
is totally different ballgame so we've
got to really think about it like that
yeah yeah did we ever complexify this
[ __ ] I got a bag of weed you need a bag
of weed here it's something that is dear
to my heart because I want to make sure
that as you know what we see behind the
scenes is not what most people see when
they go to the dispensary they see a
very different experience and I you know
it's getting closer to that experience
that we are so fond of and making sure
that that quality is upheld all the way
through to the first time they open it
you know that's major
you know it's hardly why for instance
here look this is induction sealed here
and this is something I've been playing
with for months for rosin and that's
really important to me is because when
these things get packed you know a lot
of people are disappointed in rosin
because it's it gets them all caked out
and dry and not what they want hey I
don't mean to interrupt but I gotta go
take my kids I just wanted to say one
last thing I'm big fans of everyone here
med caner is my favorite way to bring
all my flour around and thank you for
doing what you're doing with that
sealing because that last thing you said
I've heard so many people say that about
their rosin and I'm so glad you came up
with that I just wanted to make sure I
got that out before I left
thanks a bow
so what you just talked about seals is
something I thought was the biggest
thing is the type of seals and all these
containers and how the sealing worth all
across the board and I bought every LP
that I can actually purse spend a couple
thousand just to look at containers and
packaging not even smoking it I really
need that you know what they're doing
and it's and this is a big big part that
we're talking about it's actually is
these lives in these seals and and how
they're actually shipping this stuff and
how dry it is and you know it's yeah I
mean I'll they'll piece out there
listening you're welcome what are you
guys doing I'm like you guys after water
is like pathetic man like come on look
what do you guys doing in and then I'm
just not getting it and Health Canada
has to get involved too and they are
down in the United States there's some
more stuff woman to talk about what
they're doing the United States and in
Canada Health Canada was in meetings a
couple months ago they're starting to
set a standard between 55 to 65 active
water what I'm hearing we're finally
getting its standardization at some
point right across the board because we
would start controlling that you can
start controlling terpenes everything if
there's anything you know you want to
bounce ideas off of you know reach out
to market so you know so you know what
it's just like this this next step for
perfect yeah yeah whoa boys you've got
this huge you know all of our material
really relies on that and you know like
you're kind of pointing it out we you
know we're industrialized in an
ornamental crop and it really is
something they look at active water and
you know what I mean so it's really that
a:8w got we gotta really start paying
attention to did you want to explain the
differences to everyone or did you
already I'm not having that I was gonna
talk more about that but relative
humidity in the air octaves one is
what's inside of the containers so if
there's a certain amount of water or
moisture content inside of a pod what
you seal it the active water is how it
rehydrates and goes back and forth and
there's certain steps of where it's
gotta be it can't be above like thirty
percent moisture content that's gonna be
above sixty five percent relative
humidity which would cause mold which
active water content comes into play and
I've done a lot of testing and that's
what I want to talk more about it like
you know I'm learning I'm learning with
other people are teaching me this
because I really want to know and they
know that I have a voice that we're
using in order to educate everybody on
this so I love the bounce more ideas
also some people and really bring this
to light and talk more about it yeah so
let me ask you to do in terms of them
testing you know has there been any any
long-term test put together that kind of
outlined the relative humidity and
microbes that are that or really
deactive has done a lot of heavy
HM this those are the people I'm working
with and a lot of deep research that
they're doing with their company I'm
doing my own little stuff you know just
find the researcher find out what's
going on with it talking more about it
and that's why I want to bring it to
light because I need to learn more I
know my little port here you know what I
mean and yep let's just kind of let's
educate it going yeah try to keep
learning from each other yeah I mean
there's right and that's that's part of
why we've been exploring induction
sailing and a new pack and I mean it is
like not touching it you know like it
all goes down to how you harvest and how
you dry and how that cures and hey if
you're touching it so many times you
know I I'm so methought you're so
detailed about what we're doing that it
gets so obsessive you know because this
care so much room with an active water
meter testing as you know comes down all
the way through and then I I was really
interested pretty cool about it and I
screwed up and I left my lights on my D
go I went back in and I had tried out
all my tops down to like 50 percent RH
in the room so I tested the act of water
40 41 now tell you about
I always Krampus 64 percent RH in my
room well it's a via nothing else level
strange straight across the board was 52
so then I brought my humidity up to 70
relative humidity and all of my weed was
58 to 61 hear what I'm saying yep and
then what are you actually putting in it
so I've been looking at you know the
storage aspect of it that's been a big
part of it as well and what you watch
parts oh no I'm not dealing you know I'm
dealing with like 240 pounds a week you
know every 12 days you know there's like
a new problem you know so it's like you
know we we look at those you know we
look at it in terms of like how you know
we've got to keep this is you gotta keep
this at under 64% yes octave water
rotating mini and this is all with a
talk about for like I said yeah I got to
catch a plane and I really want to get
in but hey that was awesome I mean it
yeah I mean these little it's funny like
small Bop problems become very complex
really quickly especially with what the
amount we're dealing with in volume with
these
he's eating was storing how the storing
it's going all these and you know wasn't
because I'm seeing these big news these
big production says and I'm look I'm
drooling like wow look at this but how
they able to start liquid Mars doing
with embarq see these are the next big
steps all these extractions how to store
these cannolis for future reference and
exactly
that's what's so awesome we guys are
doing and looking at all these different
extractions because flour is not one
thing but now we're stepping into the
next field which is going to be
extractive it's gonna be those edibles
how they storing those edibles how are
they you know this is all stuff they're
gonna have to really take a look at
before they legalize this here coming up
on October 20th and and you know John
it's why I've always said that embarks
part of embarks real value will be the
data that it collects I understand you
know that's going to be incredibly like
just priceless data you know like what
would we pay for it right now if it came
up for sale if it existed and we could
just buy it what would you pay for it
that's part of what we're doing in the
states to market it so the you know flip
side you know down here Happy Valley is
really focusing on keeping our ethos
forward you know like not forgetting
that we've got quality medicine to
uphold not just a you know a you know
manufacturing situation to to run you
know and it depends on who you want to
be in the market to you know there's a
lot of LPS that might just be fine with
that you know yeah yeah well you have
your liquid anything in the industry
yeah
have your little gradient you know I'm
you're hydrating have people who set
standards all across the board you know
the whole thing you're gonna have here
your keg and you're gonna have your
five-star yeah we want to be then the
pastime well if I started story start
we're all in that and not playing so
that's what we want that's what we focus
on and that's what we want to see
because hey you know what
you know grown ones fantastic and great
but you know it consumes a lot of my own
time and I like to see better quality
hit the market so when I am in need I
can actually go and Lexie get something
that has truly quality that I that I'm
gonna be able to consume that's gonna
help me with my pain exactly because
let's be honest life's too short to be
selling some swag cameras
kids I'm setting the lineup with these
guys opening up clubs and I'm having no
you know no packs of stuff I'm trying to
get people who ever try to you never
tried cannabis before did you yeah
a true experience and not by something
that is dry or not done properly is like
no it's a parable representation of what
cannabis can be and I don't really think
it's the faults necessarily of Elpida
it's like the government and the rules
that they've placed on these companies
are like I'd like to see anyone try like
me everyone fights for like we should
all be allowed to try it's like all
right like you know that's a lot of
bankrupt people you know that's what I
see in the States right now is like
everybody you just want you know
especially that this house the CBD you
know craze right now it's it's actually
pretty dangerous for the longevity of
the of the industry when you got stuff
like that happening say it down D for
20k dude what's going on man we've been
waiting for that for an hour and 34
minutes no yeah no just 34 minutes look
my bonds ripping ready to go is everyone
else's creamy [ __ ] glass of OG Kush
some headband not a few strains up here
we're working with right now but seem to
be pressing pretty greasy it's nice
come hard well that was it I can still
hear that in my headphones you know what
last minute Hastert's today but I'm very
stoked to just have gotten some
conversation and got some peeps to come
in some of the oh jeez John Ian and he
and Mike West and have a call and share
what he's doing you know you never even
mentioned which i think is great Colin
it's hilarious you keep calling your
company in your group we but you haven't
even mentioned the name of the actual
comfort
yeah so so we're yeah so I guess that's
a good thing I should i should really
well I think it's it's for a lot of
reason we're we're just you know getting
all of our our materials together and
we're you know we're finishing our
facility and I just think the timing of
it all and we've been working really
hard behind the scenes as you know
Marcus putting together and taking great
care and crafting what we're we're you
know putting together and Happy Valley
is the name of the company and Marcus's
is a part of that and we have a lot of
exciting great things happening in terms
of solving that stack we've got 27
thousand square feet of canopy coming
online with another 60 60 to follow in
the couple years behind that hopefully
sooner than that but it's all focused
around solving lists and putting our
ethos forward and making sure that we we
do our best that that good medicine is
put into the right people's hands and
that's really at the end of the day
we're trying to do so everything you
were talking about Johnny man it's like
yeah that's like where my head's at for
the past years just trying to figure out
how each cultivar that we know can be
done in a certain amount of square foot
facility can now be scaled and and that
same quality can be upheld all the way
through and I think we've you know we've
we get in there you know and then you
know people like you and sharing in
these conversations will help us get kid
even closer to what we're all looking
for so you know what's the best thing
about what we do is we just keep doing
what we love to do yep no doubt that's
it this is true this is true but yeah so
we're excited man we're gonna relaunch
in in mass and uh most likely in the
fall this year and you know it's just
this is like accumulation of so many
years of designing facilities and then
getting to this this place with you know
such a beautiful facility you know we're
really really lucky to have this and and
it's I'm really excited to have Marcus
along for the ride with this one sir
I did yeah Massachusetts yeah birdie
representing you know what I gotta thank
the 373 people that actually in the last
minute I don't know if they get a
notification they must but thank you
guys for coming and hanging out you guys
must be the oh geez of hash Church
because everybody pastor story and ice
and not one and all the ones we're just
says I don't know and then today you
didn't ask trip so you know what all
those oh these out there yeah yeah well
it's been almost four years maybe over
four years since we started this this
sort of conversation I guess you would
say and you know I felt like when it was
going really strong that there were
these new contenders that were up and up
and coming but when it dropped and we
stopped doing it I really didn't feel
like anything replaced you know the
weekly conversations that would occur
and I don't pretend to think that every
minute of these conversations were worth
recording or whatnot but definitely
there were always gems within the hours
that we shared each Sunday that seemed
to like manifest and put form to you
know part of the industry as we know it
today and I'm not trying to say that in
an in a in a bragging type of way
because I was a very small part of it
there was a hundred plus people that
came on and shared their conversation
here on hash church over those years but
it is incredible from like the talking
about rosin presses into an entire
industry the talking about all of these
different things I mean even for me for
embark you know hash Church was you know
where I met Mike West who is gonna be a
big part of embarked and who has already
been a big part of embark and I I met
him on hashed Church literally he would
come into hash Church in his lab running
his co2 machine in the background while
we were all having discussions and then
every hour or so we'd walk over to the
mic and drop some crazy large like boom
but like I gotta go back to the machine
for a second so that's that's how I met
you Mike was through hashed Church so
it's kind of interesting to see I mean
obviously I knew Johnny B and D 420k
long before hashed Church I've known
those guys for I don't even know how
long probably is about as long as I've
known Colin for that matter what's
hanging out just like three or four of
us all the time chanting because you're
running around but even way before that
I mean holy [ __ ] I've known you guys for
a couple of decades it's a long time
it's good to have you guys no doubt my
Marcus what's that Michael just being
able to you know walk hang out and watch
church wall you're sitting in the lab
for hours yeah there's more nearly as
fun as listening to knowledge yeah yeah
for sure no that's that's I never really
thought of that but I always had people
contact me and tell me oh we put hash
Church on in our in our you know glass
shop or we put hash search on and are in
our dispensary I was like right on
that's that's great I seen it a few
times I think I even was filming one
time and I went into a dispensary I
think it was my friends in my Orca and
hashed Church was on their TVs and I was
caught I asked him I was like did you do
that on purpose and he was like no not
at all it was just the timing of walking
in so that was pretty cool
Rob's mark how about what signing
autographs signing autographs how do you
mean you just give them the pictures
with those people at the mall at the
airport oh yeah yeah yeah listen you're
a [ __ ] movie star you can sign
autographs I'm like a lowly hash maker
but my the stuff that I did nobody came
up and talked to me about it talk to us
but they come up and centered us on you
guys you bet I love what you guys are
doing the house Church is just nice my
brother and sister for the first time we
were filled with not right I know that
was incredible to you about results that
was an emotional moment I was part of it
yeah I was awesome man it was
it was really cool yeah no that was
definitely coming and ripping with us on
Christmas right so many nice memories of
really cool moments throughout the whole
thing like when we started this it was
just literally going in and getting high
together showing what we're making on
the dry set and stuff and I could check
this out our little parchment so
everything is like it was so brand-new
in the industry nobody was even selling
dry sift or anything like that because
it was so hard to make and so hard to
acquire that when you got caught you
kept course I [ __ ] gold gold dust
peace out Johnny B thanks for dropping
knowledge today people were impressed in
the chat room
they said Johnny B's on fire let's talk
next week
love you guys Darren you rock man that's
rice if you don't forget the back of
that card talk more about that that's
how look at how have started even rosin
with Tony pressing old hash and that's
all grown with the curling iron and like
all of these texts yeah they all started
from us screwing around on how scourge
guys you rock piece these brothers you
know right I wondered how many things of
how many industries started like
businesses and everything like that
because that's everything that's been
okay the interesting thing about that is
that when you share the information in
conversation things blow up you know
when you hold your IP to yourself as
strong as you can and this is the sort
of this is that hard part of coming from
the industry and getting into these
larger companies where you're like okay
like there's more on like it was easy to
think that way over here cuz it was just
a couple of thousand invested but when
you have tens of millions invested it's
crazy how you have to be more careful
and it's too bad because you're right
like a lot of the conversations that
happened on here people were able to
take that information that what they
heard on here and basically you know
deuce
things serious with it executed whether
for a small personal gain to make a pure
medicine for themselves or to you know
create and produce medicine for others
or maybe they started a company and
touch tens of thousands you know selling
a product like a rosin press or
something yeah
well I'm doing a consulting business up
here in Prince George it's not quite
launched yet but it's gonna be right
away where it's just everybody can grow
therefore plants and all that stuff but
there's a way they got to do it they got
it register they got to do all this sort
of stuff to make it to make it good for
themselves but I just want to show them
how I do it myself and how I process it
myself whether I'm dry sifting bubbling
or rasa ting the flower or the bubble
house whatever and let them have their
grow their medicine and and make it as
pure as they want and I'll go on and
consult for them and do it for a very
reasonable price because it's only four
plants at a time these are all all just
normal humans now not wanting to get
[ __ ] taken to the cleaners to learn
how to do something right and it's just
my way it's not like late like I you
know I don't know everything but I do
have access to pretty much everything I
need to know if I want to if I need to
reach out for it right yeah exactly
it's good this whole internet thing go
figure information is just available at
our fingertips at any given time and the
cannabis industry is no doubt blowing up
with once again companies like embark
willing to set and set a new bar and we
certainly won't be the last and we
certainly aren't the first to set a new
bar and that's how things just keep
escalating and escalating to a point
where for me I love the idea of I'll
always love the idea of personal growth
of people being able to grow their own
to me that's sacred and people should
always be able to have that but the
bottom line is because I have a license
to grow my own and don't have a plant in
the ground it's actually a lot of work
and takes a lot of attention and focus
and it's not just something you can do
in the background when you have multiple
kids and five businesses and you get
pulled in twelve different directions at
any given time I can't I
have time to grow cannabis to take care
of it properly and that's that's that's
the truth for a lot of people so in that
sense canvas needs to be made accessible
to all those other people who should
have access to as the same as the person
who decides they want to grow it for
themselves and I think what John EB was
talking about well I know it because I
used to broker cannabis myself I know
what good cannabis looks like and what
bad cannabis looks like and when you
package great cannabis incorrectly at
the wrong time with the wrong amount of
moisture for the wrong amount of time
you destroy it
you absolutely [ __ ] it up it goes from
being like whatever they call it now it
used to be a trip I guess it's a
quadruple a this goes down to like in my
opinion a see when it just gets wet and
it just gets funky and hade like
smelling and it doesn't cure outright
and the Terps are [ __ ] and
everything's [ __ ] that that is not
necessarily on the grower you know
unless he's also the guy that packaged
it up now if you're working for a
company and you grow some great cannabis
and you give it to the company and then
they package it incorrectly and you know
go figure as well I think a lot of that
packaging incorrectly is not accidental
I think that these that these government
agencies like Health Canada they seem to
go out of their way to make things not
as easy as they could be I don't know
why I've been dealing with them since
1994 when we applied for a hemp license
and although I will say this about
Health Canada because it's easy to get
upset with what they're doing and how
they're doing it they have at least
grown immensely over the course of the
last 20 years since they started doing
licensing in Canada it's amazing how
much more and more and more and more is
available it hasn't been like an
ironclad like this is what you get and
this and for the last 20 years that's
all we've got we've consistently added
more and more things so I suspect it's
like a damn door that will eventually
burst open and the cannabis
consciousness will flood through in a
way that they can finally I think we'll
laugh one day when we look back that we
used to have to treat cannabis like
plutonium with you know level 9 vaults
with biometrics to acquire entry
like all of these other things no that's
I don't know I just think as a as a
industry we could we could commit more
to better things like if you didn't have
to spend two million dollars on your
vault you could donate like five hundred
grand to like you know building schools
somewhere you know helping with
education or in some way creating
philanthropy but they just create this
enormous amount of yeah and we yeah we
well the other thing is is that I see in
terms of like packaging we don't have
the mission we don't have a machine we
have some machines we're very limited
I don't listen we don't have machines
because we do we do have very limited
machines that are within our reach that
actually handle the material right we
just we don't and we we have things like
dog food sorters that are they're trying
to pass office orders for for our
industry and it's just not the right way
to do it but I understand how long it
takes to pack 30,000 units that's a long
time and yeah so there's nothing else
like it though is there with these
volatile gases evaporate off the plant
while moisture contents are are also
evaporating and mixing with the terpenes
in the air and going back into the flood
this is Mel's amazing but it's never
it's just going into my face oh yeah
yeah you're right though but yeah it's
we'll get there though I think it's
we're just at the inception a lot of
those that's the infancy for sure you
know yeah we're just trying and trying a
lot of great people focused on trying to
make it the best that we can make it you
know and I don't just mean like the
companies I'm working with I mean
there's a ton of great people in this
industry that are kind of focused on and
I think sometimes people get a little
like you know kind of like oh who's this
new person or whatever doing this that
and the other thing but for me I just
I'm like a kid in a candy store I'm like
so excited like I saw canopy announced
Martha Stewart the other day for their
CBD brand and I was like it just put a
smile on my face I was like and then of
course other people were offended by
what does Martha Stewart know I'm like I
don't know she just has like a
distribution access to like 409
million women around the world like yeah
what is Martha Stewart know like I just
I thought it was cool other people they
didn't think it was so cool I guess but
the Stewart is solid man she's [ __ ]
times
she did her bed I guess I can't be the
size of it man but but you're right I
mean canopy's smart man they came in you
know I you know they're not they're not
you know they're a tough one they're
they're very very aggressive company man
you know hey hey
regardless I feel self-conscious you
know I think everybody on not me not me
I saw that well
now the reality of Hallie not hanging
around us and it's so large and out of
control that it's it's really puts a
reality spin on it I'll be honest I saw
that simply as I'm gonna supply them
with CBD hey some people find
opportunity absolutely I totally see
that
yeah no doubt it's it's a listen anytime
there's someone's pushing a cannabinoid
I find that positive yeah I mean I don't
know how's everything awful Martha
Stewart did her bid right D she did
that's funny I love all the different
perspectives from her church I can just
imagine someone who's never been on hash
Church before talking about this
tomorrow at work when they're like we're
talking and when that guy when that guy
in the Slayer shirt said she did her bid
I fell off my chair
[Laughter]
she didn't whether she's solid
yes exactly these are solid even solid
solid oh my goodness thank God for
having a hashed Church today I've missed
it I'll be honest I needed one of these
huh had to be done so I should mention a
few things because there's all these
other things that are coming up and
happening let me see if I can figure
this out actually because
this is somewhat important I want to
have a few announcements to make so yeah
announcements but I have to be smart how
I make the announcements I thought
better than talking about it I would
kind of show it but it's on Instagram so
it's not quite and I don't even know if
he sent it to me oh my god did he know
it's on here
I wonder how I'm gonna be able to maybe
I can repost it is that what I can do
sorry for sounding like a 65 year old
like never been on technology before I
don't know what these buttons are doing
now also saw read all my 65 year old
friends because that was a terrible
stereotype oh my goodness okay so I was
going to announce the I'm gonna be a
judge well first first first things
first the team at embark is heading to
the ICBC conference in Spain March 14th
so that's gonna be really cool that's
what Alex Rogers who was on hash Church
the last time talking about it actually
and so we have will be there well we I
think I'm speaking on a panel and then
the after-party is gonna be lit it's
Damian Marley which I'm pretty stoked
about having an after-party at the W it
with Damian Marley and Barcelona that's
just gonna be surreal to say the least
so hopefully anyone that's coming to
spannabis will make sure you show up a
day early cuz spannabis which we will
also be at is the 15th 16th and 17th and
that's that's in Barcelona in the
hospital at Zone and it'll be the same
area that it's always been in and I'll
probably be walking around and cruising
around and then also I'm going to be
this is a full circle with HQ hemp
quarters in Barcelona the first place I
ever got a membership at great guy owns
owned by David he does a contest called
masters of rasen you might have seen it
you can check it out on Instagram at
Masters of rosin and he's got like
Crockett and DNA and like a whole bunch
of really cool people that were judges I
hadn't been in touch with him to let him
know that I was going but I did let him
know I was going a couple weeks ago and
I guess Jerome Baker Jason Harris wasn't
able to make it so his spot dropped and
so David called me and now I'm gonna be
a judge in that Wow what an amazing time
stuntman Sam
although you are reverberating right now
because the next thing I'm getting to is
the legends of hash actually I like the
echo legends of hash [ __ ] come on and
havin fun dude
let me let me see if I can bring it up
because we are doing a legends of hash
this year and we're gonna be doing it
with flat four-to-one and flux who's I
guess got himself a spot in Barcelona so
we're gonna be kind of breaking that in
with the legends of hash there's a
legends of hash there's no trophies
there's no like announcements of like
this that the other thing it's just like
if you want to come and smoke some hash
we'll have some people judging there
will be a small announcement that you
know first second and third and why the
judges thought that but really that's
the main the main thing is to come
celebrate hashish with us and nothing
nothing nothing more so let me find this
picture cuz we finally got the shot done
and then let me go to screen save so I
can show ya what it looks like all right
here we go start screen shared is that
all warped own oh there it goes so when
you think of that Barcelona Sunday yeah
March 17 legends of hash and then I'll
be supplying the address to the place
when you get your ticket so we're super
excited about that shout out to suomi
Laval this is one of his photos from the
great book hashish it is called hashish
right skunk man Sam absolutely correct
Hershey yeah it's not a Marcus yeah yeah
well like I said shout-out to those
those folks screen in the hash and shout
out to suomi or whoever took I think he
took all his photos as well as that is
that also correct or incorrect Sam I'm
not sure if he took all the photos but I
would not
surprised a lot of words in the book it
has a short introduction by some that's
true somebody in some famous Valley in
England but right well there it is that
those are my announcements anyway for
ICBC spannabis legends of hash masters
of rosin I should make a legends of hash
Instagram but now I've said it some
trolls already registered it so guess I
won't do that he's gonna be like pay me
for it
no no we're not doing that we don't tell
oh I know what another thing that I'm
gonna mention we are gonna have the good
folks at move the movement I invited
Darrell in today I kind of wanted him to
talk about it a little bit but I don't
know if you guys saw those a couple of
interviews I did with these guys in a
really cool building I think it was at
the chat no it wasn't the chat it might
have been the chat center I can't
remember it was a cool building on the
UBC campus really cool round like it
just had a really great look to it and
he did a bunch of interviews with Kurt I
saw John Conroy and and Chris Bennett
and myself and a whole bunch of other
people so they if you check out move the
movement it's it's really great thing
that they're doing kind of getting these
great stories out of the community in a
really professional manner editing
really to perfection and then and then
putting it out as a very enjoyable story
they're gonna be coming to Spain with us
and they're gonna film I guess two full
days with us so or with me and the crew
and so I don't know exactly what those
two days will be but I suspect it will
for sure be the ICBC conference because
that'll be a whole day and then
hopefully he'll do like a section of
masters of rosin because there'll be
some great footage there as well as a
portion of the legends which is going to
be the first time I know Sam's probably
like what it's like yeah if you know
this will be the first time we've
actually allowed anyone to take video
but there also won't be the same group
of people that were particularly on
video over the last 20 years
however if Scott man Sam does
it's to grace us with his presence there
will not be video anywhere near here he
is oh my god who's that guy in the Bella
klava so how are you doing skunkman Sam
how are things in Amsterdam it's okay
and when you come to the EU are you just
going to Spain I tried to come through
Amsterdam and KLM was all sold out so I
ended up having to go through Germany so
because there's no direct flights for me
probably need your vibrations more than
Amsterdam well I was kind of hoping I
won't lie that I was going to be able to
spend at least the day with with you and
yours
that's what I was trying to make happen
and I couldn't believe it personally
because I booked the flight like a week
and a half ago or something and it's not
for another couple of weeks
I guess it's less than a couple of weeks
now Wow jeez times really flying here in
your people book page three months six
months in advance
Jesus how did they do that how could you
possibly know where you're going to be
with their working schedule oh my god
what a nightmare I guess that's why I've
been told to avoid certain places during
certain times in like the South in the
Mediterranean you know Italy France
Spain the islands menorca Majorca Abita
they just fill up with people like you
said at the all at the exact same time
like it's probably dead the day before
and then literally the next day it's
like at full capacity and they're all on
the roads and they're all flying they're
all driving every you just yeah it's not
so fun now I can't deal with that I
can't deal with that well it was a
last-minute hashed Church today
did you did you actually mention the
company yet Colin or no yeah I did I did
a while back okay
cuz I was happy yeah man it's really
exciting because we you know we spent so
much time behind the scenes over the
past two decades that it's really nice
to come out with an outfit that allows
us to come into the market man and it's
it's it feels really special to be able
to be a part of that and a way that we
get to kind of do it our way and that's
that's really you know that's that's
what I'm looking forward to so you're
sure it's exciting big big things big
things I mean I think listen I've known
you for almost 20 years as well and I'm
going through the exact same thing you
know this is exciting time finally
having a team together that can execute
a plan you know not having to of like
you know sold my soul to an LP like I
avoided that and just to create my own
thing like create our own thing that's
exactly that's different from from
anything else so you know definitely the
the the best of Luck's to the embarks
and the happy valleys of the cannabis
world that's for sure I'm [ __ ] yeah
we're I think we're good we're excited
to be be good stewards of the plant and
preservation s of genetics and make sure
that these things live on in a way that
they get to be able to be used by by as
many patients as we can and you know
that's part of the just part of the
process you know going through all the
stock and going through old stock and
it'll be fun absolutely you know but
yeah so I've got to get going guys but
um I appreciate the time that I spent
with y'all and I look forward to being
on next time thank you for coming out
dude I appreciate it last minute as well
I put the word out to about 20 folks so
I was happy to get you know five five
six people come in that was great yeah
Sam always an honor to be on with you I
would love to ask you a million
questions but I've got to get going but
I was gonna ask you a question too about
preservation of a variety yeah please
this variety or clone
right because preservation of seed
varieties that's a lot of work you got a
reproducible at least 2,000 individual
plant can be every year no doubt so
that's that's a great question so it's
now that I have the space to do it it's
going to be I'm going to get into
preservation of seed form before it was
all about just preserving specific
cultivars and phenotypes and now it's
about going in and actually preserving
lines in a way I've never even had
access to do it you know I've never
really had I've never been able to to
not only just mono crop so this is a
really unique situation for me to be
able to have upwards to 15,000 square
feet just to preserve and explore I've
been doing it a long time and we we came
up with the minimum number is 2,000 for
a male female variety well that's yeah I
share that same sentiment and I'd love
to learn a bit more about your your
ideologies and what you've learned over
the years obviously you've spent
tremendous amount of times with the
plant and in numerous sized facilities
and I think it I can only benefit from
your knowledge you know so it it would
be awesome to sit down with you and talk
about that and in terms of numbers what
have you seen at mm well it's genetics
statistical analysis if you have less
than 2000 then you're not preserving the
genes in that variety you're preserving
right so you're okay that makes a lot of
sense so you're basically at that under
2000 year basically selective breeding
or really selective preservation a
selective preservation not the entire
gene pool of that
variety exactly right okay that makes a
lot of sense um a lot yeah okay so in
terms of a hybrid variety that's maybe a
poly bridge well a hybrid you do you
think that more seeds need to be kept
because there's more genetic variation
happening I mean there you're not going
to be keeping the same material because
you'll be what twos and threes
I mean they segregate out right that
makes sense and do you believe in in
preservation specifically precious
preservation do you believe open
pollination with many males is is the
only way to preserve or mind race
absolutely it's the only way or so all
you young guys out there listening in
take note to this land race that's the
man so that makes a lot of sense because
you know today what we have is is is
mostly what I would call very limited
selective breeding going on
so we're scoping sewed and our lens is
so narrow that when we do find something
desirable it just makes you wonder how
many other desirable traits are in that
that same gene pool if they're actually
at the space to run it if you think
about how land races are created people
start growing cannabis in a particular
area whether that's Afghanistan or
Thailand or Burma or wherever and they
but the deep pool there is limited by
its a large population that's a farmers
over for thousands and thousands of
thousands of plants sometimes even
bigger and but it it's cut off from of
the gene flow so it it becomes it
travels down and because
it's own land rates that don't variety
with a unique set of genes and terpenes
and cannabinoids and that's what you
want preserve everything right okay so
here's a question for you in terms of
land race varieties what I'm seeing a
lot today is a lot of people are going
out trekking out there and collecting
some land race and then they're
furthering the line maybe they're doing
some young reading and then
predominantly a lot of the people I've
talked to that ran that same variety
they're getting a lot of hermaphrodite
traits because they're running him in
for environments that they're just the
these didn't program the genetics itself
are just so far into it itself that it
just starts to have adverse reactions to
it what are your thoughts on inbreeding
those types of lines to make them
readily available or we try to damaging
those lines by doing things like that
well I don't know what you mean by
inbreeding or inbreeding or hybridize
well you're taking let's say we find a
male and a female of of the same variety
and then we make more seeds out of that
okay and but we narrow the scope by only
having like a few different females and
maybe five or ten different females and
five to the 20 males that are
pollinating these things it's clearly
not enough to to preserve the doctor
people but you may preserve two really
nice good examples and a segment of that
gene pool you might preserve and it
might be really interesting I can't say
without gene
sure okay well that kind of answers it
because they I think a lot of people are
that I've talked to outside of my
personal experience are finding a lot of
hermaphrodite traits coming out because
they're running them inside and in a
very under lighting that they're not
used to I have not really seen for my
product being expressed by that I mean
if variety does not have intersex genes
then usually [ __ ] it around with it
doesn't really change
I've seen step remember lights or grown
in greenhouses and that or breathe or
outdoors in the ground then doesn't seem
to really change alter the the intersex
expression particularly that I've seen
now there are some there are certain
varieties like ty we learn tentacley
intersex just because they were from
tamiya for hundreds if not thousands of
years and the few seeds that they did
found were very likely caused by
intersect sure I always think it's to be
honest when when I hear people tell me
those things I always believe it's their
environment that's causing the problems
not the not the actual genetics so that
that kind of reaffirms well I've got
I've come across varieties that you no
matter what kind of environmental stress
you put on them it they would not
express any sort of intersex expression
and all the new book and I be
interesting to take those to where
you're talking about and you try to make
them turn intersex
yeah well it's it'll be interesting you
know I've got a few varieties there's
some Iranian varieties that I've I was
given that I'm very interested to run
and a few things from Morocco and Nepal
that should be really interesting to run
in the coming months them I'm actually
really excited about the biggest problem
too is when people collect land receipts
today is are they pure for example in
Morocco there are no pure land races
they're all gone the same thing in
Jamaica and probably in Mexico and any
other country were lots of Westerners
though and take seeds to help the locals
so here's another good question in terms
of land truthy and so I I've actually I
share that same ideology where it's like
I don't I feel like at this day and age
it's almost nearly impossible to find
true land race unless you really go very
very deep
and that takes a lot of effort and not
everybody's built for that but I think
what I saw technically it's illegal
today because but there are genetic
treaties worldwide but all the countries
are signatory to that says you cannot go
and take genes from a country like
Thailand or India or wherever and take
them back to America reproduce them and
sell them for profit without cherry with
both the government and the farmers and
etc etc that's all that wasn't there
when I was collecting seeds but it's
there now yeah I would imagine you know
when you were avidly collecting in that
in that way that you would probably come
across things that and I'm sure you
probably still have some of these things
that are occurring expressions out that
are just not seen today at all and not
see that's pretty exciting place to be
Sam and also really is is all the
different cannabinoids in Turkey in
different expressions of ratios and well
also to some plant or auto some plants
are are all female so I mean there are
wide leaps skin elite them early late
maturing etcetera etcetera but I mean
really it's the terpenes with THC as a
recreational user firstly am interested
absolutely and the the idea that you
know we've come across that the single
cannabinoid is therapeutic is really
interesting to me do you think through
the years of you being involved in
cannabinoids was there such a heavy you
know did they always weigh so much
strength into a single cannabinoid or is
this do you feel this is really twenty
or twenty first century thing
I mean recreational cannabis
it was pretty much all THC ganja if you
analyze that it was pretty much just THC
now hashish also had other cannabinoids
because it wasn't picked for they didn't
smoke individual plants the way they do
with ganja so you could save the seeds
of the best pretty easy you just get the
most residents the biggest yield and the
best quality because you smoke it but
with hashish they collected the most
resinous plants so sometimes it was all
THC and sometimes it wasn't but Cente
were smoking resin from a field not from
individual plants nobody really knew
right and that's the that's the weird
place that we're in now as we know so
much and we continue to learn so much
that it's you know it's like peridot you
know it's just opening up a whole vortex
you know but that's interesting I
appreciate that insight in terms of like
now here's another question in terms of
terpene profile you know we you know the
Western world is landed on this gassy
diesel II cami thing you know I've seen
that in a lot of Afghan for right
Afghanistan or like you know any like a
sit role like sitar l that are that
expressed those types of traits or is
that very much do you believe in you
know just coming out of just being a
hybrid you know enough poly hybrid or
those types of in terms of land race or
those types of smells foreign to you or
they are they very familiar I'm not sure
if it is because it's a hybrid in other
words the diesel and that kind of stuff
yeah I'm not sure I don't have a deep
background with diesel so I can't really
speak of Lauren gently but but one thing
I can tell you is absolutely people
prefer high terpene contents their
particular individual trip means they
enjoy my
different for each person by absolutely
it's better and traditionally it was
hard to find because cannabis by the
time it arrived in America if it was an
important product years and years ago it
had been dried maybe in the Sun but it
would been processed
it'll be shipped really long visits so
it was no where near as terpene rich as
the varieties that we have now and when
you smoke a really rich Turkish variety
I mean there is no doubt as it's better
yeah no doubt
yeah in terms of hash you know I've
heard you say since numerous times that
terpenes can be washed away with water
are there specific varieties that you've
noticed that hold true to their terpene
profound more than others over the years
I would think Marcus knows better than
me but over here one of the ones that
was known to do that was I forgot today
but I'm sorry but Marcus and you know a
bunch of varieties that are that retain
most of their terpenes with water
process there's definitely some and I'll
never forget the first one I ever came
across was the Rene which seemed to be
some type of like like often blueberry
and Renee were mistaken for one another
they it was very dense and it grew these
just incredible I mean I'm talking like
I'm not really even sure if I've ever
smelled a terpene profile stinkier than
the original Renee I mean it was it got
people kick what's that one of the ones
with that held up against water here I
remember that it was across Osetra yeah
yeah that one did have a nice lemony
flavor it kept the smell after water
personal commotion smelled that yeah
that's again when it retains I mean I
have a list of ones that work really
well Sam I was just curious that if you
and your personal experience had had any
that where you're kind of your favorites
that's why I asked it but yeah I mean
there's a yeah there's a long list of
how about that how about that one we
made in Jamaica that time what was
trippy about that of too was the color
the cottage oh yeah ready she ready
around oldish oh yeah no I remember it
I'll never forget that hassle but yes it
had a different smell it smelled like it
wasn't you know raw marijuana or just
God yeah yeah no it wasn't it was a
contender let me tell ya it was a
contender it was so nice to have just a
big ball of it to just be like in
Jamaica loving life with a big ball of
melt just like this is good this is good
it's nice about Jamaica is you can buy
you know a kilo weed for a hundred or
200 bucks or whatever and who cares you
just grind it up and some water - yeah
yep that's I mean that's what I was
doing I was even happy to be honest once
I knew I was getting the quality that I
got with you that time I was happy to
pay 300 bucks it's like dude here's some
extra like you're doing a great job you
know I'd go visit his grow and he didn't
have one of the things I always had to
do in Jamaica in particular was ID I'd
go around the outer perimeters of the
property however big his property was
and if I because often they you know
they don't have any way of disposing
certain things and so if they were using
you know chemicals pesticides fungicides
all these nasty things on their plants
you could usually find the bottles
somewhere on the property and that
particular guy the doctor he never used
chemicals period he was hilarious
actually
he thought the bugs were there to tell
him what fruit was the safest to eat so
he was like he
pick a sugar cane and he'd be like see
the worm like this one he's like no
chemicals and then he'd cut the worm
section out and like squeeze the cane
juice by hand into a little kibosh for
me with you know like a hint of passion
fruits and a little lemon this is like
on the top of his Gro that I I took Pete
Brady they're from cannabis culture the
photographer and I took Remo up there as
well which holy smokes it was quite a
challenge to say the least good times in
Jamaica hey what's going on pop that was
cool whose dog is that
dude that's that's the hash Church
mascot what are you talking about it did
I thought he was about to drop serious
knowledge yeah he's got some serious
knowledge of jobs he's way he was he was
gonna say great hash you will make
[Laughter]
what's going on Rackham's oh can you
hear me alright I can hear you just fine
but your lips aren't moving there you go
you look like that's what you would
sound like this is the CEO himself Oh
your lips move that time that's awesome
dude right on beautiful beautiful animal
cheers Greg I love dogs welcome we're
just uh we're just kind of shooting the
[ __ ] you know I don't even know what our
conversation was about but uh welcome
I'm sure
remember stations about to get into hash
and oil glad I could be here yeah dude
for sure I'm sure most of you guys know
Rackham's have checked out his Instagram
it's been making the big hand roll like
[ __ ] Harry Potter wands of diamonds
[Laughter]
yeah something like that
you're definitely gonna be on the the
cart too of rot the past present and
future of rosin because people are
looking for that advanced tech yeah a
lot of people have been trying to reach
out to me and feel obviously you know
shout out to him for being the first
to kind of put that on the map so to
speak straight up do you know I'll never
forget the way when he first posted
those like just in a in a before he
broke them like there was a pile of them
yeah I was like what the [ __ ] is this I
was the exact same way I just couldn't
believe is like wait what's going on
here I love that about the cannabis
scene you know something can just happen
overnight where you're suddenly like
it's like okay and and you know what the
key has always been and I always say
this to people like the key is obviously
to have the passion to want to do these
things but to have the material to do it
with if you you know that's how bubble
bags really took off because I was in
this very unique position and had access
to just a stupid amount of product to
make hash with it was insane it was like
to the point where you know even when
pot was still selling for like three
thousand dollars a pound my friends
would come over with like two or three
pounds of like beautiful flower like
this isn't like you know early 2000 and
and just drop it into the 20 gallon bags
and and make a batch of water hash with
it and I was just like damn dude that
was like a like a $9,000 - chick grows
on trees the sky said there's two kinds
of folks that deal with cannabis I love
this quote those who use four clips and
those who yeah that you know what that
joke should always be told with a sound
effect in the background yeah and what
what quote was that from was that from
Howard Marks mr. nice or who did you say
said that no no some hippie dog friend
of mine oh really because Howard Marks
definitely has that in his book maybe it
was from your hippy dog friend I
wouldn't be surprised he's definitely
mentioning people that you knew I would
I figured you did I figured you did
what's that there and how are the
diamonds made oh here we go
[Laughter]
[ __ ] wands exactly I can't believe it
how do you do it buddy I mean it's
really it's really really basic I've
showed it online a little bit now I've
kind of released a tech to a certain
extent I mean I'm not sure how I'll feel
about that because he was the first one
it didn't really share probably corazon
specific reasons but I just got to the
point where it was such common sense to
me when I realized that I was done that
I just felt like I needed to share with
people it's just it's a matter of
keeping the material malleable enough to
form it in the way that you want to
there's no trick there's no magic
there's no Hogwarts [ __ ] it's just
really basic hey did you share that just
on a story or in an actual post I think
I did a time lapse post or I did I did
an actual live story in which I said and
I am yeah I'm gonna be putting that on
YouTube here pretty soon I think I'm
gonna edit it and do it proper but uh
which one is it is it um I can't
remember to be honest we do have to go
back but essentially it's just it's just
melting down you're a at a certain point
to where it's not completely 100%
carving because you got to get it to
that point to where it can liquefy and
go from that chalky consistency to the
liquid consistency and then form it
while it's cooling down but that's the
trick right you wait too long yeah it'll
just shatter all over the place you do
it too early it'll just stick all over
to everything so alright it's uh it
might be up in one of my one of my posts
on my feet might know I did a time-lapse
of the melt itself but I'm I did a live
feed a couple weeks back I saw it it was
great I just can't find it on your thing
right now okay I'm not sure if I started
there's like high times baller jars
clear domes
yeah I might not have posted it on that
part I think
we get to my phone so I could eventually
put it up on YouTube oh yeah okay
because I would a screenshot it and
shown it but yeah it's pretty damn cool
I mean you could give them the the quick
breakdown yeah I mean it's pretty set I
mean I we talking about the whole
separation process or just a diamond
part yeah I don't know do you do th see
a separation D oh no I haven't but I'd
love to hear the whole process I should
teach you separate and the battles yeah
if you want to share it brother yeah I
don't really mind at this point I mean
if you if everybody could look at my
feet essentially I mean none of people
that I follow a lot of people are
starting to pick up on it so I think
covert extracts up I think he's up in
Michigan two people on the East Coast
and Southwest everywhere start
everybody's starting to slowly pick up
on the separation process it's nice to
see do you have a youtube channel under
the same name
yeah records rajim there's not much down
there right now but there are a few
videos mechanical separate your videos
will be coming up shortly and do you
have a you have a youtube brother
yeah it's Rock'em Sock'em same thing
yeah cuz if you do a video I can help
you get a bunch of exposure by posting
it and linking it to your account yeah
definitely I definitely wanna do a
proper time-lapse educational video and
not just something me [ __ ] off you
know totally be great essentially the
mechanical separation process is is
taking perfectly good rosin and
separating it into two two fractions I
mean it's it when it comes down to its
really a consistency thing and it look
thing that father is aside from that
people you give the you give a patient
more opportunity to adjust the dose of
THC a or THC to its dirt profile so if
they don't want it much turf so you can
they can you not use as much of the turf
fraction or vice versa with the with the
THC a fraction what is absolutely GTA
yes its thta it hasn't converted over
yet
go ahead so getting the getting the
you're basically taking rosin and
repressing it and getting TD out of it
and then terms sauce yeah so it depends
on the rosin itself so if you take a 10
gram slab of rosin and it looks like
it's kind of chattery and snap and pool
that work that would work so if it
doesn't butter up the buttering up
quote-unquote process is what you're
looking for if it doesn't do that that's
that's the conversion of the actual the8
crystallizing within the rosin under my
assumption so if it doesn't that doesn't
happen in iran's and stays snap or a
shatter ii consistency it won't ever
crash quote-unquote or or separate
correct
so has to better content for it to
actually get to that stage spot and
repress it then right yep you have to
use like a 25 micron or smaller screen
only the main reason is to hold back
that curricula crystallization form of
THC a in the bag and allow the turfs to
flow out serious knowledge being dropped
on the on the I've been doing this the
fractions are what what's allows you to
really get really artful with it and I
think that's that's the exciting part
about it and you know I just checked out
your Instagram what you're doing there
Rackham's is amazing so you get it there
and you get the wrapping the rosin in a
like 25 micron or smaller screen and
then doing this super light low temp
press yep yeah they call it like a purse
percy profess I've heard that used yeah
you essentially want to you want to
bring the plate down like a hand pump
would be ideal because you can actually
control you know the pressure of it the
body people obviously have pneumatics
and whatnot but I use a hand pump always
have and always will
it's just I'd like to feel the pressure
but when you're initially starting your
process you want to have your plates
anywhere between like
a hundred degrees Fahrenheit or possibly
lower depending on how how biscuits the
rosin is if it's more like a crumbly one
X yeah you can bump up to eat a little
bit higher but I usually start around
100 100 Fahrenheit or around what's that
40-ish forty three Celsius I started
them there sorry when you said when he
said this go ahead you the terpene
profiles of the campus or the resin and
then after you've made rosin analyzed it
I'm wondering are the ratios of
monoterpenes changing do you know they
possibly are I haven't had testing to
confirm that so I don't quote me on that
but they very well possibly are because
you're rejecting heat back into that's
this whole process so Sam they they have
to be they have to be changing based on
on the just on science you know I mean
monitor all have a different yeah yeah
how long do you press that for on the
low temp with the hand pressed so now
here's the thing it all depends
obviously and within the solving this
game we have very very many variables we
all know that with with this process it
depends on how much you're pressing if
you're just pressing a couple of grams I
mean the first press could easily allow
you to be done within 40 45 minutes but
if you're pressing mean a half zip or an
ounce or or more that's gonna take you
quite some time to get all that Terp
fraction slowly removed from the process
of my process I'm usually doing about a
half ounce or more
I used my initial press can be anywhere
from an hour to 90 minutes at around 80
200 degrees Fahrenheit Wow yeah that's
just the first press and I base that off
of once again fill and other people that
I've seen that have made comments along
the way you know through the brush
progression of this whole process saying
that yeah my first press is at 90
minutes you know for such-and-such
temperature that I did the exact same
reactions like are you [ __ ] me
it's just like your your are you timing
it along the way where you give it a
press like oh yeah if you had this and
so so deed do so how what's your space
between your press press yeah so
initially what I do is I bring the plate
the top plate down to the bag and the
parchment and just make it so it's snug
just no really absolutely no pressure
just enough to hold the bag there and
start the start the crystallization
process or speed it up so to speak
because that's what's really happening
when your rosin sputtering in itself so
essentially you're putting it in the
press to force this to happen a lot
sooner just like a lot of people with
the new jar tech it's pretty much what
they're doing they're causing their
rosin the crash in a different way a lot
sooner than it would have normally just
sitting out but the first press is
usually around like I'll start it and
then around 20 minutes to a half-hour
I'll at least nowadays I've been bumping
up the printer a little bit obviously
starts it's starting to flow things are
starting to change they're starting to
sweat and it's what I like to call it
I'll bring the pressure down a little
bit up a little bit not much but like a
half a pump or so just to kind of keep
it moving
and then I'll bump up the temperature
about every half hour to 45 minutes I'll
bump it up a few to two degrees and this
is though so once again the slow process
for like if you have a rosin consistency
initially starting out that's kind of
like more of a sugary butter that's more
malleable and not so crumbly like a wax
consistency if it's it's kind of like a
thick peanut butter but still has those
crystal like sugar consistency inside
the rosin that'll work but it's gonna
take a lot longer because that's gonna
want to be forced out of the bag which
what you'll cause issues in the long run
for your terp fraction yeah the endgame
here is to pretty much hold back that
single connect cannabinoid in the bag as
long as possible and allow everything
else to flow out and before I was using
multiple presses I was using a not
multiple presses but I was I was doing
multiple presses
with multiple wraps and things like that
but now I've come to find out that I
just leave it wrapped in my single or
double wrapped of 25 micron or smaller
for the whole time period some of my
presses last six to seven hours
depending on what I do initial point you
want like very little pressure and you
ramp up everything just like if you're
pressing rosin like normal but you're
this repress process you want low
pressure low heat and gradually ramp up
over the course of obviously a couple
hours if you're pressing more than a
half step or an ounce perfect with low
pressure low heat long material
definitely in this process from my
experience I mean I've done mostly dry
cured Budd hatch rosin so to speak but I
have done live rosin my recent post if
you look at my diamond formations
they're all from made from whole plant
fresh frozen live rasa the turf the turf
profile is definitely a lot more in your
nose so to speak with live rosin
compared to hash rosin but that's
obviously because of the cure point
there the cure factor there there not
being one market my favorite rosin some
of them have been made from dry suited
or water sifted heads my eye I'm
wondering is there a way to completely
knocked off all of the resin from a
fresh plant that's frozen or something
but this I mean I've heard about you
know the nitrogen tech where but that
grinds up every it Cober eyes is
everything not only the the resin and
I'm trying to keep the the resin head
intact but liberated from the frozen
mask
I'm just they kind of thrown away
yeah I haven't seen anything that
extracts in pure form and the problem
with getting a contaminated product with
like a dry ice or a nitrogen is that you
end up with this contaminated very fresh
sort of you know head that's willing to
butter you know the head has got
moisture in the wax membrane it has not
been dried and cured and and therefore
you would really need to figure out a
way quickly
I guess maybe right into a freeze dryer
and then you know once all the moistures
removed from it you could potentially do
a variety of things but that's seemingly
creating a lot of stages - that has been
a new thing that people have been doing
people have been putting their their
fresh not fresh frozen but fresh uncured
bud buck down into freeze dryers and
freeze drying it yeah and they're
smoking it right out right out of the
freeze dryer like instantly and they
said it's some of the most amazing smoke
they've done now I've been curious about
washing freeze-dried bud I have yet to
try it but I'm gonna probably experiment
so you know I think this is really cool
that what you're sharing but also the
conversation because you know since
you've been talking there's been at
least three or four people just kind of
like in the chat room who just it's kind
of like their [ __ ] doesn't stink is how
they're acting and just mocking the Oh
600 kind of like that and in the
meantime it's like you know it's people
like yourself and soil grown and people
who are willing to experiment and play
around that will make the next great
discoveries that these same
[ __ ] will be enjoying in six
months from now so it's just funny to
see how it plays out where you get
people like just kind of mocking
belittling talking down I'm just it's
just it's just it's gonna happen let's
understand the point that like
everything that I'm speaking here isn't
isn't law you know this is just
something that I've learned along the
way that works for me I'm not trying to
preach this as as like scripture or
anything like that if something if you
can alter what I present to you in a
better form in a faster form more power
and people have done net-like covert for
example you look up covert extracts he
was able to get his
I think converted over in less than an
hour and it's it's it's clearer than
mine
so he's extracting mortar no more turf
than than I am
and he hasn't shared his tech which I
don't blame him for to certain extent
but everything that I've learned up
until this point
nobody's told me I'm doing wrong so if
it seems to help somebody else I'm I'm
just gonna keep sharing it the way that
I've been so people need to understand
that this isn't like the be-all end-all
way that I really love about the
industry is that every time something
news is introduced
there's always sit back and I think
what's next because there's always
something next it was the you know the
the pure dry sift and then and then the
the rosin and stuff like that and now
this part of it and six seven hours I'm
like I'm thinking to myself it's a long
time when there was no water sit fashion
yes that was a big one both both BHO and
water hash were made public to one
another well I'm sure on a lower level
they were both made public to people
throughout in a very small way but how
in 1999 is when if I released water hash
like to the masses and it already
existed on a smaller level but started
getting it out posting it on over
growing cannabis culture and cannabis
world and all of these different forums
and then the butane came along in the
same way and it just spread like
wildfire and I'm telling you I I
remember being around during that time
where you know not a lot of people had
good hash in 96 97 98 but I'll tell you
99 2000 2001 it was happening more and
more and more and it's it's been
happening consistently since then more
and more and more like some people that
are new to this have come in at a high
level of the industry but don't
understand how only 20 or so years ago
there was so many less people actually
playing around and making hash and it
was in that experimenting and in that
you
no experience of like having material to
play with and make cash and make dry
sift and create water hash and learn new
ways to dry it and press it wet and make
mistakes all of those mistakes led us to
where we are today so when you think
someone's doing something stupid with
cannabis and you think they're making a
big mistake you would do best to thank
them instead of mock them my two cents
and I just wanted to tell you thank you
for sure and are sharing that with us as
well awesome yeah from my perspective
guys it's kind of like music you know
music is very fluid and if you bring a
rigidness to that just like you bring a
rigidness to science and exploration
you're just you're just gonna be bitter
all the time and it's just there's
wonderful things out there embrace it
yeah I mean that's the reason that I
kind of continued with doing this this
mechanical separation process initially
I was like a lot of other people like
really what the [ __ ] the point of this
like you're ruining pretty rockin but
then I realized that one there's a
demand for it people wanted it and then
two it was started to become really
intriguing just the whole process behind
it and I felt like I was just thinking
in my brain how can I refine this
process even more like how far can we
take this that's mainly what my and my
main goal was to see how far I could
take it and I don't know further we can
take like once you separate the THC a
from from the cannabinoids I mean how
far how much farther can you take it
another question is is can you separate
other cannabinoids at certain
temperatures that's my next experiment
yeah absolutely
that's exactly what I'm saying like keep
going because honestly you know it's
it's about that exploration that's gonna
find you in that in that place that
you're standing alone and you're gonna
be like holy oh my God look at this who
has smoked all of the major cannabinoids
and all of the major Kirkuk tell you
what you want for recreational purposes
Medical is much much broader good for
recreational purposes you want the right
combination
terpenes that affects the way you want
the modulation and potentiation and
that's why I like doing the separation
because you can you can change the the
actual percentage or quote-unquote the
amount of terpene that you want to
introduce into your quote unquote but
yes you can do that and yeah I mean THC
or ta-ta if you're gonna smoke it I'm
not sure there's so much different
because dat a just converted to THC by
the act of its THC and the turkey yes
well I will be honest I did see it all
you had all those major cannabinoids you
had like CBG and you had CB and and you
had THC a and you had you had like 10 of
them or something in little jars and you
had terpenes as well and that was crazy
for me because that was like 2000 2001
and I was like and I've never seen
anything like that I was really just
like just started extracting heads with
water and ice I was feeling pretty good
about that then I'm like over at Sam's
place going damn like [ __ ] the rabbit
hole goes way deeper than I thought like
this is some [ __ ] crazy [ __ ] like I
started on this little rock and then I
jumped off I was like oh that's a big
jump and then Sam was like here jump
with me and we jumped into the Grand
Canyon now the to get the rosin that
you're gonna be repressing for that
length of time
what do you press flower live live fresh
frozen bubble hash or a cured bubble
hash and what did you what do you do
with that is it a long low temp press as
well so you get the butter out or what's
your process with that to make that the
the rosin you're going to be separating
on the next press so are you talking
about the initial rosin
and the type of rosin night we're gonna
be repressing yes and the starting
material you use your choices yes so I
mean as far as compared to I've had this
question a lot so flour rosin dry stiff
frozen hash rosin live whole plant fresh
frozen rosin doesn't matter as long as
it butters up I tend to let my rosin
butter up on its own a lot of people
will see me do that taffy Tech [ __ ]
like kind of a whipping it and pulling
it all that is is to bring my rosin
straight off the press into the same
consistency or one even consistency and
then I allow it to sit a lot of people
are calling that cold cure now which is
just leaving it at a room temperature
cure with parchment tp'ed over it I
allowed to do its own thing and convert
because then I know it's going to work
properly in the press for the repress
process if it doesn't convert on its own
stage battery and and clear so to speak
then it won't work and that's kind of
how I gauge it also another when you
made it frozen you made it dry cept
you've made it from the bud you've made
it from from the resin Waterson or
whatever so that you can try to
eliminate some of the variables and
understand more with in other words is
there a specific process or is it all up
to the variety but why some butters I
think it's all based on the THC a
percentage or THC a content whether
that's in the flower or the rosin
however you want to put it it's all
determined on that in my eyes I'm not
100% sure but that's just what I've
noticed a flower with a higher THC a
percentage in it will more likely
guarantee you a more butter Drazen labs
to assure yourself of that then I have
not there's one even when we use dry
cannabis it's still far more than 95 96
97 % ta ta yeah and that's a good
candidate right there that can
once you press that into rosin form if
that rosin still contains that high THC
percentage you're more likely guarantee
that you're gonna be able to separate it
or with the jar tech make it crash so
like I did a little been trained for
example cannabis products frozen dried
or whatever are in fact in the form of
genes I'm talking about that's what our
lab consistently showed for years and I
agree with that
definitely you just said jar cure what's
the jar tech the jar tech is a new
process as well a lot of the kids are
getting into nowadays it's just another
form of consistency that's all it is now
I do I can mention that there have been
reports of chirping percentages upping
with charts with jar tech not much but a
noticeable amount if you go shout out to
rosna rosin Brian Brian rosin from
Colorado I think he works with the olio
team I can't quite remember but the one
that notice showed actual lab results of
terpene percentages up being in their
percentages from the raw the rosin in
its original state to the rosin after
the jar tech but that's a whole nother
ballgame in my eyes yeah that's the
heating and then reheating and my eating
and then yeah it's a Pho tech I mean but
that's that's the tech I I enjoy that
tech to be honest I wish I knew more I
think it's I think there's something to
that for a specific end goal longer on
the show I mean yeah it helps with
shelf-life and it also helps with carbon
cartridge filling man I mean and for
that end goal and I look at all these
processes and processes like what are
you trying to do with it right like out
of a rosin press you can make you know
rosin ready to be sold at a gram but if
you want to put it in a cartridge or you
want to have it in a more viscous form
through let's say you want to mix it
with salt with diamonds you know there
it just depends on what you're trying to
do and the consistency is really help
like it's like paint you know if you
want to paint with a certain consistency
you're going to
thinner paint if you're gonna have
thicker you can use oil and that that's
what I look at the all of these
consistencies like and I think what
you're saying really falls in line with
that we're you know if you're heating it
at 200 or for you know 60 minutes or
less then you're gonna hit those
consistencies but it's all cold goes
back to what Sam was kind of alluding to
you it's all cultivars to specific in
the way that that kind of does like kind
of works is really individual to how
that was kind of even goes back to the
grow you know so yeah it's the thing
about it every time it's the same same
argument every time it's just that
variable there's so many variables by
all the way back to the plant and even
how the grower grew that point no doubt
yeah so that's what I've seen personally
is that it's like if you can get
consistency and start working with
cultivars that you know really deeply
and and have a very deep understanding
of it can be your your your canvas you
know and then that's that's you know
that's exciting you know I want you to
bring up a quick topic back to like the
fresh frozen process I know a lot of
people are kind of having the
conversations as far as cure points and
things like that with fresh frozen kind
of the rule of thumb that I've been
under the assumption of is like cutting
down your plants within four hours in
getting them frozen within four hours
this kind of your quote-unquote whole
plant fresh frozen but I'm wondering if
people who have been talking about
amongst ourselves like a a two by one or
two or three day low temp cure on flower
and then freezing it to kind of burn off
some of those more volatile Terps even
though they're gonna get burned off
anyways I'm curious about what you guys
think about that because I just ran a
crop I just took five plants I let them
cure for about two days at 65 degree
with a slightly higher or spot 60 temp
60 RH humidity and then I bucked him
down and froze them I haven't washed
them yet but I'm curious to see what
people think about that process or if
that's even worth it I almost guarantee
that in some cases it will be worth it
and in other cases it won't
gotcha you will find a sweet spot for
certain plants and certain genetics and
depending on this insane amount of
variables that I couldn't even pretend
to to list off or that could that could
affect that that could you know where
it's just certain cultivars the terpene
profile whatever it is when there's too
much moisture when it's froze and it
just has a taste that it doesn't have
when you cure it out longer because I
you muted a community buddy was I meet
it the whole time no just just I was
like you guys were really kind of
listening when I anyway I said I liked
where he was going with the conversation
and that I haven't done a lot of sort of
experimenting in that range of like cold
curing for four days versus ten days
versus whatever versus freezing it like
right off off the plant like within an
hour or two but I did do a lot of dry
material I used to make a lot of dry
material bubble like you know not fresh
frozen at all fresh frozen came a few
years later and it's funny because the
reason I had no interest in making fresh
frozen was because my hash already
melted into a liquid and dripped through
the tightest of screens so it was you
know with that Renee the terpene profile
was so present even after watery water
hashing it that it was just I mean it
really was one of the main reasons that
I think bubble bags took off because I
had this very unique access to this
incredible cultivar that just seemed to
be made for the banks and I would
consistently see and and for me how I
first got into it was I made some water
hash with some isolator bags prior to
bubble bags existing about six months
prior they were maybe a month old and
I'm I finally got some material from
breeder Steve it was the shish-kabob
that washed beautifully it was Rene
asked in the sense that it just washed
beautifully it looked like caramel when
it cured if you pressed it into a block
it was just like a caramel cube it was
extremely extremely nice material to
have access to but the fresh frozen
thing to me really started fresh frozen
and micro planing were
both incredible ways to increase your
chance of a meltable melting product in
the end you know using something that
was as fresh as possible to secure as
many terpenes as possible and shredding
the head so that the oil was on the
outside of the wax membranes so when you
held a flame to it you saw that little
sizzle you saw that little bit of melt
and that's kind of what I thought that's
what my perspective was when I saw it
first happening because here I was
making stuff with very dry material and
it was so melty and so caramely and it
was basically the question I got all the
time was how do I make my hash look like
yours and I was like I the grower it's
like it's all I did was isolate the
heads you're using the same product to
isolate your heads
it's the grower and the genetics that we
need to that you need to get a better
relationship with so for me bubble bags
were like a guiding light along your
path way of learning about these things
because it could show you when you use
material that wasn't grown properly that
wasn't good enough it would show you in
the end results like oh why is my hash
sandy why isn't it sticking together
it's like Oh cuz you grew subpar pot or
someone grew subpar genetics and didn't
grow it very well
hey welcome welcome wait Cheers
Cruz sure is I'm good I'm on the I'm on
hash Church this morning oh I didn't
think he was talking to us right now
awesome I could hear you I was like -
that fresh frozen no so I'm under I'm
under the assumption that when we first
when we first cut down our plants those
heads you know speaking of them thinking
about the heads in particular like the
heads are really soft and malleable in a
sense that they're they're not they
haven't had a chance to actually the wax
membrane build a solid coating or
foundation with the cure correct say
that again
they're like the the fresh frozen heads
compared to cured cured bud heads
those are gonna be a lot softer the met
waxed membrane not as rigid as stea
cured but correct in my eye I would
think that you're talking about the
cured heads the wax membrane yeah first
I would assume it would be harder than
softer when it was cured that it was
that it would be softer when it was
fresh that it would have moisture in it
and that it was you know absolutely true
because the same variety when it's
growing on the plant sometimes the resin
almost kills oily exact week or two and
it feels really greasy better you think
about like a grape you dry it even more
and it turns in from great to present
yeah I bring that up because going back
to the pure process what's that sound
like ma'am
I said then they can be worked with and
handled easily when they're dry correct
so I'm trying to find the happy medium
between the fresh frozen and the cures
wait that's why I'm trying to do like a
two or three-day low temp cure because I
feel like in my head that those resin
heads the wax membrane will cool that
just a couple days will allow that to
kind of solidify and I'll go keep that
Terr profile of the fresh frozen to a
certain extent it's also the reason why
you want varieties will you grow them
they're so damned terpene rich because
after you've dried them and you peered
at the three months in the box gets its
operation but it's still really dirty
rich inside that wax at the truth yeah
I'll tell ya the first time I smoked
Sam's hash and it was just bone dry and
it was just like I was just like how is
this gonna have any taste it was like a
flavor explosion in my mouth
and it was the highest I ever got in the
shortest amount of time like instantly I
was just like wow like I
I'm home this is our thesis for me this
Amherst diesel from Humboldt seat of
organization holy [ __ ]
I thought originally thought it was the
cantaloupe cush it's like on the on the
vine so to speak on the stock it smells
like a ripe cantaloupe and it's Amherst
Sour Diesel
so I'm not sure what the cross is
exactly but that's what I have here with
the 2/3 de kere on it I've done a full
two week here and I've done it fresh
frozen so now this is my middle
experiment no all the processing curing
and everything of course it changes
obvious even example is become much it
changes the last week or two before you
harvest it yep it gets into that
old-school versus new-school and I
remember I can't remember his name now
he had a seed company it's crazy that I
can't remember his name
Dutch no he was an American Tony what
was Tony's company's name Sega Martha
yes okay Sega Martha so I'm puffing with
Tony in Amsterdam some years back I've
got this like beautiful sweet skunk like
you know the herb was cured and dried
for months and then the hash was cured
and dried for months and it was just
this like light powder and I had it in
Amsterdam and I was puffing it with
everyone but I puffed it with him and he
took a big hit he blew it out and he was
just like about five minutes later he
just said dude what was that and I was
like oh it was some sweet skunk dry
sniffed and he's like he's like man it's
the first thing I've smoked in like nine
days that just didn't explode like make
me cough so horribly like just razor
blades in my throat and I was like yeah
like when you when you cure out those
lighter terpenes those those first batch
that are just they're just harsh which
just seems to be what nowadays the
younger people are wanting they want all
of it fresh frozen live living in the
plants smoking it so they're just like
turning red and coughing and I'm I've
been on both sides so I see it but I
really appreciated Tony seeing it and
appreciating it and saying hey I'm
telling you that was like the most
enjoyable thing I've smoked all week
just like that's what
some nice cured resin it doesn't like
you know it's just like sometimes you
just want to have a nice a nice rim once
again it's a quiver for me I'm I don't
want to get sucked into one or the other
with cannabis I want to be able to allow
everyone within my own judgments to just
enjoy all of it to be having fun with it
you're having fun with cannabis great
you're playing around and experimenting
awesome you know
consume your own experiments don't sell
them on the open market but other than
that I think you know like when you're
doing like chemical experiments and
stuff like Horatio used to be doing the
D limonene I was always like you know
like for a long time he didn't release
that stuff it was like more like yeah
just consume your own experiments until
you figure out the first mistakes you
were making and then once you've got
that taken care of now let the general
public check it out yep
that's what's up [ __ ] great
conversation today everyone couple of
hours burned not too bad at all I
enjoyed it I think I think we'll cut it
here but maybe plan oh no weights back
we got to do some more time for weight
are you hanging with us this time wait
Nevada County I am having trouble
figuring out why my device won't let
y'all see what I'm doing this morning
but I can talk good morning good morning
we were just I was just about to wrap up
hash Church you came back in and then I
was like we're going again it's like the
life line of the show has been pumped
right back in oh thank you we want to
hear from you man what do you been up to
how are things things are pretty
exciting here in Nevada County still
trying to figure out what to do about
the fact that Governor Brown vetoed The
Compassionate Use Act which has been a
real focus of our tivity for the less
complete respect the ridiculous thing it
is a ridiculous thing and I quite
honestly what I what I and the other
folks that are helping forests are doing
is we haven't really stopped doing what
we were doing we just I can't believe
I'm saying this on show like this but
we're being more discreet about it you
can't stop doing what you guys are doing
what you guys are doing is so
instrumental to this industry in a hole
even if it's a small thing you guys in
forests are [ __ ] amazing and you guys
cannot stop yeah you guys are doing the
right the good it's it's the right thing
you're on there you're on the right side
of it so no matter what happens to me
it's just like okay well I guess a
deeper level of civil disobedience is
now required yes yes well after years of
you know breaking unjust laws she is a
phrase I kind of gotten used to trying
to figure out how to obey the rules and
how to go along with regulators and
authorities and whatnot and it's it's
just been a real strong lesson that in
the law of unintended consequences
because particularly forests put an
incredible amount of work into getting
8:29 through the legislature last year
and then to have it vetoed like that was
really messed up no such a thing like
whoo what is that like Satan just like
came up from hell and was like I'm gonna
veto this bill well all I can come up
with all I can come up with is that the
folks who are too charged with doing the
regulations in California had no way to
deal with the idea that there were
people out there who were giving
cannabis away when the law is very clear
in California at least you can't give
cannabis away even personal use cannabis
you can't give it away
Wow so that's socks dude we can give
cannabis away up to an ounce just give
it away give it away give it away
now well awesome it's not the case in
California if you're gonna obey all the
rules anyway down to a branch not under
personal use rules Sam the personal use
when marcsa as we call it the marijuana
it was called the marijuana and I don't
remember it was back in 2016 when the
new set of laws in California were
enacted they talked about personal use
and one of the things is you can grow
six personal use plants for your own use
but you literally can't give them to
anyone else in your family you can't
give it to you fam to your friends
nothing that's what the law says of
course that's not what's happening but
and my so my take on it is that the
folks in charge of regulation the Bureau
of cannabis control the Department of
Public Health and the Department of Food
and Agriculture who are the folks to do
with the cannabis regulations in
California basically said to the
governor you can't do this to us
you can't sign a law that goes totally
contrary to everything else we've been
doing for the last two years be to it
and he did that's all I can come up with
technically you maybe you are correct
because you're living there I'm not but
it makes no difference because it
somebody comes to your house and you
give them less than an ounce of
marijuana as a yeah and they take it
with them they can transport it legally
because it's their marijuana as long as
they keep their mouth shut but we're
talking about children right now are we
we are talking about children and we're
not talking about people who are getting
ounce of flowers we'll get in so there's
no to enforce it in fact if a person
just says it's their marijuana true
that's true
but particularly in the cases that I'm
talking about we're not we're not giving
anybody trim flowers or or bags of bud
they're getting oils and preparations
formulations where we take concentrated
oils and mix them into other things to
make products for the of their needs so
anyway it's a and we had a whole you
know Chain of Custody a whole group of
folk who were helping this to happen and
a lot of them are trying to get permits
and so there's this whole funny thing
going on in the work right now around
trying to what we're doing at a local
level and I probably shouldn't say this
as well we there is a thing in
California law that allows for
compassion guidance but local ordinance
has to include it so we're working on
that front right now
at the local level and at the state
level
Senate bill 37 is already in the books
and working its way through committee I
think it is Senate bill 37 which would
basically re-establish the compassion
abuse program so that's kind of where
it's at at the moment forced and I are
because of all of this craziness forced
and I have actually submitted an
application in Nevada City to do the
simplest form of manufacturing which
would allow us to do formulations and
make some of the things that we've done
in the legal framework while working
with other folks who are in the legal
framework and it'll probably be the end
of this year before we have license and
actually actually can operate but we've
started the process is that the simplest
form so are you speaking of like a type
6 or type 2 or type 7 with solvent based
type 6 with just formulations no
extractions at all God should be
reaching out to some of the folks that
have the manufacturing licenses in order
to secure some of the oils that we need
we'll be working because even in
County there's a there's not too many
people even allowed to to have those of
them under my assumption right as far as
manufacturing licenses and whatnot oh
that's totally true I'm really close to
you so I can't wait to link up I'm
actually in Placer County oh dude well
who's ray combs I don't know
Brackins yep oh you got a beautiful
speaking of children yeah no absolutely
he'll bring his Harry Potter wand over
yeah there might be things that we can
help each other on to get because I want
to continue or help continue that what
you guys are doing as much as possible
as far as veterans and children I mean
they need as much help as we can offer
so through that
yeah the BET's that's a whole nother
conversation that is [ __ ] up I don't
want to take up everybody's time but I
heard a story the other day speaking of
vets that really was infuriating and
it's a good example of how the
California regulated market is working I
met a guy a couple of days ago he's a
hundred percent disability from wounds
received in Iraq
his wife is 90 percent disability for
the same thing they have a a child who
is challenged health-wise and they live
here in Nevada County they bought
property long story short they applied
for a permit I haven't got all the
details but one of the things that
happened is be cut yeah I don't want to
let's say anyway their property was
recently reassessed for the improvements
they had made they still haven't gotten
their permit but meantime they've had to
shut down their operations there the
valuation on their home went from
300,000 to almost 500,000 which meant
that property taxes went up dramatically
right
time when they're trying to get into the
system and basically they're considering
they're looking at having to move sell
their home and move because they can't
afford the property taxes for the place
that they're in and these are a hundred
percent and ninety percent disabled
veterans with a health challenge child
basically being run out of the market
that's the way the regulated market is
working in California and a lot of it
has to do with state regulation and
local jurisdictions local jurisdictions
have all kind of a choice about how they
want to treat cannabis city in their
your city and county regulations are
regulated are like the ones you got to
jump through first correct that's
absolutely right you have to get your
permit locally before you can even talk
to the state so that's different how
they're they're approaching it out west
than they are out in the East Coast in
some respects I mean some states we call
it to check the Box state and then you
have to go to the local component and
the other ones are just pitting you know
blind tests you know which are not
healthy for anybody because people that
aren't unfit to be operating with
intentions that have nothing to do with
patients are will the ones that are
winning those license so it's it's a
double-edged sword out there you know
definitely so I see some see some Show
and Tell happening yeah my [ __ ]
camera sucks but I'm just trying to show
that before and after of what the
Diamonds kind of look like oh yeah hold
it more in the middle of the frame
mm-hmm it's not just your camera that
sucks it's your placement that's
seriously [ __ ] off bring it up in the
[Laughter]
so timeout that's your wands broken or
that's like crashed in the jar that's a
that the one's broken down so this is
the original Drazen yeah
it's hopefully a fresh frozen and then
this I wish I had a flash on here but
and then this is the top fraction mixed
with the THCA crystals or diamonds
beautiful love that amber so on that
same topic too you know I think Marcus
you and I talked about amber color
versus clear color versus caramel color
versus everything I think that's been a
conversation as well you know do you do
we do we believe that clear rosin is a
better superior product over aged amber
heads I mean for me I just agree that if
it is when I smoke it than it is and if
it isn't when I smoke it then it isn't I
don't think it's anything I think that
color has nothing to do with quality it
is oxidization of TNT sure good but that
said I'd prefer dried and cured resin so
then it can be good well yeah exactly
that's it
can I pop in here on the issue of color
yeah for most of the preparations that
we use we want the full extract we don't
want distillate distillate is really
good at concentrating certain
cannabinoids and whatnot and I I'm not
going to get into try and talk to you
guys about that but and I could be wrong
about this but our goal mostly in
securing oils that we use for the kids
we want color we want as much of the
original chemistry that was in that
plant as possible in the plant's
preparations that we're offering well in
there it is Wade you guys are doing like
serious like
real work and then generally wear this
light-colored things come from has been
you know partially the experimentation
once again which is great but also
through Instagram hype where people just
naturally seem to think and don't get me
wrong I'm I give a like every time I see
any type of hash whether it's light dark
or in-between sometimes when I have the
variety I smoke the lighter one first
and other times I smoke the darker one
first but I think it's it's part of this
cannabis thing where in in the long in
the big picture there's always division
but what you guys are doing to me is
separate from all that drama and it's
it's real it represents a real thing
which is improving the quality of life
of young sick children which is vaak
dude how do you get really than that
yeah that's that's a special moment
right there come on yeah well thank you
for that and we've just I throw it out
there because there is I see I hear a
lot of conversation about dis lived and
clear and how important it is and how
that's what's got to happen and I yeah I
kind of just am stuck with this I the
realization that we see dramatic
differences between different cultivars
identical preparation identical
manufacturing everything's the same
except the cultivar would start with and
what we end up with is different because
the chemistry and that original plant
was different and we see dramatically
different results particularly with some
of the kids with epilepsy it's just
there's I think at least part of what's
going on is there's so many things going
on in the cannabis plant in addition to
CBD and THC there's other things going
on and of course the terpenes play a
huge part in it and because we don't
know it's what it really boils down to
because we don't know what's going on
what we've worked with was what's worked
in the past and what's worked in the
past is whole plant feko as I'm told
it's called full extract cannabis oil
has a dark color it's somewhat tari
but it comes when it's clean
it works that's really what it boils
down to man we can give a child who's
seizing the wrong preparation and it's
nothing that doesn't do anything given
the right preparation and in 15 or 20
seconds the seizures stop right which
now what you just said is is an
incredible important thing to focus back
on why the industry might not need as
much distillate as there is and how it's
all caught up in saving badly grown and
poorly you know pesticide managed
material there's also a value in
monomolecular in distillation and in
mono molecular isolation of cannabinoids
because then the scientists can play
around and do their experimenting and
playing around with mechanisms and how
they work in the brain and figure or
even simply put figure out a
formulations where you know you find
something that works if you can break
down what that is you're giving them
into components you can recreate it with
the same plants doing your own
extractions making sure that the ratios
are identical every time because these
children have such a sensitivity to any
variation of cannabinoid and terpene
change that you could create the same
thing for them every time so now they
don't ever have to you know worry that
maybe is this the week that we're gonna
get medicine that didn't have that same
yeah that didn't have that same profile
so I see the value and the importance of
both of them personally and I just can't
be divided in that I had the
conversation I think it was with CC from
Eden laughs
she's quite a proponent of full-spectrum
medicine as well which I am as well I
just also simultaneously argue for the
importance of monomolecular isolates and
and distillates as well there's a full
spectrum because the clients are not
really dark in the plant it's when
they've been degraded from oxygen or
storage or tea quartier eight years
that's when they become dark yes I'm not
saying that a little bit of CBN isn't
the
some patients I'm just saying that you
know both spectrum isn't for everybody
maybe you know whatever your illnesses
probably determines what it is exactly
and it won't just be a full spectrum
it'll be a version of the full spectrum
that once was versus the footprints that
are now present from all of those
variables and more that Sam just
mentioned so that's where the value
comes into play that you know these kids
they cannot be we need to do that work
we need to figure out the ratios that
are right for the right people and then
to be able to create them cannabis-based
arrived so not going outside of cannabis
to recreate the profile but creating the
profile from specific distillation x'
and isolations that you've created that
you can now take and put together and
create exactly what was over here still
cannabis derived not [ __ ] genetically
modified plastic weird you know like
around on whatever yeah breed a variety
of cannabis for any terpene or any
cannabinoid excursion and if you brought
identical conditions every time it'll be
identical right that's a good point Sam
and yeah you know that I love this
conversation because it talks about how
you know we're demystifying a lot of a
lot of this opinion and data really is
as we're kind of talking about it what's
right for you so individual right now
that we're not even to that point like
you're talking about Marcus that we are
able to clearly give someone a roadmap
to what what an ailment might might need
for them you know to combat that you
know like oh this you need X amount of
CBG and CBD versus with a touch of THC V
and that's going to be it like we're not
we're so far from that you know but it's
it's planting those seeds now to allow
us to flourish in that way and and to
really you know get younger minds
involved in and to take it to that place
you know in the years to come but it's
you know I'm Sam I'm sure you've seen
with
with we're on your path you know great
clear oil bad clear oil great brown oil
and bad brown oil here
pure THC to my amazement and I found
this out
must have been in early 90s they'll
clear THC is clear it has no color
whatsoever and it has a sort of a thick
oily texture kind of like superglue a
drop of it on your tongue and you rub it
around it has no smell no taste
I mean whatsoever it's every cannabis
product but more concentrated it was and
always have at least a really bitter
peppery taste on my tongue wait honey
oil I see that makes sense now
pure pata as well that has the same like
the same weird distinct even though it's
not suppose to have a taste or smell
when you when you ignite THC aim just by
itself
I've noticed that you get a weird
distinct like aroma in your mouth and
taste even though you're not supposed to
it's just like it's specific to the but
there's a difference to what you're what
you're producing probably had like Sam
you're talking about lab grade tea a
Cranham yeah there will be the
difference I would almost guarantee
would be in the fact that that little
bit of extra that they're getting out in
the lab of terpenes of other things like
Rihanna you know would probably make
that difference don't currently for sure
one of the things I'd like to pop in
here with us I I'm fully in favor of the
the pursuit of THC and THC a in its
purest forms I love it very much myself
for my own use but part of what I was
trying to say here is that in the search
for fractions of the plants chemistry
just putting it out there to not forget
about or ignore all the other things
that are going on to the
in the plant that seemed to have a role
in health as versus psychoactivity and
THC of course has a big role in health
but I think most of a secret for the
psychoactive experience and there
nothing wrong with the psychoactive
experience we all love it very much or
we wouldn't be here but there are people
who actually need the cannabis plant and
as as the leading researchers in this
work that are actually doing the work I
just beg you to keep track of those
other folks that really need this plant
really needed and sometimes it can make
let's go about finding them and
isolating them and making them available
much like what Marcus was saying but for
the moment where we're at is yeah we
mostly work with full extract oils and
so much praise to all of you and anybody
that's listening that's done the work of
finding the right genetics and
concentrating them and making them
available to the people who actually
really need this plant because in fact
there are many of them and yeah I'm
gonna stop at that point and it's time
for me to have a take a bond rip mother
mother right anyway yeah like I say what
you guys have done in helping to bring
the plant into normal relations with the
world again and in that normalization
I'm just saying there's some people who
really do need the plant and let's not
forget them
so chopping up don't worry I'm on mute
well well said Wade as always we
appreciate hearing from you look at this
Marty not done yet dr. mark in the house
listen just give us 25 minutes straight
of baller chemistry drops and we'll call
it a day
I mean you know please I would love that
how you doing you're back from your
makeup dammit that means you'll be able
to close this evening with a reggae song
beautiful it was good to see you guys it
was a pleasure talking with everybody
thank you so much I'm out here scone
yeah I was wondering I wanted to ask
mark a question about the THC egg I know
I've kind of done a little bit of
research but haven't been able to
actually talk to um you know an actual
person who knows what the [ __ ] they're
talking about as far as a relation point
of THC a in particular like that
temperature point yes very slowly of
course so it's got a you know first
thing first order rate constant which
means that the the rate of
decarboxylation accelerates linearly
with temperature yeah this is all been
worked out on a very very couple nice
papers that are out there in the
literature but you'll find it like most
cannabinoids will readily start
decarboxylated like just oh no go get
him back we'll get him back or anyone
who's about to answer we lost you mark
readily starts occurring right around
the temperature of boiling water right
okay so that that's a hundred degrees
centigrade so if you're up at like about
110 or 120 you're really going to get
decarboxylation
purring but um it it's all a matter of
you know how long you have to wait right
yeah so the lower the temperature just
the longer the process occurs to be
fully completed gotcha yeah what I
noticed is that when you start
decarboxylated especially CBD it kind of
becomes almost almost like a coke you
know it'll it'll fizz like a coca-cola
right you'll just see that co2 come
bubbling out of solution and there's
definitely an end point at which it you
know no longer bubbles and yeah
connector visual point right so in that
case then if it don't bubble it ain't
worth the trouble is the same for the
decarboxylation of CBD a as it is for
full melt hashes that's gonna be my next
experiment is trying to isolate the CBD
CBD a I haven't seen too many people try
to do that was obviously it's it's not
too many people make CBD rosin or
solving this but I think that's gonna be
my next experiment is trying to isolate
CBD rosin and then isolate the CBD a out
of that I'm curious if it'll crystallize
the same way the thta does is a lot more
SAP here I think Mike's got something to
say on the subject my quest yeah so dr.
mark we were talking earlier about I
guess fractional extrusion of the
terpene fractions out of rosin using
repressing yeah that's cool so a lot of
that would tends to happen obviously we
would want when you're when extruding
the terpene fraction out of the rosin
that was pressed the first time you're
probably going to want to keep the
plates on the top of rosin press below
the melting point of the THC or CBD a oh
of course right and then you know is it
so mark I would ask you is the
difference in temperature that great
that you could actually
actionaid out the CBD a I know I'm I
primarily fractionating with chemistry
or yeah I I
I don't think so Mike I think again
those things are gonna move around the
same speed and I I'm not sure that you
can fraction eight in in like a thermal
extrusion kinda way but it's an
interesting thought because obviously I
mean these things are just due to
different chemical species so they
behave very very differently and I think
like our our theory that we long ago
proposed on past church which is that
there's some sort of steam involvement
the involvement of the moisture that's
in the material itself that has nowhere
to go but out is part of the the
thermodynamic driving force for
basically moving the oil away from the
plant material right just like the same
way that you know waters or water builds
up underneath the tire when you hide
your plane and there's nowhere for the
car to go but just sort of in a
longitudinal direction so yeah I would
really think that again part of that
could be a fractionation mechanism where
maybe what you do is you're getting in
the leading front the more volatile
component
I think the difference between THC and
CBD a TNC a and CBD a is still about you
know 10 or 15 degrees but you know I
think that you could potentially maybe
leave leave leave the THC or I'm sorry
leave the CBD a behind and push the THC
out you know but I don't know that
anyone's actually done that or just use
a CBD cultivar that has almost no THC in
it like a penny wise or chair you want
your shot my cup exactly
yeah that's wrong yeah there's a lot of
people thinking about how do you make
those those oils less hot because that
that hotness you know again the dirty
secret is as yeah you have 0.3% THC or
below in the plant but as soon as you
can
trade that oil correct goes through the
roof so there's a lot of people who are
trying to fix this this out
chromatography certainly works because
the difference in the polarity between
CBD a and THC a is sufficient enough
that you can get decent separation on
preparators promet ography so that seems
to be the way right now I thought what
we'd find is that you could somehow
crystallize the THC a and leave the CBD
a behind but that doesn't seem to work
out too well because I'm sorry
CBD prefers to Krista form crystals as
opposed to THC in an out pain
well CBD a is also a crystalline solid
but it's less crystalline than I think
THC a and I think part of the reason why
is because there's you know a rotational
degree of freedom in CBD a because
you've you unstitched that third that
the third ring right it's not a
tricyclic structure it's only a
bicycling structure and there's
rotational degrees of freedom there that
again makes it a little bit more
orderers to crystallize what's the
matter wondering at lower temperature if
you be able to make that make that crash
so to speak under mechanical separation
versus like a higher temperature with
thta or thermal extrusion as Mark put it
[Laughter]
love it I'm using it new hashtag to come
up with a scientific term and what we
chose was thermal thermal extrusion
under pressure that's awesome what of
the pure pressure units I think they got
it right away
making rosin
nice copyrighted but we should call it
stick I want to make sure everybody
knows too with the mechanical separation
that at least with my process I never go
above 200 Gries Fahrenheit ever very
very very rarely except for my final
cleanup presses when there's absolutely
no Terps left in the in the pouch I'll
do make my final steps which I didn't
happen to mention we're using a paper or
a coffee filter organic coffee filter
wrapped around the mesh of the thca and
I'll be around 180 to 190 doing really
short hard presses at that point to
exclude any leftover Terps that are
still present but I very rarely allow
the Terp fraction to ever get close to
that 150 Fahrenheit or higher thank you
you were just experimenting seeing it
get wider and wider as you pulled it out
knowing that what you were doing made
sense yep the indication because I use
the organic Brown coffee filters so
that's indication when you first put it
in there you're starting your clean up
presses that'll be really it'll look wet
quote-unquote like it'll look like it's
it's had liquid on it and you removed
that you replace that and repeat the
process it'll let it'll look less wet
less wet and then get to the point where
there's absolutely nothing left on the
mikado filter then you'd many know
you've you've excluded the Terps as far
as you can essentially a good point as
far as temperature wise and I try to
make sure that I people know that you
don't ever need to get over you know 200
degrees Fahrenheit ever for this process
you start agrees yeah as you go as the
time the six hour period
you take the temperatures up how much
intervals up to that temperature it's
like I said the initial press is about
every half hour I'll bump it up and I
use my my machines in Celsius it's not
in Fahrenheit but I bump up even those
numbers from like 40 to 45 and about 90
minutes and then after that it's about
every 20 or 30 minutes I bump it up a
couple degrees each time until I get to
about that point that it's around 170 to
eighty Fahrenheit I try to never repress
my rosin higher than what I pressed it
initially if that makes sense so you you
rockin Celsius down in Cali I bought my
plates from lid extraction in Canada and
they [ __ ] hilarious do you're like the
one American you like I don't what it
means I'm still working on it I have a
graph sit next to my press the whole
time every time I use it oh my god
because I should skin' fusing presses
are you the temperature change is just
to to to slowly like initially just to
allow the th da to crash or convert into
crystal form and then after that is more
of a more of a flow thing the hotter the
plates get the more the oil becomes
hotter and more and more flowable so to
speak so that's the only reason for the
temperature change I'm wondering oh yeah
definitely those because I'm here mark
can it can tell us I the most of all to
terpenes for an offer like 70 65 cm
we're night yeah so they're already gone
by the time you're you're done or you're
in this process what's pressing out at
that temperature is probably
monoglycerides yeah other plans
c5 yeah wouldn't bail for sure telling
it right it takes to isoprenes to make
one monitor right so I see five and
terpene is c10 and again yeah mercy and
oh so mean and some of those real very
sensitive Olive volatile monoterpenes or
probably undergoing some kind of you
know thermal degradation reaction but
definitely volatilizing you probably are
almost guaranteed guaranteed degradation
for sure
I mean let's be real yeah yeah well I
think that's what the the popcorn flavor
now you know what I'll say that I've
only remember when the rosin
came out and I was like taking pictures
and sharing it people like oh yeah burnt
popcorn I was like what are these people
talking about burnt popcorn I've smoked
a lot of Roz and I haven't smoked any
burnt popcorn and it wasn't and it
wasn't until I think it might have been
that [ __ ] press you did accidentally
Darren when we did the Celsius
Fahrenheit mistake which was what I
laughed about earlier when Darren was
asking about temperatures because I'll
never forget this is the thing about
Celsius and Fahrenheit it's as confusing
as [ __ ] it's fun I get my press from an
American company and it's in Fahrenheit
so when he asks me hey what temperature
you doing that I'm like I'm like oh like
200 or whatever like 198 210 and so he
slaps this thing into Celsius and [ __ ]
it goes up to 220 we'll do it I almost
pissed myself it was spitting rosin out
like he said it was on his shoes it was
[ __ ] dirt dude I'm telling you we had
a [ __ ] good laugh about that there
and although that sucked in the sense
that that was the [ __ ] a lot of nice
beautiful product there got ruined but
once again experimenting right you gotta
learn this [ __ ] I felt bad actually
following instructions exactly totally
did my kid my little gold pearl the lens
that the holder everything was all
covered in Raza my shirt the same [ __ ]
same [ __ ] oh yeah you did that too I
wanna press I bought this shitty ass a
PID controller that ended up being like
I was pressing it to in a degrees
Fahrenheit but in reality the peas were
were pressing almost at 300 degrees
Fahrenheit and I didn't it was not
saying that on on the actual readout so
I had no [ __ ] clue we went to go
press a half a zip of hatch and sure
enough it just started spitting all over
the place the very first press and my
buddy my it was who was gonna be my
partner in this literally that day said
nope and then I'm not doing this sake he
was over it just like two two and a half
years ago
some bad pork I had a Van de Graaff
generator I purchased two full-sized Van
de Graaff generator not a big giant one
but it was about three feet tall
I turned it on and poured a hundred
grams of resin on top of it to see what
would happen and it charged and flung
itself and stuck to all of the walls in
the whole office a hundred grams oh yeah
yeah yeah for sure I get you but still
now it's like [ __ ] I wish I had that
hundred grams that's all over the walls
my office right now that was like a
friend one of my longtime friends Ron
Hickey he had gotten disliked I think it
was like a kilo or two of this like red
oil and I can't remember where it was
from like India or something made with
hash and so he it was I guess the guy
wore it in like a it was squished in hot
into a plastic thing that went around
his body or something and so they had it
they froze it and then they opened the
thing and they had this oil and they
were trying to they wanted to put it in
a bowl but the bowl was too small it was
the biggest bowl they had so they kind
of they kind of were bending it just a
little bit and as they were doing that
it shattered and he said there was oil
everywhere like all over his kitchen
everywhere on every sing under neath of
his table got some on it he has no idea
how but that was that made me laugh to
like some of these mistakes we do holy
[ __ ] Marcus I wanted to tell you the
dispensary called Chaya Jamaica oh yes I
know the people yes and that's what they
were doing they were giving out dabs of
we're not giving them but selling absent
Rozz
that's hilarious
yeah just rosin I mean that's the only
concentrates we saw down there that's
that's the Bob Marley
that's the Bob Marley of brand isn't it
the kya it was it was such a cool place
it was a dispensary coffee shop and gift
shop you know play for that tourist
dollar and yeah there was like jerk
chicken hot sauce there that was Bob
Marley branded a lot of Bob Marley
branded stuff yeah yeah that's the Bob
Marley brand
Kyah so those are those are the people
that run that that's awesome the
University the West Indies I saw you
went to UE beautiful you know what what
an amazing spot to have aggro Hey
unbelievable yeah random [ __ ] campus
on the second floor on that tower thing
yeah I mean I think that you know I mean
trying to get a gig down there to
basically put in an extraction lab but
we're sort of still in the works of that
but I'll keep you posted on what's going
on there
beautiful well we're still we want to
talk to you up here in Canada eventually
here as well hey bring me up ready
willing and able well we'll start with a
conversation for sure but we definitely
want to you know you know Mike's working
with me on the embark project right
right right right
we both had a talk I'm definitely
getting dr. mark up here for a
conversation
I got a room set aside so fume hood
glovebox refluxing roto anything
anything else I guess we can talk out
otherwise yeah let's let's let's talk
offline yeah totally
Natacha invited me to I guess the Zen
abyss Canadian chemical society is I
guess having now a session on cannabis I
think in Toronto or are you sure in
Quebec City I'd believe a carcass I
think it's um in June sometime but again
the fact that they're actually having a
conversation about it is is is really
cool yeah might be what worth us heading
down there to Mike yeah I mean we need
to have more opportunity for chemists in
this industry and you know the fact that
the American Chemical Society and now
the Canadian Chemical Society are paying
attention to this I think is pretty
substantial because these chemical
societies are the ones that basically
author or not author but they're the
ones that basically publish research
journals and those are the kind of
research journals that are going to give
credibility to some of the Rd that's
going on in the industry so the now Sam
grouper there so I was asked to speak at
a group of what was it National
Association of scientific materials
antigen and it's all the material man
lab chem departments and bio departments
at different universities because
there's a lot of interest at those
universities to start doing research but
you know a lot of the researchers aren't
able to do the research on campus
because of the federal IND issues so
yeah I've worked with a couple of
companies that have applied to supply
NIDA but until the DEA starts actually
issuing licenses issuing licenses the
supply is kind of limited so a lot of
the University researchers are actually
doing research with independent labs but
there's I mean as as federal law changes
in as law as places abroad allow that
[ __ ] we're gonna be able to do research
at uni levels be able to create
formulated cannabinoid stuff for
double-blind placebo trials right now we
unfortunately have to do that abroad but
as laws change we will uh be doing that
research across the US as well well
fortunately I'm even we know how
biologically significant these molecules
are so the cards are stacked in our
favor because you know all these
diseases that are mediated by the
endocannabinoids system I mean these
compounds are all really important you
know in treating those diseases and so
yeah I mean question is is you know
where do you start right you know and
when the National Institute of Health
comes out and says that all human
disease is basically somehow underpinner
connected to the endocannabinoids system
you figure that would give the
pharmaceutical companies a big woody
instead you know they're basically again
trying to do the end-around on the plant
and trying to guess you know what are
the best molecules that they can patent
to basically elicit the same you know
effects that we see with the plant
derived molecule so you know I mean
cannabis we've said it before is a
medicated plant it's not a drug and so
it needs to be regulated as such and you
know all this ideas about you know
what's going on with the with the
epidemics and the CBD industry I think a
lot of people are really fed up with the
double standard that exists in the US
regulation and they're putting pressure
on their Congress members today I just
read a letter the other day that
basically is being sent to the FDA by
several key members of Congress telling
them to get their [ __ ] [ __ ] together
and stop being so vague and so ambiguous
when it comes to the regulation of
what's being allowed and what's not
being allowed because it creates a lot
of uncertain
and risk for those who are trying to get
into the industry everybody from a
mom-and-pop little artisan CBD product
to you know your multinationals who are
trying to do you know really big
billion-dollar plays in the industry I
think there's room for everybody but the
the government needs to get the [ __ ] out
of the way because right now they're
just causing a lot of uncertainty and a
lot of speculation on how they're gonna
come down on this well and here's what I
think is gonna happen yeah well multiple
candidates that have our sponsors of
different cannabis bills that are going
to be running for election so it no
matter what happens you know over the
next year and a half it's going to be a
active cannabis federal reform is going
to be a active thing whether or not it
happens before the election or after the
election you just the way that cannabis
laws are going to be in five years are
gonna be completely different than the
way they were five years ago
oh yeah so it's laws right thank you
with a lot of states a lot of the new
states that I've seen they're cut
cutting and pasting rate similar
regulations what they see is the best
regulations on the west coast the East
Coast will cut and paste a little bit
out of each state transpose it into
their codex is their legislation and
then end up passing similar bills so you
end up having a faster evolution within
the industry of the bills getting passed
but I think I don't know if we'll see
full federal legalization before the
next presidential election but I think
that you know 2021 is gonna be a
interesting year for federal law change
and when do you think that puts
everybody's opinion on when that might
change like their idea like you just
said 2021 does anybody else see it
further out or possibility for I think
that you're gonna see federal change for
medic allowing medical or rescheduling
in 2021 it's gonna take years to pass
it's it like any let that federal
legislation it's going to take you
it's you know two steps forward and then
you'll realize that one of those steps
forward you have to take a step back and
another two steps forward got it
if rescheduling happens which it's
already happened with CBD at the federal
level in the United States if
rescheduling happens then it will be a
drug
whichever compounds it is they're
claiming as a drug and that's really not
a great direction things to go in no ok
then they control it as a ingredient
exactly Marcus exactly and so I'm really
I'm a big fan of as many people as
possible being able to grow their own
and one of the beauties of hash purchase
they've grown their own they can learn
how to make their own medicine it's it's
an ongoing thing and I in terms of
helping the general of the whole
population of a poke on the planet as
well as the animals that share it with
us that also have endocannabinoid
systems I left with normalizing the
plant physically but if you look at
legalization quote-unquote as it has
happened here in California
what it is really is really legit
commercialization it's not legalization
it's legal if there is legalization in
that yeah you can have an ounce and and
as an adult the police can't mess with
of having an ounce of dried flowers so I
saw them how to concentrate but in terms
of again folks who actually need
cannabis I know I sound like a one-trick
pony here what it's a compelling need
that's the thing it's a compelling need
and when you look at legalization so to
speak how it might play out in the
United States my fear is that yes if it
goes in the right direction of
rescheduling
where would THC land on it and how are
you going to go to a drug store because
that's where drugs are available we're
going to blow out the dispensary model
and turn that into Walgreens and CVS and
these other chain stores and that level
of commercialization is coming to the
cannabis marketplace no question about
but I think for a number of years it's
going to be very complicated and
difficult because it states rights
issues and local jurisdictions and
national policy and we'll see
I mean it's come a long way in my life I
mean most of my adult life in the United
States you could go to jail for having a
joint and now it's look at where we are
now so I give thanks every day in that
way we've come so far but right here in
California which is you know we've had
legal quote/unquote cannabis for twenty
years or more
some of the folks he most need cannabis
so their supply chain has been disrupted
because of law the legalization
structure just outlawed compassionate
use cooperatives collective model and so
that's one of the ways that legalization
can play out it's it's not great that's
enough hi mark thanks for sharing wait
thank you Marcus I really appreciate the
hash Church thing you yeah whatever I
can do to add to be involved thank you
so much well I'll tell ya we're not
really even trying we nailed three hours
today we are do we just hit three hours
right now which is unbelievable man I
was gonna do an hour my wife's been
taking me for two hours anyway my son is
anxiously awaiting me right now down at
the trampoline so I want to thank
everyone for taking the time and sharing
your information and your stories and
all of you I appreciate every single one
of you and all of the people listening
and watching I appreciate all of them as
well it's fun I missed it I won't lie I
missed hashed Church so maybe we can get
another one going next week I'll put
some invites out and send some emails
and we'll see if we can't get it up it's
just a matter of putting the energy into
it it really is an energy thing if I
could just do one every week by just
sending a blast email and again
at least 10 people I would prefer it but
the Xolos caliber sometimes are pretty
damn good when we you know do a little
pre-production value in there with just
conversation and topics and people who
will be invited etc but yeah thanks
everyone if you guys want to say your
thanks I'll let you do that and then I'm
gonna terminate today's broadcast it's
too much I thanks dr. mark thanks
Rackham's house of Harlequin skunk man
Sam D 420k Johnny B everyone hears