doing this for yourself this is good oh
yeah you gotta go into Joseph with the
mentality that their yields are gonna
suck and and you're gonna work hard to
figure it out and it might take you a
long time so if you have a lot of
material go for it but if you're the
type of dude that has like a half a
pound of material and that's all you got
and you want to make shift with it
I probably prefer you learn how to make
water hash just cause it's more failsafe
you know what it also is big-time the
material that kid just happens to be the
kid that has the fire everyone thinks
they have the fire until they try to
make full melt dry sift and then they're
like what what's going on here this
isn't right like why doesn't mine look
like yours Rob would you like to take
that question why doesn't mine look like
yours top metal the red yeah I can you
guys hear me welcome
my voice is really bad today I've got a
cool so I'm not sure how this is gonna
work
Kuban that was exactly right you know if
you don't have a whole bunch of good
product to work with don't don't even
get started and he can do a little
experiment to see what's possible but
you won't really get a lot of joy and
once you got a lot to work with
yeah a lot of utter hash is very
efficient back to the old techniques
it's really efficient and easier for
people yeah and I feel like um another
thing I wanted to touch up on well not
only do I get like almost double the
yields of water house so it kind of may
say but the quality of like the 45 that
you make into rosin comes out as an
actual desirable nice yellow oil now the
thing that I realized with Keith like in
fact if you just tumble [ __ ] on a kiefer
you press it into rosin it never is
gonna be the same color as water ouch
rosin so he's gonna be a little darker
more I don't notice lower grade I would
say right so I asked somebody and what
they told me is that the oil and the
pressure it can actually each
contaminates on the way out like
chlorophyll and stuff like that and
taint the color of the rosin not
necessarily green so there won't be a
cellophane clear you know
almost translucent no color rasa right
but when you get off so when you make
the sift the only way to get a rose in
the same color and comparable to water
actually is that you gotta make it 99
now why would you ever press 99 percent
dry sift into rosin I've done it before
it's kind of dumb
you know it's just smoke to say this but
the water hash when you got 45 it's
almost like that 45 is pure as it is it
makes beautiful oil the 73 does too and
all the grades above in all those bags
so yeah if you don't have a lot of
material you get a lot more very money
higher grade you guys sound like a bunch
of a bunch of glue heads yeah we please
do if you're tasting more than naturally
there you use them too much if it's
masking everything under it is that to
say because we extracted the resins that
we were doing too much and that it was
naturally only supposed to be done the
way nature intended well here no I'm not
saying only is way nature intended
there was a reason for curing weed there
was a reason for for treating it towards
being a finished product rather than
just jumping queue and making things
aren't fresh lead voice is messed up
because I got you know cannabis cup
along began or something but I've been
trying to stay away from this stuff I
think the fact that Tony's during that
terpenes is important that he's not just
capturing and fresh frozen or whatever
or or fresh and then and then putting
them out on the market heat he cures
them out and they changed the same way
they do on the plant or in the hash in
the vial okay that could be to but let's
leave Tony out of this I was talking
about to just a general concept of what
you guys are talking about I was
forgetting you're talking about Tony's
product let's leave products out of this
and people are out of it for the moment
unless they want to speak up you know
these right here this morning so it I
just don't see this it's fascinating but
it can really
over done like anything you know and and
not all terpenes we could there's a
reason we aged our weed it became more
smokeable after a few weeks or months
depending on how you did it you could
also ruin it but you could make it
better from the point of view of smoking
you know and it is a smokeable product
now you talk about vaporizing but I'm
not a big fan of that either you know
call me old school but you know it's not
where I'm at about to stuff so I kind of
challenged the overuse of this oh this
is what I'll say against that I have a
lot of faith in my bioassay ability and
I've been curious for a long time and
I'm not in the thing that generally
aren't true I've I've been the one lead
away from things for issues that I just
felt like you know what you made that
with a weird nickel solvent and you
don't know if you cleaned it all pink
ass and because I've tried those things
felt sick from them gotten headache
turned green and so all I know about
this is it is amazing I mean I'm telling
you I [ __ ] love it I really do what
about you Cuban I want more men and I
might be a turpino I'm not a glue head
but I'm a Terp head straight up if I put
it like this so if I have hash that is
like tur P naturally the way it comes I
want I will mess with it you know what I
mean but it just it's an interesting
product to me to see that somebody can
extract us the turbine terpenes are
smell the taste the essence of the plant
into a little vial you know what I mean
like that was just cool to me hey
perfumery is an amazing amazing field of
research you know that's what I'm
talking about there and and does anybody
still have any of the Swiss flavoring
oils left like see sunny happiness track
towards that green heavy stuff got stuff
to turn the guys have for Switzerland
10-12 years ago I don't have any more
that I use I'm going to see what that
natural cannabis
from at the best rope-a-dope it wasn't
really help that it was hybrid stuff and
see what that would do as an experiment
and also like see sunny take hop scones
yeah Jake all the resin glands off of
them put some some BHO that's just pure
THC on there that's easy to get even
close to pure THC and then start
experimenting with different terpenes
off the shelf on some neutral material
material like that for we really after
the terpenes are are we after a complex
mix of things
what are we end of here I hate let's
have some double-blind experiments and
that was Dave paint last night and seen
it in years
Dave's a really smart guy and he's not
necessarily buying this terpene thing at
all and and I'm behind him on this -
there's been no science I'm not I'm with
you guys I like it - okay we back up
your a little bit let's do these things
right and still little science let's get
a double-blind experiment that shows
these effects the only thing that's been
done is cursory for work by David and me
and a few other people and and we kind
of launched this whole thing in a way
but it's trying to do some serious
experimenting and see what's really
going on the problem is that it's it's a
circular problem we know what to expect
in two repeats so that's what we get and
that's what we portrayed back onto how
what we expect from terpenes which is
what we get and it's it's not scientific
it's been itís fine so I really like to
see some better work with this is all
I'm I'm [ __ ] floor and the me and time
take it out easy with these things none
of them have been approved for for
ventilating for for breathing they're
not really proof for that just because
terpene compounds like bergamot oil are
allowed to stick on cigarettes doesn't
mean they didn't hear search just means
they wanted to sell cigarettes so you
know there's nothing here to tell us
that this to say there's nothing here to
tell us that it's effective so we all
self trate trate well works exactly
right that was radar wave for for salt
for extracts for solvent and solvent les
extracts and I mean I looked at the
terpene
results in the Emerald cup and hopefully
Alec will be here soon to talk about
those results he's with SC labs he they
tested the milligrams per grams of the
terpenes and many of the strains were as
high as as ones that had terpenes added
but they never had terpenes added they
were just a really rich full terpene
producing plants that got made into an
extract the right way to preserve those
terpenes so what I'm saying is why not
the worry for all these years that
people have been inhaling butane solvent
extracts water extracts with potential
microbials what why haven't we you know
15 years ago said let's do the science
on that why just now with terpenes you
know can i interject something because
i'd like to ask for obvious and is there
in a sense are there mechanisms in the
chemical makeup of cannabis that combat
us being exposed to light mold on import
quality Mexican or Colombian because God
knows when we were getting brick we you
know it didn't grow brown that was
rotting so obviously we were exposed and
we were all lighting our bowls with our
big lighters and you know someone from
the lab I think it was Addison told me
that that's got a trail of 8,000 PP and
butane coming off of a low temp flame
lighter when we stick it in our Bowl and
you know and and my I think mark has a
great question what is there things in
cannabis chemicals in cannabis that
could have kind of buffered that
exposure to toxicity absolutely and if
you have any faith at all in whole plant
medicines and whole plant health care
products the answer of course is yes I
mean a complex herbal remedy or complex
herbal smoking next year or whatever you
want to call it is is going to have
compounds that may very well hurt you
but very well may very well protect you
as well all you've done by making be a
chose take an extract of the glands of
cannabis what about the other 90% you
know I mean whole whole herbal healing
people who are largely behind what is
supposedly going on with medical
cannabis are in shock about extracts
like this I mean their whole plant
extracts sort of but there's no
chlorophyll
there's no hardly there's nothing that
isn't either butane or co2 soluble so
your techniques are limiting how much is
in there you're not doing any seeing
near a whole plant extract so of course
you're missing out on the possibilities
that there are things there that are
going to ameliorate the effects of
smoking cannabis that cannabis smoking
in its raw form hasn't been bad for
people it is amazing
smoking is bad but ours are bad cannabis
smoking is good this is fantastic and it
seems to do what we're looking at right
now so far the answer would be fly no
and it's a plant experiment that we've
done so far this is a shunt from that
water hash is really a whole plant
extract a lot of ways the gland heads
are in there you know they're part of
the you have some bits of leaf stock if
you will it's it's still much more a
little closer to a whole plant extract
and solvent extracts are the beauty of
solvent extracts - Rob I was gonna ask
about my deadly allergy to hemp and the
sub allergies I have to cannabis and
what could be missing why I'm not
allergic to oils I'm allergic to dry SIV
I'm less allergic to water hash I'm
deadly allergic to the flower rosin but
I'm not allergic to solve in extracts so
the argument goes both ways because when
you fractionally distill an oil into all
those fragments and you see how many of
them are when superheated become noxious
a whole plant extract where you're gonna
cook that all down I'm like I will not
for the terpene burnt content back into
your THC and call that whole I just took
it out and I can see that I want it out
of my room
because once those terpenes were heated
they all changed and they might not all
change for the better if I was trying to
standardize a product versus every time
I throw a weed in its terpene explosion
soup and it's never the same
right I can see that I'd say reishi
you're a unique case I mean most people
don't need to refine their cannabis so
that it doesn't give them allergic
responses you're close to a unique case
first time I've ever read this but I
love you it's perfectly appropriate I
thought so too until I started looking
up adverse like emergency room reactions
to hemp protein then it starts showing
up in the comments then people are like
what the [ __ ] you talking about hemp is
not allergic I almost died I had a
tablespoon of hemp protein and it was
like getting kicked in the stomach for
four hours every four minutes with a
spike so like you're saying you have an
allergy to the plant there's something
most protein most allergies are protein
based so probably something like that in
there you're not gonna have I'm not a
doctor but you know it's you don't
extract proteins in oils obviously
whatever protein here allergic to
militia chunks of microbe bacteria in
there or something or other and there's
proteins in those but you can get things
that are small but a protein in but not
cannabis proteins so that would make
sense and a lot of sift would still have
it because it's got the hand cells in
there and they have their selves so
their proteins around around you know
trace tiny amounts but for allergies as
you know it doesn't take put a molecule
really sometimes so yeah it's
interesting so for you it's perfectly
appropriate and so it'd be a
pharmaceuticals made from synthetics I
mean as far as just trying to seek
relief I would think that they'd
wouldn't cause the allergy program
problem but it's a problem that's what I
figured because I've looked at why it's
something it's not coming out nothing
organism it could be another organism
that lives on cannabis that he did his
body looks at as an attacking organism
and through an allergen antigen response
mast cell degranulation occurs and he
has an allergic response hey Rob what's
up with the Philo's project the final
project we we presented
loudly alms the edify Lois bioscience
and I presented a workshop at the
Emerald cup and basically I covered the
new taxonomy a little bit and tried to
explain how it presents a model for us
trying to figure out the evolution of
cannabis a hypothesis to hang real data
and Mowgli's project is looking at
genetic sequences the genome sequences
of so far about 1,500 dispensary samples
and seeing how they're interrelated this
is part of the project and now what I've
been looking for along with the Sam the
skunk man is getting samples of landrace
varieties the basic building blocks that
we use to make the scenes to meet
varieties we have today the hybrid
scenes medium varieties we have today
and once we have these older samples
from the 70s from before from very early
homegrown varieties pre indica Priya
Afghan pre broadleaf drug varieties then
we'll be able to put a time sense on
this and see some of the beginning of
the evolutionary ideas corroborating
some of the history we know but it'll be
interesting too to be able to click on
your sample for instance in the database
and see how it's related to other
samples in the database and how it was
related to ancestrally see if your
hybrid variety has tie or Colombian or
african and things like that
so that's the type of thing that one of
the things you can do with a sort of
genome data
yes that's what I'm interested in I'm
interested in the evolutionary questions
it might also genome work might also be
really interesting for terpene reading
because terpene breeding is difficult at
least in comparison to cannabinoid
breeding cannabinoids are basically a
linear chain of synthesis you
cannabidiol the and THC they're both
from the same precursor that's about the
only split in the pathway that we
deal with it on a daily basis we know
the enzymes for each of these steps
there there are multiple alleles of some
of these enzymatic steps but they're
pretty well understood they're easy to
breed for potency super easy to breed
for your breeding for one one allele and
against another allele so it's just it's
very simple but terpenes are much more
complicated they start with a number of
basic molecules they have ramified
pathways controlled by lots of enzymes
and more importantly there are lots of
changes in the synthesis that are non
enzymatic they happen due to heat and
time and things like this so it's it's
just a much more difficult thing to deal
with and I think we see Suites of
terpenes come through inbreeding but
they would be analogous to one branch of
this complicated synthesis biosynthesis
pathways and those seem to be pretty
reproducible in varieties we've also
lost lots of unique aromas over the
years every breeder asked you see a pop
up once and you breathe that plane and
it's just gone you know and it's it's
that and then of course you have many
many terpenes instead of just a few
cannabinoids in many varieties so then
aroma the things that you're
appreciating particularly or the effects
that come from a suite of terpenes not
just one or two that's another aspect
when you're trying to apply what you
bred to what you got and how you use it
and how it affects patients or other
users so yeah it's really complicated so
breeding can help with this it could
give it generates get up with this could
give us our markers for some of these
terpenes that we'd be particularly
interested in rare ones for instance be
able to screen huge populations without
drying them to maturity all kinds of
advances for breeding did a genome work
so maybe turkeys in your blood is that
when you're focusing on initially a
particular genetic no no no no I'm only
interested in the evolutionary pathways
and what's really happened to make
cannabis what it is today and try to tie
the
into the human relationship with
cannabis instance my interest really do
you think man has been using cannabis in
conjunction how long have been using
cameras humans at least at least since
the beginning of the Holocene epoch
twelve thousand years ago ten twelve
thousand years ago I mean how much
before that really hard to say there's
there's a cursory evidence maybe some of
the fiber evidence that's been found is
actually cannabis but there's no proof
in areas but probably in the previous
warm periods before the Pleistocene the
last ice age Guinness was used as well
we don't really have any evidence of it
have you read Michael Pollan's book the
botany of desire uh yeah I kind of had a
hand at or hiding at least the cannabis
chapter sure I figured you would it was
kind of an interesting book the way he
goes back with humans and looks at these
important relationship these plants that
we've taken with us and sort of
popularized through our relationship
with them yeah I think you got a lot of
mileage out of that it's it's a
accessible narrative well-written
ethnobotany which is a field that most
people don't know much about you know
and it's the relationship both ethno
humanity with botany with plants and
it's it's like geography it's one of
these sort of all-encompassing field
sirs they all tie together there's death
note geography and geographical botany
so they're all related but they're
they're cool fields and what he did was
make this accessible to a lot of people
and not just I mean Canada's was sort of
the Gateway plan on the four chapters I
suppose but you know potatoes and tulips
and apples are important too and they
all told the same story of how humans
interact with plants and vice versa
so that's of course paper another
another thing to build on what Rob
saying is you know you have the flavor
of the resin heads that are being
produced I also noticed you know with
breeding and growing out large
populations the plant material has a
distinct flavor as well I mean I've
found strains where
the resin smells really good the plants
growing really great I harvest the bud
they smell like what I want them to but
the herb doesn't smoke right and I grew
that clone several times after that in
the herb just has a poor flavor or I've
gotten strains that produce like little
tiny little black embryos in it you know
and and those are just like you know I
grew some like landrace Cambodian stuff
it's like they're not seeds but they're
these little little tiny things and they
they'll crackle and stuff and there's
all these uh
you know not only is there the terpenes
that are going to be and we're not you
know extracts aside of course when
you're breeding for a plant that tastes
good when you smoke the herb it's the
the terpenes that are growing on the
plant everything but also the how the
plant material taste can have a good or
bad influence in my experience as well
yeah make sense Oh Rob's muted you can
unmute Rob it's it's the other 90% of
the plant besides the resins of course
it's gonna have its own flavors and
tastes and like any vegetable matter no
sorry
some are going to be bad yeah I hate
those little tiny nubs in some varieties
they're largely gone from our seats new
varieties but back in the day you get it
you think man I got a seedless button
you can't get those things out there
like little pyramids they don't roll out
like seeds they're they taste just as
bad yeah yeah yeah it's not it's not fun
especially when you get a plant that has
the terpene you know like the herbs
smell you're like oh oh yeah and then
you break it up you're like okay this is
this is totally [ __ ] for smoking herb
from it absolutely just someone just
told me I sound stoned and I said well I
hope so I've been working at it all
morning trying my best
hey Rob have you ever heard of this
compound called hashish een that this
French group has isolated no I oh it's
is fascinating paper I mean again we
talked about this in hashed Church about
how the a lot of the terpenes again
undergo all kinds of thermal
rearrangements especially when you heat
them up so you know you know what you
see in the GC and what you see at room
temperature might be two very very
different things and so this group in
France this is a really fascinating
paper I think I'd put the link in the
chat here identify this compound in in
several different samples the effect in
fact it was in all of the samples that
they tested and it's a five five
dimethyl one vinyl by cyclo to one one
hexane it's a very interesting structure
and when I look at it it doesn't look
like something that would be stable even
at you know at nail temperature or even
even at rosin making temperature and I'm
wondering if there's things actually
polymerizing in some way to make some
sort of polymerized version of this
terpene it's a very interesting you know
Turkey and it's pretty rare it's not
widely reported on in the literature and
until this group in France reported on
it I I had not really heard of it coming
from cannabis at all so this is a group
in in in France that's basically
reported this as being a volatile
constituent from many different samples
that they've looked at i I've never seen
it before
until this week I was just wondering if
you've ever seen it no I haven't yeah I
haven't seen it that's interesting I'd
like to know more about it's a terpenoid
huh yeah it's it's basically it's a
thermal and they've actually come up
with mechanisms to account for not just
this compound but several others that
are found that they found by it by their
GC analysis let me um post the link here
so you can be looking at paper maybe
well I think what will happen I mean the
the labs look for from
eight to maybe thirty terpenes not the
labs can find they're all named terpenes
they're the ones that can find standards
were there the easy ones we've done
analyses with with perfume labs also in
France years ago and they come up with
5060 terpenes and that are named and
then a whole lot of just numbered
retention time Peaks so they don't have
names for and there's lots and lots of
terpenes that don't don't have names
from their source plan or whatever and
I'm sure the harder we look in cannabis
the more we're gonna find and so
possibly unique to cannabis although
none have been found yet that I'm aware
yes that's my real question I mean
cannabis has this unique ability to
smell like almost every other plant on
the planet right I mean you got pine you
got fruits you got almost everything out
there it's how does it do that right how
is you know how is when most oranges all
smell like oranges there's no blue
blueberry orange or like skunk orange or
you know whatever may be it may be
possible but you know the people have
done a lot of breeding with other plants
as well and haven't really gotten such a
wide range of of terpenes and it's just
it's amazing to me that it I display
it's got to have unique ones to it
because there's plants that smell like
nothing else - there's cannabis plants
that are unique to cannabis in my
experience yeah those are manifestations
that happen at the genetic level that
like Rob said you know what the genes do
is the genes express proteins and the
proteins are essentially the Cellular's
machinery
that basically produces I mean proteins
or enzymes but they're also structural
in nature and they're basically creating
all the compounds including the terpenes
and the cannabinoids and and you know
like Rob said the unique thing about
about cannabis in terms of its its
terpenoids is that it's got this CB gea
synthase which preen elates
all at alba capsid which is a very
unique sort of you know
bond formation in in the plant kingdom
and that sort of creates that the
cannabinoid pathway but you know be that
as of May
terpenes are are are ubiquitous they're
in all the fruit and food that we eat I
mean people are like you know we can't
get good terpenes on the East Coast well
just open up your refrigerator they're
in there they're everywhere there's no
reason why mother nature would make a
unique set of phytochemicals for one
plant and not use them economically
throughout the plant kingdom so I mean
terpenes are everywhere they're the same
terpenes that are in mints in the same
terpenes in a lot of different varieties
it's just the mixture of those terpenes
it's like each individual molecule you
could think of as an instrument and a
different music that the orchestra plays
which is what we end up feeling is a
function of the ensemble of many many
different compounds and how they work
together and how they work with our
individual receptors in our bodies it's
not just individual one single terpene
that's why I always laugh one you know
people say pure terpenes there's no such
thing as pure terpenes terpenes are such
a wide class a molecule that molecules
we're talking about it's such a very
very small fraction of you know phyto
terpenes that are derived from cannabis
and alike it's such a very very small
fraction of the total terpenes it's like
fungi I mean they have their own goddamn
Kingdom there's a huge collection of
terpenes that don't resemble anything
like what cannabis and if you try to dab
those you'll probably get really sick
question and because this is something
that I get asked all the time and it is
are all these terpenes equal because
when I get handed co2 pens that are
clearly mixed with terpenes that may be
found on cannabis but we're not derived
from cannabis like the D limonene thing
like when when somebody handed me that
and it tasted oh yeah while tastes
better than the co2 oil did um but are
these things
I mean if we have terpenes that are
honestly derived from cannabis that's
one thing because that's what's on the
buds we smoke but if we are now smoking
you know essence of orange degreaser
from Florida chemists I
I mean I have to ponder it this isn't
the same thing is it the molecules are
the same molecules I mean again whether
or not they have some residuals from
where they came from could determine
whether or not they can be you know
sweat it out is oh that limonene came
from came from orange peels I mean you
could talk to her ratio about this some
of the low-level decontaminant or some
of the contamination products hydro
peroxides and whatnot can be noxious
materials but again I think you're just
getting it like an into larger dose it
would be like standing right in front of
the tuba and let the tuba play you just
get this huge dose of tuba as opposed to
being in the back of the concert hall
and listening to the tuba as it plays
along with the rest of the orchestra
which is a completely different
experience than sitting right next to
the tube and getting blasted out by the
tuba right really does that make sense
absolutely any I love your analogies of
music they're just exactly right but
it's it's a the Todd's also talking
about this quality in the source
material I mean certainly you can get
aromatherapy oils for more natural
sources and things and they've gotta be
better breathe than the keyboard cleaner
I mean you know there's levels of
limonene so yeah and where we're sitting
here at the Chateau level of extracts
and concentrates you know we're talking
in the cerebral levels but you got to
remember that there's a lot of people
who the best thing they can get is so
lousy co2 extract with some keyboard
cleaner put in it you know people
actually do smoke this stuff yeah it's
uh back to you know we need some
regulation so sorry get slightly
political again but we need regulation
for these things you know it's can't let
snake oil salesman runaround and
poisonous all right hey I asked Rob the
13 question about if we could use it as
indicators of encode what we're trying
to do at the Philo's project is work use
genome sequencing or shall I say
differences in the genome to genetics
genetic content of different plants
different individuals because that's so
really looking at um cannabinoids have
been used for this for a long time that
was the chemo taxonomic marker that was
first used and then lots of labs used
that and then carl hillock added to this
and indiana university in the in the
early 20th century published in 2004 and
five and one of the characters he used
besides cannabinoids and terpenoids he
use terpenoids as well and he used also
isozymes these are enzyme variations
they're the direct gene products are
nearly direct gene products of genes you
know they're that they're the molecules
that do the active work they express the
genes and he looked at variations in
those another way of chemo typing or
using chemicals to do cat taxonomy chemo
taxonomy now the new way of course is
with the genome sequencing but back to
terpenes oh they are useful
taxonomically i can't steal other
people's thunder and they haven't
managed to publish yet so I'll just hint
around but there are terpene classes
that have been identified these are
looking at the major terpenes not the
entire profile but the most prominent
terpenes in each group now should I say
or without saying too much um their
heritable it's all very interesting and
a paper will be out soon that talks
about this on the other hand for
taxonomic ease they're very difficult
for the same reasons ratio and
everybody's explaining about differences
in grow room part of grow room being odd
or cold or whatever the the profiles of
terpenes probably don't change as much
as the apps
lewd amounts but the problem with that
is terpenes are of varying volatility so
profiles change of all the monitor
fiends are gone you know okay but you're
more likely to see that you have the
same general profile least of the
prominent cannabinoids and the other
ones very more by epigenetic
environmental whatever reasons but so
we're taxonomic characters they're a
little bit dodgy now this won't be
stealing anybody's thunder and I waited
today and see if somebody from SC labs
came in but they didn't and I'm very
fascinating paper in my hand here that I
would like to share with people it's s
he was involved in so it's going to wait
for the beginner it's really a paper
primarily out of Nolan cane and Brian
Lynch is lab at RC Colorado Boulder
their genome guys and they've managed to
put together a number of datasets for
mostly drug varieties um they have a few
one Chinese Health variety won't be
broadly helped may be sort of an
out-group in the in the in the
experiment they've done a really
interesting job here it's on a cursory
level it's hard to match datasets
they're the first people to use the nlg
BLD nomenclature that the mark berlin
and i developed from carl Hilliard's
work and John Rick Portland's and others
and is interesting to see that more of a
genome look at the taxonomy rather than
just individual relationships so this is
a cool paper and steep hill did the
analyses of cannabinoids and terpenoids
in many of the samples and that was it
was taken into account also so back to
the US interpreting Xin taxonomy
it's the latest overlay of the paper it
mentions relationships rather than
general relationships rather than
fine-tuning things so that's kind of
where we're after beans taxonomy exists
papers called
genomic and chemical diversity in
cannabis just came out last week it is
boom it's put on bio bio r14 preprint
I'm not sure what journalist is actually
in this is a preprint copy to manuscript
copy all all any real friend just just
search genomic and chemical diversity in
cannabis
what's a quotes already you'll find it
it's Ryan Lynch my nch is primary author
Nolan Cain is the last author it's his
lab so yeah it's good stuff and this is
this is all these labs are giving us we
have this tremendous Mowgli and I gave
our our little presentation about
taxonomy and the finalist project and
then Mowgli nice at the next day on
Sunday on what they call the genetics
panel discussion moderated by Michael
Baucus a real smart guy and when his
colleagues Brian Lee was sitting on the
panel as well another real smart guy and
a breeder and known as chimera after
many of you and also on this panel were
some three really awesome games there's
Mowgli homes from Philo's Biosciences
John gage from University of British
Columbia and I believe I got the
affiliations right and Kevin mckernon
for medicinal genomics these are all
three more extremely bright guys and
they're all working hands-on with with
the cannabis genome I wish we'd invited
Nolan Cain as well there was a really
good level of sites on many fronts at
the emerald-cut the shoes really
refreshing to see there are a lot of
panels about serious things not just
political which is a big issue in
California right now but also the
science front what these guys basically
explained was that it's not a big search
for genes please not within this group
it's not a big search for intellectual
property there will come a time when you
can patent cannabis plants in America
and insistently already have there may
come a time before that when our
industry develops
happening system but that's not what
this is about what this is about is
making gene sequences from cannabis
excuse me gene sequences from cannabis
open source to make to bring them into
public domain this is what's happened
naturally for years and years growers
are proud breeders are proud of their
new varieties and the sharing with their
friends that instantly makes them public
domain there are very few cannabis
varieties that people have kept close to
the chest whose wives have said them 10
years ago don't give this to anybody you
know whatever all Wellman all very good
but that's not what this is about what
we're about is making it public domain
so that it's everybody is not anybody's
that meaning that it's for the entire
community and nobody can cubby hold out
and say it's mine only and that's could
be anybody that could be agribusiness
that could be Big Pharma's people choose
to call it or it could be you
you know the breeder some individual
person that's a very sticky difficult
slippery slope really it's uh takes a
lot of money to defend your intellectual
property rights through the patented
system and long and short of it if a big
company wants to steal from you can't
really outgo them anyway they have more
resources than you do so a better way to
protect us what would be presently being
called defensive intellectual property
rights protection and that is nearly
free you just submit varieties to a
group that is going to publish those
sequences any one of these groups might
be able to help you with that finalists
last slide certainly is we're also
sponsoring something called the open
cannabis project and that is exactly
that an open forum for for not only
publishing gene sequences but also
discussing sticky issues like what is it
cush for things of this nature and with
more
genetic evidence we have more more ways
to entertain this discourse about what
varieties are and it's I'd also like to
see something that's I'll suggested
openly now I don't see why not it's not
that big an idea I'd like to see a forum
set up by the the open cannabis project
that is set up like hash Church business
worked so well this is brilliant you
begin possibly with people weighing in
maybe Sam the Scott man can talk about
what Scott number one is you know some
knowns as you would say in a scientific
experiment ease into this no talk about
the haze talk about some other ones that
are older building blocks things with
histories are quite known or if they're
controversial least they can be resolved
by somebody who was there you know
something like that
so a forum like this would be good it
would keep people from getting fight to
the back of the room and once that
people see what's going on with the old
standard varieties and if you'll andreas
discussions even they didn't get into
the fuel you know you can get into the
fire you know all this stuff you guys
are all wise you know Liz doubt about so
yeah that's it that's a pretty much
intellectual property rights things some
dirt beatings and that's it
take a run to Rob's only here for a
couple more hours in flies away so he
made his flight later so he could join
us which I thought is cool so well thank
you always appreciate when you will help
bring those guys in when you help
facilitate them to be able to be here I
really do appreciate it and I know
everyone else does as well he's going to
come say goodbye to you that's great
maybe next Sunday - we'll see I hope so
and we'll try to keep the conversation
up to par for Baba Rob the high level
acknowledgments excellent very good