computer okay here we go welcome
everybody to Hash Church
3.0 episode 17 we're still going we just
can't be stopped it's uh these people
just have nothing else to do they just
need hash church we all need hash church
and so here we are on a Sunday morning
bright and early no we're not on
clubhouse right now we are on hash
church so welcome to everyone welcome to
Johnny B and etan and hemp guy and
everyone else that's going to show up
here in the near future how how the hell
are you
guys doing
good rock and
roll I'm I'm loading up a bowl and doing
the first thing we need to do this is my
first rip of the day oh Super Bowl is it
Super Bowl Sunday Johnny in this bowl it
is I got some first bounce cleaned up
nicely and hitting it on the old school
so it's kind of like old
nice lighting it with the lighter old
school style I remember doing
that I need matches thanks for the the
tip there SC man you uh the matches are
the best way of actually smoking and I
used to use the hempline all the time
but I kept going out I kept tasting the
hempwick and I was like you got to be
careful with the hemp line when you use
the lighter you got to use it and then
you
pull taste that butane and it really
really is kind of like I know um and I'm
using Remo today see Remo there's the
Ames Institute that's going to be Dr
Allison in the house balancing out all
this male
energy with some wonderful female
energy good morning this Temple flow
Rosen bubble is a killer good morning
Allison how are you doing I am
recovering from a long day of
psychedelics I can hear it in your voice
you had a really good DayDay didn't you
no no I'm at a ladyes retreat what are
you talking about Johnny
B oh no it wasn't that good what no
spiritual enlightenment was found what
everybody stayed grounded what no no so
we started the day with I um I led um a
uh a ketamine assisted uh spiritual
journey for everybody but myself so I
was the sitter and
then I don't even think we ate breakfast
and went straight into MDMA and
LSD
and enjoyed the
snow um and
that uh I think I think carried on into
really way into the
night um I think we ate a meal yesterday
maybe
like AC bradic May she did we did eat AC
bradoock made this amazing African uh
peanut soup with prawns in it um we did
eat so that was our meal for the day but
it was
a it was an interesting day you know you
get a group of
ladies it had peanuts in it yes
interesting have you ever heard of uh
staying away from peanuts before an
iwaska
trip I have not well I've heard of going
vegan um before an iasa trip but not
peanuts no my friend Sean my friend Sean
got pretty into it and he was really
focused on the diet and he started you
know creating a list of foods that
should absolutely be avoided that
through his own bio essay and man he
said that the the eating of peanuts was
probably one of the biggest mistakes he
ever did before before an iwaska trip
and I guess it just you know for
whatever reason those particular p
interacted in a bad way and just caused
him uh just an excessive amount of
purging probably the worst thing to eat
before iasa is The Musical
Fruit ah The Musical
Fruit yeah oh yeah that makes sense that
do well isn't iasa kind of like ketamine
in the sense that you usually get
nauseous I know when I was given
ketamine I was moving so fast in my
brain that I got nauseous um K ketamine
there's a difference and and I think
everyone yesterday who took all the
other drugs as well was like ketamina is
very different than any drug including
iasa um iasa can tend to cause um an
evacuation either the front the back um
and so having a diet that um uh has like
no Dairy and no and no meats can help
minimize
that evacuation process if you will but
if you're still holding on to a lot of
emotional and psychic material you're
going to purge or get nauseous either
way and I find that with ketamine
especially with my chronic pain patients
who' have been holding on to um pain and
emotional trauma on a cellular level
they tend to get nauseous and throw up
as well lot there's a lot of purging um
but yesterday thankfully nobody got
nauseous nobody threw up and it was a
really positive um beginning to the
start of the women's
retreat that's awesome that's what we
like to hear that's amazing and I'm I'm
just so glad you could pop in for a few
minutes yeah yeah well I'd hope that
like some of these other ladies would um
but like I said um I left them at like 2
in the morning um because I tapped
out well doing that many different drugs
I think they might be sleeping right now
considering it started off with the
ketamine and MDMA then yeah that's a
that's a robust day of psychon noting it
really and it was snowing so like there
was also like some snow trail walking
and some hot tubbing and some art making
and um it was we set pure intentions for
the weekend you know we started out
where we talked about like what we
wanted to achieve um and um we're
achieving
it good morning
Mark do you
consider do you consider uh Kine a true
psychedelic or is it just a very strong
depersonalization
drug well that's a really good question
Sam um for in the intent and purposes of
our Clinic you know um I would say that
it causes an ego death and that there in
lies the a property of psychedelics that
we can use
therapeutically
um I I um yeah so I think that it
depends on who you talk
to like a veterinarian probably wouldn't
say that oh yeah Academy and
psychedelic but at the aims Institute we
consider it
psychedelic it was quite PS when I used
it oh yeah I I remember going to a
psychedelic conference in Whistler that
had everyone it was the it was the whole
gamut and I think it might have been in
like the early 2000s or the very late
90s and I met a guy there who was it's a
very small community in the 90s in the
early 2000s the Psychedelic Community
was just this fraction of the Cannabis
community that would kind of travel
around and you could meet these people
and very easy to meet almost the entire
community at at a single one or two
events and I met a guy a real Tripper
and he he would he told me like by far
his favorite psychedelic experience was
intermuscular injections of ketamine and
he was literally like I leave my body I
Fly Through the Universe I can go and
and and visit planets I can I can go
around stars and I was just like I was
like holy [ __ ] dude like I thought I was
Hardcore with five grams of mushrooms
this [ __ ] is intramuscular
injecting ketamine ketamine really g a
separation of like especially I mean
some of the ladies yesterday did have
outof body experiences um some of them
you know who are more Psychonauts tended
will probably want to move forward with
an intramuscular just to experience that
real true outof Body Experience um I
can't say that any
I've done a lot of
psychedelics and ketamine is just very
different and yet and yet I would
consider it
psychedelic any uh any assistance you
would suggest for the come out the one
thing I didn't like I only did it once
and it was in her muscular uh Dr Lily's
Assistant gave it to me uh I hated the
come out it took so long because I guess
of the dosage we're given on10th of what
they give a child for uh surgery I guess
was what was administered is there any
suggestion for the come out of that
because it took so long it just was very
uncomfortable um yeah um did you take
any Zofran or any type of anti nausea
with it no no no no no we all got
nauseous during it and as about oh yeah
no no no you I always keep um uh so I
always keep some zofran on me um just a
dissolvable you know tablet of it um in
our office we give dissolvable tablets
and we also do in especially if
someone's on their journey and they and
they're starting to get really nauseous
we'll give them an injection and it
helps
[Music]
dramatically I I found that uh what
ketamine reminded me the most of was uh
PCP
it's exactly like this that and the
other and well I suppose it can be at
times but it's very much you know on its
own at times I think in terms of a of a
chemical but I agree you know my my
first time taking it I concur with uh
with Sam it was it was pretty heavy you
know it was like it was just too heavy
but the this the in the next few times
was was much more manageable because of
the you know just a lower dose it was
more accurate it was it
wasn't try this you know like it wasn't
because it was too strong that was not
uh I mean I've taken STP for God's sakes
and uh but but the the it's just a
really different High than what I
consider psychedelics you know like LSD
DMT uh you know uh all of these type of
drugs masculine suicide and they're
they're absolutely true psychedelics
without anybody's doubt whereas uh I I
have my doubts about uh uh ketamine I do
you think that people are
actually experiencing what they think
they're experiencing or do you think
it's all Just an Illusion as a result of
their egod depth do you have an opinion
I do have an opinion I think that they
really are experiencing what they're
experiencing in their mind um uh and I
think that it takes them into to the
other reality the other realm um
wherever that might be um and there's
enough people and studies that show that
um with that ego death that um they're
they're inside their unconscious
mind and but I hear what you're saying
Sam I I hear what you're saying
um if we were able in our office to use
true psychedelic you know plant medicine
um we would be using it and we're trying
but we have to start somewhere and
because ketamine does have psychedelic
properties and it does show um the
healing properties of uh for people with
trauma um and mental illness who are
seeking relief uh we have to start
somewhere so that's that's kind of our
Gateway into to psychedelic assisted
therapy on
I always called ketamine the Cadillac of
pcps well you know it's interesting I
hear what you guys were saying like I
remember in my 20s taking it at a club
in Miami and people were like don't
don't take too much because you don't
want to end up in a khole and um I
remember it was really heavy like I felt
like you know like I was my legs were
disconnected from the floor and um but
now you know as I'm older and I take it
for um like a therapeutic purpose uh I'm
actually wanting to be in that khole and
I I I want to go and delve into to my
mind so angel angel dust right Fen
cycline was always like sprinkled on
bowls or there was always the rumor
about you know weed that was laced with
Fen cycline and you like to get WETM the
late 80s yeah I I I just always I just
always Fred that if you look at if you
look at the compound itself or just the
structure of the compound that it's not
going to be it's not going to be
um it's not going to be thermally stable
and it's going to degrade right versus
vaporizing so the canabo when you heat
them up they vaporize but these things
contain nitrogens and when you heat up
compounds that contain nitrogens they
often degrade that's why all all the
psychedelics normally like the
phenethylamines are are are just water
soluble and they're they're you know
ingested and you don't necessarily need
to smoke stuff and I just remember
people like getting all spaced out
because they were sprinkling white
powder on their bowls and I'm like oh no
don't do that you know just didn't seem
right right yeah but you don't have to
do it that way you can turn PCP into a
base and use uh ethanol to soak it into
any herb yeah like like the
sophisticated dead heads who used to
drop so I remember ketaman on Grateful
Dead tour in the early 90s and I
remember specifically people who enjoyed
taking it during in the second set of
the Dead show there was always something
called drums in space and it got really
Spacey like they went into their
percussion solos and there were just
lights it was just really it was like
the most
psychedelically intense part of the show
and that's when people busted out Decay
and usually it was a um like an afrine
spray bottle like a a a nasal spray and
they take it and you'd see people like
like they'd be like this and then they'd
be like that and then you know what they
were doing and like C can you actually
smoke or vaporize ketamine I I don't
know the answer to that yeah I I don't
know Sam you know I just when I look at
the the chem so the chemical structure
of those are related so fenine and
ketamine are are not phenethylamines but
they're um so they're not like elopa and
they're not like amphetamines they're
they're actually uh uh Benzel amines and
they're they're different in that they
have just a different set of chemistry
they hit I think Allison don't they hit
the N ndma receptor and methyl de
aspartic acid receptor which has
peripheral impact on the whole central
nervous system which is why they use
these things as as animal tranquilizers
because want to say that I was young and
stupid and I'm not recommending anybody
smoke uh angel dust PCP uh it it I don't
believe there's any redeeming factor in
it whatsoever well I it's just too much
of a disassociative it's uh it's yeah so
I I I saw this news blurb where that guy
Marcus Rogan up in BC his little R&amp;D
thing is going to start looking at um
uh Vape smart like he he's he's got like
some kind of GC set up that they're
going to actually pull air through Vapes
to actually quantitate different types
of impurities and whatnot you think
they'd want to try to try that like put
little bit of PCP like on some herb burn
it or something and see like really what
comes off because I always thought just
looking at the structure I'm like man
those things are going to degrade as
soon as they heat up so all those people
who were smoking PCP laced weed again I
think it has a lot to do with the same
thing that people who smoke that
synthetic spice if you look at that
compound that compound unlike canono is
got a nitrogen in it and when those
nitrogen compounds heat up they
thermally eliminate through something
called a cop re um uh I'm sorry let's
see what is the name of that degradation
it's called a Hoffman degradation
Hoffman degradations happen with
nitrogen containing compounds when you
heat them up can't keep it from
happening you heat up nitrogen compounds
in the presence of air they degrade to
these really toxic compounds called
nitroso and nitrosamine compounds some
of the most toxic [ __ ] we know in
mankind so I mean like that that's what
those people were all freaked out seeing
Jesus on back in the day when they were
sprinkling that [ __ ] on their poles it's
funny because again I think they thought
that this wow that's really potent it's
like dude you're probably smoking all
kinds of degradation toxic degradation
products and not even knowing what
you're getting you know I I don't think
you can smoke it to answer your question
no clinical trials were ever done on any
of the Huffman compounds he he invented
I don't know maybe a hundred of them and
uh yeah that that's right but you bring
up a good point Sam so like I think most
of these because they're water soluble
um you could make just a uh a like a a
spray an internasal spray you know just
take a couple hits and you're good you
know man Mark when you start with these
like science you know experiments so
early in the morning I'm like wow I just
get hey it's new out east get I love it
I have a question a whole six hours to
be thinking about [ __ ] man go ahead
you know since we're talking about
compounds and uh as a young buck when I
was really into atis Huxley and and
reading more about what they were up to
and his whole crew I read about AMT
right and I I took it and I read when I
read about it he described it as the
rollsroyce of LSD and I wanted to just
ask the
question you know Allison what what's
your take on that and Sam and everyone
in the room as a chemical what what's
going on there um and can anyone shed
any light on that if it really is the
Rolls-Royce I didn't hear I didn't hear
what compound you were talking about
sorry
AMT AMT not DMT no
AMT I'm not familiar with AMT I'm not
familiar with it and I thought I had
taken
everything well maybe I'm the only one
um it's extremely long you got the you
got the initials wrong or something
something what does it stand for
AMT Hold On Let's uh let's let's take it
look it up um
Google
yeah we're gonna
doch um
so alpha alpha methyl
tryptamine um okay it it was described
by Aldis Huxley as the Rolls-Royce of
LSD and at a time in my life life I was
very much learning about myself okay so
in what you're saying is instead of
dimethylamine D it's Alpha methyl
tryptamine no I've never heard of it
I've had some of the other tryptamines
in other words like
d yeah I've never seen a a no neither
have I but now I want to try it it was
very very intense and long and I I've
taken it a few more than a few times and
I just you know I've had a couple times
with a close friend of mine and you know
we we'd make music on this stuff and and
I just remember him looking at me being
like is this forever you know at one
point it was so long abnormally long
when you smoke it does it smell and
taste better than DMT which smells like
burning plastic or burning metal so what
the way that we did it you know the this
was not control was not controlled at
the time when we were getting this stuff
so we would makeing we would you know
really study the dosage and we would get
it and make pills out of it and take it
that way and the onset was a much
cleaner version of coming an cleaner
onset than I'd ever seen from any other
substance like this and it was a very
clear almost unbelievably psychedelic
experience but you're very cognitive and
and um you're riding that line of like
surrealism and you say it lasted a long
time because DNT oh if you smoke it it
doesn't last 15 minutes I mean it's
really fast right this is like huge
Peaks and valleys and and very expansive
um yeah I started to understand what AIS
Huxley was talking about immediately in
the middle of it I was like wow this
guy's really knows what's up at the time
you know it was it was really incredible
but um I haven't heard much about it
since I don't really hear people talk
about it I went through a phase of my
life where I was really into these
compounds and started there was a time
when you could just order this stuff I
mean there was a time when you could
order AMT I mean DMT and and F mayo and
all these other other compounds and um
it was a very interesting point in my
life but I I think it's it was just
curious you know it was just very
curious you know I don't really hear
much about it but it was um it truly was
like you know sitting in that
Rolls-Royce if you will I started to
understand it so if DMT is the
workingman Psychedelic what would you
call this one col it the serious
overtime it's just like to well it's
like my my buddy Dan said it was like
this seems abnormally
long um you know so uh that's that's all
I it was so long ago guys it was like 20
almost you know 15 we were able to
actually access time to know if it was
an hour two hours five hours that's the
thing you would be so out of T out of
sync with time and then you'd be you
know you come in and out of these Peaks
and valleys if you will um whatever
analogy we're going to use and and you
would just be like wow it's like what
time is it like um so that's that's what
I do remember of it but it's been quite
some time since I've Revisited this part
of my journey um but yeah that's I just
you know I read about it atis Huxley was
a someone I was reading a lot about at
the time
and um him and his crew just talked
about it like hey this is the rolls rice
of LSD and I I just that all that that
that analogy always stuck with me and
you know so that's why I asked thanks
for sharing I'd never heard about that
yeah cool sweet that's pretty
cool yeah it's in it's in tal and he
he's got a a prep for it so those
chemists who want to be out there and be
Cowboys you could actually make it if
you want from from tryptamine so it has
that Alpha methyl Group which is similar
to to ndma right which has got a alpha
methyl group too as well so well it
reminded me of AMT uh I mean it reminded
me of of MDMA when we when you're the
onset is very much like that but there's
all it's like it reminds me of it was
like this hybrid of all these things and
I started to understand why they were
talking about it in that light because
you're like wow the onsets amazing wow
this is amaz like it just like all the
blocks fit it wasn't like
um you know like when you eat mushrooms
your body's like what are you doing to
yourself you know there's this this
moment of this push and pull um and that
you just I never experienced that with
with this so well I always like DMT
because when you take a big inhalation
of it before you let it out you're
already on the top of the rocket going a
million miles an hour
well said tast like
[ __ ] well well that's my question for
the for the chemical question for the
day I I did try ketamine because when I
was told it was a horse tranquilizer and
it might help with with pain and then
when Allison was talking about how it
felt disconnected I felt like I was on
the floor and I couldn't move and I was
moving at like a turtle speed minus like
I couldn't even do anything so I thought
like how can I function using this in
life so hence hash is the go-to for me
but uh well but I would tell you use
smaller amounts Johnny B yeah I'm just
curious because everybody's been talking
even about what with psychedelic we
utilize we do utilize ketamine for
chronic pain in our Clinic um and we use
what's called like troes or lozes and I
usually work with them I mean of course
it's Dr Agarwal who's the one that
prescribes it and tells them what to
take um but I work with them on a weekly
basis to make sure that like you're on
the right track and we usually start
with a quarter of a Troy so that would
be like maybe 25 milligrams I'm curious
now because between Lo I've always taken
lots of mushrooms and then like a reset
but I've never done micros and I've
always done excessive amounts of
different drugs to try and see if it
would help me but I've never done small
amounts where I can't feel it so now I'm
kind of reassessing things by listening
to people on clubhouse and talking here
I'm kind of in this whole new okay I I
take 250 milligram caps like three times
a day and and my my my my points are
getting that I'm taking too much so I'm
trying to like I've taken like resets on
days where I don't like do dabs or smoke
weed for the whole day now i' be doing
this every month and stuff like that
trying to find things that are going to
work more so I'm kind of curious about
this next step of being able to deal
with with chronic pain so um this is
great I'm gonna say can you hear me I'm
gonna say that if you're using plant
medicine and plant medicine you're able
to get it to work for you
um I would use plant medicine until you
max out on plant medicine
is and then like let's talk about adding
ketamine if um plant medicine no longer
works for
you but you have options now even with
um soloc can also help with pain
yeah was actually how
it I was going to welcome Josh into the
room I saw him just uh kind of sneak in
there how's it going
buddy very good Happy Valentine's Day to
everyone and my lovely Valentine will
probably be down here in a little bit
and um wonderful conversation this
morning so good morning Happy
Valentine's
Day love you all
happy V Day to
everybody I will be taking my wife for a
romantic walk in the forest later
tonight up and through the trees and the
snow that's my Valentine's Day plan I'm
not buying cards and flowers and candies
and chocolate teddy bears and all that
sort of you know pardon my French
[ __ ] but I am going to spend time
with her and appreciate her and
appreciate our Vibes and uh do it in
nature my wife and I are going to out to
a fancy restaurant at the drive-thru at
In-N-Out tonight so you know type of in
ins service dining that I can accompany
me during this Co yeah buddy that's
awesome that is awesome you know my
partner he gave me um the freedom to be
with my ladies for this weekend as my
Valentine's Day and he's out with his
men friends all camping and um yeah we
just try to express love every day
rather than one day of the year
you know one day we're going to have to
have our wives do an episode of hash
church and not any of us and just have
our wives on here I think that would be
absolutely spectacular just telling
stories talking [ __ ] about us Kelly
could moderate it because she's always
here and the women that are on has
church do they bring their
husbands I mean why not it'd be pretty
uh I think it would just be a fun fun
thing one day like I know I mean has
anyone ever seen my wife at Chan's wife
Dr Park's wife like Colin's wife like
you know no Sam I bet you uh I bet you
your lady would like to come on hash
church and bust out a few old Sam
stories she'd be talking about herbalism
the whole time and how i' you know pack
too many
balls you been with your wife since high
school hav't you like when you guys like
first dated and you guys have been
together ever since you guys have quite
a love story actually should tell I I
think Sam is in the same boat I mean uh
I've seen his pictures of him and his
wife they they were they were
kids 53 years 53 years that's
awesome congratulations for for her
being able to put up with you that long
seriously what3 years it will be 53
years it's 52 right now that's beautiful
Sam Wade how about Wade and
Monica she the skunk woman oh here's you
you guys
And1
here yeah I'm as
well dead
Tour 1989 I guess I'm
32 yeah wow that's awesome you guys have
had long-term relationships had a
longterm relation if you if you can't
tell Allison most of the guys on this
panel are extremely committed regardless
of what they are committed to they're
just committed we should all be
committed in fact whether it's hash or
or marriages or relationships I love it
or my wife for n years before we tied
the old nter and uh we've been together
for a really long time like almost two
decades you have to know when you're
content right isn't that like one of the
secrets of life like really
separating happiness from being content
like everything in life is just a matter
of choices and so yeah and balance I've
been you have the choice you have the
choice of being right or being happy
choose
appropriately right you have to make
compromises and you if you're smart you
have some idea of what life is going to
be with that person in five or 10 years
I mean at least uh otherwise uh yeah in
America marriage is just another
throwaway consumer item unfortunately
more than half the people who marry get
divorced did you know people who got
married were one one of the partners
consumed and the other one did not and
and those marriages never lasted right
right I mean so really want to make a
bet well well so that that I'm I'm
asking that I guess I just about to say
the same thing that that was the that my
wife does not puff if she was to Puff
she would Puff CBD to go to sleep she
does not smoke that's like my
wife CBD but does not just at this age
she's not into Delta 9 or Del you know
GCA my ex let me rephrase that so like
the marriages where one was Pro and the
other was not again or or or totally
against so those marriages never I I
know several marriages where weed
consumption was basically the reason why
the marriage
ended my my original marriage uh which I
got married at the Cannabis Cup in
Amsterdam uh dude we were both we were
both proponents of cannabis but after we
were married a few years she stopped and
we grew apart and uh yeah it was a it
was a problem for us and it it didn't
get any better until we finally
divorced would be number one in that I
don't think we should be talking about
cannabis we should talk about how
alcohol ruins relationships but uh I
think cannabis saves relationships in my
opinion I agree I agree but you know
what I don't think I could be with
anyone who didn't use cannabis I've
tried and it just doesn't work doesn't
work well you know what's neat about
that is that people use cannabis
differently now so you can use cannabis
by eating essential amino acid Rich seed
oil you can wear hemp clothing you can
take CBD you don't have to be getting
high to be using cannabis so there's uh
you know like my wife does all three of
those things that I just mentioned but
she has no interest in in smoking
cannabis to uh alter her Consciousness
with THC she's not she's a little
sensitive to the THC but she enjoys all
of the other things so I guess in that
sense we both still enjoy you have
someone that supports you Marcus um but
when um you know like I call them like
um a square when like you meet a square
and they find out you you use between
two and five grams a day to them that is
like whoa whoa you got a problem Oh you
smoke too much or you know and that
doesn't work absolutely you know I was
talking about this recently with my wife
in regards to how you know we celebrate
our celebrations and our successes but
we don't really celebrate the Hard Road
and things that define us to becoming
who we are you know because my successes
do not Define me it's my failures it's
my difficult road that I took it's all
the bad pictures I took that create the
good ones that I take and so that is a
mentality I wish human beings had a
little bit more like you know like we
love to promote the podium and the
pedestal but we don't really promote the
whole difficult hard gnarly road that it
takes to get there and I think sometimes
you know manifesting you know that
experience where you're like a user and
the other person is not a user is all
part of that defining you know who you
are I think it's interesting that a lot
of us have been in long-term
relationships and and even like our son
sky and and then Sierra they've been
together for almost 10 years now and
they're 24 years old and uh you know I
just think it it it it is a good quality
that we have how long Wade um how long
have you been together with
Monica we're coming on uh 20 years now
um yeah I had a previous marriage with
the mother of my
children um and she and I have uh
managed to maintain being good friends
but we came to understand we just
couldn't live with each
other that was the mother of my children
um and yeah since you called me out I
wanted to jump in here and
say all this conversation about
psychedelics and all of the alphabet
soup of various compounds that inh
induced The psychodelic
Experience
um I I personally uh not that it really
matters but I personally only have
experienced with LSD and uh mushrooms
and Cactus and uh yeah they were all
quite different but the central point
that we keep making reference to has to
do with ego death and uh I would just
look at each of us in turn who have
experienced uh these psychedelics and I
don't think any of us have a shortage of
ego our egos are still present it's just
that we've come to realize that all of
this three-dimensional reality that we
live in is just a construct uh
and I I really haven't imbibed in
psychedelics
in oh probably as long as I've known
Monica uh we actually recently sourced
some highquality LSD that we're
considering uh sharing that experience
together but for years I I have tried to
remember what the Psychedelic experience
taught me and build that exper exp
erience in my head through I suppose you
could call it meditation or just really
what I do is spend a lot of time looking
at nature and things that are happening
in the garden and around us on the farm
um and trying to see where I fit into
that and where humans fit into it and
how we can work together with what we
have
to um make this world a little sweeter
place um and so I I really want to
encourage and and recommend to people
who have not tried the Psychedelic
experience to do that to because it is
it's a it's a it's a dramatically quick
way to understand the
illusion that makes our world seem so
real um and uh and to recognize the true
essence of who you are as a human being
and what the opportunity for that life
is um it just seems seems important to
recognize that all of these all of these
drugs including psychedelics really only
help us Glimpse the truth they don't
help us live it and and you have to do
that work of living what's real for
yourself uh drugs can help us see that
and that's true about cannabis as well I
mean you know I'm I'm a missionary about
cannabis and its potential benefits for
humans but what's true is it's it's an
aid
uh just like in healing one of my one of
my favorite uh analogies about healing
is that um just like healing can happen
in a hospital or as a result of taking
some prescription drug uh what's really
true about healing is it comes from
within ourselves our bodies heal
themselves and in that same way spirit
Spirit can happen in a church or a
temple or a
mosque but it really comes from within
us it's our experience of spirit that is
real it's not the church itself so uh
sorry to heavy up on you on a Sunday
morning but there's amen no amen Wade I
love you can talk all day long from this
is church we gotta get beauti thank you
I appreciate that too we consider it an
essential thing on our property did you
want to say something else Wayne just
that I feel such a deep respect for this
group of people and the platform that
Marcus has created and the way that each
of us is willing
to uh be who you are and uh feel
welcomed while doing so thank
you thank you totally well put someone
in the chat just said Wade's voice just
lifts away all anxiety I would suspect
that Allison if you're using ketamine
currently to walk people through their
Journeys you might want to look into
using Wade's voice uh for some of the
integration because man that is it's all
just Rings true and it's all love and
kind someone said it the other day Wade
comes out and opens his mouth and just
showers everyone with love and and gold
nuggets and I just I just you know
that's really funny as I'm sitting here
I'm waiting for my coffee or whatever I
shared with one of the ladies that like
you know about about Wade and how
beautiful his words come out and and how
it's easy to be drawn because it's it's
just um everything is with love and
positivity he has a war spot sorry go
ahead he has a warmth about him when he
speaks but it also it comes from a well
of knowledge it isn't just spouting
anything if you can hear the wealth the
wealth of knowledge and the depth of the
person within it is uh yeah I would
recommend having him narrate anything
you needed to do T
to tell you the truth I patented all of
that knowledge so I actually own it and
if anybody wants to use Wade's knowledge
they have to pay me
royalties thank you Sam that the only
way do you take royalties and
hash I I'll take good
karma that's you I just had someone ask
that I would go on my podcast Mike so
hopefully that sounds a little better
I've turned off the airpods and I've
turned on the raspberry microphone you
don't you don't sound like you're in a
tin can excellent well I should have
known that earlier thanks for mentioning
that uh bdnf guy I'm on my good mic
now what what are you smoking on right
now
man hey guys how are you guys doing D
you're rolling it up yeah man I'm uh
loving the conversation you guys are
getting more into the psychedelics like
every every week it's it's awesome
man I have a
little I I take uh I take uh micro doing
almost three four or five times a week
of
psilocybin and I've had a few Journeys
but uh I don't go go too much past that
as it a few times but the micro do with
the siloc cybin really is something
that's proven really beneficial to me to
to
um you know like usually I use it when
I'm really tired and and I don't have as
much patience Within Myself to be
kind um and I take the psilocybin and it
just gives me that empathy and that
understanding of kind of where I am in
the scene and so good practice it seems
to be that empathy does not lie in the
ego yeah
welcome Josh heyen I have a message for
you AC says to tell you hi love him she
said to tell you she loves you much love
and great
respect much love and great respect he
said I don't get any hellos from AC oh
and now Marcus is upset AC because you
Marcus too she said she loves you
too just say hi to from the dragon
FL uh dragon fly Josh from dragon flyer
hi is what um I'm going to have I mean
you guys are in my in my ear so she
can't actually hear you she hears me
talking to you but she can't actually
hear
you so hold on I'm gonna take my earbud
out and let her say um good
morning good morning good morning good
morning how everybody good
morning great AC good to hear from you
how was your uh how was your psychedelic
trips
yesterday oh it was
fantastic it was fantastic and you know
then there's tonight
now rinse lather repeat huh yeah well I
had never done um ketamine session like
that before and it was really different
and it was very very interesting and we
had one G who' never quite made the
connection between psychedelics and uh
medicine and healing and she made that
connection yesterday that was awesome
give thanks that's a beautiful thing and
that's that's all part of the connection
that we need in this time in this
difficult time that often wants to
connect us from the sacred and
disconnect us from our self owered place
and I
think breaks that chain right just like
the melium just like the roots just like
fungi as a whole breaks rules there's no
rules in fungi and also psychedelics
follow that line so I think it's part of
that just breaking the programming we're
in like an everyday programming of news
and food and medicine and all this stuff
and and I think it takes the power of
something like psychedelics and all the
different forms to truly break that
chain and and show us what's important
which a lot of times resides in the
heart
and yeah absolutely my attention going
in was something a little different but
where it took me was all about
connection everything you're just saying
we have lost our connection to so many
things and each other and this is a good
way to get it
back if only everyone would do it it's
funny that bands work it's it's funny
like bands like the Grateful Dead and
and fish and some other bands have kind
of figured this out that you know
there's a there's different ways to get
connections and plant medicines are
definitely on the list you know the
experiences I had particularly at fish
shows certainly weren't alcohol
influence they seem to be psychedelic
influence like lots of people just not
only looking to connect through the the
set and setting which is the show but
also that parking lot Vibe and just you
know like people just looking for that
so desperately I mean people followed
that band around for 30 plus years for
for a reason you know like not just
because because there was a hole was
something missing and when you go on
tour I felt it myself I felt like that
hole got filled I was like oh my God
these are my people like there's so many
likeminded people I can have so many
amazing conversations and experiences
and I can do it while fish is melting my
brain with a beautiful split open and
melt jam and there's all the kindness
that surrounds it the kindness the
creativity and uh just openness to to
actually meet other people and and make
those kinds of connections
and for us who didn't have access to the
drugs or the scenes I mean we heard
about the scene and that's what drove me
to shake down street was dude they've
got every drug available there's people
walk around with mushrooms and I'll be
damned if some guy isn't walk around
with a 25 gram amonita going mushrooms
mushrooms you
know don't forget
your Bo balls with armpit hairs in them
oh
yeah and your Guatemalan short and your
tie-dye
t-shirts and your your jewelry and yeah
just anything that you need to look like
a
hippie it was
great people I started at the age of 14
seeing those guys and it was just yeah I
was like whoa you know and living in
northern New Jersey it was easy growing
up in the late 70s early 80s to go see
the Grateful Dead by just traveling like
a 2hour
circled and around New York City you
could literally see hundreds of shows
and not have to travel too far but there
was like a spirit of Adventure because
you didn't always have tickets right and
you're like driving and it was before
cell phone so you're unable to hook up
with people until you got there and
unlike today it wasn't broadcasted to
the world so to be there to witness the
magic you had to be in the building you
needed a piece of a little ticket that
got you into the building and if you're
lucky like with dead and Mark will
remember with fish you actually got a
tape of the show like the next day and
you're listening to the show that you
just saw that just blew your mind and
now you have it on tape for the rest of
your life it was it was just such an
incredible adventure to to live and and
um fish had this incredible uh Crescendo
after Garcia died in '95 I think they
were certainly The Heirs app parent for
like the next Traveling Circus the next
large traveling circus they already had
an incredible body of music and they
were being incredibly creative at the
time and just like the dead they weren't
the commercial success but they let
people tour and they let people tape and
that whole Shakedown Street like when
the fish show rolled into town it was
just like the dead they needed to give
them their own parking lot there were
campers there were tpps there were just
all kinds of just this traveling circus
that would travel around and that was
part of the culture of the music and you
hit it on the head Marcus it was really
unique because if you went to like I
don't know like a Almond Brothers show
or or Neil Young there was never a
traveling circus associated with any
other band I mean I guess on the jam
band maybe at a much lower level some of
the Bands had it but you know fish had
this sort of crescend all the way up to
the Millennium and when they played
their show at Big Cypress in the
Everglades it was the largest gathering
on the planet for the Millennium the
largest gathering was the fish show that
I was at along with my lovely wife a
bunch of my friends and it was just it
was incredible because they played from
Midnight all throughout the night all
seven and a half hours yeah how many
people I think um was like 85 th000
people Marcus I I can't remember it was
a big one I I wasn't at seol but I had
Bubble Bags there and I had friends
there and Marcel brought the fish 2000
bubbler there which was like at the time
a $10,000 pipe that he like literally
said he lit and he passed and then he
didn't see it for hours and he would
just catch glimpses of it moving around
the place and then at the end of the day
at night it kind of came back to him but
that crosseyed and painless
that they did oh my God man that crossy
and painless from seal Indian
Reservation big Cyprus was uh pretty
much my favorite version of that song it
just incredible to witness the sun the
sun coming up that day Marcus was just
incredible it's like velvet sea was
right at Sunrise and you know you're
just there and you're spent but you're
you're in this new you know Millennium
and remember everyone thought like
computers were going to take over the
world or computers were going to crash
or something but um there's actually a
famous YouTube or clip Up on YouTube
that
shows Peter Jennings who was uh I guess
hosting ABC's uh rocking the Millennium
New Years and they actually cut to fish
and they do heavy things and um yeah it
just it was really surreal to be there
but the reason why I was mentioning that
is it seemed like that was kind of like
a crescendo that was hit and then after
that it was just like H like what do we
do like what could we do that would
possibly top that like
they Davis after he wrote Sketches of
Spain you know like musically it was
like the Pinnacle for him like you just
where do you go next he was like where
do I go from here you know what I mean
but then he came back and ripped [ __ ]
Brew at 42 years old and changed again
change music change the world in which
we
perceive you know GR
and and and playing a 100,000 person
event in 1973 at Watkins Glenn in New
Jersey like after 1973 you'd think oh
[ __ ] how are we going to go bigger than
that and next thing you know you make
the wall of sound which is 89,000 watt
uh you know system with every single
string on its own channel and Oley just
coming out of jail to create the largest
sound system that's ever been known to
mankind so I'm pretty sure humans are uh
you know capable of creating the new
best thing and uh I know I'm just
thankful for that creativity I want also
to add to the the Psychedelic lore that
barter fairs were really important back
in the day when I think to that year
1974 which I call buttery buttery soft
Grateful Dead is like 74 to 76 it was so
good it was they sounded so great they
were so on their game really you think
we could create that again now I mean
even when you listen to all of the music
back then Steely Dan all the mtown all
the R&amp;B stuff that was happening in the
70s dude the 70s will never be able to I
I don't think music will ever be like
that again ever again it'll be
different George Clinton in the
7s it seemed to just get distorted to
the point where now somebody you know
doesn't do a studio release or a record
they do some recording on Tik Tok and
next thing you know they're the next you
know International sensation I mean I
think what we witnessed in like the 70s
and the 80s I mean that groovy music
when you go back and listen to that I
mean all that great good Steely Dan and
all that great stuff even like through
the 80s with like bands like Los Lobos I
mean we'll never see that level of
creativ ity and really goodness in music
again I well that's what they said about
Sabbath and Zeppelin and the Beatles and
the stones and all these incredible
bands but the bottom line is is we will
it's a guarantee if you want to be like
musically blown away like truly like not
not so much the music but lyrics like
I've been tripping on this guy Harry
Mack lately I can't even say enough
about him this guy does live freestyles
he writes entire songs from the top of
his head in an instant with three words
that given to get get given to him and
he's doing it on YouTube he's doing it
on omegal it's very very different from
what you're talking about but it goes to
show that there are things that have
never existed that are just starting to
exist and if that can exist then
something else can exist you know in the
future and I I'm I have faith that human
beings are only going to get tastier and
better and I mean when I saw this young
rock band that came out I'm probably
going to forget their name but they
sounded so much like Zeppelin and Rush
have you heard these these young kids I
can't remember talk and then also like
uh Kevin Parker from uh Tam and Paulo
that kid's a a killer songwriter I mean
you know it's newer but I mean he's got
a lot of creativity with his guitar
pedals and he's a baller I mean he he
knows what he's doing and you know I
agree I think music and different ways
is going to reshape the future and look
the you know we were touching about the
wall of sound I mean think about it I
don't know if many people realize this
like the reason we have noise cancelling
microphones is literally because of the
wall of sound like we like in terms of
live music the wall of sound was the
beginning of where we're at like that
was live they the they were the first
band to really think about the live
experience in terms of why don't what do
I experience in the studio is not being
experienced to the crowd and how do we
translate that and the wall sound really
took those ideologies and they they used
brains and their their passion to get
get us where we're at today with
festivals I mean before we had any of
this stuff we had just terrible sound
and I don't I don't you know we don't
realize that said Colin that was due to
ousley I know but but again but it was
working with the band you know what I
mean like and then working with um
Macintosh in Upstate New York to to
actually design the drivers to to
amplify everything correctly I mean it's
incredible entire creation of selling
the whole entire population LSD on top
of it all really helps serious well and
a steal yourf Face logo as well as the
buckles because the first thing he tried
to do is sell me a buckle when I met him
he's like hey you want to buckle of
course that but you know there's still
musical Geniuses out there I mean go
check out this piano player uh haromi I
mean she is absolutely amazing as you
know there's prodigies and those amazing
you know jazz players that are still
Rising with each generation so you know
it's also about staying plugged in and
looking and listening because I think
what is it the average person stops
listening to new music at the age of 32
so you know you have to always be you
know reaching out I know it sounds weird
but that's a if you go look at
Psychology a lot of people cut off their
music around
3233 and everything below that for their
Generations they listen to so it's just
you know it's also about plugging in and
checking in because there's still
amazing musicianship out there that will
raise the level we're starting to see
rock music just starting to make a so
step by step that was Greta Greta Van
fleet was the band's name yeah Greta and
they're dude those kids RI I mean and
while we're on the topic of jazz we lost
an absolute Visionary uh this past week
um chick Korea chick um I mean you want
to talk about an innovator this guy
was the first person to take an electric
piano with Herby Hancock and really
incorporate that into jazz I mean that's
that's a sounds like a small feat but
that's literally like Dylan plugging his
guitar in for the first time yeah haromi
haromi did a jam with actual chick Korea
that's awesome man yeah chick is a major
inspiration to me and um we lost a
legend I mean but what will be like that
again you know like that that's what I'm
kind of like if you look at the ch
change in popular music that happened in
the three decades between the 1930s and
the
1960s and then you look at like the
three decades like that have unfolded
since today there's hardly any change
right and and I'll agree with what ATN
said is that there are incredibly
talented musicians out there one of my
current favorites right now is none
other than William apostel AKA Billy
strings Billy string is just you know
Doc Watson reincarnated Doc Watson and
Clarence white reincarnated and if you
don't know who those people are look him
up again he is a true Bluegrass player
through and through but can shred
anything and he's just an incredible
talent but it's Bill Monroe blueglass
which you know was invented back in the
you know 30s and 40 so I'm just
wondering like what's next what's the
next big thing that's GNA AR well
they're talking about Zappa in the chat
room you know there's Zappa's long gone
yet I seen dzel Zappa play Zappa Zappa
play Zappa a few years ago and that [ __ ]
tore my head off I sat in the front row
absolutely flabbergasted at the quality
of his ability to play the guitar but
also the ability to pull people from
Frank's groups into his group and and
just everything was so so on point that
uh I have an appreciation for that
FR Zappa movie that's out there right
now Marcus which one uh the the Zappa
movie that's out there there's a
documentary on Frank's Zappa I'm not
sure I've seen a few but is it like a
new one I think it's on on Netflix is it
on Netflix did you see it Sam yes I've
seen it yeah I've seen that too Mark
it's a really good one um I also rubert
NE Neeve um passed away I mean rubert NE
is responsible for pretty much every
record in existence that's been recorded
if they were in any major Studio his you
know the the the ne console was a a
mixing board that had very specific
components that allowed a very Dynamic
richness to be captured from through
microphones and um you know that was he
was a major contributor behind the
curtain to a lot of our our the favorite
records that we all listen to yeah the
first wall of sound was actually put
together in studios by Phil Spectre oh
no way that's interesting I didn't
realize that oh Phil Spectre who just
recently died that's right in
prison in prison and all his cook well
he sort of went Looney Tunes at the
end heard of you mean right before he
murdered his wife his wife or how many
people did he actually murder though
because he only got caught for
one seriously
hey how about a shout out how about a
shout out to Stevie Ray Von if we're
gonna talk about genius musicians has
you know I got catch him I got to catch
I saw him I saw him and his brother Jam
together on the Riverboat president on
the same guitar that was a when was a
short neck the other was a long neck and
they ripped that [ __ ] apart man the
whole place was just jaw dropped
everywhere wow I was gonna say a lot a
lot of it is access and and access to to
media and access to create media it's
totally changed from from the era of the
70s and the 80s and even the 90s where
every iPhone and and iPad you get has a
sound engineer system in it you know
Garage Band we could all create [ __ ]
epic music right now right there and and
then we can also put it out really easy
with a couple clicks I could put it on
iTunes and it's available and and that
has like spread out the interest and
who's listening to what and so I I think
a lot more people are listening to a lot
more diverse music and there's a lot of
people kicking ass right now and it's
really interesting and there's a lot of
influences that are being melded
and man I just you know that's just kind
of what I was thinking when I was here
and all that and like because I listen
to all the great stuff too in high
school I was listening to the the 70s
bands and [ __ ] rocking out and
thinking man there's that that was the
era of music you know people were really
meld in sound and the guitars were
ripping and and that's what we kind of
modeled our music after but then it it
changed you know because we had
influence from the stuff of our time you
know and well music has changed yeah the
stuff that's coming out right now I kind
of think is mimicking the 80s the synth
80s stuff and I I kind of love it you
know but it's meddled with hip hop and
and beats that are different than than
we had in the 80s you know that's really
cool you got people being exposed to
music that weren't being exposed to
music so YouTube has this entire culture
of reaction videos where you have people
who have never heard of these bands
getting suggestions through their
YouTube comments to go on and you know
oh you got to hear Texas Flood by Stevie
Ron if you've never heard and seen that
you just won't believe it and I've been
watching all sorts of these reaction
videos because it's just like really
unique people from where they could be
from like the inner city of Chicago or
Baltimore and they're just like hey
what's up I'm a re I'm a YouTube
reaction guy um Stevie Knight is one of
the guys I watch that I really like he's
a big kind of muscle dude and he's
always watch Jamal Mark is Kelly talking
I wanted to make sure I wasn't talking
yeah Jamal I watched Jamal Jamal's
amazing he's funny he's from South
Central LA I wanted to tell you story
really quick um I W I got to see Frank
Zappa in Chicago in
1988 and um we were out it was it was
like a in the middle of summertime so it
was a bears show and I had traded a bag
of weed to this guy he said heyy I'm
going give you a ticket you got to go
see this show it's after hours it
doesn't start till midnight and uh you
know the guy's name is Frank Zappa I was
like I don't even know who that is I
really didn't even know who Frank Zappa
was in 1988 you know I didn't know who
he was so I went into this little
underground bar and they were handing
everybody fans at the at the door so
like some of them were really beautiful
fans some of them were paper fans and
they were handing out fans and then when
we went in Frank Zappa came out onto the
stage and he said all my
fans I love all my fans look at all my
beautiful
fans and then he continued to rock the
house down for a 50 person show I think
unbelievable I really think that fish
needs to have a permanent picture of
Frank Zappa on their stage on every
single show that they play because
without Frank Zappa you know fish is
unique but wow they always prop out
Frank I mean Peaches on regalia that's
their Ode to Frank and they Crush I I
suspect if Frank ever saw them play that
he would be like he'd be impressed hey
Sam weren't you weren't you Frank
Frank's neighbor at one point
Sam yeah for several years in Laurel
Canyon uh and I I dated uh dzel uh
babysitter Christina from hot rat
in the swimming pool Frank was the only
one allowed to even jam with like Pink
Floyd they wouldn't jam with anybody but
they would let Frank come up and jam
with him well I've also heard uh Frank
play cover songs of like Jimmy Hendrick
or or Eric Clapton and Frank can just
run circles around I mean Frank was a
gen guitar player with without a doubt
I've been to about maybe 50 of Frank's
concerts at about uh maybe a similar
number of uh him just practicing he was
a true composer he was a true composers
composing no he he was a musical genius
with you know what it's hard to mention
Frank without mentioning Sun raw who was
another musical composer and if if you
don't know who Sun raw is I really you
know space is the place is his
autobiography which is absolutely
spectacular and he has quite a few
stories about Frank in that book um yeah
Sun RW spases the place so is that sort
of psychedelic Punk oh yeah it's
important big big Steve Parish Big Steve
Parish who for many years was Jerry
Garcia's roie has got a show on XM
called Big Steve hour and just last week
he was recalling uh a caller called in
and asked why the Dead never played with
Zappa and and big Steve basically said
the reason why uh Zappa didn't like the
Greatful de is because Zappa hated
cannabis yeah he hated Dr a lot of drugs
cannabis having to deal with music and
rock and roll and the fact that all rock
and roll musicians were kind of
categorized as Stoners he said the
reason why he didn't come around us any
because he couldn't deal with the level
of cannabis use and when they did come
together he was a total not social you
know kind of [ __ ] well he did like
two drugs he liked nicotine and
caffeine yeah but and
sex yeah yeah but he hated cannabis and
his cannabis use is well do or his K
hatred for cannabis use is well
documented it's it talked about in in
space as the place as well they talk
about it in the autobiography that uh
because people who played with sun raw
also played with um Frank and they had
strict rules to not hang out with not
just the Grateful Dead But a huge amount
of people and groups and musicians that
were doing all sorts of drugs because
yeah FR it it it altered his you know he
he was an OCD genius that wanted
everyone to be doing kind of you know
composing what they wanted and they were
tripping balls on acid it wasn't uh it
wasn't coming together for him I guess
Zappa reminds me of like a more
accessible John M glin um I always kind
of associated their work very similar
but he was just more accessible and was
more together in terms of the way he put
I was just gonna add the only thing
about the movie that I found a little
disappointing was you know there were so
many players in and out of the mothers
especially in the earlier years that
were [ __ ] incredible LOL George got
kicked out of the mothers because of his
drug use I mean he went on and made
little feet uh you know there's just the
the the list is endless of musicians
that were around Frank Zappa that re
don't forget Jimmy Carl Black he's the
Indian of the
group and how about a shout out for Bill
lwell shout out for Bill lwell he's got
uh I mean he's been involved in
thousands of recordings when you
mentioned John mcglocklin I immediately
clicked to Bill lwell and he got bill
John zor a lot of those guys
zor yeah the downtown you know the not
mention the stone in New York I mean um
yeah you know there's a huge down you I
was involved in the downtown scene a bit
um and I I you know those guy like I
think Bill lives in San Francisco now
and he's still doing shows um much
smaller settings but yeah an incredible
player and someone that's inspired
myself and I know that he's really moved
music forward in terms of what you're
saying Mark through the 90s I think he
held the torch in terms of experimental
stuff yeah well who takes a Miles Davis
album I know like and or who takes a bob
Marly album like I'm just gonna [ __ ]
with this and see what I can pull off of
that and that that I can't remember the
titles of thees one can't
remember one but incredible albums and
really deep you know you very
psychedelic in a lot of lot lot of
Senses i' highly recommend panoa dreams
Freedom ambient translations of Bob
Marley and dub Robbie shangar yeah I was
saying Robbie shangar he he was one that
was not okay with cannabis smoking he
wasn't okay with drugs and was
influencing the culture but but he
decided that he was going to just open
himself up to it because there was a
dream and also he had a Healer who he
had been working with his whole life
ever since he was a child and the Healer
had told him you know I do think that
you need to open up your music you know
for him and and open up your arms to
this and I think that because he did
that it really made his music so much
better so much more Rich well and he he
gave he gave us he gave music an
Incredible Gift right Nora Jones is his
daughter and she's incredible I don't
know if you've ever seen
nor yeah she is just she's
unbelievable and how about I how about
we shout outad alahaka Hussein if we're
going to shout out Ravi Shankar and his
son Zakir Hussein who is probably one of
the greatest players of the TAA to ever
walk the face of the Earth that man
brought me to tears at several concerts
that I've recorded of of uh I saw him
with the Grateful Dead back in the day I
just yeah their music really changed for
the better I I believe it became so much
more world and so much more palatable
when cannabis became sort of part of you
know the tuning of it and and he even
talks about it sort of intimately in an
interview of how against drugs he is and
how he does feel like playing with other
people under the influence did help his
music did help him actually he says
reach Shiva in a different way so that's
pretty interesting he was open like that
I would just add the opposite end of the
spectrum and just give a lot of love to
George Clinton and the P Funk Allstars
and Funkadelic and their whole influence
on the culture and spoken words Bo booty
Bo booty came from that traditional
James Brown style and then just blew the
top off with George Clinton so like by
the time we saw George Clinton in the
mid early 90s I mean that was five to
six hours straight no breaks total
Church you know just Rhythm down to the
core and and if it weren't for LSD it
would be really hard to go to one of
those shows I remember seeing him come
out on stage with a cape that just said
inhale on it just like Arms Wide Open it
was so
rad hey welcome
Debbie how's it going it's going good I
saw you on clubhouse the other day I was
like Debbie's on clubhouse oh yeah hi
Debbie hey Colin I like Clubhouse it's
fun I was on there this morning talking
about uh heavy topic should uh white
women be considered Equity under these
cannabis regulations and you know I
don't think so equality we we're working
for equality but Equity is a different
thing so oh man that's a fun way to wake
up your Sunday I saw you in that room
and I was like damn that's uh that's
going to be some heavy conversation
going on in there
it was it was fun it was fun though
yeah awesome well welcome we've been
talking about music all day we've talked
very about yeah we started out talking
about ketamine and psychedelics as we
have the ases Institute Dr Allison and
AC bradoock and some other women did
some Journeys there yesterday and I
guess they're going to go again today so
they started us out talking about every
drug but cannbis and then that kind of
led us into all of these amazing sort of
musicians and we've it's been
interesting like I'll say like once
again you know even when we're just
shooting the [ __ ] like if you want to
learn about some great musicians and
bands the last 45 minute conversation in
here dropped like I want to say 50 plus
musicians and I'm guessing not everyone
knew the names of each person that we
dropped so yeah just talking about all
these great musicians and the sort of
effects that psychedelics and cannabis
has had on these musicians and yeah just
here's my contribution uh I ate an
edible a couple weeks ago and I made a
seven hour Spotify playlist so you know
you can go get that damn I'll check that
out yeah send that to me send that to me
I'll put it up in the comment we were
talking the dead Debbie so I bet you
there is there's one or two songs on
there because as we know how beneficial
or influential the the Lots were to you
know can and to getting the message out
on canvas hell yeah I put one 11 minute
long Grateful Dead song on there and I
realized well I can't do that again
because um that's when people turn off
the playlist but
uh that's when some people turn on the
playlist that's a dark star that dark
star is too short I like alligator I put
alligator on there because that's the
ultimate um LSD recording you know like
that's the one where they were just so
high on every drug possible they're like
let us in the studio you know I love
that one like Viola Lee Blues from back
in the day too a good old Viola Lee
Blues where they hit that drop at the
end they just get right back in the room
it's just
like do you guys listen to the uh XM
channel The Grateful Dead channel on XM
they have today in Grateful Dead history
well um the last couple days they've
been playing the shows from the Filmore
East uh February uh uh uh 11th 12th 13
14th New York City uh 1970 you know and
I've had these on cassette tapes since I
was probably a sophomore in high school
so I'm going back to
1970 I don't know eight is so oh my God
to hear those in such great sound
quality is just unbelievable and the
almonds came out during uh I think it
was love light or something like that
and you could hear Greg almond singing
because Greg almond takes the mic and
you could totally make out Dwayne's
playing because Dwayne just sounds
different than Garcia it's just not
Garcia at all I mean I've been listening
to this piece of music for isn't where
the almonds really got influenced by the
dead to really go into shred yeah I feel
like that was the show well they always
had they had the two drummer thing going
on too and I think both of those bands
mutually influenced each other but if
you think about that it was such a
magical period for the dead because they
were just about to go into the uh uh
studio and record uh work in Man's dead
then you know later on in the year they
get busted in New Orleans and so now
they got to you know quickly put
American Beauty together so those two
albums came out in 1970 you know and I
was only eight years old when they came
out but um I was on tour you know just a
handful of years later and it was just
it was oh my God so so magical there
were so 1972 Vanita um Oregon Country
Fair show where they did um Springfield
creary benefit which was Ken Key's
brother um has a Springfield creamy
which is ny's yogurt which is the first
yogurt in America to have
probiotics thanks kenkey for and and
family for introducing probiotics to us
in our yogurt back in the early 70s and
then to have 20,000 people show up at
the Oregon Country Fair lot 1972 minimal
cars in the parking lot because most
people came in and school buses are
hitchhiked and it was like 110 degrees
out well that was during the gas lines
too so nobody wanted a weit in the gas
lines they're all hitel anyway Sunshine
Daydream is is the name of the show yeah
that that I think that movie is either
on Amazon or something you could watch
it I think there's clips of it on I know
the bird song is up on is up on YouTube
and again yeah that really weird you
know n completely Stark naked hippie
that's kind of like behind Jerry right
and the camera every once in a while you
get Jerry and you get this naked hippie
who's kind of like doing that sitting up
on a pole oh yeah it was what an
incredible again had those tapes for
years some of my most played cassette
tapes that I have in my collection or
the those Vita shows randomly put on my
my dcy bear scarf I don't know if you
guys can see this but I just apparently
came right in at the right time by the
way at remember all those uh Farm kids
that you that came and helped us at
cannabis Action Network like the second
generation kids from the farm in
Tennessee the movement Yeah Yeah we
actually went to the farm in Tennessee
and they made us fresh mushrooms and
fresh tofu and yeah they're great
amazing people man Stephen inae
gasin yeah Steph Gaskin actually married
me at my original wedding at the High
Times Cannabis Cup I was
there know and AA also cool because of
our Midwifery connection and anyone who
doesn't have the book spiritual
Midwifery that is a mus have book
whether you're having a baby or not
there is a beautiful stories in there of
people that took their power back and
had home births they created a whole
line of buses and school buses that went
around the country and then they finally
settled in Tennessee and created a a
thing called the farm and the farm still
functions to this day as a let's say A
Women and Children's Health Clinic along
with educational Outreach for
midwives andal healing we're not talking
about the seven tribes buses are we
those crazy brown and white buses
extremely different the 12 tribes was
the the group that got the people that
were too high that was Joshua and then
they they they comforted them with Jesus
and and Christianity and food right
the and I have to say I pulled I pulled
my girlfriends off of those buses all
the time my first modus oper Ren die was
if anybody was missing I would go and
see josu in the buses and be like all
right someone's missing and there they
would be drinking chai in the back
telling me they were having the best
experience of their life and they were
going to go home to Oklahoma with them
so you know that's also you know the 12
tribe also is a very amazing group of
self-sufficient people that creates
really good food at festivals like
Common Ground Cafe now more of the
common there's even 12 tribes up here in
British Columbia and they have places
that are really powerful so you know
it's it's it's definitely a cult a lot
of the Mustard Seed cafes and stuff are
still run by them but they're not
they're not so um a scary they're like
Earth loving Christian
anarchists I remember the common
grounders that moved into Winnipeg and
they were definitely very much the same
people that had those buses on dead tour
they like come and eat our Bakery goods
and told to stay away from those buses
oh dude I'm telling you because I wanted
to see the people that they that they
that they were able to attract same
markk I'd go in there I'd check him out
but yeah I was told the same thing
fiddle music in the
background so so
endearing
Spinners I wonder how many of those
people still are around with their
little
followings yeah I don't know you know I
would I haven't seen Spinners in a long
time but that's definitely where I would
hang out I'll say this much they
couldn't keep up with fish five and a
half hour spin one and that was pretty
incredible I feel like I entered a new
realm we talk a lot about you know drugs
and and and meditation and things that
get get you into other Realms and into
you know other lines of thinking and
spinning is unbelievably incredible and
you know the whole Sufi religion is is
sparked off of that and anyone who
hasn't anyone who hasn't taken a moment
to spin in a really big open field and
spin past where you're scared spin past
where you're dizzy and there's this
incredible calm in the center and you
know people spin to find that incredible
calm and they say that it's a place
where you can clearly speak to God and
it really is like a true place and I
found that balance so many times at at
Dead shows and I never even knew these
people I never even spoke to these
people I would just go and spin for four
hours next to them and feel this
vibration and and and find maybe some
questions that I was looking for in the
week or you know in my life between sets
at Oakland there was the Spinners and
the percussion players the percussion
players just beyond the confines of
Shakedown Street usually toward the end
they had the Disco bus you remember the
Disco bus and so the Disco bus would put
these really big speakers on top of the
bus and just blare the loudest disco
music and just attract this crowd of
really spun out people all around just
grooving disco it great man it's so
fun spun out is when you don't find the
center of the spin when you find the
center of the spin you
have you never spun
out and I think it's interesting you
know how the are you know extremely you
know they're Muslim you know and but I
think we're
they also
smoke very open to cannabis use and the
Sufi religion connection and and the
Disco bus for sure because it always
made you say yeah after the show okay
I'll have another hit because you knew
the Disco bus was gonna go on for
another four more hours and you were
safe and Tak it out killer bags of weed
were found at the Disco bus let's be
real eventually nitrous mob would find
would find the Disco bus and so then the
people would start buying balloons which
would feed the Disco bus so you'd have
all these balloonatics all sucking on
nitrous all danc in Disco it was just I
wonder how different the scene would
have been if the full melt bubble could
have been there on the early Grateful
Dead
days they never had it there was there
was there was F there was bubble and
Keef at Grateful Dead it this wasn't
popularized in the same way there there
were he insane hash oil makers in Eugene
at the time so just not full melt hash
you never saw full melt hash you might
have seen hash oil but you weren't
seeing full melt hash at those shows
when you dry sift those dry sifts melt
as as we know they do they absolutely
melt they just aren't full melt they
melted what they thought was the melti
of the dry sift they were probably 50%
heads but there was just there was
beautiful Origins there we'll say yeah
also the old there was still an import
uh business at that point with the
hashes coming through so we said I mean
none of it seemed very good but you can
still get the uh kind of brown and black
hashes that came in in bricks totally
totally that was the more
likely and I feel like that that would
definitely Bubble Up I don't know
anybody the tours you would buy it in
they would just uh uh measure it out not
have a scale because having a scale at
that time either was difficult or it was
always the triple beam and you didn't
really want to have a scale on you so
they had the long coils and then they
would just measure it out to like a a
half inch or an inch and that was what
the weight of it was and when you lit
that up right at first it definitely had
a sweet bubble to it but not it was
really quite no no not even close to
full melt but it would bubble just for a
second and I remember talking about how
cool that was you know I just remember
being at the whole enchilada Country
Fair like really early 90s and some
crazy amazing hippie coming out and
pretty much knocking us over with Keith
you know like we were just like what the
hell is this and and it was just it was
really special you know it was unicorn
tears back then country country fair was
the collection of the most heady people
so that you know you were going to find
you are G to find the best of the best
either there or at the southern Oregon
barter Fair one of the
two I forgot about the days when we were
all experts at eyeballing the weight of
cannabis just by looking at it the the
art of eyeballing the gram and eigh and
quarter an ounce hell
yeah always had the fish scale how many
fingers
yeah taking it back time for a dab
everybody let's do this up got some
cookies and cream going down in my bowl
right now go all this talk of hash got
me
excited me and ATN SP off from dead tour
onto the other tours we did vans uh
further we did a laala paloa horde we're
everywhere fishbone took us out uh
Prim Prim took us out yeah that was fun
were you guys at the festival was it the
last Outside Lands where they actually
allowed cannabis sales on site at the
festival I didn't that one the
greenlands or something like that it was
called I missed it yeah Susan's doing
that I think Susan sorz was that a
success or did did the people who put
that together I mean are they gonna are
is there going to be more things like
that you know I think there'll
definitely be more things like that yeah
as soon as uh you know they would have
had one this time I think it would have
happened again definitely yeah I know
Susan was also doing it at um oh what's
the big Festival down in Southern
California in this
February coella coella yeah yeah
Coachella that there as
well are they gonna have stupid like cor
where you have to buy your cannabis over
here and you have to smoke it over here
you're not going to be able to like
mingle in the in the rest of the crowd I
mean is it going to be like really
restrictive on where you can use it do
you know no I know people are trying to
get kiosks at uh like Shoreline and
other places so that whenever there are
shows they can actually show up and
actually have a cannabis kiosk but I've
only heard the discussions of that I've
not actually seen it in real practice
because that was all getting ready to
kick off preco but yeah my fear is the
same as you Mark is that you wouldn't be
able to bring in your own cannabis you
would have to buy this expensive ass you
know whatever weed we decide you have to
buy and to consume it here I don't know
if it's
a
or Beer Garden area that they're telling
you to consume it in it's not like you
can buy it and take it back to your seat
which is [ __ ] which is even worse
with cannabis because they want to put
up a wall because like somehow it's okay
to see someone drinking something
because you know that could be water it
could be juice it could be alcohol but
smoking like in Washington they've done
a few events and they make them put up
an eight wall eight foot wall in the
park so you have a band over here and
you have this sectioned off eight foot
wall where everyone's smoking weed and
they can't see the band
and then there's two people in front of
the band like no see see here at the
emerald Cup in California they have the
alcohol people penned up in their pans
and you can smoke cannabis anywhere
pretty much so you know that's what's up
that's how it should be and that's how
hopefully it will become but yeah this
separation of church and state yeah
alcohol they need to be pinned cannabis
should agreed agreed here here what's
that s what's the biggest music event
that folks have been to uh with me it
was 400,000
people I would have to say my biggest
event was certainly not a music event it
was the Maha Kumba and I think there was
like 2.8 million people there did you
meet most of them I met like a good
chunk of them you know all the ones with
good hash anyway the ones that I needed
to meet was there a portapotty ins
sight no you just [ __ ] in the ganes dude
I'm
joking this was in the north it was
quite clean everyone thinks the ganis
are so disgusting and dirty because of
varasi where they burn the bodies this
is up north in harir near uh
rishikesh no the water's quite nice up
there it's beautiful I was I people were
like oh my God you went in the ganes I'm
like yeah dude it was like looked like
North Vancouver like it was just like
water coming out of Foothills of the
Himalayas like it was it was it it was
really
beautiful I wanted to kind oh go ahead I
swam in the ganji in benarus and I saw
pieces of body burn Float by yeah like a
hand it was actually less than a hand oh
it happens I kind of wanted to change
the subject a little bit because
recently what I did was I went on a
3-day tour here in um uh the interior in
the okaga
I went to Penticton and I went to Vernon
and I went to Colona cruised around to
some other little smaller spots like
alliver and I went and visited all these
different people with shops and I kind
of wanted to get your guys's opinion on
this because you know these people have
some of them are Legacy some of them are
not either way both sides have like
spent an enormous amount of time and
energy to get to where they are by now
first being potentially civil
disobedient but now kind of saying okay
we're going to follow the rules we're
going to get in line we're going to jump
through these burning hoops and so
they've got their shops and of course
you know all their shops are there's
some difference um I definitely didn't
come to the Cs I would have been at your
place you kidding me um that was Josh
and Kelly texting me privately better
not have come to the CPS of course not I
would be talking to you for sure so you
know to get this out basically you know
there's you can kind of create different
Vibes in your shops but every single
package look looks exactly the same so
there you know it's this Canada
packaging thing that really kind of
affects you know your ability to stand
out I will give it up to the cottage I
believe in Penticton um I've I I thought
it was so cool and if you go on my
Instagram you might still be able to see
the shots it was a little cottage and
then you walk in and it looked like the
foyer of a little old lady's home with
these beautiful couches and plants and
stuff and then there was plants growing
Down the Walls and then you walked into
this great room that was all hardwood
floors and all wooden kind of walls and
beautiful uh wallpaper like what's
behind Josh and Kelly you know really
cool all around the place it set a Vibe
I felt like I was visiting my plug who
stayed at his grandma's house the night
before and then you walk in and there
there's just a guy standing there behind
a couple of counters and he was super
nice and super cool and so you've got
all these people working really hard
trying to get this done and now you have
this other element you have the
indigenous people who are like well we
want to play too we've got our
sovereignty we want to play we should be
allowed to play so I wish I remembered
her name Selena who is in Vernon had
told me the story of a good friend of
hers who was a native is a native woman
and was trying to go the the the route
of the legal and it was just like one
obstacle wall after another and finally
she was like you know what I'm going to
throw a c can down right on Native uh
property and we're just going to start
selling weed like that I think she even
created something called The Green Mile
where there's like a bunch of them all
kind of together and if you drive
through the Okanogan they're everywhere
they are literally everywhere and they
don't have limits they can sell as much
as they want they can advertise so they
have signs all over the highways and on
posts and stuff and let me tell you it
was a point of
contention with a lot of the shop owners
and I think the rep that I was with was
extremely surprised when I said what I
said and I think think you guys might
have an idea what I'm going to say I
said
uh they they were like well it's not
fair it's not fair they're you know
there they don't have to follow the
rules we've had to do all this stuff and
I'm like really it's not fair hey h so
but what about when you stole their
children and murdered their ancestors
what about when our ancestors did that
what about that that also was not fair
well I thought the rep was going to have
a heart attack when I said that to the
first store owner in uh I think it was
in pent tikton I found the conversation
to be enlightening I I told them that
they need to get behind the indigenous
population and the natives and they need
to support them in every way that they
can you do not want to stand against
these people on this issue cannabis is
actually making something a little bit
right somehow cannabis is making things
right for the native populace right
population right now in Canada and I
just thought holy [ __ ] this is amazing
and I also convinced each and every one
of those stores that I had this
discussion with that it will help you
believe it or not because the
government's going to see it they're
going to realize there's no competing
with these No Limits and edible No
Limits and go in and buy a quarter pound
if you want and advertise on the street
and I really am a firm believer that
that's going to leech over into the the
legal Federal program that we have now
because there's no getting away from it
this loophole is so good the government
is absolutely [ __ ] on this one and
it's also the right thing to do yeah
does that mean that the materials are
not analyzed for
safety I would say some probably are and
some probably aren't I don't want to say
but yet they definitely don't have to
follow all the same regulations uh in
fact any of them it's their own thing
and the shops are busy people are
definitely buying at those Shops and and
uh you know Finding loyalty there so I
think that not standing standing against
them is one of the biggest mistakes you
could make as a cannabis shop owner
right now in my opinion and I'm going to
say one thing we have we have such an
incredible opportunity right now to be
able to work with the indigenous nations
in Canada to be able to get rightful
education in there because they have
sort of a wide openen slate and we're
finding that these shop owners and a lot
of people of the first nations are so
incredibly open to doing it right and
stepping in in a way that is really
empowering the First Nations and also
empowering cannabis so we're working
with the ministry right now we're
putting together so many different Sops
different pilot projects that's working
directly with the First Nations peoples
because this is a loophole that cannabis
can have a higher better voice and a
higher effect on the federal laws so
that we can put things into place to say
see look at how this can actually be
done better so it would be really silly
for the LPS to go against anything
that's happening there because they also
have the ability to go through this
direction to change the way that
cannabis Commerce is being done today
also so it's a really incredible
opportunity and thank you so M much
Marcus for both defending that and also
bringing up this because we've been
living and breathing this um in our home
right now and working with the ministry
and writing down Sops and really working
hard to uh you know give cannabis more
of a medical stance which is where it
needs to be there's a lot of deep issues
on that and I would encourage people to
look up uh what residential schools are
in Canada and also uh indigenous women
going missing and murdered in Canada is
a really huge thing and also in First
Nations um and in there in tribes
there's a lot of issues with addiction
and and and cannabis is is helping that
so there's a lot of tribes and Nations
that are coming together to accept it to
help them you know with their addictions
so um we see it as a really positive and
I and I also you know for any people who
are associated with LPS in order to have
LPS there has to be a portion that
you've been uh you've made a commitment
towards education you've made a
commitment to the communities that
you're set up in and I really want to
plead and encourage these LPS to reach
out to these indigenous Nations to reach
out to a lot of these different shop
owners and let's start swapping
education let's use that Federal funding
to make bridges for cannabis this is
really important and we still have doors
open um to create more education for the
general public as well as for the First
Nations as well as for a lot of
addictions that Josh was just mentioning
that are just super incredibly High here
in Canada currently in British
col can help currently in British
Columbia addictions and opioid deaths
are killing more people than covid if
I'm not you know on that and also yeah
it's it's way higher so it's like oh
great we're all wearing masks but that
does is not stopping desk but uh Johnny
B looked like you had something to say
and I'd be interested to hear what you
what you were thinking comes to medical
and you're talking about this and and
and you can go into into say chillak and
and I can go in and buy a chocolate
that's 10 milligrams but I can go down
the street to the reserve and buy a bag
of gummies that's 250 milligrams so I
mean there's quite a difference when it
comes to medical so I mean if you're in
need of those type of Edibles that's
where you go because they actually have
what you need they actually have those
high doses so I don't have to sit here
and eat like 25 of these I'm taking 250
milligram caps I go to the store here I
can only buy 10 milligrams at a time so
that's really disgusting and then if I
if I buy more than four items well
that's over my 30 grams so I actually
have to leave and go back in right so I
mean you got to go home and then go back
in because you can't have all of that on
you out in the world you'd have wait a
second I'm medical so I can carry 150
grams so I can go in and out a few times
because I am Medical but once again so
I'm gonna have to walk out with a huge
Bay in order to get my so that's why I
like what's going on with with um
what's happening on the tribe stuff is
they're actually able to cater to those
high doses Edibles that are needed and
and that's one other thing that the
government's really got to lighten up on
because that's another encouragement for
people to go there and get proper
dosaging for themselves because you
can't get that in the legal system in
reality but that is a legal system so
let me rephrase that you can get this
only in certain parts in the system that
are legal you know what also Johnny that
there's there's this real limitations
with the legal system for um for LPS and
the limitation is that if we want to
supply a province they're going to
require that we you know make some
product you know sell it to them and
then if they sell that product and it's
good and people like it they want to be
able to order it right away and if you
don't have it available to order right
away you can fall to the bottom of the
que and so people are desperate to make
sure so right away that limits you
massively now there's no way that you
can support a craft grower
um to who's only growing small amounts
because what I'm going to buy 50 kilos
from this guy and he's not going to have
it again for three more months like this
might sell out in two days I might need
to re have a reorder available in seven
days it's another reason why we're
limited to not seeing 90 Micron 73
Micron how the hell am I going to
produce 10 kilos of just 90 Micron and
then have another 10 kilos of it
available in a month or a week or or two
months so what happens is all of that
other small lot gets funneled into
medical the very place it shouldn't be
because when medical people find
something that they like they love they
need and you're never going to make it
again oh sorry man that was just a
couple hundred grams you know we just
got a certain amount of stuff from so
and so and we're probably not going to
see that stuff anymore I think he killed
the Clone you know like so they've got
it set up to protect the recreational
market so you always have more and it's
available or you drop the queue but they
they've left the most vulnerable people
once once again the very people who
everyone used as their shield for the
last 10 plus year in Canada so they
could continue to grow cannabis sell it
and pay their mortgages while claiming
it was for the patient uh it's just
[ __ ] I mean there's a lot of
[ __ ] still there but Civil
Disobedience got us this far A little
bit more Civil Disobedience we'll get us
further sorry Debbie did you have
something to say oh I I didn't mean to
interrupt I'm so sorry but uh yeah on
the topic of [ __ ] I wanted to tell
you guys the bad news about the
California law which is that um uh
people who live on the uh Native
American reservations here if they want
to participate in the Cannabis industry
they have to uh sign away their
Sovereign rights so uh there there is
only one cannabis company that's owned
by Native American in the entire State
nobody that lives on the reservation
who's going to sign away their Sovereign
rights to to be able to participate in
the Cannabis industry it's a absolute
travesty travesty so yeah I was gonna
gonna bring that up I'm in Washington
and it's the same similar deal because
of the federal lack of federal um you
know allow allowance that the tribes
here they they in Washington choose to
operate underwat they've done it they a
pack deal and it's been a big big to-do
took them a couple years to figure out
they did some pack but they basically
operate as if they're licensed
recreational stores you wouldn't know
the difference they have the same
product they buy from 502
producers um interestingly they they
lined it up where they can ship to other
tribes so they kind of did have that
forethought that they could ship to any
other Sovereign Nation you know tribe
but um it's it's it's not what you're
talking about Marcus you know and they
didn't have the they didn't have the
guts I think because of the our you know
our federal deal you
know and
totally giv
right I mean that's the game right now
and I don't necessarily want to get into
it right now we're dealing with state of
emergency all over the place here in
Canada and S rights are being given left
right and center and handing it over I
know that's a bigger conversation but
wow my heart goes in down into the chair
and I think people could look so
relevant right now they could look into
what it means to be a
I'm thankful for what's happening in
Canada right now though because there is
you know a medical program that is still
functioning and that is a good thing for
medical people and I would just on the
note of someone finding a strain or one
particular varietal that works for them
and then being worried
about whether they can get it again I
think it's really important for those
people to look into potentially if they
can having that strain on their land and
growing that as one of their four plants
because especially in Canada you can do
that
and nothing
connects yeah grow your own now you're
connected to the plant itself you're
connected to the create life creation
process
and you're making your own medicine
which is a
self-empowering action and you're
continuing to have the same varietal
that works for you and if you can grow
four of your own and you're going to do
it outside because you don't want to
invest a whole bunch of money into
having an indoor system and you don't
know how to do it well I really suggest
that you do it regeneratively because if
you need those 200 milligram gummies
throughout the whole year then you want
to grow those plants really really big
and you want to grow them heavy weight
and you want to grow really good
medicine that you can have throughout
the year and now that is having
sovereignty with cannabis so if we want
to talk sovereignty with cannabis
everybody can grow their own cannabis
still here in Canada and really we all
need to take the federal government up
on that and also have medical for more
than than
four say yeah and those four plants
could be as big as you can grow them you
look down south they're growing plants
getting 25 lbs out of one plant so I
mean you can veg this all through your
winter inside if you want the first bed
of sunshine put that thing outside bury
it in the dirt have those soils ready
and feed that thing because it's going
to reach for the skies guys and and you
can really because you're not limited to
how much you're only limited to how many
you can only carry 30 grams with you but
when you're at home Sky's a limit so
remember that so it's not about you can
get as much as you can there's different
methods of growing four plants indoors I
did one plant under each light I've seen
people now just at a place that got
completely bouns out a plant made one
plant really it's four feet by four feet
I was pretty amazed I'm going to go back
and take some pictures today this
afternoon it's really cool what people
are doing out there with their four
plant limit guys so definitely grow your
own I love it hey and I want to add to
that grow your own I want to give Selena
and the wise wom Seed Company a huge
shout out because she gave me
this incredible pack of seeds from Wise
women's seeds and they are like air
hairloom hairloom Tomatoes you know like
sage plants um some violets some some
amarith just like just endless amounts
of awesome seeds all sorts of foods and
companion plants and uh I am definitely
wanting to shout out Wise Women seeds
and uh Selena in particular for helping
curate this for and my wife and my
family and I we're going to build some
uh I'm going to be talking to the
dragonfly Earth medicine we're going to
get some uh some proper area built up
and some good soils in and uh yeah get
these seeds cracking grow your own
baby because we're gonna head out to the
coast here soon we're gonna come help
you build it awesome that's what's up
you're going to stop by my place me too
and help me that's yeah yeah definitely
Johnny for sure that we're without a
doubt we're also we're also heading out
to Victoria um to see a fight with um
Elias who is the first Canadian athlete
to be a THC um cannabis athlete and he's
on our story right now so big love to
Elias and the work that he's been doing
at becoming a cannabis athlete so we're
going to be supporting really and really
pushing uh the the conversation forward
that how silly that year saying that
it's okay to use a plant but only part
of the plant and and this sort of you
know uh separatism has to has to end oh
okay well you can use the plant but you
can only use part of the plant and if
you use this part of the plant then you
could be tested and I mean it's just
absolutely ridiculous I think that often
humans run themselves in a circle and
eat their tail and we just need to stop
this the plant gives us what it needs in
the right doses that for us to to to be
able to get relief from and for us to be
able to live happier healthy lives
especially athletes who are not really
supported except by sponsors and maybe
they only would get free material or or
you know free whatever from different
sponsors but they're not supporting
their health their longevity and their
well-being well into the future so that
conversation really needs to change
because there's a tremendous amount of
Youth that look up to athletes in the
world and the athletes need to carry the
conversation forward with the sponsors
backing them of Education of health and
well-being so that the youth can be
raised in that type of an
educ and I would just add that part of
cannabis what it's given us is Earth
conscious it's giving us that nature
awareness so like when Johnny B's
talking about having to go to the store
and get a stack of 10 milligram things I
mean that's a lot of garbage so why so a
lot of sugar we're healing ourselves
while ailing the Earth or getting
diabetes to be able to get 200
milligrams like there let's create a
little bit of sense here in the idea of
holistic understanding like and I have
to bring it back to science like we keep
relying on only this
idealized you know
specific you know standard that takes
away all of the holistic V versions of
it and then we are only looking at
things with blinders on and the more
that we sort of open up the conversation
and sure we can use that scientific
experiment for one of the great
discoveries to be able to explain
something that's fantastic but if we're
using it as the
only way to explain something and also
be able to make laws and move forward on
then we're really missing out on you
know something so much more deep and
something so much more powerful for
Humanity as a
whole also I just say you know shout out
to Tar um tar Le has been um is doing a
a start your own seed thing on her
YouTube channel so for home Growers that
are interested in having a larger plant
or a big plant in their backyard or even
inside starting it now you know with the
moon cycles is going to be a a really
good way to get a large Plant and then
it's you have to decide how big of a pot
you're going to put it in and how many
times you think you'll have to
transplant it in a few month you know
two or three months it's going to take
to put it in the ground but you know
there's some good in-depth conversation
going on there and demm pure is going to
be putting out a contest but we don't
want to call it a contest we want to
call it a protest but it's not like your
traditional type of a protest it's sort
of like a fun protest and um put it out
of like show us your four plants and you
know talk about all the other things
that you could be growing in Now show us
your your legal plants so that all those
people can partake in ination too and
backyard backyard Transformations we're
incredible backyard transformation this
been unbelievable ran lamby on Instagram
you know has dug out his in a lawn in
his backyard and made trenches and put
wood in in there and he's like I don't
know what I'm doing I'm throwing logs in
the ground we' watched people take up
their entire Concrete in Downtown LA
literally renting a jackhammer their
entire concrete that they had you know
for 25 years is all dug up it goes on
and on and on we've seen so many
pictures of people's backyards fully
transformed we've been talking with
Earth kind a lot over the years Ur t h k
y n d Earth kind and
cannabismo and sometimes in Oregon but
South Central Los Angeles and and we
have a as a group deem P have been
talking about creating a
regenerative uh Farm not Farm but an
inner city urban farm where you
transform a a a vacant lot into a
beautiful garden and also he's talked
about creating I think this is good for
other Municipal areas where they'd have
local backyard gardens come together as
a co-op and make medicine for themselves
so neighborhoods of people getting
together growing four plants in their
backyard and then creating meetings
where they can share how to make
medicine together and they all make the
medicine together to work to give to
themselves throughout the winter it's
self-empowerment it's Community
empowerment and it's it's herbalism you
know it's it's learning about herbalism
because you'll always have companion
plants you'll always have flowers and
mint and all the other things and what
brings Community together better than
talking about their buds that they grew
in their backyard I mean come on we all
love talking about our buds that we grow
so it's it's you know Josh and I always
say that backyard gardens
you know are going to save the world and
actually believe that they might be the
only thing
can they have to to save the world so I
think it's like a bee song they Mis
wrote it it's come together right now
over
weed I like it sorry I'm uh dealing with
uh on the side here someone who's my
admin has has offended in one of my
groups I don't think people realize how
hard it is to administrate these groups
on Facebook and that there's a lot of
people who go there just to kind of
cause trouble and we're just kind of
trying to curate these groups to share
information to let everyone kind of gain
information and it's endless how many
people hit me oh your mod deleted me or
I treated me poorly and blah I'm just
like man it's because of the stress he
has this poor guy is liter and he's been
on hash Church before this poor guy has
done a lot of good in these groups he
shared an enormous amount of knowledge
with people and you just can't win with
these hey I want to like to shout out uh
a few things here real quick I want to
shout out to Johnny B thank you very
much for my hat and cubes as well as my
mask um it's much love and appreciate it
all the way around
there uh I also want to uh congratulate
patients out of time there having their
25th anniversary right now and of course
the emerald cup uh we're actually uh
yeah we actually changed the actual
voting in the last couple of days
because uh packaging and labeling was
part of the overall and now that's been
pulled out and it's going to be a
separate part of the um competition Al
together so pushing for environmentally
sound packaging and um last but not
least just to be
uh uh to deal with the realism um we
lost an employee this week at Berkeley
Patients Group uh one of our employees
she was only 30 years old Morgan Medina
passed away suddenly this week so um
prayers and ups and love I've never lost
an employee actually um we've had others
retire and pass away but um shout out to
their friends families and employees and
support out there and you know uh she
was one who just celebrated her one-year
anniversary with us just last week and
uh she had extra care and love for
patience and uh she was one of those
unsung heroes that helped everybody so
uh much love and
respect thanks for sharing that iang
that's s sorry to hear that go ahead
Debbie so sorry I'm going to blame my uh
stuttering behavior on the raw Garden
dab I did a few minutes ago because I
like forgot how to use the English
language for a minute but I think I'm
back um no our buddy Bo from Oregon
passed away too I want to mention that
he is
uh known Bo for probably 30 the entire
32 years I've been involved in the
movement and um shout out to the Oregon
family and uh yeah we love you and happy
Valentine's Day everyone too I want to
say that let's keep love for each other
all the time oh bo uh uh I was a general
manager for at Rosenthal and for his
first trial I had to disappear and I
Disappeared a few times and uh bo hid me
up in Oregon for three weeks and allowed
me to go to work in the gardens for John
SEO and the Oregon crew of which I went
and fixed the gardens they had a whole
bunch of large plants that were
overgrown with white pottery mildew so I
went in and fix the plants the whole
time I was kind of you know setting
stuff there and Bo fed me hid me out
gave me the room and everything man much
love Bo you were a great
spirit and condolences to the BPG posy
that is never
easy no and thank you just to remember
everybody you know we never know if is
today is your first or your last so you
know hug in love and remind each other
that you know life is short life is
quick and we have the time that we have
so enjoy it and don't don't forget to
tell anybody you love them and uh in
that case I love you all especially all
you all here much love love you guys
sorry for your
loss really love you guys thanks so much
and I just wanted to say that this time
has you know created such incredible
divisiveness you know in the world in
politics um and now you know
unfortunately even within on households
so you know know this divide is being
felt everywhere and and it's running
really really deep and I guess just
since it's Valentine's Day you know I
think that building bridges for love is
really
important
and you know if we're gonna make a
choice and I just always really resonate
with what the the ancient Buddhists say
and and and the dreamers who dreamed
this existence into
time and that's love and
fear and I just really encourage
everyone listening and all of us and
even myself to really resonate In Fear
And I mean resonate in love and to
outride fear because it really isn't
serving anything and it just creates a
continuous noise so happy Valentine's
Day everybody and here's to love
you know on that note I think I'm going
to cut her short today I've got my wife
and my child waiting on the other side
of the door to go hang out and go for a
nice little hike I have absolutely
enjoyed today's uh episode and show with
all of you guys we had some good
conversation um I do have a couple of
small announcements I wanted to mention
sra's um talk that's going to be had
here soon I believe it's Mark Lewis from
nepro Ryan Lee kimer genetics uh Rob
Clark Rob conell Clark is going to be
there Mojave Richmond is going to be on
that panel um I had sent out an email to
Rob mentioning that hey if you wanted to
come on here and promote it before and
he sort of said you know what before you
know let's not scoop the scoop let's
I'll do we'll do that and then we'll
come on hash Church afterwards and we
can talk about it so hey marus I know at
least he'll hey Marcus he's actually in
the middle of a patience Out of Time
conference
today yeah yeah I've been emailing with
him
actually gotcha yeah thank you so he'll
probably uh those guys uh Mojave and all
those guys will get them on in the next
couple of weeks two or three weeks and
go to segra
dl.com and they'll have a registration
form you can fill out uh and you can
check out I believe it's on the 25th of
February the segra um you know Heavy
Hitters um Growers breeders panel I
think it's going to be really awesome
with the group of guys that they got on
there
I also wanted to mention that I did
invite corvan Cooper on through his
group he just was released from prison I
guess he was one of the guys that got a
uh um Trump um pardoned him and so I
thought it would be cool to use hash
Church platform to help him with his
re-entry maybe you know help you know
put some money in his GoFundMe and you
know let him tell his story use the
platform so we're hoping on getting
corvan on here uh in the next week or
two and uh other than that you know
everyone thanks for coming and shooting
the [ __ ] and chatting and being so cool
and I also love each and every one of
you so thank you hey Wade has something
to say before you go I
want uh two things uh I heard on
clubhouse last night that Corvin Cooper
is looking for a place to stay somewhere
in Southern California uh for the next
two weeks he's got a an apartment he's
going to be able to move into on March
1st but uh between now and then he's
looking for a place uh to stay uh so if
anybody's uh hooked up in that way and
have a spot uh pointing out that
pointing that direction the other thing
I wanted to say was uh about Valentine's
Day St Valentine is also the patron
saint of
epilepsy and
um I spoke to Forest the other day for
the first time in I don't know almost
two months and
uh he he said that he was able to call
because Silas was relatively free of
seizures and I wanted to share that with
all of you because I know you you've uh
we've had Forest on here and um uh I
care very much about that family and and
the struggle that they're living um so
yeah uh as you as you walk about and
give thanks for love in the
world uh remember uh that if you're en
enjoying full health give gratitude for
that and recognize that it is a gift in
your life and on that note thank you so
much Marcus and JN and Sam and dragonfly
family and Johnny B and oh my goodness
thank you so much hash
church that's it everybody peace to the
out we'll see you next week ciao for now