all right here we go I guess we better
go live on YouTube if we can't get this
going on bubble man's world public let's
do this let us do this oh wow we got
people popping in left right and center
I haven't even gone live yet this is
cool this is the new way to do things in
2020 we're just setting up the YouTube
meeting guys it should go live here in a
second and I will introduce you if we're
all gravy a little bit rusty on this
2020 hash Church first of the year just
waiting for zoom - ah there we go
set up the YouTube video all right I'm
gonna link that into the old YouTube
chat and then I will get - here we go
boom there you guys go
welcome guys and hear me I can hear hear
I can hear you great jack is on mute I
think I haven't set up so when you come
in it automatically mutes you okay there
you go oh dude all right welcome guys
good morning sir
very cool to have both of you guys in
first because you're kind of my you know
a chance been a front line guy for a
long time
at Berkeley's patient group you know you
know doing doing the good good work jack
has also now how many years has it been
jack what I've been doing this work I've
been working where I am for about the
last five years yeah exactly five years
maybe you want to give us a little bit
of a lowdown on what you've been doing
cuz Jack's Jack's new to you guys jack
is certainly not new to me jack and I go
back fought far like 20 20 plus years we
worked in the cannabis industry together
I came out from Winnipeg and I met him
and we just kind of clicked right away
he was kind of a bit of an aggressive
character at the time but I really liked
it it was kind of Winnipeg
and made me feel like I was at home and
give him a little lowdown on what you've
been up to you know obviously for the
last five years but also a little bit in
regards to how you got there okay okay
well thanks for the thanks for the intro
Marcus definitely yeah where Marcus and
I met was was definitely the nineties in
Vancouver when there was that that time
when all of us were busy from there I
like a lot of people in the business I
had my own my own personal difficulties
and through those I ended up leaving
Vancouver and coming over here to the
island and I did that quite a while back
and in trying to you know heal myself
you know I did a lot of things that did
involve cannabis and at the same time I
ran a volunteer-based mobile needle
exchange in the streets of Victoria so
tell them a little bit about kind of how
you went down the road and got into drug
addiction and where you ended up because
that really sets the story and I'm sure
it might be a little bit sensitive to
talk about get into that a little bit
because dude you lived some serious [ __ ]
that really in my opinion led you to do
the work that you're doing today yeah
your your right ear right Marcus um I
mean for me just like a lot of people I
think I came out to to be see from from
Ontario and I got a new cannabis scene
like like any twenty-year-old who wants
to go out and make their own way and I
became very successful at that is how I
how Markus and I met and once you kind
of get to a certain level in the
cannabis world you're no longer just
dealing with people who are only in the
cannabis business and and through that I
found that I was just not a happy person
you know I got all the things in life
that I was supposed to get you know
physical things things that I was taught
that would help me to
to feel better when I didn't feel better
when I had those things I turned then to
the other drugs that did I was involved
with the the business of and and that
for a long time that made me stronger
that made me seem like a like my average
friends you know and and nobody really
knew about it because you know I was
making enough money to to to hide what
that was and and I went on that way for
probably you know a solid a solid decade
and you know I guess in that world I
just experienced even even further
traumas you know it made me want to do
the things that I do now to try to
challenge what what drug policy exists
because I always felt like it was the
criminalization of cannabis that ended
me up meeting into a world that I really
had no exposure to I grew up as a little
hippie kid selling hash to university
students and eventually that became such
a big thing that I was involved in the
smuggling business and then that
involved of course all the other things
that that that come with that and so
yeah well for me I always felt like
cannabis was always a healthy part of my
life it was always something that I came
back to when I needed to to gather
myself so I mean I don't know what else
you want to but it leads into so listen
Jack had some problems he got addicted
to some drugs and when I say he got
addicted to drugs
Jack excelled at being a when I saw him
at the end he was literally on main in
Hastings like in the worst situation I'm
telling you it's a death sentence when
you end up down there very very very few
people go down there okay so not only
did Jack come back from that he started
doing what he's doing in Victoria
right now and that's that's what I was
getting to wanting you to tell us about
what the work that you're doing now
based on the experiences that you had
using cannabis to help other people who
are in your current situation get back
okay great because that's that's an easy
story you know what I mean I I basically
I came over here I was real quiet and in
order to kind of get my own head back
together I wanted to learn what it was
to do something for nothing you know so
I volunteered my time in a in a in a
needle exchange that served food and
[ __ ] you know because I wanted to find
out what a what what it was why people
were nice to each other I think and
through that experience it led me to
that was in a different Health Services
Agency and then I was called by this
group called solid which at the time
only had one staff member in a shit-ton
of volunteers and their story was like a
lot of their members were their story
was very similar to mine you know we're
so so for four years I just we just did
them a while needle exchange we went out
and ended that and as everybody knows
the opioid crisis is a is a real problem
and so I ran an agency of people with
lived experience of either current or
past experience with drug use and
through that we started doing overdose
prevention work we started the very
first temporary overdose prevention site
here in Victoria and we can and we kept
doing more of the same thing now we run
the harbor the that's the equivalent of
what do you guys have in Vancouver is
insight and through running deeps types
of projects I've been able to show
people how cannabis is an effective tool
in a harm reduction toolbox so when I'm
running a needle exchange and giving you
clean needles when I'm giving you narcan
kits in case with the worst case
scenario I
so always wanted to be able to give
people cannabis because for me that was
the thing that always kind of I never
succeeded it at government detox or
rehab centers but I always succeeded
when I gave myself time and space and
time to reflect in the plant you know so
I wanted to be able to do that for
others and so we started just giving
away edibles and joints on a weekends
here so I started out with maybe only
about 80 people they were all Street
entrenched drug users in the downtown
core and so I would always say to them
you know I probably know that you won't
try this until that day when your dealer
wasn't turn on his phone you know and
you're really sick in the in it and then
when that happens I really want you to
take the edible and I want you to tell
me what happens and so we just gave out
joints and in edibles within the within
the scene and we started doing a
secondary stream research with the
University of Victoria so if I was to
say Marcus tell me about your drug abuse
and you tell me hey I do an eight ball
of cocaine a day so then you would check
in weekly to let me know after a week of
me giving you 80 milligrams of as edible
and a joint or two how that impacted
your patterns of behaviour and we got a
lot of very positive feedback from that
so we expanded the program we reached
out to people who are large online
vendors and they started to give us more
product to give to people and so we got
up to having about 200 members and five
days a week four hours a day where the
service was running and about six months
ago we were able to move and get a
storefront that was separate from our
administrative office so now I have a
service open seven hours a day
it's an at cost cannabis service for
members only you either have to be a
person of lived experience with illicit
drug use
or on government assistance like a
disability or old age or of Aboriginal
descent those lonely people 11 to the
program because those are the people who
are most disproportionately affected by
opioid deaths totals so I know that the
community safety unit has a complaint
and has had from before over the last
month and a half but they still haven't
come to us to give us the lecture about
shutting down because I am working in
conjunction with the chief medical
officer here who is working as a kind of
lobbyist with us with the Ministry of
Health because the harbor and the other
injection services that I run have
government exemptions that allow for
drug use in those areas obviously heroin
is still illegal but where we were it's
accepted that that we have to pass drugs
back and forth there has to be an
exemption that allows for that and I'm
negotiating with the problem is to
extend that exemption over our cannabis
programs to recognize that our cannabis
programs are an element of our
life-saving services that we provide we
also do other things like run a drug
checking project so any a person who
does casual drugs on the weekend or any
you know hardened addict has access to
mass spectrometry and real information
about what's in their drugs I've run all
these services together in one place and
I feel like that's the main reason that
my cannabis service has not been shut
down yet is because I'm not a dispensary
you can come in and see that the same
thing there's $20 in the dispensaries
all over the city is $5 where we are I
have 8 or 9 staff that work for me just
in the cannabis programs in the
production attaining and distribution of
those things so the only money that we
make off cannabis is that to pay the
salaries of the people who were there
and everything else we give away so I've
gone to where I've only when we started
we made it maybe you know a hundred
dollars a day because there is no price
it's just a donation when you come in
Marcus maybe one day you have no money
maybe one day you have four dollars some
days you leave me money some days you
don't but in the end you leave the
service with something every day so
that's that's kind of the the the loose
parts of how it works you know
I wanted you to come and share this
story because I know there's a lot of
good people in the community that will
want to get behind it and support it and
I know I've you know tried to facilitate
and do whatever I can for it because it
really is the good good work and you are
such a unique person to be doing it
you're literally I just love you like I
wanted to see why people were nice to
each other like how people knew who you
were 20 plus years ago they would just
be like wow this guy has matured he has
like grown as a human being he's been
through hell and back and then back to
hell and back again and you're just kind
of shining you're doing super good
things you're helping people and you can
tell that your experience is directly
effective in the efficiencies of the
program because you know what it's like
to be a drug user you know when you talk
to them look I know you're not going to
eat this edible but you know at one
point in time they're dealers not gonna
answer their phone that dealers gonna
get busted he's gonna lose that phone's
gonna happen and that is the moment when
those drugs are not going to be
available and that is the moment when
you get that edible and that joint into
their hands and it's just such a nice
it's just such good work dude I'm proud
of you like I'm really proud of you I
really appreciate that man and and
you're right like the reason that I do
those things is because if I give you a
joint in an edible today and next week
you're you end up in jail and you get
out and you have no idea your welfare
has been cut off I can help you with
that too you know and that way when you
get those things back together you get
another put a little bit more stable and
maybe you need some other kind of help
you feel like then you can ask us for it
and it will deliver it and I think
that's the strength of the service and
it
why did I connected like primarily we
work from the health authority contracts
that's kind of what protects me in the
services that I run is that I work
essentially for the man in a lot of ways
but then this I love I love the
opportunity about how I don't know if
anybody's ever been a drug user you know
how it is like there's a point when
you're ready to tap out and if people
aren't ready to help you at that point
you kind of miss that opportunity and
sometimes months or years can go by
before somebody feels like they're in a
position again where they want to make
changes you know and recognizing that
time is the key right like who but a
drug user who's gotten out of it can
recognize it's the time yeah and this is
like a tool that allows us to have that
conversation every day with people you
know when they come in for their joint
they're at a bowl you can really have a
chance to check in with them you can
really have a chance to to make changes
in their lives like the ones that I've
been able to make for myself you know I
just try to offer the supports that I
wish would have been there for me a
decade ago and this is why today for
2020 I wanted to start with a story
about realness and truth and and not get
right into a cannabis 2.0 and licensed
productions and regulations and blah
Bloo Blee blah bluh because I know that
the majority of the people that I invite
into these rooms although some of us
many of us are going down these pathways
and checking out alternative pathways we
still all come from the foundation from
the place that you are in right now so
know that in the hash Church panelists
and the hash church congregation you
have an incredible amount of support and
with that I would like to introduce the
hash Church congregation because Jack
and I got right into it and we have a
tan in the room as well who came in
right off the bat we've got Johnny B
who's smoking a fatty and takin dabs as
Johnny B would be doing we've got mr.
skunk man Sam looking very dapper today
what do you got a lizard on your head
today that's nice
colin is in from vessel from Happy
Valley he's sideways today I don't know
why maybe he's gotta turn his phone
sideways I see Wade is in the house I
don't see his video on but welcome Wade
and welcome to the dragonfly earth
medicine crew to Josh and Kelly here in
the house dr. Marc is also in the house
and will be getting into some pretty
interesting conversations where I'm sure
he'll be dominating for at least an hour
straight so be prepared for that get out
your your pens and your paint and your
papers and then of course my my good
friend and colleague Mike West is in the
room we got Sabol Shen from ha new labs
another great guy doing good work and
opening great dialogues and then another
super righteous dude is in the house we
got boo Williams in the house right now
and all I see boo doing is good I just
see him going and giving people water
and delivering food and giving out
clothes and buying gifts for kids and
just like so there is an incredible
group of people in the room today we're
just gonna go for an organic dialogue as
per usual if anyone wants to chime in
feel free there's no direction to the
conversation I just wanted to thank each
and every one of you for showing up
today as well as all of the people who
are watching in you on YouTube right now
we got almost 500 people watching live
right now so hashtags still got it hey
Jack as somebody who is working needle
exchange thank you very much for your
dedication and your hard work is yeah
you need people in the trenches
especially those that have done it and
we need it in a unique you never know
when it's somebody's time in need so
people look through needle-exchange go
out there you know help people out do
some volunteering and you know look at
Jack and Jack you need any volunteers to
come help you out where can they come
find your help
you can find to our services saw the
solid outreach Society at 10:56 North
Park in Victoria that is their side
where our outreach office and our
cannabis services exist our
administrative office as it 1804 Cook
Street just around the corner from the
store
and I guess we always are looking for
people the people of lived experience
that is the first qualification before
anything else I just wanted to say Jack
we've talked on the phone great doctor
great to see you now and the work that
you're doing and it really touches heart
I mean down the path and I talk with a
lot of people here in the downtown
Vancouver east side and worked at
Network actually really afraid that did
talks at Carnegie Hall we'll talk to
more me on harm reduction and and right
now we have Neal Magnus and doing the
same thing here in town with the canvas
substitution project and I was killing
it and he's also got his show tooth hope
and courage and he's really really doing
the same focus or what you're doing here
in Vancouver and we're seeing this in
different parts of the world actually to
overseas or some other people we've
talked about capping the name right now
but you know it's just great work that
you guys are doing like we all support
so thanks oh thanks thanks for bringing
up Neal actually the reason that we
started our program the cannabis
substitution project because we hired a
person from Vandu Howard Howard dezhong
and he came over and told us about Neal
and that's how it really started is
moved to sitting like this you know
puffin on my couch and he was telling
the story and I just decided you know I
think I'll stop selling weed and let's
just start giving it away instead you
know and that's that's honestly how it
how it began and what we're trying to do
is make it so that Neal and Sara and
other people who are doing the same what
we've done is we've actually built a
society it has a board I have a staff I
have managers I can show on paper how
that you create cannabis it's such a
cause that you can employ people but
still give out hundreds of donations
into the community a day and that's the
thing the chief medical officer here
really wants to make the program my
Grabeel you know to migrate it to places
so I want to take all these extra tools
that I have with research connections
that I have and hand them over to people
like Neil and Sarah so they can expand
their services so instead of like once a
week having 700 people line up on
Hastings to come get their thing from
Neil I want to give Neil my playbook and
say dear Neil this is this is you know
this is what I do this is what we did
and and actually make it so that there
is this subsidized area of the market as
as Marcus said there's there's people in
this forum who have the access to go and
investigate the lp world as it sits
right now the people who I serve they
just know a way that they could be
served by that so I I'm gonna say like
when I volunteered the Green Cross I was
a member of stuff like that and then
words worked on donations and when
people come with 50 cents and then we
get them suddenly and with me bottom on
the bag whatever we always made sure
that and and that is knows the beginning
stages of working and it was basing harm
reduction in those first clubs and stuff
like that yeah that's what they all were
based around yeah and we saw on that and
it was really good and then and we saw
it kind of fade away with all the legal
dispensaries opening up and stuff like
that but now we're starting to see that
come back because truly it needs to give
back and yeah I'm just sitting here on
memory I know because it is kind of like
what Hilary did in the beginning and and
the kind of sense that Marcus and others
in the community gave but there was no
way that Hilary could afford the massage
therapists kind of listen I want to
soften their stuff like that yes I went
through those whole programs because you
know I was injured I was hooked on
pharmaceutical drug same thing no
difference
went through the whole stages of the
whole harm reduction learn the four
pillars that's all went through through
Samsung and stuff like that with the
Downtown Eastside what you're doing at
that do and all that
so there's a big better than that
between 86 and 88 89 90 and I think you
need touch bases on that yeah and that's
we started seeing that explosion so yeah
because as you know like it's just
natural that people kind of corrupted
the model that that was brought forward
like a in a true medical access because
obviously if the plant is a medicine and
access not giving access is ridiculous
but every day yeah I just exactly I just
wanted to make sure that in the changing
landscape that is the lp world that
people that I work with wouldn't be
forgotten and there would be space given
to people like yourselves like myself
people like how did you like when people
would say to me you know how did you
help solve the opioid epidemic this is
what I would want to say I brought
people who understand that drug policy
is garbage you know and I mean and
understand that problems are solved from
within community dude and when there's
no solution to the system you require a
new system and that's why what you're
doing is so cool man because you're
you're you're just doing something
completely different that actually works
and I knew people like yourselves would
agree and get on board and that's why I
did it my biggest supporters so far I
hope they don't mind me saying has been
the NCC the National compassion Club and
twisted extracts they're both those have
been two companies which have made it
possible for me to have staff make it
possible I give me it when I could say
you know what ID double the donations
you give me so that's what I'm to do
though it isn't is it the adversity that
you faced that made it so like why don't
you just do what 90% of people do and
just go online and [ __ ] and moan and
and cry about the system and how it's
not really taking care of you like I
just find it amazing why people choose
that over just like you can make change
by doing little things not that what
you're doing is little but it started
little and it's growing bigger and now
no one can deny it it's like the most
ridiculous thing to try and deny that
drug users can be helped on a and and
not just helped on the level of like how
we used to say Oh cannabis will increase
the quality of your life you know while
you're doing chemo and while you're
passing away no it can actually shrink
the tumors out of existence it can
actually help you rid yourself of these
addictions Johnny be how much oxycodone
where you taking every day
280 milligrams a day of oxycontin fast
acting super dolls of another 40 on and
then I had ten milligrams my
prescription drugs for 1,400 maybe eight
dollars a month I was hooked on heavy
pharmaceutical drugs that led in there I
went through these whole stages and
that's why it was easy when I started
talking with Jack I started doing this
home about a couple years I mean we
touch bases try doing things with the
getting feature while trying to get all
these different little mechanism set up
so he can actually supply generates to
all these people that were in need yeah
this is yet it it's it's a great feeling
to see when people actually give back
and stuff like that like myself I'm
always trying to help people I want I
don't know how to help people so I want
people to just grow their own how do I
do that by starting a YouTube channel
and working with everybody and just kind
of giving back as much as you can to
keep to the plan that's the only thing
that doesn't create a gaping hole in
your life Jack said he had everything he
had he had every physical kind of thing
he required and he was left feeling
empty you know because that's not what
makes you feel great in life please
please catch this I might even make it
fullscreen just for this one thing okay
is is your I lost my train of thought
that sucks that was an important one too
connection to other people well it's oh
sorry is the true value of life is not
is not taking it is giving and doing for
other people it's it's giving and doing
and helping that is where you start to
feel that warm glow inside and the more
you do it the better you feel sure you
have to be careful in this world
navigating because there are you know
literally sharks out there that will
consume you whole but that's not to say
you can't surrounded by them yeah you
can you can help I mean look at the work
that this do and it's it's incredible
honestly my next where the next thing
that I'd love to do that I think will be
of the greatest benefit for both
communities the community I serve and
the community at large is to start what
what I would call a therapeutic space
which is actually a grow area
because we like this many Center now you
can have a place where you can grow your
order you have a place where you can
actually learn about cannabis education
I didn't get officers like this there's
there's got to be more of a place where
there's a place where people who truly
want to learn and need and and and and
can't get it better like there are
certain times like I was saying like I
mean we have legalization that's gonna
be nice to me so seeing those those
forms of extracts that I use every day
that are going to be offered to patients
this is gonna be the biggest thing is
really is gonna be those extracts as
high concentrations of THC that you know
that we need right that are needed for
businesses stuff like that so I mean
yeah I agree Johnny what do you win we
do cannabis education classes that I
think heaven the physical garden there I
mean everybody here has been a garden
you know 100 percent the value of
standing in your room when the lights
turn on and all the plants are praying
like you know what that does for you as
a human and I think to give them that
experience instead of just teaching
people to come and be needy and here's a
joint and here's an edible that's not
what I want to do I want to create a
community where they can come in in the
days they feel good enough to water a
plant or pull some leaves or whatever
whatever task it is that they're
contributing to the medicine that
they're getting and then also for the
community it wide right for the grannies
who who think I can grow four plants and
I could do that for those people well
then Jesus come into our community
garden and I could show you how to take
a cutting and I we can talk about how
you we can give those cuttings away we
get people growing their own and be safe
for so long it's a safe this is no go
for just grow yeah this is our way to
overcome some of the shitty rules that
exist in LP system I think of if we band
together as a community to solve a
problem that exists cannabis is a its
health services you know and if we could
use the money from bat to help stem the
tide the tide of the opioid epidemic
then we can look at ourselves and and
know well yeah that that we help do that
with the plant it just seems like that
that's something that I could really get
behind and and that's why I hope the
next steps will be will we get ahead
with a little bit enough money that
we'll be able to get this therapeutic
area growing I'm gonna help you out too
because I I'm all about people growing
therefore and we got your 4.com I just
want people who grow their own form and
yeah yeah I'm gonna hook you up with
every I want to make sure you about you
on four go to your hydroponic stores buy
your stuff go to your bond shops like
people need to start growing their own
because it gets you out of bed it makes
you feel better you see that life come
out of it and the problem was I got a
lot of people were so discouraged with
it because you're over water doing
certain things but you know with with a
few good people we came up with a good
little system that for plants with LED
lighting you don't need AC units you
don't need D Huez you might need to put
in the humidifier stuff like that but
education is the key and Canada can grow
for you go on Amazon go to grow store
pretty sure Walmart all these places
will start carrying different systems
and stuff like that is legal grow your
own you know like we we have twelve to
fourteen hundred members and growing
every day so I just think that times for
if you give me a five thousand plant
count and I'm pretty sure that we can
pull in an industrial space in the
middle of downtown Victoria and and
there you go bang you're doing it you
know and therefore per household but
when you come down to say like apartment
buildings or people I was looking at and
see how people are living with doings I
flew with HIV or different conditions
then you can have one in every damn
apartment I think that we can we can
manhandle rules you know what I mean
like I would I would love to challenge
the for plant in each household because
you know I have fourteen hundred members
who don't have household so where the
[ __ ] you think you're supposed to put
listen ass that's the whole thing like
were you gonna grow their wholeness the
whole household
not everyone has a house I drove around
in nineteen it was 2007 or 2008 when
they tore down my house I had no place
let live in my truck and all I had was
my one plant Medi coach and they would
drive around that in my truck and
there's pictures of it to you I had
nowhere to go with the plan but I kept
them alive that I'm willing to someone's
bathroom estate in there for a few days
I carry this plan
with me and then I did a video on it and
that was like yeah it's like where do
you go like what do you do
amazing yeah was actually here it was a
part of my life when I just got my
license from Health Canada they tore
down my house I was protesting fighting
WCB and I kept that plant with me
because it was the only strain that
helped me so much and I and I remembered
being behind a cop I'm putting it up on
the desk so you could see it and they
just kind of signs on my truck fight
works ABC and they kind of though you
know what I mean but always standing up
for the plant not plant that plant got
me through it took me to so many
different places the cannabis community
that joins and hold you together it was
probably the biggest rewarding thing and
and walking into that lab yeah you know
what memories yeah 2020 is gonna be
explosive you know what I mean what
we've seen happen over the last decade
in 2019 with legalization and
everybody's you know complaining about
it let me say grow your own you know 2.0
is gonna be a different year 2020 we got
it before we just wanted to say you know
we really appreciate the work that
you're doing and we're backing you up so
what we're doing right now is we're
gathering the dem collective which is a
whole lot of farmers internationally we
just gathered as a meeting of the minds
at heartwood Institute in Garberville
California and this was a really big
topic of conversation on how growers
producers extractors distributors
wherever you are in the world how can we
touch compassionate care how can we
touch children who need help people who
you know are financially struggling to
be able to to reach the plant to be able
to get a hold of it so we're with you we
need to hook up and amazing amazing
conversations I really appreciate
meeting you in this format I've watched
you lots of times you know on the on the
church and I just feel privileged that
that Marcus would would have me in
because you know usually this is a
pretty high level tech of weed you know
type of format conversation and so I was
a little bit nervous too even though
this is the kind of [ __ ]
I have to do all the time for work you
know and it's just it's nice to hear
back from the people who've watched
thinking like I know this can work
because when I watch you talk when I
don't know who you are I feel like that
did you wouldn't want to help with this
and and when that comes to fruition it
gives me confidence that
ideas I had five years skulking around
picking up needles on you exchange and
how to incorporate people in the
cannabis business into the unfolding
landscape of change in drug policy and
you know how we could use the opioid
epidemic
you believe them
we lost them yeah I think we did he'll
be back
that was pretty good timing nonetheless
like he thought to say almost anything
it's really important it's really
important I mean it's it's kind of like
when there's hungry people you can give
them a fish and feed him for a day or
you can teach them how to fish and give
them a fishing pole and they can be
self-sufficient growing it's true it's a
nice thing to teach people I mean
there's no doubt about it it's just a
nice thing and I found over the years
just from growing cannabis especially as
you know my kids grew up around it it
gave them not as much interest in
cannabis but it gave them interest in
growing they were just like hey can we
grow like food so we'd start buying
seeds and planting peppers and cucumbers
and lettuce and all these other
different things and it's definitely a
good thing I mean you always kind of
hear the stories of what would happen if
you know you just couldn't go to Safeway
anymore and buy food well what would
happen would be that you would
definitely want to have a seed
collection and start being able to grow
some food and the best thing you can do
is help out others that can do nothing
for you and that is the best feeling in
the world
passing on passing on knowledge and
educating people that will only help
them better themselves it's the best
feeling ever it is true it's really
amazing what an incredible catalyst this
plant is you know it continues to
catalyze and point in directions and it
you know is illuminating areas that have
been dark for a really long time it's
illuminating big a big pharma you know
all of the problems politics poly
corporate X is what you know the word
that I've been using lately and I just
think that this plant is here to save
the world and I think we are the
medicine makers and we are the people
that need to talk about it and bring
this plant out into you know regular
mainstream world so that everybody can
jump on because I know that you all know
that this cannabis culture is
international and we connect on a very
very deep level only because of this
plant and I think it's phenomenal so
it's a unique plant in the sense that
there is this underlining like it seems
to affect compassion and humanity and
empathy and really sort of produce it in
people and that's one of the reasons why
when everyone's so concerned about like
I don't know evil cops and lawyers and
judges all because you know taking over
the cannabis industry I'm like bro they
are messing with a power that is so much
more powerful than any they fought it
for for decades they spent billions of
dollars they destroyed tens of thousands
hundreds of thousands millions of lives
and they lost to a plant and so now
they're gonna lose again they're gonna
try and make it corporate they're gonna
try and be greedy they're gonna try and
do all of these different things but
what they're not gonna understand is
that while you're handling this plant
and breathing it in and being around it
it's going to affect the way you think
promise that's what I'm looking forward
to we said it years ago my partner
actually said it to me years ago Martin
Roth chick who was one of the founders
of Manitoba harvest before Manitoba
harvest was started we were growing a
5-acre Hempfield just experimentally in
1995 in just outside of Winnipeg and I
was quite young at the time I remember I
was maybe 21 one years old or something
21 or 22 and he said to me as we left
the field in my van and we kind of
looked back and we had to hide the field
also it was not right on the highway but
he said you know this is gonna change
the way people think and that wasn't
even anything medical that was just
cannabis growing in acres in the
prairies and it truly did change the way
people think they started seeing it at
the grocery store they started consuming
it you know they're putting it into
their bodies is that affecting them of
course it is absolutely it's just a very
unique plant that is like it's viral in
the sense that it just gets out there
and these people that think they're
going to cage it and control it I think
that they'll see it'll it'll work about
as well as their prohibition did the
Mayan Prophecy also states that a flower
is what is going to save this modern
culture these modern people a single
flower and it makes a whole lot of sense
to me that this is going to be the thing
that saves the world
on that note D 420k can I get aa bone
rip mother lovers Jack's got his little
girl just in time
nice for mother lovers you know how long
I've been waiting for that it's kind of
funny you just kind of created like the
the motto or whatever it is you know
between you and dr. mark with his with
his cash church song that was also
pretty classic pretty classic nice to be
gathering with all of you and heard I'm
trying to put dry cyst on well I'm just
gonna say Aloha and Happy New Year's
everyone happy 2020 are you
come on Maui yes I'm jealous I was able
to get medical cannabis here too because
I have a I have a California cannabis
card and if you submit to cap to Hawaii
which I did last Saturday night and on
Monday I had my card so I actually went
to the dispensary and bought cannabis
and carts and all kinds of stuff just to
see what their program is like here on
the island I mean does that as well just
north of me and it's really nice because
it allows people to to check out
different growers and different
processors and really learn about what
everybody is doing it's really quite
nice yeah I would say the cannabis here
is circa 2004 2005 California it's it's
got a ways to go
the they don't have many people coming
so the cannabis seems to sit around a
while so the church and everything are
gonna be stored in these bottles that
are have a lot of oxygen and air and
so like me we exactly like all of it I
was like I would sit bone dry in a
container that just yeah sounds familiar
up here oh not bone dry the prices are a
little high you know because they have
to grow it and produce it on top of that
such as their oil here is a black sludge
because they can't use BHO or anything
else so they use alcohol Sonya is that
wonderful 2003 sludge flavor on top of
it on that there's a bubbles as well or
black sludge because again they can't
use BHO that's a class three felony here
so in Hawaii you need to work on your
laws here to get better medicine but it
was really just got a you can actually
use alcohol and do a really fast wash in
an ultrasonic machine for 30 seconds or
less than a minute and you come out with
absolutely did you hear that Hawaii such
a boring problem what's that Mike I know
it's such a boring problem making light
colored oil yeah there's plenty of ways
of doing that
just fill your solvent down right you
could use filtration there's lots of
ways of making nice or alcohol right
make dark oil it just says that yeah a
little behind bootstrapping it so I mean
they're they still haven't caught up
their technology as well as I don't
think they get out to the shows to see
what technologies out you know much less
what of roto vape is the actual cannabis
culture there at chann like you must
know people that are like born and bred
living there like that are growing
beautiful herbs and life and I have
beautiful herb that is much better than
what's grown there and I've known people
living here for decades so I get good
herb here and get a good hash
but it's just the system itself there's
two dispensaries on the island so
there's only two groves and they have to
grow and produce what they produce so
not only they're going to produce that
they have to extract it they have to
package it they have to put it in the
bottles and then you know get a show so
it's still very limited in supply I
would say ten types of herb three types
of hash three types of partridges
they're not allowed edibles here which
is different from when I got married in
Alaska they now are allowed to have
concentrates where they start off with
edibles couldn't have concentrates now
they have concentrates whereas here in
Hawaii there are no edibles and that's a
problem for people they do have pills
which are popular but no edible they
also do allow home growing though a
certain number of clients correct yes I
think it's for plants we wanted to take
a minute to to Hawaii
cannabis Expo Dana CG Oni and he just
invited us to come and we're gonna be
doing a presentation on preserving Aloha
the regenerative cannabis agriculture
and it's just amazing like we've been
having unbelievable conversations and
we've seen some beautiful weed from
Hawaii we were just at the Emerald cup
and the pakalolo farmers and a lot of
the cooperatives that are going on there
and all of the islands we're gonna be
doing a demo here Aloha love tour coming
up we're gonna go visit a whole bunch of
farms and that outreach is just massive
and we're gonna go kama ina style we're
going to the farms we're just gonna go
and visit we're gonna hang out we're
gonna share some knowledge of the Hawaii
and some of our original inspiration you
know was going to Kauai and being in the
islands and natural farming is a huge
explosion and a wave of consciousness
that's happening through cannabis right
now and a lot of that came into America
from Hawaii so there there are a lot of
amazing people on Hawaii growing it's
the system that's really kind of bunk so
like you know having to be able to it's
actually kind of a blessing to be able
to have an
grated system where you grow and produce
all your own stuff but if there's more
people involved you know so you can get
some you know different products on the
table that was yeah idea like never
before that community is reaching out to
the international community and it's
really beautiful so Mahalo to all the
Hawaii listeners out there and Mahalo
Nui low to the Hawaii cannabis
conference for inviting and regenerative
practices businesses cultivation
extraction right on I love you guys
yes hey speaking of shout uh get to
general cup and I get there mo cup and
much love to every he's not coming in
but you know we were just out to the
Emerald cup and met a lot of the family
from from Hawaii and they are everyone
is going to all the conference's you
know it's just a matter of getting
everything in place and eating what you
want
you know Nate some people have to speak
up mmm I'm gonna get down to the u.s.
one of these days it was definitely a
Hawaii especially I mean that's just
like a hop skip and a jump from
Vancouver
well fellow named Chris Cole took my
class couple years ago and he's the I
think product manager at a place called
Maui grown or something like that he
seems to be pretty knowledgeable on
extraction but yeah it sounds like their
hands are tied
based on what regulation allows be
interesting to see if they could
actually get decent rosin because I
would certainly think that that would be
something that that BHO isn't allowed so
the next best sort of flavorful extract
that's that high you know Terp extract
you can get and in a pretty safe process
that doesn't involve flammable solvent
would be would be bubble rosin now I
mean it's probably more of an opinion
than anything I mean I'll tell you some
of the tastiest Terr pious loudest [ __ ]
I ever put in a pike was Sam's dry sift
and I think just because other people
have never have never seen it they don't
think it exists so they say things like
Oh alive resins the loudest well just
the for commercial production note can
that actually be something that's viable
can you actually make a product that way
reliably and well I mean Cuban grower
did he seems to have a version of 99.9
percent it's all relative to what your
customers are willing to pay sure very
limited supply though I mean like what
you want to have a you know a more
robust process kind of like what you
guys run
yeah I don't know the main difference
between dry cept and water hash and
flour rosin is rice if we get a very
small yield from the plant with water
you get a much higher you okay but the
thing that we haven't mentioned is that
the way you grow Sam and your
understanding of grown growing your like
a plant whisperer the your your plant
express themselves little frightening
way to grow in the ground
I know organically in the ground there's
some with some with some yeah and in
white they have a longer season you can
grow outdoors and why you grow really
late Merilee drug varieties they produce
fantastic product but it's not
mass-produced people are growing small
amounts of it because it's not
mass-produced yeah yeah we'll see one
day maybe hey Sam I got a question
around Island produced weed you know
like a lot of the Caribbean islands have
very high calcium levels in the soil
because they're basically coral or
volcanic but there's still a lot of
calcium is there ways that you can
counteract all the calcium richness in
Island soils so yeah what do you want to
do you want to raise the pH or is it the
pH because I think it's just a high
preponderance of calcium in the soil
just totally screws up some varieties
and and they're trying to solve that
down in the Caribbean yeah I think it's
because to make them I'm not sure if it
has to do whether it's a coral island or
a volcanic island the Caribbean islands
are coral based
so that it has a higher coral coral
reefs which then turn into limestone
calcite carbonate so that's generally
gonna make more basic but one of the
nice things about the tropics is you can
there's world ruin world around in the
tropics is coco coir one of the things
that is a big issue with cars the salt
ratio but it is core does act as a good
buffer for calcium but I generally
Dragonfly hit the head on the nail when
you look at fungal dominant soils in
general fungal dominant soils tend to be
slightly more acidic so you know
throwing compost would a lot of Coco
Coco pith or cocoa husk is going to help
kind of buffer some of the calcium
chloride mulch mulch like your life
depends on it become a mound farmer when
you think you have too much on there
throw 10 times more of stuff on top of
it and create a mound and yo-you mulch
mulch
there's not oh it's called compost
because you're just putting the compost
on top of the beds on top of the plants
you know cold compost is mulching layer
there yeah that's true and you know even
on Jimmy there's a lot of different
kinds of soil so I mean you got red dirt
you got the black dirt you got the hard
coral dirt in wet side of the island dry
side so you know if you're on an island
you have to really use if you need to
you know different parts of the island
for my favorite thing about Jamaica and
generally any island and watching new
people be like I'm gonna go and grow
herb like in Jamaica or st. Lucia and
wherever and I'm just like we'll have
you ever for my prior life is an
industrial scientist we did a
a wood decay study on the Island of
Hawaii as it turns out
Hawaii is an ideal place to study wood
preservatives because of the fauna there
and what I noticed is that from one side
of the island to the other the the
stratigraphy or the geography or the
geology I guess that's the word I'm
looking for changed immensely on one
side of the island we basically needed a
chisel to put stakes into the ground the
island dirt or the soil was like so hard
and almost impenetrable and on the other
side of the island it was like floral
and swampy and lush it was just it was
just so different that it was just only
literally I think maybe about like 20 or
30 miles from each other it was just a
completely different geology so is that
to known as the leeward and the
essentially in sailing in sailing mini
it has to do with where the prevailing
wind is right exactly so obviously if
you're an island you get you get hit
from a prevailing wind side generally
it's you know in the Atlantic Ocean
Caribbean it's going to be facing the
Atlantic that wind is that side of the
mountain is going to have most of the
moisture picked up and then deposited on
on the leeward side I think it is where
the rain or the rain shadow says that's
wrong straws and the toothbrushes and
the tampon wrappers and all the other
disgusting [ __ ] ends up now - sorry it's
sittin Sam what were you about to say
it's like I thought I was saying that
when an island has a mountain like
Hawaii
it's got the north side in the south
side the north side is much wetter than
for example exactly what it was Sam
interesting so in terms of the islands
you know
let's take you know Antigua for instance
you who's got an interesting thing on
unraveling their you know coral has a
lot of calcium
would it be best to to dig up that soil
and and amend it
you know what would your your thoughts
on on going directly in the dirt and and
using amendments the I wouldn't a
thousand percent just build mounds on
top of it and forget about what's
happening below it because what's
happening below it's gonna transform as
soon as every worm in the area comes and
all the micro but nothing changes
earth-like microbiology so it's it's
kind of just like oh especially in
Jamaica I mean there's every kind of
vegetation in the world so what you'd
want to do it was just crap you know get
a machete and just go and just start
getting all the different kinds of you
know leaves and stuff that you can you
know and then you find some you know
it's around for some go do we're on
there a lot less sticks there's lots of
sticks around and and the sticks or are
incredibly important and and banana
trees are always constantly shedding and
banana trees are you know really
prolific around any tropical area and
when we were injured we chipped up all
the banana and the bamboo that was down
on the ground that was fresh and the
brown so you get a mixed green and brown
and within two weeks we were directly
planting inside of that shipped you know
mass and the plants just took right off
and most most have little deposits on
the land somewhere pretty decent soils
so you can kind of layer that on the top
of whatever you've prepared as a bed you
can kind of use that as a starting off
point for your transplanting or even you
know get some of the topsoil off and
kind of pull it on top of the bed and
sort of cap off what you've created or
organic matter wise and then you know
the plant grows and you just keep doing
it over the course of the year or you
could just take Uriel and make like a
hole like this inside of the material
fill it with some nice dirt that you
feel like has you know a good proper
ratio good balance and then plant a seed
directly into there and by the time that
the plant matures it's actually ready to
come
breakdown material so so the
microbiology is breaking down over time
and and it's interesting you said I only
have experience in Costa Rica growing
actually crops in that particular
climate and it's similar but it's
different because the soil down there is
very the biology is very different but
it's it has its own challenges so it's
really it's great to hear that the
layering technique is working for you
guys in in terms of Jamaica because that
you know I've gotten a lot of questions
for people in Antigua and things like
that and I don't have enough experience
so this is it's great we can have this
dialogue here to share that information
[Music]
next crop on the ground cover them with
about 3 feet of mulch and the potatoes
would root into the ground and just from
right through the mulch and then
afterwards I didn't have to dig up the
tomatoes I just had to pull the mulch
off hmm well that's kind of what I'm
talking about with Mound life I mean
it's it's kind of a man mentality it's
almost like you're just a mob gardener
you're just you'd plant as much as you
can on the mound and and use it to your
advantage it also saves water and and
these are not just techniques that work
in Jamaica of course like we you've gone
to Bali Thailand South East Asia
different places Hawaii all the islands
we're going again to Hawaii like we said
so we're really excited but these
techniques are not really they work
everywhere we're in British Columbia we
do it we are walking looking all down
the west coast to Michigan tomato I'm in
Jamaica I'm in Bali it's it's working
everywhere it does change what you're
layering you know I mean the
biodiversity of your bio region is what
you're gonna use so I were just not
really needing to bring men mints all
over the place we're using what we have
there and also plastic culture I mean
mark mentioned the word plastic and
plastic is is really killing the earth
and its really stab looking at modern
agriculture use plastics so much
and again layering and using mulch is
the answer to to plastic it stops weeds
from growing and it builds soil I could
go on forever about we're super
solutions orientated but I just wanted
to take one one second to talk about a
major problem and can save the world
but plastic culture had cannot so it's
really important that we become
intelligent on how we're planting this
incredibly sacred plant that is what we
were talking about earlier going to save
the world is going to change people's
minds you need to do it in a way that's
respectful to the earth will stop
plastic is for oil to get too expensive
to make single-use plastic until it oil
is expensive we will have plastic or
never damn it's so sadly true but we'll
see
well dr. mark had some interesting
thoughts on plastic I think last time we
were on the show and and if Mark if you
can elaborate a little bit more on the
on the knowledge you have with with
using hemp you know the last time we
talked you had some really interesting
thoughts about that and I was wondering
if you could share some more that it
looks like mark is not with us at the
moment oh no I thought he was the one
talking about how plastic is not he felt
like it was viable he had some very
interesting thoughts that are different
than what I've heard I don't know enough
about and plastics to speed on it but I
I'm so fascinated in its the problem
that we've seen is that there's no
conventional recycler that will take the
current hemp plastic that's being made
that's out there or at least like I
think it's Cerner who is pushing that
currently so the problem is we can get a
hand plastic to the problem is you can't
recycle it no recycling place would take
it so there's a whole problem of the
supply chain still that these products
are created but the they haven't figured
how to break it down right a pet plant
is biodegradable you don't have to
recycle it you can you know put it in
compost piles these are not compostable
though right so that then answers the
question and the thing that makes you
know the way that it's tucked together
you know what is emulsified not together
which is polymers and a half-life of
these polymers you know just because you
can't meet it with a naked eye doesn't
mean that it's not just lying there in
the soil and what they call
biodegradable which definitely you know
severely changes microbiology in the
soil if you're having residual polymers
sure yeah
we're uh we're pretty messed up we we
start using our heads to start trying to
fix problems and three new problems and
I mean the intention was good however
it's still not done we still have to
what do they say what the road to hell
good intentions my friend I know that
Donna packaging sa na Colorado is making
different biodegradable plastics and
hemp plastics and there are really heavy
good packaging company and packaging is
a really important issue to talk about
and even with hemp cultivation I mean do
we need and in New York I know it's like
there's a few classification perhaps
there's cannabinoid and industrial hemp
and if you add or again you might think
industr does the enemy you know and you
can't have male and female plants around
but when you're talking about a food
source or you're talking about plastics
instead of you know polymers and and
maybe there's polymers in the hemp
plastic I don't know where's mark but
yeah we are needing to move forward with
intelligent
culture decisions and having industrial
hemp growing on earth is extremely
important for fibers I mean we're
wearing cotton and cotton this still
slave laborers being used to produce
cotton all over the place and if we had
him more hemp textiles we would know
where it came from and the supply chain
of where it came from so it's all part
of that see I don't think anybody's
producing hemp fiber they need to Canada
or America
yeah exactly and I wish that that you
know we could somehow see be instead
Taylor so one gate for you know big
wide-open Prairie is that are you know
growing canola are growing corn or
brochure you know alfalfa it would be
really amazing to see a lot of textile
going on in Canada it's all about the
machinery well it's a quick oh go ahead
like no this is Colin oh I was just
saying that there's a couple mills in
New York State that are very interested
in the material itself I think for them
it's about is there a market for them
and how do they learn to work within
that market and that's what I know from
from talking to them but a you know I
would love to see more fabrics and
things like that and Marcus you had
mentioned M Taylor that was hoodlum and
I wear their jackets all the time and
you know it's not a hundred percent damp
but it's a it's a very nice brand that's
been around for a while that's been
really embracing Hampton and t really is
processing and and the factories that
you have to build for processing
spinning wheat multi-million dollar
fifty miles of the where it's meeting
grown you can't be trucking the hemp all
over the universe sure well I know a
Taylor is working on a project in the
u.s. to produce fibers grow them in the
us and produce fibers and and you know
make make products for sale that's one
of the things that they're trying to do
in 2020 yeah ultimately when you look at
the evolution and deployment of hemp in
North America the a lot of Europe as
well as they didn't ban hemp as heavily
as North America did during Prohibition
so many of the many of the European
clothing designers continued to have
access to hemp in forms of different
forms of canvas or silk or soap blends
now that hemp has slowly been regulated
here in North America we're starting to
see a lot of brands focusing on CBD but
there are some brands working on either
food or fiber or plastic prod products
the issue is is like mentioned you know
you need to have you know your supply
relatively close you know within two to
three hundred kilometres and enough
acreage being cultivated in order to you
know process and run that facility that
lumber mill that fiber plant the quartic
ating line or even seed line for seed
oil processing and operate that plant
for 300 to 320 days a year
in order to you know anybody who
processes any factory primary processor
that processes him no no I don't it all
has to be within 50 kilometers right
exactly yeah that makes sense
all right I'm back okay where do we
begin
oh my gosh yeah I don't know my i think
the russians hacked my computer in
fashion they didn't want to be telling
the truth
let's see here so yeah have plastic so
the people out selling hemp plastic
right now are you know hemp is a is a is
a source
of cellulose but so is switchgrass and
so is trees so it has to be economical
if it's not economical it's difficult to
convince people to put capital
investment into a business that's not
going to make money so it has to be able
to make money and Sam hit the nail on
the head in fact I'll go back to
something that Sam I just said which is
as long as we have cheap oil and cheap
petrochemical sources we will continue
to create and make and use single-use
plastic the other thing that cheap oil
unfortunately handicaps is the cost of
all alternative energy whether it's
windmills dams wave catchers whatever
you use in to generate energy ultimately
the cost of that alternative energy is
pegged to the price of fossil fuels
because of the infrastructure that
currently exists today and that's you
know Walmart Amazon the industrial
manufacturing base which uses a lot of
petrochemical fuel because that's the
cheapest form of fuel on the planet you
know the notion that we can somehow turn
have into fuel is is really not based in
reality at all because it actually
consumes more fuel to convert have into
ethanol than it then it creates so
you're actually it's a negative it it
actually uses more petrochemicals and
the only reason why they can pull that
stunt off down in Brazil and places that
are growing sugarcane is because they
have a lot of cane juice which is
enriched with sugar which all you do is
you throw yeast in there and then the
yeast makes the sugar poop out ethanol
and yeah you could put ethanol in as a
liquid fuel down in places where there
already is
investment made into an infrastructure
to grow sugar cane on a shit-ton [ __ ]
scale right and so that's why Ethan all
can make a solution down there but
turning happen to ethanol I always see
all these memes about all the things
that hemp can do and turning it into a
liquid biofuel is absolutely crazy and
and and and nuts and and and you can get
the seed oil seed oils can be burned but
it has such a more higher value as a
nutritional product and what you can do
with seed oils as opposed to the lowest
value of something that you just put
into an internal combustion engine or
some generator to burn just for its fuel
value I mean it's just absolutely
ridiculous in fact the analysis has
already been done on biofuels and this
is why you don't see cellulosic ethanol
being produced today is that if you take
the same amount of cellulose and rather
than you know cellular think of
cellulose is it's it's high molecular
weight glucose it's a glucose molecule
which is a sugar which it's a many many
different copy so it sees high long
chains and so think of that as storage
sunlight right so it took a lot of
energy by the plant through
photosynthesis to convert those photons
into this long molecule so the wonderful
thing about cellulose and Cellular's
derived from heme is it's amazingly
strong you know depending on how you
measure its strength it could be as
strong as super high-strength fibers
like Kevlar so it really it makes sense
to use the heme not to digest it down to
a sugar to feed to a yeast to poop it
over into ethanol we're there's a
tremendous capacity that exists today in
the world for grain derived ethanol we
don't need ethanol from half
that's stupid and it doesn't make sense
and because it can't you can't make
money doing it
you'll never be capital investment into
it but what there will be capital
investment into is where you could use
the strength of the hemp fibers to
reinforce composite materials and I
think that that's sort of like where
have plastic is going the current if you
google have plastic and you go to that
site what you'll see is that they're
taking regular plastics like poly
carbonate that's what my computer's made
out that's what my I think that's what
my glass frame is made out of
polycarbonate plastic it's what CD ROMs
are made out of polypropylene
polyethylene these are all petrochemical
derived polymers and what they're doing
is they're taking a petrochemical
derived polymer that cost about 25 cents
to 75 cents a pound they're adding hemp
fiber right in terms of either heard or
actually elongated fibers or oriented
fibers right to get the inherent
strength that those fibers give to the
material so now you can use say rather a
2-inch piece of plastic in that support
versus a you know five inch piece of
plastic so you're using less plastic
because you're using the strength of the
hemp fibers to be enforced of plastic
but the problem is is that they're
trying to sell that plastic in
competition with the 20 cent a pound
plastic at like 2 or 5 bucks a pound so
who's gonna buy an incumbent at 2 or 5
dollars a pound
it still has petrochemical derived
plastic in it right but it has happen it
which I guess is cool right because it's
and they're lightweight again again
you're used the world will use less
plastic but you know basically what
they're competing with is one of the
ingredients that's in their product
right and and so there's other fibers
that you could use you know jute is used
quite a bit
there's a lot of other fibers that can
be used other than ham I so this is what
I've said on hash Church a few times and
thanks for bringing it up because again
it's just a reoccurring theme and I
don't think that things have changed a
whole lot what's really going to change
I think and have is is not necessarily
going to be the CBD aspect I think it's
going to be the fact that we have to
feed more people
unless irritable farmable land in the
future and so if you have to raise
protein per acre to feed livestock right
now soybean delivers somewhere between
360 to 380 pounds of soluble protein per
acre with hemp they believe the
estimates are somewhere north of a
thousand pounds an acre so when it comes
to how do you use an acre of land most
efficiently raise a plant that produces
protein that humans need and animals
need in their diet it will be half hands
down as as the winner but now you're
taking on the likes of Syngenta and
Monsanto and DuPont and Cargill and
Bungie and archers Daniel Midland
you're taking on the large corporate
machine that exists and that have put
genetically modified crops into our diet
and into Commerce so yeah it's all up to
mark that hemp will not give you that
much protein per acre I mean most
probably they don't really know I I can
tell you because I was out on Hempfield
this this past year um ahem produces a
[ __ ] ton of [ __ ] seeds man I mean
holy [ __ ] we had a couple a couple areas
go out to seed Sam and believable this
is a growing heresy for years and years
and years you get ton per acre is tough
you know well
right now in the world is finola that's
a variety I develop okay that'll give
you to fund and that way what's gonna
happen is that food is gonna be the main
driver for him to oversee bean and at
that point there will need to be
infrastructure to process all of this
available hemp fiber which is a
byproduct and as you know Marcus hemp
oil creates a heart healthy oil that
should be more prevalent in humans diets
I think that that's gonna be the
ultimate driver that's gonna create all
this hat biomass that you're gonna start
seeing you know paper products cardboard
craft paper craft papers just think of
like brown paper bag or brown cardboard
that's called craft paper which is
nothing more than just ground up trees
newsprint you know what newspaper is
printed on is nothing more than just
ground-up trees so you know they're
taking basically the waste off of the
sawmill floor after they've gone through
and lumbered as much as they possibly
can out of the trees bring it across the
street to the paper mill and use the old
craft process which requires sulfur
that's why it always smells like rotten
eggs in and around the the paper mill
which is right next to thee right next
to the right next to the maybe in the
future what you'll see is you'll see a
ham farm and then next to the hemp farm
because they're processing oil and
crushin seeds and and making that
beautiful oil that Marcus has showed
pictures of and ultimately next door
will be a hemp fiber processing plant
that'll press that [ __ ] into boards and
and cardboard and paper and fiber and
all the other stuff is that going to
replace plastic now the unfortunately
you can't make plastic moldable plastics
like polyethylene and polypropylene
which are used
and processed they usually come in these
huge barrels and they're just these
small little beads and they melt and in
the melt they can be processed and
formed into the screen of your laptop or
the case of yourself you can't do that
with cellulose based polymers when you
when you heat up cellulose based
polymers they they degrade in the melt
and so the cellulose based polymers like
cellophane which is just xanthate 'add
cellulose just to make it soluble has to
be solvent based and cast and films and
they don't have an engineering modulus
so they can't be used like more
thermoset polymers which you know again
flowin to melt set up in the mouth make
high molecular weight strong plastic
components were things like marine you
know aeronautical and and and
transportation we can't rid ourselves
from plastic I don't think I think
plastics is going to be around we just
got to try to get away from single-use
plastic for cellulose wasn't
biodegradable we would be choking in the
forest so cellophane could be used for a
lot of things but clear plastic as well
Sophie yeah is used to wrap candy bars
and I mean cellophane was actually I
think it wasn't invented in DuPont I
think the Germans invented it but DuPont
stole it I think and they you know again
that was a big advance to be able to
keep bread fresh you know these to say
oh that's greater than sliced bread I
think that came back from the fact that
you could make sliced bread put it in a
cellophane wrapped package and it could
actually maintain its freshness that was
a that was a real advance many years ago
better than sliced bread okay so can we
shift a little bit into this th CP paper
that was that's a great topic I was
gonna you had to almost predict it right
because the smaller homologs were known
right like tcv was known no this is just
you know so it's got a couple extra
carbons on the on the output a love of
the molecule and if you know about the
biosynthetic pathway the way that's put
together through the polyketide synthase
you'll know that you could change the
substrate on which that enzyme acts on
and it just extends the Tinkertoys just
two more carbon atoms so yeah i mean i
think it's really cool that they found
it and then they they came up with a
synthesis of it too which is italians
are noted for their synthetic work so
it's beautiful to see nice piece of
synthesis come out on how to make the
molecule so they can identify it and
then they showed a little bit of data in
mice right i I got the paper open on my
desktop and look at can you can you send
the link so I can send it in Marcus or
send it into the YouTube chat room
either or no one my computer crashed I
lost the whole I'll just take a second
no problem any human being taken DHCP
yet have you heard of any human beat I
don't need a tiny tiny amount right
might be found in the planet I mean
signaling even a 90% or 100% pure like
wow I have no earthly idea I mean I've
just read about the molecule for the
first time I think a week ago today on
my birthday I think I found out about
this is just like you know just read
about it so I have no [ __ ] clue but
you know there's a tie and who knows
what the [ __ ] they're up to right in
fact I think from what I remember from
reading I think on a thread on a
facebook chat someone told me that this
was actually
owned by the Italian Army you know see
that's what I'm payin along I think that
governments and and high-powered people
have known about crazy cannabinoids in
cannabis for you there's an as part of
why they squashed it because it can't be
GMO and then there's these things that
keep people alive forever and and things
in there I certainly can be GMOs you're
wrong well anyway it also breaks rules
so we'll see what happens when you GMO
it I want to hear what happens when the
human being tries it remember pure THC
is the ultimate whatever yes twenty
years ago and it wasn't as strong as 90%
resin head hash from skunk because skunk
had the terpenes and that potentiated
the pure THC even stronger than pure THC
so this is this is one curiosity that I
think a lot of people are interested in
this particular molecule because they
did some dockings you know we all know
that the the active site of cb1 is now
known right there's a crystal structure
of it right and the promise of having a
crystal structure of your receptor is
think of it as like the photographic
negative for what you want the molecule
to look like right key to fit in the
lock right so if you know what the
receptor looks like well [ __ ] you should
be able to design the perfect lock
that's called rational drug design well
rational drug design doesn't always work
as well as it should however it's awful
good at making predictions around
potency and and relative potency and and
the molecular mechanic calculations come
out that this thing has 30 x times the
binding energy by extending the alkyl
chain by two carbons which is a
fascinating
Oshin because you know the question is
is how long does that hydrophobic
channel and the active site of the
enzyme it is I mean maybe you could
extend it a little bit more maybe every
time you extend it or maybe there's a
sweet spot and have to extend it too
much it won't fit in there anymore or
maybe like a lot of alkyl chains they
end up actually not sort of wagging out
in a straight fashion like you would
draw it on the molecular structure but
what they end up actually doing is
curling back on the molecule itself and
creating some kind of three-dimensional
you know topography on the molecule that
just gives a better fit into the
receptor site so I'll finish by just
saying the molecular mechanics predict
that there's going to be a 30x increase
in binding now again that's just a
computer model and docking this thing on
the computer this is what the computer
says ultimately how potent it is I think
needs to be fleshed out in take pure T C
and you smoke it then delivers THC to
the bloodstream in the brain if you eat
it it delivers 11 hydroxy to the brain
and the bloodstream so after a pass
through the liver now I'm wondering the
same thing about this G HCV I mean if
you eat it and you smoke it are there
different potencies different effects
because 11 hydroxy GHC don't have
identical effects
no I think part of the 1100 C issue is
that when you increase the polarity of
the molecule it decreases its ability to
cross the blood-brain barrier
blood-brain barrier is a very very
hydrophobic kind of passage and
certainly changing the polarity of the
molecule even changing from THC a the
THC even though there's a lot of arguing
and speculation on this
a lot of belief is is that that change
in and of itself is affecting it's
promiscuity across the blood-brain
barrier not everything that's in the
blood makes it into the brain and vice
versa so there has to be some
compartment and an understanding on what
types of properties of molecules make
make that happen I think I mentioned
this last year we're working with a
group in Minnesota that has a liposomal
delivery to sneak things across the
blood-brain barrier and wouldn't it be
great to find out that again like you
say Sam by the time it gets in there
it's the 11 hydroxy and oh it's a whole
lot less because it doesn't cross as
readily as THC but it also has I think a
higher affinity for cb1 receptor in and
of itself I mean that's I think what
most interests me is that if you can
increase this alkyl chain maybe again
the decrease in the alkyl chain is one
of the reasons why you see differential
activity with THC v so the longer that
alkyl chain comes the more potent it is
and and maybe again that's something
that could be potentiated by terpenes or
something maybe that's not but I'd like
to think and I don't know I have no data
to support this at all but this is just
one of those ghost cannabinoids that has
been in cannabis forever we're just
discovering it now right now he has a
couple like this so this would so just
like they all have like a c3 analog like
the variants they all have them
much cutting out Russians keep freezing
mark
oh I'm sorry there's no reason to
believe that if the c9 is there and the
c7 is there that the c11 and the C
a13 all these different alkyl chains
might be there because again it may just
be the promiscuity of the polyketide
synthase that's in that particular
strain that determines what of those
minor metabolites are made but I find
really interesting is it's found in the
plant so that's yeah I can breed what
one that's 90% th e e yeah I mean I
think it's always been there we just
never knew it yeah yeah GDP GDP CD c BD
p CB you know right exactly
there's no reason to believe that's
unique to the c5 commander so yeah it's
really cool I love the fact that they
synthesized it too right isn't that just
so great shows you how easy these
molecules are to make you know plant
does a really great job in synthesizing
them but you know that they're probably
going to put that try to express that
the genes that code for that enzyme in
yeast and and and and and and and try to
make it in bacteria and algae and other
things through heterologous expression
that turns out to be another real
exciting field and cannabinoids today is
you know the ability to make them
outside of the plant for the pineapple
Sam so in terms of breeding I you know
Sam in all your years that you know
since this is a new cannabinoid do you
believe that you know a lot will be
revealed in terms of a
isolating this and and you know a
genetic selection and is this something
you think that we will be able to you
know exploit the same ways we've been
able to you can pretty for it but right
now the levels are extremely extremely
extremely my new so right you what you
need to do is get a population that has
a significant amount whether that 25 or
you know just half of one percent even
and then by stuffing and breeding that
you can you know quickly give it up to
boy above 10 percent and then from there
you take it into the program and then
select DHCP but do people take it like I
said everybody care tht was a catch me
out
well it's only half as strong as 50% of
THC it resin with the right Derby's so
what about THC P with the right terpenes
no I don't know discovery so these
people have found it in these varieties
of cannabis it may be in all the
varieties of cannabis that we've ever
smoked we also might be in their
standard food see it it's the third
shallow and and the file in and it's
right but I don't you know like hey the
underdog could pull through - you never
know what I always said it that things
that we might not recognize or have
discovered that are present in the
smallest amounts may have very profound
effects on these on these these
entourage effects do it is finding the
peaks when they analyze this either high
pressure liquid chromatography or maybe
even mass spec or mass spec man that's
right it's a molecular weight is that
molecular weight and to figure it out
and then what they did is they went back
and synthesized the decarboxylated
I understand exactly and if you look at
it but peak that they found was so
[ __ ] minut it's a they've already
identified all the bigger piece now the
finding really minut ones
yeah the concentrations that they
reported if I remember correctly I
thought my head was about 60 milligrams
per gram so it's it's it's very very my
name I think the CBD one was like maybe
about half that like 30 milligrams per
gram so yes very very minut amount but I
think what what I I think what this
demonstrates is the promiscuity of the
polyketide synthase which puts together
that building block in the in the
cannabinoid biosynthesis it you should
be exactly the same with all the minor 1
2 3 4 5 it was not a large amount now
this is recall in science of a football
team paper because you look at look at
how many authors 12 authors holy [ __ ] I
wish I had 11 scientists in my lab all
with Italian last name running around
doing this kind of work
holy [ __ ] football in size paper
here this is huh
this is significant I mean I'm again
this is a very significant finding
certainly a wonderful thing to see in
the literature now the question is is
like when we've characterized our
extracts before and we can characterize
say 95 or 96 percent is the remaining 2%
molecules like this that again now now
we could really try to quantify
everything that we're extracting out of
the plant there's going to be several
more discoveries like this I think that
are gonna help understand what those
minor third and fourth cellos in the
orchestra are thanks for sharing your
green mic yeah I love that the plant is
offering this chemistry to us and I love
that the scientists including folks on
the panel today are trying to understand
what this plant is doing and I loved
Mark's suggestion we might have we might
have been consuming this cannabinoid all
along it's why I think the whole plant
thing is so important and meantime happy
new year everyone and sorry my camera's
not working but yeah this is this is a
really great church this morning I among
other things the conversation about
Hawaii and how to restore soil on
Islands it would apply to urban
landscapes and places where mining
activity has happened and whatnot you
can you can use the use the material you
got and and really a lot I've been
fascinated lately by reading up on
what's called Korean natural farming and
kind of stunned at how much of it I'm
already doing in my practices here and
the dim pure family really defined
beautifully a lot of what's going on
there I really do think that it's it's
in the genetics of the plant as well as
in the practices of how we share with
people how to work with this plant
everything from in the garden - when
you're offering it to an end user for
its therapeutic effects the whole plant
is the real story and that's all I got
at the moment I just love the church
thank you all of you for coming it's so
beautiful to see you and like I said I'm
gonna figure out I might have to replace
my computer to get this camera issue
fixed but much love and happy new year
and I think 2020 we're gonna be able to
see better
ciao yeah thanks for sharing wait I was
hoping we'd hear from you at one point
in time we've had oh we've had some some
long long dominated conversations with
specific people which have been
absolutely incredible and amazing but I
love to hear from some of you guys that
haven't said anything we haven't heard
from Dee we haven't heard from Sabo it's
true yeah I've been drinking deep as
well Marcus this is so beautiful thank
you for making this happen this morning
yeah well a new year a new a new energy
available so the last year was very busy
for me and I sort of was unable to focus
on I'm really making videos on on really
posting on YouTube and a couple of key
things YouTube sort of closed my channel
but they definitely made some changes to
my channel on their end where I was I
wasn't even sure if I was even gonna be
able to still live stream so I'm glad
that we're able to do that that's kind
of a blessing and it's always good to be
able to send out a link and actually get
you know get some of you just to say
yeah I'll come in cuz that's the key
right if I show up by myself it's not
it's not a show so we're gonna it's good
I'd love to talk about cannabis hash
everything 2020 everybody in chat to
write the chat is just chat
it takes on its own right and it
police's itself right when someone gets
out of line just a bunch of peaceful
cannabinoids universal bong rip with
everybody in the chat online in the
video all of it it's always nice to do
that on a Sunday morning all right
Ashley reliving that bong rip that Santa
Claus came and had with us that one time
there that's why I had to stay from
children yeah you teeth will be hammered
on me too I wasn't able to do anything
for months like you can upload you
couldn't even they can only comment on
stuff so people are always asking you
can't upload videos on but people be
getting slapped with all these new rules
and I hate doing videos saying that hey
if you're 19 please don't be on my
channel there's it's it's I think really
come on oh it's a setting John it's a
setting you don't have to say that you
can't have people under 19 there's a
there's an adult setting I do that
analyst for not this is not for children
and then they won't the algorithm won't
allow it to get into zones where you
know maybe people that are younger are
gonna be I don't think they need to be
polish you have to do is claim that it's
Russian that's about it well here's that
universal bond wrap that D 420k said
everyone's ready mother lovers a few
interesting things in the processing
world are happening there seems to be a
lot of interest in this whole CRC
business and a lot of people reached out
is a color remediation chromatography I
think that's what the I think that's
what the acronym stands for mm-hmm but
if you all know who Murphy Marie is
she's working with Santo Gardens and
those folks and Colorado I just saw say
I'm at the fish show about tomorrow so
it's good to see those guys but Mike
Mike from hi Dolph you see him - yes you
know I did I saw Mike it at the biz con
but it did not see Mike at the fish
shows I'm gonna shout out to Mike yeah
shout out to Mike for sure big Matt
shout out to Mike man our mutual friend
Mike Bishop yeah Mike's a man friend of
mine he's yeah I like the hide off sales
guy from out west right
originally from Delaware not too far
from here but I guess the CRC things
really get a lot of attention because a
lot of people have different techniques
and different methods and different
packing materials and it's just really
interesting to see people using good
chromatography techniques to you know
there's the old saying which is you
can't make you can't make good oil from
batter and typically vice versa or you
like to think that if you have really
good herb if your if your extraction
methods really good but I guess this was
originally brought up not just for color
remediation I think it was really
brought up for remediating hot material
or pesticide material but it's just it's
really cool to see that again you're
seeing a lot of high quality product out
there and I don't think it gives growers
the license to spray whatever they want
just because you can clean it up later
in a chromatography step but
chromatography is certainly a sort of a
trend and I see a lot of instrument
manufacturers now making columns and
hardware to do that kind of work
the
other trend I saw at bisque on is that
you know for we were talking about this
earlier about doing extraction and and
the dark oil that ATM showed us which
typically means you've extracted
pigments and other crap or somewhere
along the line things turned dark due to
oxidation well you know certainly you
can do and I've seen this where you can
do a low-temperature
extraction with ethanol and actually
make a product that social Shh you know
pure that it'll shatter out just like a
butane extract would so you can get a
low selective alcohol pull that makes a
really golden colored extract it's not
dark at all and it's it's dabble and it
tastes really good I know that Chris
Bukowski of the folks that move have
been using ethanol extract and they're
crushing it they're doing really well in
the markets they're serving but a big
trend that I see now is that people are
moving away from cryogenic extraction of
ethanol and just doing an extraction at
room temperature and then processing the
room-temperature extract to remove what
you're extracting out at room
temperature that you don't want so like
the fats waxes lipids any sugars or any
other water soluble that are coming out
you could remove by again either
chromatography or one of the new
techniques of something called
lenticular filtration lenticular
filtration is what it's called it's
similar to the filtration apparatus if
anyone's ever looked inside like a
swimming pool filter you know you
basically have all of these discs that
have filtered meat material in it and
basically the material the stuff flows
from in inside these radial distance
flows out in through the filtration
process and again it was really news to
me that you can basically do a
room-temperature extraction with ethanol
and the right processing of that ethanol
such that you didn't need to winterize
the extract cuz winterization is just
really ugly and messy and sloppy and
it's real nice to be able to have a
selective extract that you don't have to
winterize so to just to sort of trends
that I see happening in extraction you
know there's still a lot of work going
on in in scaling up of of hamp
operations that bisque on this year yeah
it was kind of like you know the biggest
shiniest stainless steel tank farms you
could wheel into that room to try to get
you know people who were spending lots
of money to put large hemp processing
facilities uh tends to be something
that's happening is so you would think
again with the increase in the amount of
have processing infrastructure what's
now happened you know be careful what
you wish for is the price isolate has
refreshed and it's Marya finish this
thought before it dies of loneliness so
so a lot of people who invested in
growing hemp in in 2019 with the notion
that they were going to be able to
convert and get like you know anywhere
between five to maybe ten thousand
dollars a kilo for their isolate are
really bumming because right now that
you know exchange price isolate is just
a little north of two thousand bucks a
kilo so the CBD market is crashed and
and and what seems to really be taking
off are the other cannabinoids like CBG
and CBN so those are couple trends that
are happening here in the States
cbn prices are through the roof and and
you see more and more CBG stuff coming
online and I see a couple growers over
in Italy Swiss guy in the north of Italy
who's got a CBG variety that shows
somewhere about 14 to 15 percent
CBG based on dried wait so just a couple
of trends just wanted to share with
everyone go ahead Sam what do you think
about remediation we have been cleaning
up pesticide sprayed
herb what do you think of that because I
don't have proven all yeah I know to
prove you I don't think you know if it
grown right you know cannabis doesn't
need pesticides and III haven't I hate
to enable that by coming up with ways of
cleaning up tainted oil but I I don't
want my well I was gonna say I don't
want my kids I don't want my my my
friends kids dying of a vape pen that's
got you know you know pesticide
contamination in oil from a black market
card that they bought out a dead company
show you know really bad I feel really
bad for the folks who feel that the last
resort they have is past asides you know
it just it shows that they've failed but
when they've invested so much of their
livelihood and they're gonna financially
be in ruin if they don't you know
they're they're up against the wall and
that's just a tough situation to be in a
situation created only by the
ridiculousness of the black market and
one thing if they're cleaning up mold
and fungus I mean that happens to the
best people who were serious growers but
when they're cleaning up pesticides and
fungicides are not just giving the
creepy crawlers
yes much easier to grow it without those
things in it I agree I think that the
the issue that exists is what happens
one hot oil is discovered right does
that does that create again
a paper trail back to the person who
applied the pesticides such that some
regulatory authority could come and shut
that individual down or you know cite
that individual and find them such that
if it happens again then they lose their
license I mean certainly again this is
something that oh another significant
thing that that's happened since our
last hashtag is the EPA has now allowed
its the handful of agrochemical
treatments they're not chemicals
themselves they're all biological
treatments which would make Josh and
Kelly happy they're all they're all
biologicals right so they're all sort of
a part of I guess what you'd call the
the bio IPM strategy of using bugs to
treat bugs but I guess the thing that
doesn't sit very well again is that
there are no real safety studies that
show that when you apply those materials
to cannabinoids that the cannabis is
safe for consumption so we go back to is
it really appropriate to apply crop
protection products like fungicides even
if they're biologically sors to
biologically derived is it really useful
for cannabis production and I don't have
the answer to that I think that there's
not enough known really like the
bacterium and the different types of for
years that they're making and what kind
of effects is gonna have on the soil and
also the aquatic life which you know a
lot of that doesn't go Cornell has a
whole lot of studies on a lot of
different products and
super-intelligent there but you know
we're fine but the one encouraging thing
if I could just interrupt for a second
calorie would be that with the EPA
taking the step in this direction if I'm
a company that wants to make a product
like that now there's a regulatory
pathway to develop that study and
there's a I could actually get a return
on in my investment if I do the studies
to show that this biological which is
part of our natural environment could be
used at this use rate to control this
particular type of pathogen that attacks
cannabis and taints cannabis with
microbiological infection this product
can be used now companies don't have to
be in the dark about doing the safety
and efficacy studies to support a
product like that and it's no longer the
EPA's gonna categorically say no
cannabis is Schedule one and no we won't
look at any product registrations the
EPA's mandate is to make sure that the
crop protection chemicals that are used
on the food supply and on chemicals of
commerce that come in contact with
humans like in cosmetics that those are
safe they don't always get it right and
the Environmental Working Group will let
you know that in spades but I can tell
you it's a step in the right direction
that they're looking to say look we need
to regulate products for this industry
because if we don't that's just a total
wrong move altogether in general I would
think that biologicals are probably
safer than but I'm making a big
statement they say that but in general I
do find that to be true yeah I just
think that it's really interesting you
know mark what he said of course it
makes sense any kind of Avenue that you
can get more research and more study on
it is better it's just really
interesting that things become you know
put into the Reg
related market before we even have the
opportunity for environmental studies
even look at it so already it's screwed
up you know you were saying you know do
we need to go back to the farmer who
tested hot on any kind of a pesticide or
a fungicide test you know it's we need
to go back to the FDA we need to go back
to the EPA you know yeah and also you
know there's a lot of these different
micro biology foliage that you can spray
on your plants or you can put on your
soils but we need to look at it in a
more holistic view what's it doing to
they said before is our aquatic life and
what's also totally and the way the
system is in place right now again the
EPA is is is is the regulatory authority
that doesn't do those testing but what
they do to testing the responsibility
for the testing and and and the data
package is is is is on is on the
registrant is on the person who wants to
register the product under something
called FIFRA which is the federal
insecticide fungicide and rodenticide
act so our US government says that if
you want to make a product that fits in
that product category you have to
register it with the EPA and what EPA
does is it just got a group of experts
typically academics and other folks who
look at the not just safety which is
what does this thing do to humans what
does this thing do to the environment
what does it do to non target pests but
also does it actually [ __ ] work you
know and and and again to do those
studies takes years and millions of
investment and typically like for a
chemical company like my former employer
um they would spend anywhere between 10
to 50 million dollars just to get that
one product over the goal line so it's
not
cheap thing to do because you have to do
toxicity and animals and assumes you get
a bad result on tox you're dead in the
water
now all that investment up to that point
you're dead so it's just it's a yeah one
thing that's happening it has to be done
in order to show safety and again
because cannabis was illegal all these
companies that sell products into the
space would touch this with a ten-foot
pole because they have to break the law
to show now it's interesting with
tobacco right because
you
in such microscopic space that you know
work creating a cannabis and in
accordance with nature and we're passing
all the tests and then when we go not we
as a community go to make it edibles you
know they'll fail the test from from the
cacao used or they'll failed tests from
other food streams that they're now
using so the cross over of the scrutiny
that's happening with the can have in a
space is cannabis basis is entering into
the food chain and we've been you know
studying about how there's like a
feminization of men and happening on
earth and and through xenoestrogens and
that's through the plastics that we were
talking about been through food
processing and so many different things
that is just incredibly important that
we have these conversations and get to a
more healthy space because the FDA
allows up to like three thousand
chemicals to be added to food without
any certifications and this is just
regular food streams so you know I think
we need to use it's it's an issue on our
community to have to go through such
scrutiny to grow but it's also shedding
light on the rest of our world so that
the consciousness that's expanding
through our use of cannabis and our and
then our business practices is now
allowing us to say wow look at the food
supply the food supply is incredibly you
know challenged right now and we have
incredible scientists and and
microbiology friends that won't even
enter the cannabis space at the moment
because they're just so directed into
food and food security and and scene
saving and stuff so I appreciate these
conversations I appreciate everyone
bringing it to the table and and you
know it's really our mission in life you
know to make a healthier world and and
this medicine is an incredibly powerful
one and yeah we're bringing that
consciousness to everything
oh okay sorry I was talking but I was on
mute yeah I was like okay so what I
asked Josh and Kelly and any you know
specifically Josh and Kelly because I
was wondering in regards to what you
just said did you guys actually watch
that little documentary I sent you the
link for we didn't just got electricity
back tonight Chad when you get a chance
for sure yeah I know you guys work how
many days did you have no electricity
for five we lost electricity at 8
o'clock on New Year's Eve and didn't get
it back to yesterday how to force like
quit couldn't make any of our you know
it's just like family clothes it does
actually just Josh Nye and that's been a
long time just like him and I here since
we lost our power the other night only
for like the night but in a very short
period of time my son my other son my
daughter our cat our dog the wife myself
we were all just like kind of hanging
out having a nice fire and it was like
this is nice I like here that we lose
our electricity because we have our
power you know I mean I like that it got
away from well you guys should watch
that documentary you're gonna really
enjoy it and it's it's all about like
growing in organics and like Paul
Stamets is in it I think the guys that
put it together did a really good job
I'm gonna share the link with some other
people on the panel everyone on the
panel okay I want to do I want to do a
show on it eventually because I think
it's a really cool documentary and shout
out to the brother from Calgary who
turned me on to it it's facing his name
right now it's just terrible but he just
like super love when I was in Calgary
not too long ago for the CHT a hemp
conference that was there make sure you
share it with the collective well I sent
it to you guys and I said if you want
you can share with the collective I
didn't know the collective rules and I
didn't want to be like oh maybe I'm not
supposed to be like promote documentary
I think you guys will really love it
what it's all about yeah yeah exactly
awesome what do you do with a pure
grower and the electricity goes out and
a generator seriously I've always had a
generator because it happens and at that
time you throw in like a team five into
like a 121 I've gone through some storms
I was gonna what are you guys five days
how did you get through with your plants
mothers or anything like that like what
are you doing they're like I only have
any kind of backup my mother's going so
we're not doing any kind of
high-intensity flowering anything and we
just keep the plants near the window you
know we did put a generator on for a
little bit because the freezer was was
coming out and stuff so you know if we
had because yeah we just I think that
near the window just works good enough
for that for us but that's why we're
annual growers because you know it takes
a lot to grow here in the winter and
lead to actually lose electricity quite
a bit here so it's pretty difficult so
we just do a really beautiful big you
know annual grow and then we use the
whole winter to process so like during
the winter work you know it with it
electricity off we can still make hash
and and say that's time to my cash you
know we have been able to make some
really good try sift and this cold
weather and everything and you know it
gives us a chance to connect with an
Abbe annoyed I've always had a battery
pal just in case just uploading my
heating mat and my t5b keep my babies
warm because if the lights going on a
few times so I've just got it's happened
in the past I've always
we have gravity-fed water and wood heat
and really we all them phenol to me and
as far as food greens and stuff we just
sprout you know so you know we're
basically in exist mode at the moment
but we are getting ready to travel and
spread the good word and and be out at
the science of regenerative cannabis so
we're gonna head out towards Maine and
humble really soon down in California
but we're also gonna be out in Maine and
mark it be really cool to meet up with
you out in the East Coast I don't know
you can head up to Maine or maybe we
come see you but it would be really
valuable to us all in the in the
regenerative cannabis movement just to
see you know what what you had to offer
I'm gonna say gravity-fed I just started
hooked up Auto pots but like the first
time and like just put up like 16 and
what a revolute like I it's so nice
because I can actually go away I don't
have to be there every day
I love the granary fun yeah I'm stoked
2020 I want to show the trailer for that
little movie I was talking about you
guys can kind of keep talking until I
figure it out it's sharing the screen
didn't seem to be quite as simple as I
thought it would be all right forget
about it I'm not doing it everyone can
go check them out there at Earth
conscious life.org and the the DVD the
movie is called the need to grow save
the soil save the world need to grow I
like that it's it's very careful it's
very safe save all relievers he's still
on I hope he's still on well he said he
said he said in the chat that he was
gonna get
to take his little ones for a hike yeah
he's a family man I should have given
him a better opportunity this morning
but they just worked out the way it
worked and yeah that's a bummer I wanted
to tell him about I wanted to tell him
about something so you know this whole
vape pen crisis or this whole vaping
crisis has been really you know blown
out of proportion and is actually done
enough damage to actually move markets
and change market dynamics on what's
going on and so one of the things I
think few experts have recognized I want
to you know point out Jeff at the
workshop and Chris that true terpenes is
that we better move on this issue fast
and move responsibly and so we're gonna
be starting a cannabis vaping
Association and really want people like
say about and other experts to be part
of that discussion because to me it's
like main mission is you know is to
collect and disseminate science-based
information and best practices for you
know cannabis vaporization products
because we believe that have done
properly
cannabis vaping is safe but yeah if done
properly so that means that we really
need to be responsive on setting up a
regulatory some type of regulatory
framework on what's allowed and maybe
even come up with a list of things that
shouldn't be used like this vitamin E
acetate just for example or if they find
MCT to be bad you know and if the
studies are out there and the best
practices are you know what if you want
to make a cannabis vape pen there's
other things that you can do other
alternatives that you can use rather
than these things between them are
problematic so again I think it's a
wonderful thing that you know thought
leaders in our industry are trying to
get ahead of this issue and not let the
you know
hysteria and the media kind of blow it
way out of proportion because I know
we've all seen these you know you know
honey grab the children articles it's
just it's crazy that they try to again
really steer with knee-jerk reaction and
clickbait to really get people you know
all worked up on this issue when you
know let's face it a lot of people are
using cannabis vape pens certainly the
the deaths and and the illnesses is
nowhere near that of tobacco so cry me a
[ __ ] River if they're their concerns
about safety when they let tobacco and
and and and and make a team vaping thing
go which is completely a juggernaut
going towards destruction anyway because
their active ingredient is toxic and
ours ISM so hey I think it's just a
really good move by again people in our
industry to put this together and people
like me are gonna participate and I hope
people like Sabo and other folks who are
in the vape end of our industry or have
a real important role to play to make
sure that you know common sense is used
and that we have you know a fair level
level field for the evaluation of things
like terpenes like we all know we we
love terpenes terpenes are what drew
humans to cannabis right but that
doesn't mean that you should be you know
using them at at the concentration that
they're used at certain times you know
there could be very very you know at
where do you think that level is mark
like you know if you make a great
extract from up from a color that's
close to 5% Turkey and content that
you're gonna get a fairly high terpene
percentage in that extract yeah so I
mean again like I remember looking
originally at somewhat like the original
I'm going back to like 2014 when when we
looked at using NMR to try to identify
you know how clean some of these
mixtures work
but I think that a lot has to do with
not just the not just the amount of what
you're using I mean certainly like
limonene is a solvent right
there's limonene in cannabis but the
limonene that's in your orange cleaner I
mean one of the reasons why ours cleaner
works so good is because they need to
add emulsifiers to keep the limonene and
solution and that basically makes a good
cleaner those compounds again at high
concentrations could have really
detrimental effects and and and I think
that like people who are like buying
terpenes from terpene providers like
true terpenes have to realize that you
know when you put I guess a vape pen
formula together I mean I guess the
concept of adding a terpene is that you
could flavor it all that and maybe thin
it out a little bit but you know if you
don't have the analytical equipment in
your home or in your lab or wherever
you're doing this work I mean you're
really not doing your your customers any
just any justice because you really
don't know at what level is is is
appropriate and again like Sam's always
talked about terpenes potentiate the
cannabinoids we know that's part of the
entourage effect but I think you can
completely overwhelm the concentrate or
an extract or a vape and fluid with way
too much terpenes or you know is one
drop on a diamond is that too much is
that not enough I mean who knows
III can't you find a balance between
cannabis based terpenes and food based
terpenes well okay so we that was the
discussion we had many years ago so
terpenes are molecules they have no
memory from which nice Wranglers they
came from so limonene derived from well
actually that's not entirely true
because like there's two different
isomers of pining there's a right handed
and a left handed version and one is
more predominant in pine species in
North America and the other one is more
predominant in Europe and they don't
fully understand why so that's an
example where yeah it depends which
biological source that comes from well I
have I have some to chime in on this one
in the sense that the real difference is
is that cannabis derived turkeys are
always profiles and right and plant and
fruit terpenes are always like single
molecule terpenes not really no there's
a profile why would why would orange
peel just make one turkey and there's
probably well I know when Horatio was
ordering pure terpenes and he was
getting his delimiting that it was like
eventually he figured out there was a
small small small tiny percentage of
citrus oils that he figured out how to
remove which we did a video on which
totally freaked me out because when he
first oil I was like it smells like
oranges he's like no no it's fine and
then months later he's like well
actually figured this out and I went and
filmed it and he showed that like he
took a clear delimit een and took and
pulled the oranges [ __ ] out of it you
could ever imagine and it was the citrus
oils from five gallons of this [ __ ] that
he like had us like a leader of or
something but it was freaked me out in
the sense that I was like so there's
another sesquiterpene called Valencia
Lancia oranges and it's got a real much
more fruity er orange essence than
limonene Lima need to be smells like
orange cleaner but Valencia smells like
somebody just twisted an orange peel
under your nose you know it's got that
almost bitterness of orange that comes
through in the in the orange peel or the
orange zest but you know Marcus you hit
it on the head which is that any terpene
profile like in cannabis and if you look
at the amount of terpenes in cannabis if
you were to take like the idea
extract this you want the terpenes and
the cannabinoids and very little else
and that's why we love live resin
because you can almost get there in fact
again I got to go back and look at some
of our old data because now that I know
that that THC B he was in there or could
be in there that can take some we had
live resin that was analyzing for
anywhere between 90 to 93 percent
cannabinoids and the rest were almost
terpenes almost all the way up to 100
percent so we were almost able to make
the perfect extract from cannabis which
was just terpenes and cannabinoids and
very little else whatever else was in
there was somewhere like about 2 or 3%
maybe these can Abbi no it's that these
Italians discovered maybe that was the
missing jigsaw pieces yeah we just found
them underneath the couch yeah that's
cool to think about really is because I
think that the crazy thing is is that if
you're if you're isolating cannabinoids
there's no reason why those would be
partitioned out right is you're doing a
very nonpolar extraction those are gonna
come along for the ride so you go back
and look at a bunch of data and see if
see if those other the Italian
discovered cannabinoids are in there
they might be in there right there's all
kinds of printed evidence where you
should be able to find that beat as an
identified beat right right Sam I mean I
mean who's gonna go back into I wonder
if these guys have already done and and
obviously you know I see something I
want to hydrogenate it's got I get that
thing I got a we got it we got to see
what we can do there because there's a
whole new bunch of structures that we
could make yeah and they're worth work I
would be very tempted to breed a TV TP
dominant variety I don't think it'd be
better yeah here's what I think here's
what I think these guys have already
figured out because because it's it's
in army I think they've already figured
out that they gotta identify the
promiscuity of that enzyme to work on
those higher homologs figure out
experimental mutant put that in eco lie
and it's over express it through
heterologous expression and use that way
to make this thing that's exactly what I
was thinking so that's one way to do it
that's one way to do it
I was cannabis Friday it's like the
tools of modern biology exist and
there's scientists who are in the lab
working on this very thing right now as
we're talking about it I'll bet you a
dollar to a doughnut right and many
times a plant is doing it as we speak
I know the plants been doing it for
years we just didn't know about it very
true very true I don't know exactly what
you said but at ecole I I started to get
frightened well kool-aid they could use
yeast they can use several vehicles to
accomplish the same thing but sure so
far deeper to do it that way they do
growing in the plant well but just it's
isolated like you said Sam in so little
quantity now it's a race between trying
to breathe okay hold of a variety that's
got two point zero one percent yes I
think those guys like John John page and
those guys and chimera those guys will
identify the genes that close for the
mutant for that and they'll figure that
[ __ ] out add that [ __ ] up man that's
they should do that
science folks I mean this is you know
this is where plant biotechnology exists
today it's like I see no reason with
them but it was us using classical
breeding that explained the inheritance
of the cannabinoids so with that
sue Sam with that said how many
generations do you think it would take
to bring you know let's say 0.1% to 10
or 14 if that for five generations plus
creating poly hybrids from several that
on TTV was that from the th TV story
yeah I mean T TV we the varieties that I
started with I had four different
families that I used South African
Afghan and what I did was I sucked them
each for three or four generations and
then crossed the inbred families that
were starting to lose a bigger start
diluted resistance or yield and way down
but then when I crossed him and made
hybrid inside of them it restored on but
it wasn't bigger and it worked really
really well
41 z since it ended up over 1012 someone
meeting 15% K TV and smoothing there's
no THC I mean like point zero so I I met
up with with Paul Daley a couple months
back at his place in Oakland so he's
working at Doug's Varon with David Lam
pack they're in Oakland California and
they're only half as high yeah there
yeah so
4080 yes yeah exactly he showed me their
display was I want to say it was like
working I'm surprised it's taken 10-15
years for people
yes so I think I'm not if I remember
correctly it was it was like 50 percent
THC and like 35 percent THC V in a
distillate that's made from that plan
that Your Honor I understand but that's
not a particular great ratio of I mean
if you're after THC with it it's great
but if you don't want to see if you want
the THC be I think it would be really
cool to breed a plant that didn't make
the the c5 at all and just made c3 and
c7 right right just breathe the the THC
out and just make the P in the V what
about see people synthase produces the
cannabinoid which is the case in these
then that means it can be bred to be
more instead of 1% you can give it over
10 15 maybe even 20 not sure I'm not
sure it's a particular synthase though
Sam I think it might be the promiscuity
of a mutant synthase right it might just
be changing the substrates it already
exists is creating multi-product that's
right that's right
possibility yeah but you just tweak
that's what I'm saying this is like I'm
presuming the other way this is a jigsaw
puzzle for miter and biotechnology and
what under
ends it is really valuable intellectual
property well there's a dozen companies
worldwide inhibitor kind of produced GMO
cannabinoids mostly CBD and THC but
they're even in the mall and so far none
of them are able to produce it cheaper
then as people are saying but see to it
well the same things going to happen
that's because it's really cheap so who
are some of those companies sound that
are doing that doing this pathetic yeah
I have a list of them send me an email
and I'll send you the whole list of all
the companies they know better working
with the notion that you can converse is
going them you know just the notion that
you can brew it you could brew and use
fermentation closest to was the folks at
Dartmouth University in Germany okay and
they published four or five papers on
producing CBD but I went there and
visited with Rob and what we saw was
they also have the ability to put in a
suite of cannabinoids with a suite of
turkeys all in the single yeast Wow yeah
that I said Jesus Christ you are gonna
complete with cannabis but so far nobody
is producing cannabinoids or to CBD for
2000 kilo in vitro well I definitely met
a group in this last year that were very
interesting I I cringe personally when I
hear about synthetic cannabinoids and
people making them I like the idea
yeah yeah these these are full-on like
chemical like synthetic like black to be
cheaper than right maybe different
compounds right mark you're talking
about completely different no I'm
talking about this group you know I'm
under okay so I can't talk about it much
but I can say that they definitely have
example mark or Utah they may start with
a limit all which came back cost 30
pounds in the kilo
yeah these guys aren't doing that at all
it's something totally different their
quote is we built a better mousetrap Wow
and it's very insane now for me that
what okay how I kind of I didn't like
support it but how I kind of got around
to actually listening to it because like
I said my skin starts to crawl he was
like listen like we're not interested in
taking over you know trying to compete
with plant based compounds what we're
trying to do is build the better
mousetrap so that we can produce novel
and unique cannabinoids so that science
can get an early step on studying them
you know ones that are not available in
in large they're not talking about
creating new ones they're talking about
creating ones like THC pee
you know or before that like maybe a th
TV or a CVG you know one of the ones
that are more novel one of the ones that
are less available by the ton you know
maybe even other more novel ones CBC or
CV I don't you know like this was what
they were taking but yet CBD Ruby's
cheapest CBD in the near future well
it's not right now CBD a decade or a
half ago with $70,000 and it still is
today and some in some circles okay no
it's the pharmaceutical sir
if you're if you're a pharmaceutical
company purchasing CBD actually and
produced in a GMP facility and your
companies in Germany trust me you're not
being 100 dollars a kilo trust me they
paid they pay huge a ridiculous amount
of money and I'm glad that CBDs I've got
twelve hundred dollars a kilo personally
wonderful today was two pounds yeah it's
a DVD yeah oh I can hook up for 1200
then you can isolate I ninety-nine point
Marcus did what I was saying about that
price going down and a lot of people who
got into the hemp industry so to speak
this year kind of like really you know
lost their shirts because again I think
they were they were based on what
isolate prices were going as little as
12 months ago my god I was seeing stuff
going for like 75 to like you know
ninety five hundred dollars a kilo for
several you know tens of hundreds of
kilos so I mean III don't think that
this was a one-time thing I think it is
like a what a supply demand so a lot of
people grew so there's this huge supply
the ability to process that supply is
not where it needs to be but I think was
really enhanced in the last say two
years in those seasons a lot of
processing capacity went in you saw what
what Chris Brody is doing he's got in
South Carolina oh my god the size of
those those wipers are like four-story
high and a distillate flowing out of
that thing like a volcano oh it is when
you have that level of production
capacity certainly supply demand I can
it's just going to be a huge supply you
know I think people who are speculating
and buying from Joe and selling to Bob
you know there's it's it's become a very
it's just that the market just tanked
market Aggie yeah not here our market is
kind of jacked and weird and controlled
and we need to you know we need to
deregulate it while still maintaining
some of the important regulations
because I have kind of put together the
fact that you know if and we mentioned
they were mentioning it in chat today
that if the if some of the food people
started you know actually getting if
people started testing what's in their
food the way they do their cannabis I
think they would be absolutely shocked
like you know shocked so maybe that
aspect could kind of leak over into food
and we could start you know figuring out
ways and solutions to keep poisons and
toxins from infiltrating our air and our
I think you're mistaken
most people just don't yeah but like
most people in America want cheaper
prices America is only 300 million
people and there's 7 billion the last
time I checked in the world so they're a
very small small small percentage of the
actual population of the world they're 5
percent we're not really America or the
United States different right yeah we
won't get into that holy [ __ ] we still
got some folks hanging out here how many
people are we still got here we got a
good crew here alright I put it on
full-page we got yeah Jack's still in
the house Johnny B and Colin and D for
20 K and it is just got a beautiful like
I should have just put his thing on it's
just like a beautiful view that is nice
hey Marcus I I heard that I heard that
solvent based extracts turned out okay
Canada is that right yeah they have a
whole list of what you can and can't do
and mostly it's you know all you know
hydrocarbons are right are allowed and
ethanol is allowed and you know so
people are jumping on that there's all
probably I would say for sure multiple
licensed production facilities well for
sure many running Co to many many some
running water extraction and dry seft
already now Roz and I seems an LP the
other day posted I actually had to do a
double-take and I should have you know
kept the picture because it was a giant
jar of just you know golden amber rosin
and it just to me just looked like you
know one of the beautiful jars of one of
the many hash makers and oil makers that
I follow on Instagram but then I caught
like a look and it was like it was a
licensed producer in Canada and I was
like wow that's kind of crazy yeah I was
eyes them kind of brought a smile to my
face it's like we need to get these
[ __ ] products into these these very
slow going
indoor hands it's incredibly slow going
system in Canada and it's look it's very
easy to kind of spend your time trying
to fight it and argue with an old [ __ ]
in wine or you can do like Jack did and
just be like I'm just gonna create a
different system that just operates sort
of parallel and it's like is that all
because my back protection or is it also
be reduced any of it continuous
production um I would say it's batch for
now but I mean that's what they're all
trying to build a lot of the bigger ones
are trying to build to you know have it
that sort of conveyor belt like they're
consistently growing their can see
everyone in Canada seems to think that
being vertically integrated and growing
everything and processing everything I
were a little different we just want to
process we don't want to get into
growing it or anything like that now
that doesn't mean that we don't have a
very big importance for you know having
relationships with tissue culture
companies that we can share with our
potential customers where you know they
can go in a save 15% of their room that
currently is being mothered into bloom
so now they're generating revenue that
will not only pay for the tissue culture
of plants that will come much cleaner
totally you know
initiated of all fungi and bacteria and
viruses to us as a processor that's a
huge advantage but we don't want to have
to like we want to facilitate like only
here here's a tissue culture company
here's some genetics that you can have
will be at the back end if you want us
to purchase some of the material or if
you want to create a partnership where
we collaborate and do something together
and we just really want to offer
processing because the the complexity of
of growing cannabis is it's just not
something that our company is interested
in offering processing just because it
because solvent but because solvent
extracts are now available are you to
start doing solvent based extraction at
embark uh embark absolutely that's what
Mike is gonna be doing at embark my
quest he's now not awesome anymore but
yeah that's his sort of wheelhouse right
away you know right away when I when we
got the idea of embark with the two
other founders Michael and Bruce my
partners they approached me they said
yeah we you know you're that you're the
hash guy you're the extract guy we want
to bring you on and I kind of had this
you know epiphany of like you know all
these different stories from people like
you know curing their cancers and
putting cancers into remissions with
different solvent extracts you know it
couldn't be ignored to the point where I
had to get over my own ego and be like
look I want to focus on solvent list
that's my what I love but I have all
these colleagues and people that I know
in the industry and it was very easy to
call Mike up and be like look would you
be interested in coming over and you
know and then my other partner in
Colorado who's been doing cryo ethanol
for five years and producing you know
lots of CBD isolate he was interested in
having the project in Canada so I
thought look you can you know you can be
this guy I was talking to Indra for a
while about his his units for for embark
because he had been so known in the
industry and he had started you know
that whole process so it was very easy
for me to just be like look all focus on
my wheelhouse healthy water extraction
for dry sifting and and wet washing but
why don't we create a
cuivre this is kind of my idea from
almost the very very beginning that we
do you know ultrasonic cryo ethanol we
do co2 we do hydro carbon we do dry sift
we do wet wash we do rosin and we even
do terpene extractions so we have this
quiver that's available I thought just
from a data standpoint of of processing
for multiple growers and multiple you
know licensed production growers and
craft growers that we would create an
incredible variety of data that in you
know in connection to the tissue culture
companies could really start creating a
beautiful landscape for easy navigation
on oh well this LP wants to grow
specifically for dry sifting oh well
talk to Sager International they're a
tissue culture company they've compiled
all of this data come together with
embark and there's like four pages of
their menu is cultivars that are
specific for dry sifting and then
getting into the nuances of well what
does that mean well it means that those
cultivars are gonna produce a higher
variety of higher ratio of capitate
stocks trichomes in sessile stock
trichomes and less of the bulbous ones
that sit on those single Stipe cells and
tend to not really effectively come off
in in both water extraction and
mechanical screen separation so things
like that I'm super excited about cool
will are yes yes what's the highest
extraction rate of resin cleanup 99 okay
you've heard of promo variety dry city
water hash you said you've gotten well
here's the thing when I get when I I
don't unfortunately don't dry sift
enough from plant matter what I do is I
dry sift from farmers grades sift and
because I'm missing the initial ratio of
what you know I always know like okay
like from from most material I might get
20% heads out of out of you know farmers
grade sift that's that's high that's
like
good a good one now from really like you
know higher-end material with us real
you know maybe in a tumbler like the
great gardener matt baron would do if he
just did a quick like minute or
something it could get to be fifty
percent and he was growing fairly well
in that fifty percent heads would
actually produce a pseudo melty product
and you know if you're doing a trim bin
and trimming over it without even
touching it yeah i've seen it come out
in the 90s but how much of it do I get
is impossible for me to know because I
only know from a kilo of sifts if I get
a kilo of sift and I work with it to
clean it up it's still pretty far out
but cannabis can be cheap enough that
they can afford to dissect it because
it's much more you get much more
cannabinoids in a key
well and it's like it's this it's the
system the plant setup to store those
compounds in so the micro encapsulated
resin gland is my favorite form of
having hash in just like little dusted
you know just scoop it out with a little
scooper and you're good I like their
cured a little bit for the better more
like dried raisins rather than a fat you
see great mm-hmm
absolutely but then again you were you
know you have some did you ever test the
percentage of terpenes that were in like
the skunk or whatever like that's not a
that's not a one two three is it I did
one time oh I'm not sure maybe I just
don't remember what actual percentage
like the skunk it wasn't enormous lehigh
and I don't remember what the difference
was between herb and number one farmers
ash because I tested both
be interesting to find out the herb I
would think it would be over that 3%
like maybe even 3.0 yeah what might
because percent or whatever but it's I
mean I've I've never heard anything
higher than 10 but maybe yeah tends
insane that's what I'm saying and then
we talked about like extracting that in
making a high terpene you know where
you're fresh frozen or you're you're
freezing it before you're doing you know
you're preserving every last terpene
that is you're bumping those terpene
contents hi
i sometimes wonder if you're saving too
many or if the when you're carrying your
baby british little more about twitter
feeds and maybe i don't know who's to
know well [ __ ] i want to say one more
time I want to talk about the need to
grow just briefly I'm gonna share it
with some friends Tanner who was a part
of the need to grow it was I think a big
part of it like a director producer or
something he sent me an email I guess
he's watching or my friend from Calgary
is watching
he said that he'd love to come on hash
Church and talk about living soil and
and you know that the differences of the
living soil and big AG and he could
bring the director potentially the green
powerhouse inventor there's this guy who
creates this powerhouse generator thing
on this film called the need to grow and
you can you can check out the need to
grow at Earth conscious life dot org I
think it's like I don't know a few bucks
to watch definitely worth it there's
some super inspirational [ __ ] in that
film I watched it this last trip to
Calgary and I really really enjoyed it
it was it was just really positive so I
wanted to mention that one more time and
get you know I'll say you guys I'll send
you guys the link here in the chat room
and then actually I'll yeah yeah and
then here's the password right here I
guess I
just keeping that personal to yourselves
because they are you know raising money
to pay for their project and I'd love
for people to support them but that's
gonna be a hashed Church coming up I
also dropped a photo for for the
promotion of hashed Church thanks to
Matthew Tanner for doing that devolved
media on Instagram get our little hash
picture for the hash Church episode this
week and in that post I mentioned hey
tag your favorite hash makers so for all
of you hash makers that got tagged in
that I will be hitting you up one by one
and sending you a link to a meeting room
that I'll have set up on my Zune it's
not gonna be filmed or live but I want
you guys to come in I'll probably have
some of my panelists linked up in there
as well we can fit like 49 at a time now
so it's pretty gnarly we're gonna have
to learn to not talk over one another
but I want to have a conversation with
all these hash makers there were so many
of them and I want to kind of suss out a
really great conversation maybe for next
week maybe for two or three weeks in the
future we do have lifts coming to town
and here in Vancouver which is a big
event about tours at my facility in
Delta and I'm going on a couple of tours
of producers here in British Columbia so
I will be fairly busy but I'd love to
keep consistent with hash search and get
another episode
I don't want those hash makers to think
that you know because they didn't get on
this week maybe that's what they were
thinking I haven't forgotten about you I
think it's a great idea to stay
connected to all these people who are
actually getting their hands dirty in
regards to producing full melt ashes and
solvent less raw sands and all these
other products I love the idea of having
another episode that's just really
focused on hash the thing that of course
I love so much and this is hash Church
so I want to be more yeah we need more
hash Johnny B and Johnny B and I are
gonna be filming puff Wednesday's
hopefully once a week so I mean last
week we filmed that it was pissing rain
we ended our room we ended up we ended
up under a [ __ ] hot like bridge -
Road in West Vancouver and it was kind
of funny because the quote of the year
was like wow we have legalization Johnny
B was like we have Lee
and then my quote was like yeah we're
standing under a bridge like that's
where we're puffing with our
legalization so yeah we're gonna be
doing more of those have puff Wednesdays
and hash Church I want to stay
consistent with 3.0 we'll see how many
we can get in the bag for the year 2020
and I guess thanks to everyone for
coming in and sharing you know Jack
thank you dude for coming in if you guys
want to hook up with Jack I will link
you up with Jack you can hit me up I can
link you up with him on Facebook I can
link you up with his I'm sure he's got a
phone number email and some other stuff
and websites that I'll put in the
comments section of the YouTube video
and then I'll post the video in the
Facebook group ash Church and we'll put
not your phone number and stuff but your
your email stuff so that people could do
good help you just thanks so much for
having me in the in the private chat I
put up a link to our website so that I
mean if you can go have a look at what
that is and explain that to the people
you have been your own network so we can
just hopefully keep this as a ongoing
conversation and since you and Johnny BT
aren't that far away maybe you could
come sit in our smoke hole Oh back to
our cannabis program for one of your
puff Wednesdays or something - dude
straight up you're right besides the
city I saw all the stuff in there the
canned stuff like that I was looking in
the window we weren't that funny back
happy back the capping businesses that's
my landlord owns that and I mean we were
we were blacklisted here in Victoria by
all the big real estate companies and so
we had a cannabis activists who his his
kid ran the bomb City and so he rented a
the our administrative office is about
the bomb City it's a beautiful old
Victorian like apartment and then we
have that North Park which was the dank
Bank and trees and a bunch of other
doing we cleaned it up a bit and made it
into a nice outreach
and I dropped a sea-can out back so
everyday we have support groups and
cannabis education groups back there
where people can keep dry and I've built
a an overhang so that there's an outdoor
smoking area since we're allowed to not
get away with a lot of things I'm trying
to push the boundaries of what we can do
to make people comfortable in the
community beautiful man I [ __ ] love
it and they'll definitely be having you
back on to update us and Johnny B and I
will come out to Victoria and do a tough
Wednesday with you get with you guys
over the [ __ ] puffs Wednesday that's
gonna be the best puffs Wednesday ever I
want to thank dr. mark for laying down
some super knowledge today we superly
appreciate you he saw on Facebook he's
on Instagram what's your Instagram like
yes B yeah
remember when we used to all have pen
names right I was at Mark II saw like
the girl that saw my brother he saw and
he saw all right I wanted to share one
thing with everybody I joined I took a
full-time position with a company called
be our brands effective January 1 so I'm
now their chief science officer and
adulation we're the company that owns
Mary's medicinals you may have heard of
us yes you know I tried to get a
conversation going with those guys to
get them up in Canada and man they just
like could not answer the phone
well now we can lubricate that
discussion people that's amazing dude
that's amazing I wanted to figure out a
way how we were gonna work in some way
and that that would be a very cool way
to work with you well I have it on my
radar I want to come up to British
Columbia and I want to go trout fishing
with David Lemieux who's the archivist
for the Grateful Dead and and also visit
all my friends up in Canada so I I have
it on my list of things to do in 2020
yeah yeah for you who does nothing but
Rho fishing and stuff up on the legs up
near Mary he's a very good friend of
mine he's got some of the best week in
Canada well look forward to hosting you
up here for sure mark that'll be amazing
it can't wait to visit it's such a
beautiful place in the world that I
haven't been that I need to go we'll
give you the tour of embark skunk man
Sam thank you as always a pleasure here
and you drop knowledge bombs as well I'm
Johnny B wait laughter we didn't get to
see you but we certainly got to hear you
and that was a real pleasure you got a
nice soft kind voice and I you didn't
say much today but I did appreciate the
few things that you did say and I would
chime in for a second yes just say one
of the things that's on my list this
year is to renew my passport so I didn't
come see y'all up there yeah looking
forward to it and bring forests back
that that's a hard story right now
Silas is struggling a lot and I've seen
forests maybe three times in the last
four months because as he tells me he's
trying to keep his son alive he's going
through puberty
he's got type 1 diabetes so trying to
keep him fed and his blood levels
glucose levels in check and all that so
yeah I'm totally supporting him trying
to do that
keeping Silas alive seems like a really
important work at the moment for him and
doing what I can to keep the families
that were involved in the cloud rheostat
work provided the the medical thing in
California has really blown apart kind
of tragically the collective model
there's some room with the donations tax
relief and whatnot but anyway I don't
want to I don't want to go down a long
rabbit hole I just
want to thank you again for doing the
church and thank all of those folks who
offered their point of view and their
their voices to what we're talking about
because I really do think this plant is
the healing of the people and on that
note happy new year thanks Wade
appreciate you too I'm gonna reach out
to forest and see I just at least to
send them some positive words and you
know let them know that we're always
thinking of them there's new email you
did I appreciate your kindness thinking
about today so sure much love yeah it's
Hannah thanks for coming out as always
enjoy the tropics man it's absolutely
beautiful thanks for sharing that with
us absolutely and I have some exciting
news Berkeley patients group has a new
location that's coming in 2020 we now
have it now we just have to build it out
we'll have a bigger location again so
good things happen and all the way
around
beautiful beautiful yeah and you can
find at yeah at 80 n 4 to zero on
Instagram that's correct right attend
the letters the letters eighty and 420
not spelling out my name it's just
letters
etienne 420 yahoo.com so much love
everybody have a happy new year
beautiful D 420k
thanks so much brother good to see you
dude haven't seen you really once in the
new year so this is our first time
getting to share a bowl we'll have to
have many more in the new year and Colin
thanks for coming out dude maybe next
time we'll get you to tickle the ivories
for us can't be can't be coming in with
about oh you're on mute can't be coming
in with a bunch of pianos and expect not
to be thanks for having me as always man
oh yeah I'd like to we can get into some
hash next time and love to talk about
what I've been up to here you can check
out Colin at vessel life science on
Instagram and Johnny be is 420 weed
master we best 420 for one point we must
420 weed master exactly
and 20 24 22 on Instagram
be 420k on Instagram
don't you have a D for turning K on
Facebook - yeah yeah alright well i'm bc
bubbleman on instagram and this is bolo
man's world and i really appreciate
everyone for coming in we're gonna we're
gonna stop thank you good day brother