hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world welcome to hash
Church 2.0 episode 11 squeeze in these
2.0 shows out slowly but surely just
wanted to thank everyone who's in the
chatroom who's been holding it down for
geez for a while now that's seventies
mama in there we got Cuban chronic and
Robert sellers came up and red river
organics and apparently 128 people that
have been waiting for hashed Church to
start this morning so without further
ado why don't I invite some folks in
here shall we shall we do that let's do
it let's see if this email gets fired
off gotta listen for it there it goes
well shouldn't well hopefully to see
some familiars today and maybe some
unfamiliar Zhai have at least one person
who's coming on that's never been on
before hello Alex Mountjoy from the UK
welcome welcome welcome everybody
welcome Ron Jones and welcome at yeah
now that's what's up what's up can hear
me I missed you I've been busy you have
been busy you've got all sorts of things
going on don't you
yeah it is a season it's fall yes yes
tis the season as well well it's great
to see dude man I'll tell you it seems
like it's been forever since so oh we
just had so many things sort of line up
with you know terrible things going on
and sicknesses and busyness and just
tell us what's going on down in Cali
with that Jan oh wow
well locally in California we're still
dealing with the new regulations
federally we got the first VA bill or
any cannabis bill out of subcommittee
ever and then we did it again this past
week so federally things are definitely
changing even with we have an office
currently and then the biggest thing
we're getting ready for our 19th
anniversary at BPG next month
Wow nineteen years doing this food
that's that's almost helped well that is
how old bubble bags is bubble bags turns
20 in March of next year yeah we'll be
into that's next October for us but yeah
it's we're the dedicated you know we've
been doing this a while and we put our
money where our mouth is literally take
you know decades ago well it's
definitely one of the first sort of you
know I guess I met I guess I met Debbie
at least 20 years ago maybe even like 21
or 22 years ago right um right before it
that all sort of started rolling but
amazing how fast things go as you just
get get older times just passing right
we're just like in the early days it
just seemed to take very long periods of
time to pass these years and now it's
just I seem like I blink and a fiver has
gone by well we've told a lot of wrote
in these last 20 years as well you know
20 years ago they said it never happened
in our lifetimes right and you know
being neck deep in it and doing
everything that we've done we've picked
up people like Johnny B and others along
the way that have joined the cause and
now we're just an unstoppable momentum
hi Johnny be like we said like years ago
you know and that trees falling in the
force and it's calling it's like that's
what happen with cannabis not true is
following it eventually it was gonna hit
the ground and that was gonna it's we
are today Wow let's get him close for
like 31 days away from the legalization
here in Canada we're at the grassroots
conference yesterday and talking about
it you know what it's everybody's
looking at a huge change it's good today
across the board I mean it's exciting
and it's scary too absolutely
well it's not perfect and everybody
expected perfection right out the gate
from you know your laws and our laws and
of course they're not perfect so people
think that since we won we get to give
up and you know have a great time and
it's like no this is where we need to
actually be in and involved and the old
saying goes if you're
part of the discussion if you're not at
the table then you're on the menu so the
best thing is to always be involved so
that you are always you know talking
about you may not always be on the menu
but at the same time you can at least
help and contribute because we all have
fostered knowledge from what we've
gained from doing what we've done you
know some have gone into consultants
others just you know double down and we
do what we do so proud of everybody here
for what y'all have done up in Canada
and hopefully someday we'll have some
reflection and what's going on in the
United States and I apologize for our
stupid government really [ __ ] with
y'all and your people up there in Canada
regarding you know coming to the United
States they're threatening to boycott
people for life from coming into the
United States I'm reading this morning
that you know the United States is
trying to talk to Canada but our
president in charge is just being an
asset regarding everything including
Canada and you guys are our friends you
guys have taken care of us over the
years in times of need and I just think
it's shameful what's how the United
States is treated you know you fellow
Canadians as spell especially cannabis
Canadians
it's absolutely beyond shameful it's a
bummer there's no doubt about that
welcome Johnny be to the old hashed
Church room we got 362 viewers here at
9:06 a.m. so there's some people waiting
to hear what we have to say it's uh it
is unfortunate that this is going on
this is a major thing for Canadians this
is what a chance talking about is not
just people that are smoking and growing
cannabis but even having any type of
investments in stock in companies sort
of in any way connected to the cannabis
industry or cannabis as a whole they've
been threatening and they've actually
been doing it to a certain degree I
don't want to blow it out of proportions
but they have been blocking and banning
people for life now that really doesn't
mean you're never allowed to go to the
US again but what that does is it denies
you for a solid six months while you
apply for a waiver to get down and it
can be even more than six months and
then it's of course up to the discretion
of homeland security
whether they let you in at all and I
have heard people getting banned for a
cannabis offense and then getting let
back in after you know a six to eight
months sort of jumping through the hoops
but that's nothing really people want to
be be having to do especially people
this really mostly affects Canadians
only affects Canadians in the sense that
if they have a company in the US and
they have a company in Canada and they
have to go back and forth if they get
banned for life you know those people if
they're pertinent to that company if
they need to be down there in that
company doing particular work it really
throws the whole company off in a way
that you know could be potentially
detrimental for for a company depending
on how they position themselves so it's
definitely changing the way people look
at things and welcome to my quest are
you doing buddy couple of peace symbols
it's good morning good morning can you
guys hear me okay we can hear you okay
you kind of sound like you're in a
tunnel with one of those mega mega horns
but you can't we can hear you I think
that the only time it really skips out
is when you're you're you become you far
away from the microphone and then it'll
do a little skipping but I heard you
perfect just there cursed at the beard
McMahon true for the beard yes the beard
curse well none of us really it's really
trying to know that I guess I have a
tiny bit of stubble at ten and well it's
a little bit under your beard there
units I keep a chin strap he keeps the
chin strap okay not to be full alopecia
it's like no no I have scars from some
shrapnel I took sorry oh I kind of wear
this to kind of cover up the scars wow
that's heavy
Vancouver that's probably gonna sum up
on Monday that in regards that's
basically fighting for all the
compassionate clubs that it be serving
medical patients in Canada that are been
going to be forced to shut down in a
sense on October 17th because there's no
access and is it's we were talking about
it yesterday and a lot of people I'm
talking with a lot of patients are quite
scared
with legalization because they won't be
able to have an interaction they've had
for the last 20 years with other members
and other patients with the bud tenders
and stuff like that and it's on the
medical and it's it's it's really scary
for a lot of patients because a place of
access they've been going to for quite
some time
I think the B CCS are about places so is
basically it's not going anywhere though
there's no way after October 17th the BC
compassion plugs going at it but all
these places are now being threatened
with this new bar there was a news
article that said only one the CC said
they only expected one light to be
issued so I would just say this these
places have been under threat by law for
all twenty years that they've existed
yes so we have to understand that they
are you know the BC compassion Club is
the epitome wipe the board clean of this
and the argument is very very simple
it's the civil disobedience that created
the entire medical program that we have
today and so we're still going to
require you know civil disobedience
until like a 10 says until it becomes
perfect you have to have a seat at the
table and Hillary definitely has a seat
at all the tables across Canada whether
it's you know the fully regulated
federal the creator of regulations on
that side I know she sits at the table
or if it's even from the you know more
the street side black market civil
disobedience gray market she's got her
foot in that world as well and I just I
have faith in people like Hillary to
take it to the next level for sure well
it's part of the eternal vigilance that
we've always talked about you know if
part of the reality is that you know
we've risked our freedoms and now that
we've seen the change in the laws we
think we can get complacent like here in
California with the passes 64 we were
blocked from giving away free cannabis
so we've had to spend the last few
months down in Sacramento lobbying
Sacramento for a law as because they
were gonna outlaw compassion programs at
a certain point so we have passed it
we've gotten it through and now we're
just waiting on the governor's signature
so that's part of the reality of the
long haul and where you have to plug in
yourself you have to physically go put
on suits physically go down to your
representatives your assembly people and
you talk to them you have meetings with
them it's not that hard people it sounds
so frightening and so intimidating but
it is so absolutely [ __ ] simple all
you need is just to dress nice go down
look professional and talk to people
it's not that difficult it's us for some
reason people have always thought it was
some sort of a crazy reality to allow us
to get here but it's your direct
plugging in and if our people in khalad
rias network and others hadn't have
actually plugged in directly to
California we would be [ __ ] out of luck
still now I know that's a totally
different thing dealing with the state
and you're dealing with the federal
government so but it still takes your
you know your interactions you're
talking to your lobbying as well you can
still affect that change to an extent
there's an extent you can't I can't now
but there's an extent that you still
can't correct yeah you know we've kind
of been pushed in a way with this
cannabis community to the point where we
were disconnected from all that was
available to us in the same way what
you're saying at Tsang which is the
simplicity of joining into that system
and playing the game that they play and
getting at that table it's it's kind of
the same metaphor for you know the
hashish production the processing the
growing you know cannabis growers are
doing it in the basement they're doing
it with these lights that they've you
know originally taken off of a hockey
arena or something and you you sort of
climbed through the history of it and
you see that as we start incorporating
things from the agricultural community
it suddenly is like oh it's so much
easier if we have tables that move on
rollers and it's so it's like yeah if
you actually plug in the system that's
been designed to do this work already
with non cannabis plants you can
actually accelerate yourself to a level
that is beyond and above anything that
you saw
we're doing in a basement with with this
you know the the stolen lights or
whatnot and I feel it's sort of a
metaphor for you know the same sort of
the bureaucracies we've just always been
apart from these systems we've always
just had to build our own Borough rooms
on spec and jerry-rigged everything and
MacGyver this MacGyver that and now it's
kind of to the point where we've gotten
you know we've gotten to a seat at the
table cannabis is so mainstream I can't
even tell you I got off a flight the
other day and I get on the bus that's
taking me to long-term parking and you
know the guy across from me I think he's
like works for Air Canada but in fact
he's actually a broker of cannabis deals
that I've sat at at a boardroom in the
last two weeks when I was in Nanaimo and
he's like hey didn't I just sit with you
at a boardroom and I'm like oh my god
yeah we started talking a little bit
he's like oh I was just I was just out
you know doing talking with Mackay
investments in Toronto to get the deal
done and he's talking about all this
different things well he ends up getting
off the bus and the guy next to me who's
just this old dude he's like oh are you
in the marijuana business and I'm like
yes I am and he's like well I do
certification for all the big machinery
all the co2 units and all that and I'm
just sitting there going like this is
just [ __ ] crazy at this point in time
there was like four people on the bus
and three of them were all in the
cannabis industry off of just a random
flight so it's it's a lot easier to open
this discussion nowadays everyone seems
to have it on their lips you know you
want to open up a discussion with
someone that even seems to be maybe from
back in the day they might be an anti
cannabis person you just crack that CBD
just that word that term and all of a
sudden it's like ohm or are you talking
about the CBDs well I are I'm interested
in the CBDs it just makes me laugh even
the whole turn of the CBDs it used to
make me cringe I have to admit now it
makes me laugh I think it's oh no no I
didn't see it printed in place and it's
just it makes my head it's like come on
people there's only one but as you were
saying though you know this this change
that we're talking about people it takes
time it's not gonna happen overnight you
know it's taken us 20 years to get here
but how many of us have plugged in over
these 20-plus
years you know it took somebody like you
know skunk man Sam over there you know
50-plus years he's been doing this to
arrive at this point I skunk man mad
Sam's in the house I didn't even see him
sneak in what's going on Sam silence it
seems and prayers if you will positive
thoughts to Forrest and Silas apparently
Silas has been having some some non-stop
seizures for about ten weeks now some
sense send our positivity up to Silas
and Forrest and howdy howdy Sam were
just sending positivity positivity to
forest and to Silas his son who's
they've he hasn't been able to make it
on hash search the last few weeks
because he's been in it deep with forest
so with Silas or area so we're thinking
about you guys and welcome to dr. mark
who also have snuck in there while I was
yammering away with that yeah hey how's
everyone doing
you know what pretty good we got 471
viewers in the room he might join us
later here in the actual video chat and
in the meantime yeah
just talking about cannabis all these
different things that are going on
Johnny B was mentioning here in Canada
we've got about one month till October
17th I doubt the Liberal government push
it back further what's that right well
it's the 16th so legalization stopped
over 17 so that's 31 days and you know
what I we know one thing I don't think
it'll be one cannabis pot shop open
legally across Canada does it sounds
like any provinces or any municipalities
are ready to even pull the trigger and I
don't think there's any government that
even has a supply chain ready for these
stores to be honest
so I think there's a I think there's
only 30 days in September is that yeah
30 31 days 30 30 30 days 30 that's kind
of what I thought smoke some it's Sunday
morning that's that's better than the 1
minute warning for 4/20 but 30 days a
means yeah I mean with these roadside
screening devices that now come back is
completely set we're not going to get
because even temperature term that
affects these things but I mean lot of
people scared to drive
I saw you post that one about the RCMP
we're gonna be taking semen samples you
realize that was a fake news story right
I don't think I posted that one that was
a bitmap Jenner posted it maintainer
Canada fake news it's funny it was a
funny story but it was people were like
what the heck and then women were like
what are they gonna do with us it's
gonna be interesting what's gonna happen
on that end and stuff like that I mean
hopefully on officers will taking you
know instead of using a machine we'll go
back to the standard roadside screening
I mean you know you can tell us someone
from toxicated and not behind the wheel
it's not that hard on people who are
medically using or just using it just so
they can actually have a better quality
of life he could tell they're not
intoxicated so I have to admit I'm not
the reason I'm not worried about it is
because it seems as though we're heading
in the right direction and you know all
of these like these the worries of like
oh the laws that are coming into our so
bad it's like who the hell is ever going
to get a 14 year sentence for for
something like having an ounce of weed
or you know passing a joint to someone
that was like a year younger than them
and under the age of 18 or something it
just it just seems like their fear and
scars to be laws that I can't imagine
that lawyers like John Conroy and Kurtz
who saw and all these other kin
lawyers Jack Lloyd and Rob w/e lorry
there they're just gonna crush these
clear breaches of the Charter like
they've crushed all the other clear
breaches of the Charter the unique thing
about Canada is when we take these guys
to court we win which is a seemingly
impossible task but I swear to god it's
not that that hard because if you were
to hear them and and John can attest
because he was there as well if you hear
some of the things that come out of
these people's mouths that are
testifying against cannabis at these
hearings they just sound so stupid that
there's not really a judge on the planet
that can't see through it completely
it's beyond ridiculous some of the
things that they say and they end up you
know borderline purging themselves
perjuring themselves to the point where
it's just you can't even take anything
they say seriously and they end up
really building the case for us more
than we build the case when we testify
on our side it's a it's pretty early
that's what happened last week with the
dispensary case he spent all week with
Missy their fight against us and John
figures you can wrap it up on Monday
because just a lot of stuff being sent
people walk out stuff like that canvas
isn't medical this Ock you see it's but
again this goes back to plugging in and
doing it guys I know it's a you say it
sounds simple but if you guys had in a
sued and actually have done that then
nothing would have happened so it just
shows you the case you know it is such
an integral part of the change that is
needed so you know more of talking to
the audience here then you know you
awesome folks who are doing it you know
but it's more of just to make them aware
how they can still plug in and how
important it is to plug in you know of
course going to court isn't cheap it is
easy but it isn't cheap you have to have
lawyers you have to have you know
precedents you know things simple things
like that but you know you can as you
say you know move the discussion you're
actually moving the line in the sand
you're out there holding these people
accountable this knowledge that we've
learned is cannabis you have to go out
there you have to talk to these people
directly who are
buying and counteracting their arguments
directly because if not if you don't do
it who else will biggest thing right now
is where patients can be able to access
their medicine once they can where they
mentally medicate with it if they're in
and and in low-income housing or
anything like that are there no smoke
free zones there's no place for patients
to now go where they able to it all
these clubs that have existed now for
years so there's another fight along the
way and that's gonna be able to be able
to consume cannabis in a safe
environment other than your home that a
lot of people aren't gonna be able to
safely consume
I predict we will win oh we did and
we'll win and like miles high it's gonna
be like it's it's human rights yeah this
you cannot tell someone they cannot
medicate because of their condition
because they're in a wrong place of a
living or they're they're walking you
know give me a break it's let's see what
happens with Court but I mean we're
faced with right we're facing the same
problems the United States you know
people don't have access so now we have
to have safe access zones or safe access
access areas such as just a dabbing
lounge or someplace where people can go
there's very few of them I think they
said there's only a seven in the United
States currently and there's currently
millions of users and you know many
legal states that just want access so in
Colorado they had to win it at the local
level in Denver and in Las Vegas they're
looking at doing that but it's a fight
that is the next step past just gaining
access to the planet now we have to have
safe access and a harbor that we can be
able to go to that we can you know be
social
you know that's it's so key it's such an
integral part of this plant that is
completely lost unfortunately well on
that on that term I want her on that
point I would like to shout out the
gentlemen in Malaysia who's currently
facing being hung for producing and
supplying cannabis oil to some hundreds
of patients that he managed CBD oil CBD
all right yeah CBD oil so he's he's you
know like we've come such a far away
that you know on one
sort of side of things there are people
like this gentleman who's facing death
which is you know we worry about access
but we don't have worries like that you
know people can still practice civil
disobedience and not end up being
murdered for it so you got a shout this
guy out big time I really hope that
something gets done in regards to humans
human rights and that they don't end up
hanging this guy for supplying cannabis
oil because it will be a nightmare story
as it often is when they hang people in
Malaysia for being homosexual or you
know getting caught with drugs or all
these other just absolutely ridiculous
zero-tolerance policies and that leads
me into also shouting out Sarah Blythe
from Vancouver who recently had her
cannabis taken from the Vancouver PD
that she was supplying to opiate addicts
so it was a it was for opiate addicts on
the street who could use something as an
alternative so they go down there and
they you know sell or give cannabis away
at cost they don't make any profits
whatsoever or and the PD and all of
their brilliance thought the other day
it would be a good idea to go and steal
that for storm troopers deep come in and
take the medicine off the table and walk
away with it strapped with guns and it
just seemed like you know I haven't
really seen the Vancouver PD do
something that's stupid in a long time
generally they're they're not too too
bad when it comes to cannabis and the
cannabis laws they usually just sort of
turn their head the other way but they
they went right in there and took away
that cannabis off the table generally
while people standing in the very
vicinity were selling fentanyl
guaranteed that's where you know
wherever the the addicts are that's
where the opioid and fentanyl dealers
are as well and that was just a real you
know Dana Larson posted about it it got
shared hundreds of times the small video
that Sarah made and I just you know
shout out to her and the work that those
guys are all doing on the streets of
Vancouver that's the frontlines right
there that is millions on the war on
drugs for sure today to given away to
give it away packages to patients or
anybody who's suffering from opioid
addiction so the Downey said again today
we did topple with that kind of culture
news live data talked about that and
yeah they just walked in and grabbed it
and walked away and they came back and
asked her well who's on the fence and I
wanna know that like really never seen
before in Vancouver especially with all
the projects we've been doing and the
east side of harm reduction over the
years we'd be giving away cannabis for
years and years to patients around there
and people suffering and they just
walked in and walked away with it it was
servicing and we didn't wash it over and
over
Wow in the United States this week a
guy's mother was killed he was being
served a warrant for a marijuana arrest
and mom tried to block and she was
killed by the police shot and killed so
it's still happening unfortunately
people are still dying for marijuana in
North America the stupidity is still
ongoing so I have to give a shout out to
Michael Kravitz in them who were doing
work directly at the UN level they have
actually been working with the UN minor
councils to arrive at education for them
regarding cannabis and within the next
year we may see a major change at the
1961 convention treaty which has been an
upholding of these heinous laws that
have caused Malaysia to continue to
execute people for something like
cannabis or CBD so at the unexplained
the 1961 tree and and how it's because
this is a big thing that's happening
next Oh at the UN level well it
basically if you receive any money from
the United States government you have to
have a cannabis eradication program
going on and so the United States gives
money to practically every country and
so by doing so part of that law passed
by Gabriel moss and them is to make sure
that there is a cannabis eradication
program going on and so that has been
the main stakeholder at the UN level
that people have been utilizing to
manipulate their country situations such
as the gentleman being hung in Malaysia
and hopefully if that is changed and
removed at the UN level of which they
are talking and it looks like it could
be moving that direct
it would strike that and that would be a
huge change because they are dealing
with the medicalization of cannabis in
our end discussions regarding it because
it's not only happened in the United
States and Canada it's happened in
multiple countries to the point where
the UN had to take notice so there are
brave people down there that are going
down all the time and are really
challenging people at the UN level what
effect that will have we hope that is
positive but again is this something
they've been working on for years and
this is part of that plugging in and
being active thing that is will affect
change but it's slow and at the UN level
it's very very slow but the change is
happening people are there they are
challenging the system but yeah and I
think there's there's a couple of
approaches there there's a couple couple
groups that are working on essentially a
medical exemption because there are
there's a numerous numerous country UN
countries have medical marijuana laws
you know Canada Uruguay have federal
recreational laws in the words so it
makes sense if you look at the slow
transition along usually any state or
federal support UN is going to pass
medical before they pass over the
counter and you're seeing countries like
France also starting to change their
liability right and and you have to
understand that you know France is
basically the header for the EU so what
they decide a lot of people will go same
with Germany in Germany now has medical
cannabis and so you know France is going
in that direction you've got of course
in Netherlands which was really one of
the first so this momentum is building
at not only a local at a country it's
now at a UN level that this is very
important because it affects all the
small countries as well as the big
countries and a medical marijuana always
has been it was it was restricted
correct
yeah it
we're leaving go ahead Mike yeah so
we'll we'll get back in Owenton so the
UN is always allowed medical marijuana
to be produced and researched under the
under specific federal guidelines if
every government is allowed to develop
their own program the u.s. decided to go
with a program where they license the
University of Mississippi to produce and
the issue with the u.s. is that you know
combination of DEA NIDA have to approve
the investigative new drug program that
made it incredibly difficult but other
countries there is some researching in
both cannabinoids and artificial paths
for better or worse but ultimately the
UN has the ability to it change the
scheduling of cannabis on us on a
international level to treat it as a
medical product or as a non dangerous
drug ultimately I think a lot of a lot
of dates are looking at it treating it
like alcohol but in the long term it's
probably a safer drug than tobacco so we
as humans need to treat drugs and
differently different schedules based on
their potential harm to society and then
in all likelihood you're going to see
that general trend towards legalization
but it's a slow and steady progress and
unfortunately especially if the UN it
only has these sessions once every
couple of years I believe and it's going
to be the first time that they actually
have the ability to amend the singles
treaty Concannon yeah the first time
since 1961 so that's significant that
shows you the generations of change but
also the generations of oppression that
we've lived under you know which is
beyond unfortunate
yeah and if they don't get anything
changed at this session next years then
it could be some time before it could be
a changed on a national international
level that window is narrow as well so
all the viewers need to contact their
politicians get them I mean essentially
understanding what's going on there
because that's that's something that you
know in order for the u.s. to release
some of this depression on the research
of Canada we need to be able to accept
cannabis as medical products so that
they can be researched here in the
States as well as international it and
so we can also share that research in it
we can also cross borders and do that
research we can combine you know one of
the things we need to start doing is we
need a germ plasm Institute here in the
north and Americas you know we we have
things that are acclimated over and in
Europe etc and we have of course seed
companies but we have no Institute's
that are actually saving the germ plasm
testing it making sure the terpene files
are proper for what this genetic is et
cetera you know it has a monopoly on
genetics and that's that's unfair to the
medical patients there you sue Sisley
put out a paper that showed that you
miss is not even capable of producing
flowers that meet state regulations for
recreational grade cannabis or matter or
medical because it fails molds and
mildews yeah so and it's something that
that the you know did the federal
government DEA and probably jeff
sessions needed you start issuing the
two two two five five licenses that are
going to open up the having multiple
cultivators for medical research
products that's been allow state
licensed cultivators across the u.s. to
start supplying research that university
level and then we're gonna need
university researchers and students at
those universities to drive that
research forward there's no way Jeff
Sessions is going to do anything sorry
as much as I would love
- no no I don't its train DeLaet the
building and easy
he's either left left behind or you're
gonna have to just get out of the way oh
he'll get out of the way it's just he's
he's gonna get run over by it that's
what's gonna happen to a lot of these
you know what momentum is too big or
recreation they do not work that's not
what they're contracted to do by being
an RDA they do what they're contracted
to do and the ni da has never set these
standards for them and so of course are
not meeting them because they haven't
been asked to and I'm not saying that
Mississippi State and doctor'll totally
who runs it are the richest people in
the world but be honest I like doctor
also live and he is in favor of medical
cannabis absolutely oh yeah no I mono
for that research and I'm glad that
they've actually increased increased
their canopy and increased their
biodiversity of genetics but ultimately
the news when you when you're cultivated
in one region in Mississippi
you know you're out either indoor or
outdoor but outdoors where they do
significant production field you're
limited on the terpenoids
and cannabinoids that are produced just
based on the environmental conditions
did you have to select code versus you
can survive in that moist and warm
climate and then you know being a more
southern latitude it's going to be
harder to produce higher levels of the
rare cannabinoids that they generally
prefer the rather spectrums yeah I know
when there's been some papers put out
there that show that you know CBD
strains groans grown at higher latitudes
produce higher CBD ratios so it's
something that I think that being able
to have gardens for multiple different
terroirs is going to be able to produce
a wider
range of cannabinoid profiles that you
can end up researching more medical
conditions it Mississippi also
discovered many of the cannabinoids with
their research and yeah I feel conflict
with Mississippi but the truth of it is
is it dr. old slowly would have got much
further he has a patent on GP
suppository I mean he believes in it
no yeah nothing against what they're
doing at Mississippi I've got a ton of
respect for real solely but you missus
you you miss shouldn't have a monopoly
on the research and they're suing for
that right now
and it's working its way through the
system there are people trying to
challenge that in the United States so
it's just you know it takes years to
work its way through the system you know
it took me five years to sue the
government and deal with them so a you
know change doesn't happen quickly and
then when you enter the the rubbin
courts it's unpredictable longer and
more expensive than you all ever realize
there is research that's being done
someone's taking a bog wreck that's
being legally purchased in legal states
and being brought back to the laboratory
and being and being researched so you
may not hear about it in the scientific
literature but there is research being
done on commercial cannabis not grown
congratulations doctor on your cannabis
patent this week thank you yeah
congratulate thank you
Oh congratulations as well and I want to
welcome to the room mr. D 420k as well
as someone new who has never been with
us that I've actually met online which
is roster Ronnie is in the house as well
I don't know if he's still here if he's
frozen up but I definitely wanted to
welcome both those fellows into the room
let's get a bog rip in get that out of
the way bong rip mother lovers let's do
it bong rip mother lovers you
od I met someone
what I didn't hear you mark did you hear
me D now you muted I muted yeah I can
hear you I know what I made it myself
all right no I met someone that reminded
me of you the other day dude he was this
I met him out in front of Trev Dealey he
pulled up in this just [ __ ] savage
motorcycle chopper Grim Reaper all over
it you know big muscular dude just look
like a dude that would like you know
looked like a dude back in the day that
I just wouldn't have approached and been
like hey how's it going man what's going
on but I did anyway I approached them at
first I was like dude what's going on
man your bike is awesome like holy [ __ ]
he's like oh thanks brother thanks and I
just sort of walked away went inside the
motorcycle shop and finished doing what
I was doing he said hey brother would
tell me about your bike tell me about
yourself so I I started telling him a
little bit about my bike and how it was
my dad's and he ended up passing away on
it and I restored it he was like that's
unbelievable what a great way to visit
you know I visit with with some people
that way as well and my bike then he
tells me that he runs a camp called camp
my way and it's for soldiers and first
responders who suffer with PTSD and he
takes these guys out into the forest and
he takes them canoeing and
paddleboarding and fishing and just
basically camping to unplug and get away
from all the sort of pressures of social
media and the pressures of society and
he actually did a yesterday he did a
poker run from Trev Deeley to Squamish
up to Whistler and back I wasn't able to
make it because it was my son's birthday
and it was pouring rain but man at 3
o'clock I went out in my truck and I saw
them all driving back from Whistler in
the pouring rain the guy was right up in
front on his Grim Reaper bike and I just
thought man this guy is his name's
Terrence he he was telling me how he
lived homeless he was addicted to drugs
he lived on the streets of Hastings
Hastings in Maine for for three years
and he the guy just was totally ripped
and healthy looking and he was like you
know it's it's people like us that have
to suffer and walk this road that can
that can go back and help the people
that are walking in this on this road
right now and I was just like tons of
tons about him reminded me about about
you like he just he had a different life
but a similar life and he was just like
now he was just like he was like mad I'd
rather hug people than hurt people I
know exactly how you feel man it amazes
me how you pull this stuff out of people
complete strangers we've sat and
Vancouver on up on a bench on the side
of the [ __ ] sidewalk and strangers
have come and spoken and the guy just
just these people sit down and Mark just
takes him out of you know takes them
into their gets [ __ ] out of them that
just you would not be offering to people
completely right and it's pretty amazing
and and the lifestyle you know with him
doing that for the soldiers and spent
man that is such a that is so great I
got so many buddies I'd love to turn
that turn them on to right here in my
own hometown that I that I helped with
you know it's my I got it I got to put
this in here this summer my dad bought a
motorcycle and he bought himself a
brand-new big [ __ ] decker CVO and me
and him and my bro chance we did a six
thousand kilometer ride this summer in
August up to Dawson City then down to
Rupert we went through fires we went
through all the smoke went through the
good stuff the bad some rain 8-day trip
we did 6,000 kilometres and I had fun
200 joints rolled up and I came home
with about 13 yeah that's amazing that
your dad pulled that off buddy
I said to him first I'm like okay you
know like a week before a month before
I'm like okay if you if you start
getting you getting tired or anything
like that don't worry about it
just we can pull over anytime we get a
hotel in the afternoon although she goes
you know [ __ ] don't worry about me kid
I'm worried about
you guys keep it up with me he's almost
60 okay and he [ __ ] he was leading us
like we don't take turns doing beam in
front he when he was in front he was
doing 150 160 steady just [ __ ]
honking on it we were going slower than
him he did [ __ ] great not one problem
not one hiccup not a sore back nothing
it was beautiful well I would just say
to those of you out there that don't
ride motorcycles you know riding a
motorcycle for 6,000 kilometers is
serious business that is no joke you can
you can you can weed out the weak real
quick
but I bet you you've had guys in three
days turn around and go back dude we've
had guys that the first night the first
leg of the trip come up with so many
excuses the next morning yeah I gotta
get back to this I just like you know
dude don't worry about it it's okay if
you can't handle it I'm not I'd have
more respect free if you looked at me
and said [ __ ] this I ain't doing this
instead of feeding me the [ __ ]
[ __ ] I gotta do this I gotta do that
what do you mean you're packed up you're
ready for six days with us come on
honestly don't matter I give you a hug
and [ __ ] you see you know we've we've
rolled in some unbelievable conditions
monsoons I've ridden in the [ __ ]
mountains and snow and you don't both
feet down on the ground still cruising
because we thought you can't stop don't
turn around you know it's uh it's
amazing we've been on some rides mark
that you know mark rides right beside
you no we're [ __ ] cornering
everything when you're riding like that
you're with your bros yeah it's
beautiful man we really enjoy I've
always had a connection with motorcycles
and it's there's something about being
on the big Harley's with your bros like
flying down the road even with just D
420k going down to see this guy highway
going 100 plus K you know 14 to 18
inches apart from one another on the
highway and just I'm ripping around
turns us
it feels amazing it's empowering yeah
and you know like for me it's therapy
I'm like you know I get anxiety every
day and I deal with all that stuff and
all that getting on a bike two gears
it's gone and I got my bike 106 this
year it's a [ __ ] hot rod and it goes
like [ __ ] crazy I love it I was
really impressed with the motor was done
by my buddy and xcalibur cycles and
Prince George have you guys seen this I
don't know what is it you holding up a
green vial you know it this is yes yes
it is a amazing book on the evolution of
glass pipe and its artist and it breaks
down it's not every great artist but
it's quite a few of a lot of them of
some of the most fun I just saw the ease
one there's an L the ease one that was
that was blown for our gallery show in
2003 the degenerate art show that
slinger and I through you make Earth
glass honey oh that goes back well
probably the earliest glass makers I
would assume you know in the seventies I
was in Afghanistan in 71 and they broke
a coca-cola bottle off Amanda the
general amount of it but I'm sure that
was ratified before that well I've given
up two Snodgrass for sure at least in
our culture in our community the the the
touring Grateful Dead fish type culture
Snodgrass seemed to be one of the first
promoting and popularizing color blown
glass glass that changes colors and
shows to their patterns as you as you
get it darker and whatnot and will have
to have Snodgrass on one day when we do
our glass church that's more indicated
glass I just met
well he was really he was just art I
mean you would basically say Bob
Snodgrass is the start of the
American in the North American glass
scene he is his pipes that were going
out and around you know they were very
stuck spoke about in hushed tones back
in the early late eighties early 90s and
I was seeing these pipes and they were
thousands of dollars back then I'm like
oh Jesus Christ that's a lot of you know
money people but they were the most
amazing beautiful first of his kind and
of course then he taught others and now
this is what it's you know evolution
into you know that's Debbie you know
right there you know which is you know
mothership which is you know I heard
that's changed you know Jake is no
longer with them and Scott's not an
owner he's a worker there now that's
trippy yeah things change but the the
art and everything I highly recommend I
think you find on online but this is the
pipe is an amazing book with great
photography which gives a just a great
visual history of the current masters
that are that are out there and
available for you to go find you know a
lot of these shops you know that are
popping up and around that have also
changed with glass they're available
there's amazing pieces of art there
America available in practically every
city USA now as well as in Canada
listen it's full circle go ahead mark I
was just gonna say I I remember going
back to the 70s the famous steam roller
which was nothing more than a glass tube
it was a pipe where I didn't have a bowl
on the side of it
so I think if I remember correctly that
was the first time I ever smoked out of
anything that was just all glass of the
all glass steam roller which I remember
being quite popular and that to me
laughs look like to like the one it has
one hit but I think for designer pipes
you're absolutely right bob was I
remember those mark yeah do you roll
totally paper roll to do the same thing
because I like to be out of the firm way
afterwards I will say this much about
the steam roller not
being created more dead smoke in a pipe
than the I mean then the steamroller
that was some like lick you so hard you
fill that thing up and then take a break
and then go to hit it again it was just
like razor blades like dirty also
reasoning that it would be so cool that
you and so oxygenated yeah isopropyl
alcohol just to clean it out completely
have a completely clean piece of glass
again so yeah oh my god yeah I'm glad
things have changed for the better for
everybody needless to say oh hey Sam yes
can we tell the story about the pipes
that you used to clean your your pipe in
your sink your stink that you have dude
I'll tell you listen this what I did was
I would go ahead tell it I cleaned my
glass farms with boiling hot water from
a saucepan that I boil and dr. barbers
and then I flush it down the sink I have
a sink to my bedroom because this
apartment I have actually was a hotel
and they had Saints in each Devon so the
either you could piss in them or wash
your face or something and so I was
doing this for years and after about
five or ten and years the things that
wouldn't Brennan is already born I tried
sticking up ruler Reuter down there I
tried two different wide compounds that
even the way by that I just gave up it
didn't use it for about a year and then
I called the plumber and he came and he
showed them a snake down there and he
says what is all this black [ __ ] because
it was dry
and sort of almost like hard and glassy
but was chipping alcohols and didn't
react and what was really funny was
about another five or ten years later
you had to do it again dude like the
whole pipe was just almost solid of
rocks I'm surprised you didn't save it
and test it and smoke it I bet you it
was the highest-quality craphole of the
world has are seen CBN love for days
just like pure cannabinoid like
destruction like whatever like Sam's
hash to this day no one's ever put
anything in my pipe that's that's like
it I'm telling you it's like the first
time you smoke it you're literally like
this must be from Mars this is from
another [ __ ] planet this is not of
this earth how can it be so strong it's
like right away you're like is there
like like something else easier to do
that you know a decade or more ago when
there wasn't so much competition out
there now lots of people are making
incredibly potent materials the secret
of mine was it was ricin and it was
really Turkey rich naturally I think the
fact that you lived in all the hash
producing countries collected the seeds
grew the mountain bred them grew those
and made hash I think there's a longer
story to why it's so ridiculous yeah if
I have to say that without a doubt some
of the strongest cannabis that's got
that I've ever smoked was with Sam and
the reason why I started blending and
creating my blends was because there was
nothing I could find as strong hands
down that really for one hit or two hits
that really put you really where you
needed to be my favorite started with
sometime I imagined it's one gram
inspect it in a glass they call them oil
pipes because
the oil in them and then you heat the
glass from underneath and then you can
take a doggone well I I did the same
thing but it - there's my tricep gave it
to Rob Clark
he took him an enormous [ __ ] hit like
the carburetor hit and then looked at me
and when he couldn't breathe he couldn't
talk saying I'm taking [ __ ]
I killed Rob Park with marijuana after
about more than a minute a weason bar he
was able to take breath he said when it
happened is he taking so much vapor that
all of his little long hairs got coated
and they were all stuck together and he
couldn't get any [ __ ] oxygen oh my
god yeah you guys told me that story and
him telling the story of being on all
fours while he was doing it made it even
funnier yeah unfortunately because I'm
such a mean person I was laughing at him
the whole time I'll tell you some some
of that would have made an incredible
footage like you guys would have had the
most incredible reality TV show even
though it would have been ahead of its
time like to be able to watch today some
of these things like you given out
Graham those goo balls for the Queen's
Day celebration in Holland like a gram
of dry sift in one ball like that's
that's a heroic dose yeah it wasn't even
in the ball what I gave Rob it was
completely dry at powder and yeah well
he was smoking it right yeah
and we heated it from underneath but it
just turned into a liquid pool and
bubbles of a pot and he didn't quite
finish it and he tried I was talking
about those balls those goo balls he
used to make oh yeah you're talking
about perhaps Coco he's correct
I call them goo balls those had a half a
gram of TT or gram of TT depending on
the versions but yeah a lot of people
would eat one or two of them and they
could walk I
warned everybody really carefully before
they beg but if you want to I'm good to
you oh my god like the woman at breeder
Steve's wedding who told me I'm from
Jamaica I'll need two of those brownies
less than an hour later she's on a
gurney getting taken out mean the
Brandis looking at me matter-of-factly
and saying when I'm from Jamaica give me
two and I was like all right like if you
want there's a ton of Bud in these
brownies but three people that got sent
to the hospital that way it Evan bones
birthday parties write down my news 50
80 plates yeah yeah I took almost every
single birthday party that I attended
with party those out that there would be
people laying in the grass and they
weren't getting up yeah that's I've
always said it kind of as a joke but I
maybe think that it's not a joke but you
could possibly give someone a high
enough dose of edibles and then like
operate on them no doubt that [ __ ] puts
you I've seen people be out for like 30
plus hours like like using a mirror to
check to see if they're still breathing
like barely like the heartbeat slows
down so much everything is so slow it's
incredible
well when I had surgery I took a look
like it was like 600 milligrams and they
had to do with the anesthesiologist I
don't know exactly how much weed I was
taking because I was eating a lot of
cannabis as you know before my surgery
so they had a baby Dan was a good
surgeon I bet yeah getting knocked out
hey roster Ronnie how are you doing
brother
yeah I'm good Tammy can you hear me yeah
man I can hear you welcome yeah bless up
thank you
vitami on I'm happy to be on here with
the panel some some good guests I've
always watched all the scenes since day
one of the hash shirt so it's really
nice to be on represent in Colorado yeah
man well you know from what I know of
you you're you're a cannabis warrior you
seem to fight yeah yeah man I'm you know
it's kind of been a long time as far as
being in an industry I've been at this
since like 2010 started off with native
roots had a hash company that's the
bubble for a couple years and you know
did the solvent list thing really
grinding out trying to put put that on
the map educate people on good
conscience clean cannabis you know so
that's kind of where I've been the last
couple years have been like ups and
downs as we've seen like the industry
changing here in Colorado as far as
going from you know from that
mom-and-pop shop to more of the Walmart
mentality a lot of companies coming and
go and the solvent this world and and
just a lot of changes going on and I'm
happy to still be in it and still have a
voice so that's kind of primarily why I
wanted to get on here and like you know
spread my story and and show some love
to everybody you know I think more love
is needed in this cannabis community
it's a it's a pretty vast community once
you start thinking about it and how far
it reaches so you know we all play we
all play a role I guess thanks
absolutely man well I always thought of
you also as a bubble ambassador you were
always making the fire bubble oh yeah
yeah you know that's when I got when I
got put on you know with native roots
the owner of that shop at the time had
you know when I guess when the cannabis
industry started here in Colorado there
was a lot of people that knew each other
and they're all coming from the same
backgrounds primarily of being you know
trust fund kids they're having a lot of
extra money or being able to get
involved and be able to afford to get
involved in the industry so everybody
really knew each other and so with that
I was able to network enough to start
you know brushing up on the solvent list
aspect of it I was actually looking to
get out of the industry
at the time when I was working with
native roots and the owner came to me
and he goes hey man you're not going
anywhere he goes you're way too valuable
you're way too much of a people person
we're gonna start a company he's all
your the roster it's bubble hash we're
gonna call it roster bubble you know
started up the Instagram put my head
down for about two years and really
tried to grind away at it and my first
one of my first eleven followers was you
so that was huge for me because I was
you know once I checked out the page I
was like whoa this is the man right here
you know and that kind of started off
yeah I had a lot of clutch people around
me that helped me you know that I could
look to to mold my my talents in my
artistry a little bit better so you know
hats off to all those you know pioneers
and people that have been putting in the
work you know like I said like mila
bubbleman nicotine trichome heavy you
know dab logic all these people around
me locally to not just you know
internationally but that had a big
influence on the direction I saw myself
going and you know that's just I'm
really blessed just to be involved with
cannabis it's really changed my life in
a lot of ways so you know good thanks
that's awesome dude absolutely well you
know what I'm sort of mission statement
in 2018 is to bring back the full mount
you know solvent las' mind is one of the
last people really just pumping the
bubble bags hard there's still people
doing it here and there some great hash
makers as you just mentioned and ken
wall and many others I just want to see
it grow again I want to see more people
making firewater hash not you know I see
people all the time they're like oh I
just want to make some nice bubble to
squish for Oz and I'm like dude you
should want to make some nice bubble so
it comes out six stars so you don't have
to squish it for
it's quick you get that hot little
half-full pleasure to to enjoy that
thing with the set back Mount sift today
any little bit was gifted to me from a
friend yeah fire girl for sure yeah you
know I feel the same way I think here in
Colorado we're seeing that Rhian solvent
lifts we always go through our ups and
downs you know with what's latest and
greatest and what's trending you know
from rising to disel it and now you know
the vape the vape world seems to being
taken over as far as the vague presence
and trying to incorporate rosin and
solvent listen to that world is kind of
the new new wave of things but here in
the last couple weeks I've been hearing
a lot of people speak about bring him
back you know that good old solvent less
passion and using it as a staple in
their shops I'm just that but this this
idea of more organic and more clean
medicine has taken hold because we
talked about it years ago that
eventually the bottom is going to fall
out as we get to this Walmart mentality
that the mom-and-pop shops that are
doing the real quality work and doing
real clean medicine are gonna have a
foothold and be able to stand out as
long as they put in the work to get
there and I'm seeing I'm hearing more
about it as of recent this idea and this
you know so I kind of feel we're at the
forefront of this change of more
boutique shops you know the craft night
verse microbe
did he freeze up on me yep
yeah alright I think he was out in the
greenhouse or something well hopefully
he comes back hey I wanted to welcome
Wade to the room as well or at least
waits for head yes wait here listening
in grateful good to see you guys
yeah I wanted to check in about
inspiration which was your suggestion on
topic today I'm feeling really inspired
this morning we had a big event
yesterday here on the farm the
International cannabis Farmers
Association is a group of outdoor
growers who are really focused on data
and how it relates to regulation in the
California marketplace and yeah we had
about I don't know 40 people come to the
farm and I just want to put it out there
I see F a dot farm and then there's
another thing going on Sun and Earth
certification this is suggested set of
guidelines for what appellations of
origin and a certification process if
you will that's all about regenerative
practices I'm pretty thrilled to see
what they've done and like I said that's
up put it up on the the group chat thing
would that be the thing to do Marcus
instead of trying to repeat it again
yeah yeah you can put it into this chat
you can put it into the other chat we
can put it on the Facebook page we can
get it out there okay and yeah there it
doesn't cost anything to be a member
what they're really looking for is
feedback from small farmers about how
the regulatory framework in California
at least is working out but literally
internationally we'd love to hear from
people about
if they think that the sun and earth
certification protocols for example
would work on commercial scale I'm
pretty convinced they are it's basically
a good description of dragonfly Earth
medicines practices go ahead Sam I have
a question for you Wade yeah people are
doing Appalachians but I hear this all
over Northern California especially but
most of them are growing in man-made
soils or digging big holes which they're
filling with other soil so how can you
get an appellation if you're not using
the Nene burger I've often wondered this
I couldn't agree more especially when
you work see Appalachians as the model
that's being used in wine where do I saw
everything to do with terroir the soil
sun and earth certification does include
a terroir component but it's also really
focused on cultivars it's really focused
on practices the approach that you use
to generate your the amendments you need
on your farm for years I've been doing
ferments and composts and permaculture
and harvesting mushrooms from spots on
the property all about trying to create
our own amendments here on the farm that
way we know that cannabis because it's a
bio accumulator doesn't accumulate any
problematic materials from things you're
bringing in from another supplier like
you were saying Sam if you're buying
dirt or soil how do you know what's
actually in that soil you don't but if
you're making it yourself even more so
it's not difficult terroir from that
area well yes
one of the factors that I think is going
to be played up in cannabis is
environmental conditions how in very
different environmental conditions
affect different versions of cannabis
certain cultivars flourish in some
environments and other cultivars do not
you've spoken about that before just
look at fungus resistance for example so
part of Appalachians is like I say as
you were saying that the native soils
part of it is practices and because if
you like here in Nevada County there's
quite a few people who work in pots
large pots that are in the ground but
because the ground here a lot of the
county is old mine tailings this is gold
country all the rocks got dug up and
front three hundred years ago and there
are large areas of the county where it's
just vast rock fields you can literally
see them in satellite views but there
are other places where there's
incredibly rich soil we happen to be
fortunate enough to have found one of
them and by adding to the diversity in
the soil and into the diversity of this
the plants and wild insect native life
of that size scale if you will what I
found is once you find the right
cultivars the plants flourish you know
you know integrated pest management is a
lot easier when you've got the plants
that are right for the situation you're
in so I think that's part of
Appalachians another part of
Appalachians is the historical culture
the actual history multi-generational
history of cannabis work in Northern
California so also whoever is really
really important
yes exactly Sam so so that was that's
kind of inspiring to me I really feel
like it is one path forward that allows
small farmers to have a chance to
actually survive in the coming in the
marketplace that already exists here in
California and so I want to change the
subject now because that's a very
depressing subject the whole regulated
market in California bubble bags
I love the bubble bags Marcus thank you
it's it's a gift to all of us and for me
in my life it's again if you're talking
about small farmers if you educate
yourself on how to use the bags and what
you're actually doing in that process
you can make extraordinarily high
quality in material if you're beginning
source material is of quality and you
handle it properly every step of the way
and that their beautiful design home
scale high quality manufacturing
technique and that's pretty far out
thank you yeah dude I made a batch the
other day for the first time in a while
actually I was doing an online course
that I'm doing over at ganja talks
University it was a Brazilian guy that
contacted me and said hey you know the
people in Brazil could really use this
information but they really kind of
require it in Portuguese so they did
Portuguese subtitles for these videos
and I did three of them so far on bubble
hash and then yesterday was the live
demo for that module of the course and
the course gives you the three bubble
bag videos plus the live demo then it
gives you three dry sift videos plus a
live demo then it gives you three rosin
videos and a lot plus a live demo so
that'll be the full solvent list course
that I'm doing with ganja talks and
yesterday or two days ago yeah was the
first was the first live demo video so I
made some bubble hash flap gave me a
half pound of some beautiful bud that
turned out to be really nice melty stuff
pretty dark but really really nice
probably gonna be before Marcus was
distributing bubble bags and a few of
the boats the the truth of it was nobody
had really really really clean hashish I
mean you could buy imported a sheet but
to find it as clean as you can make at
home Hey
guys and gals I love y'all but I'm gonna
have to head out here so I'll see y'all
next time and just to give a heads up
I'm gonna be at the state of cannabis
conference a 2.0 and September 25th and
26 on the Queen Mary in Long Beach so if
y'all anybody you know so come on down
if you're able to and much love to you
guys and I'll see y'all next time thanks
that tear good to chat with you good to
have you in and yeah I agree
Sam it was the truth that was the sort
of amazing thing to be lucky enough to
be in that position to release the
bubble bags around 1999 isolator bags
had just come out in 1998 at the end of
that year bubble bags came out at the
start of 99 and it was just a unique
thing to be able to teach people how to
create hash that was just you know the
ultimate bragging rights sort of speak
to have this quality of hash that was
just liquefying and melting and bubbling
in a way that no one had really ever
seen or money could make rush it that
that time to but nobody was making it
very clean I mean I was but very few
people were making it where it would
melt and bubble and well and it was
indeed your dry sip that got me sort of
before water hash was even a thing it
was in 1995 but my first cop that I was
there with owned I ended up smoked some
I didn't know at the time that it was
your sift but Rob had it and I think it
was at that old Thai food restaurant
that we used to go to the small one that
Rob would always take people to and I
remember hearing him on the stairs say
if it don't bubble it ain't worth the
trouble and just like watching this hash
bubble and dripped through the screen
and drip down the down stem of the of
the Ruhr and I was just like what the
[ __ ] and that sat with me for a couple
of years kind of trying to figure out
like what was that like how did they how
did they have hash that melted into
liquid you know before it existed it was
kind of an impossible thing to wrap your
head around and it wasn't until seeing
the isolator bags you know three and a
half years later and then coming out
with our own bags and starting to be
murder we realized holy smokes like this
is this real an enormous amount of
friendships for me around the world
that's for sure how I met dee 420k i'm
sure actually yep
oh yes watering it a little argument
between me and someone else said come on
down to the melting point if you're in
Vancouver tough tough with me Dee 420k
yeah yeah me smoke back [ __ ] volcano
like tried that volcano you put some
real ugly leaf in there that was the old
gave me a big bag of that it was like
holy [ __ ] does this ever [ __ ] taste
good and I was the first time I spent
money like that on something that I
smoked on I think it was like [ __ ] I
think back then they're like 1,400 bucks
err I was at least a thousand Canadian
for sure maybe they looked I bought one
what was that yeah you did pretty much
everyone I blaze down especially with
that little trick right cuz of course I
had better but I just wanted to show
people the sort of power of this little
tool where you could just put something
in that was seemingly and didn't look
that good and just vaporize the resin
off of it and get a super tasty tasty
rip that was a long time ago that was 15
years ago
um that's how I sold the volcanoes out
of the store I had up here in Prince
George I had a shitty bag of sweet
Island skunk that was in a leaf in a bag
well we're getting the wind in the mic
welcome back restaurant I did just mute
you cuz you got the wind there were you
in a greenhouse by the way yeah I'm
actually a work yep greenhouse hybrid
model definitely supplemental lighting
nice yeah so like I was saying earlier
it's really nice to get back to this
remerged
emergence of solvent lists at least the
talks of it coming back and a real clean
product for for the consumers and for
the patients out there that's kind of
what I based my whole energy off of when
I started with native roots like I said
the owner was like hey you're the Rasta
it's bubble hash you know we're gonna
start a company called Rasta bubble so I
put my head down for like two years
really focused on making that better
making that a real thing and like I said
like certain key things there was
something that I caught YouTube I think
it was a YouTube video of bubble man at
high times you know getting people
getting getting people lifted off of his
hash and like showing them the process
off of you know drying on the cardboard
and there was a couple key things that
you said and one of them being he was
said if everybody's doing it it's
probably wrong and that was key it stuck
out stuck out for me as far as part of
my technique and it really changed
changed my game as far as like my drying
technique and and the actual end product
so you know hats off to you for the
advice and you know that type of stuff
is crucial I think the information that
we share like like be a hash search and
just in general is key for any anybody
in all people to like be consuming clean
cannabis I think is the goal in the long
term you know we don't we want to put
good medicine out for people not just
stuff that's going to sell that's could
you tell us how you do your curing
technique you're drunk technique yeah
well it's kind of changed at least
evolved over over sometime just within
an introduction of the freeze dryer you
know I did a seven-day cure process from
you know from actual washing to 24-hour
like drying on racks part
paper then would go into a cold room for
good you know what [ __ ] freezer for
good six seven days and then I'd be
visited and then if you're talking
commercially then I would go into graham
jars glass graham jars and from the
parchment if we were going into like a
commercial aspect but if it's like for
personal head stash or anything like
that I go into mason jars just small you
know deep dish low mason jars but like
with the freeze dryer commercially
that's kind of changed the game as far
as you know rosin pressing and being
able to keep up to speed from me myself
I put up a lot of numbers here in
Colorado as far as making hash by myself
I've never really worked with a team I
might have somebody that might grab my
hash out for me or help me do like
certain tasks but nothing as far as the
process and production of it it's always
been me and trying to put up high scale
numbers and that's the thing with native
roots as we got to one from one store to
eight stores quality became an issue you
know because it's not just me dealing
with the product but when it goes to the
bud tenders and how they store it at the
shop where it's being stored how it's
being stored all those things come into
a part and then also you know as we
scale up it seems like quality becomes
you know less of an importance and
quantity becomes more of the importance
so that reflects and the concentrates
for sure and not something that I you
know typically want to go buy for
quality over over quantity all day so
yeah you know and with that said in the
last couple years the dynamics of the
industry changing like I said solvent
list is kind of you know taking a
backseat when it when it came to rosin
and then resins taking a backseat when
it came to the sauces and the diamonds
and you know in the distillate so is
it's nice like I said I've been hearing
more talks here locally be amongst
owners and shop owners and patients that
really want to see this reemergence of
just good quality salt on this hash
regardless if it's fresh frozen or if
it's dry I mean I think the idea of like
you know a pure form to concentrate is
is what people are leaning towards you
know less chemicals absolutely okay
thank you very much man that's uh that's
just some good information right there
how about your dry sifting when you're
doing any static tak with that with the
paint rollers I've been seeing that and
I kind of I haven't tried the paint
roller technique with the static tech
I've tried everything else with the
static time every kind of material with
the static tack but the paint roller and
I've had quite a few messages saying hey
try the paint roller make a video of it
all that kind of stuff have you been
yeah no I haven't actually you know I
did get a set of dry set screens which I
was working with for probably a good six
seven months and to me dry sifting is
kind of like the Zen the Zen extract as
far as like you know I find myself I can
just get caught lost up in the process
alone it's almost like doing a bonsai
tree for me you know it's real
meditation and um and to fight you know
I'll repress through the screens like
once I get to the lower screen Laure
mesh screen repress through the screen
but as far as static tech I never got an
opportunity to really try it I'm no
cuban cuban kind of hit me off with like
his tack at least what you know the
steps of what to go by so when I got my
screens I messed his Cuba Cuban hit me
up he's like try this this and this and
then he recommended the static as well
but I just never got a chance to apply
it oh do it man do it yeah it changed
the game for me like like it changed the
whole game for me 100%
nice yeah I definitely will probably get
to it here pretty soon I'm kind of down
harvest stuff I've relocated when I was
with native roots I got a job
opportunity it was kind of one I
couldn't refuse they they wanted to pay
my rent for a year move me out to
Glenwood Springs I worked at Aspen for
about three years real culture shock for
me and my family but a real great
opportunity just the experience to be on
that side of the state kind of a part of
Colorado I never seen before but with
that said the pulse of the industry and
what drives the industry and kind of the
energy that I came from really wasn't
out in that area or that sided side of
the state
so I kind of brought that energy with me
out there it helped open several several
nips and you know we're also working in
another greenhouse that was doing
organics organic growing so I've learned
a lot in the last three years which
didn't so much resolve and revolve
around cannabis or solvent list but more
on a whole level of cannabis and and how
to function and operate within this
industry and and be successful at it and
not compromise I wanted to welcome Eric
to the room I see he's come in under the
name Bridgette but we're gonna call them
that's my loaner computer nice how's it
going dude it's going good
how you guys been oh fall here summers
winding down and it's starting to get
rainy and I guess we'll get that for a
couple of months until until the snow
starts falling and then it's Mountain
culture all winter long sledding
snowboarding skiing yeah I took I took
our boat out of the water yesterday and
I was like oh it's so bittersweet to you
know close the summer out pull the boat
out and then oh my god it's time to tune
up the snowboards and get all that gear
ready now so you know it's bittersweet
to say goodbye to summer but when
there's always fun - but yeah I've been
having an exciting time lately I've been
traveling a lot going to lots of
different greenhouses and I got to check
out the loud packed greenhouse last week
and a bunch of others in the Monterey
County area and and I actually finally
found some really clean grows I was
surprised that Monterey area you can
find a lot of the cannabis plants are
covered in dust and besides other things
too but it's a real dusty area I've
found and so I was able to actually loud
packs one of them and there's another
farm over in Salinas that I was really
impressed like dust free really clean
testing clean all these good things
happening so it was kind of fun to
finally see some progress I guess you
could say out there damn testing clean
and Salinas I've never heard those two
things in like
yeah it's not I don't know how common
that is but it's it's definitely
happening and it's far and few between
but yeah it was a fun trip I saw a lot
of glass greenhouses polycarbonate
greenhouses the acrylic covers like got
to see all kinds of stuff so I'm
learning a lot as I go and I missed Wade
last night I didn't realize that was
your house Wade I was busy pulling the
boat out and all that other stuff and I
didn't get a chance to come to that
meeting at the for the Appalachians it
was kind of I found it last minute so
I've been meaning to call you back Wade
and talk about that yeah those folks
left that's a little that's why I was
late getting on Church this morning but
and I spoke about it earlier I'll fill
you in next time I see you I'm pretty
excited about it
there's a CDFA is doing the first
scoping meeting down in Sacramento the
series of scoping meetings they're doing
on Appalachians this happening Wednesday
down in Sacramento and I'm gonna make a
road trip get in the car and go do down
there they're gonna do a heritage rally
on preservation of culture and then the
scoping meeting from 1:00 to 4:00 maybe
I can make dad I'm not sure but yeah
definitely catch up with you on that now
that I'm back okay cool let's talk later
one thing I was talking about earlier
also was about I was really given chops
about bubble bags and what a difference
they'd made and how accessible to small
farmers high quality concentrates are
now as a result and I mean it's been
that way for a long time but it was
really one of the first ways that you
could harvest trichomes and and get high
purity so yeah yeah shout out to bubble
man on the bubble dad it's for sure I
feel like it's kind of the Burton
of hash bags you know it's accessible
for everyone and anyone it's gotten to
that point that you know we can all use
it and hold I mean it's you know
virtually you know the same processes
can be done for anyone and I think
that's what's dope about it is that you
know we should be all more supportive of
each other you know especially with
people doing good work and quality work
not so much that competition mentality
but you know that it is what it is you
know the strong will survive but you got
to be supportive of those that are doing
good work as well you know I mean
absolutely you got to it's the bubble
ambassadors pushing the message out
there clean unadulterated cannabinoid
HEIs my very favorite I'm always happy
when people are puffing on the phone
Melton I'm extra happy when people say
hey bubble man you want to smoke some
hash and they pull out full mouth I'm
like uh actually I I really do
I was at I was at Vance I went into vans
the other day the shop with my
four-year-old son and I'm walking around
in there and I hear from across the
store this guy go bubble man and it was
like one of the guys that worked there
and he's like helping a woman with her
like twelve-year-old son and he just
he's like I'll be right back and he runs
across the store to me and my son and
he's like dude I'm a huge huge fan of
the seulement list quiver I love bubble
hash dry sift and rosin I just wanted to
thank you I was it was quite an amazing
feeling actually I was like right on you
know I'm a huge fan of the solvent list
quiver it's like just being able to sort
of have you know have people recognize
just from a shirt even wearing something
like this the 90 microns shirt generally
people will see that if they're in the
no one kind of give you that sort of
like I like the 90 micron it's just
awesome when we were in the airport
meeting my brother and sister those
people came up to us that's right
that's right thank you happens a lot
when we're together too it makes it puts
a huge smile on my finish - yeah sure
yeah it's funny right it's just nice to
have like like-minded people it's kind
of like being at a Phish show without
being at a fish show we're just like
random people can come right out of this
huge crowd of people and be like hey hey
I like the phone mount you like the
phone out absolutely love the phone
mount
maybe I'll have a puff of some foam out
right now we've blazed a few of those
people down too right there and then
pretty much yep yeah it's happened many
times it happened on my Whistler video
in the gondola at the end of the video
paddy and I end up puffing a bunch of
people down that we had never met before
that were that we're excited to have a
little puff it's kind of one of the joys
of cannabis and it's really it shows the
our of cannabis even under the umbrella
of paranoia and the umbrella of
prohibition people were still willing to
sort of you know have trust and have
faith and the thing what the DEA really
always were attacked
attacking were where it was trust you
know like back in the day when Howard
was doing his thing Howard Marks they
you know doing things with with tons of
material that was like on the cuff it
was like oh yeah the semi is at this
address just pull up you know way what
you eat it like no the DEA started
getting people to rat on one another and
busting people they just sort of
disintegrated that trust and some people
have always held on to it maybe not
necessarily to do like a five time deal
or whatnot but to just have trust at a
concert and share a joint with someone
or smokeable with someone that you don't
know and I think it's gonna be one of
the powers of cannabis when cannabis
becomes more legal and prohibition drops
away that we're gonna see this
incredible power of just being able to
be like before you get to the concert I
can remember driving to a Jethro Tull
concert in the sixties and or late
sixties and it was a long beach if I
remember correct and we were driving
Hollywood we're on the freeway and I
noticed that the car next to us that was
on the freeway there was three guys in
their past and they're joining so I
waved at them cuz I'm a smoker one week
the cars got really close to each other
and we traded joints on the freeway I
don't know who these people were never
saw them again they were probably going
to get through it all who knows that's
pretty awesome bong rip passing doobies
out the window at 80 K an hour although
I guess you guys don't drive kilometers
down there 50 miles an hour maybe
Bhangra you smile that
[Music]
just enjoying day I was just thinking
about like a convertible and just a
convertible would be great because you
could just kind of like toss it right
into the car as it's moving you know not
have to worry about getting it through
the window because the entire top is
down so I can only assume on those hot
summer days in California that there's a
lot of convertibles driving around and
so convertible would just make a bigger
target throw the joint into it not so
easy to joints in a convertible
they run it's just hard to light him
right Sam well it's yeah it's almost
important but you can use a cigarette
lighter for that oh maybe a hot coil oh
boy
hey Mark did I read the chat earlier
that Andrew was trying to get in then
who was
Indra our friend Indra John Davis well
he says he can't get into the actual
YouTube chat room oh oh he can't get a
chattering okay I didn't know if he was
trying to get on is he still in the
penalty box he's not in the penalty box
no I just I just listen I just want to
make sure that the conversation is not
all about one person's product right and
I just I hear you we all have things
going on there's all sorts of things and
it's you know you guys were talking
about bubble bags that's great and we're
talking about the khalad race it's
always good to mention these things I
just like for me I would love for hashed
church to be nonstop bubble hat bubble
talk for for the two or three hours
every episode but people don't want that
they don't want to just hear about
bubble hash for two or three hours every
week so we mention it here and there I
could probably count on like one or two
hands how many times I've mentioned
my own product on past church I got a
question for Sam it's kind of going back
to that green house hashed Church we had
a while back when he was talking about
sexing plants by putting him in the dark
for one day I had people comment on that
or asked me after Sam wanted to know
what size or what stage are the plants
and when you actually do this sexing of
the plants or when when's the best time
new small big in the beginning they were
from seed but later on everybody grew
with Colin so it was but clones you
usually know what the sex is already so
it's usually seeds that they're grown
and they have to be at least maybe a
foot tall then I mean you can sexing if
you're just going to sex of them
strictly only sex them need to need to
do it a bit earlier but if you're going
to flower them then you want to have a
little size to the plant before you plow
it yeah because there's a lot of people
popping beans or planting seeds nowadays
compared to getting clowns just because
the whole clone fiasco in California was
so such a dirty business that you know
the Philo's came out now and has sex
testing kits also to help people that
they can go I guess as soon as the plant
I'm not sure which stage exactly it has
to be and they can take yourself as soon
as you I think you can even use my
pronunciations terrible terabyte title I
didn't or you know the little rowdy
people before the sale urgently oh well
but the problem with those tests is they
can tell you if the DNA is made of a
female correct but they can't tell you
if it's a female but to intersect so
he's still got to do your work dude well
and that's the problem a lot of the test
kits for most people are expensive and
so with the expense of the test kit the
knowledge the
dropped that day on hashed Church about
being able to sex the plants and putting
him in the dark for one day was huge
that'll work really good for early fast
maturing varieties for later maturing
varieties you might walk two or three
days okay okay yeah cuz it got a lot of
people's attention after that one
because like I said the sex test kid is
kind of expensive for craft growers and
a lot of people are popping seeds and so
you know everybody wants to eat
everything and nothing figured it out uh
so we'll just show sex it will not
pitching the flower and it's easy breezy
yeah that's amazing I didn't think one
day was enough but it makes sense why
you see this two weeks later it will
deflect our sex and just to clear sex at
the crotches if you only do it one day
like that so it'll draw a couple of
either male or female flowers whatever
the plant is uh later [ __ ] I mean he
never really left then you've just
powered a tiny tiny tiny bit
i'm peacing out got charged to do before
my lights go off nice talking with all
of you
hey crazy everybody take it easy deep
and enjoy the day I know I'm going to
shower now I want a little in a thing at
least back when I was doing indoor
farming I found I don't know how I
discovered it maybe it was part of
trying to understand photo period and
how it affects cannabis but I found that
most of the different cultivars I was
working with if I gave them a 24 hour
period of darkness when I moved them
from their growing phase to their
flowering phase I would reduce as much
as a week to 10 days off of the amount
of time that it took them to finish
flowering and I wonder if anyone else
would also late yeah it's also slightly
reduces yield ah well I was younger
flowery gives more yield in general it
might be that I didn't
that because the other practices I was
working with this was when I was in my
learning curve about how plants
responded indoors but I remember
learning that one fairly early on and
maybe other things contributed to the
increase in the yields that I saw but
yeah I I want a second what Eric brought
up and what you've shared with us
already that cannabis is incredibly
sensitive to photo sent this photo
period how long a period of darkness it
has and you can do a lot with learning
about your plants by taking cuttings of
seedlings and putting them in dark and
seeing what's going on with them yeah
one of the first things we did was we
took the exact same phone and we have it
be maintained under 18 or 24 hours from
light or whatever it was and then we
took identical size pots identical
science clone to the same quote and we
flowered some of them under a hour
or that and lovely flower just
at me from 1820 to 12 whatever I wish
would easy for flour and other ones we
brought it down gradual so notice we
knocked off uh two three four minutes a
day and it absolutely gives you
different form different yields
different results
another thing that I have run into Sam
and I have a question about is that I
run into a lot of people that are doing
like deprivation you know early
flowering in the summertime when it's
really hot and a lot of people get great
buds and great quality and it doesn't
cool down much in the evening time but a
lot of people try to say that they
experience the plants being finished
seven to ten days sooner than they
normally would if they were like grown
indoors let's say like a lot of people
will say oh this plant flowers in you
know 60 70 or whatever days but in a
greenhouse doing light deprivation in
the middle of the summer they actually
feel like or seen that they harvest like
I sent seven to ten days earlier have
you ever well there's a couple possible
reasons number one is the loads you
receive from the Sun in a greenhouse are
way beyond anything you're given
artificially the flights so all of the
temperatures I've seen what you're
saying too but I can't say concretely
what why it was in their case but I
started to suspect to their just say
yeah it's kind of a fun phenomenon I
guess you could say or something that
occurs or happens that I hear a lot but
I don't know if it's through testing or
people just looking at it going yeah
it's done and going through that method
or whatever I know in general I I liked
cooler temperatures at night and I also
like not such extreme high temperatures
I find really high temperatures have a
tendency to pull it off the terpenes
faster or the living plant I mean I can
agree with you on that one of the things
I found
through our my practices was and I found
this this summer at a farm actually and
it was kind of ironic to see see it
happening there is that a lot a lot of
times I would put my greenhouse where it
gets four o'clock shade by a tree in the
afternoon and if it gets full Sun all
day long and then starts to go in the
shade about four you know 4:30
maybe even earlier at times we would see
the plants start to cool down before we
pull the light depth cover and that
would actually you know nowadays with
the more advanced greenhouses you can
still run ventilation and do all these
things that we couldn't do before but
even for the do-it-yourselfer palm tarps
doesn't have a lot of ventilation when
they do all that carbon so the minute
they pull the tarp we're seeing less
condensation in the greenhouses because
of the fact that plants have a chance to
cool down and you know I see I think
help the quality of the Canada it's
quite a bit because of that fact and it
has that chance to cool down a little
bit before we encase it in that bubble
it makes sense to me I mean well when
the plants are really cooking in the
greenhouse and it's really freaking hot
their stomata are completely open and
that transpiring water vapor like you
can't believe which is not good when he
closes it all up no cuz I went to a farm
that actually was asking me some
questions and they had one that's at the
top of the hill in the middle of the Sun
and then they had another greenhouse
that's down below and got in the shade
and the stuff in the shade in the early
afternoon had better quality and the
stuff that was up in the full Sun and
they pulled the tarps at the same time
and did a lot of these things but to
stuff down load by cooler quicker and I
thought that was you know one of the
main reasons it was better 25 years ago
we still didn't until recently so every
time we would spray our greenhouse with
white they call it called care it's like
a white paint that's water-soluble and
you spray the outside and agree
to reduce meat in the summertime on the
right levels in the heat and it it
absolutely consistent their canvas with
no loss of yield then high temperatures
and way more life I'm just holding down
the chat room that's the reason I'm not
talking right now there's a whole thing
going on in the chat room right now that
I'm just sort of trying to stay on top
of I'm just kind of working away I got a
cord running across the top of my laptop
because it died I sure didn't while I'm
sitting here I might as well um put some
clothes and some dirt with you guys
that's it you know working away I'm like
Sifton making my medicine for the
weekend
plant my plants and make sure
everything's ready to go for next crop
nice you should come over here one of
these days John I have some some resin
but this boxes is all the animals that
were entered in the Karma Cup this year
I'm gonna head downtown and I'll watch
that court case with the dispensaries
tomorrow and maybe when it's over before
I should come on up and say yeah make
sure you do it earlier than later
because I think I'm flying to Toronto
tomorrow and then on to Manitoba - maybe
secure some acres of biomass for a CVD
project I'm working on that's awesome
well we'll talk up to church and we'll
make some arrangements sounds good
sounds good
ten more minutes I think a to our church
will be in order today nice and short
shorts it's always educational going on
I got a Hindu Kush but that it yes it's
a Hindu Kush clone that my my little
puppet Sammy was working on
nice good job Sammy little Hindu Kush
just a little good job Sammy Sammy's
getting his hands dirty
what's that does anyone hear that yeah
yeah hear it totally is he come out like
robot total robot rest our robot might
need to come back in it's really we're
not hearing you good I did kind of hear
him saying okay that was robotic for
sure all right doc Wireless yeah
Wireless does suck a little bit doesn't
it
so CBD big big companies moving in a
town I guess we're gonna get a lot of
CBD medicine on the market here for
legalization quite quickly I see yeah
yeah it's a big part of the lab that I'm
involved with building they're gonna
definitely do we're going to definitely
do large-scale crude oil production and
distillation and isolate for CBD and THC
a we do not with fields or with the
plant tourists or separations I know
there's a lot of stuff going on in my
home I think all of the above you do the
row of 20 CBD I'm doing the rubber
you're doing the robot it's cuz you're
not meeting your Mike maybe how do I
sound now better much better
yeah it's cuz when when when we don't
need our mics it makes
that robot thing even more sort of easy
to happen so sorry about that Roboto
bubbleman in the house but uh yeah what
was I saying
I guess I was talking about Oh that
we're gonna go all the routes have green
house partners have filled growing hemp
have crude oil from you know countries
like Jamaica and Colombia be able to get
imported into Canada that we can produce
isolate from I think having a variety of
sort of streams makes the most sense but
and it's the only exciting time to a
legalization at least you know now I
understand whenever you say that there's
always some sour sap in the audience
that's like this is it legalization this
is prohibition 2.0 but I'm not sure
those people remember having their doors
kicked in and being arrested and having
their kids taken away and all that or
other fun stuff that happened in the
days of prohibition this is definitely
better it's not perfect just like when
alcohol prohibition and if it didn't end
and then you could just buy alcohol on
every street corner it was like slow and
steady and you couldn't even put like
beer signs in your window right away or
other you know alcohol sold here so I
think I'm hoping that it's not going to
take as long as it did with alcohol 20
to 30 plus years but regardless if it
does we've made some big strides in the
last 10 to 20 years in this in this
community industry whatever you however
you wanted last the last five years just
catastrophic that what the changes that
be just amazing I mean it just solves
2012 it just like something happened and
it just kind of just one like that and
now we're seeing it I see well I think
it all started back in the 60s right
right I think it's better that big
business and government is involved
because they're not involved that big
business and government will hate
cavernous and it'll just be illegal
forever and
and that's not better that's definitely
not better agreed I have this sort of
argument all the time because people
like we don't need all these regulations
and I'm like I think we need some
regulations maybe we don't need all of
them but some it's like imagine going to
a kitchen at a restaurant that doesn't
have to follow food safety simple food
safety regulations I mean those are put
in place for the for the end for the end
consumer safety so that you don't end up
with food poisoning or eating so I end
up with the kitchens but also breed rats
in the same room for selling rats I'm
telling you it's it's definitely a good
idea and I hear the argument all the
time where people are like these legal
companies are just poisoning us they've
already had recalls and I'm like listen
that means they got caught and they got
and it's known the other side of the
coin is that nobody ever knows because
nobody ever gets caught because nobody's
testing and you just put it into the
black market and sell it that doesn't
seem better either I don't understand
the mentality and people thinking like
I'm gonna continue to buy from the black
mark I mean I get this if you're in one
of those people that can grow your own
then amazing it's great to grow your own
but it's not realistic to think that the
majority of people are going to grow
their own cannabis for their own
medicine we do it because we love it and
it's our passion but it is a substantial
amount of work when it all breaks down
and to think that it's as simple as most
people grow their own tomatoes or is a
tobacco or make their own beard wine
sure we all know people who do but not
the majority not the majority and even
the people that do did they grow enough
tomatoes for their entire year or do
they eat their own Tomatoes for a month
or two and that was just kind of a nice
little thing you know are they literally
producing all their food all like 24
hours a day 365 days a year it's it's
rare for sure are they making their own
clothes and you know like cannabis has
got to be available to those that want
it and
it and not just those that can grow it
so I see it
I love access it's fantastic it'll be
great to see I hope your bubble hash in
the store sent dry says Bob you gotta
start making it you know I'm working
with Whistler technologies now and we're
producing some large-scale reactors and
linear actuators for washing large
amounts of water hash at a time so
that's a project I'm very excited about
we got a nice 300 liter unit coming out
you can check the check us out at
Whistler tech Whistler technologies on
Instagram they're got a three-count I'm
greedy new cannabis variety for each of
the resin heads will be the size of a
large great feed builds all the
sweetness out the window it's like you
just like you don't even notice you
could use the largest hold screen and
it's gonna catch them but if that's wise
you could pick them with a pair of
tweezers I say you decide how these
tweezers
you use more like a fishing net very
nice partly depending on doing the hemp
extraction in Canada yeah you could get
one of have you seen the machine that
harvests cherries from cherry trees yes
it's just like it goes under and it
opens this big umbrella under the tree
and then it grabs the trunk and it
shakes the [ __ ] out of the tree and all
the cherries fall into this piece and go
down it's a we got to make those custom
custom units for the new cultivar that
Sam's working on yes variety but when
you shake the tree maybe cannabis tree
the chemical just breaks off immediately
even in hot temperatures it falls down
into your net right be awesome I mean I
want
not project for I have to say the sift
is the tastiest of all tastes and 11
thank you for you guys for showing us
how to make epic medicine available can
I'll do it at home yes and thanks
everyone for coming out today I'm gonna
call it a day here at the two-hour mark
of hashed Church episode eleven pastors
2.0 episode eleven
thank you guys sort of last minute once
again for coming on and making
conversation thanks for Mike West who's
come and gone and thanks to raster
Ronnie who's come and gone and thanks to
Etienne Fontaine who has come and gone
and of course Dee 420k who has come and
gone the rest you guys dr. mark Johnny
be Wade the skunk man Sam and the 500
people who are still viewing this thank
you all so much I hope you have a great
Sunday and we will see you next time
peace out buddy these guys thank you
everybody