alright hey everybody welcome to a hash
Church episode 10 of hashed Church 2.0
bubbleman here and I will send out the
link to send out the link that's what we
do here on hash Church at 9:00 a.m.
every Sunday morning not that we've done
every Sunday morning for the last few
months but we're getting back into the
track of things here sometimes it's a
little bit difficult to get a show
organized so these last couple of shows
have really just been sort of fly by the
seat of my pants invite whoever can come
the night before and kind of go from
there so see who comes in now people
popping in the chat room all morning
we got Ron Jones and John Maddox and
seventies Mama's in there and Rackham
Cuban chronic Cuban grower it's it
should be a good one we already have a
hundred and ninety-six viewers in the
room if you can imagine very very quick
it is on like Donkey Kong
jaepo my headphones just fell out I
guess I see if I can get those back in
see if we'll get someone coming into the
room here oh that's gonna be difficult
oh my got it look at that sorry about
that just plug it back the headphones
and we'll see if we can get some people
in this room here well that doesn't feel
right
well there's Tom how you doing Tom good
morning Tom how's it going how are we
doing today doing pretty good trying to
fix my yeah there we go it wasn't
plugged in all the way I could only hear
you in one speaker I've got this shaky
computer screen because I'm trying to
plug my headphones in from the front
how are things going by you going well
going well out here you know it's the
the seasons are changing the evenings
are getting cooler you know it's my
favorite time of year we're eating
tomatoes and melons and you know kind of
for me you know what time of year
is by what you're eating you know
absolutely I also love the harvest
season but I also love it for another
reason that it is the reason that a
variety of psychedelic mushrooms tend to
appear each year here in the Pacific
Northwest so gonna be picking stun Z's
gonna be picking Semillon sea otters
gonna be picking Sian essence gonna be
picking as our essence and bail systems
so all of those different psychedelic
mushrooms will be popping up here in
British Columbia really probably within
the next month month and a half
depending on the spots and that's always
kind of a nice just a little bonus a
little nature bonus all right I hear ya
yeah we just got through picking all of
our blackberries and everything's coming
in
everything's knocking out pretty well
I've got this oh gee that just won't
flip but you know probably needs another
few days other than that everything's
going real well hey buddy what's up how
you doing Mike good it's finally
starting to clear up some of the smoke
out here in Eastern Washington no it's
been a been an interesting summer we it
was unreasonably beautiful all spring
but you know looking a little bit boxed
in Bruce most of the backbone yeah we've
been pretty lucky out here like the
portland-vancouver area and the north
end of the Willamette Valley here we
seem to get up not as much smoke as
everybody else we did have a few days
but it on the long run after driving up
and down the coast we really had it
pretty easy around here yeah there's
more wind and a traveling up and down
the Columbia floor you kind of helps
keep it keep the air clean yeah we get
this we get this nice little breeze
every evening and this little
microclimate that we live off of we get
this Columbia Gorge breeze it starts
about one o'clock and goes to 11 o'clock
at night and it and it's just you know
really been amazing place to live it's a
little bit cooler here than let's say in
Portland or you know further south and
and I really appreciate this little
little microclimates and I think that's
one of the things everybody's got to get
used to when they're going out there is
figure out where you're living figure
out the microclimates go talk to the
other regular farmers see what they're
up to and you'll really get a you know a
good idea of how things go in your you
know little area very true very true
welcome both to Mike and to skunkman Sam
I'm of course in Vancouver so we got
smoked out hard this year like we did
last year the last couple years have
kind of been the worst two on record for
a while but cliff this locust cleared up
here as well we've got nice clear skies
we don't smell it anymore so a little
bit better how you doing Sam
excellent excellent good to see you here
on this early Sunday morning I guess mid
evening for you in Amsterdam that is
correct
very good well we've got dragonfly earth
medicine saying they were gonna pop in a
little bit later on I think Wade said he
was gonna be making it in I think Mark
shadown said he was going to be popping
in for a bit so we'll have a nice little
chat today as we did maybe Cuban too I'm
not sure he says he's real tired but
maybe he'll come in and have a
conversation with us I see Johnny B's
holding down the chat room in there Oh
Dave P from function Junction what's
going on Dave P I was just in function
Junction the other day visiting Whistler
Medical went on a little tour there of
both the Whistler medical in Whistler
and the Whistler medical in Pemberton
and I have to say like I was extremely
impressed with the facility that they've
built I mean I love Whistler medical in
Whistler they're just limited they're in
a smaller space but they've got a really
beautiful building they built in
Pemberton they got a great group of
people that are just all about skiing
and growing great herb which in my
opinion is a wonderful foundation for
owning a licensed facility here in
Canada a lot of people their mission is
to just make cash
which you know I guess that's a mission
as well but as we all come from this
industry for so long it's nice to have
oh I gotta meet either salmon coming
through pretty hard on your microphone
it's just nice to have that foundation
of actual you know mission statement of
quality over profits so I was very
impressed with their facility I'm sure
I'll end up doing a tour over there in
the next little bit and maybe being able
to do a video of showing the whole flow
but it is beyond impressive when it
comes to an indoor grow here in in the
Pacific Northwest I was impressed can
you say more about the 80 acres under
glass not as of yet cosmic lettuce was
at but as that comes to fruition I will
absolutely sometimes it's a little bit
early that was something I mentioned
earlier in chat room today I am gonna be
going and touring 80 acres under glass
this week upcoming week
and maybe I will do some video it's not
cannabis right now they're growing some
vegetables but they're looking at
getting into the cannabis marketplace
and what better opportunity when you
have close to a hundred acres of
greenhouses to do such a thing and so
how was your uh your experience after
you left
Vancouver Mike did you have a good week
yeah it's been a pretty interesting week
I mean my micro is giving me issues as I
mentioned so my truck's been in the shop
for the week but it's been a good weeks
we came back ended up coming back and
had a couple meetings out here with a
beverage company here in east side of
the state looking at doing some
investments with them so that's alright
yeah I guess good gotta get some stuff
maintaining the vehicle is required oh
yeah I know well that facility though
definitely a nice facility
it's bigger than most of the licensed
crews in Washington state's largest
grows in Washington are 30,000 square
feet canopies which you can you can have
up to three of them on a parcel but you
know when you're looking at doing a you
know large scale temp labs you want to
be able to source from multiple acres
so when same things true in preparation
or candidates in Canada you know now
that now that Canada is going full
federal recreational you're going to be
able to start seeing shifts from you
know people growing small less than one
acre parcels of cannabis with 5200
strains on them to having an acre plus
of each strain and that really opens up
the door on you know how you can process
cannabis and how it can you can vastly
increase its availability to well that's
kind of one of the purposes of embark is
to build this large-scale extraction lab
that does the quiver all the different
levels of extraction that we can do
legally here in Canada and then be able
to offer to our customers to be able to
come in with a small sample of 10 or 20
kilos run it through all the different
processes show them where their strong
points are where their weak points are
and allow them to pick and choose the
type of extractions that they want to do
building up to eventually growing the
cannabis specifically for the type of
extractions they want to do so that's
something that we're very excited about
and definitely you know a company like
Sega for tissue culture is gonna be a
big part of that having the lab is going
to be a big part of that and then of
course the growers that's the magical
Trinity right there where the growers
are getting their cultivars cleaned you
know free of microbial pathogen and
fungi and then being able to you know
acquire that for the lab so you know we
have a little bit of an advantage in the
sense that we don't have to deal with
contaminants you could imagine in a big
in a large-scale facility like
could become a problem for quarantine
and could be a problem for cross
contamination of the machinery Oh Kevin
Monaco says why not just kill him why
pass around shitty clones well just keep
in mind like 90% of people are passing
around shitty clones and just because
your clones don't show powdery mildew or
they don't show like bugs or or botrytis
or specific things that are quite
visible there are all sorts of things
they can that can impregnate your clones
that can just slow it down that can
affect the expression of the terpene and
the cannabinoids that won't necessarily
show you you know splotches on the
leaves or powdery mildew growing in the
buds but will affect the outcome of your
of your crop and when you're growing you
know 80 acres or 10 acres or whatever
that's that's a lot of cannabis and you
you want it to be able to really have
the renewed vigour of a tissue culture
plant you want it to be clean fresh and
you want it to express itself to the to
the maximum of its potential of its
genetic potential so and the best way to
take the cultivators are standing out
dirty clones
that's we'd put them out of business is
by giving consumers a better option you
can give consumers a genetically pure
clone that can have any fat taken taken
through tissue so it had its genetic
bigger restored and being very rapidly
able to hand out at this point in time
on there's a warden Astaire ward in
circle fading in that war this is
probably going well there's there's tons
of different microclimates that you I'm
smoking on some gold right now but
growing equatorial zebras in Washington
state probably isn't the best thing to
do is trying to go green outdoors but if
you can have that are adapted to
whatever state or what
return while you're in and then you that
really open the star doors for the part
to be able to yeah best express the
phenotypes themselves without having to
worry about those basic things like we
genetics for potential and passage or
even pretend from sits on Tennessee
breeders out that are yeah been
accounted time breeding out in unstable
genetics we want to hang out and provide
genetic to the consumers who the
producers that are able enough in the K
dot it on yeah just try to stand a
little closer to it oh sorry just trying
to try to get a little closer to your
mic there Mike you were cutting out a
tiny little bit but yeah you know these
tissue culture companies is well part of
what they really you know the most
important factor is their microbiology
lab being able to fingerprint the
genetic and let you know that the
planets that you're buying is an
accurate description an accurate genetic
match of the plant you believe you're
buying and then of course you know with
the certification through the
microbiology lab that there's not going
to be these certain pathogens and
vectors for for problem everyone's quiet
now all right well I'll just keep
talking maybe we'll load up a bowl here
little uh a little vape exhale I invited
Sabo today I'm not sure if he's gonna be
able to make it but hey Marcus hey how
are you doing there dr. mark good fish
yes Denver Colorado oh [ __ ] I saw that
you were on fish tour man you're living
out my dreams with all these fish shows
it's been so long since I've been to a
fish yes right yeah fish need of a man
back dude I want to be back at the shows
for rather country Kuroda's light rig is
just unbelievable like moves up and down
during the show it's just really really
incredible
I am out here to promote this company
1906 which has collaborated with fish
lyricist Tom Marshall to come up with
two different medicated chocolate
products ones called bliss which is a
like a Reese's Peanut Butter Cup sort of
situation and the other is called go
which is a expresso bean and so this is
a Tom Marshall signature you'd see Tom
Marshall is the litters as primary
lyricist efficient tray and stasia's
songwriting partner that's amazing I
really or maybe we heard they were
that's awesome
I had no I mean I heard rumors that they
were gonna be dude well being in so it's
it's really nice to see that's that's
really awesome welcome Cuban by the way
I could help but not click and join in
you know so set up and stuff wash my
face off a little bit even though you're
exhausted it's almost like I like a
[ __ ] psychedelic exhaustion level
where sometimes I think I hear and see
things but it's really that probably
haven't slept eight hours in days yeah
well like I said I was what's that mark
hash exhaustion like tennis elbow you
know it's just a you know catch the dogs
the work you know yeah a casualty of the
industry or what you do you know oh no
I'm not tired because of the hash I
actually haven't made much hash this
year bro like I think that in all of
2018 I probably didn't do maybe not even
a week's worth of what I did in 2015 so
it's not hash but I am raising puppies I
have a litter of 14 day old pups they
need they need to get fed every two to
three hours and at first they're kind of
quiet you know you can set a bed next to
the whelping box and it's cool but when
they start making noise and they're
sleeping all day but crying all night
dude it's [ __ ] rough
I feel you on that hash thing you know I
haven't been making as much myself I'm
ready to gear up but going to Whistler a
couple of weeks ago we just we worked
for about four hours and we made almost
two kilos of dried bubble love this sort
of industrial scaling up of hashing and
not pulling these like 10 and 20 20 gram
bags but pulling these like multi ounce
screens that you know add up to many
many kilos after after a short period of
time and that was just out of the 250
litre machine we didn't even use the
thousand liter machine so you can
imagine once we start dumping 40 or 50
dry kilos into one of those large-scale
units that we'll be able to make maybe
five kilos in a shot or whatnot maybe a
little more so as soon as you posted the
video of the washer a couple weeks ago
people started hitting me up like yo
check out this badass machine bubbleman
is using and it's pretty badass indeed
but I noticed that it stirs from the top
absolutely a washer spin from the bottom
without any correct material how do you
know about that because I'm a big
believer on the chamber spinning yeah I
love the chamber spinning and that's why
we really designed the large-scale unit
the thing that we didn't really share is
the is the spinner the linear actuator
and what it actually looks like and how
much time and energy it took to design
that to actually spin the material so
all of the material gets spin rather
than just some simple thing that spins
and the material doesn't get touched so
the problem in a GE EU GMP certified
facility like it is federally here in
Canada microbials are a big problem and
when you spin from the bottom you are
going to have some serious problems with
bacteria unless you can take that
machine apart every single time and
that's the real problem I love spinning
from the bottom Kuban and we're not
stopping we're trying to figure it out
but I can tell you that the people that
have figured it out like if you take
those machines apart and you look in the
bottom there's going to be things that
get captured you have to take the
Machine apart every single time you mix
and it really becomes a problem for for
workflow maybe if you had
many units and you were able to run you
know fresh batches in each reactor
throughout your day and at the end of
the day you you you steeps you steam
clean or autoclave all of these
stainless steel chambers but the real
problem is having that thing spinning at
the bottom and having water and hash get
into the that area and stay and not
clean out properly then you're then
you're looking at a microbial nightmare
and for Health Canada they just won't
pass it it won't be able to be sold so
this is one of our problems I'm a
hundred percent on point with you I love
the spinning from the bottom at the same
time we're getting 17 to 20 percent
yields out of the water hash that we're
running up in Whistler not always
sometimes it's as low as 12% but what
these guys have done with their data
points and the mixing you know they'll
mix for you know an hour plus but
they'll stop it at five minutes 10
minutes 15 minutes and they there's a
graph that's been created for each
different cultivar where you can see
where it actually starts starts really
clearing out the material and this has
been a problem with bubble hash for a
long time it's easy to get the good
stuff off and that's all I ever really
promoted but there's an enormous amount
of stuff that's left over that can be
used in plant fat extractions that can
be used in all sorts of different other
sort of products and it was getting left
behind and people were always just like
okay I'm getting 10 or 12 percent and
they were quite happy with it but
getting upwards of 17 20 percent and
even 25 percent return on bubble hash is
something that we are actually pretty
stoked about so when we sell these
machines all of that data is coming with
it so it comes along with the IP of the
different cultivars the graphs for each
cultivar are the mixing times and the
shape and size of the blade that goes in
to spin so 100% on point and very very
very good question yeah and I'm on board
with you on the other sterilizing the
washers or the vessels every run I mean
it's very important any or plant matter
or what they call here it's funny in
California they call material biomass
it's crazy term but as long as you have
biomass water and you leave it in a
chain
even a small particle can contaminate
the hash you know if days after if it
runs through so we modify the washers
heavily you know when I was a washing I
still used the washers that you sold
years ago but on
I definitely feel you on those designs
but you can still fabricate something
with that like minimalistic concept in
mind with easily removable parts not a
lot of little nooks and crannies to
clean in between runs right I mean not
as easy as you would think we're
definitely trying and working on it I
was just looking at the Delta
separations units up on the Sunshine
Coast the other day my buddy's got one
of those and it mixes from the bottom
but it only really runs a couple you
know two to six pounds at a time maybe
eight pounds and I'm sure we're looking
at 40 and 50 kilo runs and maybe even
eventually getting it bigger than that
so we want to you know the lab that I'm
that I'm building and Mike's going to be
a big part of this we want to bring him
on for the co2 extraction and to help
with other parts of the ice live and
whatnot we're really looking to make
sure that this that the traditional hash
rooms and I say traditional in the sense
of water extraction dry sifting in rosin
versus the solvent extractions like cryo
ethanol versus the co2 extraction I want
to make sure that the hash has a
footprint that is at least substantial
compared to the oil that we're going to
be producing because the you know the
cryo ethanol that were that we're going
to be doing has the capabilities of
processing almost 10,000 pounds per day
of plant matter and so to be able to do
that much you know even at 50 kilos
every two hours in the thousand liter
reactor and we get four of those
reactors you know that kilos of water
hash run every two hours we could
probably do about a thousand kilos a day
through the water hash extractors it's
still you know only ten percent of
what's going to be produced in the oil
so of course me being a solvent list guy
I love the idea of getting that up as
high as we can and anytime you scale
anything up generally there are these
arcs that happen these sort of
exponential arcs that
occur and it just becomes a little bit
more difficult you never really realize
like with water hash it's the thrashing
ratios the threshing ratios that you get
where you how much threshing versus how
much water versus how much ice versus
how much plant matter is in there it
changes as the reactor gets bigger and
bigger and you really have to accord to
that but I'm definitely on point with
you in the sense that I love the idea of
a bottom you know chamber and we thought
of a few different ideas we've got
engineers on this we've moved this well
beyond hash makers we've hired engineers
who are very much engineers than
mechanical engineers this is what they
think about and it's all about putting
those two groups of people together and
whistler technologies is really sort of
pushing the forefront on this right now
with hiring engineers to sit with hash
makers and to work together to overcome
these obstacles because an engineer will
come up with all these ideas based on
not really understanding the subtle
nuances of the resin gland and the
breaking of the resin gland and how it
sinks in the water and so the hash
makers really tuned into these things
collecting the hash workflow whereas the
engineers just trying to solve problems
so when you put those two people
together I think there's going to be
some real real breakthroughs in the in
the upcoming year or years with water
extraction as well as dry sifting oh
yeah that's awesome
and I mean you you have to I personally
don't have the balls to run that much
material at one time bro that's like my
biggest fear like [ __ ] something up
like that so I always do like washers
have you ever had like a washer drain or
just [ __ ] up you're like man thank God
it's just a pound straight up dude the
scalability thing is terrifying but I
read a really good quote from someone
recently it was if your dreams aren't
terrifying you if your dreams aren't
making you terrified then you need to
you know dream bigger and I really that
really resonated with me you know I was
like okay I guess I'm on point cuz I'm
like you know one minute I'm like this
is amazing this is gonna be awesome and
then the next minute I'm half
idiot act like holy [ __ ] like this is uh
this is this is this could be too much
this could be eres you know and like you
said a pound as a pound but 50 kilos is
50 kilos hey welcome to Wade laughter
and 2d 420 Kane just showed up into the
room welcome guys
so you have just to get this question
out real quick before I yes I have a bad
memory brush smoke too much and I forget
[ __ ] no do it ash Church bro I take so
many dabs by by the end of the church
dude I'm like blast well you need to get
some alpha pining dominant terpene
cultivars and push those mercy and
cultivars to the side for a bit because
you'll you'll get that focus back you'll
get that you know real focus back but go
ahead ask your question
so how are you draining these 50 kilos
out of time definitely not through no
twenty gal bubble bags so that means you
must be designing some heat oh yeah dude
you didn't see you didn't see those
screens no I loved that's crazy
are they steel stainless steel yeah did
man so you know engineers dude like you
said they're good at solutions and when
they bring [ __ ] like that I'm like nah
man don't reinvent the wheel
they'll bag with the meshes to shape but
now that I see you're with the mesh well
you see the bottom here too it's not a
very good but at the bottom right here
yeah that's about sixty thousand US
dollars and what it does is it vibrates
and you can set it to vibrate so it's
offset or onset you can there's all
these different settings that you can do
in the stainless steel screens you can
vibrate them so the patterns travel in
one direction travel in the other
direction go towards the center go
towards the outward area it is
unbelievable to watch man I'm telling
you you would be like a kid in a [ __ ]
candy store watching this thing operate
it's the UH but it's no joke they're
definitely they're definitely costly
units they're from the mining industry
and the amount of control that you have
over them it's the first time I saw it
I was just like yes this is absolutely
on point and I was super glad that you
know give a shout-out to Daniel and
Kelvin and all the crew over at Whistler
technologies I'm super stoked to join
that team and just move water extraction
dry sifting into this I guess industrial
scale that is so needed without the
worry which everyone's always got the
worry and Kuban just sort of pointed it
out it's not it's not just you know
mucking up the pound it's losing the
quality so it's a very interesting thing
what we're trying to do is create
something that can not sacrifice the
quality but acquire the quality in that
first pass and then still acquire the
rest of the of the actual resin without
just doing plant fat extractions or
solvent extractions we want to really be
able to get as much of that hash off in
the traditional ways which is micro
encapsulated resin glands you know maybe
there's not maybe a lot of people don't
think it's different but cannabinoids
that have been melted off with heats or
solvents are just different from the
micro encapsulated resins and it's why
some people prefer hash and some people
prefer oil
I love having in both of them in my
quiver you can imagine for many many
years I smoked only hash I would not
smoke solvent extracted hash and that's
oil and that's all there really was
and so when rosin came out that was huge
for me because suddenly now I was able
to play around with oil when you know
ask someone like Dee who's known me for
a long time did I ever smoked oil the
answer's [ __ ] no I think he's frozen up
but actually I tried to have yourself
long traveled we first met and you were
very polite and said thank you very much
I'll give this to some of my employees
and they might like yeah and you saw
what I got you know yeah that changed
changed my world changed it very fair
and then definitely changed your
direction at least yeah I remember the I
was at the the volcano you brought out a
little bit of real shitty this is my
always all go to to sell these I don't
or to was come in the back and I'll take
some we felt that I've had for about two
years and I'll put it in the little
thing there and we'll vape it and tell
me how you like it and it tastes like
[ __ ] killer hash every time I'd sell
them every time just like that just
because of that and that's what you did
to me let's just put a little of this in
there and try that out you know people
always kind of laugh about older
material a big problem in the Canadian
situation LP situations sometimes before
they get their license though well I was
talking to a guy yesterday he's got
three hundred thousand grams in this
vault he hasn't sold a gram yet they
just got their license to sell yesterday
and people are always like ah you know
who wants to smoke year old resin like
that's that's bunk and I can assure you
that it is not bunk especially from the
hash makers perspective cured resin
makes wonderful wonderful hash I have
some here some rosin that I made this is
some harmony this was on but I grew in
2012 so the bud was six years old and I
pulled it out of my freezer when I put
this under people's noses every single
time it's the same thing the eyebrows go
up and the Wow
comes out of their mouth and it's not
because I'm some amazing grower it's
really more that the cultivar was
special I got it from reefer man it's
the Harmony it has an absolute [ __ ]
beautiful nose super stinky you can
smell it from like you know a hundred
feet away type of thing when I opened it
at a show people come in depending on
the way the air is is flowing but nobody
can believe that that [ __ ] is six years
old now it was left in herb you know in
bud and I froze the bud and I just
squished it maybe three or four months
ago now I'm not even sure but you can do
some amazing things with older material
go ahead the most important thing once
you have it frozen percent you 100% I
mean my god it lasted that that's what
makes a difference you can freeze resin
for a decade barely cake bingo and
that's what you know that's that's what
you can do if you're forced to have herb
in storage for long periods of time
don't let it be ruined just store it in
a freezer I mean
is it like if it starts raining and
stuff you can harvest the plants freeze
them before you drive them at all then
then what you can do is you can take
them out later as you need them and hang
them up to dry and let them dry in a
normal two-week drive and their barn the
color changes a little bit the colors
darken up a little bit from the freezing
but except with that man it works
don't be easy I love that everything you
say is first-hand experience like you
guaranteed did this to crops absolutely
I'd never did people I know didn't have
enough room to dry they lived in a
little tiny Shack and they had no place
else to dry so but they had a freezer
deep freeze so they filled it up and
close it out you know had room it
reminds me of Switzerland back in like
early 2000 2001 2002 and suddenly you
know they were kind of allowing it as an
aromatherapy product if you put the bud
in a little little pillow pouch they
could sell it at stores and so people
were growing just there was no licensing
it was Swiss style it was just like any
can just grow it and so people were like
boom like putting up acres and acres and
acres just the most ridiculous amount of
cannabis and some of the barns that I
saw I mean it was it was inspiring and
then it was like heart-wrenching because
it was so much of the material and I'm
sure you guys remember intro talking
about this back in the day of like him
going in and cleaning out the mouse piss
and the mouse [ __ ] like the the herb
just molded it was just they packed it
so tight into these barns because they
didn't have enough room to dry it and it
would have just been incredible had they
had a system where they could freeze a
large scale freezers and just you know
process it as as they could you know and
that's that's the problem with biomass
if you can only process 100 100 kilos a
day and you've harvested three or four
hundred thousand kilos you're just it's
not it's it's not going to be conducive
to a
proper workflow which might not be easy
either what's that said breezy that
large amount may not be that easy this
one kind of a big preview well I'm
looking at them right now industrial
scale you know the half a million two
million dollar freeze dryers and man are
they inspirational the the you know to
be able to freeze-dry fifty kilos of or
five ten ten to fifty kilos of bubble at
a time sure you can put about I think
it's about five kilos and a freeze dryer
you know in a harvest right I think in
the big the large scientific one you can
do about five kilos we want to be able
to do 50 to 100 kilos without having a
wall of freeze dryer so we've been
looking at these industrial ones and
they are no joke all the air out of
those warehouse yeah I suspect as well
that you'll have large-scale
refrigeration and pulling the oxygen out
of the air and replacing it with
nitrogen is definitely another way to I
mean there's you know what it's funny
Mike because all of these things that
we're looking to discover are already
being done in other industries like
almost every aspect of what we're
looking to do for scalability when it
comes into the tissue culture aspect
when it comes into large-scale freezing
and drying curing when it comes to
large-scale processing these things
already exist on a very large scale
throughout the agricultural community in
from seed crops vegetables to whatever
so it's just gonna be really a matter of
you know tweaking out some of those
things and and getting proper engineers
with proper hash makers and harvesters
and trimmers and cures and all the
people that do all these different jobs
to get these things really you know sort
of created into a proper workflow that
that that will that won't sacrifice
quality
don't forget the chemist man I could
never forget the chemist a lot of what
we're doing mark is is chemistry and I'm
sure we're gonna have you out at one
point in time to come visit this place
because it's going to be the Willy Wonka
calorie lab even if you love it
I can't wait when you were describing
sitting before mark that's very similar
to a process that's used in the pigment
industry the separating pigment for
paint and coatings and and so they have
these industrial sivir
scales that you wouldn't believe I mean
it would fill silos I mean just huge
gigantic things and and one thing I
haven't always learned and I guess you
guys will learn this everyone will learn
this no matter what you do whenever you
scale something up like if you're taking
something from like the experimental Rd
scale to maybe like the smaller
production scale to the like ultimate
like huge levels of production you
always find new I won't call them issues
but just thing is there's always new
things to deal with when you're working
at such a small scale you may not
realize that you're generating say
something that could do what chemists
would call a runaway reaction which is
something that you couldn't necessarily
predict on a really small scale but when
you have stuff sitting around at that
temperature at that stage in the process
now you're gonna have heat buildup or
something else is going to happen and
you always always find new stuff
whenever you go to it's just like making
coffee you know making coffee in a gonna
in a k-cup versus making a pot of coffee
versus just making a huge amount of I
mean it's just it's totally it's a you
always find new [ __ ]
like you were talking about microbial
build-up there's always just set
sediments that build up sedimentation
and a lot of these batch processes which
sounds like most of what you guys are
running or what I would call a batch
process as opposed to a continuous
process which is just the switch that
you turn on and oil comes out or ash
comes out just some continuous like
think of like a VTA unit is like the oil
machine right as long as you have it
backed up with precursor you just turn
on that switch and shale machine just
oil starts coming out right that's a
continuous process versus a batch
process which I like your two liters
smaller you know distillation where you
need to like fill it each time and like
baking a cake you you make your
distillate and then you need to clean it
out and you need to you know the
cleaning as a you know really a function
of the overall process is one of the
most important parts to make sure that
you clean your reactor and get
everything clean for the next batch so
you don't have you know contamination
and it's just it's a really important
thing when you go to scale things up if
you were to take like a two liter you
know distillation and go to like a 20
liter distillation there's gonna be
issues that you just can't predict until
you're running that distillation and
you're doing that equipment you know
you're now that's why listen you have to
you have to design these units
specifically with the intent of not only
producing that quality and the quality
quantity as well but with the in mind
that you're going to be needing to clean
these units a lot and the cleaning has
to be effective and it has to be a part
of the workflow and it has to be
somewhat quick you can't have downtime
for days because you need to clean your
monster unit and yeah it's it's super
important sorry I muted you there mark I
just yeah the other thing I wanted to
add and again people who are you know
again thinking about this kind of thing
is you want to add an area in your
facility for this cleaning because you
don't want to have that cleaning in your
production area you almost want to take
it into like a side area where you can
do cleaning away from like if you can
back it up with a second unit while your
team is cleaning one unit you could you
you you know what I mean I mean you want
you want to allocate space for cleaning
if you're looking at putting a floor
plan or
planning the use of space in an area I
think cleaning space is well you know
well you use space in this kind of
operation yeah absolutely agreed
although I guess the cryo ethanol unit
can work by just running ethanol through
the unit you don't really have to like
take that unit away and yeah are you
getting free-floating plant material or
is it in socks or like how is the cryo
ethanol wow that but that all that IP
belongs to my partner Anthony who runs
infinite CBD and sinner tech down in
Colorado
so he'd really be the one to talk about
that he's gonna be the one running that
aspect of the lab I'm not a co2 or an
ethanol guy but we'll get him on past
church here one of these days maybe even
today I'll invite him on to talk a
little bit about cryo ethanol it's not
impossible if he's coming if he's coming
to the fish show check me out at the
Bliss lounge before the show Tom
Marshall is gonna be there and signing
people's things so I'm gonna get a
selfie with Tom Marshall and say hi and
yeah if he's listening let's let's hook
up at the Bliss Lounge at Dick's at fish
if you're gonna be there
absolutely man I wish I was I wish we
you're here to mark I'll channel yeah
I'll do a live stream tonight and I'll
put you on camera buddy dude that's
that's the way I go to fish shows now
actually I know I know you
vicarious ly through me brother that
that's cool 100% mr. miner mr. miner
also sends me his couch s tour links and
so I got a give mister yeah we know mr.
miner I know I'm pretty well I've danced
around that dude for damn near what 20
25 years yeah Hanks Bob a lot of people
it shows well you know our curve ball
this festival here in upstate New York
was canceled I know I don't know if you
heard this but yeah there was a camp I
saw it I heard it I saw the photo of the
guy telling Trey on stage while it was
helping
happening I was all over it but I should
say Thank You mr. miner it was a real
heartbreaking thing so I mean there's a
lot of energy from that closed down
festival that kind of is sort of
centralized here in Denver and yeah last
night of the three night run tonight so
small poncho pot poncho says small bats
will always be the highest grade and I I
tend to agree with them but it's also
the obstacle that I want to turn into
the opportunity to change that statement
I want to see that statement change and
it was really skunk man Sam who kind of
changed that for me when you know he we
were sitting down one time and he just
said you know all these people that
think you can't grow super-awesome
herb large-scale are just wrong I know
because I've done it and I've seen it
and I've you know he has he's grown like
fields of cannabis that it are like of
the highest quality that if you
extracted the resin and you smoked it
you surely wouldn't be like yeah it's
okay it's like at the top echelon of
greatness and so I'm thinking why can't
we to do the same thing with extraction
that's what we need to do to make it
available to make it accessible for
everyone the highest quality we need to
figure out that obstacle of overcoming
scalability and so it's a mission that
I'm on hey Marcus I just wanted to
comment on temperature too I mean yeah
whenever you look at any chemical
degradation process the cooler you could
make things the slower that degradation
process becomes so that yeah you think
things hold in the dark and dry very Sam
good advice 100% good advice and
definitely something that we're paying
careful attention to cold cold cold cold
cold
we're gonna design this problem yourself
the other thing you got to remember
these deep these chiller units throw a
lot of heat into the room that they live
in so if like if you're if your area is
like a confined area and you have
chiller units that are running to chill
various parts of your operation those
chillers through
a lot of heat in the area so you want to
make sure that you know again you have a
way to remove the heat from that room
if you can't ya know these are all parts
of the design we're looking at putting
certain things on the roof we were
trying to get them on the outside of the
building but some of the limitations
with the property footprint won't allow
for that so we're definitely on the
first meeting I walked through first
with Mike I did a great video with Mike
in the specific we'll be able to release
it at one point in time but you know the
project's just in its infancy stages so
we're gonna kind of leave that as a
little bit more on the down-low
but definitely the second walkthrough
that I did well actually the fourth or
fifth walkthrough I did was with a team
of 25 people construction electrician's
engineers architects the whole nine
yards we started walking through this
facility and it's quite incredible when
you get that many brilliant minds
together specifically you know a lot of
moving parts to start focusing on on a
project and you just go room by room and
you just basically you write down the
pain points the obstacles that are in
your way and then you get those minds on
you know taking those pain points apart
and and offering relief to each one so
it's an exciting thing to be a part of
obviously you know like Kuban mentioned
there's this large scale fear that comes
with large scale scalability but you
can't let that fear keep you from
pushing the boundaries you know we may
not be the only ones that are doing this
but the work that we do is definitely
going to affect the community much like
the work that that we did with bubble
bags over the years has has deeply
affected the community I mean I'll tell
you 1999 pre bubble bags was a different
world in the world of extractions it was
a real different world this whole full
mel bubble and you know 99.9% heads sure
Sam was on the boat but he was it was a
very lonely journey because he was
literally the only one and so now you
know most people on this panel have made
it have have access to it it's just kind
of a no-brainer water ice beautiful
plant matter walk-in freezer
operate
Center process you know 50 or so kilos a
day really easy I that was Lobo back I
mean once I realized that I can operate
this dissecting machine in the middle of
the summer time when it was hot and
humid which normally that puts a
screeching halt for our safety hundred
percent when you've got a cold and dry
then you can do it year-round
you just have to free some material
overnight and we're equip it in the
morning and keep it [ __ ] cold and dry
ya know it's it's it's a big changer
it's one of the beautiful things about
living in Canada I will say because the
winters tend to be cold and dry and so
you've obviously seen some of the dry
sifting videos I hope that I put out on
the man's world
he works when the winter's that way I
didn't invent it it was invented by
people in Afghanistan other places and
says the best 15 is when it's cold yeah
absolutely well you may not have
invented it but you certainly had a deep
impact on the world of hash makers I'll
tell you just in that moment where you
allowed me to photograph your resin when
I first met Sam back in the day he was
just he was almost like there was all I
was almost afraid he was like the
professor he just had so much knowledge
I didn't want to offend him I didn't you
know he's very particular fellow in the
sense that that he was just he just was
a no [ __ ] around kind of guy and so you
know if you know I didn't even want to
ask him hey could I photograph your
resin but at one point after a few trips
to his house I I asked I said hey can I
can I photograph your resume he's like
yeah sure why not then that you know
that photograph of that 99.9% heads that
was the first time that a photograph
like that showed up on the Internet in
the cannabis world and I'll tell you it
really really really affected a lot of
people in regards to what can be done it
showed the masses it is possible
absolutely.i I [ __ ] myself damn near
when I took that picture in your living
room when I saw what was before I took
the picture when I focused the camera
and saw what your hash looked like under
a microscope I just couldn't I couldn't
believe it I could not believe that you
did that with dry said dry sifting like
that you didn't that you didn't use
water water just was so easy to extract
the heads but then it's also extracting
these water-soluble x' it's it's pulling
something out the waters smelly the
waters dark it's it's not staying in the
hash and you know Sam had all of that
presence in his hash so it was
definitely a big shout out to him and
shout out to Cuban for helping keep the
popularization going and shout-out to D
for 20k and shout out to all the hash
makers for that for that matter as well
as the growers because [ __ ] we are
nothing without you we are nothing
without the growers that's my that's my
humble opinion should we get a nice big
bong ripen or what yeah come on say it
say what about the steep makers people
absolutely what about the landrace
farmers yeah I'll shout out the land
I'll shout out everyone keep going dude
will shout at the land raise farmers
will shout out the seed collectors
because those those guys did some
important work collecting you know Sam
going and living in all the hash
producing countries and collecting those
seeds back in the time where it was you
know probably fairly dangerous to do
that work that was also huge even the
land rice farmers I mean the present
land rice farmers are really only there
they're just present caretakers of the
energy because it meets some of these
lab races I mean the Heritage has been
going on for hundreds of years it
it's incredible it's quite interesting
the jaw the shoulders of giants that we
all sit upon it whether you are aware of
the history that brought this to you or
not
some of the prohibition that occurred
you know the yanking of the teeth out in
the Cairo square for the for the Sufis
like a lot of people suffered a lot of
years for this plant to thrive and
continue to be collected to be grown to
be processed and to be vaporized I mean
that's powerful to you know from
generation to generation and I feel like
the internet really knew things up to
when it came to cannabis thanks to like
that picture that you took and of Sam's
work it motivated me to be able to
figure out what to do with a bunch of
Keef that I had sitting around without
the internet would have never seen it
you know so that's powerful and I got a
I had a thought cuz the other a lot of
people are like man waters a solvent and
I heard you say it last week and I don't
get into those type of talks because to
me you know if it's not butane or
whatever then to me hash is hash you
know
but if water is a solvent it's keef and
dry sift the only real deal not solve it
well it's the least it's the least
footprint so whenever you use anything
to extract you leave a footprint or you
extract something that leaves that
footprint so with water hash it's simple
whatever we're pulling out into the
water is our footprint it's what's been
removed from the hash and there's those
processes occur in all forms of
extraction but with with solvents leave
behind some of the alcohol or the phot
Ameche tested afterwards you can usually
find a tiny bit of that with water all
you have to do is drag those open and
the footprint is gone from the materials
but it's still you know and I will say
this Cuban the highest quality of water
hash I've had is absolutely on point for
the highest quality dry sip that I've
had when you break into most those tens
I II it's been grown like a ten out of
ten it's been processed and
cured like a ten out of ten to me
they're right on par but generally most
people's water hash is not a ten so
anytime you get like a sift that's a
nine whatever or upwards of a ten it's
gonna seem nicer than most water hashes
that being said when you have that six
star water hash that drips away to
nothing and has all the flavor of the
bud for me they're both on point I would
have a hard time picking one over the
others but you just don't get the same
yields from dry so most people but much
higher yields yeah that's true as well I
mean even while we were in Jamaica and
you had that beautiful dry sift and we
made that beautiful water hash I think
we smoked them both pretty you know like
I don't remember just smoking all of the
dry sip till it was gone and then
smoking the water hash which is
generally what I do when something's
just better if something's much better
it's a very easy decision and it's why
you know it's why we I kind of had that
idea for legends we're you know legends
of hash but we don't have to judge it
why don't we just put like a gram or two
grams of everybody's hash out on the
table on a separate plate and the hash
that's gone first and just taking you
know a hit
not taking like half a gram each time
but just taking your one or two hits
from each one because there could be 20
or 30 or 40 varieties on the table and
that's 20 or 30 or 40 hits just take one
hit of each one and see which one you go
back to because it whittles down like
any connoisseur forty cultivars on the
table he'll know the top five right away
by looking at them and then by smoking
them he'll Whittle it down to light this
is the one I just I don't know I just
keep taking it until it's gone and then
it's sort of like a nod to the hash
maker very much like how some of the
Baba's do it in Shivaratri in Nepal
where when it's Shiva's birthday and
they have these hash gatherings my
manufacturers told me that's exactly how
they do it they put it out on the plate
and whoever's plate is empty first
everyone you know gives their respect
that way and I think that's a really
kind of cool way to do it the People's
Choice yeah I like that they did that
similar style with the
the invitational they had a nice dinner
they had everyone brought their own jar
and it just started getting passed
around until there was a unanimous
decision who had the heat I didn't
attend but it sounded cool you know
III definitely get that water hash and
rice if comparison personally I really
like water hash
I like water hash mother and rice if
myself if it's good water hash ro proper
fresh frozen like like slow spin first
wash don't don't spin for 15 minutes and
give me that 90 because I'm not gonna
like that over dry suit but some nice
like dripping to water is good but when
people start making water hash and they
use tap water or some filtered water and
then there's like some some of that hard
water taste no matter how good the resin
is how about some fluoridated ice yeah
like all that stuff I could taste that
stuff because I've taste pier resin when
I make dry sift and what I'm trying to
do is I can enhance that terpene with
the fresh frozen terpenes but not add
calcium and magnesium and all that other
weird [ __ ] from like not good source
water or ice so water house you know it
it all depends on who's making it beside
only he likes the bubbles that's Sam
stuff I tried to sneak some fiji bubble
some fiji water bubble and he was not
having it carbonation you know just co2
water you know where it pops and and
gets on your face when you're dabbing it
it's just like popping and shake off
those bulbous heads on the plat matter
huh with the pear just publish them
right off oh dude it's a secret tak
don't tell anyone can't tell anyone
oh [ __ ] 536 people are watching
including the dragonfly Earth Medicine
crew have to real quickly promise not to
tell you I think they're all promising
now in chat welcome guys
hey everybody hey everybody happy Sunday
I think it's you guys you guys look
called profession conferences today and
now we're just in a hotel room in
Spokane well I love it you guys clean up
well let me tell you thank you you're
good-looking people and I love that you
guys were in the garden last week and
how you like in the street like hotel
room you like look we like to keep a
foot in the corporate world but we're
also very much dragonfly earth medicine
people and we like to grow the medicine
definitely cultivation is our main thing
you know the to us that's the beginning
you know we like we like home births and
natural births for human beings as well
and we also really like you know natural
cultivation and you know pure
cultivation it's really important to us
we were just shouting out the hash
makers then we were shouting out the
growers and then Sam of course and his
great wisdom was like hey what about
like the land race you know it's
stewards the people who have been like
and the seed collectors that went and
grabbed gathered these seeds like whoo
it definitely you can follow it way way
way way back but I give props to all all
of the aspects of cannabis space
brothers who brought the seeds to go
maverick
ah yes the space brothers he came down
where were they from Sirius B or
something like that or was that the
dolphin people we just lost two hundred
people mark marks Aldo is going to gonna
comment on that take myself off mute but
I don't have anything I love that you're
this you know analytical chemist mind
but you're like super trippy fish dude
as well you must just hear some great
things at these fishes mmm
blame it on Garcia man it was all
because I was spun out kid on dead tour
in the eighties you know following just
being passionate you know that's what
Jerry Garcia teaches us is to be
passionate and what we do and to
understand everything that's happened
before you you know you really have to
have an appreciate just like music and
science you have to have a
appreciation of everything that's
happened before you to be able to
internalize it and then do something new
well that's where that's where humility
comes in humility comes into play
because you have to be humble to accept
those things you've got I think that's
one of my best qualities but uh but I
think the other thing that you have to
really do is you have to really figure
that the best way you can learn is just
keep the channels of communication open
so even like ass church or the chat chat
room is just I think the best thing
about having a hashed Church is waking
up to know that this whole group of
people even before the program starts is
in the room you know and I can tell you
exactly who they are they're like the
same 50 people they're there every time
right so as soon as you bless us with
the idea of hey we're gonna have an
episode this week there's already like a
cosmic gathering kind of like the way
there used to be at a Grateful Dead show
people just knew they sweet would come
because it was there it's definitely a
pretty cool way of looking at it and
definitely a big shout out to the core
group the 70s Mamas and the bingo long
bar T's tastebud for 20s they just yeah
he just said taste put for 20 we never
leave mark if I set up the chat room on
unlike Monday tomorrow for next week
there there will be like a big chunk of
them in there for the whole week which
is great I mean you know what it's this
it's this passing around of ideas that
open dialog and you get a lot of people
in the fear and sparsity world in that
corporate greed of like oh I got it I
got to make sure it's kind of musical
chairs but with a ball and it's dialogue
and it's the the ball is the logos it's
the language and we pass that ball
around and sometimes it lands on someone
and it cracks open and that's the timing
and so many people are afraid of that
that it's not going to land on them
they've just locked it up they're not
sharing anything and they don't they're
not really active in the dialogue and
this is sort of a problem I'm sure in
many aspects of life but definitely in
the cannabis
industry it's a big problem that people
are just afraid to see those great ideas
go around land on someone and then have
it blow up for them I'm I'm down with
that
I'm good with whoever it lands on as
long as we keep the dialogue going what
do you say there Johnny be making some
sift excellent getting it done Johnny
B's getting it done I always have to do
that you know I'm hoping that solvent
less wine comes in today I did pass him
the link and he was gonna come in today
while he washed some bubble so we could
have I think every hashed Church there
should be some hash making that just
seems like like a good idea so my old oh
nice nice in here it's nice and chilly
about the microscope sitting right here
and I get to play beautiful and you're
all whited out in the white room you're
in the white room I'm in the white room
though it's a nicer room to be in plus
I'm in it's uh it's quieter in here I
don't have the headphones on that could
work in a commute yeah I wonder if
that's what Eric Clapton was singing
about in the white room well one thing
I've seen with all of these labs that
were seeing they're all white they're
all nice and clean at least with white
he could see if there's any dirt or
anything on the walls or anything like
that so and it was easy to build this
was beginning this was my house room
before I was gonna live on a yoga studio
and make it a hot cold room but instead
I taught myself a nice little house room
because I'm making hash you're gonna
like bingo Lombardi's quote Johnny
Johnny B with the bangin still cheers I
mean not my brush I got my cars
I got all my little chicks and
everything else that you guys have
showed me what I've learned
the years from from you and everybody
else of the industry that it showed me
so much it's pretty cool to see how
things are going at what you're doing
dude on a huge scale we talked I was
talking with some people some help
farmers on what's going on in Manitoba
that's some pretty crazy stuff how they
will start separating everything from
the fields down so they can now have
those try cones from the plants yes
pretty amazing what they're doing out
there they got a whole collective so
they're getting all the farmers from all
the hem fields are coming out all in and
they do like thinking basic to a
processing plant like what you're doing
I think it's pretty cool they needed
this on an industrial scale and I think
it's the next level of this whole
industry is being able to we're gonna
beat up we're gonna be that processing
plant or at least none of them know
remember the first time I was in
California in Central Valley and
California excuse me and I saw them
pulling a harvesting machine and there
was maybe 12 people singing in a row as
it pulled through the roads of beans and
the people that were doing the work were
walking in front of this machine and
they would feed it into the machine
everything that they were making from
the beads right backs and I don't think
there was people walking and thankfully
machines was pulling the beans awkward
the bean plant and then beating them to
people who were sitting in rows and they
were boxing it and then the boxes would
be quick frozen not quick frozen but
quick chilled and then they were being
sent to retailers and the wholesalers
all across the nation but that will be
the future with cannabis it will be it
in the field and quick chill in the
frozen
and then central processing plant yeah
you'll be the other end there mark
grabbing it with a smile on my face the
dream come true so where are you guys at
Josh and Kelly what are you guys where
you guys at
we're in Spokane right now um often we
come down here but where we're at right
now as far as the industry goes and you
know we're just everyday everyday in the
soil everyday in the greenhouses every
day in our breeding rooms you know same
thing that we've been doing for the past
26 years and you know although the
industry is changing and there's a lot
of things that are happening it's still
like we have to keep our focus and what
it is that we came here for and how we
brought this forward so it's important
you know we're keeping our focus on the
farm and there's a lot of you know bombs
going off everywhere and lots of people
giving us offers and all this kind of
stuff but we're just really keeping our
head down and and really playing the
game of humility because we feel like
it's really important and that's what we
need to show the plant every day
humility and we also see that the world
is in a clean cannabis shortage you know
we find that you know that you know the
cultivation you know needs to be really
thought out in order to be like as clean
as it as we all wanted to be in stuff so
that's a big part of our work and and
and certification that we created and
working with other ones you know that
are being created too that are outside
of ours and so we're just working really
diligently on clean cultivation and yeah
we always free up our education you know
we were talking about passing
information around and it's actually
very rare for humans to have original
thought you know humanity doesn't come
up with original thought too often but
if we can have good thoughts that we
pass around easily and freely then
that's the way that we're gonna be able
to bring up the whole race of humanity
yeah and um you know Bob Snodgrass told
us a really great story one time which
you know he's such an amazing person and
everything that he's done for glass and
everything over the years as his algebra
teacher in high school taught him about
the bell curve with knowledge that
humans you know I'll know a certain
amount of thick knowledge and they're in
there rising up but they're the the
curve is more flat but once everyone
starts sharing information the the
knowledge goes up really sharply and our
humanity you know and our and our
abilities to do things you know gets
much greater because we're sharing
information and that's really why we
evolve you know more as a race when
we're sharing things with each other and
we feel like that's that's what we want
to be a part of absolutely should I
should hook you guys up with my quest
while you're out in Spokane he just left
the chatroom but he's I'm pretty sure in
Spokane yeah we love it that'd be great
we're here
awesome well we've got Johnny be sifting
how are you doing today Wade thumbs up
thumbs up from Wade yeah I'm doing good
actually
it's the weather's cooled off a little
bit here and the big news in our world
at the moment is is mixed on the plus
side the California Legislature passed a
bunch of bills yesterday was their last
day or Friday was the last day of the
legislative session for this year and
Senate bill 829 which we've been pushing
pretty hard for passed out of the
assembly and the Senate and has gone to
the governor for a signature and there
were enough yes boats that if he vetoes
it it will go into a law anyway there
were I think two or three out of sixty
some in the assembly and two in the
Senate who voted no and everyone else
voted yes and it allows compassionate
use licensing and not really sure it's
like any law how the regulations play
out is going to have a huge
impact on how it actually works but
there's great enthusiasm for it among
the regulator's they recognize that
legitimate medical need that's not
always based on ability to pay is a real
thing and the model in California for a
long time has been about giving it away
to people who need it
WAM was one of the first entities I knew
of doing that kind of work and yeah
there were a number of other bills
defining premesis and whatnot anyway the
the state is trying its best to sort out
all the problems that have come with
regulation in California
on the downside some of the kids in the
network the kids with epilepsy including
Silas Forest son are dealing with a lot
of seizures right now Silas had a series
of grand Mal's night before last and
it's not just Silas it's a number of
other kids in the network so I don't
know what's going on in the in the world
other than the insanity that is going on
in the world that's affecting these kids
but yeah how are the fires there how's
the smoke the the smoke has been good in
our area several of the big fires are
mostly contained the one that was
happening down in southern Mendocino in
Lake County they're pretty much
contained it but it's it's like a
hundred and some thousand acres the
biggest fire California's ever had and
it's still early in the fire season so
we're all kind of holding our breath I
wonder if that could be a part of it
though you know maybe it's not affecting
you know most people but people there's
people that are sensitive like that you
know with with seizures and whatnot any
little stress on their system can cause
that to to fire yeah that would make
perfect sense
the we humans are uniquely sensitive to
our environments we were very capable of
dealing with all kinds of
craziness unless we have compromises in
our well-being in other areas and you
know we were doing shoutouts earlier to
all the people that have helped the
plant
I wanted to pipe up and give a shout out
to the plant herself for surviving all
this prohibition that's been going on
and give thanks to all the humans who
have worked with her to see this amazing
unveiling of what's possible with this
plant I just feel like with all the
craziness that's going on in the world I
mean my whole life I've been dreaming
about as the rust is used to say the
herb is the healing of the people and
it's actually happening now and give
thanks for all of us and all of those
who have come before us and to the plant
the amazing beautiful cannabis linnaeus
sativa indica ruderalis etc that yeah
this plant takes water soil and light
and turns it into oil that's a pretty
trippy thing it's I just give I feel
deep deep deep gratitude for this plant
and it's part in my life and for what
I've seen it can do for other people so
that's kind of where Wade's at at the
moment
much love to all of you I'm hanging out
and just listening mostly because I'm in
awe of the people that gather around you
for hash Church Marcos thank you
awesome Wade thanks for your positive
words as always and patient Marcus oh
yes my remember look who came to visit
me this is chief 7 Turtles Scott
Sebastian Dan's a champion plant breeder
so don't forget about the plant breeders
here's one Colorado I finally was able
to get we're looking for house isn't
right now oh well good on you dude
welcome to house Church you're in good
company yeah you remember I talked to
you like a year - no - two years ago
yeah
you're on maybe like two years ago two
days ago yeah yeah absolutely yeah
that's amazing that that much time has
even gone by these conversations just
people haven't interested in them so
just tell your friends I'm in a legal
state now and I'm interested in all the
stuff I learned in industry I can use in
cannabis now beautiful well I'm sure you
won't have a hard time in Colorado my
god that place seems to be popping wait
please
Colorado oh yeah God we looked all over
our again we looked in California and we
just keep coming back to Colorado yeah
well it seems like you're not the only
ones that's for sure Colorado seems to
have a growth going on with people
interested in the cannabis it seems like
out of all the states it has some pretty
decent right that's a mature market it's
a mature market especially for
connoisseur products like I think what
you see now very prevalent in the stores
I was in rare dankness yesterday and got
some got some live resin but um yeah no
slabs not you know you know really see
shatter anymore you see a lot more
diamonds and sauce and yeah some solvent
list but a lot of diamonds and sauce
people seem to like that product
category out here well it's the hot pot
it's the newest of the new it's the
Instagram fame right it's hashtag
diamonds it's like of course people are
all over that [ __ ]
instagrams kind of trippy how it directs
the popularity of what people are going
to produce that in the fact that
tasty and sweet and gets you super
ripped I guess are all factors speaking
of where's that oh there you go Darrin
can you please say your important
sentence he's talking right now I can
see him big conversation you got us on
mute actually reviewing us hey Darren
keep talking to my just needed a quick
bong wrap mother lovers that's all Oh
mother lovers thank you very much
sifting there you go I was gonna say
that you know it would be nice to see a
lot more organic cultivation in Colorado
that's the one thing that is a little
they're a little light on the organic
cultivation so I'd love to see that that
that community get a lot more charge out
there I think that's a good thing always
you know that's one of the things I love
about Whistler Pemberton the Whistler
Medical they grow organically they're
you know one of the few that are pumping
out the OGIS and it's it's just nice to
be around it's nice to be in rooms that
are that's like made like soil you know
not that I'm like dissing on on the
other options or whatnot but I will also
say that generally I don't know exactly
what the noticeable difference is in the
actual resin gland I'm not sure how much
of that is absorbing like pesticides or
foliar sprays or whatnot but definitely
I could say that material like that was
grown outdoor organically but not
flushed and just had like the darkest
ash ever
I made hash from it and it was just like
I smoked it and loved it it was sweet
skunk and I remember people just
complaining they were like oh you got
that sweet skunk I'm like yeah it was
great and they were like really I was
kind of disappointed and I'm like well
that's weird and it took me a while to
figure out that they were all smoking
the flower and the ash was burning super
dark and I was smoking the hash and that
leaving the food and the plant didn't
affect the resin really at all what do
you guys have to say about that oh well
there's a number of cases where the
resin glands you suck up pesticides and
failed tests so there's there's got ants
giant list farms that you know would
really disagree with that that statement
however if they're at resin glands are
clean and nice and they could be really
similar I guess our biggest mission in
life is to show that the cultivation of
the resin to begin with um there's so
much waste that goes into cultivating
flowers and there's so much energy use
that goes into it that you really if you
want to factor in all of the carbon
footprint that goes with it or the trash
crit rate you know you'd have to be
really concerned so that that's what
we're at you know I mean it's it's the
the amount of like every single time you
throw something out of those large-scale
operations out of out of rock wall you
have to throw all that away and say I
mean it's you know on all the tubes it's
it's not it's you know there is so much
that we don't know about cannabis still
you know now we're just being able to
get funding to be able to do the testing
and to be able to understand what it is
that we're looking for and I do believe
that you know I'm hoping that cannabis
will have the last laugh that it can't
be you know controlled in the same way
that tobacco has been controlled you
know tobacco was taken over the plants
totally in control and we you know it
was like the big corporations got ahold
of it and then no more real studies and
tests really came out of it after that
as far as organic cultivation and I feel
like you know maybe she will have the
last laugh in that she produces a lot of
cabin cannabinoids and chirping and
things that she produces into herself
when she's really happy and in a soil
situation so and we also like believe in
origins and we really resonate with like
Wade and and what he has to say big
enough the plan and the origins of the
soil and the earth and
that and for us that's what we
recognized you know we recognized the
naturalness and we recognized the plant
and its full potential so some of the
organic growers they need to maybe they
flush to make their ash look better for
people and stuff but in the end of the
day you know if they're doing a really
you know conscious grow and stuff you
know it does have to burn correctly for
the consumer and all that but you know
if it's bad for the earth but it smokes
well I just don't see that as a good
okay no no I feel yeah absolutely I'm
definitely not
you know stoked on the use of pesticides
even though you know 99.9% of people eat
it on their food for almost every single
meal that they have as well as the
clothes that they wear as well as the
vehicles that they drive as well as it's
just so saturated into our system I'm I
would love to see us get rid of as many
of these things as possible and create a
more sort of synergistic symbiotic
experience for the world it doesn't seem
sustainable to say the least to continue
to poison everything on such a mass
scale that you know we cause pollution
and and and great disruptions in our
oceans and our nature cycles but it is
what it is now we're such a reactionary
society you know in America we don't do
anything until we're not proactive we're
reactionary just like when you see a
salmonella outbreak or any of those
things that go after the processor they
got through the farm but they don't
change the general overall problem like
in Japan there's no point zero zero
parts per million of any kind of fecal
or any microbial matter in an in South
Korea
there's 0.3 0.3 and 0.03 and then in
Europe it's 0.5 so but in America it's
5,000 parts per million so we really
live in a super toxic since I've been
able to make money and turn a profit at
our expense so I believe that organics
is the only way to go the small farmer
we really have to work on see a
homegrown homegrown really concerns me
they're gonna try to get rid of it and
every
State they've been successful here in
Washington and they've got the state
near you I mean without the home grow
and the small farmer you know and people
out there there's a lot of there's no
new thing such a massive scale I'd like
to focus on smaller scale I've been
teaching a class at Clark College here
in Vancouver cannabis in your health and
then I do how growers do it it's a three
hour intensive on taking your plants to
harvest for highest yield and I really
love to show everybody the clean organic
route to go there's no reason we
shouldn't be taking that route it's
better for the environment you know and
and you got a bent Abdul tube thing and
the mylar bags and how bad are those
they're choking out our oceans you can't
get rid of them I find him in my ditches
out here in the country I mean it's
really really really bad and you know as
cannabis and steward of the land we
really need to put our best foot forward
and I really believe the the growers who
care about and the processors who really
care about it are putting their sell
their product in glass jars and they're
using biodegradable packaging and I do
that is must if as we continue on or
we're just going to destroy planet Earth
even more that's true for sure you know
it's kind of that right there it's the
quiver of access in the sense of we need
exactly what you're teaching that small
scale you know scalability where people
are doing it for themselves but it's
just never gonna happen for everyone
it's gonna be a percentage of people
that do it that way so then we also need
large scale and that can't be done in a
toxic level it has to be done in a way
that's like we're smart enough to figure
it out there's no reason why scalability
has to be a bad thing I just think it
should never phase out small scale small
scale should always have a place in the
cannabis industry I always want to have
my own garden in the back I always want
to be able to process my own stuff a
variety of ways at home but at the same
time I know so many people out there who
that's never going to be the reality for
them ever just the way they don't raise
their own chickens to eat eggs every
morning just the way they don't make
their
clothes from there you know metal that
they grow in their backyard it's just
there's both both sides need to exist
and you know like people like my mom for
example like she is most comfortable
ordering her cannabis from a large-scale
facility it's just comfortable to her
she just goes online she gets it done
she feels good about it she's not
opposed to going into dispensaries but
she's worked for the police for 35 years
so the laws is a big part of it as well
but I just see both sides being fairly
valid as you know I'm sitting here going
I want to go as large as I can and Tom's
like I want to teach small-scale I
totally respect what you're saying but
think that that large scale has its
place as well to give people there's
room there's room for all of us we all
have our space in this cannabis world
you know everybody has their own little
position and and and it takes all of us
to get this plan and to get this
industry in the right place where it's
it's actually benefitting people and
benefiting the planet that's definitely
that's definitely a big part of it
you know we want it to be more positive
and beneficial in that sense that there
are a lot of people just think of the
amount of pesticides that have been
sprayed on cannabis alone even in the
black market over the you know the last
four or five decades that's all that is
a lot of pesticides or even wine they
just did a case study on a hundred
different wines in California and this
is one thing that we're not testing for
in cannabis because you know which is
glyphosate and a hundred percent of
those tests came out with you know
really high levels of glyphosate that's
not part of our pesticide levels you
know when people go and bring their
cannabis and they're not testing for
glyphosate when you go and you bring
your soil sample and you have to pay
extra to get a glyphosate test and we
really encourage people to do glyphosate
tests because their amendments may be
Omri certified but they may be still
spraying glyphosate say on their alfalfa
that they can buy in bulk and if you
utilize that in large amounts on your
soil then you're gonna start having
massive microbiology die offs which is
really huge and that's something that
then goes up into the flower so like you
see
what wouldn't glyphosate just peel the
plant no glyphosate doesn't kill the
plant glyphosate is utilized and say
maybe you know if you're buying large
amounts of alfalfa and that you wanted
I'm talking about using glyphosate on
the ganja no inputs that come in that we
use for the ganja mm-hmm and and we're
finding we're doing massive tests on a
lot of these inputs that people think or
organic or think that are natural I
think that our whole foods and they're
coming out really high in glyphosate
levels and then we get calls from some
people and we're saying hey you know our
soil is becoming acidic over time what's
going on and then we look all the way
through it and we find out wow the South
alpha that you've been adding on weekly
has glyphosate in it and it's killing
your microbiology which is in turn is
making me here in soil acidic yeah so
it's not just looking at like the
finished product what goes into it what
what creates the finished product you
know how can you be responsible from the
very first ripple that we do on our farm
I think Marcus you made a good point I
mean toxicities everywhere and Tom and
the toxicities everywhere and so when we
have an opportunity to to choose
something we're gonna choose the natural
thing because we're already inundated
with all the toxins everywhere and I
think about you know Grass Valley and
stuff down there I mean charcoal and and
and carbon and the air is gonna suck out
all the toxins in the air and then it's
gonna fall on people and they're gonna
be breathing in carbon that it's known
just suck up toxins that's why you take
activated charcoal every day to flush
the toxins out of your body and stuff so
you know I we just believe you know
toxicity in cannabis and toxicity and
life is probably our biggest work I mean
we love growing and cultivating
everything but like talking about the
toxicity it's a big thing you know and
suddenly really we really want to start
to delineate and you really look at what
it is that you're eating or what it is
that you're putting in your gardens like
you were saying Marcus toxicity is
everywhere but if we can do our very
best and do our research and talk to the
people who are already doing a good job
in organics and how they're doing it
share information then we can bring this
plant up and I do believe that you know
like wait you were saying we do need to
have you know give Big Ups to the plant
it's important she's brought us all the
way this far and we're having a you know
a relationship together it's it's an
equal relationship the plant and the
human and how is it that we can do the
best buy the plant so she can do the
best buy us well I think that's one of
the beauties of the Dragonfly earth
medicine approach closed-loop systems
like if you're talking about alfalfa
instead of buying alfalfa that's likely
been treated with various things like
glyphosate by alfalfa seed and put it in
the ground and get it so it's self
seeding and meantime your compost
streams everything by generating your
own inputs on the farm and of course you
can only do this if you have enough
space and a place to do it but I think
any place
anybody that can have a garden where you
can grow tomatoes you can grow beautiful
cannabis and you can do it responsibly
in the way that you guys talked about
closed-loop systems you know worms your
own compost piles ferments mushrooms
it's about restoring the environment in
the place that you're working it's not
about cannabis can be a resource
extraction industry or it could be a
resource rebuilding environment and
regenerative aspect of it we feel yes
and it is true you know like in getting
to what you add on to your tears oils
and what you're adding into your
reservoirs or whatever to find out where
those come from and like you're a same
way yeah closed-loop systems you know a
hundred percent where it came from and I
want to remind everybody you know we did
a numbers game a few years ago on how
much each one of our plants you know
cost us to be able to grow and we grow
huge massive monsters that put out a
whole lot of pounds you know and for BC
the
it's a lot and we spent $24 on each
plant $24 so you know that really takes
a lot of the stress out of and that's
how you stay in business the other thing
is let's not forget what we what we know
about the plant let's not forget what we
learned what we learned it's a my it's a
remediating plant it sucks up what's in
the earth so we have to be seriously
careful what we put in there if we want
the clean safe access that we all are
talking about and our peer certification
is is where it sets people up it's not
just a certification to put rules and
regulations on people by any means it's
being able to give farmers the tools
that they can pass their concentrates
that they pass their flowers so that
when they go to market that they're
successful it's not something that's
like here's a list of a bunch of things
good luck you know they're feeding their
mind with healthy food that they're
growing on the farm it's true the food
is covered in my club you know you can
get strawberries right now in tustin
there's Michael a mutant all on it the
problem with Michael butanol is is the
smoking of it and it turning into
cyanide but yes it is a thing and that's
why we're passionate about it and we're
working in Canada now to and starting to
create dialogue about you know a new
co-op and and and new answers to the
Bill c-45 and what's happening in Canada
and it is our work to combine
like-minded people here in Canada and
and create a new system that can be
recognized
you know forth for the people of Canada
so that some people that want the lp and
the the large scale operations can they
can buy that from them and no one's
trying to get rid of that and no one
will be able to get rid of it but we're
also trying to keep that that conscious
culture of the herb the herb is a
natural thing that makes our minds open
it makes us want to feel good and safe
access it's so important you know we
talk about safe access and safe access
doesn't mean just you know being able to
access it but that it is safe and people
who have medical issues which you know
I'm sorry to say but we're looking at a
massive amount of people on this planet
that have medical issues it's very rare
that I need people that you know are
even eating organically and running
every day that
not having issues you know with the
amount of toxins that are in the air we
really owe it to those people to give
them good safe clean access and I think
it's really important that we educate
these people and educate these big
industry people that organics is a
cheaper route it is a more sustainable
rare good day people are gonna be
looking for that clean organic route
there's no doubt about it it's all about
people's health and the more toxic the
earth gets the more toxic we get the
more of the things everybody's looking
for the answer in cannabis is but it's
got to be clean organic cannabis and it
really starts like you said with the
inputs and knowing the sources and the
whole way through the genetics how it's
been handled
the whole way through but you know in
education we can really change things at
a big level yeah I guess the big problem
is the profit margins you know it's
these it's that it's that people are
locked into these profit margins in the
now and they're I think that you know I
don't exactly know how to put it into
words but you just always see especially
with the scalability where people are
just like now we're doing it this way
now and just like spraying all these
harmful pesticides it's just
unbelievable how all of us look at the
price of all the songs that
oh yeah it's out of this world and all
the salts and these salt mixtures that
are putting in there and it's just you
can really taste the end in the end
product at least I can you know what I
mean and and I'm open to smoking a lot
of happiness but I was kind of like mine
you know because I grew it and I took
care of it and and I think everybody
should have be able to on some kind of
scale if they had the desire to be able
to grow their own own own you really
know what's going on it you know it's
been our lifestyle my wife you know has
has immune system problems her whole
life and we've found a farm with good
clean well water and where we can pretty
much lis take care of ourselves through
cannabis and all the vegetables we grow
and stuff and it's it's a full it's a
full cycle for us and it really keeps
her healthy she's healthier now than
she's ever been in her life and that
she's out there working
side by side with me in the garden day
in and day out she's an amazing woman
and I'm really happy I think a lot of
people are gonna know that you know the
clean organic lifestyle is going to be
the healthiest way if you really want to
live a long healthy life thank you thank
you Tom and awesome you know
unfortunately a lot of these big
corporations that are coming into the
cannabis industry right now are looking
towards big AG to be there educator and
I'm sorry but when is big AG had good
ideas they've taken all of our soils
they've ruined it and they're the ones
that are saying you know better it's not
interesting and they don't know better
and it's unfortunate that a lot of these
big corporations are not looking towards
maybe the cannabis farmers that have
been doing this for a really long time
they're going straight and direct to
Department of bags and agricultural
education which to me is just dumbing us
down and I don't have a place for it no
me neither I mean you know I've been
able to educate a lot of people along
the way on organics you know we had the
federal government here seven agents
from the CDC and I got to educate them
on production the processing of organic
cannabis and how we do it here on our
farm and you know that's brought opened
up a lot of a lot of opportunities for
me to get out there and keep educating
about organics and the sustainable ways
because it like I said at the end of the
day I don't we got to live here and
organics is the only way and
sustainability is the only way I see us
getting out alive
what kind of breeding is that you want
to do with cannabis hey hold on a second
we were just talking so everyone knows
cheep seven for those familiar tip days
Scott you wrote what do you live in
Oregon you've probably heard a since
many tips it was one of the first yeah
journals back in the 80s and I wrote a
pun I wrote like three articles on
breeding just basic stuff but the one
was called lose about reciprocal
recurrent selection but anyhow to answer
your question I've already given a two
talks at the University of Wisconsin
about like what they do you know how we
use you know how we did breeding in
industry and then how I would apply and
then the second seminar was about how I
would apply that to cannabis and it was
packed
both room both seminars were packed and
they said it was the first seminar ever
given on cannabis breeding at the etho
at the University because it's still
it's still illegal there and it was
really interesting two days but uh you
know it has nothing to do okay can you
describe the technique so basically the
thing this has nothing to do with
organic versus pesticide its breeding it
I mean it's how to make better selection
decisions and basically the techniques I
learned were how to pick how to pick the
best plant even if it's in the wrong
part of the field and it doesn't like if
you select it by its genetics you'll
pick the right plant regardless if it's
not been nurtured properly you know and
I can explain all that stuff to you guys
later I have a whole seminar about it
and I'm gonna try to give it this week
at the University of Colorado Marc's
gonna hook me Colorado State car out of
state which is where they do the hemp
breeding and all that but in Fort
Collins Colorado but um I wouldn't knock
industry too much because they're like
ten years ahead of everybody else in
terms of how to use molecular markers
that's what my specialty was and it was
all native traits I didn't do any
transgenics or any of that exactly what
you talking about
but molecular markers or genetic markers
for breeding from cannabis which hardly
any of identified yet but yes that will
be the future I agree it's being from
what I heard through the grapevine all
the traits are being mapped right now at
private company
these they're not all they're not
sharing all the information because it's
not you know it's not leave trying to
develop an electrical property yeah
they're trying to go up in elections but
I guarantee you there's enough people
working on this that somebody is going
to set up a company that will just
genotype and they'll do it really
cheaply and they'll do the whole you
know not just like specific traits and
you'll be able to you know like I said
earlier it would take a long time to
describe it but it's very very efficient
and very smart technology and it's my
class bioscience do that
what's that doesn't file a finalist has
already done the fingerprinting so they
can tell this is different from this but
the next step is this is better than
this you know
like when they get with cows yeah yeah
and all this stuff is so functional
genomics it's just it's just genetic
more it's called marker-assisted
selection or mass yeah it's where you
just take a smear of each plant and you
can come from that smear whether it's
more appropriate for the particular
ginger you're looking at and my
specialty with complex traits like yield
and that you have to handle in a
different way because there's not like
specific yield genes there there are
yield genes but they have a different
effect in every background so you have
to study each background separately and
that's kind of that knowledge is not
well known not even in industry we this
was something that was top-secret when I
was working at Pioneer and I'm finally
allowed to talk about it because I
published a couple papers on it and so
now now I can talk about it but it
wasn't easy to let them to get
permission to talk about without the
rights to use that I'll just write it to
everybody I read your papers good good
I'm glad you read it man I'm my probably
already patented your process - no I'm
not patenting things I I want
my Papa did he said he patented your
process okay did you power to you man so
I mean I'm I've been waiting for two
years to do this but I I'm married a
Brazilian and it took us two years to
get us permanent residency and now we
finally can move to a cool state Iowa is
terrible I was just doing as little as
they possibly can yeah that's great corn
isn't it corn and soybeans
I personally modified corn yeah I mean I
mean I was my program at pioneer was
Native traits like not using transgenics
because it doesn't always make sense you
know sometimes the jeans are out there
you don't have to you don't have to pull
them out of another species no and
that's still 9 90% of plant breeding is
still that what you hear is like the
transgenic stuff is still only a small
part it's it's um it's the pesticides
that are the problem not the genes you
know because you know you put a few
things together yeah these are together
they're bred to handle lots of pesticide
yeah so yeah you're right totally a
control the disease and they control the
medicine and and the other thing I know
from growing soybeans in the greenhouse
it's it's not easy to grow them
organically you know you really have to
control things and I grew I grew we
organically but on a very small scale
and I had fans going to prevent the
fungi from taking hold and all that
stuff but number I'm really excited to
just actually dive into this now because
I've been waiting I don't like me he's
an industry retread I mean like when you
guys joshie tell him I love you I love
everything that you guys do everything
you say is so
scientifically right on it's so like you
guys are even connected and with the
scientific underpinning of everything
that you say and I just wanted to go
back to your comment about an industry
again yeah I used to be it worked some
big bad chemical company that I probably
should have worked but that's how I met
this guy right and we stand what brought
us together remember what brought us
together music guitar kick guitar right
guitar music jerry garcia brought us
together and and now we have a champion
soybean breeder who said our revoit
industry and jumping into the cannabis
world and it is we need more people like
me and scott you know who of course
because if you believe that cannabis can
rejuvenate and revitalize and improve
everybody's life well that includes big
industry let's get big industry love the
cannabis so hopefully it will improve
all of them including the industry
itself and you know mark honestly you
got a wonder was it Jerry Garcia that
originally brought you guys together or
was it we you know it's like often the
first conversation is yeah it's like the
cannabis is it together and I just love
that it really is true that not only is
it you know remediating the soil but
it's remediating our minds you know so
many of us are able to have these
conversations in depth and be able to
see all different parts of the wheel
because our mind has been remediated by
this amazing plan I think it's really
awesome how mysterious and unbelievable
the ganja plant is and how many layers
like you can't just transgenic it you
can't just genetically you can't just
that the heads and the whatever the
cryogenics so deep and so technical that
the greatest of minds are just racking
their selves over it and the plants just
like give me some Sun I love it it is a
beautiful thing
I like that conversation to go back to
mark and the chief there I I could do
what we could do
hache church on this and invite some of
the people from segre that have built a
molecular biology lab and are also
looking into doing that work we can
invite Kevin mckernon we could invite
mouths Lee from we could have a really
great conversation have Sam of course
that would be a good like three to four
hour one I was even thinking I don't
know what your seminar is but you should
definitely come do it on bubble man's
world he'd love to see well I have two
seminars they both take about in an hour
so it's not know and one is one is you
know basically what I did in soybean and
it would really change it was a big
breakthrough and but the same thing will
work in cannabis it's it's it's it's
just another crop you know it's there
the differences the second seminar is
about how cannabis is different from
other crops and how that affects the
strategy in the tweaking the tweaking of
the IP what's that like how you would
tweak the IP that works for soybeans to
make it work with cannabis yeah and in
fact cannabis is a lot easier because
the fact that you once you have a plant
you like you can just clone it it's not
that easy and soybean you know you gotta
like in breed it and fix it for all the
traits and it's it's it's like an eight
year process you know Jesus cuz you got
to test it well I can't in soybean it
has to be better and it has to be tested
across like a hundred different
fireman's or nobody's gonna buy it
so that's you're talking about four a
four seed variety yeah any introduced
bone that's one thing but if you want a
four seed variety achievement are given
eight years probably yeah yeah like if
you can do something like Sam knows this
you can do some em breeding did you say
that um you got the f3 now we got to f4
and a few cases in f5 but it
every negative recessive trait pops up
and it has absolutely no health no vigor
and in most cases it's functionally
sterile which means the pollen although
it still can be transferred by q-tip -
it doesn't that he's and it it's sticky
or something like that so it's
impossible to breathe without extra
extra care well so most soybean
varieties even though they were
supposedly inbred they were f3 derived
so they still had a lot of segregation
even even though all the plants look the
same and it's probably going to be the
same thing in cannabis maybe they'll be
f2 derived but you'll select
phenotypically so that it looks uniform
but you're never gonna get it
genetically homozygous it would die
before that and are you are you familiar
with them allen cap euler's work or AKA
mushroom he's got like the largest
soybean collection in the world and has
done amazing amounts of work with the
genome and and all different kinds of
things for soybeans well the world
collection that I knew that I used to
champion Illinois it had like 30
thousand different accessions and I've
tapped it several times screened it for
various traits and I actually came up
with some really cool you know like some
wild soybeans that I have a patent on a
fart list soybean the soybean that
doesn't make you fart fart list soybean
it doesn't give you gas and it was just
a mutant that didn't produce stachyose
that here's stachyose is what makes you
fart but it never really made it to the
market because it was only worth to pig
as pig feed for chicken feed it was only
worth 50 cents more bushel and it cost
50 cents just to keep it separate so the
identity preservation costs are 50 cents
so you
all the value because you have to keep
it separate you know keeping separate
elevators and that I thought after that
so like economics plays a big role in
what makes it to market you know but
that's good that's that's been how
economics affects farting yeah it's like
well we don't really care if the pigs if
it's not worth more than 50 cents that's
crazy
nothing with fart less beans though come
on
that's what's screwing up the atmosphere
of methane that's way worse than co2
it's like it's like 10 times worse than
carbon dioxide
shout out faded faded AF who said that
gold the avenue is less methane with
fart less beans
that's pretty hilarious that's just
funny that you you just never know
what's gonna come up in conversation on
hash Church but every campus is like is
a plant breeders dream because you're in
the infancy
there's tons of variation there's oh
it's like the coolest plant to work on I
think and it's me it's medicine it's
food it's fiber it's it's good for the
soil it's unbelievable that day that
it's illegal I mean I just can't get
that shows you well that's why it's
illegal and all I think all the things
you just said are exactly why it's
illegal but there's all these people
like us they're just so passionate about
it we can't believe it you know it keeps
us up at night you know so I was like I
got a cool statement there's six hundred
people or five hundred and sixty people
watching right now just for us to talk
about this very thing there's a lot of
people worldwide and it's growing more
and more and more as I see people
developing a relationship outside of
that that strip of prohibition that we
all have you know the most passionate
seem to be like you really have to push
through that prohibition thing it's like
so this is going to endanger my life my
family my freedom I say
like all of these things my like it's a
it's a big thing to step through that
veil and and and sort of own all of that
to be a canvas person in the last 30 40
50 years and now we're into entering
this new level where I think there's
some of the animosity comes from people
from though from the community the old
school community where they see these
people coming in that have not had to
step through that veil and personally I
say stop presenting people for for not
having to step through that veil because
that's the whole point of our activism
for the last 50 plus years was to remove
that veil so that people could step
freely through it and it doesn't matter
if they haven't been involved in the
industry for 10 or 20 or 30 or 40 years
it's okay they can still come and and
put their hat in the ring and and do
their thing and I'm excited to see that
sort of opening it's sort of like now
we're instead of breeding with like a
hundred or a thousand we're opening it
up to the millions you know to hundreds
of thousands the numbers are just so
great that we're gonna pull some great
people into this into this industry grow
I mean isn't it better for them to grow
earth that the infringing dart or a
policeman straight up I'm in the same
agreeance and I also get criticized for
it when they're like now they're coming
in to take over the industry it's like
no they're just coming in to be a part
in the industry no we're not gonna let
anyone take anything we're the ones that
our own civil disobedience is the thing
that's why we're so protective of our
baby yeah I guess because civil
disobedience that's opened up this
Avenue now it's just a matter of
maintaining some proper stewards you
know Hillary black she gets she gets
people on her all the time because she
works for canopy and it's like I love
having Hillary black in the ear of
canopy I could not picture a better
person to be in the you know I heard
recently canopy is now bigger than like
Air Canada
and WestJet combines two of our big
airlines in Canada this is a cannabis
company and they have Hillary Black in
their ear I have my money on Hillary
over canopy in in that conversation
she's just too sweet she'll just infect
them with sweetness and hurt her
positivity and and the way she's always
been a real proper stewardess of the
plant you know of the highest integrity
and I don't think that we've brought her
to not educate people on it you know I
think that it's totally important that
new people are coming and being involved
but I think that we can take all of what
we've learned in the past 40 years and
bring it forward to to make it more you
know viable for the industry to go
forward and have success I would hope it
would be more respect I go to a lot of
conferences and I went to one last week
maybe look down on the Pioneers I was
sitting next to a table of people
talking and I overheard him say wow
you're a true pioneer you've been in the
industry for four years and I was this
like I had to speak up I whoa whoa whoa
whoa whoa whoa let's hold on a minute
now
there's been people doing this 4050
years people are dedicated my friends
went to jail they died also you have the
honor of doing this and you don't know
me or you don't know any of these people
what they've done you know before you
throw a broad spectrum you know diss on
our whole community and all the people
that got you here you know let's step
back and you should respect this a
little bit more so it's it's a two-edged
sword out there we don't you know I love
all the science that's come into the
industry a really you know raises the
bar and puts it into a whole nother
international level I love that part but
just a little respect from people
towards the Pioneers would be in a
highly appreciate that that goes back to
perspective it's kind of when you hear
like a fourteen-year-old kid said
remember back in the day and that was
like three years ago because that's what
his perspective is and it's a perfect
example of even how you framed it was
like your friends went to jail your
friends died well that's still a very
small perspective when you go back some
centuries to people that were being
flogged and murdered and killed over
this plant this has been happening for
so much longer than any of us have been
alive that it's it's a real thing like
this this prohibition of cannabis goes
back way beyond our friends and family
way beyond 40 or 50 years it goes far
back for these countries to have
produced these plants these Sufis to
have gone through the torture that they
went through for eating hashish like all
of these different histories it would be
great to have Chris Bennett in the room
right now because he busted out an
accurate description of all these things
but you know those guys are also a part
of that pioneering that maybe we don't
give credit to enough so now we can
easily see why maybe the next group
isn't giving credit easily enough it's
all about our perspective and how it's
framed in the timeline that we've
existed in and so I agree with you on
one level and on the other level I just
see it as a natural cycle of humans that
we ourselves as the apparent pioneers in
this particular 40 to 50 year run are
maybe also forgetting the the last 50
before us and the hundred years before
that and the you know these cultivars to
have they've come a long way these
plants these these are not yesterday's
plants smoking cannabis for about 500
years before that because smoking is a
new world convention cannabis was an old
world invention so Columbus had to mix
the two up before we started smoking but
there was prohibition there was
prohibition in the evening of cannabis -
oh absolutely the Garden of Poker in
Egypt you know I think there was 1350 or
something like that like you said if
they caught you they would give you
rotten milk make you drink it and if you
threw up brain or the Eton hashish then
they pulled your teeth out oh that's
just nuts and you know there's there's
5,000 years it goes backs as amok
moxibustion you know cannabis was used
to burn and moxibustion and you can see
that in the old
ancient Chinese health texts and if they
were burning it then it was all around
the patient so the Scythian stood that
as well didn't they aren't they one of
the oldest once again I wish Chris was
here because he's just got such a great
grasp on the Chinese maybe two or three
thousand years ago you have a Cynthia
miss what they did was made through
flowering cannabis on top of embers in a
fire underneath attempt they got in the
chant with it and according to Herodotus
they screaming who is joy the hot box in
right there that's some old-school hot
box on just a couple thousand years ago
so hopefully yes we should always you
know and that also comes just with
ignorance when you don't know something
people saying oh you're a pioneer you've
been in this industry for four years
because I have to admit Tom I've heard
that as well but from my perspective I
and I honestly my natural natural
reaction to it was that I chuckled III I
wasn't offended at all I just thought
like oh it was just funny right because
it's like I know something they don't
and he can't be mad at them because they
don't know they're just coming in with
this really narrow slice of the pie but
potentially and we all started somewhere
in 40 or 50 years they could get to
where where a lot of us are and being in
a position to help educate the next
round of young ignorant box that are go
ahead sorry
alright not to but I was just saying
that I think the industry everything's
just changing so fast like I think it's
almost like a modern issue it's just
like what do we even know about two
years ago seems like forever ago you
know I mean on certain levels you know
pioneers google it so simple you know or
girls do know everything cuz all they
have to do is ask the question and they
can google it so it's like we don't need
elders anymore instant response and it's
it's very
automatic I feel like you know you have
a question you can have it answered well
that's a really symptomatic response
what are the roots that go all the way
down to that possible question and it is
a real issue with society today and I
would say this is an attempt industry I
mean two years ago is like a revelation
that you can get CBD isolate well now
it's a revelation that you just take the
THC out of it you know it's like oh you
just have seen the isolate oh that's a
thing in the past but we want the full
spectrum no THC or so my god whatever
that thing oh okay you know anyway I
think it's interesting out how fast
things are changing agreed it's deadly
oh man I have to ask you a question
please do it I saw your video about when
you went that you make and you were
looking for all the fields were you were
doing selections and you found that one
field where everything looked more
uniform and you were selecting the
female the best females do you still
have that seed I have I have most of
those seeds yeah I have seeds that go
way back before videos to from around 95
96 in Jamaica and so there was this
other guy that I worked that I talked to
in Oregon and he got this strain from
from Africa called Malawi I think it was
nice
Malawi yeah Malawi he said it's really
the most potent the only problem is it's
very late maturing so so he bought some
seeds and he's breeding it to be earlier
you know earlier maturing but I guess if
you're growing indoors that doesn't
matter right you can pretty much do that
with lights right yeah or if you're just
a tropical place like Jamaica it doesn't
what I was really impressed with that
video because that's exactly what plant
breeders do let her do native traits you
go to you go to a place like that and
you just you just start collecting stuff
you know and that field of all these
females that you share
that is like that's like that's what
turned me on to plant breeding just to
see the genetic diversity right in front
of your face and those were slightly
those were intimated right so they were
like a population absolutely
but they still had tons of diversity oh
yeah well Jamaica is this crazy inbred
Island of cannabis cultivars it's hard
to find those those those pure I I don't
want to say landrace cuz even they were
brought there from most likely India but
some of those older narrow leaf drug
cultivars those tall ones that's what I
was always looking for but of course
most of what you end up finding is the
short stacked single buds
turtle Jewett is talking about going
someplace and collecting teeth you can't
do that anymore that's illegal that's so
biopiracy actually there's enough
diversity now I think to keep us going
for a while that's not true
three-quarters of the people out there
will suppose was at least partially
collected but though it's not collecting
for disease resistance no it's the next
phase in cannabis we get apartment
because of population sizes maybe you
need for that and also because it's a
little bit more sophisticated breeding
than than just three yeah just go into
anyone's grow room and you can see that
people have not focused
disease resistant cultivars as of yet
sometimes you have to go back to really
wild stuff to get to get it because the
gene pool has been so bottle necked
but your teeth the exact opposite is
what's actually true since the
introduction of widely drug varieties
thank you thank you for I actually I
know a little bit
[Laughter]
when if you select for just drug types
that's what you're gonna get you know
well you know it's it's even different
than that that both the narrow leaf the
equatorial tropical narrowly drug
varieties then they have high resistance
to mold and powdery mildew and that kind
of stuff
whereas materials from Afghanistan up in
the mountains they don't have any
resistance to it and when you bring them
down to areas where there are those
problems your implants and the hybrids
of those plants serious serious problems
with yeah that's for sure that's what we
can really listen to the plant and what
it is the genetics are telling us and
where the genetics have come from and I
do believe that lots of small-time
growers for a very long time have been
breeding for pesticide you know for pest
issues and for fungi issues for a very
long time so there are small breeders
out there they've been doing it a super
long time I realize that there may not
be like a large industry big breeding
but there are a lot of amazing varieties
out there that are totally resistant to
pests and fungi and they're going
through maybe hundreds of seeds you know
in their field a thousand and then they
go through and only pollinate the ones
that you know look the best I mean who's
gonna go into a plant and pollinate
something with powdery mildew all over
it I mean okay so it happens but I that
person is not really working with I
believe that those that those years of
expertise that people have been doing
you know in their small gardens does
play does have a play in the breeding
industry moving forward right well just
to give you a clue of what I mean by
diversity in order to find some traits
that I was looking for ice cream like
15,000 different accessions and found
one that had the fart lestrade I mean
still you'd have to make a commitment if
you want it if you want to do that
breeding and and I'm guessing the reason
the narrow leaf ones are
more disease-resistant to enjoy is cuz
air moves through the canopy better we
saw that and soybean you know like
there's narrow eat soybeans well it's
partly that and partly the other thing
is that they come from an environment
that's wet humid and hot and wet humid
and hot and if they don't have natural
resistance we're gonna see existence a
variety right powdery mildew is actually
pretty common in a lot of resistance
genes are not hard to find in a lot of
crops I don't know about I don't know
about cannabis yet because I never
looked for it but it should be easy to
find because it's an obligate parasite
it evolved with the plant it can only
live on that plant and maybe one wild
other you know so when when you have a
situation like that the host develops
resistance genes very quickly so they're
there they're out there you just got to
look for them I have not seen very much
I've grown thousands thousands of Afghan
seeds that are important from
Afghanistan many different times and let
me tell you in general they have zero
resistance do they have do they all have
broad leaves yes of course
that's what I was saying it's the narrow
leaf itself if you have one plant
growing in the middle of a whole bunch
of narrow leaf plants that one gets
mildewy and all the rest of them no it's
not density it's not it's I mean what
you're saying is partly but that's not
the core reason the core reason is they
don't have any genetic resistance to
these also I think that we're seeing a
tremendous you know you know
non-resistant and variety of different
types of leaf mildews you know it's
really easy to say oh it's p.m. or oh
it's DM but
we're seeing a tremendous amount of
different types of mildews that are
landing on plants and I don't see it any
different than humans you know I see a
candida infection exactly the same
inside of a human as I would see on a
plant and we're seeing humans you know
much less of a healthy microbiome in the
same way that we're seeing unhealthy
microbiome in plants it has to do with
the toxicity whatever they're spraying
up in the atmosphere whatever is going
into our soils whatever is going into
the into the water systems is really you
know bringing down the immune response
and I think that that is something that
you know the reason why it's such a huge
conversation PM PM everybody that you
talk to in the industry is talking about
this there's a reason why it has to do
with genetics it has to do with
environment and it you know and it has
to do with the time that we're living
right now so we're seeing more and more
people affected in their microbiome or
soil affected in the microbiome and more
plants affected in the microbiome so we
have to be smarter than that we have to
clean up our act and we have to produce
genetics that are immune to these things
Sam were you able to produce any soils
or any ways to enhance the immune system
to create organic growing in general
biodynamic organic bread in general does
that really a lot but I'd like to repeat
that if I'm growing huge amounts of
narrow league plants do I grow a few the
Afghan ones do in with them and they
yeah they're like magnets for it for
sure I mean it does you don't really
have to be a plant breeder to understand
that one comes from a super dry arid
area and has never encountered powdery
mildew before and the other has grown in
in the tropical like super humid super
hot environment like where where if you
put an Afghan there just go to Jamaica
and see they put the O's Afghan and they
just get powdery mildew it's crazy
and we could say the same as somebody
who's been living up in Siberia they're
in
tire life and then bring them to the
tropics and what kind of things come out
of them you know what their body is
totally used to what their genetics are
used to and then it's it's really
amazing because I do work in large
clinics in in tropical areas and a lot
of the doctors or nurses or midwives
that come down into that area they get
really sick because they've been dealing
with like cold environment for a long
time and talk about all different types
of mildews and fungi that will come out
of them to be able to acclimate it's
amazing I don't see us any different
than the plants true that for sure I
definitely from traveling I saw it a lot
just people going to countries they've
never been to far-off countries and
picking up weird viruses weird little
little sicknesses and that's all because
of the microbiome and how much it
changes from region to region and that
microbiome is is inside of the genetics
it's inside of the seed as much as it
you know is resistant or non resistant
when it grows out into a clamp true
enough we'll [ __ ] two and a half hours
not too bad just gonna keep going you
want to call it a day what's how's
everyone feeling I'm good by this guy I
have to go check into my air B&amp;B ah the
air B&amp;B well I've texted mark to put us
in touch with one another I have some
more questions for I want to keep in
touch though guys yeah thanks for coming
and opening up the conversation it was a
good one nice to meet you hopefully we
meet on the flip side I have lots of
questions for you for sure it's gonna be
about two or three months before I'm in
Colorado so I gotta sell my house and
all that stuff but just be patient
Cali reach out to me and I'll I'll put
you in contact with Scott too so you can
I would love that
that would be great thanks so much
thought for coming on in your inputs
awesome thank you thank you see you
later chief yeah see you Sam
bye bye yeah all right
thank everyone for coming out d 420k and
Johnny B the Dragonfly earth medicine
crew farmer Tom skunk man Sam Wade
laughter and of course dr. mark Sheldon
and Scott always a good conversation
with everyone I did appreciate I just
you know what I appreciate not everyone
agreeing on everything I appreciate the
discourse you know being able to have
dialogue about different things and not
get upset and start calling each other
names but just have like an adult
conversation I mean I wish actually
Kuban would have come back in because
when we started the organics talk he was
talking a lot about how he does not do
organics and he just had his own good
points that would have made I just think
it's okay for us to disagree and that's
kind of the biggest value here on hash
search in my opinion as you know Josh
was saying this industry is changing so
fast
month after month after month that it's
pretty important to have a dialogue
going to let people kind of catch up and
keep up with what's going on and the
changes that are so consistent but I
want to thank all of you for coming out
and sharing your time and of course the
people who are watching and listening
thanks a lot we'll see you next Sunday
if if I can make it happen
so thanks I would guess not a good one
he definitely had a little Michael
Keaton thing going on for sure
I was curious about myself awesome
everyone have a great Sunday thanks so
much everyone blessings peace