episode nine and I've already got a few
folks in the house what's going on hemp
guy I'm trying to figure out why my
camera's not on I'll figure it out well
s's figured his out ha
mat I got help I needed I need help dude
it's so good to see you man yeah nice to
see you too holy smokes right on welcome
brother welcome
little little hash church in the morning
oh Debbie's here with the Golden Gate
Bridge behind
her how you doing Debbie good morning
not bad how about you or should I say
Deborah oh that's fancy is that what it
says yeah it does
indeed and I have no idea how to change
it holy cow that's okay we can rock
Deborah I'm uh look at me I'm Bubble Man
Marcus Richardson so got three silly
names here so put the third behind it
and I got my Japanese friend's name yeah
dude I love it his laptop right now ah
matsuzaki well welcome
hayate and welcome Johnny B what's going
on everybody morning morning great to
see
everybody see again Brothers hi morning
skunk M morning Mark morning de
everybody
it's been it's been a while since we've
had a hash Church you know there's been
so much going on in the world right now
oh and s's going to melt some hash you
know the first time I saw s do that was
probably a very very long time ago I
think 2001 or 2002 I'm telling you dude
because I picture that Jason Lee bubbler
that you bought from me in the
background as you're doing it I have it
I have it right where I am now I think
of course of course you
do that's awesome well yeah lots going
on in the world I thought it would be a
kind of a good idea to have a little
gathering of hash Church alumni here
maybe some new maybe some old and just
kind of get together not with any really
particular narrative to discuss or
script but really just you know get
together with with all of you guys find
out what's going on in your neck of the
woods with all the I mean full-blown
Madness you know I'm I'm trying I want
to try and keep it positive but at the
same time I want to hear exactly what
everyone's kind of going through these
days in regards to all the madness
there's a lot of Madness going out there
did you get to check out London and
Germany and Berlin oh I saw that one in
London how many people was that not as
many as in Germany really I didn't see
Germany but I saw London it looked like
Germany like I just put some pictures up
on my Facebook like Germany was
outrageous you know wow well I thought
the picture of London was pretty
outrageous so Germany really must have
been outrageous it looked like over a
100,000 people in London and and over a
million in Germany
damn well people are out protesting and
here we are just puffing we got a couple
hundred people watching in the room
right now puffing is one of the best
things you can do straight
up straight up I agree you know
obviously we're all quite biased and
we've been saying this for a long time
but when you hear mainstream media
people when you when you hear Dr Bonnie
Henry who's our health lady here in BC
say you know just like uh you know stay
at home with friends and smoke some
joints and I was like excuse me did she
just say to to hang out with friends and
smoke joints did she say smoke joints
really yeah she was talking about like
puffing yeah I mean it's you know we're
allowed to smoke joints now so why not
right I like that yeah it's it's it's at
the point right now that every time I go
out and I roll a joint I actually I got
like four or five in front of me soon as
when I light up a joint with some
friends I just hand them one now because
it's you just can't share anymore it's
it's like that puff and pass is RO one
for your friend H you know it's the
Jamaican way to be honest the Jamaicans
taught me that so many years ago they
were just like well why you want to pass
your joint around like why don't you
just roll your own spliff and I was like
man I never even thought of such a thing
and same reason what you know why
because we always want to share
something we're like here you
let joint first you want to do is such a
big part of it
man
well I think the bigger reason was in
America a Jo used to be
expensive now it's I mean in Jamaica
it's cheap so why share
I recognize that
voice yeah you
do you recognize that voice that's uh
that's skunkman Sam in the house welcome
Colin Colin Palmer the house and welcome
uh wow look at look at Mark scalone that
was H that was a pretty fancy shot you
had there
bud that's what's up hey Deb how are you
good to see you good
that's what we call that's what we call
the money
[Laughter]
shot not scare the investors out of the
room the money shot so how's everybody
been doing honestly what's been going on
in the world of all of you you know
what's what's I can honestly say that
absolutely nothing has changed in my
life I stay at home I never go see
anybody and uh everything's exactly the
same you never go see anybody so you
don't lose any
cars he was socially
isolated to be socially isolated s you
gotta expand on that one dude that that
[ __ ] is funny not not now in
private oh I think Sam's a big enough
man to acknowledge that that [ __ ]
happened I mean it was classic it's
amazing no never ever happened to
me it's it's just you know what it
really is the story that sort of leads
into um oh what the heck is his name now
karma karma genetics has a cultiv called
where is my bike and everyone's like
what the [ __ ] is that it's like it was
the Amnesia Haze crossed with that biker
cush and it was like I think one of the
first guys to ever smoke it basically
came back and was like I lost my bike
which is not really most like lots of
people have lost their bikes in
Amsterdam particularly people who go
there who rent a bike and have never
been there and the place all looks the
same and you park your bike out in front
of a little spot and the next thing you
know you're walking around you get
separated from your bike that bike's
gone if you're never ever gonna see
especially if you don't lock it
especially if you don't lock it exactly
there's no doubt about that but doing it
with a car is like the next like the
next level that's
I yeah oh my goodness no no one even got
a new car out of it well yeah you're
right actually some omita says someone
got a new car out of it it's true you're
right you're right you're right without
even knowing the story you're right
that's funny all right I'm loading up
some lime pop 87 little bit of rosin
that I squished with Flav the other
day anybody else using tons of Edibles
during this whole Co thing that's my my
god I've been I've been doing Edibles
almost every other day almost every
other day I last night I went to I went
to the sauna and I ate a bunch of
Edibles I got in the hot tub I did a few
sweats on the Edibles and like I'm not
on my phone when I'm in the sauna and
I'm not talking that much I'm mostly
like internalizing and it was fantastic
eating Edibles at the sun I highly
recommend it
I've been just puffing a lot not so much
eating
Edibles uh mainly because I'm working in
the lab five days a week so I can't just
get utterly
destroyed and and still operate multiple
lab technicians and multiple modalities
of extraction and all highly regulated
QA and all this other stuff that you
have to sort of deal with but um puffing
has certainly been my friend there's no
doubt about that well that's probably
why because you do you guys hear my shop
got looted and robbed and cl horrible
horrible horrible I actually see it in
your face I see that I see that
disappointment in your face and usually
usually usually I never see that in your
face your face is like optimistic like
you know inspiring and it still is but I
see now I know that look I saw on your
face oh God so about but I forgot about
that that happened to you and that sucks
that's what happens we're still close so
yeah maybe that's why I'm eating the
Edibles right you just got to like shut
down that thought process that happens
you know when something really bad like
that little traum been dealing Trauma
from it you know because it was bad you
guys all all 10 dispensaries in Oakland
got targeted by looters and robbers like
every one of us and the majority of us
lost everything we lost everything our
our security cameras our doors our
Windows our all of our weed all of our
money all of our equipment so I mean
because the Oakland Police Department I
don't blame the Rock per se I blame
societal issues of course being so bad
but also Oakland Police Department
didn't help us at all they actually left
our place unguarded for eight hours what
the hell these guys were able to get a
thousand pound safe out of there in that
course of that eight hours
so that's that's some [ __ ] for sure
I remember back in the day when someone
drove a car through the front of the
Compassion Club which would actually
later end up leading to me getting
busted with Compassion Club cannabis
because they didn't want to keep it at
the facility because they were getting
robbed well these guys drive a car
through the fac right through the window
this is in the
90s late '90s they get this the safe had
to be close to a th000 pounds as well it
was ridiculous how far they moved it
scraped up the floor bent the door so it
was just somehow cracked the tiniest bit
well it had like 35 pounds of Renee in
the safe so this little crack was like
you might as well have had a thousand
light grow in full bloom inside that
safe it stunk so bad the cops showed up
and Hillary was certain like oh this is
not going to go well and they guarded
that safe for like hours just standing
next to the safe not doing much it's not
like they were standing there with their
guns out they just were a presence and I
mean how hard is that for the police
department to be doing I mean in my
opinion that would be probably one of
the safest places to be just go hang out
next to this safe you know you got your
cop car there no one's going to come and
bother you I'm really sorry that
happened to you and and all the rest of
the and everyone millions and millions
of dollars some of my friends lost $2
million doar like above you know
millions of dollars in their facilities
but um after that the police felt so bad
they have stepped up a little bit at
least to be preventative and one of the
weirder conversations I've ever had with
the police which I've had a lot at this
point but yeah the captain of the police
department's like how about next time
we'll guard it just bring it all down to
the police department and we'll and
we'll we'll sort it at the Police
Department during the civil unrest and
then people oh my God is this really
happening the police tell me to bring my
weed down so they'll put it I thought
the police I thought the police always
said crime doesn't
pay yeah that's their motto that's why
people don't trust them it's like man
like even your motto's way off
like it's terrible I know I know you're
not going to smoke us B
you better smoke
one Sam when's the last time you smoked
a spliff
Sam the last time I had either uh women
or slaves at my
house he went there only Sam you have to
know the context of that without
thinking Sam's a total douche right now
and I can promise you he's not but that
was borderline over the over the over
the top I haven't smoked a joint in 19
years myself you haven't no oh I know
not a long I spoke to Joint last night
nice wedding cake Mac it was delicious
actually yeah I wish I wish I could I
don't know why I can't I think uh you
know it has to be great weed yeah it has
to be great weed for sure but something
happened s after I got turned on to
bubble and I was making bubble in 99 and
I was getting Renee and it was so
flavorful it almost blasted out my my
nose and my taste buds with this Renee
profile and for two and a half years I
smoked that [ __ ] chronic every day and
then someone was like Hey like uh this
is a really it was a super nice joint in
Jamaica of like Lamb's bread they're
like you got to smoke this it's so nice
and I was like all right and I just took
a little little puff of it and it just
tasted like like an ashtray it was just
like it was wet on the end and it was
like I don't know just I was like I've
ruined joints for myself which was
really actually quite a sad day I wasn't
stoked about it at all it was like I
couldn't get back to the perspective
because I like many of you absolutely
loved joints like I would look at it the
way s's looking at his yeah 53 years at
doing this yeah exactly dude and I was
only like 20 some odd or 15 years in or
something you know like I wasn't
so I get it I wish I could go back and
enjoy it but I
can't on the commercial Market but it's
nowhere you know you can't get that
stuff at least I'm trying I know Marcus
is trying too oh yeah it's a lot of but
I think some of the newer varieties are
really tasty Marcus and I I I would say
that some of the newer stuff I've been
smoking on these these really expansive
poly Hy hybrids that have just been
super worked I mean the tpping profiles
on some of them are really exent I love
them I love them in in in pure form
diluted on plant matter and wrapped in
paper and glue not so much I'm with you
on that but last night was was
interesting I I as you know I'm not huge
on joints at all and I yeah I mean I
didn't smoke the whole thing but like
you know definitely definitely got a
not so what every what's everybody
smoking on today what are you guys uh
summer what are you smoking on out in
Amsterdam
brother well this is like five different
kinds I always call it s salad because
almost every time unless I'm testing
something
out I'm always making a mix because
that's how that's my favorite kind of
splp nice man anything new that you're
working on that you're really enjoying
lately like or something that I got this
amazing lavnes going it's
halfes
and the tpin are very unique I was gonna
say funky they must be super funky yeah
and nice gross patterns you
know
wow like giant I to check that
out I uh I like the sounds of that dude
you picked two pretty darn good ones I
mean
listen I love that Haze that narrow Leaf
drug cultivar tpine profile that is just
you know we you know in North America we
call it exotic it's those exotic exotic
flavors especally when it's the
Southeast Asian one it's super EXO yeah
yeah it's uh I mean [ __ ] I remember uh
you breaking up that 26 week sativa at
uh I think David's from uh Ripper seeds
we were making hash there and you were
in the back room in Barcelona yeah I
remember yeah that was uh it's funny
because there's a video of that on my
Channel all these different stories
often that I talk about I'll be like
whoa there's actually a video of that on
on this on this YouTube channel it's
it's pretty
trippy have the video of the
experience 26 week Haze was the longest
I'd ever heard flowering I used to grow
one back in the day that was about 16
weeks um that we thought was long you
know even that's long these days it's
long but that uh that 26 weer that you
had was
uh ridiculous that should be available
too I had one that went till under
natural photo period in h Central Coast
California it went until April the 1 and
I called it April pools phas
it was planted you know like in
September or something like that but it
just took forever to
flower damn damn that's insane I got a
plant that I'm running right now so I'm
in like week six of flower and it's just
starting to get buzs I'm like [ __ ] this
thing is gonna go probably that 16 weeks
because it is
across Colombian uh 24 weeks of T
Colombia with grco cookies and it's just
like you can tell it's like oh it's
going to go that
long and
look what photo period do you put it on
J right now I'm on 11 and a half hours a
day uh because I'm trying to match my
ppfd to get the right moles a day so
I've got 30 moles a day at
756 ppfd at my canopy but I had a major
pH problem I was feeding at 4.5 so I'm
TR of recovering from that if I can
for like two
weeks was that low for two weeks yeah I
thought it was light stress in the
beginning and it was like stress I was
hitting them at like um 1500 ppfd 1256
to 1500 at 18 hours a day so when I went
into flower things changed I started
seeing light stress and then through
that my meter started failing that went
into PPM to a new scen lock out to well
these sativas now that are now they're
recovering the other ones probably won't
but I'm gonna I'm actually being able to
see these longer flowering plants
hopefully we'll recover from and be able
to see what they I get from them but the
phot period right now we think sound
11.5 hours at um like I said I'm at
750 ppfd at the top of the canopy so
that gives me 30 moles a day I
think
and because you can usually speed up uh
flowering or shorten flowering depending
on what you want to call it by uh not
doing 122 but doing you know 11 hours of
light a day or but
whatever that's I'm also introducing the
so the plants feel like they're in the
shade so hopefully that
might I liked how Johnny B went deep on
that uh answer like how how much were
you EXP in Johnny B to answer like that
skunk man
Sam that's fine with me I mean Johnny B
Tri to be S Mr science and uh he's doing
did a pretty good job on that light
answer I'm just gonna give him a little
high five there P of pating you know and
what he knows about well I like that
about Johnny B that he goes deep and
he's like he gets into [ __ ] and he's
like hey I'm learning he never tries to
act like he's the big expert but he's
like he's got great information and he's
learning it and uh he's here to share it
with us so [ __ ] thanks Johnny B I
really want to share it with people in
that pH low 4.5 like really showing
people because it looked like it was
nutrient burn and I thought it was a a
nitrogen burn and then I thought it was
light stress and there was so many and
I'm testing my meters like crazy I
actually went to Blue lab and then one
guy I brought in he goes your meter's
eight years old dude he goes you're only
good for two years your meter's dead I'm
like well why does this stuff last
forever these days but that was a huge
lesson for me was was really I have
three uh not double triple checking my
my calibrations and actually not
comparing with another pen so having two
is is now I'll always have a second pen
to double check with things because I
relied on one meter for so long well I
appreciate your honesty your
transparency and your courage in a time
when so many people are so afraid to
show any vulnerability or weakness on
social media
here you are just blasting it out to the
world oh I [ __ ] got bugs oh I I I
[ __ ] up my plants I did this and what
you're doing is you're making the
mistakes that they're all afraid to
either talk about or share or show and
you're doing it in a way that are
allowing people to be like oh [ __ ] maybe
that's what happened to my plants you
know because people are the internet is
horrendous it's like uh it's you know
you go on there and all of a sudden
you're under full attack like if you
just posted if it wasn't you posting
that picture and it was anyone else you
know they would just be like fully
destroyed on social media look at this
Noob like people are not as willing to
help so I do really appreciate your
ability to share your mistakes with
everyone and get past them and show how
you can continue to grow healthy plants
it's it's pretty cool
man you know what it's the plant that
always teaches me to grow forward and
and it's showing me uh like I have that
amazing cany like with the room was
doing so well and I was so proud of it
and it's just like it just kind of like
at any second you can that's how quick
you can lose a crop and people really I
mean I I've never had this problem
before and it it went through everything
so it's good to be able to share with
people at the same time people are
teaching me so much so as I'm sharing
I'm learning so much coming back because
now everybody's like oh try this hey
your pH got to be 6.6 these the lights
are are more like Ferraris you're gonna
have to tune up your engine you're going
to need to add a little bit more of this
and change your like there's a few
different things that I'm learning going
into this new phase of the next level
growing with VPD with LEDs with looking
at those canopies looking at the ppfd
look at the amount of moles the plants
are getting a day and really dialing
that in like right now I'm learning that
with LEDs like I can come in at the end
the last couple weeks of my flowering
add a far red the plants feel like
they're in the shade they're going to
actually just elongate more get bigger
Buds and that's just the research that's
coming out of uh Apple D Technologies
which is through grinby from and this is
all NASA research right now so it's
pretty cool to see how the Direction
with LED growing because I've been
growing with LEDs for so long to see
it's next step in the future of growing
and I always say this green Rush right
now is LED lights for cannabis that is
the biggest green Rush right now for the
industry is LED lights because there's
so many lights on the market now before
you just go and buy an HBS bul or a dual
land gabita there's H there's so many
LED lights on the market guys now it's
it's it's overwhelming what light what
like not to choose which ones work for
what applications we got ones for veg
ones for flow ones for late flow like
it's pretty cool to see how we're able
to dial this in now and I've been down
the rabbit hole huge learning about ppfd
uh photo synthetic flux density and the
amount of photons that leaving the light
source and the amount of actually
hitting the leaf and there's just so
much more to know and and it's pretty
cool you know I always love sharing this
with you guys because I I kind of want
you guys to share back so hit me up and
let's talk about growing you know what I
mean that's what I love so much bong rip
have to say dabs away bong rip indeed
that was uh that was awesome dude I'm uh
I'm always stoked I was stoked when you
got into the the the active water that
was unique and different not a lot of
people were were doing it and of course
tons of people are are are light experts
and whatnot but you're you're honest and
trustworthy I think that's like your
your how you differ from a lot of these
different from people you're actually
trustworthy you're not uh out to uh
direct people in the wrong in the wrong
way so cheers Johnny B and cheers
everyone else on the panel right now I
really appreciate you all showing up
here today for a little hash Church
something we haven't really done in a
long
time hey me and Colin have a project
we're working on
together tell us after meeting on H
church because um well you guys know
that Magnolia has a dab bar so and there
I was dabbing probably last time I was
on hash church and and Co was just
heating up and I'm looking at the rig
going and I think we even talked about
it how do we clean those things so that
we can use them in a public space and I
could use it and then it could be
cleaned and somebody else could use it
like how do you actually flip the glass
wear in a um in a commercial cannabis
setting in a dab bar so when we had our
panel discussion here everyone was like
uh I don't know you know we couldn't
really come up with it so me and Colin
formed a little committee and um have
been working for a couple months now so
I don't know Colin do you want to tell
them about the Sops at all because Colin
developed the Sops and now we need some
other people to PE peer review we need
to do peer review yeah so it's been
super fun we just kind of been meeting
um once a week after hours just um
chatting about the need for clean
utensils in a in a social setting that
could be used time and time again and
how those things are turned over and
what that means and terms of of
disinfecting things and and how to keep
that you know really clean for the for
the user so they feel safe and they feel
like it's a you know a place that they
can go to to really use their medicine
so we've just you know we put together
some guidelines and and kind of a an
overview that we're we're working
through right now and I I think we'd
like to pass it around to other you know
other people on the panel or other just
other people in our community to get
feedback so we can develop this to uh
set policy so can help shape that moving
forward postco and how people could use
that to inform their businesses and
allow them to all operate essentially
because it's it's going to be a tough
thing to understand and I think if we
can just have dialogue now um it it
won't be as tough and we can all you
know use the information
together so um that's kind of where
we're at I mean wouldn't you say I think
we've we've got a good framework
together and I think we you know we have
uh
you know we've got a good set of people
that are that are on the panel right now
but I think you know as Deb was saying I
think we we'd love to to have
everybody's thoughts and ideas you know
kind of circulate into this document
would be
great yeah because it's actually
multistep right you got to start with
the clean surface to clean it then you
got to clean the goop off of it then you
got to uh sanitize it then you got to
disinfect it and you know then you got
to keep it safe in between use and uh
our hope is to um postco not have the
government come and say you can't do
that everyone's going to get covid and
then we can just step in and be like
well we came up we took months we did a
big survey we came up with these ideas
WE peer reviewed them through a bunch of
scientists and experts and uh you don't
need to worry so um it's been pretty fun
that's amazing that's really cool guys I
uh want to take this chance to welcome
uh Josh and Kelly who I saw just come
come into the room in a little bit ago
dragonfly Earth medicine in the house
also wanted to welcome Valerie carral
who's in the house I see her picture up
and uh Peter Peter from soil balance Pro
is back to visit with us so welcome all
of you guys uh to Hash church today here
on Sunday morning at least where I am
good morning good morning thank you for
the
invitation oh absolutely Valerie it's uh
it was so good to hear you speak the
last time you were on with Josh and
Kelly they did they were doing the demm
your series and you ended up on there I
believe and it was uh it was really
amazing I I even learned some new stuff
about you I just thought you you spoke
so authentic and so from the heart and
it was totally like hair standing up on
my arms the whole time and on the back
of my neck I was like damn like I
remember how amazing you were but then I
was reminded by how amazing you are so
uh yeah really
welcome did you have any problems pretty
inspired group here right and it's easy
to do that being with
a with a deure is pretty uh damn pure I
mean it's pretty sweet so yeah we had a
had a really nice communication with all
the communications leading up to that
there's a ton of work that's going into
this uh process I really appreciate that
um Josh and Kelly and just the immensity
of the well really that everyone's doing
right now because we're trying to uh
rise up so to speak with the limitations
that we are all facing and the
challenges and still with the Deep
connection to one another so it makes it
a a great opportunity but um bit
challenging
so yeah so I I just really appreciate
these opportunities to chat
with with my comrades and inspired folks
here
so thank you and Valerie did the fires
bring any problems to you to your
Collective no well we thought that our
North County fire burned from the
mapping but it turns out that third fire
in Santa Cruz in the last almost 50
years and it did not it did not burn we
got in sneaking in and you have to do
you have to do it get around the uh you
have to those plants need water so it's
really scorched and hot but there's safe
passage safe road in behind you know
through
properties yeah so it's you know another
good it's good fortune just again you
know it's tragedy if you
um it's tragedy if you're in the way but
nature does this and you know kind of a
I was reading that um quote by uh Dr
Martin Luther King
that's uh riots are the protests of the
unheard and you know this is what we're
see we have it in the streets and we've
we've um we're hearing Nature's Riot and
um we haven't listened so well I mean
even with we just all have to put our
ears to the ground and to each other's
heart and try to more deeply listen to
the greater needs that are surrounding
us because the world's in a riot and our
people are too because we haven't heard
and haven't listened and um it's getting
louder and hotter and yeah so but uh
yeah I was just thinking you know even
uh a thousand strikes and covid CO's
like this Nature's little biot
terrorism and um and fires and
hurricanes and tornadoes and it's nature
but it is it is profound and impactful
and I'm getting ready to host some
people again that are displaced a lot of
a lot of people in this n in in this
vicinity right now are are in deep
trouble and I know that many of you have
been faced with with this as well this
problem with facing these issues as well
in in your
communities so yeah we're going to host
some folks here and U it'll be nice to
have some new safe protected covid
protected folks in the house you know
it's a it's a crazy time the time that
we have to reimagine how to deeply
connect I mean we can deeply connect but
it's interesting right we walk around
with masks on and try to see each
other's I just I've just gotten to
saying hello to people because it's hard
to tell if someone's smiling or not and
I think I think that um we want to
connect we really do but it's not that
simple process
so anyway thanks I digressed here a bit
thanks for asking Big Love and and
respect to you on that and on that note
and that's that's the that's the the big
energy that's been going into everyone's
farm this year I think is just to bring
that self-reliance and just that to
bring that stability through your own
work and through your own community and
and realizing that you're as strong as
your community that's around you and
stuff so big Shout and the big love to
Brett from uh do do peros there in Santa
Cruz who did lose his home and uh Cruz
extracts few Farms you know that did
lose their FS Farms there's ways you can
reach out to them and help them but yeah
it's been pretty hectic it's been pretty
hectic and I love it you know like
Valerie you just said you know people
hit the streets people are hitting the
streets and I think that that's just
such an amazing term for uh you know
communing with with our community uh
when we say hit the streets and when we
say that we're out protesting we're with
Community we're we're we're with our our
our people and I think that that's more
important than ever that we reach out to
community right now that even though we
might be behind masks we have this
incredible ability to reach out to
community um and connect almost on a
deeper level so you know even though
it's through screens and we can't touch
and we are isolated physically we're
able to go deeper than I know that we've
ever gone before and the work that's
getting done through community and
through connection is astounding right
now in this industry and I just have so
much love and appreciation for all of
these amazing people that are connected
to this master plant doing the good work
for the all of humanity so thank you
Valerie for your work and everybody else
here on this panel amazing and
everything that you were doing at the
dispensary big love to everyone I saw S
I haven't seen him in a while um yeah
big love thanks for having us today
Marcus yeah so much totally welcome it's
great to see and hear you guys it's
always a pleasure and uh Peter how about
yourself bud how have you been yeah well
I'm super grateful
to be here with all you guys thank you
so much for for having me um been doing
a lot of work in the last uh couple
years since since I've been on hash
church it's been a while I think or
maybe a year since the last time around
there yeah it seems like it's been
forever since I even did one so I mean
even in this 3.0 series there's only
been nine of them it's
been yeah so been doing a lot of hemp
Consulting lately so we uh we consulted
for 160 different hemp Farmers uh in
2019 uh which was a journey man we kind
of we kind of went into large scale
industrial Agriculture and and we uh we
tried to help a lot of these guys
transition or learn how to grow
organically so chemical Farmers that had
been historically you know accustomed to
pushing a button to you know take care
of their problems were now coming into
this whole new world of of growing and
and being in integrity in a different
Consciousness with nature so it was uh
it was unbelievable to see you know how
a human being could actually get uh
reconnected to to Nature through the
experience of this plant so guys that
have been traditional chemical Farmers
to actually be like wow maybe this is
the gateway to a whole another energy or
world that uh can teach me how to become
more integrated with nature so I got to
experience
uh firsthand with hundreds of farmers so
it was it was amazing that's incredible
dude see yeah it was it was a beautiful
beautiful thing so to to see you know
some of the things that are happening
now uh the relativity of what had
happened um you know in my experience
and watching these Farmers is almost
like it's like an education that maybe
right now what we need to do is all as a
community like dragonfly was saying has
kind of come together in a more integ
integrated interdependent way where
where we're understanding that that um
taking care of our Earth right now uh
for her she's crying out to us you know
is is so important to to solve a lot of
these issues from the ground up and and
and so that's what we're doing with with
soil balance is trying to take care of
the soil because the more we we care for
our Earth in a in a considerate
compassionate way relatively speaking
everything should get a lot you know
more
balanced I love it's more balanced in I
love I love the idea of chemical Farmers
transitioning into a more sustainable
regenerative organic way and and having
Revelations about it that's that's
pretty cool right there it was far out
it was heard of the term chemical
chemical farmer before in a way being a
chemist that kind of excites me right
but
um chemical farmer just a non-organic
farmer is that what you're defining
chemical uh yeah the guys that are using
systemic fungicides and and biocides and
uh synthetic FS yeah basically so a
conventional a conventional yeah yeah
conventional what a nice word they gave
themselves though eh they yeah chemical
farming like there could actually grow
and make
chemicals everything's a
chemical is doing it making
phytochemicals I mean y let's not you
know distinguish between well we do
distinguish between a little bit because
phyto in front of chemical kind of
changes the definition of that
particular chemical at least in regards
to where it came from and so then that
gives people their belief systems right
they're like well I trust nature but I
don't trust
Dupont and Peter you said you consulted
for a couple hundred businesses how many
of them grew a crop in 2020 in other
words how many of them in N
2019 actually made a profit on growing H
that's a great question so we we again
we consulted for 160 pretty large scale
uh operations um right now uh
95% of our customers are not growing
hemp again this season and and they're
sitting on uh millions of pounds of of
biomass that they can't sell and you
know I I've thought a lot about why that
is and one of the things that that I
believe is that um you know they they
they spent so much time with the the
logistics of cultivating that they
didn't put enough focus on you know good
cultivation methodologies and practices
in taking care of their soil and so the
tpine levels inside the finished
commodity were like 0.1 0.2% tpin so
then what they were doing is they were
um taking that oil they were actually
processing it you know on an industrial
scale with ethanol and CO2 and what was
happening is those those processing
methods were were burning out that very
small amount of turpine content that was
inside of the flower so what ended up
happening in was you know people were
started to sell this this uh you know
full spectrum organic CBD isolate really
because it didn't have the the most
important compounds uh to to the
efficacy you know know full spectrum
isolate that caught my ear as
well I heard that too heard that too it
would have to be
disate and it wouldn't be full spectrum
because distillate isn't full spectrum
well here's the thing the the CBD the
CBD was going into these tines and bait
pens and and Edibles and topicals people
were using CBD um and they were
disenchanted so they're like I'm
spending 60 bucks on this CBD tinure and
I don't feel anything am I supposed to
feel something and so what ended up
happening was um my opinion was that
those tpin were not in that finished
product that was being put out to the
market on a large large scale and so the
absorption rates in the industry were
really low
because um it didn't work you know it
was working it was working I mean they
were getting it effect there was if the
tinure is made with an extract where the
tpin are retained then they're going to
have all the plantin and probably plant
pigments going to taste like but if it's
just made with isolate or you know even
distillate oh Mark you got muted well a
dist a distillate with no tpin right so
again the the flour has
0.1% tpes in it the the the the CO2 and
the ethanol goes into an extreme heat as
you guys know as processors it burns out
the small amount of tpin that are in
there and if you look at the profiles of
the treated flour there was only maybe
five or six types of Tarpin in the
profile versus like what you guys are
getting is like 20 types of tpin are
what dragonfly gets they get a broad
spectrum because they they've got that
biodiversity in there so you're already
starting out with a disadvantage then
you're burning the out and so you know
again it was advertised as this amazing
product that's going to heal people
started taking it and they didn't really
feel much and so they didn't want to
spend 60 bucks again on on a tin what
what about the idea of these farmers who
were uh conventional Farmers I'm
guessing their land was you know very
contaminated with synthetic chemicals
and then they're planting a phyto
remediative plant like hemp I wonder
what that plant would be pulling up up
into this you know into its very being
like right into its cells right into the
resin right into all of those things
because that would be uh that would be
that would that's always my kind of
worry and you know most of those most of
those chemicals degrade though you know
and they degrade and when they do uh
they're mostly degraded by like light
and and heat but also mostly degraded by
by bugs by microbes I mean a lot of
those they're just organic compounds and
they're degraded in the soil so there's
not really too many persistent compounds
that are used well there's a few and I
know the tobacco industry has one called
radium 226 because it's how Joe Strobel
one of the first hemp farmers in Canada
learned that hemp was a fighter
remediative plant because people weren't
really talking about it at least in the
small circles we knew of back then but
this tobacco Farmer Joe Strobel who got
the first license to grow hemp in Canada
in over like 75 years 1994 in Ontario he
was a tobacco farmer and Jeff K was his
partner was a lawyer they got it done
they planted this 5 acre experimental
field and I guess because of this
chemical this radioactive nucleotide
that basically gets put into the soil
they have to like test the soil every
year and at the end of the hemp crop
they tested it and it was shockingly low
lower than they'd ever seen it go down
by like some ridiculous amount I don't
know what it was but five or 10 times
and so then they had to test the hemp to
figure out what was going on and that
was actually you know that was the that
was the information that came to our
group that started that uh fighter
remediative project project in Chernobyl
growing hemp to remove radioactive
nucleotides out of the soil because it
definitely does that it does it does and
it pulls out heavy metals um it can pull
out all kinds of different uh you know
um locked up chlorinated hydrocarbons
that are ins solubilized in the soil so
um one of the things that we really
tried to do was cultivate the hemp in a
highly biologically active system where
you know the biology on thousands of
Acres was was dead it was it was
destroyed because of you know how the
compounds in in a lot of these materials
actually burns out the the biology so
what we had to do because um just to
digress a little bit what what good
biology will do is it will actually grow
on the rizosphere and it will kind of
mediate some of the absorption rates of
toxins that go into the plant believe it
or not it's a beautiful natural thing
and the correct biology can actually
attach to those hydrocarbons um
solubilize them and help them leech out
of the soil by increasing the bulk
density of the soil and and and the
paracity so that way when water comes in
a lot of those toxins are leeched out
and and purified um but that isn't the
case in a lot of these large scale
operations so we had to really um you
know do some preliminary testing you
know um we couldn't plant like in in
areas where they were doing cotton
because of glyphosate drift I mean there
were there were so many different
challenges uh that what we what we faced
and it's it's been a battle man it's
been like 14 hour days working with
these guys um and uh trying to help them
really I mean that's that's the whole
focus and right now it's it's
unfortunate that that a lot of these
farmers are not able you know good good
people people kind beautiful people that
that want to you know grow this plant
they believe in this plant they believe
it's it's it's going to help so much and
and uh they're having a hard time on on
top of all the other so so so here's a
question kind of to Mark H Dr Mark as
well as to dragonfly Earth medicine
because I hear mark saying well those
are you know I he used the term chemical
wrong and I could see that get under
your skin as a chemist and that's okay
that's okay don't worry about
it chemicals we're all chemicals it's
true but at the same time don't you
believe Mark Dr Mark that some of the
chemicals that are being put on the
scale on large scale are destroying the
soil or they do you really believe they
absolutely yeah they must be right they
not they're not destroying the soil but
what they're in doing is they're alter
they're altering the bi they're right
they're and and so it's kind of like
Mother Nature's biome will kind of adapt
to this new synthetic chemical that Dow
or dupon or whoever is making and
spraying but like like one of the things
that I noticed I mean it's really
interesting to hear you say all that
Peter because um the folks around here
well so I where I live in Pennsylvania
most of the Amish are also tobacco
farmers and so they understand growing a
crop for essentially essential oil or
for to be sold for smoking purposes so
they're able to basically grow to the
volume at which they can dry and so they
all have these tobacco barns they're
really cool looking barns they're the
sides of the Barn open like wings right
because it could air out the the air has
to exchange and so the tobacco gets
picked right around the time that hemp
gets picked actually gets picked just
prior to that gets hung up in these
Barns and I tell you man when you walk
up to the edge of these barns I'm not a
cigarette smoker I don't use tobacco any
form when you walk up next to these
barns man that air is intoxicating it is
really for a non-cigarette smoker like
whoa you're just kind of like Blown Away
by it but anyway the first year that
they really grew widespread around here
most of these Farms are on the order of
about 10 some of them are more like
around 40 to 60 to 80 acres and a lot of
them grow feed corn for uh for the dairy
industry pretty big in my area of
Pennsylvania but again they're also
growing tobacco and where they grew
tobacco they have a whole system where
they have these carts that go out and
they hang tobacco leaves on the cart and
they bring well they didn't have all
that worked out for hemp so they needed
to figure that out so last year was kind
of like a a training wheels years you
know a lot of them they didn't dry right
away some of them had issues
with bugs and some of them had issues
with some people brought dryers into the
area were able to dry him but for the
most part I think they had a pretty
successful crop when they compare it to
the return on value that they can get uh
compared to another crop so a lot of
these folks are growing ornamentals you
know for the flow markets and they're
growing uh vegetables like tomatoes and
melons cantaloupes watermelons stuff
like that yeah so um it is a different
kind of Agriculture but um to speak to
your organic thing I think a lot of
these folks grow organically and what
they're doing is they're they're bolting
on The Organic certification onto their
existing Organic certification so if you
already have an organic farm and they've
already been come out to certify it to
make sure that your processes and really
everything that touches the crop is
organic and chemical free although they
do list uh a list of chemicals that you
could use in an organic thing they just
organic chemicals but organic chemicals
you know just to finally divide it I
mean I miss organic chemical unless
we're importing feed stocks from Mars
everything comes from planet Earth so um
uh where was I going with oh that's not
true I've been to s's house and I've
seen some [ __ ] that was absolutely not
from planet
Eartha come on now bringing in some
stuff from sad Stardust right but I I
think for the most part um I would say
that what really stalled was sort of
like the the
FDA in making an exception and the fdn C
rule so they could include CBD in things
like topicals and foods and stuff like
that and so what that did is it created
all this huge glut of biomass that's on
the market and and what that did is it
made so about a year ago the price of
isolate from large manufacturers in like
Portland and Denver area that were
processing lots of H price of isolate
was on the order of about 5,000 to maybe
7,000 a kilo and that's for multiple
kilograms and they want to look for you
know big contracts so they could set up
some big Supply chains well now uh the
bottom has just crashed on that market
you can get those same kilograms now for
less than ,000 a kilogram so there's
such a supply
but there's no real pull through in the
retail you say that and then you go on
the internet and you find all of these
companies selling everything from
gummies to lotions to all this stuff
that you know is uh as you know pet was
saying is derived from hemp so a lot of
folks are putting you know either
isolate there's this
whole category now of tfree distillates
so in order for it to be farm bill legal
it has have a THC content of below um 3%
so there's a whole new how about the new
amendment that the da how about the new
Amendment the DEA just made to the
definition of of H well what what so
what they're trying to do with that
Marcus is they're trying they they're
they're trying to harmonize the controll
dangerous substance act with the farm
bill so the farm bill basically says if
it's below 3% THC attempt therefore it's
legal by the farm bill well we all know
that even if you uh purify the oil or
even if you shuck the buds from 3% plant
you're going to purify Beyond that3
certainly when you make a a crude uh
extract or a distillate or an isolate
well not the isolate but the distillate
you're going to concentrate the the THC
and so I I don't think they truly
fundamentally understood that when they
when they passed the farm bill
and so what that's come up with now is
now again there's a whole new group of
processors that are basically offering
what's called tfree remedi or distillate
remediation will take the distillate
that's got a THC higher it won't matter
though because the way that Amendment
sits is that the second your product
becomes over 3% it's now a schedule one
substance yeah you're right and so in
your in your workflow you're now now
breaking a schedule one law right right
and so no one's going to be like that's
that's a major blow
they classify something called work in
progress hemp extract and so the work in
progress hemp exract so everything
between the biomass and the diluted
tincture itself is all yeah schedule one
but they wanted to basically say look if
that's in a process
where it's not you know being sold or
not crossing state lines and it's okay
but you know it yeah it has uh created a
lot of upset in the industry and the
other thing that people were doing
markets we kind of talked a little bit
about this on the chat is um a lot of
people because of the price of CBD is
down they're converting THC over into
Delta 8 THC by michan's chemistry thank
you professor michul for pointing out
that you can just treat um CBD under
acidic conditions and in fact I think
when people were making CBD distillate
and they were adding bleaching Clays to
the CBD distillate they were when they
were distilling they were observing THC
over in the product and I think it's
because the CLE the Clays themselves are
acidic in nature and are acidic enough
to promote the um isomerization from CBD
over the THC but you get delta8 THC
almost predominantly but you do get a
little bit of Delta 9 and that's one of
the issues with the Delta 8 Supply now
and you see Delta 8 all over the place
most of that Delta 8 has Beyond 3% Delta
9 which is which is part of what is
problematic about that DEA interim final
ruling that's what they call it interim
final R final ruling did you see the
second part of
it uh well
I know that they're asking for public
comment so well before before public
comment in the definition change they
also made another change which was for
any companies that had FDA whatever the
term is compliancy or approved or
whatever which I think one company in
the world has they no longer have to
apply for import or export licenses to
move their product over the border so
that's the part that may left an even
worse taste in my mouth about the whole
thing when I saw that I was like oh man
they are like lining up the chess
board yeah Mark you you kind of brought
something up I've been thinking a lot
about I I grew I work with a 2600 Acre
Farm in up state New York that is fully
regenerative um certified organic and we
you know they they grow 30 Acres of of
hemp on rotation up there and um you
know last season you know we've been
work been asked specifically for T free
I mean this whole year it's just been T
free do you have T free um but then it
you know as I look at the Barns and I
look at the totes I just I question like
what's enough and how do we all balance
the amount that we grow versus what
someone else grows so there is Harmony
and everyone does have a a place and
then it goes back to the idea of
Appalachia and then the terar that we've
all been talking about about specific
regions only working with specific Cult
of ours you know what what are your
thoughts on on what's enough guys like I
I I think about this often you know
because it's we've learned to scale but
you know what's what's the right amount
to scale to you know so I think my
thoughts are that dragonfly Earth
medicine and permaculture and some of
the Growers that I'm talking to with
what they're doing like if we actually
have again a deep a deeper connection
and and respect and do things in
Integrity with our planet then a
permaculture setting is actually going
to produce uh the correct amount of food
that that we can sustain our populations
on I mean they've already figured it
[Laughter]
out true enough true enough oh you're
muted planet's intelligence is is just
so so so uh you know perfect it's a
sacred vessel that we just have to you
know allow to produce the amount of
tomatoes and corn and cabbage and wheat
and soy that we need to eat and and
it'll and it'll show us what what we're
supposed to to have you know what we're
supposed to receive from it way that I
go of see
it I'm I'm gonna speak I'm gonna speak
in an analogy for a second I'm gonna
speak with analogy and I've done this
before right so um I used to say that
you know THC is the deep end CBD is the
shallow end and the two ends of the pool
are connected together right and so
mother nature didn't make an exclusion
but the analogy I'd like to use for for
the tfree thing is purple paint right so
what's purple paint made of it's made of
red paint and blue paint right so uh
well in the political year we'll call
CBD blue and we'll call THC red okay so
you have to
separate the red from the blue paint
yeah you can do it by chromatography but
you get a big fraction in the Middle
where you get a lot of THC and CBD you
have to bring right back through in your
chromatography so chromatography is just
not it's a ugly process it doesn't scale
well you have to use a shitload of
solvent it's expensive it just the whole
need to make a tfree product is just
completely just ludicrous all based on
they didn't figure well if the plants
got three G when they concentrate it
it's going to be more you know
concentrated as long as it's back down
to the three in the final product that
only puts it in tinctures and lotions
and stuff like that okay so you can't
dab It Whatever at least they should be
able to make it harmonize in that way so
the work in progress hemp extract has
got to be something that they got to let
hemp processors be able to handle right
because if you're bringing in three into
the building as soon as you concentrate
it as soon as you grind it as soon as
you make an extract out of it it's over3
so the whole point of the industry is to
be able to extract and use the plant
that the farm bill has already said is
legal well they and they let that happen
they let that happen right to the point
where the industry almost destroyed
itself and it's there's no value in the
product now well and Marcus what that
tells you is how bright the intellectual
furnaces are that are burning down easy
days right I mean so well and and I
apologize to jump in but Valerie Could
you actually speak on a little bit of
your experience on the efficacy of like
natural like the the actual extract kind
of ratios of the plant uh versus this
whole kind of conversation around tfree
or separating Delta 9 so it's just
isolated pure
CBD right well yeah thank thanks Alec I
um you know I think there c a few things
here well many things on the table but
that as we look at the overproduction of
CBD and we ask ourselves well how did
that even happen it's it's obvious that
it's the marketing behind it well it's
you know it's the trending it's what
information came out and was hyped and
you know it's a little bit like you know
the conspiracy of
CBD it's the the qanon the really what
happened here it's not even really
complet true I mean what occurs in or
may be found in
some um in some titrations and in some
instances is not true across the board
and of course every single being is
unique and my findings now this is you
know it's limited right it's not uh it's
anecdotal but I work with people so
that's that's um quite a good uh
a good uh
cross-section and I find that without
the THC the tfree is essentially for the
people that with whom I've worked
essentially
ineffective um not to say that there is
no benefit for some people there's there
is but I would say it's very few it is
very few at least in our in our uh the
cross-section of our
membership and you know I think I think
the imbalance here is as the market
become as laws are written to take over
the market or control the market a
Marketplace no matter what Market that
is um the danger is in the hype or the
trending that surrounds that product and
so I mean there there's an over
production of
hemp if we look at the re uh the reasons
are many
and one is because you know perfectly
good Farmers needed to grow something to
be able to live on to to gain enough
Revenue but really CBD the the high it's
CBD is not really the answer I'm not
saying that it is not part of an answer
but it is not um the efficacy that
relates to CBD only um with
Cancers even with um our unique uh group
of of epileptic patients and especially
with
children especially with the children
that we work with um THC is a very
profound part of their of the healing
process for them or at least to sustain
Wellness to reduce seizure activity so I
mean I think that again there there are
two different topics on the table one
is farming and maintaining the
relationship of farmers to the food and
Medicine plant medicines and plant Foods
remediating yeah it it bio remediates as
well so but how and and that is not only
food for us as human beings but food for
nature the planet as well and the
balance that we bring into living and uh
feeding off this planet and nurturing it
so it's a very uh it's a it's a huge
opportunity and yet we're not working
together we're working against an an um
an umbrella or really a a a dome of um
kind of federal pirating and corporate
you know the how the corporations in how
corporations influence the laws in order
to
obtain uh complete control over um a
product and Ma the Mass delivery of that
product I would say you know that
CBD trended to be a great deal more than
it is and not not that it doesn't have
some efficacy because of course it
does um now without THC I mean we just
again that's within our group we don't
see the effectiveness I just haven't
seen it
personally I'm not talking about a
handful of people either it's quite a
big number again it is not you know
10,000 people but and and and Val can I
actually jump in on that too um yes so
you I know I know Jason David has the
exact same story as well you know with
all the PS kids that he works with um
you know they found kind of because
there was so many kind of CBD products
in the market that were just isolated
CBD you know they were having issues
with administering that to a lot of
pediatri epilepsy kids where they would
in fact have more seizures than they've
had in recent time and so ultimately I
know Jaden um his son and Jason's David
whole journey with his pediatric
epilepsy group um was kind of in diving
more into acidic cannaboids because
they're finding more consistent ability
across batches to fight uh effect and
healing than they would in just the
batch to batch kind of isolated CBDs
where they were trying to find a kind of
more whole plant kind of side of it um
but yeah I just wanted to kind of point
that out um and then and then kind of to
the fter remediation Point um you know
it's interesting because you know the
end canav system is the it's the master
homeostatic regulating system in our
body you know bringer of balance and so
I feel like it's doing that to the Earth
too where we plant it and so much of the
Cannabis and he that we're planting um
inadvertently is fter remediating the
soil and bioaccumulating all the toxins
from heavy metals and historical
agricultural compounds that are used in
the area thought to have you know
multiple day Half Lives turning out to
have you know decade half- lives when
they're in the soil in the dark
hidden under the ground because of how
much they were used in the past and so
you know just this idea of homeostasis
regulation and how kind of cannabis is
doing that to our body and in healing I
feel like it's definitely doing that to
the Earth too and so what we're when we
talk about planting hemp it's like where
are we what are we planting it for you
know is it going for drug medicines for
whole plant extracts are going to
Pediatric epilepsy kids and cancer
patients or or should it be going to
grow go grow rope for multiple years and
fight to remediate the soil um you know
and focus on that side of it you know so
that one day they can do whole plant
extracts instead of just you know
isolate CBD because anybody that's doing
isolate isolate CBD is essentially you
know in a forced position to do that
because of how much heavy metals or
pesticides are in there you know be and
that's beyond the just working to get
around the 3% you know legal limit yeah
it's the warp regulation you know like
the people that I'm working with are you
know again they're they're able to get
into the shallow end of the pool they
can't get to go down to the deep end yet
so they got to keep everything compliant
and this this latest interim ruling from
the from the DEA is just problematic in
that anybody who's taking you know
legalized hemp which was made legal from
the farm bill it says it's 3% into their
building now as Marcus points out as
soon as they're processing it it becomes
again schedule one material and that
just I think it just points out the
inconsistencies in the two and you know
what what I don't hope is that they're
given Trump an idea to throw a Hil Mary
here to save the hemp industry fact I
should have said that probably um but
you know I I I think again I I I really
I I understand what you're saying
Valerie and love to be able to use the
whole plant Spectrum if the cannabis
plant
teaches anything it teach tees us that
single ingredient medicine is just not
appropriate and not correct so I totally
agree with you and I think your your
patient
results speak volumes to to to that
point I think if you follow it back to
its route it's really quite easy and
simple to see you know oh how did CBD
get so hyped it's like well you had an
enormous amount of people who decided
they wanted to make money in an industry
like cannabis that wasn't cannabis that
didn't have t HC that somehow had
isolated through this you know narrative
that was created however many years ago
oh no this is hemp a distant relative of
cannabis well and and Mark we said
before the you know pharmaceutical
companies have us lulled into believing
whatever is wrong with you there's a
there's a pill for that and that pill
typically in the in the FDA Paradigm
contains a single active ingredient so
bethin or B or I don't even know how
they name those anymore they just seem
like to have some fictitious name that
doesn't I guess piss people off or is
politically correct but you know if you
listen to those commercials on
television it it's amazing the the C
commercials more about all the side
effects you're going to get when you
take this FDA approved drug well that's
reason
12,967 that I do not have cable
television
snip get rid of that stuff wanted to
mention that besides the problem with
low Turks and the uh bad
soils uh in
2018 less than 50,000 acres of hemp for
CBD was grown in the United States in
180,000 Acres was planted for CBD and
the CBD percentages were higher
so think about it supply and demand uh
is is a hard uh reality to
fight and and having absolutely no
infrastructure doesn't help in any way
shape or form because it's easier to do
CBD because all you have to do is put it
on a screen as opposed to actually crush
the herds actually R the hemp by water
or Biologicals Etc so unless these CBD
people invest in an infrastructure we're
stuck with it
hi welcome etan and happy belated
birthday
brother thank you buddy much love to you
all great to see
you I like that lamp ATN that's cool
never seen that Etsy it's just a
lampshade I was wondering of
course well I don't like I'd love to be
able to pick up a a CBD drink out when I
was out and about but when I look at
anything CBD on the menu it immed
mediately repels me because I'm thinking
like is it some weird Bizarro distillate
how do I know it's safe I mean I already
know it's not going to have any effect
but you know just the idea to me now it
just it's a turnoff I think that's a
marketing issue I think once the market
Narrows and we can trust the suppliers
and how the how the CBD is made maybe we
will be able to enjoy it more in the
real world assuming you can find pure
CBD there is a use for it but I can
mention what you do is you uh make a
small pipe load of
homegrown DC weed you put a little
sprinkle full of the pure CBD on top of
it and you vape it or you smoke it and
Wango Bango you get the benefits of the
THC the tpin the full spectrum and the
CBD kick in the
butt something like that is is
and what what what we ended up doing was
we um we we had um really good hemp
flour so we really grew you know
sustainable regenerative organic uh hemp
crops and so because we baby these
plants so well we actually um got really
high tpes in in the flower profile so we
were getting between 2.5 and
2.7% uh Tarpin in our hemp that's that's
great Peter what were the percentages of
CBD so we were getting well it depend on
the genetic expression so you know some
and it depend on the heterogeneous soil
so um and and the
fertilization most of our customers were
getting between 15 and 22% CBD again
contingent on the genetic capacity
before we had to pull before we hit the
aggregate weren't the majority of those
getting more than 3% THC
um yeah yeah they were whenever I see
people that had more than 15% CBD they
usually break to THC limits right yeah
that's that's that's goes to the
genetics of the plant but but so what we
did to to go to go more along your point
was because we had about you know an
average of 2.5 tpes and and uh between
20 and 25 tpine types in the profile we
extracted those so we so we extracted
the tpin from a lot of this hemp flour
and then we added it to a lot of the CBD
tines that were out there and and we had
some experiments where you know some of
our customers would give that U CBD what
we are calling right now as an isolate
to their customers um with the tpes
added and without the tpin and with a
lower amount of CBD the efficacy was
like 10x as far as the I understand and
that makes a lot of sense Peter my
question is when you did that was the
profile and the ratios in the turpin's
constant in other words from the dried
manicured flower or whatever you were
using to the finished extracted Turing
did the ratios REM remain or did you
lose some of the more volatile monot
turpins so we we processed it room
temperature so that was a big thing that
took us about six months to try and
figure out um and we captured the good
majority of them so one lb told us we
had uh more than than 30 spikes um
within the analysis um and so we kept
most of them the smell also was was the
same if you smelled the flower versus
the Turpin it was very tells you a
lot if the smell is the same that's a
good sign yeah it was the same um so
yeah when we took those tpin and we
added them to these edible and and
topical um products people were actually
feeling it they were like whoa this is
what CBD is supposed to feel like I
didn't know that this is what it was so
you still got that that full body
relaxation joyous creative all those
beautiful things that you get with this
plant aside from having the psychoactive
effect thank you for saying that so was
wondering what are we supposed to be
experiencing with CBD I mean here I am
an expert with the shop and everything I
don't even know yeah people don't know
what they're supposed to feel and again
what we're finding is you need to add
tpin at a milligram per cannabinoid
ratio so people don't even know how to
apply tpin yet in some of these products
saying oh there's Tarpin in your product
so what we have found in our testing is
that for every like um and it depends on
whether you're doing a tinure or a vape
but let's say if you're doing a tinure
that has a th000 milligrams of CBD you
want around 100 milligrams of tpes so so
that's a good ratio on a VAP pen now on
a tinure or wait might have said that
backwards on a on a Tiner you would want
like 5% because otherwise the Tarpin are
too spicy so you'd want like 50
milligrams of Tarpin inside a th000
milligrams of CBD that's kind of like a
natural ratio whereas in a in a vape pen
you'd want about a 100 milligram yeah
and I understand what you're saying
Peter because you don't really find even
bread for tpping breaking much over the
five six% tpping by dry weight content
yeah you just I mean it it can be done
but it's it's not being sold it's very
rare and it uh it's a lot of work
breeding something like that that breaks
you know
5% yeah and and and what's been nice for
us is we' started to play with our tpin
in the in the THC market and and people
are calling us back some of the vapen
companies that have that started to use
our turps and they're and they're saying
that they're high for like four hours
you know they're they're not not really
high but you know four hours later
they're still feeling the effects they
still have that that those those are H
you can also dial in the Tes so but
you're just adding the ones that offer
the specific synergestic effects with
THC or CBD whatever uh I I prefer THC
myself but uh so that if you add uh
Marine uh pining uh loline and a couple
of other ones they will not only
modulate it in particular
[Music]
way you like have the power to
potentiate TC and make it
stronger those those are hemped Peter
they're they're all hemp derived and and
we did different extractions right so
when we used the good agricultural
practices we got we got 25 tpin in the
profile maybe more sometimes in the in
in the other sides where where we
weren't really amending the soils we had
like five so what would happen is you
know what what we're starting to see is
that it's not what one tpine does on its
own um but but what they producing
combination that truly make them
efficacious so how are you I have tpin
I'm sorry how are you isolating your
hemp
tpin so we have we have a couple
different ways we've been playing with
all kinds of different uh extraction
methodologies but but we can chat about
that you know you and
I yeah he's he's got something different
Mark you gotta you got go to email I'm
sorry I didn't mean to No it's it's all
good it's interesting
though what I was gonna say Mark
is was touching on is this is Ian Valley
um and it's um 68% total Tac it's 11.7%
tcv
2.8% CBC F 5.5%
um
CBG so but at 11% tpin this thing gets
me you know where I need to go really
quickly and I really enjoy it and it's
actually more enjoyable on the rolloff
on the back end than than a you know
something in the 80s to me um and I can
go back to it time and time again
throughout the day and not feel
lethargic at all um so I think you know
to your point the modu and what Sam was
touching on you know the modulating
factors of of the tpin are really
extremely important more so than I ever
thought and ever really belied to be and
I think you know what you you've been
touching on really proves
that that's an awesome mixture Colin
that's an awesome mixture out there
there's is beautiful too it's really
there's less than 10 Turing that
potentiate cannabis there's uh maybe
twice that number that modulate the
effects and make it you know up or down
or you know those kinds of
things yeah the lemong G is a beautiful
variety I'm sure a lot of you guys have
grown it but for some reason the the in
the processing of it it really
translates in for solvent this really
well um but it's a really hard one to
work with to get volume um it really
doesn't you taking off S he's taking off
that was a cool way to do it I like that
go ahead
Colin well I just been I've been honing
in on this process Marcus as you know
and we've all been learning about this a
lot over the years and I think you know
um to fractionate you know is really
interesting to me and I think you know
to add to go back and look at the tpine
process and I don't want to touch on the
process too much because I think like
you all in this room we have our our
things we we want to you know hold to
the chest but uh man in hash in hash
church we used to talk about our [ __ ]
all the time
yeah if it's cool guys I'll talk about
it so I think that that that's what it
under vacuum I vote we Chang the names
to Hash secret Church yeah t all right
so so extracting Turpin I think there's
several different methodologies there's
the you know there's under nitrogen
under vacuum that goes into cult ws and
so on and so forth and then there's the
steam distillation and then there's even
deeper things that that are mixtures of
all these things so you know I'm really
interested in working with all those and
and putting it back as an ingredient
like you all are I I but I I question I
just want to open up the dialogue to
this what do you believe for tpin would
be the right Avenue for uh real
extraction of the cesa tpes and you know
the lot of the monotes that we
know that transform and and as they dry
how do we create these experiences
because it's a very different case
structure on my palette when I smoke
flour because it's cured turpins and
they're different types of turpins right
when we're extracting it mostly it's it
for me it's fresh material it's live and
I'm getting a very specific type of
tpine so I just I want to open up the
idea that you know what are your
thoughts on these different types of
tpin and how they can be utilized
together um to create these experiences
that are more Prof found and closer to
the relationships that we have
throughout the plant's life cycle if you
will well I found the monot Turin were
much more uh appropriate for both
modulation and especially uh uh
potentiation but uh yeah what what is
Marine is that is is that a monot turine
mark yes yes yes yes and merine is kind
of like like the way cbga is kind of
like the mother I understand exactly
avonoids merine is kind of like the
mother of all turpins so usually things
that are rich with mercine are rich with
the other monoterpenoids that merine can
easily be rearranged to and that other
one was that that
hashen uh tpine right the degradation
turpine that they find in in hash and
that that's just one of them right don't
know anybody who smoked hashen with THC
to report what it does to THC didn't
those guys I thought those at that
Italian group did
that not that I know they didn't smoke
it with pure hash well I guess the point
is is that if you're smoking if you're
smoking old hash aged hash with a lot of
crust on the outside you're probably
smoking some hashen that may be true but
that's not science that's just
speculation we could do that on well
here we like to do a mixture of Science
and speculation yeah [ __ ] yes we do
specu science here
exactly exactly [ __ ] not exactly I do
have some uh 10-year-old hash sitting
here that's pretty crusty on the outside
I could do a little experiment I guess I
remember we smoked some in pton Marcus
that was that that same stuff it
probably was did it taste like
perfume I don't remember but I was just
super lit I remember that uh walking
looking out looking out the mountains
with you it's got the craziest tur
profile that I've never like I when I
first started smoking it because I I had
a bunch of it and I broke it up in a
bunch of different ways and put it in a
bunch of different spots and I just
wanted to see how it preserved
differently but the one that seemed to
preserve the most unique just hardened
over completely and then this goo in the
middle just has this like almost Mendo
breath like perfume taste to it it's
it's insane when you exhale
it yes see you got wine and just
likees go ahead Valerie go ahead Valerie
excuse me Mark um are are any of you
working with flavonoid their antioxidant
um capabilities and the capacity for
that yeah there's 21 flavonoids found in
cannabis or 23 and uh
I was going to explore them just like we
did with Turin 25 years ago but what I
found out was that flavonoids when you
smoke them if you take them orally
they're active if you smoke them they
deactivates them and they're not
contributing to the uh subjective
effects of THC which is my interest
are they affected then by
um in extraction
like can for second just ask the
question they're not thermally
stable are they affected by
low olive oil extraction yes same way
they are yes absolutely yeah there like
Mark was about to J Mark why don't you
chime in
and so so they um so most of them are
what are called glycosides and what
glycosides are they're two portions to
the molecule there's sort of like a
turpenoid portion to the molecule and
there's kind of like a sugar portion
molecule and these things are absolutely
thermally unstable in fact I think
they're part of the components that make
distillate like orange and dark red and
like when you see some of those dark
colors in there and the one thing about
flavonoids is that they really have
what's called a a high
coefficient which means that a little
bit of the compound goes a long way in
terms of imparting color into it so what
I do know is that they are thermally
unstable so any process that applies
heat to an extract will degrade those
compounds and and I've seen we've uh
seen them in our chromatography come
after the canono and typically what that
means means is that they're really
really polar this is just on normal
phase chromatography just you know flash
chromatography on the bench and uh
there's just a mixture of of uh many
many different compounds at least we
found um
so temperature room temperature is the
key with the tpes what's that the I'm
sorry temperature yeah room temperature
processing right um with with a multip
step distillation process is is is key
to to keeping the Integrity of all of
those those little guys I agree so if
you had some sort of methodology then
that
could actually then heat from its stable
point to the vaporization of cannabis
could there be a vaporization intake
that way as opposed to a flash
heat it's interesting thought um I just
don't
think I could be wrong I don't think you
can distill them I think they thermally
degrade again when abouts when you talk
about flavonoids is a very general class
of compounds but the ones that are found
in in cannabis for the most part are
gdes and typically you can't distill
those typically so well the thing I run
into mostly is I at least in the state
I'm in with the license that I'm a part
of is um we don't have anyone that can
really test for them um on the hemp side
there's there's someone in Florida that
you can send your send your material to
but it's it's really difficult I mean to
you know I'm asking questions that no
one has the equipment to give me answers
for or with you know so it's it's really
hard it's very limited in terms of what
we can actually learn at least for me
well uh that's that's kind of true and
kind of not I mean if do you have access
to
hlc um well the labs I work with in the
state of Massachusetts only go so far
there's three labs in the total State
it's it's hard I'm you got to have an
hlc in your lab Colin you should have
one that you can just do your art R&amp;D
routine research with so you can answer
question for yourself when I get we're
in the midst of it's a big conversation
but yes it's coming it's coming it's
just it's been a slow burn for a lot of
reasons but um the common flavonoids I
do believe that there's hlc standards
for him so you can actually develop
analytical and follow up with me we can
talk about it offline if you want I I
will absolutely that would be awesome um
but Valerie brought up a good point you
know the flavenoids are really important
um in a plethora of ways and I think
they're really interesting to me it's
just it's it's cool that you brought
that up because it's something it's a
conversation I have with myself
often oh I so then there has to be a way
to um retain flavonoids
you know aside from chewing on a bud um
yeah so there has to be a way to retain
them if any of you explored that um
opportunity does does Flash freezing
help or does that destroy or
shatter no but I I think she brought up
a good point I think just what about
just room temperature juicing yeah
exactly well juicing juicing is
obviously a great way to do it it's
cumbersome and of course not available
to the majority of people I would say
right especially people who are ill who
cannot either wait to grow a
plant um so it' be good to you know
to and then of course freeze and sell
something or give it away either because
of the dangers that are associated with
that and Mark are the flavonoids water
soluble uh actually some of them are but
they won't they're not very water
soluble what they will create is an
Emulsion because there's kind of like a
carbohydrate portion of the molecule
that's water soluble but then there's a
turpenoid portion which is more
hydrocarbon like so it would create like
a soap you know it would create like an
Emulsion so kind of yes and no but um I
I think the the the other interesting
aspect about it is that as cannabis ages
you know um flavonoids are uh
antioxidants and I believe that they do
have some role in our food and our diet
to act as antioxidants right now
obviously we don't consume most of our
antioxidants in our diet by smoking them
we eat them right so um so juicing makes
a lot of sense on that level is right I
mean that's why the raw food it's
flavonoids are an important part of the
antioxidant cult personal culture
so I me it just seems sensible to figure
out a way to provide them for people who
cannot access them in the way that we
normally or so uh whether it's socially
or
medically uh what sort of juicer do you
recommend for someone to use because I
figure you probably need a little more
industrial strength you know using to
work with hemp it can destroy
conventional Machinery so I I what type
of juicer do you use Valerie and what do
you everybody recommend for the people
who are watching a
Norwalk yeah get a
Norwalk I would
agree I H norwalk's incredible it has
the is there a particular model or is it
just known as Norwalk um let's just see
I don't even know what mine is it has a
hydraulic press built into
it
whoa it's
expensive I figured so excellent
machines yeah it's the part of the whole
I think Gerson Gerson Therapy um there
Gerson also has
a and um but the Norwalk Juicer is
generally the one that's what it has a
hydraulic press and I think some of a
like a Vortex cutter something like that
that they they talk about but it's um
and then you know they're expensive so
so you there are other there are
alternatives I don't really know what is
comparable to it but they do it is
supposed to be the premium juicer what
what does a Norwalk cost on average um
it was like 500 bucks or something yeah
around there years ago you can get more
expensive ones but yeah yeah there's
$5,000 Norwalk juicers just yeah but
those are big industrial machines not as
big as you'd think well I mean they're
around a grand or so I
mean yeah I I haven't bought one for 35
or 40 years so there's there's one on
there there you'll always find one on
eBay for 500 but I don't think you're
you know you're gonna find it I think
they're probably more like a thousand to
2,000 somewhere in there and you have
there is a moneyback guarantee but yeah
if you're going to use it and uh it it's
it's a really hard good quality machine
but would be tough to find a better
one um wonder what
alternatives now what about fresh
pressing I mean we've talked too you
know we've talked about juicing but what
about pressing I'm not talking like
rosin pressing but is there a way to
cold press uh the Cannabis in a way that
would be worthy
H sure must
be
Doc I have no idea I mean I would think
yes I mean you're talking like cold
pressed olive oil like that kind of
processing yeah I mean um it's just it
it's almost it almost gets into the
rosin category right because if you're
actually you know squeezing the plant
aren't you going to like sort of like
thermally extrude the the oil I I I I
have I have no idea I I I you know can't
com if you're worried about the
temperatures Mark you could freeze it
overnight first then put it through that
machine yeah I mean I'm I'm still my
mind was stuck on our last conversation
about flavonoids I was thinking more
like along the lines of what type of
benefits do you see with flavonoids
where perhaps like a a water hash again
where you're getting a real sort of cold
extract but a particular combination of
canono flavonoids and all the other
minor components that you could get in
an extract like that versus something
where you're you know I hate a putting
heat on these tpine profiles because
heat is just heat and air uh starts
roasting the Turpin and especially the
monot turps that Sam was talking about
the most sensitive
compounds of of the fragrance profile
itself will all start oxidizing and you
it'll leave yeah when you see the
analysis of processed heavily processed
materials it's high in CES Turing low in
monot yeah I think I think that I think
that what I all that reflects really Sam
is that they did probably a solvent
recovery somewhere in their extraction
process and during that solvent recovery
they probably boiled off most volatile
turbines and what remains behind or the
yeah less
volle know what kind of uh results we
would get because we don't how many
people juice consistently fresh cannabis
so it's it's I have a measurable what's
the me we measure those benefits we're
not really looking at it so we can't
exactly measure it yet I mean juicing is
in juicing fresh cannabis is incredible
it it's remarkable so and and if I
jump sorry sorry I was I just was
getting my I'm just getting finished
getting the hair cut at Barber called
get faded um so so I had a coule I was
really on faded yeah get faded Barber
Shop pretty funny mask on bro what are
you doing man all right I just got to my
car um sorry so so on on the juicing
part um so do Dr Courtney was my first
medical doctor in California and he's in
so many ways you know the be a big boss
dude on the on the juicing you know he
really Godfather juicing all the things
and you became a really good friend of
mine before he moved to South America um
but he he towards the end there he was
really um advocating also blending you
know like deaning uh the plant and
blending you know if you have a Vitamix
or a ninja you know it's a lot more uh
accessible for the average you know kind
of patient with a plant or two in their
yard but you know very very great way
also to get the C can avonoids and I'm
sure also preserving whatever flavonoids
present in the in the material um and
and since we're on juicing I'll kind of
back off but I would love to at some
point whenever um you know kind of share
some information on the mono and Sasa
Turpin to some of the turpine kind of
dialogue that was happening a little bit
ago Dr William Courtney came to mind the
second they started talking about
juicing to me as well and uh he's uh
yeah definitely incredible and uh I
still follow him on Facebook which his
wife now runs that account and they make
posts every once in a while about their
chickens and stuff so I hope they're
doing
Welling really really brought it to the
Forefront cool temperatures are
important is the biggest problem
accessibility for for everyone becomes
the biggest problem because we don't
know what it can do obviously it has
benefits
but yeah would a wine press work guys I
mean after to to sans's point you know
some of the guys in our lab use a wine
press to squeeze out material after it's
been
decarbed um and spent just to kind of
help it along to get green wasted and
you know I think that perhaps something
it's just like a crank that just cranked
down with a big circular vat and uh
perhaps something like that would
work yeah I think of flash freezing and
then pressing because I you know
avoiding the heat but somehow trying to
save everything possible but I mean
you'd need a field of that just to get
an ounce you know
um well I you know I use my Vitamix a
lot for just because I the whole whole
plant excuse me whole plant access and
so it's thick and it was quite difficult
to
drink whole plant cannabis so my my
Growers sent me quite difficult really
so I would just put I just smoothie
though well in small amounts yeah I mean
I do that all the time so I mean I
really do I what I do normally is is um
just pour it through a
c and so you know the plant matter which
is quite difficult to digest one of the
reasons it's great to build with um is
you know just pouring it I mean I don't
know there's no science behind this I
don't know but that I really need to
ingest all that fiber M that cellulose
so
um but I think straining it seems
perfectly reasonable Le does to me and I
I use the Vitamix as well and it it
seems to work really well if I if I
don't put a lot of buds in there if I
put maybe like four or five buds in the
in the Vitamix and just blend it up um
it's real smooth and like water and it
tastes good so I like the
Vitamix with some hemp seed you know
don't strin the H Seed put little Tarin
in there maybe some some Roots some
berock root some elderberries keep
healthy oh you have the uh juice bar
going
on some apples and grapes and dates yeah
yeah apples and apples and cannabis are
great together perfect I'm a big fan of
carrot and ginger
nice be honest I love the I love Ginger
amazing the recipe
section yeah exactly everyone's got
their favorites that's for sure the next
show there's a creative cooking on in
House Church if everybody makes their
own uh you know one they like then
somebody will make a hash Church recipe
book of actually you know well that
actually brings me to something at which
I will show you guys right now so one a
gentleman hit me up not too long ago and
he said listen I've been watching you
guys on hash church since the beginning
you've totally gotten me jumped down
this Rabbit Hole super
inspired um I started you know learning
how to grow and had some failures and
then had some successes and then I
started like you know playing around
with with just crossing some plants and
he he he made a cross and he wanted to
name it hash church and so he sent me
this picture of the plant and he said
yeah this is it like it's it creates
lots of resin and the hash is really
good and it dumps in the one in the in
the 120 in the 90 bag um and so I wanted
to give a shout out to Mark who who made
this plant which was the DNA kosher DNA
genetics kosher sorbet crossed with
kanuck cookies so that is a kosher cush
crossed with a sorbet to make one parent
and then a OG Kush crossed with a Durban
Poison to make the other parent and so
this is the potentially it's going to be
called the hash church I just want to
grow it out and they got a little
Canadian there's a little Canadian thing
going on there is there I don't know I
just think it's really cool that he that
he hit us up and he he sent me right
away this is the beauty of living in
Canada right now he's like hey can I
send you like some seeds of the hash
church and some uh and some clones and
I'm like why yes you can actually uh
absolutely and so he sent me a couple
but they didn't really make it he didn't
send them very in the in the best way
and then he sent you know I have to
actually go get the the containers that
he that he sent these in because they
were so beautiful it kind of blew my
mind he was like he beef caked it up
first he just sent them in those kind of
cheap little clone you know with a
little light on it then he like made his
own PVC piping drilled holes put these
little lights with a a battery pack on
each one and then painted them up like a
tattoo artist would so best friend Farms
welcome say hello for 2 minutes while I
go get these uh clone containers and
interrupt you when I get back and show
you how ridiculous These are nice Frosty
Frosty job there buddy yeah great great
uh work on your soil biology the the
Tricom structure is unbelievable good
job on that great job how many week was
that did he hear us speak up man I hear
you all right I'm uh gonna make this a
little bit bigger and I'm GNA
show can you guys hear
me couldn't hear best friend Farms
though oh well we'll get him unmuted
kind of late there you go dude there you
go no you're not late at all I'm about
to show these sick clone um cases that
Mark made uh when he sent me the hash
Church cut and so this is one of them
all right I just got to make uh mute
your mic there there we go there we go
yeah and then this one too both kind of
looks like kind of looks like prison TS
man it looks pretty cool in my opinion I
didn't I haven't spent as much time in
prison as Sam has
but oh I was a tattoo artist for 25
years in prison in Chino
right yeah P pull them back toward you a
little bit Marcus yeah that's better to
see oh they're get my hand out of the
way there we go yeah and then the other
sides are just
uh well done well done so shout out to
Mark I've given late right Mark exactly
exactly now I was pretty impressed with
this gift I love being uh living in
Canada right now where we can send each
other clones you know it's like it's not
illegal it's just it's absolutely
incredible and amazing and I hope that
it it it spreads all over the world uh
and more importantly um I hope that
everyone that is currently in prison for
cannabis offenses uh gets let out like
yesterday uh that is uh the last
prisoners project that Steve D'Angelo
has been doing and a whole group of
people that are involved with is
definitely worth checking into and
looking into and giving support to
because while we're living in this sort
of mildly utopian uh world of cannabis
being legal on this at least small level
because I still hear plenty of people
complaining about everything that's
wrong with it I think they forget about
what it was like to have their doors
kicked in and their dog shot and then
taken off to prison but I digress um
yeah let's let those let's get those
folks out of prison who are in there for
cannabis um absolutely ridiculous
Civilized
Nation and then can't stop asking for
for more right never
never and give them jobs in the Cannabis
industry they've earned their
stripes absolutely it's uh it's sad that
there's places that actually want to
keep people from working in the Cannabis
industry that have cannabis felonies
it's like dude that is a resume if I've
never seen one absolutely I agree
100% shout out also shout out also to
Farmer and the Felon they you know um
uh Ned Dennis from canac Craft are
working on that um and they're
supporting last PR project also but
they're really trying to put the farmer
a drug war veteran on a pedestal and to
really recognize those rockers that were
earned and
uh that farmer has and usually grows
some of the best herb ever right they're
really doing remarkable work they
continue to wham's going to be having a
little a little Spotlight with them it's
really appreciated
that's awesome but it'll take a while
before it gets there not this
month yeah Gatherings have definitely
been kind of put on hold I mean no one's
really talking about it but talk about
like a major hit to people who love
getting together and enjoying cannabis
together like a respiratory illness
virus World pandemic like not only can
you not really are you're not supposed
to even gather but you can't do the very
thing that we used to do which was get
all together puff lots of cannabis and
cough in each other's faces that's just
done yeah but you know what we did you
know we used to go see live music where
bands would be on a stage and people
would be dancing and yeah the whole and
then we had a 209 20y year overnight
success story where we got deemed
essential because we actually fought
back and got our rights to be equal and
open so that was actually quite a
herculan undertaking we did in
California that now everybody else has
been able to benefit from so you know
Canabis has been deemed essential so
we're goingon to use this postco to
actually fight back harder I will say I
was in the only state that that deemed
recreational non-essential it was insane
uh it was it was insane uh I really you
I
think
Massachusetts it's it's brutal and I
think that that hindered a lot of access
who was essential well this is also this
also is why you have to work hard over
the years and still maintain and this is
where the Grassroots where we had the
support in California we've maintain 20
years of working with our
Representatives so when we called them
they we got responses this shows the
Grassroots work that still needs to be
laid in Massachusetts so that because we
saw you try to fight back but you just
didn't have the network that we had to
to rely on so take this as a note that
want to come online work within your
state local and federal because we got
our local Authority in Berkeley which
forced the state to say well if
Berkeley's going to do it then we're
gonna have to allow it in the state and
that the bay area caused the rest of the
state which caused the rest of the
nation so right we really need to take
Focus after this and really get down to
activating your people to get active
with your representatives local
state yeah no no doubt yeah it's it's
it's a totally different Beast out here
as you know it's like it's it's
different than the California Market but
I think to your point they they listen
when it's when it has to do with policy
and they are open it's just going after
it and putting it together as you're
saying I'm I'm 100% behind it I I I
think it's just important for you know
the N the whole conversation as as a
national conversation to be brought
together because it's it's time it's
it's you know it's we need to have that
conversation I think that it needs to be
put prop to the table in a real way um
but like you're saying it's it's got to
be policy
driven so
yeah so this is cool so I just left my
joint in the front of my computer and I
can feel the heat coming up from it and
you can just see how all the resin's
kind of melting into the joint now so I
kind of like activated it
you activated your joint that's John
Johnny B Tech right there joint
activation Tech joint activ I'm just
sting here smiling I'm like coming up
I'm like what's going on like my all my
res from mying in and there and I'm
like activate as much all right love the
passion love the passion for the hashen
got my got melt shirt on
today well do you do you got melt
I'm all about the Mel and st's awesome
he's always making the hash and he's
talking about the
hash shout out to Stu shout out to Iced
Earth
uh best Farms I wanted to ask you how's
uh how's how are things going in the
season how's how's Maine
going oh it's going really well uh
thanks for asking so just been super
busy out straight um harvesting
vegetables left and right and the second
depth session has just been harvesting
over the last week and into this next
week so yeah I had a great great turn
had high humidity this summer but we
fought through it with good Vigor and
health and good living soil and yeah um
going really well some of those crosses
yeah exactly some what are the some
I'm running a bunch of new gear this
year uh the gas mask of course loving
that one that's our best hash plant
period but it did really good in the
depth and second depth turn even better
I have a lot of Woodstock Pharmacy gear
going this this turn who's a local
breeder up here in
Maine so I've really promising results
on that Route 26 that I posted recently
and um very what I'm guessing is a great
pie forward or Sunday driver great pie
feno friendly super great gassy um my
favorite plant in the dep right now
though hybrid is a white haze from the
swamp boys I got three phenotypes and
they are just absolutely monstrous and
amazing stacked up super greasy white
and what I understand it to be is a lot
of the 90 95% Plus likability on the
piff side for when I kind of went back
on when I posted that's the info I got
back was what they were working with was
Heavy piff and I'm kind of new to that
one but not new to Hay so yeah that New
York City pit is a little faster
finisher I used to run that pit the New
York City piff a lot um along with the
diesel but it's that's a cool one that
that having those jeans in there is
going to be I bet the taste is going to
be in just beautiful because that stuff
is just legendary
looks like power smoke like it I don't
know how the hash will be on it although
I'm interested because the you know the
F1 Vigor to it and the formation it's
it's clustering up and knuckling up with
the with the white is insane just insane
arms if you would
like exion please enter it
now yeah I mean that that's I can't wait
to see it man and hopefully come up and
uh check it out you reach oh I love you
yeah one of the phenotypes is absolutely
Haze forward I'd love to share them with
you I think you'd be real intrigued with
those
for I I had a quick question so so hay
hay is like is tor pentalene which is
like the Jack train wreck Sage deran
cing so piff I always heard of I always
heard of piff from the East Coast I
never smell that what does that smell so
it's very sweet it's really it's like a
sweet it it it's such a int tense tpine
um sweet crunchberry with a haze in
there it's it's just it's just like this
sweet it's it's a very
unique forward Berry that in the air uh
yeah it it's
unmistakable yeah it's like it's
unmistakable it's it's why New York like
most of the people that smoke cannabis
in New York their taste for the for
cannabis is so heightened
uh because of those varieties that have
been grown in this you know
predominantly you know spread out
through the city so it's it's really an
interesting can culture there um but
that variety if you can get it get your
hands on that cut it's it's it's a fast
finishing Haze that just is just
beautiful it's it's it's
the you know I'd say it's the best way
yeah I mean it's it's like picked up on
the haze colum from what I remember back
even out of Amsterdam or New York old
school Haze and it just like especially
meeting the white in this one feno of
the three that's obviously the piff
heavy all day is just like you said so
exotically Pine Berry loud Haze type I
it's yeah it's new to me too that's why
I'm so pulled to it so yeah I can't wait
to check it out I I was you know if you
if you we have to get you the piff but
um but it's uh it's a beautiful variety
I think it's you know a lot of people
it's very coveted but it's at the same
time it's it really reminds me of the
mango Haze that guys I think that's one
I'm trying to think of like a variety
that's accessible that people have all
had it's like it's like the M mango Haze
but a more Berry in in there um it's
really interesting guys I don't know I
think that's I'm super stoked for you
because the white also doesn't really it
could go either way with the white you
know in terms of of a you know the P1
stock but it's uh
and it met really well yeah it met
really well with the white I got some
arms of it that are literally like the
size of my arm with clusters like my
fist right up it and that one's like a
more gassy Pine versus the Pino which
is that piffin know is all big white
kind of cactus looking talking like you
know 10 12 inch col is like three four
inches wide in the depth and you can't
touch it it's just totally will grease
your hands completely all out it's like
it's Haze Grease it's a really greasy
hybrid nice and yeah sounds like a just
yeah yeah yeah that's cool we got a new
a new hybrid in there that I'm looking
at for hash too though like coming onto
the indoor in back a gas mask is a
Woodstock Pharmacy gear also thing and
it's called snow drift which is the old
snow dog cross to uh Knack which is OG
KB Mac and I got this one phenotype that
it's just absolutely velvety grease snow
dog forward all day and just looks like
the hash plant like legendary type hash
Mak did it pass any of the Mac tpine
profiles on because I I did some work
with the Mac I made an F2 of it and and
used it as a mail and it it really
passed a lot of the the haze traits on
um in terms of the chine profile um it
looks like one F like did that yeah I'm
actually the tpine haze side of the map
right now nice yeah the Mac only I've
worked with it just a little bit but
it's uh it seems to throw that that
tpine in the mix like predominantly in
most of the fenos so it's it's cool it's
it's actually pretty pretty interesting
uh variety I know you can go either way
with that one I know a lot of people are
either love it or or don't like it you
know but you remember that big sir holy
the Big Sir holy weed out west that one
I that one crossed to an OG when I was
back up in Humble years ago was some of
the loudest and and friendliest like
Pleasant to smoke um rosin or bubble has
like solventless especially was just
absolutely standout favorite was the Big
Sir holy OG out west I remember with
same tpine family
too right yeah that's that's cool I've
been uh I've been doing we've been doing
some pheno hunts lately and it's it's
been fun to to see the new tpine
profiles that are happening some some
interesting like Jolly Rancher style
smells coming out um it's you get that
profile out of uh actually eth jelly
Rancher that's the name of the type this
yeah it's really it's interesting and
then um God we did wedding cake times
Mac um and that that's interesting
because it has like a wedding cake kind
of gas and then when you on the exhale
you get the m and the tarpine on the
back end which is which is which is
really nice um but yeah that's you know
I've been really really looking forward
to trying new stuff out I've been also
this lemon brulee washed uh did about 60
pounds washed 60 pounds of it and um
it's it's pretty cool it's an
interesting variety it's it's the lemon
G times Ken DEA Ken so it's it's good it
kind of brings the lemon G profile into
a better return for hash you know so for
for the guys that are looking for the
lemong G profile that don't get the
returns they're looking for off the
lemong G I'd say to take a look at that
that cross I think that's Co genetics um
that that makes those but yeah wait did
you say covid genetics yeah Co out of
Colorado oh nice I yeah know that
thought the name was I've never heard
yeah yeah um one of the guys that I
worked with at at the facility he's
friends with him and he he just you know
he showed me his work and I thought it
was pretty interesting and I know um
Jordy from the Dutch consultant agency
had run some stuff of his out you know
at will Cox and he found some success
with it so I just you know I'm not
always you know so keen on just jumping
in to try and stuff but you know it
seemed like the right parent stock to to
go after to Pho hunt with to find
something so I think they they found you
know two fenos when they ran it and then
kept the you I think they're keeping
number five or something like that I
washed number nine and number five so
we're gonna try to look at the numbers
on that
so but it's uh it's interesting you know
like feno hunting is like that black box
you know like you get in there and it's
like a little bit of light it gets
exciting and then there's like another
light flickers in the the next Corner
over there and you're like oh look at
that one
know I agree it's fun yeah yeah I love
it keepers not some some don't make the
make the cut you know we definitely saw
some you know a little bit of early mold
on a few types that had to just get cut
right out even uh
unfortunately but we had some great
resistance actually showing on I should
share the 24 karat gold cross with a
On's trop cookie that I did I A friend
gave me an F2 male Oni that trop cookie
like couple years back and I decided to
use him because he was Powerhouse
looking and colorful and man the
resistance factor and even TP meeting I
got on the uh the trop cookie meets the
you know the kosher Tangi there went
back I got a spread where one of the
largest Thro the largest yielder
actually is just watermelon papaya all
day like super super watermelon Jolly
Rancher forward
have you run the the zum zum crosses at
all the the watermelon stuff that became
the you know a lot of the stuff that
became the watermelon Skittles I guess
and all that stuff I haven't I heard
about it I was
assuming ien very watermelon esque but
that's what it reminds me of that's a
really interesting variety to R that's
the second watermelon turp I found
actually now that's I've heard of the
gear you're talking about but I haven't
tried it now I found watermelon over
three years I brought back a strawberry
fields that was crossed to a forum cut
from that I bred out west and we just
got or what was it Forum cut to yeah
Strawberry Fields and it was just all
day we called it strawberry Frost
cookies but it was watermelon forward
now this one the 24K trop cook you need
needs it's a little bit more papaya
friendly but watermelon same watermelon
turp hard to believe how similar to the
other one it is even for watermelon on
papaya like is to me like Legend it's
just like his Pinnacle that that papaya
I would always search that out and it's
just amazing it's a it's that profile is
just special it's really really
delicious to enjoyable experience to
have um I wanted since we were talking
about theer hunts I was thinking about
Sam and and you know he's probably grown
more plants than any of us in our entire
lives and I was curious to ask Sam you
know what varieties and what part of the
world where those varieties from that
really you that you've seen that produce
the right type of heads for water hash
and like is there any anything that
you've ever done that's looked at that
type of stuff you're talking about doing
it with water sifting I don't think it
matters though if it works for dry
sifting like if it's a great strain for
dry sifting I'm just trying to get Sam
to still answer your question because if
you ask him in regards to water hash
he's gonna say I'm not the best person
to ask that question to yeah you ask
them from a dry sift
standpoint yeah so from a sifting
standpoint or or an extraction
standpoint that that you prefer in
general to be honest uh afghan with
Afghan indicia WID Leaf varieties
actually uh have bigger heads of resin
and uh the plants are actually bred to
produce resin they don't care if it's on
the flowers the leaves the whatever but
you know lots of lots of resom the other
problem of course with these widely
varieties is in Afghanistan and places
like this is that they uh they're not uh
all THC because uh 25% of them are high
in THC only 25% of them are high in CBD
only and 50% of them have a blend can
avonoids so because they're breed and
selected for resin and the farmers
aren't smoking individual plants that's
happened over generations and
generations and
generations and and they would Steve
that and then just like mix them
together and then press that Sam is that
kind of how they would well what people
are mostly growing and people are seeing
mostly today are uh poly hybrids between
uh wide leaf and narrow Leaf equatorial
and uh Middle Eastern and they can find
some with really nice Turing selections
and really nice head size and lots of
heads because uh I mean if you want lots
of hash you've got to have lots of heads
that's where it starts
right right cool Sam
I all the countries that have
traditional hash like uh West
Bengal uh many places in India Thailand
Burma Vietnam Laos all those countries
they all uh had
traditional uh integrated hash I mean
excuse me ganja business and they
produced fantastic uh marijuana at the
top end of the scale
interesting that's getting for a man
that's I appreciate
that you you mind if I ask a question um
Sam uh what do you know about Alpha
pining um because uh you in in our data
what we see SC Labs is you know it's
whenever it's present or dominant in a
profile without mirene because it's
usually a tertiary tpine to mirene but
um tertiary secondary but it's rarely
like co-dominant or
dominant with without mirene being
present then we see it like less than
like three four per of the time you know
kind of actually Alpha pining dominant
and I had heard that that tpine kind of
came in through hemp lineage like do you
know anything about that or do you know
anything to no I I think uh what's found
mostly uh in hemp itself not hybrid hemp
with modern hemp that's spread for CBD
with THC varieties
uh but uh was hemp was Meine and
copyline I think those were the two big
ones right that well that's what I've
I've always seen myself but um yeah just
T pining itself is just such an
interesting Turing to me I've very
rarely seen it actually as a well pining
is one that potentiates THC but in my
mind it also makes it slightly fuzzier
so it's not really clear
potentiation but it it does potentiate
THC there's there's a paper I'll share
uh with Marcus that love shared with a
group but it's it's around pining when
together with THC helps to decrease the
negative memory impairment effects THC
as on short term and so you know yeah
super curious on that and you know I've
totally said this before you know it's
that equivalent of taking the walk
through the forest and clearing your
head I I I can't wait to read that paper
dude yeah I'll find that right
now what a joy it is to gather with you
all on the Sunday morning Sunday
afternoon Sunday evening for some of you
um uh in
particular um it's nice it's been I
don't know if it's been months or how
long it's been I think it's been
definitely some months before we sort of
chilled out and did a little hash chir
so it's it's been a bit I I appreciate
your guys' time you know coming and
hanging out and chilling and shooting
the [ __ ] during this Global pandemic but
it is a way to see people across even
that live in our own town hi Josh I
haven't seen you in a long time you grew
a long beard yes I did hi hi Barbers are
hard to get to these days I mean me too
not that you can see I dropped my
computer and my phone my uh video my
camera doesn't work I should drop it
again perhaps
I can't blame Barber all of you excuse
me Josh go
ahead just gonna say I can't blame this
on the barber though yeah no it's style
too um thanks you guys thanks for all
the insights and the communication and
the connection it's pretty pretty sweet
and especially during this time when we
are so separated that we don't become
divided too
distant yeah welcome welcome to Hash
Church dude this is been a this is great
insights in church more than I've got as
a kid I would say there's a lot of
different convers I did have my first
out of the body experience at a high
mass when I was quite young wow we'll
have to more on that on another show
Church another church I'll tell you
about one of my first out of body
experiences and it did not happen at
church well the second
didn't interesting yeah welcome
Jos hi how's it going it's going good
man we're just uh you know getting into
it here talking tpin talking flavonoids
talking
canabo just talking all about the things
that we seem to geek out on pretty big
as we get deeper and deeper down the
rabbit hole that is the Cannabis
Community
Dash
industry well thanks for inviting me to
Hash Church yeah no um I was I was
mentioning earlier to Marcus uh really
stoked to kind of have J on it's for one
it's always been a great honor to be
part of has church and I'm really really
grateful for the opportunity and and um
you know it was it was funny actually I
was just getting a haircut um at get
faded barber shop and I was I had the
hash Church YouTube up and because I was
watching and I got one of I was off and
the the guy that was cutting my hair was
actually big uping Marcus and he's a
fellow hash maker himself that's a
barber also but I just thought that was
a funny anecdote but um but yeah this is
this this has been a really trippy year
and um and on the testing side of it you
know SC labs this is this is our 10th
year testing cannabis and uh I was
really stoked for for Josh to join today
because you know we've been doing some
kind of you know bit of diving and like
investigative journalism in a bit of a
way kind of um you know just you know
with identifying Trends as they're
happening kind of in the California like
licensed testing Market you know as
certain things are popping or Trends are
happening you know where we're kind of
uh you know we're we're we're in it to
try to help identify the issue and then
overcome to help our you know people
that we work with to to overcome these
these issues that we see you know
oftentimes coming from outside cannabis
Supply chains and so so Josh actually
just authored uh a paper we we put out a
public service announcement to uh all
the all those we serve around kind of
this batch of contaminated pre-roll
cones like the pre-rolled cone papers
that there's commercial sources there's
um there's uh consumer sources you get
through head shops um and so so we saw
this this trend in um some some some you
know a trend of about five or six groups
failing for uh Organo phosphate chlorop
pyos um in Rolling roll in in um
pre-roll pre-rolls and and really
quickly we identified it was paper and
so we started we we basically dug in
kind of and did a pretty wide uh
consumer and Commercial rolling paper
and blunt wrap um kind of testing and
report and so Josh kind of was just um
you just compiled all that and and yeah
just wanted I set that up for you Josh
if you be down to share
some yeah I mean yeah Alex said it
pretty good so we we had a couple a
cluster of of of pre-rolls fail um and
and we knew that the the material that
had got into them was clean so so you
know kind of digging in like Alex said
we we we traced it back to the the cones
um and uh the the the funny thing is uh
um when when we when we went and
actually did a study of of of multi
rolling paper Brands we didn't find a
lot of that pesticide in the uh in in in
the brands that we tested so you know it
seems like it was a you know kind of
it's a batch by batch um issue but but
this this you know these failures sort
of precipitated the study we did and and
so we went and um you know kind of got
pulled out any any type of rolling paper
product we get our hands on and I think
got about 120 and you know not
surprisingly um you know paper has Trace
levels of of metals and and sometimes
Trace levels of of P pesticides um you
know all these papers come from you know
uh organic or you know uh plant-based
sources and so um it's not surprising to
find Metals in Plants um and and you
know there's not you know it wasn't it
wasn't a a story of kind of you know
rolling papers are all grossly
contaminated but we certainly did find
some instances of of really contaminated
rolling papers that you know if I was a
um you know pre-roll manufacturer for
sure I'd want to be cognizant of and if
you know and and and certainly um you
know if I was a consumer i' kind of want
to know um you know some of these but
but anyway so so um for the most part
you know rolling papers are were we're
relatively clean but um in a small
portion of the samples we found you know
hundreds of times the allowable limits
in California for um you know things
like lead um and and other heavy metals
and then and then in some of the Ring
papers we found you know enough
pesticide where I would be concerned if
I was a pre-roll manufacturer that in in
States like California I might actually
fail a compliance batch test because
just because what were the levels what
the levels of the pesticide you see um
in pesticides so it it depends on the
pesticide but you know in some in some
instances we were seeing you know seven
seven or eight times the allowable limit
in California so if you had you know in
in it seemed to be um it seemed to be
certainly the the the one product
category that was really kind of
concerning was cellulose based rolling
papers so um we only happen to have
three cellulose based rolling papers in
our sample size sample set of like 120
samples so I didn't have a really good
sample size to draw from um but and and
I can pull it up really quick here but
in in two of the three um all three of
them failed for or would have I I say
failed would have failed in California
had they been cannabis for an inhalable
cannibal cannabis product but two of the
three had hundreds of times the
allowable limit of lead um and then um
and then yeah and then some of the some
of the uh the the sort of wraps were
also kind of the other product category
that was um you know had some
significant contamination in it we
didn't see a lot of contamination in the
in the actual Rolling Papers themselves
the kind of hemp based or the fiber
based Rolling Papers certainly some you
know some Trace detections in in one or
two that were you know kind of would
approach the California acent but again
you know a rolling paper only
constitutes a small portion of you know
of thousands of ppms tens of ppms what
were the so what was the concentration
regime so the cellulose ones were around
I want to say like kind of I mean they
absolutely blew our kind of high
calibrations but it was I mean look in
exess of 50 part per million of lead you
know in the cellulose like clear roll um
type papers that you know I mean there
AR they're not super big I remember I
used to smoke those you know because it
was unique and interesting because you
could see through it when you smoke it
um but then but yeah you we saw the
chlorop pyros issue was largely kind of
you know within this commercial source
of of uh rolling paper cones pre-rolled
cones you know because it seems like
there's a few factories in the world
that make these you know from one in
check is Volo one so what was the level
of Chlor pure fos was that just like
about 10 PPM
orm no no no it was it was like you know
kind of between like three 300 part per
billion to like a part per million you
know whereas whereas about 30 part per
billion is a fail for a cannabis product
in California and so essentially people
are taking these you know these highly
contaminated con and then diluting the
pesticide with clean cannabis that then
was still kind of creating fails because
of how much you know pesticide was in
the paper you know and then yeah then
like Josh was saying besides that you
know a lot of what we were seeing then
was in the thicker ply type of you know
kind of cones or not cones sorry the um
hemp and you know tobacco kind of blunt
wrap type um type products yeah I just
pulled it up so um you know uh CER
methine was was an issue with with just
seemed like one brand of of wraps um we
had three of them and all three of them
hit for CER mithin well over the action
limit they're like yeah between two and
seven parts per million one part per
million would be the action limit in
California so I mean over I mean not not
you know I you know nothing I'd be you
know overly concerned with unless I was
a manufacturer who was trying to you
know not fail a batch test um you know
as a consumer it's not you know grossly
contaminated but yeah the cellus based
rolling papers like Alex said they were
um you know between 60 and 50 one was 60
one was 55 parts per Mill million for
lead and in California just to give you
kind of a background the action limit is
50 parts per billion so I I misspoke
they were a thousand times um they're a
thousand times over the action limit so
yeah you know based on what you're
telling me I wonder if those compounds
are actually applied to containers for
Pest Control you know a lot of that [ __ ]
coming over from China what they do is
they just
broadcast pest
pesticide XYZ over containers in in
shipping areas that again are not very
segregated on you know what's SE and
what's not but um I don't I don't know I
mean those are really really low levels
of those compounds I mean yeah you don't
want to see any of those things in in
your cannabis but when you're measuring
stuff at the at the part Pavilion level
remember this conversation Alec yeah
it's like taking a lint brush to nework
York City sidewalk you're going to find
everything man I mean you start looking
at we um looked at uh what was that uh
Backwoods right we went and took
Backwoods and found out they had Roundup
and all kinds of [ __ ] in there I mean
yeah I mean just background exposure we
live in a chemically contaminated World
Josh mean what's the likelihood that
this is actually either applied during
the paper making process or like I said
maybe more accurate applied in a pest
control kind of way that had nothing to
do with the cellulose or nothing to do
with the factory that made the well the
well the two different things the
cellulose based rolling the cellulose
rolling papers were were lead so that
that came from from kind of probably
whatever was in the the fiber you know
the cellul source that they used to
produce these or it's coming from from
you know really kind of poorly designed
um you know uh equipment you know if
people if if you know wherever these
papers are produced um if if the machine
just you know had had lead lead parts
and I mean that that happens all the
time in manufacturing it's not you know
that but what was the level of lead
again 60 parts per million that you know
that's that's a ton of lead that's a
that's a lot of lead yeah yeah yeah um
and but but with with the with the
pesticides yeah like in pesticides
weren't a huge issue like these these
three for super methine I mean that's
enough where it wasn't like you know it
didn't probably get picked up from
somewhere but yeah you're right it could
have been fumigated I don't think anyone
is applying pesticides to the papers um
you know or maybe the hemp Source but I
I you know Industrial Hemp I don't think
you know they they they they you know I
don't know I I want to make guesses but
and then we had a couple that that
tested positive for Chlor pyol but not
in the levels we saw that in in in sort
of the samples that had precipitated the
study in the first place so yeah these
you know these could have been you know
in stored in a facility that was
fumigated or um you know there's there's
lots of way these these contaminations
can can reach the product you know the
the the cellulose papers I would I would
say like yeah dude if I was you know
this this sort of a consumer uh you know
consumer safety issue and and and these
these these these particular samples
that we tested I you know I would not
want to consume certainly and I I I I
wouldn't recommend people do but you
know yeah like I said the the amount of
CPP methine even even in these blunt
wraps that that you know were were well
over the acttion limit in California um
I don't think you know by the time you
you put cannabis in it I mean I I don't
know I'm I'm not an epidemiologist but I
wouldn't personally be you know overly
concerned about this myself as a
consumer but um certainly as a
manufacturer of of pre-roll products you
know I think it's just something you
know it's something we identified as is
another you know another thing another
input that that manufacturers should be
aware of is is another example of you
know you gotta you got to check all your
inputs um you know with with the
regulations we're working with yeah and
if I may real quick on that um you so so
and just to give a little more context
you know um Public Service Announcement
Less on like public health scare but it
was more sending out to you know all the
clients that we work with in California
as a source that has been you know kind
of identified bringing in you know
failures you know of 3,000 you know
batch you know product batch you know
kind of you final finished product and
you know 3,000 pre-rolls or what have
you and so so we're kind of putting it
out more in in like an insight to help
kind of navigate and eliminate potential
fail you know and that's what we do a
lot of you know because you know because
you know across all these tests and you
know I totally understand what you're
saying Mark you know like there's such
tiny action limits but you know you you
know I would you know be be that as it
may you know we only see one to two%
fail rate across all compliance testing
you know so even as strict as these
standards are pretty [ __ ] good right
well and now cannabis is being proudly
touted as cleaner than food or cleaner
than water most it is you know right
yeah and and so and so at a different
we're held at a different level of
scrutiny and we how we able to do it we
have to be have you guys ever done any
non-cannabis testing other than these
papers like I was thinking more in terms
of like you know uh you know everyone
was concerned with the vape pen
manufacturing happening over in China
and that there could be lead and solder
and components of you guys so I take it
you're doing this metal testing by um by
ICP which again is a really
sophisticated test right I mean you have
to have the instrument and experts like
Josh to run it so it's not something
trivial like you could run other kinds
of tests so yeah and and if I may I'd
love Josh to kind of you know kind of
jump in because we're we even we got
smoke he fell off no he's right there
he's just on
mute but no but I just I just wanted to
make a point about supply chain yeah
because because what we find we find
ourselves in this position where we're
helping all those that we serve be you
know qualify their inputs Beyond
cannabis you know because cannabis is a
massive phyto remediator bioaccumulator
on its own you know but but we're also
helping them vet all these other supply
chain sources that they're going to be
adding something to cannabis whether
it's a rolling paper whether it's raw
cacao to make chocolates you know we
come to come to find out raw you know
Cacao is a phyto remediator of cadmium
and if it's grown around mountainous
regions in the world like the Andes then
then the percentage of cacao that you do
a dark chocolate the higher the chance
you're going to fail for you know a
cannabis test because of the c s of caca
you know and same thing with qualifying
essential oils you know so it's almost
like there's don't forget the wrapper
that you're wrapping that cannabis
product in you know every all the
packaging yeah everything that cannabis
is everything that the product touches
right has an analytical qu quality
component that you guys and probably
other labs too are just trying to get
their hands around yeah and and you know
like putting live resin super high
turpine Rich extracts into a jar and
having a styrofoam insert kind of at the
top that seals it down and you see the
turpine ring around it probably not a
good idea oxide from the polyethylene
plastic you know so so yeah so there's
all these sources you know but I I'll
let Josh jump in on the heavy metal side
but but you know it's it's really
fascinating because it's we're just
seeing these consume you know consumer
trends of within kind of the testing
Market you know of all these inputs that
are other than cannabis but I really see
this like glimmer of hope that you know
the the scrutiny that we're held to now
is why can't food or every other
industry qualify to these standards
especially when when Stoners are put to
it we are able to kind of make it with
you know one to two% fail rate you know
even as strict as the standards
are hey don't under underestimate what a
stoner could do with an
hlc and amen to that I always say that
food and you know like when people are
like oh cannabis shouldn't be regulated
like this I mean look at our food and
I'm like yeah it's killing you like at
an accelerated rate like the food is
killing people right now the water the
air quality and I would just add before
Josh uh says uh what he's going to say
is that these kaix containers are the
first container that I actually
saw taking into account the Tarpin
consuming the
plastic so this is like a you know I
don't know if it's PTFE or what it is
but they he had told me originally this
is basically non-consumed by tpin it's
just a thin little layer and it fits
right inside the cap you can't even see
it wow boom kayb containers pretty cool
pretty cool little containers holding
holding all Industries to a new standard
that are going to come work with
cannabis and you know I've never seen
anything that market that's brilliant
yeah Jos and I don't have too much to to
to add other than you mention the The
Vape cartridges um you know it just you
know it's it's been you know it's been a
bit of a whack-a-mole as we as we you
know at least with us in California as
we've gone through the regulations um
you know just identifying you know a lot
of things that you know people just
didn't think think about before before
anyone was kind of looking for the
contaminants so when we started doing
heavy metal testing that was one of the
um you know that was one of the sources
of contamination that popped up right
away all of a sudden you know we we
switched over to Metals testing and
there weren't a lot of labs or a lot of
customers that were that interested in
in doing Metals testing before it was
required so it came as a bit of a
surprise to everyone and as soon as you
know kind of the regulations flipped and
and and and if if you're not from
California we we sort of um implemented
our regulations in sort of a tiered
fashion and so the metals testing was
sort of the last tier um of of of
testing that was required and you know
immediately all of a sudden everyone
realized that you know the majority of
Vape cartridges on the market were
failing for lead because like you said
there the the manufacturers of the
actual cartridges were were were using
lead in in in the um in the Wicks I
believe and uh um but it was it was one
of those things that is solder too right
yeah yep and solder and that's and
that's a big source of contamination in
a lot of uh you know a lot manufacturing
things we're talking about papers
earlier that those are the type of
places where enters but but solder is
defined by a certain percentage of lead
right I I'm not an electrical person but
I think that a solder is just an alloy
of lead tin and a bunch of other stuff
so as soon as you hear solder you're
like oh yeah test that [ __ ] for lead
right and if you're making any type of
food grade food grade equipment you need
to use special lead free solder and
that's one of those one of those things
that often gets overlooked and so but
but then as soon as you know as soon as
we were doing the testing it took you
know it took a matter of weeks to to
kind of spool up these factories to
produce new cartridges using I guess a
different solder um formula and I mean
it happened over Chinese New Years and
most of these are produced in China so
there was a little bit of a a delay
because of the holiday I remember that
was that was stressful times but um you
know within a matter of weeks people
were able to get cartridges that could
pass back out on the market and um and
it just kind of goes to show that with a
lot of these testing regulations we do a
lot of testing of of organic produce you
know you're talking about kind of what's
in the food you know in in I guess with
food you have the choice of going
organic but even still um we we test a
lot of organic produce because we use
you know like lettuce or or spinach as
as as sort of blanks for some of our
tests and things like that and and we
have to purchase and we trying to get it
pesticide free um and that's really hard
to do even with Organics um because you
know just Drift from other farms and
what not um and just really hard to to
identify sources of contamination unless
you're actually doing batch testing and
it just it just falls on on on the labs
like us to um you know to help you know
help guide that conversation and push
for common sense regulation where where
testing doesn't become a burden um and
people see it as sort of you know I
guess one of the value ads of of of
purchasing um cannabis on the on the on
the regulated market is is is that you
know that there's a quality control that
goes into it you know there's testing
that goes into it and and you know as
long as we can keep doing that and not
be too burdensome um Josh Josh here's a
question I just love to ask and you're
probably one of the only people in the
world who could answer this with having
the knowledge and and experience that
you've had which is that if there are
lead components in the solder and if the
cannabis oil inside a vape cartridge
comes in contact is is there I mean I
understand chemistry at the molecular
basis but I I I don't really know is
there a sizable leeching of the lead
into the cannabis oil so now what you're
vaporizing what you're so yeah there's
lead inside the the cartridge let's just
you know get over that fact but what
you're actually vaporizing does that
actually contain lead and do you have
data to say like how long the lifetime
of an oil in a a cartridge that contains
lead should be so like maybe they could
just put an expiration date so the
longer say like a cartridge sits around
the more lead leashes into the oil till
it reaches a certain level yeah it
definitely it definitely leeches into
the oil because that's you know that's
what we're testing for for our you know
our testing and and so when when when
they were putting lead into these
cartridges you know we were that's what
where we were seeing it is in the actual
oil um and and certainly the longer they
sit the more chance there is for that
lead to leech but um lead lead isn't
super isn't going to be soluble in in
the oil very well what we saw more is
the source contamination is is sort of
how the um cartridges were produced
because that was still early early days
of producing cartridges um I think at
the time most people were still putting
them together by hand um and so you know
we would open up a cartridge and you
would see in the oil you would see like
it look like glitter like little metal
flx just from you know that whoever put
that cartridge together put used a
little too much force or you know just
bad workmanship and and sort of metal
metal was kind of flaking off into the
material so I I think in general too it
was just kind of early on in the process
and bad quality control and that that
played a l large part in it too as is it
just seemed it seemed how the the
cartridges
[Music]
were form metal Sal coating on the
surface of say your solder because a lot
of times a lot of these Metals will form
oxides because when they react with air
like uh Statue liberty is perfect
example right that green color and the
Statue liberty that's copper oxide
because the oxide is basically corroded
over the years and basically the oxide
is what's covering so you could imagine
that yeah thca and other acidic
components and cannabis oil extracts
that go inside pen cartridges could now
make a
soluble metal complex so now what's
being so what's being vaporized not
really so worried about all these metal
particulates in there I'd be more
worried about some sort of lead phca
salt that's vaporized that I'm taking
into my lungs
right and and we didn't speak we you
know we don't we don't speciate you know
the the the metals the metals and and
Mercury's a lot like that too Mercury is
and it's not one we we've seen in
cartridges but Mercury is you know very
Mercury's volatile um but Elemental
Mercury isn't isn't is toxic is is you
know is is you know it's not the toxic
species of of of mercury when compared
to things like the the organic species
of mercury so um so that that that all
those Dynamics all play a large part in
it and we don't have good data on the
vapor and we we actually just recently
um we we we got a a vaporizing a vaping
robot essentially that um where we can
now um you know vaporize these pens you
stick the pens in it it can it can it
can has a little finger that can touch
the button and so you can you can play
that goes right into the GC well yeah we
we we capture the vapor and then we then
we inject it right into the GC or the
ICP and so we we first started kind of
with the Organics but we're working
right now with with um Metals analysis
of the vapor and so that's actually
something we've been we've been working
on so maybe yeah I'd love to see you
guys back back up those findings from
what Robert strong in on degradation to
what uh croline and Benzene and all
thing I think there's a lot of hand
waving you know about some of the
degradation chemistry that happens on
dabbing you know I mean those guys got a
lot of PR out about that and there's
some studies and I wanted to try to go
reproduce that in my lab but you need
one of those cigarette smoking machines
which I just don't have so you know yeah
as soon as I mean we're doing it to to
to share the results so you know we
we'll let you know what we find out but
that's that's that's actually our next
project right now so
yeah yeah I think that the funny I want
say the funny thing but the ironic thing
is that again people I think I mean
people love vape pens they just love the
convenience of it and everything and
when covid kind of came around it was
also one of those things where the whole
communal aspect of cannabis use you know
of passing a joint was just not
happening anymore everyone was doing
their own personal vaporized of their
own personal thing and so again I get
asked questions about this all the time
you know what about
all these pen parts from China you know
are they made in factories full of
people with covid you know and uh you
know another uh question I'm asked all
the time that I don't know if you guys
have any experience with but can plant
material be a a a vector for for virus
virus transfer you know like if people
are sick in a grow you know can they
contaminate plant material so that that
plant material is dangerous in a CO as
far as I know that doesn't happen
Okay and the virus on surfaces I don't
think there's any proof that it lasted
longer than a few
days yeah I mean I think that it's
pretty well known I think the way that
people get this is by breathing the air
that other people are breathing who
contaminated or or touching it with
their hands and then rubbing their
faces one thing I can tell you those
outdoor cannabis would would have much
less chance of transmitting Co without
the UV exposure so it's another plug for
outdoor
cannabis and and so so this would be a
great great group to ask this like I I I
hope I I saw some paper or somebody post
something um I didn't look into but I
thought it was even just a like you know
some fake news or something but smoking
cannabis had some effect in minimizing
covid exposure is that totally BS oh
there's a couple studies there's people
who are really thinking their teeth in
there's a group up in British Columbia
by Marcus that uh published that it uh
CBD does seem to inhibit the enzyme that
required for covid to take hold in the
body that's just sort of like a Layman's
way of describing it but there's a
couple groups that yeah are now showing
it's interesting on last has church when
we had it last time and the very same
question was asked there was a a YouTube
published by an Israeli guy who had no
um data whatsoever to say that it's
effective to treat or prevent covid uh
but since then there's been a lot of
people a lot of people looking at
it the alternative cannaboids as well
CBG and CBD too as
well shout out to arjent from Strain
Hunters he's rocking some covid-19 right
now he's been I think he's in day N9 or
10 he's been doing updates on his
Instagram doing the sort of healthy walk
in the forest in the morning stay away
from people but saying he's getting real
tired and I guess yesterday it said that
he kind of had a turn for the worst and
was feeling pretty bad so send Positive
Vibes to arjin yeah the the famous
grower Rob Carney who is from Crest Deb
Colorado who's known for the puck and
known for hashplant and some a few other
things he he uh successfully uh knock on
wood uh had covid and was successfully
treated he was on the respirator a lot
of us thought we were we never never
going to see him again but he pulled
through unfortunately I'm starting to
learn of more more people that I know
that didn't weren't so
lucky well we'll wish them the best and
anyone else I I haven't your mask I
haven't really met a ton of people or
know a ton of people that are cannabis
you know daily
inhalers that have gotten it I've I've
I've only heard of maybe a few and the
ones that did didn't seem to have very
bad uh
symptoms maybe there's something to that
I don't know I just someone asked me I
think it was Mark Mark McCoy actually
from VP tech asked me and I had to think
about it and was like no come to think
about it
no guess I'll ask that question to all
you do you guys know any daily inhalers
that have been negatively affected by
covid-19 no other than
Rob
no Mark McCoy pick up Mark mcco the
people I I know a guy who passed but he
was already he already had COPD so he
already had lung
issues um I guess was more suscep to
it time for a
dab almost done got about 14 minutes
left thank you all again for coming and
in the last 20 years I've only gotten
the flu once or twice for a day or two
at the most and I I my wife always said
it was because I smoke so
much for sure it is there's no doubt
about it I can't believe you didn't get
the plague when we were all in Barcelona
together every single person in that
apartment but you got the
plague well even even I didn't feel
great for about one day dude did your
wife not end up in the hospital with
that yes and you seemed like you wanted
to go to the hospital oh my God I was so
sick man and that went on for weeks when
I got home I've never felt anything like
it it was beyond
horrible that that to many people too
close and the ultimate is sharing
pipes I know I think I got it at that
huge party at that Palace that advanced
nutrients through I'm not sure if you
went there but um no I I went there with
you oh yeah of course you did we were
there okay so that's that's where I
think I picked it up we saw his
mess fairly early in the evening that is
correct we did did that's true we did
that was a huge Palace though I'll tell
you what that was uh yeah he knows how
to waste money oh my
God
geez I guess if you got it I don't know
not really [ __ ]
that go to the Palace get the plague
there's a there's a story in there for
you if you didn't catch it don't be
hypnotized by great wealth it's going to
lead you to early
death but you'll be buried well yeah
you'll be buried so
well so beautiful still naked but golden
caskets for
everyone gem encrusted that what a waste
right feeding people that are starving
that would be a good start I mean I
don't know like no donate your body to
science so we you dude I have been
donating my body to science for like the
last 48 years I feel why let it end at
your death yeah exactly it's been my
whole
life I I think you know C cannabis has
never been more important in this time
of Co right couldn't agree more right
yeah I feel like it's on its way from
you know I mean just in such like just
like miraculous like serendipitous
timing just shifting from Felony to
public Central service you know in this
time of Co I mean everybody would have
just been wiped out you know that's been
work you know just working to you know
build and uh you know and so I can't
help but to feel you know through this
time of Co and as the economic impact
really is felt nationally you know I
feel like it's cannabis and hemp is
going to be quickly progress to
strategic National Global resource you
know in in a huge way and and
I'm sorry said homegrown people going to
grow more people going to grow a lot
more cannabis now I believe there's
going to be a lot more growing at home
and around the world it's GNA be a
beautiful thing yeah and I and I feel
like the apocalypse is a beautiful thing
it's not you know everybody's freaking
out that the you know everybody's
freaking out like we're in the
apocalypse like it's all hell you know
kind of you know doom day fire and
although we're in a deep state of
suffering in this earth and just
everything that's happening and the
amount of immense human suffering is is
over
I just I can't help but feel you know
the root the root of the word apocalypse
means the time of Revelation or the
great unveiling and [ __ ] it seems like
we're in that time you know just the
faith and institutions faith and all
trust you know all gurus everything
everybody's a per everybody you know all
this stuff you know is happening and and
and and and as a result you know I feel
like you know in this time of Revelation
I feel like cannabis and Hamp are almost
the leading Horsemen of this apocalypse
you know and and you know the the more
we can Embrace and engage the plant the
more we can help it can help give us the
tools you know to alleviate suffering
and to lead in this time this new time
of Revelation and and this shifting of
times and and then you know leading the
and then you know leading the charge for
all the other plant superheroes that are
you know the other horsemen yeah well
said Alec for sure I I'm in full
agreeance I love the shift that's been
happening slowly but surely with
mainstream and alcohol consumption and
you know people are understanding now
that alcohol consumption during these
times as well as really any times it's
just not noticeable people become
hypnotized by it particularly people who
are abusing it on a high level they
don't realize how foggy they're getting
they don't realize how many how they're
just vibing at a lower frequency how it
just brings them down and creates
depression and it's not the party that
it seems to be and you can see so many
people in you know in quarantine like
for five six months and drinking more
and getting into fights and beaten wives
and beaten kids and slowly but surely I
see this this shift where people are
like acknowledging this this drug and
what it does and how it'll take
everything from you if you allow it and
that it's you know potentially based on
the amount of death deaths yeah based on
the amount of deaths annually that it
produces it's probably one of the most
dangerous drugs on the planet it's it's
incredible how mainstream it is so now
people shifting into maybe I'll try some
cannabis and not only like unraveling
the lie that is alcohol but now
unraveling the lie that is cannabis and
realizing in this shift wow like I've
had enough of that and I'm look for
looking forward to a little bit more of
this hey I hate to be the voice of
dissension but I just started drinking
and I actually think it's quite an
interesting drug um you know I'm I
practice makes perfect I'm not good at
it or anything but um yeah I really
haven't ever been a drinker the
difference between a drug and a medicine
is dose right or or poison medicine
intention yeah alcohol is not a medicine
alcohol is a
solent yeah you know what I mostly get
my um views on it from growing up in an
incubator of alcoholism in my city and
the way people abused it and that you
know my mother working at 911 and me
asking her hey what percentage of calls
are 911 related and her saying oh you
know probably between like 80 and 85 and
my sister chiming in going come on Mom
it's got to be 90 because she also works
there and I'm thinking like wow like 80
to 90% of the calls that go into the
police or alcohol related like that is a
huge like serious tear on the social
fabric like the cost of that alone and
then I start thinking it must be the
equivalent at the hospitals like there
must be such a huge percentage of people
that are ending up at the H hospitals
through whether you know car accidents
because people are drunk or fights or
this that and the other thing and it
just sort of started to blow my mind at
the cost of this this particular drug
that just seems to cause so much pain
and anguish and I think from an
extractor perspective I think of like
yeah like Mark said it's a solvent what
it does is it extracts the essence of
things and you can see people who have
abused it over the course of 30 or 40
years have had their Essence extracted
you know it just won't take that
medicine from the from the plant it's
seems to do it from people too at least
from my limited perspective I don't feel
that way about people who seem to have a
relationship with it where they can
actually just drink a glass of it and
have quite an enjoyment uh it's more the
people that seem to be out of control
from it that just uh they they tend to
fall into the hook where they hang out
with people who can enjoy alcohol
without having a problem and then there
you know it doesn't work out that way
for them but that's just my perspective
it used to medicine you know uh so did
tobacco I mean there was a relationship
to it that that I think the problems are
endemic so they're social as well
cultural they're and and deeply um
emotional so those are the the deeper
issues where we blame the drug and we
name we name and blame the drug because
I'm sort of like um feel like
that's what is some drugs are bad you
know um
and it seems like the the immunity
defense though it goes down so far with
alcohol use that besides the addictive
Tendencies and the social repercussion
that just personally just my opinion but
it seems like watching now this day more
than ever people got to keep their
immune defense high and alcohol I know
if I ever had more than one I haven't
drank for you know 15 16 months straight
just quit over a year ago but I know
back then even it would it would lower
my immunity and I wouldn't even feel
whole I wouldn't feel you know healthier
well even if I was living well otherwise
so I just feel like it it's the immunity
defense hit that it takes that's too
much risk these days you know so you
guys are trying to talk me out of
drinking
huh yeah I think I no you know what
actually I'm gonna just I I I want to
say that I think we we um we blame the
drug there's you know walking in the
smoke and being living in it now it's
takes an immune hit and not disagreeing
with you that our bodies do react to uh
negative um input dark it's a dark has
dark qualities but really the it doesn't
it's we that possess the dark qualities
and then we understood uh you know that
we we engage them and instead you know
our our we're not attending the Church
of of Consciousness enough you know of
awareness of communicating that between
and with one another listen listening
listening to One Another because we
always have something to say like I'm
saying something right now myself but
I'm but I just mean I think we we have
um we have an opportunity to take to to
uh dismiss the blame around the the
items and put it more directly where
sorry about my phone here
um to place it more take personal
responsibility to uh
address our frailties as as human beings
and and uh to to recognize the fraes in
one another Without Blame or judgment
and which super hard to do I'm not
saying I don't judge I'm a big judger
then you know I I think my you know have
I have a big ego and I you know I'm
trying to tame it maybe by the time I
really am a 100 it'll be a little more
under control but I'm not I'm just
saying so I found it was kind of
surprising to me that wow I'm like this
alcohol
is this is interesting but you know it's
not um I really think one of the most
important things that this isolation or
this period of isolation for me is the
the uh way that I'm absolutely stuck
with myself you know it's just so
obvious to be with me that um there it's
everything is magnified it's bigger it's
oh I'm the only one in the room what the
hell what the hell's going on started
drinking you started drinking during
this covid shutdown thing and well I
mean wait I started drinking I don't as
matter of fact I'm drunk now it's why I
don't have my that's why I dropped my
computer no I'm just saying I I never
really have been a drinker and um so
actually yeah I I was more speaking less
I was more speaking to alcohol having
been a medicine and that we take things
to a place where we devalue them and
while I didn't say that um I think
that's true that we put it uh we put the
a
spin on the things around us when really
it's our spin it's what's happening
within us that leads us to become
abusive to others and abuse ourselves
and if we're abusing ourselves and our
bodies Our temples this magical
Exquisite 50 trillion cell
piece of magnificence and and miraculous
or magical manifestation then yeah then
we take that to others so I don't I'm
just saying it's not the
alcohol I think I think it's tough to
divorce alcohol from all the baggage
though that comes along with it and so
I'm just glad that now you know with
cannabis and like Alex said maybe some
other plant medicines we're we're having
other options because from my
perspective alcohol is one of the
heaviest heaviest drugs out there and
I've tried most of them and uh yeah and
for it to be kind of the only option we
had for so long um that seem like a Wise
Wise Choice because there is a lot of
bers that comes with it um you know
maybe if you could take that all away
and experience it like you're
experiencing it um kind of for the first
time then and you could do it without
all that stuff I I could see where maybe
maybe there would be some some benefit
to alcohol but right yeah drugs there
speed there's you know there go ahead
well anyway go ahead well well and and
you yeah that you're Tri to the queen
you're also like one of the highest
level like wizard like Jedi I know in my
life that has worked with medicines of
all sorts and types and so you know
you're Al you are also coming to it with
a very you know uh realized you know
aware perspective and and you know yeah
you to you know kind of on that botney
of Desire level you know kind of how
much these certain plants that built
Empires and kind of industry and how
much human suffering and and and
violence and just destruction and just
yeah all that that it led to you know I
feel like you know again though it's
like that's you know I feel like the
that's where these other plants are
coming in and all the work that you've
done and we are doing with cannabis and
helping to raise this vibration to 420
because we're not because now that like
you know we because we are know we know
this plant and we have this love and
reverence for this plant and the work
we're doing with it is now helping to
spiritually forklift so many of our
friends and family that are in these
states of pure abuse and suffering and
use of you know alcohol as the only
medicine or in their case pure poison to
to to further destroy their life whereas
kind of we know these other plants are
available to expand our repertoire you
know in our medicine portfolio because
it's like poisons and medicines and it's
like what do you choose to invive in and
you know kind of cannabis you know where
we see this benefit we bringing this
benefit out to the world and you know I
feel like we're we need to be the the
spiritual and psychedelic astronauts
that we are to continue that you know
kind of leveling up to 720 and Beyond
you know to help bring these other
medicines that are so needed in this
level this moment of suffering you know
like iasa peyote all these you know
indigenous rights of Passage and
traditions that are you know
purposefully supposed their their
purpose is to help heal and alleviate
the trauma and suffering of the past and
your ancestry and and so it's like
alcohol is not going to do that but you
know starting to work with other plants
you know can get you to a point I in in
life where you can you know kind of not
over leverage one plant or poison Ally
that you have in your life over another
but but to to to really just have
reverence for the plants and for the
what you put in your body and yeah that
in fact your body is the temple yeah
that's the reverence point and and
actually it's quite interesting because
um ex I've not many times and learned
this really from uh primarily time at
repeated um that people with neuropathic
pain it's it's extremely difficult
to uh minimize neuropathic pain it's
quite difficult and and it's hard to to
get ahead of it um without being really
drugged and some very interesting pieces
of information whereby uh delivered to
me uh through patients who are allergic
to opiates which uh you know can
complicate the problem because you can
often use cannabis with other drugs to
uh step away from the pain and then once
you're out of the suff the sufferings
out of the pain you can deal with the
pain but the suffering is what
overwhelms and many folks have told me
that applying or adding a small amount
of alcohol really helps to uh minimize
that so you know when you Le I I think
what we villainize the things around us
and not I mean I've known a lot of
drunks that have driven me crazy as
matter of fact I had to ask somebody to
leave this place because you know really
couldn't the behavior surrounding
alcohol abuse was you know too much for
for me so so whatever that's I it's the
way that we you know it's just a
personal responsibility and and you know
whether or not people can manage to look
at ourselves that's it's not no small
task right so and um and I like to play
I don't know if it's the dev Devil's
Advocate but I I like to stand on this
side where no you know where nobody's
standing because I think I do think
alcohol has value and I've seen it work
and have recommended it to people like
have you tried to drink you know because
pain is so um pervasive and minimizes
life it minim s suffering takes the joy
the pleasure out of life and you it is
so difficult to use pain to transcend as
a Transcendent tool it can be and I've
had the experience twice in my life once
with cannabis and pain and once with an
extreme amount of pain to be able to
only twice and I'm old and had a lot of
pain you know so like um I I feel like
only two times could I ride the pain to
another expression or experience now um
neither of those was with alcohol to be
honest this is more of a new trend so um
and um I just think that we we have a
tendency to I do I don't know whatever
what y'all are doing but I do I have a
tendency to look at the object and
whether it's the object of Desire or
repulsion it's still the object and it's
not really the it's not really the point
right it's not really the point is it so
well said Valerie absolutely agree with
all that you said there and I just
happen to sit on the other side of the
fence where I'm I'm more like like you
know I see I see Christianity going into
every culture and just and ripping out
their plant sacraments and replacing it
with their plant their Sacrament wine
the blood of Christ alcohol and I see
what alcohol seems to have done to
indigenous populations around the world
and I just have such a hard time
accepting it as you know I'm not saying
get rid of alcohol Forever by any means
I just think that it's so pervasive and
it's so promoted and people seem to not
even know how to gather without having
it around and become so dependent on and
it causes so much pain that uh I don't
know how to remove that I mean I get
that there's root causes of everyone's
pain is in rooted in trauma that they've
had probably as a child and of course if
we all looked inside of one another etc
etc I get all that but at the same time
I think maybe life would just be a
little bit better if that [ __ ] wasn't
available on every single Street Corner
in every single City it's just so
pervasive yeah a tool of Oppression for
sure alcohol is part of Canadian culture
right I mean you know uh during provis
here in the US a lot of booze came in
from Canada so there was a supply chain
that was created and the thing that
always bothers me especially when they
make the comparison to our industry
cannabis yeah is how double standard it
is like with advertising and everything
and how alcohol consumption is glorified
around
sporting uh things and just the whole
alcohol culture and alcohol mentality of
consumption and um and the behavior that
supposedly hey if I drink a Coors Light
I'm G to have all these Scandal clad
women around the pool with me and oh
that's cool yet you know cannabis can't
even get you know a commercial during
the Super Bowl I mean it's it's well
wait a minute when when it does it will
have the scantily Cloud women that's
what's already
happening that's not far we that's I
still if you looked at acreage acreage
did have a a commercial that they paid a
big Ad Agency all ready to sort of pitch
to to do Super Bowl advertising and they
were shot down by the network but the
point is is that yeah we the there's
such an unfair landscape
in between the glorification of alcohol
[Music]
consumption and what they've done to
demonize cannabis consumption and I
think there to me I'm Marcus I don't
know if this is the way you feel again
being Canadian I mean I I I I just feel
that man there's too much alcohol you we
don't need more people drinking alcohol
I love a craft beer and I certainly love
my single Mal Scotch but I I you know
what I'll abstain from alcohol use if it
means making cannabis use fully legal
and accessible to everybody well I'm
certainly not a prohibitionist and I
certainly wasn't saying prohibit alcohol
I was just saying don't make it
available on every single street corner
like everywhere just like booze booze
booze don't let like like it seems to
have a ve a fairly low ld50 number and
yet it just is in everyone's house
without being protected it's just like
there's oh there's little babies and
little toddlers and oh I've got enough
alcohol here to kill like five children
an ld50 Mark right yeah well that's what
I'm saying well it is it is one of the
Matrix tools you know I mean just like
the amount of I mean you know to me
what's just soed is just this like Cy of
almost just drone that happens from the
food system poisoning us the Reliance on
the Pharmaceuticals that then drawn us
out further and then it turns out that b
are owned by the same people you know
making the poisons that are liate
killing our microbiome and then you know
kind of Bayer selling the you know
Pharmaceuticals to make us better and
then you know and then the recreational
drug of choice is then tobacco with you
know as well as alcohol and tobacco you
know the way tobacco is used is one of
the greatest crimes against humanity you
know they call it the red man's curse
you know and and is it's taken this one
of the greatest most prayed upon
sacraments and herbs to to use in a
specific way to pray
and to amplify your prayer out into the
universe and we took it and we
completely raped it sprayed it with all
the poisons and chemicals you know of
World War II and kind of death and
pesticides and poison and created an
industry around smoking as you stress on
life and taking smoke breaks and amplify
and you're you're not you don't use the
tobacco in the way that it's supposed to
be used you use it in a way to amplify
the destructive power of tobacco of your
body and and so it's like you know
between
the the way tobacco and alcohol have
been fetishized you know for for you
know kind of as as as the alleviators of
stress and and the tools for us to you
know chill out after a hard day at work
you know I think those combined with the
food system that's poisoned is just one
of the greatest crimes against humanity
and this Matrix out drone drones that's
led to kind of so much in suffering and
and that's where yeah I feel like and I
agree with you Marcus you know cannabis
you know I mean in so many ways it's
like it's you know it's the yeah leveler
up in that way and I feel like bringing
up the frequency and the vibration and
and the level of suffering and healing
and so you know bring it down and then
it brings way for the other plants but
it's yeah it's it's it's a trip because
you tobacco same way it's been used in
such a profoundly um dishonest or not or
dis disrespectful way and and and way
that you know I mean tobacco hasn't
killed kind of the people in the way I
mean the way it's used in Pape in Brazil
the tobacco snuffs that's used the the
wayi mapacho and and North North
American South American you know
indigenous tradition it's like very very
different
plant I think that that it won't be too
long before we see cannabis advertised
in the way that both well tobacco less
of course now but alcohol the way that
it's it's advertised and the kind of um
relationship that's created by um a
corporate
infrastructure that supports this a
specific typee of advertising it's to
reach as many people to sell as much
product and so as long as we I think uh
as long as we are not um self-reflective
and not looking at not
uh productizing marketing um the what is
it that we're selling so I mean I think
that that's obviously that's what
happened with uh with alcohol and I mean
I I don't know I don't smoke cigarettes
but you know I smoke pot and um so I I I
I mean I just think that
we I'm not going to say that I haven't
known some bad drunks because I
certainly have and um never seem to try
it does that doesn't seem so attractive
to me I've uh but
I but I really question the way that we
look at the world around us and the way
that we um engage with with the the
things that we do I a wee but me you
know the way I do way I look at myself
and what I buy and how how it is sold to
me and and I see I see cannabis as very
paralleling alcohol and um very soon you
know the next big uh what is it that you
what game were we just played what game
was supposed to have been played that
that this was it the Super Bowl is that
what you were saying Mark Super Bowl
yeah
yeah Super Bowl sorry I'm not a sports
guy but
um you know it's just it's just we we
have take responsibility we also have to
call out responsibility on on the
marketing the way that cannabis is being
um um marketed and the way it's being
absconded and and the Viewpoint you know
I mean if you open a magazine and look
at cannabis the way it's sold is very
much the way that Al is sold and that's
so you know kind of getting less and
less I mean we're seeing different kinds
of marketing occurring but but you know
I guess the question is really what do
we want to sell and what do we want to
buy and um who do we buy it from you
know that's my I have a much bigger um
uh you know I want to make am I want to
Prohibition for Amazon you know to me
one of the dark that's the dark side
it's not what you drink
it's where does it come from who makes
it how do they make it who suffers
because of
it what is the service that's being done
are we serving ourselves our planet the
people that we work with are we serving
what what do we serve and um and the
people that and who do we serve so right
now we a lot of us serve Amazon and we
serve a very dark Mission and just save
I don't know a buck or5 dollars or a
thousand or whatever so and there are
other ways do it and all of it is linked
and you guys are right I mean I'm not
going to I'm going to bust out my bottle
in a second now that's why you can't see
me I I'm totally kidding um so I I just
think those there are so many really big
questions and it's all linked it's all
linked to just everything with it's the
micro rizone we're talking about it
right here but what and what how does
that extend to every single thing that
we take in that we everything that we do
our actions
every puff we take every breath we
breathe every word we speak you know
does it improve upon the silence does um
so yeah my alcohol
rrap appreciate it um really appreciate
the conversation completely today uh on
every level we talked about some good
things got me excited to be here for
another episode of hash church we did go
over a little bit only 16 minutes I just
want wanted to do it till noon today but
uh everyone that came everyone that's
here Mr skunkman Sam and Johnny B and
best friend Farms Brian and Josh and
Alec from SC labs and Valerie carral
thank you all so much also saying thanks
to Colin and etan and Peter and Debbie
and the dragonfly Earth medicine and
Som I can't believe I remembered all
that that was pretty good actually um
thank you all for coming and sharing in
the in the topic that we all love so
much about the plant and the resins that
we all love so much and even expanding
into other things I know that the people
watching today definitely enjoyed the
show I've been keeping my eye on the
chat all day I think we had three or 400
people in there for most of the of the
time so I hope to do another one soon
and in the
meantime just keep being you be safe be
well and uh May the full melt bless your
bowls sooner if not then later thank you
for the invitation
marus you so much