okay welcome everybody hash
Church 3.0 episode 21 so I will be oh
andan is in the room welcome both to
Wade
andan hope you guys are doing well good
morgan so far so
good excellent I just got to go share
the channel in my YouTube the new link
that just went up so give me a few
seconds to do
that you seeing some nice Spring weather
down in the Bay Area at
10 so far so good yeah I mean well you
know it's a typical between 50s to 70s
you know but uh you can definitely see
the uh flowers on the trees as well as
the grasses are growing so signs of
spring are here and
uh yeah at night you know Orion starting
to pass out here and we can see you know
Mars still pretty clearly so um yeah
it's been we've been pretty lucky all in
all true that yes oh but up there you
could definitely be seeing it warming up
yes oh yeah um some of the plum trees
have bloomed out um number of the other
food trees are blooming not blooming
they're budding um the daffodils and the
early spring flowers are
popping uh lots of color coming back to
the landscape which is one the beauties
of
spring yeah it's happening we've had
about three or four days in a row of
warm days cool nights and uh yeah snow
has melted and yeah like that he good
morning good
morning Josh and
Kelly oh he's muted himself
hi
Josh
headphones what's up you're muted
Josh can hear you
hippie feel like there's someone we
can't see no one two three four oh
there's three people entered the waiting
room well I better let those people in
admit admit
admit they would probably appreciate
coming in so welcome to uh dragonfly
Earth medicine Josh is in the house
colins's just popping in Johnny [ __ ]
B is here of course and uh skunkman Sam
a man who really shouldn't need an
introduction but there's a little one
anyway we stretching our necks out guys
is that what's going on yeah stretching
my neck how are you I my neck's been
acting a little weird the last six hours
so don't know why
Ruthie in the house hey guys how's it
going it's going good man how about you
going good man dude you're making me
miss my regenerative hat I I for the
last nine months I'm like I got a mail
mail him the new one and I just have not
done it what did I do with my old one
I'll mail you a new one I just I just
got to get my act together somehow I'm
mailing all the time but I just can't
remember what happened to my old one I
wore that hat every day like until it
was it's kind of a hat I I have like six
of them that I rotate through oh yeah I
use a lot of these ones you know the
Embark ones but yeah this method seven
one's kind of nice it's little and I
just wear what I have but I do I I I
missed the one and I can't remember who
sent it to me I I feel like it might
have been
like I had the uh compost one that
looked like Compton and that was dope
yeah that was a dope one too and then
you you hooked me up with regenerative
right after that those were my two
favorite hats so welcome to the room
everybody [ __ ] where's
Sky where's Sky now we hear him he's
turned his camera off and he's talking
in the
background yeah that was pretty
funny
Sky
Stella
[Music]
Stella nice easy chill morning here in
hash church we got a bunch of folks in
the room right now I don't know how many
there are but I'm sure there's a few I
can't seem to
uh see the numbers here like I usually
do oh there we
go there we go awesome well I hope
everyone's doing well today at the end
of another week I just spent five days
up in Whistler myself so I feel
very regenerative in fact that that's my
regeneration you know humans need uh
regeneration as well you know to
maintain
sustainability plants and humans are
very similar in that way did you come
out of your
Chrysalis popped right out it's spring
spring is in the air and for those of
you that don't know that is my time I
have a birthday coming up here in like
like three days or something I'll be 48
years old March 31st that's my spring
chicken birthday pretty excited about
that not that I'm turning 48 but just uh
generally the mountain turns into a
Wonderland at the end of March uh we'll
usually get one last storm we'll get
this really beautiful powder uh and I'm
hoping on making it up to Whistler for
my birthday as uh some of my best
birthdays have been up there my friend
has dug out an eagloo took him three
weeks he dug out a beautiful eagloo up
on Whistler Mountain and he's been
hanging out with a pine Martin up there
this little cool little weasel creature
has been coming up and visit visiting
him and eating fruits and nuts out of
his hand and uh yeah it's just all
around super cool so I'm looking to go
spend my birthday with this little Pine
Martin maybe a couple of Ravens and some
whiskey Jacks uh and some friends we'll
see how it goes that's really cool sky
and Kendall and the kids went up to
Kendall's cabin out near um vilmont and
snowmobile like 80 kilometers out into
the into the the High Country and they
were feeding Pine Martins too
there was a whole Pine Martin family
that was in the house and I mean they're
they can be you know a vicious little
creature yeah and they're just the
coolest uh Paws and the be they have
these weird little noises and they're
they like almost like snow
otters they have locking
Jaws the IR are really cool up here too
which are white and they look similar to
the Pine Martin but they're smaller and
completely white yeah yeah those are
I've seen them on the mountain which is
incredible to say because they are next
to impossible to
see um but I have seen them on the
mountains before those perfectly white
ones that just you know they you only
see them while they're moving and the
minute they stop moving they just
disappear in the in the snow it's pretty
awesome we had the rare occasion of
seeing a wolverine recently uh coming
down from Revel Stoke and uh it was just
this amazing creature you know coming
across the road and I don't know if
anyone knows about wolverines but
they're one of the most elusive beings
in our forest one of the other elusive
beings in our forest is the mountain
caribou and the mountain caribou are
also kind of threatened in this in this
area and there's a thing that everyone
should know about called the Y to Y
Corridor which is the Yellowstone to
Yellow Knife uh or to the uh yeah to
Yellow Knife up in Northwest territory's
Corridor where they're trying to keep as
much of an
intact Corridor of wilderness going up
you know to to Alaska to keep that
flowing for animals so the purcel
Wilderness is in that and people should
look into the purcel Wilderness and and
even will it Wilderness forever is an
area that people are trying to make into
the park so please look into Willet
Wilderness forever and see if you can
sign those petitions and just create
more Wilderness in British Columbia
beautifully said absolutely uh my friend
bushy Wayne Uh on Instagram posted a
footage of uh I don't know if it was
Wolverine or Badger but it was one of
the two and it was their tracks and he
was following it in his I don't I think
it was in his plane but it seemed like a
helicopter footage but you're just over
this crazy like forested snow covered
mountain range and you just see these
tracks and he follows them for quite
some time it's a it's pretty cool
footage for those of you that might want
to check it
out oh and also Bush Wayne is really
cool and does amazing stuff in the
mountains and I know he's a friend of
yours Marcus and and his partner is
important to note Sarah and everything
but uh um amazing stuff that bush Wayne
does hey I wanted to shout out both um
Bingo Lombardi and 70s mama who have
just been they've been the admins in our
chat room here in YouTube for a very
long time and I just don't think we give
them enough props 70s mom has been away
and we've been missing her uh she just
came on just now and said she would love
to invite Wade laughter to speak to her
CSC students about harleyquinn and CBD
in general I was lucky enough to speak
to her students it was very enjoyable
70s mom has been one of our longtime
admins and she's been taking care of the
chat so Wade uh I can hook you up with
her afterwards and I'm sure you can uh
uh help her out and do something
wonderful together thank you and yes I'd
love to it's it is I consider that the
primary focus of my work is helping
people understand what cannabis can do
uh in addition to the lovely benefit of
getting aide so uh yeah please Marcus
hook us up and I'd be glad to yeah shout
out to 70's mom as well she invited me
on to one of her classes as well it was
a wonderful fun easygoing experience uh
you'll enjoy it way
totally another person who does classes
is Selena
Wong uh who lives in Vernon and she's
been on hash Church before and she's had
her own show on here uh the Selena Wong
show The Flower of Life show and uh she
does a a class with some local native
women and I also did her class and it
was I think I've done it twice now in
fact and it was also well worth uh the
time and energy and I just thought it
was great to meet some new folks and
hear from them and help educate them on
things that I happen to know and so I'm
sure Selena would be pretty stoked to uh
have any of the people on the panel here
dragonfly Earth Madison and and Josh and
and Wade and a and and everyone really
um I think that you guys would be would
do good to get in touch with her as well
because she's doing uh good things as
well we're super in touch with Selena we
think she's one of the greatest people
ever she's does do really amazing work
part of the spiritual community in
British Colombia and uh yeah I'm pretty
sure she has an online uh website that's
maybe a dispensary of some type and
everything so yeah just she's a really
beautiful woman awesome we support her
in every
way just like to uh shout out uh Brandon
and Amanda for uh down at Kush Kirk for
this guava punch we just made this guava
punch hash at the house here the other
day with uh subsidium and the canab
Ander llin and and Adam and stuff and
wow this guava punch came out like
spectacular big up beautiful that was
something that was something they bred
down there on their Farm yeah guava
punch came out of the um guava and the
punch breath so we got the punch breath
oh no the strawberry guava I'm pretty
sure it's a strawberry guava by punch
breath um and yeah they gave us seeds
last year we grew them on the property
this year feno hunted it cloned it got
it out to the community here in the cies
and started making hash with it you know
and it's just
specular you know this other one kind
one
that's say what how did like what did
you that looks like Rosen to me what
what kind of has oh I'm sorry it's Rosen
from I'm
sorry it's it's from from uh hash I made
ice water hash out of fresh frozen
pressed it at 180
degrees and have kept it you know
perfectly it's just spec and and and the
it's it almost rips your face apart when
you open the the thing it just peels
your skin back it's just
like
ah little guava I have a little grape
guava that was given to me by press no
this one was given to me by globby
Johnson and then I've got the banana
pudding that was given to me by pressed
out they look very similar in color for
for certain of what you have there we'll
have to get together and have a little
puff down
soon you're on mute
Josh glue
pig from Josh wax down in La the glue
Pig he gave us the Alien OG the glue Pig
the Hog's
Breath and something else and it the
hash just turned out really phenomenal
or the rosin and hash both turned out
really good from it beautiful beautiful
well let's have ourselves a little Bowl
here on hash church we certainly don't
snub our noses at some nice solventless
oil or for that matter any type of oil
we have all sorts of different panelists
that enjoy all sorts of different things
here we try to be inclusive and remove
ourselves from these silly divisions
that we get caught up in sometimes as
human
beings Josh did you uh get to deploy any
of the uh the the things I sent over to
you to the little notes here and there
in the
process so I just want everyone to know
how stoked I am about Colin because he
shared with me some tech that was really
really phenomenal and yes Colin I really
appreciate that I'm sort of in the
middle of a couple runs right now uh to
be able to give you like the full uh you
know sort of reply on on my thoughts on
it and again I'm sort of somewhat new at
it and everything in this last year but
yes incredible work and I think that has
a lot to do with why the TPS are so
strong on it I mean in some cases the
tpping are
strong than the flower was and I maybe
that's normal but you know in our case
here you know the the
uh tures are just crazy in
there you know I I think you have an
opportunity to with the the knowledge
that I I gave I passed on you to to
retain a lot and um but I think um you
know we always lose a little bit it's
just where we're at I don't unless
you're using a lab kico or things like
that I think it's and even then you're
still you know I don't think anybody
really has any true date on it quite yet
but um or maybe they do I just I'm not
aware of it but uh I'm super stoked that
you able to utilize it and have fun with
it and uh yeah make great medicine I'm
so stoked so yeah please give me some
feedback I I I'd love hearing you know
how it went so thanks I feel like you
guys talking in
c i g i uh I helped I helped uh Josh
with some uh some freeze dryer
techniques and uh just gave him some
pointers and and and uh you know just
gave him the armed him with the the
right stuff and you know let him do his
thing and I think he
he took the sheet music and made some
beautiful music you
know as I call it you know and is this
something we're sharing with our
audience or is this something that we're
keeping a little closer to our our chest
we're keeping a little closer but but
it's uh you know I I just had to ask
because we talked about it so long like
a while ago and I just we haven't
checked in on each other and I I just
wanted to ask because you you pulled up
that beautiful jar and I was like that
looks pretty familiar
the same reason I asked because it was
mentioned on hash church I had to
mention like are we talking about this
we can talk about it in the future maybe
one day I'll invite a bunch of people on
who use freeze dryers and we'll spend
the first hour just talking about
settings and uh how to sublimate out the
water it's not as tricky as you might
think um depending on the type of freeze
dryer that you have it's just like
anything you learn the variables and
then you tune the variables to find The
Sweet Spot and how you do that
is by making mistakes and it's not that
difficult you make little mistakes they
they direct you as long as you're paying
attention and you have that awareness
you'll find that sweet spot making rosin
is no different you've got pressure
you've got heat you've got time those
are your three variables now you're
going to tune each of those variables in
and you're going to hone in on that
sweet spot and um The Sweet Spot could
change from person to person who knows
for me it's always about definitely
getting my yield because I hate the idea
of leaving things behind but also
preserving you know the flavor as much
as I can um yeah that's kind of kind of
my my um my process we use a bunch of
different freeze dryers that my work so
a freeze dryer conversation really would
have to be with people who are using the
same freeze dryers because if you've got
people who are using lab conos and
people who using freeze dry Coes um
their their the conversation is not
going to be the same conversation
they'll uh
they'll they'll be thinking that uh what
one person says doesn't align with what
the other person
says an elevation I find sometimes has a
a big play into settings as well
um you know so that'll change based on
where you are GE
geographically uh also Flynn from wuce
Winery has some really good Tech and
ganji Gill was just bigging him up on
his story not too long ago for helping
him uh bring his dry time down quite a
bit and also continue to keep his uh
quality up so I think that you know if
you can keep your times down and still
and times down TPS up that's kind of the
lecher got it down to seven hours but
it's also you know part of that is that
his screens that he uses that we've
purchased that insert into the freeze
dryer they have very big metal frames
and then they're basically screens that
the hash sits on so the sub sublimation
of the water happens way faster but it's
also seemingly faster because you put a
lot less hash in because of that big
metal frame when we first started I
can't tell you how many times I muffined
out my freeze dryer putting in so much
hash that every single tray that I
pulled out was like the hash had risen
right to the top of the the bottom of
the next tray and the the cleaning of
the freeze dryer when you do that is
Extreme like that silicone mat that is
on the top you know freeze dryers tend
to look like they're upside down when
they go in that's because those heaters
have um a silicone mat that goes over
top of them and that's kind of what
buffers the Heat and controls the
sublimation of the water and so we used
to oh my God we used to put like three
four wet kilos of hash into these things
and that's just too much the amount that
seems to come out perfectly is you know
around 700 to 800 dried ground Rams from
a from a harvest right at least which is
really the freeze dryer that 90% of
people in the in the industry and
Community are using right now because
they're a lyophilization oven that is
like really the most basic one that you
could possibly buy and because of freeze
dry Co who who is the manufacturer for
Harvest Right and makes all of those uh
freeze dryers they already had a
business where they were creating freeze
dryers for a variety of Industries so to
create a little side Hub where they
could just start pumping out these very
small little home units really even the
laboratory one uh is more of a home unit
than than not in my opinion I got
attacked pretty good on my Facebook page
the other day when I mentioned to a
friend to avoid using the oil pumps that
come with the Harvest rights and uh yeah
this guy just came at me fairly
intellectually you know not very passive
aggressively I I felt like he had just
been you know under house arrest like
all of us for the last year and was
probably at the his rope and he was like
I think I'll take it out on bubble man
today like that seems like a as good as
any and uh his argument was that that
you know the oil pumps work fine if you
know how to use the the oil um uh and
the and the and the pump properly for me
I love the idea of mitigating all risk
when it comes to and funny enough you
know just as I'm about to talk about
mitigating risk in a laboratory Dr
Markell pops into the room so that's
pretty trippy well played Dr Mark well
played I know you didn't hear what I
just said but uh I'm talking about
mitigating risk in the
laboratory and the atomized oil from
those pumps that unless you have it
piped out of your lab goes into the air
and is not good for for humans and is
definitely not something you want to
find on your hash so I'm talking about
Mark right now why I think a scroll pump
is a better idea than an oil pump oh
yeah any La for for freeze drying
yeah okay yep yep yeah so that's
basically the conversation so you know
first of all the scroll pump is way more
expensive but you don't have to deal
with changing the oil like after every
batch which in my opinion is a very
large Vector for potential contamination
because the oil is kind of invisible and
it transfers very easily depending on
your ability in the lab and everyone has
different abilities and so that's one
good way to to mitigate that risk is by
getting rid of it secondary the the
scroll pump in the long run will be the
cheaper option because you won't be
continually buying oil to put into the
pump it costs money to do that Andor a
pump that that breaks because you didn't
change the oil when you were supposed to
yeah well it's all about getting there's
water that ends up in that oil and then
you have to separate it filter it out
they give you the whole thing but it's
it's nasty there's no invariably all of
that all that pump uh exhaust should be
exhausted like out a fumehood because
otherwise you're going to develop this
film of stuff all over the inside of
your lab which you try to keep clean but
it it's a greasy kind of grime that just
ends up collecting everywhere and it
it'll attract dust too and and dirt and
why people aren't thinking about it is
because uh
it's it's invisible basically and they
don't the one difference that they're
not doing is doing microbial testing on
their lab weekly where you just swab
everything and send it off and find out
what's going on if you're not doing that
and you're just
assuming that's
scary the new premium pumps I'll just
say um you you can get like 20 Cycles
out of it without changing the oil not
that I'm promoting the oil pump after
everything you said but the new premium
pumps that come from Harvest Right don't
have to be changed every single time so
that's that's a positive thing but the
squirrel pumps are great maybe someone
could put a link of the squ some of the
squirrel pumps that you're talking about
up on theat SR squirrel sorry squirrel
friend thanks for the squirrel pump
squirrel p liol leoy is another great
company has Parmer yeah cold farmer is
also another is a good one and uh yeah I
mean leol is what I what VTA uses and
you know I've have a few of them on on
some other devices and yeah there're
sometimes called they're sometimes
called diaphragm pumps right are is a
diaphragm pump the same as a scroll pump
I think it's the same right definitely
heard them spoken about in the same
sentence right I think it's just and so
the fundamental difference between that
and oil pump is just the whole pumping
mechanism is just oilfree because
basically what you're doing is you're
compressing and
decompressing a diaphragm which creates
a vacuum right and if you have your
valve set up right as as as the as the
diaphragm is decompressed it creates a
negative pressure or vacuum which again
creates sort of like this pulsating kind
of negative pressure right so that's why
it there's kind of like a noise to it
because the diaphragm is going back and
forth and it's only on the fourth cycle
that it actually pulls the vacuum
otherwise it needs to push so it's
pulling and pushing pulling and pushing
but you're only sort of capturing the
pulling so to
speak Dr Mar you're looking very Jerry
today you just have yeah like the black
shirt with the hair you just like you
just have this I act like Jerry too you
just have this like yeah you just have
the ism going you know yeah I just want
to go back for one second on scroll
pumps versus diaphragms because I just
checked it out the scroll technology is
based on smooth orbital operation while
diaphragm pumping involves abrupt
cycling of the diaphragm cylinder pum
pretty but I believe they're so are they
both oiless Mark are they both they
don't involve an oil um I'd have to go
in deeper scroll definitely does not I
don't think diaphragm does either um
that use two spiral Scrolls to compress
air and move them towards you but you
know your your point of oil
contamination in in the hash is still
you know regardless you want to
basically use an oilf free pump and
again oil free pumps can only give you a
vacuum of so much but for just drying
water you only need uh that kind of
vacuum you don't really need a really
really deep vacuum that only the oil can
give you and yes uh someone in the chat
just mentioned that the oil that Harvest
Right supplies is not the best oil
absolutely Ely 100 Agreed 100% agreed
but is there really a best oil to be
anywhere near your
hash hash
oil that's the only
one I like it well people really enjoyed
that little bit of the conversation I
will tell you just from reading the chat
people were like Bring it on I got my
notepad out this is important
information things that um people are
looking to save time and mitigate risk
and so Mark does Harvest Right sell a
pump with their machine that they sell
the um
the oil pump that comes with it it's an
oil pump oh yeah upgrade to as well I
believe I don't know what it is I
I they sell the scroll as
well okay yeah it's
$2,000 yeah 1400 US but it's not the
standard pump that so if someone gets a
freeze dryer and they think that they
have the thing that they need to freeze
dry their hash that's not that's not the
situation well they can get the job done
I'm not saying they can't but it's you
know it seems inevitable at one point
that with all the risk it's kind of like
when you're back in the day before pfte
came out which is uh distilled water
with spores for mushrooms in a syringe
we had to use things called transfer
Chambers which of course mark would know
what that is because it's a pretty
standard thing in a lab when you really
need to avoid this microbial world that
we absolutely live in you have to create
a small chamber and kill all the
bacteria in it and like go in with
gloves and do your work in there and so
you know unless you're doing your oil
changes in there to me I just couldn't
take the risk every time I saw that oil
I just wanted it out of my lab
immediately and uh that's what we made
sure we did before there was any
problems it's really great if you could
have kind of like your your vacuum pumps
kind of like in like a a mechanical room
area that's adequately ventilated and so
if they do end up spewing stuff it's
kind of in a separate room from where
your product is out and open because you
know those vacuum lines they all need to
be exhausted and very rarely I'll go
into a lab and it'll smell sour and
it'll be kind of like again that Grime
and it's like you guys realize you're
sending all that vacuum stuff vacum
doesn't just
disappear it's got to go somewhere right
ends up all over your lab right and
you're right those
microscopic particles I I imagine a hash
just could be a magnet for all that you
know I'll tell you and even worse so how
about if they're making rosin and
they're actually pressing rosin in
parchment
paper which we know I think I've even
shown it right here on hash Church yeah
even hash pressed in parchment paper
particularly touched by humans seems to
send and charge that thing statically
and so when the rosin is hanging in a in
a band you can take your finger and put
it nearby and the rosin will go like
this towards your finger which means so
charged know that it's literally yeah
man absolutely take some hash or some or
some and put it in parchment and like
press it with your hands a little bit
and then open it up and hang it and then
go like this with your finger and you'll
literally see the rosin go like that
I've done it on hash church for
sure the wide world of hash man that's
totally [ __ ] cool dude tricks you
could can you teach it to do tricks well
you can how about this from a microbial
or a contamination mind in a lab would
you want to see that [ __ ] like like
exposed in any way like it's literally
pulling a Charged pulling like anything
that's floating in the air like you just
have has to be kept really really clean
I think it'll take a little while but
eventually PE people are going to become
aware of all these things as they make
little mistakes in their labs and have
their
problems because this is a relatively
new industry and we're not all chemists
that come from a chemistry background
that were trained to to work in in Labs
you know
like I don't know the best I could ever
train my hashes to burn up in a small
series of little fires that's the only
trick I've been able to teach it to I
mean you know I I put on a little flette
before and flung it into a bowl but you
know that's about it I always feel like
the hash is training me don't touch me
this way you're gonna get stuck all over
your fingers Colin don't don't do don't
do that Michael of looking at it botney
of desire for any of those of you who
have read that book you know it's an
interesting thing when you think of
almost like Corps infecting the mind of
the insect to climb to the tallest tree
so it can fruit and explode its spores
to fall find more uh insects to infect I
sometimes wonder like is uh C is
skunkman Sam breeding cannabis or is
cannabis directing skunkman Sam through
some sort
of what do you think skunkman Wag the
tail but the boty of the desire but
desire is what binds you to The Wheel of
Life so I guess we all got to get away
from boty maybe it'll just grow
itself well I think I've always kind of
convinced that as like my man has always
spread cannabis no cannabis has gotten
man to spread it throughout the entire
world so uh yeah I think cannabis is a
wee bit smarter than some of us humans
in some
respects one of the things we're getting
ready to do on the farm today as soon as
we're finished is plant ganja outside
because it's a really good uh planting
Mo what What mo is it today it's Libra
why is Libra good uh Libra is just a
it's a air sign it's really awesome for
flowers only you really don't want to be
planting any your veggies that's for in
the next couple of days uh when the moon
um moves into cancer or Scorpio moves
into Scorpio in a couple of days and
then that's just going to be way better
for your pumpkins and your squashes and
all of your brasas and things like that
time to get those in the garden as well
as all of your peas and your spinaches
so in the next couple of days but today
is is a really awesome day and tomorrow
morning for planting flowers so I'm sort
of half in and half out honestly all I
can do is look outside and go oh geez
it's a planting day so we're expecting
we're direct sewing everything uh this
year everything we're not even doing any
little pots no lights anywhere of
nothing we've just realized that we can
direct SE with some greenhouse plastic
over some stuff outside and and if
people look at her the sunlight just
seems like you know after 30 years of
growing we've just come to that that's
you know what's easy and how can we grow
gardens for when we're 89 or 90 and this
is just the way to do it we don't have
to carry pots around we just carry a
little bag of seeds out to the garden
and direct so it's been awesome the only
plants that we may put in pots are some
of the ones that we uh may want to keep
as a male we we did um think about we
digging up some of the males out of the
direct sto out of the greenhouse and in
some cases that worked we had to put it
in the shade in in a creek we put it in
a Creek in the shade for a couple days
let it like kind of come back to life
then repot it then bring it up into a
semi-shady area and it's amazing it
keeps growing and it gives us pollen and
some ways I like that better than
cutting the top off and putting it in a
glass jar but you can cut the top off
and put it in the glass jar when it's
fruited enough but you have to get it
fruited enough and sometimes
that means there's pollen going through
the air but you know so it's good to
have research and developing Farms out
there but uh this year you can look on
our Instagram the last couple days we
showed how we've prepared our beds this
year and we really like you know the
ramal chip uh wood chips and how they
are going to feed our rizosphere and we
really like the idea that when the the
seed germinates and the first root comes
out it's going to hit micro risal spores
and Indigenous microorganisms and then
all the roots are going to grow through
these
Birch uh Birch chips that we have and
and then the the fungi is going to eat
you can see how easy it is for the fungi
to come on and eat like sawdust and wood
chips so it's just going to be this
total Fusion of of fungi and Roots
growing together and I love the oil
secretions that that come from the
weight of the plant uptakes those
nutrients and it comes out in the hash
when you have a juicy Rich Nar
soil substrate it comes out in the hash
and the tri comes get more amazing and
the flavors are are stronger and they
last
longer somebody just asked to on the
chat
just
address it it's a super
aome about uming so they really your
your your temperatures at night are
around five degrees Celsius then you can
really start planting that's just
telling you that it's a good yeah or 45
degrees um Fahrenheit and that's just
telling you hey you know it's probably a
good time to start putting in seeds if
it's going to be super wet and rainy and
that temperature you might want to hold
off until the rains sort of pass but
when you've got optimal soil
temperatures as well as optimal Moon
signs somebody wrote in there that it's
pseudoscience but really the moon signs
are what moves the ocean the moon signs
are what decides when plants uptake
nutrients trees we know when we look at
when they're in a water sign they uptake
a tremendous amount more of water and
different humidities during that time
like you know it's pretty obvious yeah
and we've tried um to do all different
types of tests you know planting in a in
a fire moon right next to one in a water
Moon and be like yeah you know we're
really going to docu M this or sometimes
we have to push it because you just
can't get around it and you have to
plant anyway because we're running out
of time or the weather and we notice
it's it's it's tremendously different
when you hit it on the right Moon as
opposed to when you don't it's it's and
Maria Maria Maria th is one biodynamic
woman I mean she did tons of tests and
proved you know that she even modified
the biodynamic planting calendar into a
more modern calendar um so yeah now is a
really good time to plant outdoors you
can plant outdoors on one thing if you
make hash and it has a little seed in it
you can put the hash out in on your beds
you know like the leftover Leaf while
you're making hash the seeds kind of
germinate they sort of they don't
germinate but they they soak like you
would a sprout and then when you put the
the hash drags out on your this for the
home Gardener out on the on the soil
like in a greenhouse I we you know you
could do that for the last month we've
had uh drgs with seeds in it on top of
soil and soon as the Earth temperature
gets warm enough sprouts come up so and
some there's some beds out there that
have like a thousand Sprouts coming up
and these seeds have been
frozen 50 times over the last you know
two months because it freezes nearly
every night and what seeds go through is
something called serot and some like
through the winter seeds fall in the
fall and they go through this serotinous
state where they go dormant even though
they're starting to germinate they go DM
it until the temperatures come right and
cannabis seeds are like that so you can
plant a cannabis seed in colder
temperatures than say you can put a
clone outside and anyone who's a
gardener knows that you know volunteers
coming up are so much more vigorous
they're so much more adapted to the soil
around them they're ready for the
microbial life that they're going to
uptake because they've already known it
throughout the whole winter and also I'm
still seeing on the chats here that
somebody is talking about pseudoscience
and they want the scientific papers well
let's go ahead and let's look back
before industrialized Revolution the
scientific papers on the moon signs and
moon plantings were incredibly vast you
can go back to the early 1800s and way
into the early 1900s before we started
mechanized big agriculture that really
is aligned with um you know not nature
and not the moon and you know it's not
reallying at Natural Sciences so let you
know I just want to let people know that
there's papers out there and there are a
lot of comparison studies that will
actually really blow your mind um so and
I'll leave I'll leave it here rudol
Steiner wrote 1 million pages of
documents before 1920 have a look at it
you can decide whether you think they're
valuable
I had a couple questions um on that last
thing um I I can't point to the paper
but I know that in the in the forestry
world uh there's somebody who's been
looking at what what sort of harvest in
terms of uh firewood Andor Lumber uh by
weight do you see based on when the tree
is cut and trees that are cut in Full
Moon particularly in water signs produce
like as much as 40% more by weight at
Harvest
um is it relevant to cannabis I can't
prove that but um I definitely I I use
the biodynamic calendar in in the work
here on the farm uh deep appreciation to
miss Stone indeed um and then I had a
question for you guys um do you soak the
seeds before you put them in direct SE
uh sewing in a greenhouse or do you
water the soil to keep them moist enough
that they
sprout we just soak them in our mouth
and um usually I'll count how many holes
that I want to do and in each hole we'll
maybe put three to five seeds and and we
can do this and we can direct sew like
this because we are breeders and we do
have so many seeds and people gift us so
many seeds so we have this ability to
maybe pick the very best female na in
each hole so I'll sort of count all of
the different holes that I want to plant
and then I'll count out the seeds I'll
put them in my mouth I'll sort of suck
on them a little bit I'll make all of
the labels and the name tags that that
you know is needed for those holes and
then I'll just plant them I would so it
only gets a pre- soak with um saliva I
would that's it probably add that the
most magical thing is that we use a dowo
Zing Crystal and this will be really
great for the people who love pseudo
science we use a dowsing Crystal over
every one of our seed packages and we we
truly believe in this we we lay our
seeds out you know in front of us on a
table from all the people that we get it
from and we use a crystal and you can
get a a yes or a no from the crystal on
whether that plant you have to ask an
intentional simple question you have to
say is this you know whatever you want
is this medicine good for me does this
medicine make hash will this cure
Crohn's disease canc or whatever it is
and you ask the question to the Crystal
and that goes through and so we choose
our seeds based off that then we put
them in our our mouth to get the DNA and
then we will roll it in Lush Roots a
little micro Rizal fungi with our saliva
on it and then we'll put it into the
soil direct which also has indigenous
microorganisms and all of the other
living cultures that we've put into the
soil and then we wet the soil down and
then that's right we let nature and soil
germinate the seed and it's our belief
that if it doesn't grow out of that soil
in that moon sign with that then really
it's not meant to be on our land and
grown out with our intentions the way
that we wanted to and I understand if
someone has specific seeds that they
want to grow there's there's other ways
of doing it but this is just the way
that we do it on on our farm and this is
the way that we've come to too and and
it also we do lot of tests and a lot of
different observations and we'll soak
some and we'll put some over here we'll
try some in wherever but you know it's
just good to always try out different
things and when you're rich in seeds or
you're a breeder then why not try out a
lot of different mediums and a and a lot
of different areas and try to plant out
of moon signs that are optimal and see
what happens you know I think it's
really awesome because you people can
listen to us here on hash church or they
can go and do it themselves because I
feel like the very best relationship
that we can have not only with nature
but with the cannabis plant is to grow
our own and the reason why you put it in
your mouth is because you're creating
that
relationship with the seed with your DNA
with the microbiology in your mouth and
in your and then in the soil you know
when we compare
microbiology of the soil to the
microbiology of our own body it's
totally similar there's no differences
you know what is in soil and what makes
plants and trees healthy is the same
microbiology that helps break down our
own seed coating yeah our own uh food
inside of our body which helps make us
healthy it's it's a it's a cycle you
know I think that often we're always
looking for proof and proof is always
given in science when when we isolate
and when we isolate things we're only
seeing it from a very small
pinpoint place in a whole you know
Universe of
microcosmic
possibilities so I think that um you
know when we are relying on just
pinpoint uh you know accuracies I think
that we are not valuing all of the
possibilities that nature and Humanity
has to
offer someone asked how long we keep the
seeds in the mouth and you can keep the
seeds in your mouth as long as really
you want to you could say your favorite
prayer or you could set your intention
for that seed and that's how long you
kept it in your mouth I think it's again
you an
intuition so as you guys are talking and
that was just awesome someone sent me
this stuff while back and you're telling
me I should like roll my peps after it
roots in this
stuff that's awesome M
fungi you know if it's the Spore has to
touch the the root in order a living
route in order for the score to to come
alive so if you can get direct contact
if you clone I mean once my
clones I dip this into this there I just
opened this right now as you're talking
about this right so I've been someone
sent me this for promix a while back so
I'm just curious about it because now
I'm really interested in what you're
talking about sorry I'm just running
around so I'm going to just get my
clones and when they root I would just
kind of roll that in some of this stuff
or is that what you're
saying I'll just read this you know I
guess well what you do is you you would
make a little micro risal solution
okay sorry you could use a little corn
starch and water and and and make a
little dip gel with microle fungi and
maybe aloe and then you can dip your you
can dip your cutting into it right and
so you do you pull the cutting out it
has aloe juice and micro isal fungi on
it
so what wait it's just you want it
wrapped around the stock of the Clone
that you're
taking so when you put the Clone in
point what you're
saying okay I didn't hear what you said
there okay sorry oh my microphone's over
here so when I cut a clone I would dip
it in um into something like this first
before I put it into the Pete and then
allow it to root but not after inoculate
the Pete the stock and when you
transplant it okay so you do okay yeah
as much as you can don't overuse the
micro isal fungi and I would just flag
like with micro risal products you know
check the sourcing of the product some
of that is grown on GMO
substrate some of it's certified organic
so you know if you want to get some of
it is just single species it might be
only feeding you
know yeah it's just a single species
poly polyculture is just super important
so you know and we're we're recommending
a living microbial cloning you know
often cloning is used with with
fungicides and and a sterile environment
the type of cloning that we're talking
about is the exact opposite where you
make a living soil bed and you put micro
isal fungi and stalks in it and when The
Roots come out they're full of white
hairs and the white hairs are where the
the the plant uptakes nutrients so
you're automatically getting an
inoculation on your root and that
inoculation stays with the plant its
entire life yeah okay and that's why
it's important to get the micro asle
fungi root on there as soon as possible
now a lot of people do indigenous
microorganisms and make soils that
they're getting micro isal fungi wild
from the environment and that's also
recommended it's also recommended it's
just if you want to ensure you know the
studied micro isal fungi thing you can
do an a very easy root dip or or dusting
of the roots in the very beginning and
then that will last its whole entire
life you don't necessarily even have to
do it again unless maybe two weeks into
it you could do another drench and and
an inoculated root zone is gonna help
your plant double in size which is why
we joke around Lush roots 8.40 that we
have is 420 time 2 just for fun great
product I was just gonna say you got you
know Josh the I've been using your
product um and boy have I seen
incredible increase in Vigor um the Lush
Roots alone is is really awesome I did
some some really isolated tests with uh
some motor breath 15 some chmd some Sour
Diesel clones and then um uh just
recently banana uh um you know St Nana
clone uh so I am seeing side by side
results and uh you know I've always
rolled my clones in in my gzel and then
then transplanted right but having this
this Lush Roots is um is really
incredible stuff man it's you know
Johnny if you should get some man it's
it's really great um I I plan on
continuing to incorporate it into my
whole regimen at this point it's it's
really phenomenal so really beautiful
work guys thank you for the first time
we listened to you guys talk about this
for a long time so I have to like change
everything I've redone the whole room
I'm looking at cutting new clones tying
things down I have these products and
I'm gonna be like calling you guys daily
and I'm G to come up for a visit and you
try by my house a few times I missed you
on the Sunshine Coast the other day you
were there I was there the next day so
it was kind of funny I was I was like
saw Joel the day after so I was like oh
I just missed you guys but um awesome
love listening to you guys I'm quiet
here and taking the information
again we didn't make it through
Vancouver we were fully feeling you and
and we really wanted to stop but we were
like on this Midnight Mission after
coming out of the coast and made it
through but we we did have an amazing
time and I wanted to touch really
quickly on what Josh was saying about
this idea
of of what is sterile and the idea of
bringing sort of half sterilized
techniques into your Garden it's sort of
like these half sterilized techniques
too you know with the mask and and what
people are wearing and and like what
what is sterile what is not sterile it's
it's like microbial life is all around
us it's everywhere and and when we call
something clean we tend to go towards
maybe the science side of it and say
sterilized is what is clean but I'd like
to sort of open up the minds to people
on the idea that when you have a
tremendous amount of beneficial
microbiology on your side and you're
working with beneficial
microbiology then that can be more of a
definition of what clean is because we
are you know utilize microbiology
everywhere all the time and it's on the
plants that you're getting if you're
getting cuting or you're getting clones
there's already an end aiic system
within those cuting that's you know
there's nothing that's truly sterile so
when you're using a product like a um a
dip or or something that's used for
rooting gels or something like that
that's a fungicide that Josh said it's
actually
sterilizing everything around where
you're dipping it which means that
you're killing all of the bacteria all
of the fungi even the endophytic fungi
which is inside or the cyano bacteria
which is on the outside of the plant
where if you have a healthy clone then
you really don't want to be killing that
because that's your health that's your
Vitality that's the well-being in the
plant that's going to go up inside of
the plant and become its own healthy
microbiome so when you Ally with this
microbiology that we're talking about
like these endos and these ectos it's
it's really similar um you know to just
allying with nature and getting that
cleanliness
from nature so just a little thought
there for everybody and healthy microbes
eat pathogens as breakfast that's their
whole entire purpose so fusarium and
pythium tend to propagate in
ster cloning environments this is why
tissue culture has become such a big
thing maybe Mark can talk or someone can
talk about tissue culture and how that's
different than what we're saying but uh
I believe that like Kelly said a healthy
microbiology system eats
path I was going to say I cut clones two
days ago so I'm going to go in pull
those out of the pets make up this dip
it in there and put them back in cuz
they're probably just starting to swell
a little bit so I have that little
window right now thank you so much for
the lesson because that's what I'm doing
this afternoon so that's awesome I can't
wait okay time to do it job got quiet
for a
second
Le do a little
dab we had an amazing trip we'll just
say and we we got to visit Terry Willard
um and Alexandra on the island and
they're just such amazing people and
they're Elders in our community and they
started you know people should look into
Wild Rose College um it's an herbal
College
online and people have they've been just
doing a you know they even have a
cannabis course now that they're doing
online which I think is really valuable
to like the hom grower and and the and
people Beyond it was really wonderful to
see their their way they've transformed
their their six acres and utilizing
alternative energy and hugle culture
swes and polyculture diversity and all
the different medicines they're making
and uh you know going along the coast we
just uh got and it just it's just
reminding me I don't mean to cut you off
just really quickly like you know the
world is a really crazy place if anybody
has a backyard or even like a 5 by 10
piece of land
like I mean gardening is so incredibly
healing if you're even if you're going
to only grow like a couple of tomato
plants and you can watch them grow that
means that you're outside that means
that you're with the soil and I just am
really encouraging people to have little
backyard gardens or to share backyard
gardens with those people who do have
backyards
um because we really believe that
backyard gardens are going to be what
saves the Earth and and it's humans I
mean I think the Earth is going to be
totally fine whether we're here well
it'll be way better if we're not here
but um since we are here and we do want
to save ourselves and I think it's
probably really optimal that we all get
into backyard gardening and growing our
own food uh so that we can be eating
good nutrients and up taking good
microbiology so that we have the ability
to think outside of the box of what
which just science and media is teaching
us something outside of that um I think
will be really helpful for our
species and building bird houses B
houses and minor B hotels are really
good thing to do right now we're we
going to build swallow houses because
the swallows come back I wrote a note
from last year that they came back on
April 15th so I'm trying to prepare I
want to have a you know a good amount of
swallow houses for them so creating
habitat is also very important in a time
when we're losing a lot of
habitat I like it Peppers peppers are an
easy thing to grow and if you eat
peppers you got to clean out the seeds
so now you have pepper seeds right so
there there so easy to grow and you know
we just uh had a meal with peppers my
daughter was so inspired like Dad look
there's all the seeds here I'm like okay
let's
go all different kinds of peppers you
now have seeds
for so many things we eat have seeds and
it is true there are so many things we
can save seeds from that we eat and we
often throw it away yeah well with
tomatoes you kind of eat the seeds right
so with some things you eat the seeds
but like so we tried to actually strain
out of some of the Tomato pulp a few of
the seeds and it didn't really work out
too
well so we'll just go buy those seeds
but the thing with us is like we we live
close to um and you would love these
guys Josh and Kelly um our local Amish
farmer who um you know we've been buying
produce from him for probably about 20
years now I mean and we've seen his
business grow to where he's making
package Goods now and has Dairy which
means he needs Refrigeration which when
we first went there they had no
electricity at all they were just kind
of like a Farm Stand literally just
selling produce that was just freshly
harvested it's now more of the Amish
Market you know that baked goods and
dairy stuff and stuff like that but um
Yeah man they just they they're totally
regenerative Farmers you could tell
because when you go there you just you
you see it happening you know and and
the whole family is involved and it just
it's so cool they they they they
peacefully coexist in we we kind of live
in Philadelphia creep Suburbia you know
a Suburbia from Philadelphia and
Westchester and Baltimore kind of like
they all kind of creep together I mean
where we live now 20 30 years well 20
years ago we were here so 40 years ago
this was all Farmland but um the Amish
basically run all of the local farms in
this area and and they they're they're
just amazing man they they just and
they're out there're they're growing
hemp now too which is really amazing too
but we try to support our local Amish
guy because it means the world to him
that you know my wife is there probably
two or three times a week buying our
fresh produce we'll buy our our eggs and
our some of our Dairy not all of our
Dairy from him but um yeah man I mean
it's just it's regenerative farming all
of their um livestock practice is all
organic and open range for like their
chickens and their turkeys and stuff
like that they sell they sell goat milk
and goat cheese which is really again
probably unique to them but you well
maybe not unique to them but um it just
it's so great that they can peacefully
coexist and farm in
2021 by the methods that I think have
been farmed that you know for for
Generations go ahead Sam I'm sorry no no
problem you know me I butt into
everybody and uh I I just wanted to say
that if you want to save tomato seeds
two points one make sure it's not a
hybrid because you can't save hybrid
tomato seeds second uh so you use an
open pollinated oldfashioned type
variety second thing is you scoop out or
squeeze out the seeds and you put them
in a glass jar and let them ferment for
a few
days then you take them out wash them in
clean water dry them and you can use
them the next year you know when it's
ready to plant but without that
fermentation product it doesn't
work wow Sam dropping the real knowledge
here there you go tell me more Sam about
the you can't if it's a hybrid because I
assume like when I buy tomatoes like at
the grocery store that those are
probably all commercial hybrid Tomatoes
right so is itely yes okay so is it so
can you say what you said before which
is that you're not allowed to take those
seeds from those Tom no it's not that
you can't you're not allowed to it's
they won't reproduce like the hybrid
because the a hybrid an F1 hybrid has
two different parents two different
lines and you only are reproducing the
F1 which is it it's not this an F1
hybrid when you self it to itself it'll
prod 25% like the mother 25% like the
father and 50% somewhere in between the
two so you don't get what you want
whereas if you use like an heirloom
variety of tomato like brandy wine well
that's true breeding and if you ferment
the seeds and save them they will
absolutely work Wonderful because I've
done it for
decades and also the roma tomato is one
that is still somewhat a Heritage
variety that you can also keep seed from
which is one of the most common ones in
the grocery store that's actually still
an old
variety we've grown Roma tomatoes for a
while in this one area and we're the
tomatoes have kind of gotten mature the
end of the season sometimes we just
leave them out there they drop the seeds
and they yeah just keep growing year
after year and yeah in the fruit yeah
what a wonderful tomato that is that's
just you could eat them just raw just
with salt and pepper I mean they're just
yeah you could put them in sauce I love
those Tomatoes I love r or my wife's
favorite is Brandy Wine mine favorite is
Cherokee purple you can't beat it for in
my taste so Sam you mentioned not being
able to start the seeds um is there a
reason why are they just not fertile or
or what's the reasoning behind the
hybrids not being able to be well
no it's but they will grow but instead
of being the F1 hybrid that the parents
were they will be uh
F2 and therefore 25% like the mother 25%
like the father and 50% in between and I
doubt very many of them will be like the
F1 hybrid that you bought in the first
place because it was so
wonderful makes sense thanks for the EXP
you know Mark I loved what you were
saying there about supporting the local
Amish people is that you're also
supporting your local biome and what
everybody is talking about here and when
you're getting those cheeses and when
you're getting those veggies you're
supporting your own healthy
microbiome which is inevitably your own
healthy
microbiome um which is really awesome
intelligent to do and also what we're
talking about here with uh germination
of any kind of seeds is what is it doing
in nature so tomatoes are really awesome
they come up all over the garden as
volunteers and when they do that is when
a tomato drops off of the plant whole
and then it overwinters and it's rotting
or fermenting inside of its own
serotinous sugars carbohydrates Ates its
own State then it has the ability those
enzymes eat away at the outside or the
hole of the seed which helps it to
germinate faster in that environment so
whenever we're planting seeds you know
you you want to be able to think about
oh well what is it doing in nature and
how can I you know mimic that so that it
will have that its best germination as
well as its most potential growth Poss
POS it's absolutely true I mean some
seeds have to be frozen or they will not
grow I'm not talking cannabis seeds I'm
talking about seeds of everything in the
universe and other things yeah each one
has its own like you say if you see how
they propagate in nature that's probably
what you have to do something to them
we're growing a California
seoa Giant Sequoia in our yard that was
started by our neighbor who's an elder
AR arborous n natur naturalist and he
got the seeds while he was down in the
SEO he brought them back you know the
pine cones uh or the the seoa cones I'll
call them um brought them back up put
them in his freezer for 11 years that's
what he did because that's what how long
it took and then he took the seeds out
of the freezer and propagated about 20
of them and he's got them growing on his
property and now we have a giant sequoia
that's probably around 10 feet tall now
growing in British Columbia we also have
the Dawn Redwood growing on our property
which is the Redwood from from China for
for so many years you know in America
and North American and European
botanists used to think that the only
redwoods were in California but then I
believe it was the 30s botanists were
traveling the world and studying
species and they came across this
firewood this was the story I heard
someone could maybe prove me wrong or
something when they found this firewood
and they said wow this looks like
Redwood can you take me to where the
tree is and they took him to the tree
and they're like holy this is like a
type of SEO I think it's seoa um Meta
Meta something and that's the scientific
name so it's called a Dawn Redwood and
this Redwood loses its needles in the
fall and then it grows back in the
springtime it definitely grows different
but um like the Larch tree or the
tamarak over in this area those are the
two conifers that I can think of at the
moment that lose their their leaves or
their needles in the fall and then grow
them back bright green in the springtime
so um yeah we were able to propagate
unique Conifer trees on our property
sequia redwoods when I was young my mom
took me to uh King's Canyon and sequ
national parks in California and they
sold little redwood trees growing about
6 Ines tall you could buy them for like
five bucks from the camp uh was part of
the forest office gift
house yeah you can still get them um I
belong to a couple of local Bond Die
societies and they have uh you know
spring uh where they everyone will bring
out their sprouts and uh they'll do a
little exchange as well as you can buy
certain trees or some starters we've got
an Oakland Bonsai as well because
they've got a full-on redwood Bonsai
here which is uh part of the uh National
Bonsai Western dosens which is actually
here in Oakland California so they have
an amazing program and as well as the
first female bonai Master she went to
Japan and studied and she is here she's
such a [ __ ] badass just
amazing little
have
time yeah I want to give a shout out to
Danny and Alice in mayorca these
incredible people that uh hosted us some
years ago a couple of friends of mine uh
Los Gardens was with me and uh Neil um
who who was um yeah just a longtime good
friend of mine who grew all that where
as my bike that I used to press and he's
the grower behind that and I went and
visited his grow a few times and did
some did some some things on him as well
but uh we went there and they were the
most gracious hosts they had a little
shop there um and he was growing
spectacular herb that he was selling at
his shop and he really sort of showed us
around the island of mayorca gave us the
history of it and we rented motorcycles
and cruised all around these epic areas
in
mayorca um and he they just had uh a
second
uh uh that a second child so just after
we had left they had had their first
child and now they just had uh their
second so he says yes we have Sky who is
now two and Austin so I just wanted to
shout them out they're just such awesome
people growing beautiful fruit in
mayorca with beautiful property if
you've never been to mayorca uh I would
check it out it's a very unique Island
it's a it's a it's a destination for
cyclists and motorcyclists because one
of the areas that we went on had this
incredible road that youve just I mean
the closest thing I ever saw to it was
in Switzerland and Switzerland certainly
isn't like a tropical island so yeah
it's just uh you know across the water
from Barcelona in between Africa and uh
Spain and it's definitely a a cool spot
and a worthwhile spot to go check out I
don't know if you guys still have your
shop over there Danny but if you do and
you want to say the name I'll gladly
shout that out as well because uh if you
do go to
mayorca uh I would suggest um supporting
Danny and Alice uh in all of their uh
business uh yes shout out to the baleric
islands beautiful thing
yes super beautiful I feel blessed to
have gotten to go Sak calobra right that
was the motorcycle ride if you guys want
to Google
saoba c a l r o b a that um that is the
road that you can see on mayorca that of
course we had to ride uh motorcycles and
rip oh John was there also that's right
John was also on that trip Neil and John
uh as well as Los Gardens and
myself so much
fun all right so I want to kind of
bounce back to a second for the uh the
Redwood there that was found in China
you think that goes back to uh gandan
land when it was all one land mass and
one of those things that was left in a
pocket per se if you know because I
always kind of wondered if you know
cannabis you know was kind of spread
around you know via gandana land per se
because it was never originally found in
North America it was seemed to have been
found later on here but in other parts
of the world so it's always been kind of
fascinated about the one land mass that
is kind of always spread out in the
Flora and Fauna that have survived in
Regional in California we also have the
coastal
redwoods of which you used to harvest in
right the coastal redwoods are the
sequoia Seer virn and the the the Sierra
Nevadas are the
seoa gigantium I believe and I think
that's a really um interesting
hypothesis ATN and I totally agree with
that I mean when we're talking about
plants and trees we're talking about you
know millions of years years of of
evolution and survival and uh also I you
know we know about
dragonflies for example there's giant
dragonfly migrations people should look
up dragonfly migrations in some cases
dragonflies migrate 250000 miles across
whole uh oceans and stuff so other
things do too you know and I think that
birds and different things have do have
the potential to carry seeds vas you
know Long Way dist distances especially
if they catch a A headwind or something
they find themselves a thousand miles
away in a few days you know I think
seeds can travel like that but I I like
that hypothesis of the Continuum from
the land mass uh you know with
seeds kind of
curiosity last week think about on our
psychedelic Renaissance um um course
that it's a six week course and it was
the fifth week uh the speaker was a guy
named Mark Plotkin I'd never heard of
Mark before uh but he is um a student of
Richard schulties who certainly is much
more well known Richard schulties was
the Harvard
ethno uh biologist who went down to the
South America and and Mexico and
discovered all these psychedelic you of
psychedelic plants including iosa
ceremony uh I think if it wouldn't been
for Schult work I don't think it would
be as popular today as it as it as it
truly is so schy was is certainly a
Pioneer and Mark Plotkin got a a podcast
called plants of the Gods which I think
is after Richard Shy's books that he he
wrote with Albert Hoffman and uh his
podcast is extremely informative and it
the one thing the reason why I brought
it up during this discussion is because
it talks about you know ceremony and
iasa ceremony and how it's it's
connected to the culture and it's
something that you can't just
necessarily reproduce and Berkeley
California in a clinic you know it just
doesn't you can't do it by Zoom you know
it just it just doesn't just doesn't
translate very well right and as as much
of of and all this work that sh'll he
did in that like now plin is now uh uh
documented just shows like how important
it is to conserve this
biodiversity that exists down in what's
left of the of the Amazon rainforest and
and elsewhere all other you know native
areas that you know humans haven't you
know deforested or completely you know
somehow changed the natural biology
what's going on because I'm convinced
there's a whole Treasure Trove of
chemistry and molecules down there in
plant species we don't know yet because
it's funny there's certainly a
definitely an awareness from the
indigenous cultures uh in fact there's
still cultures today that exist today
that have had no outside contact with
the Western World and and to me I was to
hear that to know that the are still
cultures today that have not had contact
with with the Western world to me at
least was was fascinating to hear but um
the other thing is that just the areas
that they're they're living on you know
are increasingly getting smaller and
smaller but thank God to these
conservation efforts people like Mark
plin and he's involved in that whole uh
Amazon conservation society which is you
know again a huge huge thing that's just
trying to keep as much of the
biodiversity that we possibly can and
learn it in a way that doesn't totally
exploit it commercially but in a way
where again we can understand I mean
there's all kinds of clinical work going
on around DMT again partially because
it's one of the active ingredients in ha
iasa that coupled with the monoamine
oxidase inhibitor harmaline so there's
something that's that's happening there
monomolecular medicine that we've talked
about here on hash Church doesn't quite
get so there's there's there's things
and there's clues that these indigenous
cultures have and these Shaman know and
they they they they know and and really
disease is a manifestation of some off
balance between society and the
environment and and and and they've
they're they've figured it out and how
ironic that you know here we are in the
what the 20 first century we're looking
to them for answers to solve our
problems and disease and hunger and
we're going to the shaman and we need
these places to basically still exist
and I was in a clubhouse room the other
day again where they were talking about
clinical use of
iasa to treat you know behavioral
disorders and it's just amazing that
we're at that point but I I don't think
think that that's a true you know
manifestation of like where the where
the medicine comes from and what
the experience is all about and I think
some Shaman is just counting some money
because he just made a whole lot of
money by selling out but I'd be
interested in what everybody else
thought on
that anyway yeah no I I agree that um
yeah it's it's interesting how you know
it's it's partly the Shamanism has been
sort of marketed a little bit you know
so that's that maybe that's just a human
thing but it reminds me of Terence
McKenna and Dennis McKenna and Wade
Davies and Ethan Russo different people
that have gone you know made their life
out of going to South America and trying
to find plant medicine and see how it
can pertain to ours also psychedelic
plant medicine it reminds of Papa new
guine and and the diversity on Papa new
guini and all the tribes that live there
and I think these these tribes have
allied with diversity and they've allied
with with nature and they do have the
key into the unknown and and We Know by
by searching tombs and using science to
find out about different compounds that
are SE on mummies or whatever and you
know they found cocaine on mummies in in
Egypt where cocaine was probably from
America so you you would think for
millions of
years you know these native cultures
were in total contact with each other
and and probably sharing medicine you
know I mean I don't think you can really
stop humans from from traveling around
so I like that there's a nature magic
still I like that we're in a modern
world we can use science in a way that
we choose and I like that there's still
nature magic out there that reminds us
that you know
nature is producing these healing
compounds whether science proves it or
not you know so in some cases our
intuition can lead us towards health and
this is why I feel we've dedicated our
life towards you know nature and and
natural healing and stuff so I
appreciate you saying that and we are
recently given some iasa bark to take
with mushrooms a little bite of iasa
bark with
psilocybin really changes the
psychedelic experience of it and um you
know I like that these medicines are
coming into our modern world well he he
was telling the story about I I forget
the species of toad but the toad that
they they lck right and he was showing a
picture of that toad to another tribe
that was thousands of miles away and
completely isolated from them and and
and his his uh his contact there was
like oh we got a toad like that he goes
no no no no this toad is from on the
other side over over near Peru by the
coast this isn't this goes no no no no
we got a toad like that and certainly
sure
enough this guy showed them a toad that
also produce the same kind of
psychedelic effect so they identified
like a new species of toad down there
that they can lick you
know so crazy
man you know it's what else is out there
I mean there's got to be I mean I mean
and again I think that if those cultures
go away if somehow the western
civilization pollutes it just down there
such that there's no more indigenous
culture all that knowledge will go away
and that is fundamental knowledge that
has been passed down for generations and
generations and generations on how to
live in a multi you know use using all
of these plants and fun
and if there's something wrong with you
you go to the medicine man and he can
make it better whether it's a cut with
an infection or whether you got the
fever or whether you got malaria I mean
they have all the cures for everything
to to live down
there it's it's amazing to
me so Paul stamitz is the speaker
tomorrow it's the last
class it's yeah so it's the the finale
they bring Paul in at the very end that
full our conversation because someone
mentioned this in chat I believe it was
fried Piper when we were talking about
the botney of Desire who said Paul
stamin said that mushrooms are probably
cultivating
us to add that to the sure are man they
sure are well that's not
actually very far off at all because if
we're made up of trillions of
microbiology I mean trillions 380
trillion more 380 trillion that could
possibly be pathogenic and then rest is
sort of infinite so if we're made up of
all of that then these are all thinking
living breathing exceda eating
beings that are highly intelligent
because they are still here in numerous
amounts so I always say you know you
might as well Join the microb Revolution
because there's a lot more of them than
there are us and also the other thought
is that you know e everything that
you're sitting around you know people
talk about Plastics and how it's bad for
the Earth and yes all of that stuff it
takes so long but every single thing
that feeds us every single thing that we
like type on the fact that we're looking
through this computer everything
everything everything came from the
Earth
and I just think that that's interesting
if we like take that mindscape and we
and I just know that when we're gone the
microbiology is going to proliferate and
and totally take care of that because
the Earth is what made it of course
totally out of balance with Humanity but
still it's just a really interesting
conversation that you know when you take
plant medicine seems to come up in the
you know cerebral cortex of um you know
discussion to to set the mind to so I
just think that it's really interesting
when we talk about closed loops and when
we talk about the Earth and we talk
about how we're all intermixed and
involved and how science is related on
such a small microcosm you know point
that we have to express and something we
have to you know explain but it is just
it's such a wide observational
experience that's getting us there so I
think that it's important that we don't
just doubt or let go of that in
intuitive observational experience that
we're having to help guide us to you
know a much better place than we're in
right now because we have that ability
and the plant medicines continue to show
us that sorry for the rant but it's big
out
there everything is going to degrade
except for fluoropolymers we don't know
what happens to them they seem to last
forever so fluoropolymers might be uh
yeah so so Teflon right dental floss
yeah so so um you know billions and
years from now the only thing that will
exist from us is the Fukushima radiation
and and the uh and T dental floss those
be our Footprints that's
right the Fukushima dental floss era
I can only imagine how many times we've
gone through this cycle and don't even
have any idea wouldn't that be an error
not an error
error we learned from Paul statement
said there was and I took this course on
Cortez that it was there's been five
mass extinctions obviously he didn't
make this up but he was teaching it to
us there have been five mass extinctions
on Earth where it damn near wiped out
all of life on earth and the last one I
think was called the PT EX
Extinction and what he was suggesting
was that life on Earth came back from
you know the BC Coast Area and that
repopulated the earth I mean you know
maybe there's some more there but I like
that you know even during mass
extinctions the Earth re repopulates
itself and the hopie the Hy have the
same prophecy that they say that this
humanity is on its fifth stage of
humanity and they believe that we came
out of the Rocks so so if there was some
kind of a big cataclysmic event of heat
or something that made it so the Earth
was inhabitable it makes sense that we
would come out of the Rocks you know the
ones that did survive so there's a super
interesting uh the prophecy Rock people
can look up the the prophecy rock down
at Four Corners uh in the southwest and
it talks about you know where Humanity
goes in two different directions and it
might be interesting that we're in an
area like that right now you know where
there's just two types of things going
on and I like the idea that we're you
know connecting with indigenous cultures
Mark I I'll let you say something again
because I think that we can all take on
getting um local plants you know and
native plants back onto our property and
bringing in more native plants into our
polyculture is really important and
working on connecting with First Nations
and Native cultures even in North
America where we are at the moment you
know cultures native all over the world
are very important um we've been
recently contacted uh by gw's smoke
break and and the um the family there to
to work with the Lakota um you know in
in uh South Dakota and you know and and
if that if that works out you know it'
be amazing to be able to collaborate
with native peoples to bring you know to
help enhance their you know what they
have to offer us because in so many
cases is you know that's been wiped out
through residential schools and
reservations and all this stuff so
colonialization but information is still
there I think that we have the ability
to still retrieve it and I think that
the retrieval of that information is
going to come from the earth because
she's always been interacting with us
that's the funny thing we you know if we
think about that like we're interacting
on certain levels and in certain time
periods but the Earth has always been
interacting
with Humanity or with the planet or I
mean with the the plants and the animals
that are on it so there's there's some
kind of a
resonant uh
Everlasting higher
intelligence um it's there for the
taking like the all knowing and it's
totally there for the taking all we have
to do is allow it in and and on that
note I believe we have to to take to
take off and get our seeds planted we
want to give so much thanks for the
people out there in the community doing
amazing things um also we had some a
beautiful tour here in British Columbia
and I think we should give thanks to a
few people um Cy's finest just became a
micro license here in the cutney so big
love to them you can I really hope
success for the the families here in the
cies that and really showing all of the
work that the community is doing here to
you know step into the system to try to
make changes here to make it so that the
Legacy Market still has um a place and
still has a voice um in the industry so
big UPS to those guys who are doing
really amazing work it's it takes so
much time energy and money to finally
achieve a license yeah and Cy's finest
has done and thanks
toks living soil thanks to Chay at Rose
Bud um you can look at Rose outdo LP uh
we went out to his property another
Coots Vibes doing really good things for
the community and with his cultivars
because I've been talking to him lately
was that like Sarah's secret and stuff
Sarah secret so wait where's we have
some
rosin from here uh I have some bubble
yeah well th this is just what I have in
some parchment here and the Sarah's
finest is looking really really good and
Sarah secret or Sarah's secret which is
very fine um is grown Outdoors here in
British Columbia here in the cies and
it's a really beautiful outdoor varietal
that hashes really well and you can look
forward to seeing some good topicals and
different things coming from that farm
and the collective of uh Co-op here in
in the cies um want yeah we've been
definitely talking I've been talking to
Chay I've been talking to Logan at dun
I've been talking to just a few
different local uh even even Patrick uh
um his new LP I've been talking to those
guys as well I of course want to support
all the local craft Growers that are
that are I I basically want to support
all the Growers that are getting to that
level that are at they're at a point
where it's like yes this is this is the
um this is what the what everyone needs
so let's make it accessible so yeah I'm
really glad you shouted those those
spots out and continue and Suzanne with
white Grizzly over in the slow can
amazing woman all the ladies in the slow
can totally in love with everything
they've done yeah still carrying The
Vibes here in the CP still still making
it happen and and also we're going out
to plant seeds because our big goal in
in you know and has been for a whole lot
of years just to be planting fire
unbelievable genetics that everybody in
Canada and Northern climates can just
put in a small amount of soil and it
grows beautiful amazing dank flowers so
that's really our focus and our goal
because we still really believe when you
grow your own you're getting the most
medicine out of the plants you're having
a beautiful relationship with your own
medicine and that's really important as
well as you're getting out in your own
backyard so you know everybody in Canada
you can plant your four let's get on it
let's get out there let's plant your
four and you can watch so many hash
churches on what to do with that four
and how to turn it into amazing medicine
that's what all these incredible
educators are here on this panel today
so let's really exercise that right of
plant medicine and just a couple more
Daniel brish Daniel and brishna with
Earth wolf Farms over in Lila big love
and support to you all put out some hash
big love and support to Earth wolf Farms
I just wanted to give love to to flave
421 over on Sunshine Joel the whole
family over there and and hey I wanted
to give a shout out to Canon nerd too
for bringing us this amazing we've been
hanging out with him a Sunshine Daydream
like a really old Eternal Sunshine
Sunshine Daydream from bod just a really
long
14 and just I mean like it's all that I
want to have right now so big up to the
really long flowering patient Growers
and subsidium secretto you know
subsidium out from Ontario came and
helped us and I just wanted to give love
they really gave us a lot of help with
our you know hash life and everything so
just huge love to the community
everybody beautifulity like wow you guys
are amazing and so intelligent everybody
in the chat is just coming up with great
things and I can totally understand why
it has es and flows right now we're in a
world of es and flows and I think it's a
okay to all be ourselves and just you
know it's nice that everybody gets here
and is together and just thanks so much
everybody for still hanging on to the
Cannabis Community because we do have a
culture and I just appreciate you all
more than words can say really
I'm going to be thinking about all of
the Cannabis culture as I'm planting
seeds today thank you so much for all
the inspiration and the love and the
guidance and the education and expertise
and pushing it forward and the
collaboration really hard to push it
Forward I appreciate you all so so much
thank you thanks for coming guys we
appreciate you as well and have a great
day in the garden getting those seeds
into the into the soil speaking of the
culture we're actually defining that
because uh uh as you know I'm working
with the veterans Action Council and one
of our members Michael kows who's been
working at the United Nations and we're
actually working on submitting questions
and our green paper to the United
Nations uh will be submitting that this
week but one of the things that we have
found is that United Nations accepts
cultures and especially specific
cultures so um across Ross all uh
treaties uh so we're trying to define
the Canabis culture because as we know
it's been defined and we're trying to
Define it from more of a world
perspective as opposed to a US
perspective even though the US has had
its influence on the
culture the culture of cannabis is
worldwide and as we know AC crosses
every
socioeconomic uh region so um it's going
to be very interesting to see what
happens but yes we're we're going to uh
be relying on the culture at the UN
level because the persecution of
cannabis has you know done nothing but
help us perpetuate our own growing
growing cycle our processing processing
Styles um how we ingest how we use pass
it to the left you know all these
different situations you know you come
together cannabis seems to be rather
communal you know we come together in
circles how it's produced Etc so um it's
going to be very interesting to see as
we challenge things uh culturally
because uh you know there is a cannabis
culture it's it's it's definable it's
it's actually malleable in shapes from
Regional names from genetics to even
what cannabis is that have crossed I
mean how many different Generations you
know if I say a Wade and you know a
skunk man you know I say a lid they
understand it but my generation doesn't
know what a lid is per se or why the
term lid came from you know cannabis in
the first place so it's just also
fascinating how Through the Ages from
going back to the term Muggles as
opposed to other different terminologies
that have been cultural subsets that
have crossed every boundary around the
world to continually maintain things I
mean look even as a culture we all kind
of gravitated and met where in Amsterdam
because there's a huge culture of
cannabis there that was happening that
they were you know growing judging etc
etc and those things that have continued
to spread out I mean Cannabis Cup wasn't
the first one to ever judge cannabis but
it was a cultural recognition spread out
through a magazine Etc that Drew us to a
destination where we all met and
continued to perpetuate this so it also
goes back to the discussion you know did
we perpetuate cannabis or did cannabis
perpetuate us to you know proliferate
her as well so uh just some interesting
cultural distinctions and understandings
that we're going to be pushing to try to
liberate things worldwide
further
stuff yeah trippy thoughts for sure
always in that cycle are we perpetuating
it or is it perpetuating us probably a
nice balance of the two no doubt and
obviously that would depend on on your
perspective which seems to depend on
your attitude all these filters that we
put in the way to perceive I guess
that's what this experience is it's all
these filters and this five sense prison
that we seem to be yeah and back in the
day we used to say who are The Grateful
Dead and why are they following me
right and the answer
was drugs I don't know where's the next
show I like your's answer
better Drugs That's why went I we
couldn't get good drugs where we I mean
you could get drugs but you can get good
drugs or the drugs dude you wouldn't
believe the mushrooms you find on dead
tour you wouldn't believe the LSD
they've got on dead tour and you know it
just drives drove people there just you
know sociologically because of you know
bad access you know if you're new into
the drugs scene you know you're the old
people in town don't know who the [ __ ]
you are and aren't going to deal or deal
with you per se those are things that
are earned again culturally how we even
access or allow access to certain you
know uh levels of cannabis early on we
had access to shitty Mexican it wasn't
until we earned respect that we oh this
is kind but oh oh now this is the
sellers of K oh oh oh oh Street man I
mean imagine how many kids were like
well where where are we going to get the
mushrooms oh we'll get them on Shakedown
Street Shakedown Street tell me
more I mean literally I one of my first
memories on Shakedown Street is this
dreadlock hippie walking up holding this
amonita that was literally this big this
huge TR just mushrooms mushrooms
mushrooms she like I think I found the
spot
yeah I loved it didn't I look I didn't
dig the music but I appreciated the
culture I mean there was always some bus
at the end with somebody with a huge
chalkboard with somebody who was calling
out from the show like okay they just
played this and then they would mark
down on the actual chalkboard what song
had just played inside the show so
people could be like oh outside in
Shakedown Street like oh wow they're
playing this this so awesome and it's
literally go around and then Play the
song that was on from some other show
that was recorded probably the night
before it's really [ __ ] trippy I mean
I've never SE so this was during during
the show you were out outside the venue
in the Shakedown Street area yeah while
the live Grateful Dead show was going on
in yep in like Oakland Oakland Coliseum
and stuff like that oh yeah many times
yeah it it's very common you know I just
didn't dig the music I mean I dug the
scene I like the people but you know it
just didn't carry it for me I was a I
liked hardcore I like jazz I grew up in
jazz in New Orleans so I appreciated the
free flowing of it it just wasn't my
thing but the scene and the people that
were there I mean that was the only part
place I could literally be walking
around tripping see a guy pop open a
huge Tupperware jar just brimming with
the fattest [ __ ] weed I've ever seen
and like hey br brother can you spare a
bud and you know he'd be like sure dude
and then just [ __ ] chucked a bud
right [ __ ] at me I'm like thanks bud
and [ __ ] went over to a tree at the
end of Shakedown Street sat under the
tree you know in the shade and just kind
of smoked a bud to try to come down oh
yeah no other place could I have done
something like that and be a [ __ ]
punk with my jacket and you know my
tattoos and [ __ ] like that hell no but
the Grateful Dead accepted us all it was
kind of weird loved
it yeah dead heads are pretty friendly
pretty open to anything you know if you
didn't cause any problems you know I
mean occasionally they'd get skin heads
in there and they'd have to you know
have to have have issues but for the
most part yeah it was a
free-for-all party for those of you
don't know what we're talking about is
before a well during and after Grateful
Dead concerts
they would just have this traveling
circus of many thousand people that
would just come around and make a living
off of selling food and alcohol and
shirts and Frisbee and bowls and
crystals and if you could sell it I
remember seeing things like just
lighters and papers I mean if you needed
papers at a Grateful Dead show you went
down to Shakedown Street there was some
head shop down there that was set up on
the back of their Ford truck and they
had all kinds of papers and bowls and
yeah don't forget glass pipes yeah glass
pipes yeah absolutely yep yep I we see
like Marvel Slinger and those guys out
on tour with their their you know heady
cases full of glass and you know
flashlight to you know sell pretty hey
pieces and yeah it was a whole scene
that kind of developed around them and
in some cities that was the reason why
The Grateful Dead weren't allowed to
come back because they're like oh my God
it's [ __ ] travelous circus of drugs
and then you know all the high school
kids in the area would catch oh we could
go to the Grateful Dead show stock up on
all kinds of drugs they buy acid and bu
you know all kinds of drugs and then
there would be all kinds of problems for
months after the Grateful Dead have left
town because there's this whole wake of
you
know you know it sh was fun it was back
in the day it was so much [ __ ] fun
man a wake of Freedom that's was yeah
well it was it was a real life adventure
and you know way before it got really
big like I started seeing him in the
late 70s and like they were still on
like Saturday Night Live like I was
there the night that John Belushi came
out um on stage and sang with him uh for
a song before that was in 198 80 and you
know it was just back then in the early
80s it wasn't a big thing like people
didn't really know about them and like
you'd go to an arena and you'd be able
like like um ATM was saying you'd be
able to smoke weed in an arena normally
where if you were at a rock concert
they'd bust your ass for smoking weed it
was just a different set of rules for
when the Grateful Dead came to town Bill
Graham and the other promoters would say
hey man
this group if you just let them smoke
their weed they're just going to you
know they're not going to bust chairs or
not they just want to watch the music
and come and go and again I remember
being at almond brother shows and at
Neil Young shows and other shows where I
had like a little one hitter and some
guy was giving me the flashlight all
night you know and you could be at a
Grateful Dead show and just be smoking
just all over the place great man that's
that's the beauty Vancouver because all
shows in Vancouver are a Grateful Dead
show in regards to smoking cannabis I'll
never forget the last time I was smoking
joints which was a fair while ago I saw
Neil Young play a solo show at the Queen
Elizabeth theater and I rolled like 20
huge fat joints and I wrote the names of
my favorite 20 Neil Young songs on those
joints and I was sitting in like the
sixth row on the floor right like in the
Queen Elizabeth theater in Vancouver
which is a pretty awesome venue and uh I
I I smoked one of those joints each time
he uh he did another song and uh I think
I ended up smoking like 14 of the 20 how
cool yeah it was awesome I started by
the time the song was over the joint was
still going so I'd have to pass that one
down was it just him solo Marcus or did
he have a band with him solo with about
six to eight acoustic guitars a standout
piano a
banjo and feel like I'm forgetting oh a
baby
[Music]
grand definitely a couple of shows worth
checking out it was two nights at the
Queen Elizabeth theater and I I want to
say it was like
90 six or 97 maybe I saw the Almond
Brothers the same year at the same venue
and it was also a unbelievable wonderful
experience of just mass mass puffing in
a super beautiful old school venue where
everything's like sort of inspirational
you know all the chairs are like red
Valour I mean it's not it's not it's not
a caricature but I used to
smell that Herb At The Grateful Dead
show and say that's herb not this
Mexican Brown [ __ ] or I remember getting
aaao back in the day and it definitely
had a definitely a a different flavor to
it but like many dead head kids who are
out on tour we started smoking nor cow
grown weed out on Grateful Dead tour and
there was no going back they're like oh
my God this is just a higher grade of
cannabis and the first time I smoked
blonde hash was out on Grateful Dead
tour we used to always get like the red
lebanes or the dark stuff I remember
getting stuff where you could still see
the stamp or the imprint of the hash
like the Turkish hash you know in the
New York metropolitan area but the first
time I had smoked blonde hash was yeah
out on out on Grateful Dead
tour and this quarantine got us missing
concerts no doubt I'm gonna cut it short
today we have eight more minutes I just
wanted to let everyone know that I my
son's down at the Field playing soccer
and he's uh wanting Dada to come down
and kick the ball around and what what
could you imagine being better than
after a couple of hours of hanging out
with you guys and puffing bowls and
enjoying some great dialogue I get to go
outside and run around with my six and a
half-year-old son who's just starting to
get kind of cool with soccer he wasn't
really understanding before but now he
can run and kick the ball and you know
you just uh I can see why pride is one
of the Seven Deadly Sins Not that I'm
like super religious and follow the
Bible but be careful with that [ __ ] the
love you have for your kids is blinding
it's it's it's the reason why you're a
parent and it's just it's the best
treasure that you have for all the
headaches and all the sweating and
you're worried about again bringing
someone into the world I I think being a
parent is the best thing you could do in
this life and yeah my kid just turned 24
years old man and to see him out in he's
in the industry Marcus and he's out
making hash and making a good name for
himself and he got himself a modulus
base and uh yeah
I don't know I mean to those of you who
aren't parents I guess it's something
again that you can't relate to but yeah
that that unconditional love that you
get from your children here's a good
reason they might want you to mark
because if it's not us good parents
having children who will have the
children of the future God protect
us yeah I always tell my kids when you
set foot out your our front door you're
going to interact with kids who are
parented a lot less than you so keep
that keep that in
consideration be aware for sure yeah my
thanks Marcus thanks for again having an
episode today next next month so my
that's my eldest so she turns I turned
48 at the end of the month and she turns
20 and then my son turns 18 and then my
other son turns seven all like in the
next five and a half to six months
should be fun all blessings birthday
parties yeah anyway uh thank you guys
all for coming out and sharing your time
as always I appreciate it I'm going to
go kick the ball around but uh I hope to
see you all next week where we can
continue the
conversation thanks
everybody peace man thank you take care
everybody bye
everyone enjoy your Sunday