hello can you hear me yes we can hear
you mumbling and everything no that was
me mumbling Sam
howdy Todd howdy brother and hey welcome
welcome guys we were just hearing a
little bit about the karma cup been
happening in Canada a little competition
and Sara was just telling us how there
was a hundred entries and she's giving
them two weeks to judge yes yes we are
hearing about so much of this in the
news these days especially in Colorado
and and around Denver that they're
finding pesticides particularly in
concentrate because again if it's on the
plant and it's going to be concentrated
it'll be in concentrated form and to
concentrate and certainly like some of
these products might be safe for use
with food products were it's going to be
washed off but if the cannabis is never
washed and if it's just concentrated and
god only knows what happens at nail
temperature to some of these some of
these things like Eagle I'm absolutely
convinced that is going to thermally
degrade and give off cyanide that I
don't think that that's a known
phenomena and I think that these are
things that we really have to concern
ourselves with in the industry because
what I was asking her stuff what I was
asking you more was policy on pesticide
use as opposed to pesticide testing
because um I guess the notion is is that
they've always been used now that we're
testing for them we're finding them
figure well if they're your grower and
there's a where you them and reject them
because you can actually have a science
to prove it that's your best asset just
to sit back and say hmm yeah let's let's
kind of hope no like I said you really
have to put up the money you have to
research you have to actually
you know really push your laboratory to
really get up to those standards because
most laboratories out there only doing
the THC testing and the biggest problem
that we have is you know we're dealing
in an agricultural state so we have to
deal with out all kinds of situations so
it's all about making sure that that
spectral analysis available to your
laboratory and that your laboratory is
actually going to go there so Roz
absolutely huge issue that Etienne mark
hi everybody um in California especially
but anywhere where cannabis is being
over produced it 80 unmarked either of
you have data showing different
pesticide levels and samples not
interested in the name of the I'm the
guy who submitted the sample or what the
variety was there anything else just be
interested in seeing the occurrence in
levels of different pesticides and
samples that we collected anywhere
I can get some of those for you and I'll
bring them next week - sure sure I can
show you or if you'd like I can email
you some yeah I was just on the Denver
Post article by Richard Baca that
described Mahatma extracts that had to
be pulled off the shelves after they
found out after they were already out on
the shelves that they had unacceptable
levels of I think different pesticides
mm-hmm so III know I mean I know that
there's a list of forbidden ones and
certainly I think you can use integrated
pest management in a way that you're not
actually buying these harmful chemicals
to your flowers that can be felony right
absolutely and basically the
agricultural chemicals that are approved
for integrated pest management are not
harmful to the beneficials in and fairly
lightweight in general but certainly not
armful to mammals that the big issue to
me is that at least in the state of
California you have no control
whatsoever you have advice from the
state government of
farmers normal farmers through Farm
Bureau's and through farm and feed shops
and places where they give you advice
and they ask you what you're going to
use it for and they if you use it for
the wrong thing they suggest that you
not do it it's fairly informal it's not
really a police state in California
about pesticides but they come with some
horse sense normally that the the grow
room supply shops are run like
mom-and-pop pet stores you know there's
there's nobody telling them what to do
they they get illicitly packaged avid
and flora might and all these things
that we tell you in the Netherlands you
can't buy these without a spray permit
you can't store about it without lock
and key these things are deadly
poisonous
you know when they tested the coffee
shops here did see four percent and
pesticides of fungicides
yeah even here in the Netherlands you
can you hear that yeah that's why the
cultural University and found that these
guys were not testing so that's why it
was a natural step for us to actually
reach out and grab them and bring them
into the discussion because they already
had the spectral analysis so if anybody
is thinking about doing this I highly
recommend in your local state to reach
out to your agricultural university
because they usually have a lot of that
information or have access or would know
who would yeah Mike correct rub that
that should be it it's it's a state
issue rather than federal one as far as
I understand and what we need to be of
course of self-policing
well I want to be not too rude and say
that I think it's happening everywhere
cannabis is being grown commercially I
think everybody that starts investing
money into equipment and time and plants
and then start seeing bugs and problems
they almost what are they supposed to do
you know this is the problem we have it
we don't have good policing in our own
industry and we see this happening
everywhere I don't think it's a
California thing or a No
okay I always speak about California
because that's where I'm from and that's
where I visit the most but you're
absolutely right and it's it's it's
something we need to take care of
ourselves
and we the more and more we grow it's a
self fulfilling problem the more and
more you grow the lower and lower the
price lower and lower the price the less
you could afford to toss a crop back in
the good old days when it was 4,000 a
pound and you got a crop that went bad
and you're always selling it to your
buddies you pitched it in the trash
now you dry it and we make the HMO out
of it after you've sprayed it because
you were afraid to lose it
but let me throw this out just to be
devil's advocate we've had a quasi legal
market in Amsterdam for 30 years since
8485 really going back even for other
books since the mid eighties coffee
shops have been spilling out the front
door attacks and it has the nothing to
clean up the the industry and in Holland
at all
when it comes to pesticide use
fungicides and things that are bad but
that means they don't have a market that
actually pushes and tested right now as
far as I know
Berkeley isn't sitting in the United
States that actually makes sure that you
actually test everything before it hits
the floor so it can't have something
like Mahatma happen where it comes back
positive after the fact after it's hit
the floor so I mean a lot of Education
and a lot of work still needs to happen
even in regulated societies but going
back to what Mark what you were saying
at least they're using it at least
they're finding these things science is
being used we are finding these things
because before that would have been an
issue we have to self-police I get to
quietly return it to somebody I don't
get to publicly humiliate them through
the media and say blah did this and blah
did that you know that's a whole other
industry regulation and I think what I
think Todd you wish had happened in the
Netherlands so that everybody was held
to a standard so they couldn't skirt you
know the illegalities because they're
growing in small conditions wherever
they can however they can whenever they
can growing medical cannabis
as I say growing cannabis is is easy
growing medical grade cannabis is hard
growing medical grade cannabis
consistently is an art I don't want to
make it into that big of a thing I mean
people produce food all the time that's
organic falls under organic standards I
mean it can be done I don't personally
understand what cannabis other than
prohibition cost more than Tomatoes they
flowering about the same time don't they
Rob how long does it take for a tomato
to to fully form on the vine it's a lot
easier to grow cannabis than it is to
grow tomatoes you might be able to get a
little bit more weight of tomatoes in a
given area yeah you might get more
tomatoes in a given area okay but then
they have lost some and rot they get all
kinds of problems but you can you
I remember in Lugano and buter Steve had
his tents and he ready for these tunnels
then he rented them from a tomato farmer
who had tomatoes growing next to the
steve's sweet tooth and all these
beautiful strains and this when the guy
found out what Steve was getting per
kilo I he almost fell over like he just
couldn't even wrap his head around ever
getting that much first for instance it
went commercial growers get a hold of
cannabis when it's not a gray area thing
anymore but a tall strong settles out
you'll be surprised how inexpensive
it'll be to grow a kind but you know
it's it's just another agricultural
product at that point yep sure enough
hundred dollars from a 70 year old
Christmas tree that's more work than
cannabis good old cannabis we love the
port so Rob Sam what are you guys
popping on right now
ah no some ba Joey stuff it's pretty
what's a possible sign made from focus
that close kind of not yeah we can see
it tiny piece anyone what you know me
and BHS not my favorite
so what are you smoking on Rob I just
actually haven't been smoking much
anything last few weeks I've been in
Turkey and since I got back here it's
been sorta you know same old stuff well
yeah I was in Turkey where I don't smoke
at all for the sake of staying alive
caution and staying out of jail
yeah what's going on we've all seen that
prison movie about Turkey my childhood
that movie right wait
take the guys one of the first thing I
ever saw about Turkey yeah when I saw
they'll stab you from the waist down
it's legal look I don't think I'm going
to Turkey well it's actually a wonderful
place I just did a 15 day road trip with
two really nice ladies and went to lots
of villages and talked to lots of old
ladies about what they used to do or
what their mothers used to do isn't kiss
maybe so those nice Weaver's ropemaker's
oh it's done very cool tracking down the
history of that particular areas hemp
and other textile history yeah actually
do you know the it's all about hemp but
the history there basically boils down
to rope makers who were and then making
nautical ropes for well since the 15th
century Ottoman naval stuff and they
still made their it's kinda ropes up
until just a few years ago and now
things kind of come to an end but the
rope-making the last vestige of what was
going on women haven't really woven
grain sacks and rugs and things for
about 40 50 years in those places was
that turkey Turkish growing up yes yes
all those growing right the neighbor a
lot of the the hemp for the weavings and
things was grown right in the women's
gardens they did a right close to home
and close to a water source of course
most it was whatever yeah it's it's it's
interesting it's the same land race
they're used for for hemp and also was
back in the day used for hashish that
there weren't varieties for one or the
other as I might have assumed so it
wasn't like it made sure he and strain
per se no and it wasn't like in a poll I
mean no I was like in for like an a Paul
where they use the same variety for Reb
and hashish but I also get seeds and
make textiles out of it it's not really
strong stuff it's not specifically
selected for being really strong dope in
most cases it might have been in certain
areas where they made a hashish and were
legendary for it some part of Turkey
unknown today but yeah basically when
they thrashed out the seeds they kept
the powder and that was what they and it
up happens how many plants like Nepal
would dual-use industrial and hashish
how many regions I should say word
building plants if if it was like that
in Turkey as I suspect that would be the
only other place besides an Eightball
where I know of three uses of drugs seed
and fiber all three taken from the same
standing crop not the same thing grown
three different ways but taken from the
same crop and that four seed and fiber
of course that's really common but for
were crossing over to the drug side
that's that's rare now I would assume
that back in the day
I mean since subsistence farmers even
today waste absolutely nothing in there
his produce of their daily lives that
they used plants cannabis crops 3 do you
know all 3 ways if they were interested
in the drug sighs so yeah why not there
was some THC yeah there was some THC nut
but the real abnormal of European temper
ID as we know today are abnormally low
in THC because they've been bred to be
that way
I mean just you know it is part of the
deal they're not very strong sativa is
to begin with
who knows what's up we'll find out maybe
from the Philo's project with Turkish
varieties our Afghan hybrids or
something or Indian hybrids with
European maybe they're really good
indica sativa hybrid now I have a stupid
question it's the it's it's sativas or
industrial Indo European hemp varieties
it came over to North America that we
find in Nebraska the stuff that made the
canvas for the covered wagons that went
west is this duh it was never bred to be
low THC per se correct back back now
modern the modern French and Hungarian
and other varieties regulation 2% blah
blah blah very Todd you got I mean
you're Mike and Rob is reverberating
through your mic hairy badly turned on
look go ahead Todd okay my question is
is the indo-european and varieties
around the time of Columbus those stuff
that came over to America 1500 1600 s
even 1700 there wasn't a cotton gin till
1791 so all this stuff was never bred
for its cannabinoid levels the pre EU
standards that the THC content was never
a conversation in picking for sativas as
we call them that then my dumb question
is is why is a lot of the feral hemp in
Nebraska bunk we
I think from my understanding before Rob
starts here the Manchurian strain that
was grown as a very just tall lanky
because hemp is grown 300 to 400 seed
per square metre you're talking about a
very densely glowing plant as to
supposed to the drug varietal which has
grown given usually a little more space
for some reason I'm not sure why
genetically it went the way that it did
but most of what is out there
feral has just grown so tight and so
densely as far as I know it's a
Manchurian strain originally Rob you
need to unmute yourself Rob I might be
able to do it there we go he's got it no
I don't know about it being a mentor and
stirring there there were plenty of
Chinese varieties that were brought into
into the North American hemp gene pool
and those in fact back to what taught a
snake first he's correct what what you
see escaped in the Midwest is one of
either two things it's either European
hemp that came here and was sativa
Europeans to team up what's called
narrow leaf temp varieties they were the
basic colonial cannabis if you will and
after that came breeding experiments not
to lower THC content certainly using
plants that had a low drug content and
some of those came from China and that's
really led to Kentucky hemp for instance
which is a Chinese European hybrid they
didn't know about THC until 1964 how
could they breed THC out it wasn't even
described in the chemical
wrap they did it in my in my truck
they did not beat better start over Jean
they started with gene pools that lacked
THC to begin with whether they were
Chinese gene pools or they were European
vehicles they were not selected for high
THC content by drug cultures I and I
could have said instead of THC I could
have said psychoactive effect easily
because that's really what they never
really took that into consideration when
they were greeting varieties that they
would later use for sales or for ropes
for paints and varnishes or for clothing
I was just wondering if growing an
industrial meant that the stuff turned
into a lower cannabinoid level naturally
I don't think that's basing like 80 and
inferred has anything to do with the
chemical level level of the flower at
the end of the growth no it doesn't hey
Paul we have crops are grown hemp seed
and drug crops are growing and very
narrow spacing that's so they can get
that hip stalks that they need for the
textiles they grow farther apart the
fiber be useless so it's part of the
growing him for all three crops that was
the same thing wood would hold in Turkey
if that's the way they did it which I
think they probably did back in the day
Rob where those crops self seeded from
the harvesting and making a mess or did
they actually pick a plant and then hold
those seeds and then try to like replant
was an old self seeding because that's
kind of why I thought that the more the
taller plant plants succeed the more
that seed gets spread back to the soil
and year after year tall thinner plants
become the entire crop and that would be
a form of breeding sure there's there's
various unconscious selection if you
will even if it's maybe not sterile
corrector but people aren't directly
being plant breeders and picking one
apparent they're they're applying all
kinds of different selective pressures
to the to the crop
a whole two populations and if it
depends on what they're doing to answer
your question if if people are
collecting seeds from tall skinny plants
and collected seeds from tall skinny
plants and shaking the seeds out and
collecting the powder that's kind of
selection is maybe not so important
they've they've patched together pretty
much the entire crop except the male's
which died by that point if they haven't
been taken out in useful fiber and if if
they're for instance growing them for
rope use as I just saw the way those
farmers did it is they would go after
they'd taken the the hemp when it was in
August before it's really flowered much
when all the stocks have a good fiber
content they can work the whole crop as
as one uniform batch they take those
plants they're pre flowering and around
the edge of the field where plants have
a few branches anyway they leave those
plants or seeds this is how long growers
in Southeast Asia to it so the Koreans
used to do it probably have lots and
lots of groups did it they take the
fiber first and they get the seeds later
but they're not people who also use the
plaster drug use that that's this third
factor you're throwing in there so in
that case in the case of these rope
furrows when I asked them in Turkey and
they said yeah we go back in in
September and we pull out all the plants
we didn't want and we leave the ones
that were the biggest and the greenest
they said so those are the ones are
yielding the most seed and the ones that
are still vigorous late in the year and
maybe even later maturing than ones that
have started to pass away so yeah it
depends on what they're growing it for
which selector pressures would be
important that's kind of what I thought
I know of so many harvesting practices
where's the knife you use happens to
create a certain vibration that spreads
the seeds in a good pattern so that
they're receding their crop as they're
harvesting it so there I'm thinking of
all the different uses that could go
into naturally driving the plant in one
direction or another like you said if
everyone's harvesting early there are no
seeds to self hit the ground after
harvest so it would make a big
difference what they are using to pretty
much perpetuate on their crops that
someone is harvesting and shaking the
plant and always losing a prosthetic to
the soil well don't don't want to
harvest the seed for the seed oil I mean
I would only assume that you're gonna
you know want to grab as much of that
seed oil as you possibly can and the
seed protein I mean the seed is is is
really the Golden Nugget in the crop
isn't it yeah even if they're only gonna
to reso's these it's still an outcome
that they need you know that the seeds
are precious that the concept if they go
back on the ground and there's
volunteers that come up unselected by
the farmer that's probably not likely
they rotation planted hemp at least in
Turkey and they did most places too it's
a great soil conditioner so they monitor
at a marginal a much more economic
source of protein than is soybean and if
so if you look at the the life cycle
analysis between soybean and hemp hemp
seed wins hands down and so it's just a
matter of time before that really makes
great to processed foods worldwide as
beasts more sub protein because it's
cheaper than soybean and more abundant
and actually more because that's the
higher of the pallium special yeah
that's good food that that's not however
really emphasis where I just was I never
found anybody who made hip seed oil they
did eat the seeds I never went to waste
but they basically just parched him
usually along with barley and ate him as
a snack they still do now now tragically
enough though they they don't grow the
hip seeds very much in Turkey anymore if
at all web and the markets but they
import them from as a tree
thought they'd come by ship I think from
India or Pakistan
that's right India is the market corner
and it goes mostly I've found very
surprisingly into animal feed again it's
a very cheap source of protein that they
can use the supplement alfalfa and oats
that are basically fed to animals for
animal husbandry do you know where they
grow these seed crops in India I was
wondering that when they were telling me
this I think it's mostly in a moderate
equatorial region through the Punjab
region of India is sort of one of the
classical agricultural areas where I'm
absolutely certain that again there's
just wild all around on the roadside Rob
just as you're driving through the
countryside it's just growing everywhere
everywhere yeah this is pretty small
seeds most of it it was not even as big
as the local seeds which was kind of
interesting to me it could be all my
wild stuff that's what it implies you do
bigger than more of a hand of man yeah
yeah I would agree I think the varieties
that they're actually intentionally
farming for oil and for seed purpose for
seed flour again it's a much different
variety than what's growing wild one
yeah iota since up yeah this it's kind
of sad that the cultural momentum to eat
hemp seeds is still there you can still
buy them in the markets big bags of them
but they can't grow their own
conveniently you know are economically
or whatever it's not illegal to grow
hemp seeds him
we haven't Turkey it just takes a lesson
Tom wait something's got a change I mean
this is actually a convenient point to
bring up what I saw from Lyon Laughlin
some Twitterers this week which is he's
a hemp farmer in Colorado who's grown a
crop that apparently analyzes at 0.5%
and the state is telling him that they
need to dispose of this crop it can't be
used commercially because of it's
analyzing at 0.5 and not 0.3 which is
the arbitrary cutoff
absolutely [ __ ] ridiculous to have to
throw away an entire crop now again the
the margin of error in making an HPLC
measurement is you know depends on how
the sample is handled and how it's dried
and obviously anybody who's ever done
any testing on a plant will tell you
that the top will analyze very different
than the bottom of the plant so these
state testers are basically going after
the tops of the plant that have the
highest resin content and okay they're
finding slightly out of spec higher THC
a content and allow so now the crop is
officially deemed marijuana and not hemp
anymore in always been my frustration
with them on the French EU seed with
that arbitrary number because it is
exactly that arbitrary correct me if I'm
wrong Rob but I mean we found when we
actually started doing experiments with
hemp we found even high-grade cannabis
can make some really nice huh yeah it
depends on when you're trying to make
hemp it depends on how you're growing it
it's back to that seed content but it is
going to make tall skinny stems if
that's what you want to do have a higher
fiber content in many industrial their
varieties yeah yeah when tested by dr.
Burgess yeah it just seems so arbitrary
and again you could certainly take many
many different samples and still not
have an accurate statistical
representation of the actual THC content
of the entire I mean if the notion is is
that the tops are out of spec well what
if he just waxed off the tops and just
uses the bottom for fiber uses that's
exactly what you they have to do its
batch testing and they have to take
parts of all our samples from different
parts of the plant they're not
approaching it by taking a flour sample
like it was drugs and looking for the
stoniest part that's
not the way it's done here they've
adopted the 0.3 EU stand former EU
standard it's now point two but they
didn't seem to have adopted the sampling
protocol to back it up so maybe that's
how this should be challenged by
whoever's got this correct yeah well and
then again what's the best measurement
system that they're using they're using
the HPLC method as described in the AHP
monograph for cannabis is that is that
you know so the protocol is also in the
EU regulations if they want to look it
up it's in there I don't know what they
it's GC I'm pretty sure but it's in
their way I don't think what variety of
hemp did they grow I was pointing I
don't know exactly I could actually look
into it I was actually texting with Ryan
earlier today I could actually send him
a tax and ask now because some varieties
traditionally have problems and other
varieties never have problems yeah so
well it was a cleat was it constant was
it grown seeded or was it grunts in
samia um I I don't know I don't really
want to comment because first of all
it's not making inquiries into it but
it's like if it was grown sinsemilla
that alone could have knocked it up
right I was thinking too that also the
extraction method that they're using to
analyze the sample can also affect
results I mean if you think about it
you're talking about two-tenths of a
percent difference between 0.5 and 0.3%
I mean you could mishandle a sample and
knock it out of spec you know run that
five times were the five replicates all
within this mystical margin of error I
mean all of this data has to be you
can't just say that that crop has got
5.5% burn the crop that's [ __ ]
because again even if you just look at
moisture and how that sample is handed
handled in terms of how its analyzed is
it the dried crop at 0.3% and is a THC a
or is it THC I mean these are all gonna
make a difference so I'm gonna I'm gonna
look into this and well if they're smart
he'll have it the analysis done by GC
cuz they're always a little bit lower
than HPLC yeah the problem with GC is
that GC you're sending it through a
thermal injection port at 200 degrees
and that that changes everything Manny
so doesn't raise the THC it lowers the
THC that's his problem
yes yes that's that's that's that's
correct that's correct
we just never [ __ ] around we stuck
with the Zola 2 notion that ship was
like point zero one percent and every
time the lab tested it they were just
like I guess it's industrial hemp or a
whole country basically no flaw because
my thing is this though is if we're not
well ironically now we are actually
harvesting cannabinoids from hemp
because of the CBD craze call it what
you will but I always found it a little
odd that we were having a cannabinoid
conversation when we were really
harvesting seeds and fibers and
cellulose and now maybe with
legalization in Colorado Oregon now can
we grow hemp varieties that are not
cannabinoid limited but maybe the best
expressions that could grow in that area
that's really that's really my question
and as we lose robot forest well I
absolutely I just wanted to make it in
something I think that Chris put is a
message here which is that I've heard
from hemp farmers in Colorado that time
of day when those are harvested you know
absolutely looking at the profile of the
plant during the end of flowering it's
absolutely essential to meet that point
three cutoff odds on high CBD strains
hey there's Mickey Mouse making his
first appearance on half judge isn't
that [ __ ] Mickey Mickey Mouse is an
old head yeah that's [ __ ] Mickey hey
welcome Tony and I guess welcome Brendon
Dabbs who can't even left faster than we
can say hello and of course welcome to
Chris Bennett's who came in while Rob
was chatting away
hey so Rob what do you think the first
evidence of cannabis growing for
psychoactive purposes ears based on you
know her biological data and stuff like
that I don't know I guess it's still I
don't know it's sort of back to that
same twenty five hundred twenty two
hundred years ago sort of Windows 7
stuff all moving around in Central Asia
maybe a bit earlier there Eastern Europe
oh boy it's just all that stuff comes up
about that same time tonight it seemed
like a lot of stuff I've read the
Chinese distinguished between their
initial hemp crop that they were growing
for fiber and seed whatnot and then that
of the later like Cynthia in hemp they
would call it or you know fire hamper
you know that what the GU shoes were
using likely do you think that that came
in and there were two different strains
their drug content plants then maybe be
a indo-europeans uh and then there's
already an indigenous Chinese industrial
thing because most of the even the
Chinese psychoactive purposes you know
we can see in the literature seems to
start around that same time and last
week but that date in place 100 BC on
Chen Nam you know which is yeah that's
allegorical sort of stuff but yeah
that's around that same time and later
in history Chinese historians refer to
to Western cannabis tea mom so it was
probably introduced at some point this
is later on in time that they're talking
about this but yeah there was a Western
influence wouldn't which in their case
when I'm
well what a meant that it was introduced
to the later time when they already knew
about Tama the other haps
yeah so what about think about this
recent Scythian thing with the gold
bowls and cups that were mistakenly
reported as belongs in in the press but
we're actually a preparations for
drinking cannabis yes well there there
were nice balls and if we're gonna
follow your where they came from and
you're dating in things the assumption
would be that they were from some
libation Rhossili cannabis yes yeah I
wish they were decorated somehow those
more indicative of that but that's
that's what I say about most things that
hint at what we're after but yeah yeah
well it's always hurt by some sort of
symbolic yeah drawing or something like
that you want some a little more solid
fitter welcome Tony and Brendon dab-dab
alicia's who just came into the room
we're chatting it up old school Chris
and Rob talk in history note whether the
synth Ian was coming from someplace else
you know Cynthia genetics yeah we'd have
to know genetics agenda yet the Green
crack god yes I have a question for
Robin Sam Robin am if you were left with
one genetic only one genetic what
genetic would you choose
hey Donald was gonna answer sorry to
catch her even Rob Oh Rob's muted it to
let me unmute Rob so we can hear him
chewing actually is that by myself
uh somebody long me a cell phone last
week that was really a scream now now
where are you gonna uh where are you
gonna grow this aikens it's you it's you
it's you Rob and you if you had your
choice wherever you are in the world and
you grew one strain and you were left
with one strain what strain would you
choose like a grown-up yeah you have
grown outdoors yep
respect double yep same with me you know
I I gotta say that I'm damn near in the
same boat with you guys
haze outdoors bong flowering however I
really think that a universe where I
could only grow I'm so tired of a three
years latter days could you imagine how
perfect that the resin and all of the
products made from the resolutely like
you if everyone was working on one
strain one resin and there was and there
was a legends of hash and it was like
well I've got the I've got the outdoor
haze oh yeah you too I've got some
outdoor haze yeah we've aw we've all got
the same string well let me see your
resin and then it would really be
competitive to get that resin nailed
down but at the end of the day it would
all just still be the same cereal the
same resin I I'd immediately start
working on it until I could get resin at
least the size of grapes yeah
why haven't you been
on that I have it just hasn't gotten
very far yet it's exponential they'll
grow the most right in the last few
stages what I'd like to see is somebody
really working on me it'd be a good
choice with close friend here but
working on really making hashish
varieties things that aren't necessarily
anything like the bud and a bag sort of
model that people have been breeding to
for the last 20 years more so yeah just
different try to read some different
things narrowly think outside the block
outside the box a bit would you guys
consider hash strange to be strange that
either produce a certain resin head size
consistently like good for hash like
this makes us under 70 you or what a
hash train be about robust complex
terpenes and the experience rather than
gearing it towards yields for hash well
there's two are you talking about today
in the future or are you talking about
traditionally because traditionally has
strands were strings that were made into
hashish well I just I see people say
like this is the hash plant and I'm like
I'm not gonna get a [ __ ] ton of dry sif
off of this but it might be the best
hash I've ever had in my life based on
the way it looks the way it smells
that's kind of why I'm like well look
there's two sides of hash one is like we
could just go around smelling the jars
of dry sip and that would be an
experience of itself with never smoking
it that's kind of why I'm like look I
have a lot of strains that I love and I
think this might make great hash but in
the end it might just produce a [ __ ] ton
245 you and that's not good for hash you
know for instance a friend's and so that
is is the beloved haze it has great
resin little tiny glands with lots of it
kicks your ass has a greater fiend
profile whatever it takes but it is
miserable as far as getting at any kind
of a residue from this really
disappointing dry sifting into anything
you do that it just doesn't work maybe
you can rub resin from it to get it to
work hybrid but there's yeah there's a
lot of breeding to do if you you're
just of course want varieties that have
the right terpene profile and make you
just give you whatever effect you want
also produce lots of resin that's easy
to get off the planet no matter are you
gonna do it it's uh economics in the end
is going to be about yield you know all
the restaurants going to be icing on the
cake and and a little extra Vig but
basically it's going to be how much you
can get of clean resident agricultural
unit
well that's kind of what I'm afraid of
because I think of my best yield er and
I'm like I don't want to [ __ ] smoke
grape crush hybrid just because I can
get 20 grams of 70 you sift out of it I
want to smoke blueberry when I get a
gram and a half and I just look at it
and worship it so that's kind of why I
wanted your definition of what the
flutter a path should be to be honest I
don't think you have to worry because I
bet you anything we could put pretty
much any terpene profile in any
established resin variety so I don't
think there's a big problem so I agree
we free that leaves my quick questions
in regards to that fans in regards to
when did you go across terpenes as a
modulator to connect the cannabinoid
profile well about 2000 Rob and I well I
obtained some pure THC 100% pure and
what we did was we vaporized 25 million
records mate CA yeah it was ta CA but in
here we vaporized 25 milligrams each in
the volcano on one of those little
they're like little stainless steel
brillo pad those little pads that they
have okay so
we were blown away because I mean if you
smoke 25 milligrams of hash or 25
milligrams of you get stoned and you
it's pretty good but with this it the
most describable thing about it was that
it had no individuality whatsoever like
cannabis products do it was really flat
one-dimensional kind of boring Rob I
think at the time actually said if this
is all there is to cannabis I wouldn't
be a smoker yeah if this is what you got
turned on to in high school or whatever
yeah instead of the real thing it I
don't think any of us would have really
been interested it's sort of like being
a fan of Everclear
you know the 180 something proof liquor
you can get in Nevada it's not even
legal in the state of California but
it's nothing all essentially and nobody
drinks it straight I mean you know
nobody just dilutes over the water and
drinks because they like it it's a
novelty and THC is the same thing it had
no color at all so later that day what
we did was we mixed it with a little bit
of 50% dry sipped skunk present and what
thousand loud was to create a material
that was 75 percent THC so less than 100
percent but it was also chirping rich
from the resin from the dry said when we
smoked bat the effects were twice as
strong as the pure THC and a light went
on in our heads because from the early
70s both Robert and I even before we met
had felt the terpenes might well
contribute to the synergistic effects
founding cannabis
I think one of the primary reasons was
because haze when it was tested for its
THC level was to be you know and the
high end of cannabis but when you smoked
it it was in the outer space of cannabis
I mean it was really really active and I
think that was because of the terpenes I
think that's how you thought well it
does the other amazing thing in the
early 70s and was that people started
growing cannabis you know they start
growing sinsemilla and that's when you
really noticed what the difference was
between fresh homegrown and what
imported weed of whatever kind you ever
got before what that was you know it was
eat that was a profound difference you
know just to see something fresh mother
nature density the essence of most of
the weed that you smoked back in the 70s
a moldy musty essence you know I mean I
remember my first bag of weed 1974 it
was it was moldy now that I think about
it it certainly was more I think most of
what Robert and I got even though it was
imported it was not moldy or if it was
it was very very very very slightly a
general statement that most of the
commercial weed at the time essentially
which came from Mexico was probably
fouled with with mold and all kinds of
different microbes if you look very hard
you would have found things for sure and
sound but of course is unsmoked belies
you know just when it was just playing
right yeah but okay Don dead tour in the
mid 70s by 1980 I was hooked up well
meanwhile back to terpene so we we
smoked the pure tree
THC would rise this ain't it we smoked
THC mixed with resin 5050 which rate 75
percent THC by dry weight and Wow that
that was very interesting so then what
we did here
to later we obtained all the
cannabinoids so oh the top 10
cannabinoids THC CBD CBG TV etc etc and
we also obtained the top 10 terpenes and
then we were able to try the different
cannabinoids and we found out that a
couple of interesting things like number
one if you smoke pure CBD in a fairly
large amount a tenth of a gram one
hundred milligrams then what happens is
it blocks the activity of even the
strongest dreicer - for about eight to
twelve hours so that was interesting
the other interesting thing was the THC
B is not psychoactive at all because a
lot of people that time believed it was
then we tried all the different terpenes
with THC so we tried twenty-five
milligrams of THC all double-blinded
with one terpene you know as tiny amount
as we could put it with it and what we
found out was that they're seen by
maligne tiny and a few other definitely
potentiated THC and most of the others
are a lot of the others also modulated
THC to different levels so some made to
couch lock some made you speedy and it
was like a revelation I mean we had
suspected it but we never never really
dreamed it would be that clear because
we did it with 12 different double
blinded test subjects with a hundred
questions survey before and after and we
all agreed on the same things the
different people preferred the couch
lock or the uplifting but they all
agreed that that particular compound
with THC had that effect so
laughs so this was all you know maybe 12
years ago or 13 years ago although we
started it practically 15 years ago and
it's a yeah it's it's now at first I was
afraid to release the information
because I thought people would start
coming out with skunky Sam's improve
your weed spray during mold to gold and
they have to a certain degree but what
the better side of it is when people are
extracting terpenes from the natural
cannabis sources and then adding them
back to the same that's that's pretty
benign as long as no chemicals and
solvents are being left earth
yeah I don't know what to say but the
truth of it is it it's changed cannabis
and I understand it will continue to
learn but it's really big well I'd
really like to see done is is something
much more sophisticated than we were
able to do you know and see see science
put to bear on this situation and see
what we can learn about different
terpene combinations with different
cannabinoids it's there's 140 of them
seems the most interesting Avenue for me
at the moment no right that's just what
we know so far
yeah it's over really in trace amounts
and it doesn't mean they're not
important that but about 20 of them make
up most of the terpenes and in cannabis
we smoke today but there's a smattering
of other poor other compounds and they
could be key oh so so yeah there could
be a 100 terpenes we just have an idea
yet yeah but the smaller the amounts the
less significant they are likely to be
just by odds there's probably also heavy
selective pressures involved recently
you know in a way of people breeding I
mean firmness there's or almost people
like
and there's effects they expect based on
that aroma it's this feedback loop thing
that makes it all kind of hard to study
in a more detailed way and it's and it's
it's uh it's important those things are
somehow related but they're not as
relate related in the way I would have
thought of biochemical sort of way
they're more related in in what we
individually make of each variety and
our relationship with it
it's gifts I know I'm sending the cosmic
for the scientist guy but it's
impossible to separate one from the
other I'm not even sure exactly how you
would do it statistically rigorous tests
of the terpene and can't and can happen
oh I did it'd be interesting for
somebody to set it up there's a lot more
powerful tools now that we know they are
biochemically related there's no
question about it
of course but of course but that's not
the only relationship is what I'd say
all right and I've always wondered if
they're competing pathways I mean they
use the same precursors so what exactly
is going on hard to say but we certainly
jacked up both pathways and the modern
seen some here varieties and these these
hybrids are big producers of all of the
above yeah it's not like there's a
shortage of one thing or another
they the terpenes seem to have become
sort of a mishmash and it's more now
what what plants don't have rather than
what they have in my mind that's sort of
that what makes a variety and that's
characteristic and the white smells to
me is a key chirping it has a couple of
them but also all the terpenes that it's
lacking so that it doesn't smell like
everything else it's it's pretty inbred
at this point the spaces between the
notes
how many distinctly different cannabis
varieties do you guys say if we were to
liken cannabis strains to colors and the
crayon box
how many crayons would be in that box
Rob or Sam
well there's just a couple Kanab basic
cannabinoids and all the rest of the
colors are terpenes or the vast majority
of them so you know figure it out like
that there's a hundred and forty known
terpenes but some of them are almost
just like adding a shimmer rather than a
real note Thursday then and then I put
it like this Rob you wrote in
introduction that the can of Bible there
was you know less than a dozen plants
that really ultimately shaped that hope
the whole breeding profile that the 90s
and it's the 21st century sauce so I
guess what I'm really asking is how many
different you know if you will
original strains are we really passing
around I mean it seem like there isn't
that many you know when you sit there
and we talked about haze or cush for
trainwreck or if our horse dung or a
Cali Oh
if the list goes pitch gets kind of
short is my point
and I was wondering obviously if you
guys had actually collected what we know
as modern cannabis and and and and how
wide of a selection it really is before
it gets into just a lot of hybridization
well it's already gotten into a lot of
hybridization it's already too late from
that point of view but although there's
there's several things that are going on
that are going to allow us to learn more
about these things and one of those is
the Philo's bio science project
salmon are involved with and probably
mentioned before but with this project
we're able to at this point they've
looked at six or seven hundred I don't
know maybe more by now basically
dispensary samples from six six states
thousand of them and they put together a
model from this okay
and I had I can't let you see it yet but
if it comes down to nodes that seem to
be key parts of varieties there's there
are it's hard to explain this it's not a
tree it's more of a they're carotid
related good note yeah they're they're
some varieties are obviously more
closely related to each other than they
are to other ones okay however
everything is interrelated there's
there's no little satellite that's not
related to anything else it's it's a
giant web and says a lot about with
varieties these days and how much
reshuffling of the deck as I leave
always chasin King's first canna Bible
that the introduction routes called
what's in a name and it's it came out in
two thousand I believe so this is this
is data that came basically from Sam's
seed collection seed catalog collection
from getting everyone there was pretty
much and and we also knew at that point
all the major seed company people major
like six companies so it was easy enough
to ask people if he didn't say in their
catalog what landraces primarily they'd
used to make certain varieties and then
later on which of those varieties they'd
used to make other ones after that point
in time everything the the business
became much much larger and basically
people change the names too
for whatever business reasons they had
but nobody got any mileage anymore of
telling people what was really enema
okay so that's why I published realizing
this is happening is why I published
that around that time this is 15 years
ago
since that time certainly new things
have been brought in that people had
that were not released to anybody back
in the year 2000 this is something it's
come up much more recently also so there
are new land races occasionally the
people have added in certainly in the
last 15 years the end and all this
basically people operate on cologne so
people still pop new beans and get new
materials and see it industry goes on
but all that stuff basically is highly
interrelated now when we get to
analyzing land races in the Philo's
project then we'll have this cloud which
would be like two canopy of a tree if
you want to go back to a more standard
model of lineages and as a family tree
so the land races are the predecessors
of everything we have today okay they
didn't come from outer space they came
for farmers somewhere and not that long
ago and we've been able to collect old
dead seeds and leaves from people who
still have land races and things like
this and then we're going to be able to
get a lot of the branches of the tree
that the smaller branches near near this
canopy of modern-day varieties where it
goes from here evolutionarily is a
really good question this is not a good
position to be in necessarily for a crop
plant when it happened to corn there
were flights that nearly wiped out maize
anything so there you have it it's
that's what you can learn we can learn
more from the Philo's project if anybody
wants to contribute to it I'm not that
hard to get a hold up so yeah
participate it's fun science is fun
don't be afraid of it it's fun
so take this opportunity I want to ask
Todd and Rob a combination question
because I think it goes back to
something like Mark saying like all I
got was funky moldy weed when I was a
teenager and I remember the kind of weed
I grew up on as a teenager as Jamaican
import compared to Mexican import now
when you said like weed only grow
Hayes's is it because a multitude of
factors like where you're in the tropics
these terpenes preserve well I swear
that certain strains because of the
terpenes they produce they reject mold
and they're more basically are the best
strains for shipping and transport like
Todd you've been in all different types
of situations but there's like a day
where you don't want to transport the
the stinky stinky skunk but are all were
there ever strains that you knew you
could stuff in a bag it would never go
bad and there were certain genetics that
those Terps made that strain good for
well I'll answer first because because I
have less experience in Rob you know I
think the handling in learning how to
handle your canvas is key to what what
happens to it if it gets moldy when you
you know fortunately for me I started
growing cannabis when I was only 13 and
I had to dry it in order to smoke it
so I inherently learned how to kind of
dry it and cure it I mean anything from
toaster ovens to what eventually ended
up just being patient and waiting weeks
for it to cool off and get right but
once it was right it's still a vegetable
product and if you put it in a baggie or
you put it somewhere and you're not
conscious of its humidity you can cause
it to mold up pretty easily I'm so
handling it to me is what you're talking
about ratio there's no strains because
it depends on the variety at the time of
its moisture you know what I mean like
all of these factors are working into
the conversation you know but are there
mold resistant varieties Rob
rob is muted can you unmute Rob so spoil
needed stuff okay privacy
can hear your now rub wood okay um
there are certainly susceptible roads
that's what we deal with today with this
modern poly hybrid gene pool that we
have all the varieties we have now
contain at least a smut smattering or
actually rather large percentage of
Afghan backgrounds ok the broadleaf drug
varieties cannabis indica subspecies
Afghan occur whatever you want to call
it
and these indicas as people call them
and they are indeed one indica are
predominant in a lot of the varieties
they have today and what they brought us
is an extreme susceptibility to mold
Afghanistan is a dry place there is no
reason for for a varieties to develop a
natural resistance to mold they just
wasn't an issue so before this time we
have varieties from Mexico and and
Jamaica and Colombia and and Thailand
and all these were descendant from an
Indian gene pool okay narrow leaf bred
varieties that true indica subspecies
indica and they came from semi-tropical
in tropical areas and and mountain areas
but places that had a considerable
amount of range and for them a natural
resistance to infection by mold zzz's
was a selective advantage so we had
plans to matured considerably later than
the modern-day Harvard's but they
weren't really susceptible to mold
there's a subtle other things and if you
treated him badly they could get mold I
mean you know that but you had to treat
him real badly instead of coddling them
all the time and they have mold like
today's varieties that that's that's
again the genetic background historical
background for what we see today and and
yeah it's in everything today pretty
much unless you have a variety that's
that's pre pre Afghan I guess the reason
why I wonder like I have a bunch of
plants and veg and I created a condition
in which they got infected with mold
from a maple tree and I watched as I'm
like this is the plants with the highest
you could say stem Rob terpene
production seemed to be the least
effective and I know that's a genetic
trait but I'm just looking at the
surface area of a plant a mold and the
types of terpenes that would be on those
micro trichomes that are available in
veg and when I look up those strains I'm
like okay high-end limonene and I know
Lehman in his antifungal is that some of
that attribute where I go over to the
next rain I'm like this is getting
destroyed and I rubbed the stem and I'm
like it smells like nothing I'm not
saying it's a universal quality but when
I found the weed that smelled the most
like my dad's Jamaican compressed brick
weed it was a very peppery spicy version
of Master Kush and seems that that
preservation in that resistance that
conditions where you can press the [ __ ]
out of it into a brick stuff him in
suitcase and then send it on a boat for
three weeks it seems to always come back
to a peppery terpene or a more sativa
basically that same thing I only grow
sativas I don't know much about indicas
but the tuna cush to the beating yeah I
would suggest that the peppery taste
this remaining is what's left after the
throwing for some reason half-laughs
again well I just can't hear you no I
can hear you Rob you're not okay oh [ __ ]
it was my headphone sorry
I'm sure he'll agree markets it's what
was left over and your dad's Jamaican
not just respect and Tenant but it was
what wasn't cooked out of it in transit
and and in drying and everything else it
it's what's left it's it's the
commonality of cannabis that we found in
lots of important things back in the day
in different varieties left behind
different characteristic flavors but
it's what it's what we didn't really
learn about until he grew seeds from
those like you're doing you know then
you you see the terpenes that didn't get
boiled out in transit or handling earth
any other processing that ever happens
so you know the sesqui turkey and some
of the the lower boiling point ones are
what's left in bay to carry out lean
mean human lean carry awfully knock side
yeah those are the ones usually that
give that that peppery anybody smoking
you ever used terpenes to flavor your
bomb water no but I've used what are
those things bombers you know copper
limes for fear lines so these are leaves
and Thai cooking right okay
there's fruits to grow on these things I
just happen to have a friend who has one
in their yard and they're really
limonene rich these things are just
they're just a peel basically it's
hardly anything inside there's nothing
you do that except chop it in small
pieces and fill your wrong with them
like putting ice in your bong it's a
really great thing to do with old scale
weed I learned this a long time ago this
is really good this is that terpene
enhanced I think primarily limonene is
all sweet a citrusy stuff in and they
were three yes yeah I recently did a
couple dabs with my friend Dave Malone
from green dot there in Boulder Colorado
and he flavored the bong water with a
little bit of lemongrass oil was like a
completely different dad did adapt
before and a dab after very very
different you know it's interesting
we're talking about this because back in
2003 I opened a gallery in Vancouver
called the melting point and I had a
vaporization station it was actually
called the inhalation station of
vaporization and it was about 20 plus
feet long and I had a variety of you
know all the different top-quality
vaporizers that were available at the
time you know the aeromed from Germany
and the volcano and rip tech was there
and the volatize er was there there was
a whole variety of these things and
because it was so early and really there
was a one compassion Club exist and it
was still very young we had no real
regulations or rules it was completely
not allowed and I kind of pushed the
boundaries and I just said well you know
what I'll let people bring their herbs
and use these vaporizers and sit at it
and set it up but I also what I did was
we acquired other essential oil
secreting herbs that were medicinal and
like lavender and you know like just
different things that were right right
next door to my store and we had people
come and invade these different things
and eventually people started bringing
in like pure essential oils and you take
like the tiniest little like my new
little drop of like mint and it was the
most uplifting you couldn't even believe
like some of these things were literally
giving people the effects being of being
high but in a different way from a
completely different plant oh and you
know damn near 12 years ago that we were
doing that at the old melting point
yeah mint ash someone just said what's
that yeah Roma therapy you know about to
say is listening to myself well how
about any Polonia but you know Rob you
were one of the few researchers that got
you know you and Adrian and Rob are the
few people that literally got into the
whole can of the scene and and and you
know it amazes me that you know more of
us in this don't don't go the way of the
of what you've done with him and
you know what kind of caused you to get
so what caused you that's such a broad
look at cannabis as opposed to just
being into the stuff that gets us high
they were legal they're too legal yeah
it's illegal hobby and it's it's one the
travel as well Jake she's interesting
places but it all started really I guess
because of thing of all the nature texts
and going to China and seeing a hemp
textile mill and then having time off in
China and you a little bit about 10
things already from Hungary
you know things made in villages for
people we've collected things there but
it was more like finding linens you know
it wasn't wasn't too exciting but still
part of the picture then I went on my
phone vacations at first Yunnan Province
in China not where I worked at all but
where there are a lot of minority ethnic
groups and I actually saw people wearing
things they said were made from him
and this was right about the time when
the some of the Hmong batik dyed indigo
batik dyed skirts and scraps from were
being used to make purses and bags and
things and that they were showing up
enough to have carrots and things early
ones those so that was thought to pique
my interest to be in if and I just never
looked back I started finding different
more and more different cultures that
had used temp for a long long time and
in in different ways but primarily
through their texels through their
weeding that's the thing I'm the most
interested and you know obviously your
career brought you to cannabis I mean
anyone who's picked it up is amazed with
that body of work and uh you know I'm
just utterly fascinated with the history
of cannabis and no one's ever brought it
together quite like you and Mark do in
your latest book and you know I write
books or I try to I can't imagine
experience that and I was just wondering
how long did it take you to write you
know how do you you know how did you
guys how did you come up with cannabis
evolution and that's no botany if you
don't mind me asking would be almost
twenty years ago now 19 years ago that
boom mark and I finally met each other
Mark had written his dissertation his
master's just dissertation on cannabis
and it was called man and marijuana came
out in would that have been 72 I guess
yes
and through that I wrote up in 1976 I
came up with a my way to get out of
undergraduate education and published my
honors thesis my honors dissertation
which is called a botany in ecology of
cannabis my inspiration when I went to
the library is funny Mark's book no keep
it at it Santa Barbara where I could do
it at Santa Cruz we correspondent ever
since and finally met at a time you for
ethanol a society for economic botany me
economic botany society is uh basically
a group of ethno botanist economic
botany is what we used to call the field
before ethnobotany really was that the
botany of plants that impinged on the
economics of humans became a lot more
than that it became the study of humans
and the plants they use in those
relationships all sorts of words so
through that vehicle if you will that
investigative tool death no botany which
mark was already experienced with he's
10 years my senior and a professor at
the University of Hawaii teaches the
subject um we decided to do the book I'd
already had a experience for my graduate
work I had things left from that that I
wanted to publish and we set off on this
grand project to write this book we
figured it'd take a few years and we'd
publish it well 17 years later just a
couple years ago this month we finished
we finished it
and I guess if we know it's going to
take so long we never would have tackled
it it just seems too long at the time
but when you look back at least but we
did it and it just was a growing growing
project probably half the 700 plus
citations came to us after we got well
after we get stern a lot of them in the
last 10 years last half the front and
you just keep getting more and more
information we're trying to be
comprehensive it's we wanted to have
a reference book published by Academic
Press and University of California Press
has done this and we appreciate that and
I think people feel to credible body of
knowledge I'd like it to have more
exposure mark uses anyway so uh they're
taking ideas for getting this body of
knowledge optimal people is there a
syllabus written around this book and is
this the book that will be used in
colleges when you know a cannabis course
is offered I think that most naturally
cannabis evolution and that's no Barney
will most definitely be the book that is
the required reading or the and and is
this already in practice is this
something that you're working on well
I'd like to see a curriculum build I'd
like to see it a lot more simplified
than all a massive information that's in
cannabis but yet it is a project I'm not
actively working on but I really would
like to be in it's uh it would take an
educator it would taking it an editor
would take someone who knows how to pare
down what's there and get the essential
bits into a form that appeals to people
today who want to learn which is largely
be online I would respectfully see how
much of a future in trying to to write
books except for sentimental reasons
well you know people are still reading
even though they're not reading per se
books I mean we're you know just because
they're electronically deliberate
information it's still fonts it's still
words it's still thoughts it's it's
still the same thing you know not to you
know Shakespeare Shakespeare Shakespeare
so to speak and that you're conveying a
lot of information and people who are
able to bring it in and know more than
ever I would say you know please write
more don't write less because you know
contributions like marijuana botany had
a big impact if it wasn't for authors
like you and Mel Frank I never ever
cleaned out my closet and started
growing cannabis if I had not found a
Mel Frank grow book and that's just my
reality and for you know for me to
stumble upon later your your
contribution marijuana botany I was
amazed at that and did
the way these were these were the
pebbles in the river for me to step on
as I walked across and learned in and I
wish you guys would write more honestly
uh truthfully I do and and I and I and
you know even publish it you know
shorter papers get right to the point
I mean you know now you don't have to go
through publishing houses you know I
have to wait for four big books I mean
in my opinion people like you like Mel
Frank you have if you will a literary
following where we are interested in the
stuff you're learning I get to get it
firsthand because fortunately you like
me but but the rest of the world too
would benefit from the work you do and
even if it's not these huge three
hundred and fifty thousand word 17-year
projects but you know much shorter
projects about the fascinating terpenes
and chemistry and and other elements of
cannabis that are all interconnected
right now that we're learning about in
society because everybody's learning
right now through their smartphones in
my opinion the news is coming in that's
what I'm getting out of the way to get
information out there whatever it takes
we're doing it I mean I can't because
I'm hearing and I'm like yeah you know a
good five page article on that subject
of these terpenes or why would we pick
that strain or what Jen there every
different subject we've jumped on is all
a kick-ass five-page article that you
could just go in deep on you know like
Sam discovering the terpenes then Sam
being is what you guys having access to
THC a no I was with me yes like you guys
doing that now let's say we looking at
me and bubbleman and we're [ __ ] with
the same thing
what would your article be on like when
you discover it what would you like to
see us do where would you like to see us
go like I know where I'm going in
exploring the strain not being the
strain by isolating the wet terpenes the
ones that disappear when they dry and
seeing if they modulate the strain and a
whole different profile but do you guys
ever have things like that where you
want to see like I want to deceive mid
THC a helped standardize cannabis for
hey even if it wasn't exciting for
everything else heck there's lots of
interesting things people can still do
it's uh probably more than ever really
lots of possibilities
Marcel deal wit at Mary farm I think has
a patent for using THC a for most
medical applications I believe so no
interesting to see it wouldn't hold up
in an infringement case to those so you
go ahead and patent it all you want it's
not worth the paper it's written on
thank you mark you just gave me the
go-ahead to he's using THC aid to treat
pain anything that's obvious and for
dozens of years what I've been doing is
taking all my THC a Raisa and converting
it to THC so that it was not breaking
anybody's path over the world I'll dab
to that can't patent something that's
known and obvious it's use patent it's a
medical use patent it's not a THC a I it
doesn't make a difference the use is
obvious it's known it won't hold up in
an infringement Court case of
infringement against that patent which
is why you don't see it them suing
anybody I've worked with last 25 years
I'm not a patent weird but I have a lot
of patents and I know I know what it
takes to get a patent and you know you
can get a patent
well that doesn't mean that it's gonna
hold up in an infringement case
that's definitely true
the best thing you should do is that if
you come up with something that's cool
rather than patent it just do what the
folks at coca-cola did keep it a trade
secret keep it a secret that only you
know about and then then you'll be okay
that's the type of intellectual property
you having cannabis trade secret banding
I guess you call a brand if you
trademark a brand or if you have a
branded trademark that's also a form of
intellectual property but getting
patents especially just around cannabis
or the constituents of cannabis I mean
you could come up with an end use patent
or come up with something that you think
is is new and off and not obvious what
chances are it's already been
demonstrated and if it's already been
demonstrated it's not novel and if it's
not novel it can't be an invention okay
so when did you start working on hashish
okay you were here yesterday I mean I
him California in Indiana before I
wouldn't grad school before I moved to
John Stehr dump but yeah when I got here
when I moved into a hash culture slow we
didn't in California but here there's a
hashish culture
it was the dominant deal yeah but they
didn't really have much marijuana to
speak up to be honest but for people
listening I mean you get you mentioned
what you and when you're in in college
you wrote your paper what was it called
botany and ecology of cannabis okay and
and and and then and then you follow
that up with you're in 1981 released
marijuana botany
correct and then you started working on
hashish yeah I moved
Amsterdam was at 87 maybe 1987 I guess
it was yeah 30 years ago well then just
in line of thinking of this what's your
next book project obviously now that
cannabis is finished you must be working
on something else
nice yeah I'm I'm working on another
body of cannabis knowledge actually it's
it's not going to be coming out as a
book except possibly for sentimental
value as a collection but I'm working on
trying to get this Turkish hemp
knowledge together well I have the chair
and instead of publishing something from
work I've done 10 or 20 years ago I'm
gonna do it reverse and publish the most
recent done things first and then work
back through the rest but it's all
pretty much I got a question about hash
our are you in any way looking to update
in the next you know two or three years
hashish its some of the breakthroughs
that have occurred in the world of dry
sifting in the world of rosin you know
these sort of things that are fairly new
that haven't really been written about
oh well that's an interesting you'd
mention it because at the moment the
book is sliding out of print I would say
is it's it's near future and maybe where
there was a bit of a revision a few
years ago but yeah it's maybe done its
time maybe the the new knowledge should
be somewhere else maybe it should be
written by people who do what they're
doing not me secondhand
just personally that's why I see it I
have stuff to do I mean I'm not it's not
just that but the way I think people
should write what they're doing I think
they are I think they they extend
information for YouTube and Instagram
and especially YouTube for Jesus how
many videos are there of how to do cool
stuff from a cash run those are the
people really experts these days but the
other internships you still want to put
it in print no I don't have it in that
and like the cash beats me is the is the
greatest concentration
it's the 90 micron that whole book right
it's just like you know all the best
[ __ ] let's put it all in here you know
it's like we need to have the Bible
constantly updated it's all I'm saying I
agree with you I like blast yeah
books I will always have their place
just like vinyl records you know like
people will always want vinyl they're
never gonna you know there's always
going to people that people that love
them in books that they play an
important role in the sense that one day
if some of this digital knowledge is
lost or blipped and gone that books
books can still be there yeah I like
books too I'm just frustrated by a
changes and how people favor to receive
information these days so I said yeah I
don't want to just be cranky about it
and continue publishing books just
because they're cool now if I can afford
to publish books just post they're cool
I will do that but at the moment I'd
sort of like to get so I'm not making
any money anyway I'd sort of like to get
a little bang for my not buck and
educate a bunch more people if you get
like my drift
I mean give it away I didn't make any
money on the book anyway I don't foresee
making a heap no matter if it comes out
in paperback but no matter if they'd
make the Kindle a lot cheaper whatever
it's near crypto how about the
sheesh app okay now you're talking you
know I really respect you saying that
Rob I mean I as someone that tries to
create projects like the culture high or
the Union or my first book or any of the
things I've worked on like the Emperor
it's about transmitting information and
sharing this knowledge and you don't get
paid on any of that stuff it's all a
labor of love and you know you put
seventeen turns into a book like
cannabis there is obviously only return
you think that is the good feeling you
get from sharing it with the politic but
I'm so enthused yeah I'm doing it I
don't think there's a real great kid you
know really reward you for the
contribution you played in helping us
understand what you've learned and
communicating that so thank you very
much well thank you Todd
we also spent 15 years with publishing
the IH aid the Jha Journal of the end of
the International emphasis science-based
about it but you know I was sticking
with Hershey's you know when I first saw
the journal in the 90s I was blown away
and these educational kits that you put
together were fantastic I was fortunate
enough to buy one back in the mid 90s
that had crayons and oil and fabric and
all of these wonderful elements of
teaching and you know this is something
I would love you guys to talk about
because you really took an association
into a peer-reviewed level and actually
created a little textile kit that you
could touch feel smell and learn what
cannabis wasn't and no one in the world
has done that thank you guys and I want
to say thanks for that but how the hell
did you get to that in between your hash
and your cannabis growing on Emma
crayons we did have a little free time
but no it was art kind of ideas that
that Sam and I could cook up together
you know he was one of the pioneers in
doing this really and it
just needed a a group that was was
really devoted to getting real
information out to people whatever it
was it called the International amp
Association but there's really the
International canvas Association and
Dave pate also helped us Avery is
instrumental in this and I evander were
four oh yes I and I yeah we had a good
we had a good team gone but and we
solicit articles through all over the
world it was really pretty cool there
was a lot going on in the in the early
90s that in a lot of ways
more variety of things going on than
today there probably more people
involved than ever that European
industrial hemp Association just met a
few months ago and I think they had
close to 200 delegates this time now a
bit of this is the CBD buzz because it's
become hemp issues but to write lease I
suppose but that's so so that's a little
bit a bit of a bump from that but still
I'm saying that that's a lot of
Delegates to go to an industrial hemp
meeting so and therefore pretty
international bunch I saw yeah when we
got her was just it was just becoming
legal to grow hemp again in large parts
of Europe especially well that that
effort yeah I wasn't effort we could
could help with it we helped with a
Vavilov Institute trying to preserve
what but genetics they had I'm not sure
in hindsight how successful we were and
how unsuccessful I'd been before we
started working with them but we'll find
out that we were the finalists project
again yeah we we were successful in
helping them out and keeping things
alive it's just maybe if the collections
we preserved weren't as pure breeding as
we might hope they would be somewhat car
legs work showed this and it's it's been
interpreted other ways but that's
probably just contamination and I'm
trying to keep open pollinated lines
separate they had over 400 of them which
they produced in about nine different
facilities or something back to Soviet
days but as all I fell apart
we took a money and help them get
freezers and do all that stuff they
needed to do to keep up had a lot and
grow some of it out I know that apart I
know that the part of the collection
just moved into the hands of ben
dronkers and hem flax and I had the
honour of visiting a test plot where
they had 200 different varieties growing
simultaneously and there was you know
the gentleman
and all the all the readings and such
and it was just great to see the
diversity in the varieties of hemp that
you know came from the Bella and that's
only I believed not even half of what he
got from them Turner from Dara sessions
just a hybrid between two of them and
then polished up from there so that
shows you what what gene banks can be
good for right there yeah I actually
made the hybrid and gave it to Jase
Calloway Jess ran in Finland defense
finola my high oil content was able to
survive under oh I don't know if you can
hear it not but what's even more
important is that it's the highest seed
yielding
it'll get two tonnes per hectare where
most varieties can barely get a ton yes
it makes sense I wonder if it's the oil
content or it's just the amount of seeds
that you're getting is just like double
just a little short plant with a great
phenotype for Percy production yeah I
started to speak about it in Vancouver
at the hemp symposium that they threw
here one year in the 90s I was there I
spoke at it so they you know for those
of us that are still in the world where
we're calling stuff sativa and indica
obviously cannabis evolution and that's
no botany you kind of move away from
that you know could how do you see us
classifying the current cannabis that we
smoke in a more appropriate manner well
let's talk about the cannabis we don't
smoke that would be cannabis sativa you
mentioned it earlier
this is the represents the European or
at least Western Eurasian traditional
varieties that were used for fiber and
oilseed and those became the earliest
sessions taken to America our room to
route all the rest of the cannabis would
call that cannabis sativa what Carl von
Linde a Carlos one is called cannabis
achievements it's not breaking with
tradition it's following tradition and
then the rest of the world apart from
that cannabis all the rest cannabis in
the world except for Western Europe
North America and a little bit in South
America and Chile couple other places
it's all ended all over whether it comes
from Afghanistan or India or China Korea
or Thailand some version of indica now
this is based on basically what Karl
hillock figured out using isozymes
differences in protein throughout the
differences in DNA as people for more
prone to do today but this is all I
researched it was published ten years
ago and Karl basically showed through
the diversity of these compounds and
terpenes and and phenotypic
characteristics as well gross phenotypes
that there were these differences and at
the large encompassing group was
cannabis indica divided into if you
don't include the supposed wild or
escape types type then three subspecies
basically indica subspecies indica the
narrow leaf drug varieties from India
ones that Lamarck had described and
originally called cannabis indica and
that's once again following traditions
this is a main subspecies this is what
we had before we had things from
Afghanistan Mexican Colombian Jamaican
hi all have came from the and all the
African branch - yes came from South
southern embrace came from India
originally from the Indian ganja right
marijuana was the other one that we know
for a second is like actively making
hash over there sounds like you got a
roto go in the background so big we can
completely back me 43 kilos and 200
grams of hash
during Hester yes this is real really
and he it's making history
it was so repetitive it's so long there
was only so many things that could be I
knew he wasn't subtly drumming to his
beat in his own head I knew that wasn't
it I knew wasn't it was motivated by I'm
gonna get high later ok I'm jokin
makes me want to smokes man the average
the long story but it's all make it as
short as possible there's the Chinese
varieties ok
they were also first capital and seed
primarily drug culture least not in
recent history and that would include
Korea and Japan and those varieties are
broadleaf temp varieties as bright as I
ended up calling and wide leaf varieties
as problem and then there's of course
Afghan that's cannabis indica so species
Afghan Achatz the broadleaf varieties
that's what came to us you know starting
in the late seventies and then has been
hybridized
ad infinitum with the original narrow
leaf drug rise we had and that's what
you is what we have today so that's
that's how we see the hi-c mark and I
see in others John with Portland and
Carl Hill again when Ernest small though
he just just published a foot long paper
and renamed them again which I wasn't
quite sure the need to but anyway we all
are even up for a pretty much from the
side management yeah Sam's figures it's
about right that's it'll be interesting
to put the finest project to work and
see the interrelatedness of the the land
races that were around and and back in
the day when they were first around and
ones that were found where they were
originally from and put them into this
project and see how they are
interrelated this is the evolutionary
side that fascinates me I kind of know
what happened in the historical side I'm
much more interested to figure out what
I don't know the predates the my
historical side guess your awesome
someone's asking about Japanese strains
someone's saying do you guys know any of
anything about any Japanese friends the
job yes have one registered yeah few
other land races Rebecca Mona
yeah they use them to make kimonos
ceremonial kimonos it's a really rare
expensive fiber oh yes they do go out
there well that's been mostly a place
called Tochigi ken and that's and what
the girls Tochigi sure I mean it's white
Toshi
- Chi Chi so I guess you saw the article
where they went and actually met with
the women who actually made the garments
and their teeth are worn from pulling
the hemp with their teeth yeah
separating the fiber
now I split the strips of barking and
narrower strips of bark yeah they ran
out of fingernails finer in Japan or in
Korea or in China the finest of the
finest you've ever seen how the finest
temp weaving here being sheerest him
finest yarns thinnest cloth would be
Foom Japanese or Japanese style cloth
made in Korea
you could also say but yeah it's
incredible it's like I asked a paper
question who's making the best paper in
the world right now I really don't know
that there used to be a mill that did
cigarette papers he stopped still in
Turkey but it's closed I just was I
think it's in Spain now spans got solos
solo so right natsu no solo yeah
Schneider song was the paper supplier in
Germany they're a big paper splasher
you're so good they they made custom
batches for us right
but we're brown ones iRobot can we print
journals on just to be patriotic like to
point out that we have tried to link to
your international hep association org
website and the links to the journals I
don't work I get a borrow for two if we
could request if you all get that fit
yeah maintain is a labor of love so yes
a few days ago worked according to Sam
so it'll probably come back on again
it's a bit difficult to search articles
on it it isn't really indexed you have
to go to each issue and see what's in it
sort of it's not not just smooth but
it's been up there for ages
it's done by one of them do you think
there's an apology's no I was gonna ask
is there an economic reason why a hemp
is being used more for paper and
cardboard packaging yeah it doesn't make
much sense to grow fibers unless they
have for things like packaging unless
they have a very high end use
I mean hemp flax can grow hemp fiber and
get it into mercedes-benz car door
panels and stuff but it wouldn't make
they wouldn't be able solve for enough
if a paper process your bonnet there's
also probably a limited number of paper
mills that could work with it anymore -
but that's another consideration but
even if there were but what doesn't
travel economically it needs to be done
on a local basis paper making is
polluting well yeah I mean not that just
a point the fact is is that you're
you're using mostly waste from the wood
and lumber industry to essentially turn
your into any marker and pulp that's the
real story mark you need more help
that's why there isn't enough for
anything and exactly as Rob says it
needs to be grown locally in processed
locally I've made enough paper dust
which basically they have to get rid of
they're now mandated in the lumber
industry that then everywhere else that
they make [ __ ] to get rid of their
weights responsibly they can actually
sell it to a paper mill if it's the
right quality form some of it at least
and so that's a kind of a win-win
situation for everybody they don't have
to get much for it then they gotta get
rid of it so that's what you're
competing against with any natural fiber
it's it's not just about hemp you know
it's
whoo flax I have the same problem it's
why we had such problems with dealing
with hemp in Eastern Europe we were so
landlocked to ship or move it to actual
factories to process it or strip it down
into you know fibers spin it into a
fiber then ship it into the manufacture
that puts it into a cloth etc etc so the
herd and everything is lost along the
way and it's really kind of a waste
because it's just not enough of it it's
mostly grown for the fiber itself mark
you know current or it was back when we
were dealing with it in Eastern Europe I
I guess the way myself as an industrial
chemist the way I look at it is that
it's died you lost it's also the
cheapest form of cellulose at the end of
the day is gonna win and so whether that
cheapest form of cellulose comes from
off of the floor at the sawmill because
the sawdust just happens to be there
when you're making two-by-fours and
lumber okay I get that but the other
thing that we have to take into
consideration is that there's a whole
lot more chemicals that are used to
dealing by wood than 2d lignified ham
hams got a whole lot less lignin in
there which is basically what you're
doing in a paper mill you're just
separating the lignin from the cellulose
because the cellulose is what the paper
is so at the end of the day you know I
don't know if ten years or 20 years down
the road at some point half pipe is
gonna be a more economical form of
cellulose and will replace wood that's
just an economic reality well we're
hoping for so we're just starting to see
test trials here in America in certain
states now due to you know the legality
and we're gonna see you know we're gonna
see a whole new industries come out of
it we were talking 20 years ago you know
all the 50 thousand products that can be
made etcetera etc but when the rubber
hits the road you know Ben can only sell
his herds for animal bedding no that's
what worked that's what we're tech
anomaly that's what worked locally right
no that's going to happen locally and
regionally as these things come to scale
that's
the reality is it's cheaper in excess
all right what's gonna happen and I
don't know if Rob would agree with me on
this I think the main driver is going to
be protein production in the hemp seed
protein production in the hemp seed is
going to be the economic driver that's
basically going to bring help to a scale
of farming that again is going to create
a huge volume of cellulose that's going
to be cheaper than sawdust well I can I
can tell you that the the protein and
the seed is exactly what that we grow
hemp for in Canada for 20 years but it's
not to make it cheap it's it's expensive
that seed sells for like almost $15 or
something for like a little like 400 ml
bottle or something like that so it's
become about the most expensive product
that you can get is this protein and the
protein powder isolate that's the
byproduct of pressing the seed cake to
again if instead of instead of Roundup
Ready soybeans all throughout Manitoba
and and and and Western Canada imagine
if instead of soybeans those were hemp
plants right and those were having it's
creating hemp seed for hemp seed protein
it will happen someday because and it's
just it I think we drew 33,000 hectares
last year in Manitoba Saskatchewan and
Ontario which is not a pimple on the ass
of what's grown in terms of soybean and
corn right oh god no or any like flax or
any of the other stuff and many of the
wrote Roe Grove typical row vegetables
we wrote industrial crops
yeah we still we have millions of acres
of farmable land millions of acres so
it's just a very small percentage of
that that's for sure and it's because
we've never turned it into paper we
never turned it into products I've
always considered the fact that the
infrastructures are truly immense they
are billion dollar infrastructure people
think it's just plug and play and
they're like oh let's just use hemp for
this instead of this and well just like
you don't even have to change
in fact you do have to change everything
and you do change a lot of things for
certain things and I agree with a mark
that should there be enough seed grown
and seed burden seed is the most viable
thing to do with that but always has
been since that movement changed you
know the way people were thinking about
hemp it's the fiber things falling away
pretty much and where's the paper and
that the seedings carried on did if that
really does take off then of course
you'd have a by-product from that you'd
have the chaff whatever they need to
chop it up and get rid of it like any
other industry they can put it back on
the fields you know the lumber companies
can't really put it back in the forest
but great there are no planets but there
could be a surplus of stuff one thing
I'd like to mention is that when the
hemp thing was going 20 years ago you
know in 15 20 years ago was that its
heyday would say it was really
fascinating there's a lot of energy to
it and and looking back probably a lot
of it was premature I think now is a
much more opportune time for somebody to
try to get involved in hemp business I
mean cannabis has you don't have to go
around telling people that hemp is
related to cannabis
oh yeah cannabis fallout I mean the
times have completely changed now yeah
everybody knows what canvasses everybody
knows that out comes from everybody but
a lot more people so it might be
interesting to see you know if somebody
launches something these days with a
little bit better supplies of raw
materials possibly even if the Chinese
Mills are still rocking and you know
Ben's trying to get online in Romania
it'll be interesting to see how the the
second wave of the health industry turns
out yeah I'm excited to see how that
transpires because after being part of
the initial one that kind of fizzled it
was there was a great deal of enthusiasm
and
still is and it's great so the h IH has
had its you know gathering and of people
and such and there's just leave
innovation and more pushing but again
they're still made by this you know this
fictitious EU seed that I think is limit
ating somewhat to the industrial ideas
that we've been presented about cannabis
but I still think that you know Ben and
others have proven through you know
firsthand realities even though I mean
Ben himself took 17 years lost to make a
profit
you know out of hemp flax so that's a
great deal of of time money research not
many people have that so again respect
for even having that opportunity to do
that but he's led the way for many of us
to see that yes it can be done because
my car outside has his hemp in it right
now you know and that's a beautiful
thing but yet a frustrating thing
because I still have to tell people
about it they still don't know about it
they still don't understand its
possibilities no it's really right now
it's it's a long way to go it's it's
it'll be fun to see how things change
and I think the food products the whole
seed thing is really all this has been
the biggest interest to me it I like
that the fiber and I like all the
interesting costumes women make and all
that but when you hear and talk about
the seeds and what they're good for and
out they've eaten him for years and then
you realize that that's mostly even more
important especially in places that have
marginal supplies and oh especially in
areas of the world where people don't
have enough to eat or people are dying
or they're not getting a nutrition
enough diet that you know this can this
can be mium be a matter of life and
death for a village spirit yeah for most
of those places those that are starving
if you think about it for a minute
they're not places where you can grow
hemp so it's not like we're going to
have people employed grow their own food
it's gonna have to be an aid thing you
have to ship it like rice it's gonna
have to be grown where it's temperate
you know climates when that's North turn
North Americans your issues well right
now they're too busy plowing down the
the rainforests to make room for more
cattle ranches so we could have more Big
Macs and t-bone steaks in the world
underground more soybeans to feed those
animals to to bingo
yeah so what watch wallet all the
hempseed that should be going to human
consumption bo barking t-bone steaks
right I'm gonna spine off here I'm a
meat-eater we gotta meet sometime
awesome Rob it's always much love
respect
bye bye everybody guys enjoy the evening
in Amsterdam bye