hey what's going on everybody Welcome to
Bubble man's world uh welcome to Hash
Church episode 154. two away from our
three year anniversary we wanted to give
a shout out to all the guys and gals
hanging out in the chat room little
silver diamond gianski's OG slab and of
course melty heads who gave us a good
laugh this morning and uh Sean 8033 for
joining me on my wake and bake the other
day
and I guess uh I'm gonna send out the
links to our panel our esteemed panel so
let's see how that works out
it's always interesting to see who will
come in first generally it's going to be
Etienne for the most part he seems to
make it his way in first although I
should say
155 of you have already made it in so
maybe atan isn't first maybe today he's
going to be like
160th all right so I've been pulling off
yeah let's go indeed Rand core in the
house
I think we should get going send out
some links here
oh Etienne has seen the link
oh see oh and there it is you know it
doesn't take etienna very long within a
minute two minutes tops and he's in the
room welcome Matia good morning sir oh
it's so nice to hear your voice too I
thought you might have pulled one of
these on me no I restarted my computer
beforehand to make sure
do you know how long I've been doing
that for
uh it's amazing because sometimes you
don't and everything works fine in like
last couple weeks everything I have it
set up the night before sit down and get
out and I'm like
oh I know
well I hope you're having a good week
this week I'm looking forward to another
nice episode of hash Church nothing
major planned but I did invite in um oh
I was asking forever flowering
greenhouses if you wanted to come back
in I invited Peter from soil balance and
Wade and Forest of course from the
caladrius network in the house of
harlequin
and then the regulars you know lots of
little regulars d420k and Skunk Man Sam
and Tony and yourself and whatnot so
I don't know I think it's you and me and
we should just call
what do you say there again
oh I think that's very doable
what's your puffing on today
I got a little bit of full melt a bubble
hash that I'm uh working away on here
what flavor
this one is holy grail but I do also
have
um V
foreign
[Music]
I was just showing my entries that I
have for the karma cup the I guess I get
to be a judge for the solventless entry
so I think they sent me uh they sent me
11 different entries here so throughout
the episode I may hit one or two and
write a few things in my little my
little book here you know with the uh
they got all the categories written up
quite quite beautifully here for the
karma cup how many uh how many samples
are you going through I've only got a
to go through for solvent list but I
mean if you look at her actual contest
she's got Indica she's got bud hybrid
she's got shatter hybrid shatter indica
you know pages and pages and pages and
pages of things she gets a lot of
entries into this contest so different
people are judging different aspects
like some people exactly or some people
are having Edibles and yep so these are
experienced people I take it that are
doing it or they're people who pay to
get these I think she has a selection of
both people who are I mean the karma cup
is kind of a Roots cup it's still very
much like um
it hasn't really transferred in I'm not
sure if you see it down in California I
would suspect you absolutely do but here
in Canada
there there are these cup type events
and there are these conference type
events and they are both very very
different one is very roots and one is
very corporate and so you know with the
corporate events for instance at the end
of the conference everyone actually goes
over to a bar and drinks alcohol
and so that's not happening at the karma
cup I mean some people might go and
enjoy an IPA or a beer or whatever but
for the most part it's a it's a puffing
event for puffers and that's exactly who
will be there hardcore puffers how's it
going Sam
how to howdy howdy
is it a numerical scoring system in that
little grid like do you have like three
and a four and a one and a two yes
exactly it goes one to nine and then the
other cool thing cool thing is once
you've done all your voting you can
actually she's giving us a pass right
you get your pass and I won't show it
but on the back of my pass there is a
username and a password and that allows
me to go online and transfer all of my
book information onto computer so the
book is really for you to have to keep
your information because who the hell is
going to sit in front of a computer and
puff 12 varieties and and and you know I
like to be around out in the world wake
and bakes end of the nights all these
different ways that I like to hit
something that's a smart way of doing it
because that way you can carry the book
with you wherever you go
you know go along and then when you sit
down at the computer put all the data in
there but the cool thing about having a
numerical scoring system is now you can
do statistics on it and you could do
data analysis and you could do all kinds
of different algorithms to look to see
what kind of Trends you see in the data
so that's totally cool and Sarah is very
computer savvy she worked for years in
I.T she's very smart capable girl and I
would say that is that is exactly
something she's going to be doing
that's outstanding people love data data
is awesome if you can get your hands on
data and you're a data person yeah you
love that that's it
exactly well I'm going to start it off
with a big old rip of some of this
bubble hash
hoping everyone's having a really nice
Sunday afternoon even though it's not
afternoon yet but it is afternoon for
skunk man Sam
and maybe
late afternoon
yeah right what do you like it's six
o'clock at night right now
607. all right well here's the 607 in
Amsterdam
noon on the East Coast so I
so uh what's happening in Pennsylvania
there uh doc
oh all kinds of things going on out here
so the first uh uh groups that have uh
field tests Harvest for hemp are
happening like in this last week or so
and so a lot of hemp crops are getting
mowed down which is cool to see and
um I was communicating with uh one Adam
Thompson who's a farmer up in Lycoming
County in Pennsylvania and they're
turning their stuff into uh a seed oil
so they'll be selling hemp seed oil and
making hemp seed oil from their their
I don't know Sam I I think um uh they
shared it with me once before and I
think we talked about it on hash church
but I can get back to you on that are
they churning the times back into the
soil or what are they doing
um you know I don't know and it would be
a great thing to get them onto
Ash Church sometime to talk about
exactly what they're doing with it the
only limited acreage uh plots so they
can't really do a whole lot in terms of
scale of economy that to actually make a
a profit so they're very limited and you
have to be tied in with the university
and there has to be sort of like a
purpose to what they're doing
I know that one of the plots is
specifically for um
uh phyto remediation of uh of a fouled
former uh steel mining site where I
guess they mine steel ore and there's a
bunch of you know maybe not desirable
Farm soil and and maybe a lot of
leftovers from the mining industry and
the steel industry that just sort of
left a field that was kind of like
cruddy it was too cruddy to plant corn
but they threw hemp seed down in it and
the hemp took off there so I think part
of it is to reclaim land but each
individual plot I think has to have some
kind of research project with a local
University tied to it but I can get an
update and I'll come back on
I would give a shout out to Joe Strobel
and Jeff Keim from Ontario they were the
ones that accidentally really kind of
figured out the the vital remediation
properties of cannabis by planting it on
Tobacco fields in between Seasons oh how
about that it was their first
experimental field and they knew the
radiation levels of the field because
they've been spraying radium-226 for
decades on it and so when they
registered when they when they went
through and and measured the plants they
were shocked at how much radiation they
had in them but they were then shocked
as well at how much less radiation was
actually sitting in the soil and that
was that was got to be 1993 and that was
really the reason our company cgp
started the um Chernobyl
phytoremediation project in the Ukraine
so that was it was done long before the
90s in Europe they were experimenting
with it in the 60s and 70s the 80s also
but radiation
with radiation or just heavy metals
I know there was especially heavy metals
exactly radiation I'm almost certain
they had no idea it could pull up
radiation until the 90s
yeah I agree because when I went and
dealt with that Ukrainian hemp and then
of course there was a study that came
out in um at the bio fock in 97 talking
about how uh this industrial
um uh heavy metals plant in Poland they
had done a similar situation where they
remediated it with growing up happen
they were astonished by that was one of
the first really big ones that wasn't
just a small trial no no it was really
big and it really pulled up
um a lot of the heavy metals and it made
the um
the soilologists really sit up and look
and rethink about how to reclaim lands
using you know natural biodiversity as
opposed to you know in the past just
scrape the land off and move it
somewhere else
then they had to figure out what to do
with the contaminated hemp exactly well
not only that they had to figure out
what to do with the contaminated land
and I found that out being Growing Up in
Southern Louisiana all those levees and
all that land that was built up that's
all contaminated land I knew because I
would go as a kid and roll down those uh
levees and find 13 17 19 leafed clovers
um trippy that ain't good luck no really
lucky the two options we were looking at
was uh burning and glossifying the Ash
and then the other one was an electron
scan electron cluster scientist from
Russia who was it was using electron
clusters to manipulate and and sort of
you know take radiation radioactive
nucleotides just literally take them
apart molecule by molecules so he had
this technology and I I remember that we
were sitting down uh talking to him at
one point in time not sure whatever
became of it though hey Sam are you
familiar with there's I know there's a
group uh working on
um growing hempin uh Fukushima to uh see
about if any type of remediation been in
contact with them unless one of the
Japanese groups that we were in contact
with years ago and I just don't know it
okay because I know I mean since we're
talking radiation that's the only one
for sure sure that I know that's
currently ongoing where they're trying
to figure out if there's
I mean we all know that's an
uninhabitable area for a long time and
way to clean up soil but uh what what
they got to do is figure out some way
that they can make uh rockets that they
can shoot these things into space or
something so that we can get rid of the
contaminated hemp once we got it that
sounds like it's about as good of an
idea as like pushing our sewage into the
ocean well don't they make fireworks out
of uh hemp uh burnt hemp carbon I'd
heard that in China really I've heard
that but I have not seen or one of a
manufacturers that seriously goes to
show that there really truly is 50 000
commercial products that you can make
out of hand
it's ridiculous
do anything you can do anything with it
it's kind of like a like a Snead
remember the old beneath from The Lorax
everyone needs a feed
yeah I see why the religious right
basically thinks man this is too good to
be true there's something wrong with it
yeah they all think we're insane they're
like oh my God they're wearing it
they're eating it they're smoking it
I have a friend who actually took the
old uh decorticator
um recipes from I mean the
the plans from back in the 30s and has
now made his own decorticator here in
America and is now working on
cellulastic plastic so we're gonna
investigate possibly making you know
these Lids that we put on our our uh
cannabis Etc he's gonna start looking at
making them from plastic from hemp well
shelled hemp seed you could start with
that so you've got a food product and
then you need hemp toilet paper so you
can get rid of your food product
[Music]
good call good call because cutting down
ancient trees to wipe [ __ ] off your
a-hole it's not the real most
sustainable great idea like I don't know
who came up with that idea but I suspect
it was under the influence of like
alcohol or some other shitty drug
you mean the caveman didn't have Scott's
toilet dish oh dude listen I've had the
best argument I ever had in Thailand
when my friend's wife was arguing with
this other girl about you know the North
American girl was like oh how do you
guys not use toilet paper that's
disgusting and then the Thai girl was
like you guys don't wash with water
you're disgusting and the end of the
argument was would you just wipe [ __ ]
off your arm if it got on your arm or
would you use some water and some
foreign
teach their baby cubs to lick it off
there you go well I'm not licking it off
but uh we're a strange punch the human
the human uh I think we need to restart
the world but Day program and get the
days out there again you don't need
toilet paper you just use the toilet and
Goa where a pig will uh snip up your
butt
the Truffle Pig
oh man
talk about service with a smile
oh man I think I'll stick with the bidet
I don't need that bacon uh the bacon day
yeah in the Middle East everybody just
wipes with their left hand so there's no
shaking with your left hand so there's
no toilet paper just a hole in the
ground any anybody who's a Thief what
they do is they cut off their left hand
so they have to wipe with the right hand
nobody will shake their right hand if
they only have a right hand
yeah careful one shaking with the left
hand in uh in parts of Asia and uh
literally hands down
down oh my gosh sometimes it just goes
deep it goes deep here on hash Church
it goes deep in Beaver Terps that's
better oh my gosh
but what else is new in the wonderful
world of cannabis here
well we got Natasha Dr Natasha is in the
room I think it's been a couple of weeks
since we saw you how are you doing
hey guys can you hear me okay we can
hear you great yeah it's fine doctor
nice to see you guys
yeah I've been taking uh my Sundays to
have some relaxation time the last few
weeks
um getting some Forest time in uh always
essential
which is very nice and we're fortunate
here in Vancouver we have access to some
amazing forests with
um
really amazing trees that are so big and
just
really you feel like you're standing by
something just like another being like
I've never felt like that around trees
necessarily before but when you're
walking through these old growth forests
here it's just
really you feel like
lawyers up there or are they just
redwoods
okay thanks yeah I'm not actually sure I
don't know my my trees very well but my
neighbor
my neighbor planted a sequoia in her
front yard 35 years ago and you should
see this tree
what do the Sequoias look like which are
the sequoias
I think they're the biggest trees on
Earth they're large redwoods yes exactly
yeah they have a large uh stem but they
have a very shallow root system so they
tend to grow in groups otherwise they
can tend to fall over in storms they're
similar to the big Douglas Firs that
you're seeing in our forests when you
know those huge trunks
steroids with the agaricons and the and
the and the the the the red belts that
grow around their bases and stuff
I uh yeah the uh
systems you see with these big trees are
also outstanding in the different colors
and I mean you're seeing blues and
different
well you're also dealing with them yeah
that you could drive a 16 wheeler
through it sideways without touching the
without being taller than the Sequoia
was wide there's a red belted one two or
three that I photographed in my my son's
school in my neighborhood here has an
old growth forest for the school ground
that's it's just in the forest it's
Trails it goes over creeks and stuff
it's totally huge and they just release
like four to seven year old kids into
this Forest every day and it's uh it's a
pretty cool school ground I gotta say
well to tell you the truth you know we
don't own these old growth forests we
hold them in steward-ish ship for the
Next Generation we should save them they
should all be saved there's a
biodiversity in them that's amazing when
I was in West Virginia there's virgin
Hemlock forests uh not too far outside
town and it's a little Trek to get there
but when you get In Those Old growth
forests everything around you from the
ground to the canopy is so unique
compared to other forests that you're in
because that biodiversity has been left
intact as opposed to you know destroyed
temporarily and never rebuilt through
logging so it's an amazing thing that if
if you're around and you have access to
go to a virgin Forest somewhere around
in your state or a province I highly
recommend if you've never been go in sit
down and just look yeah another one that
you might want to check out Natasha is I
could take you and David up there one
day it's just north of Whistler on
Cougar Mountain and there is an ancient
Cedar Forest there and the trees there
are bigger than any of the ones that
you've probably seen unless you've gone
to Vancouver Island to specific areas
like north of Tofino strawberry Island
you won't mirror Island you won't have
seen trees this big they're like you
know they're not as big as the Cali ones
you could pretty much almost drive a car
through these ones they're about 14 to
15 to 20 you know feet in diameter
they're huge like you pull up to them on
a dirt bike and it's you just feel like
a little peanut
it's pretty awesome yeah
that would be uh that would be amazing
to check that out
um I think the biggest tree place that I
went to check out was on Vancouver
Island near Nanaimo I can't remember
exactly where it was but it was about an
hour outside in Nanaimo we went to some
Forest that was a preserved area with
some special sort of trees I mean
horrible job explaining this but I
remember we went there specifically for
the trees and just I mean I I don't
necessarily want to just walk through I
want to go and like sit with the tree
and just
I don't know it's it's different than
um like I'm not the type of person where
I really feel Vibes or those kinds of
things like I I understand other people
do feel that
um but
in my general life I just don't feel I
don't know I don't say I'm like super
connected to feeling my surroundings but
when I'm around trees like that it's
just it's different
um and and so it really makes me want to
just sit there and um I don't know just
it just uh next to ones that are really
old and the Fallen they've uh cut
through the entire trunk so that you
could see the Rings and uh shown you
know on on the tree where Christ was
born and before for people that want to
check out photos of what Natasha was
talking about if she was in Nanaimo
looking at ancient trees it would have
been in McMillan Provincial Park and it
would have been Cathedral Grove which is
right off the highway in between
Victoria and Nanaimo and it there are
spectacular trees there but I'm telling
you the ancient Cedar Forest North of
Whistler
it's totally trippy the sound is insane
it's like quieter when the trees are
that much bigger it's even quieter in
the forest if that's somehow
I totally feel you and yeah as you're
saying the place we were was by a
highway and
um it did like I didn't feel like we
were deep in the forest and we were
seeing the trees it felt like we were
doing more of like a tourist drive
through so yeah
yeah yeah so I would like to check out
the area you're talking about I like the
more secluded Forest oh yeah this one
will take you like 45 minutes or two to
an hour just to hike up the mountain to
get to the area so I cheat I take my
dirt bike up there but uh we can walk
I like the journey to to get to the get
to the uh the site it always feels
better when you get there I feel like
you've earned it welcome Forest hey I
heard you were talking about forests
we literally are talking about trees and
forests
copyrighted it I feel like if I feel
like if Chimera was here he would have
already told us about the importance of
the terpene pining inside the forest and
how it sort of clears my name is the
most common terpene in the world
primarily from forest and it's that
fresh Forest smell that you inhale it is
literally part of that no well in Japan
we've all been hearing about the forest
therapy it's been getting more pressed
lately but they actually have areas of
forest that's uh preserved and kept uh
specifically for Forest therapy
um and there's some clinical work where
they've taken groups of like teenage
boys on who were troubled youth or
having just behavioral issues and then
they take them on these either day long
or weekend
[Music]
um
basically Forest hikes and they spend
time in the woods and they're finding
that their behavior improves their
immune profile improves and they've done
some blood markers like stress hormones
and some inflammatory immune markers
um so there's some pretty interesting
even clinical work and then they're
bringing it back to what could be
physiologically responsible and so yeah
Alpha pinene is one of the main
mechanisms of how forests when you spend
time
um in the trees you actually are
breathing in that monoterpene and
getting it into your body but even I
mean we look at the the microbes that
you're experiencing when you're the
bacteria and the fungi populations that
you're experiencing when you're in the
forest and there's even some studies
done with mice where they spend time in
certain uh dirt bacteria and they find
that their mood improves and it's
affecting their serotonin Pathways so I
don't think it's just the alpha pione
it's also the bacteria it's also
obviously like Marcus you were saying
like the sound that meditative aspect of
just being
um even the sensory deprivation you're
looking all around you and all you see
is green and trees so that's very
soothing and good for your stress
response also so yeah in the forest
especially when you you know you you
gave a perfect example like you're not
the type of person to be super feely
about Vibes and energy you got more of a
scientist mind you're going into Data
you like like I you're more like you're
like an analytical mind but the forest
is powerful enough to break through to
many many different types and you see
people all the time who are maybe not
necessarily you know going to be going
to a rainbow gathering anytime soon and
and feeling the love of the whatever but
you go into the forest and you really
see everyday people people that might
not be you know as connected to their
plants say at their house or something
on an everyday basis but they get into
that forest and especially like an
ancient beautiful like Sequoias and
Douglas Furs and Cedars like these trees
are spectacular and they are a huge huge
part of our ecosystem as we see because
when we cut them down you know the
destruction is obvious even to the most
blinded
people you see that this it's
destruction it's uh wow when you destroy
a forest then you're just left with land
it's a bummer and d420k is in the forest
although we just shut off and went to
his uh
classic photo of him on his riding
lawnmower how [ __ ] redneck is that
though honestly
d420k's photo of him on his lawnmower is
like I love that [ __ ] don't you mean
Rouge neck
Ruth can you see me we can see you in
here you bro you're in the forest we're
talking about the forest forest came in
with the name forest and we were like
how's anyone Gonna Wanna and now I can
see the forest from the trees and now
you're in the forest
enjoy it while you can because pretty
soon all combustion engines are gonna be
banned worldwide for everybody
yeah they're actually passing
anti-combustion laws in India by 2040
and other countries so they're ramping
up to already throw away fossil fuels
forever whereas America we've still got
our head so far up our ass we need
electric snowmobile
yeah trust me I need electric snowmobile
I need an electric dirt bike I need an
electric boat so I'm going to need an
electric truck well an actual competing
company just came out uh competing
against Tesla with the first electric
truck humans I think it's Tesla with
their patents given to them yeah
Tesla gave all his patents away to those
companies so they could compete how
[ __ ] cool was that at the stroke of
Genius for the entire you know we had to
drive the industry dude it's so
beautiful like I wish more people had
that like what a brilliant like the guys
got some of the most valuable patents
you know legitimately on the planet like
they have to be in the top 10 like
ridiculous money and he gives them away
gives them away to all all of his
competition not just like put it on the
internet for whoever but he actually
sent it to car companies like and you
saw he just bought his cousin's company
the Solar Company for two billion cash
you know nice to hook up your cousin
with two bill in cash and now started
that solar roof right so he's got solar
roofs for your solar house with this
storage capacity from your portable all
the way up to large municipality cities
and now you can power your car I mean
it's guys
Beyond futuristic any stunning Rockets
to and from space and they're coming
back and landing in the middle of the
ocean holy that [ __ ] blew my mind I
watched that [ __ ] with my kid and I can
honestly say there's only a few times in
life
in life where you feel there's some
world history going on you know like
when they land on the moon there's like
certain things when there's when Nassau
sends a rocket off it's like it can be
it can be fairly historical and you know
Nassau said it was impossible that you
couldn't send that Rockets up into space
and then have them come back down and
land on a platform particularly on the
ocean a moving platform he did it I like
electrical but there's still a couple of
things that kind of bug me number one is
how far you can you go on a single
charge number two is how long does it
take to recharge so you know those those
things are number three I wish come from
the electrons probably come from a
fossil fuel burning go ahead that's the
third reason yeah okay
so the electron economy where the
electrons come from that's an important
one thing from coal or nuclear power
plant you're definitely using a lot of
it to get those the material to get
those batteries built they're using a
lot of petrochemicals they have to be
but
you know it is what it is
solar collectors find those other
companies we're also using
petrochemicals merely to create products
that use petrochemicals so to cut off
one one sort of head I think is a good
thing and hopefully eventually they'll
stop using the petrochemicals
with production you'll have also of
people looking for Alternatives the way
that they're you know they they do all
the time so once you do something in
production hydrogen that sounds really
good to me sounds clean as [ __ ]
yeah unfortunately unfortunately the
cost of all alternative energy is
directly tied to the price of fossil
fuels that which are subsidized and are
being you know where they are that's the
way it is in in this era of of cheap
fossil fuels which it just uh yeah again
more so than being tied to fossil fuels
what it's really tied to is human labor
because human labor is what does
everything regardless of the illusion of
money or the actual reality of fossil
fuels versus electric it's human labor
that makes the world go round that's why
money was created so people could say oh
I'm gonna do this without cheap fossil
fuels there wouldn't be the food
production distribution consumption
system that exists in America today
they wouldn't be Amazon there wouldn't
be a different one the whole Commerce is
predicated on cheap everything would be
local yeah and money would be printed
differently you know because when I hear
people say oh it's too expensive well
money is a mental construct that we made
up that we just print as much of it as
we want but labor is real labor is the
real thing that actually gets things
done you can't extract things out of the
earth you can't grow food you can't move
things you can't do anything with labor
that's the real value in the world not
money not fossil fuels not any of this
other [ __ ] it's labor people doing
[ __ ] for people
that's my opinion you almost sound like
a slave owner really
well I can tell you that I own those
names other than myself I am a slave to
my own to my own job but uh thank you
for calling me a slave owner how do you
respond to that yeah
you know what it's skunk and Sam so if
it was anyone else you won't know but
with Skunk Man Sam you just laugh it's
like he definitely doesn't mean harm he
definitely is not being malicious he's
like he'll he's like Dave Chappelle
he'll say anything for a laugh and
you're not gonna succeed so there we go
exactly well I I
jokes have to be explained they can't be
that funny
could you explain that
oh my gosh I said if we remember it
it is crazy though
that we haven't had a bong rip yet since
d420k got into the room I've had a few
years slacking I am totally slacking
welcome uh Wade I don't know if he's on
the phone or oh no he's just I think
what has real value in the world is
creativity and inventiveness of course
you need labor to manifest it but it's
the inventiveness and creativeness
that's the biggest donation that's being
given to humanity by really bright
people
I call it the one percent inspiration 99
perspiration I get people all the time
hitting me up and saying I got a great
idea I'm going to give it to you but I
want like I want 50 percent
and I'll be like listen your great idea
is worth one percent the executive
execution of said great idea is worth 99
and that was sort of a thing my grandpa
told me years ago uh that that it's 99
perspiration and it's one percent
inspiration I I used to always say that
if ideas were what was really really
important then the wealthiest people on
the planet would be the Rainbow Tribe
Rainbow Tribe are they still around oh
yeah
they're following fish and they're
following the rainbow family they're
following the rainbow
you did yourself before Marcus when you
said rainbow gathering I hadn't heard
the rain rainbow gathering for a while
does that thing still exist yeah
definitely not on fish tour I'll tell
you that much because Mark would know if
they existed if they were unfair no the
people on this course is the 12 tribes
fuss right that
that dark red maroon looking bus that
serves cookies and wants you to come
inside is that the same like family that
is kind of like pseudo-weird religious
and you're allowed to have only one
length of ponytail and a big beard and
is that those guys yeah don't get on the
bus when we watch listen they owned
Bakery in my city they're they're
actually yeah those are the ones that
owned a bakery that's them trust me it's
them 100 they used to just call
themselves the family they have this
what was their bakery's name they made
killer killer baked goods but you go and
hang out and they'd be like oh you
should come by and hang out and you know
I had really long hair at the time and
the guy was like you know you should
really cut your ponytail it's too long
it's it's uh it's it's very egocentric
when you grow your ponytail longer than
one one hand length and he started
telling me about his weird dogmas and I
was just like all right whatever I'll
hang out and listen to this eat a really
good organic like vegan meal at their
Cafe
and uh then they were like yeah come by
and and we like to sing and play music
and dance and
I was like yeah I'll come check it out
and I came and check it out and all the
chicks were wearing like weird like
Little House on the Prairie dresses like
all the same dress that like went up to
here with the weird little sorta and it
just got weirder and weirder and weirder
I I was into weird so it wasn't like I
wanted to do it but I was like I'll just
like trip out on this and and with my
buddies and experience this moment not
laughing at them not mocking at them not
thinking I'm better than them in any way
shape or form just like
I trip on human belief systems you know
like I've got Hasidic Jewish friends
from Brooklyn and I trip on their belief
systems I've got raw foodist friends
from Switzerland and I trip on their
belief like it's just neat how fervent
we get in our belief systems well that's
right we got the right to believe what
we want and then we have the right to to
look at it and giggle sometimes with
some people you know the fish song birds
of a feather I think was written about
those folks outside Mark might know the
band well enough you know when they the
birds of a feather are flopping outside
and perhaps you'll receive invitations
I don't think it's about those fans
they turn drag them in there nitrous
balloon in one hand they're trying to
drag him into the bus for teeth
there's nothing wrong with people
believing in any belief system that they
like as long as they're not enforcing it
on others and saying well if you don't
do it then you're obviously going to
burn and to Purgatory for [ __ ] ever
because you're a heathen
right so I have a question for everyone
on the panel
what is the strangest thing that you
have ever smoked cannabis out of
have been Darren from BC he won the
Cannabis Cup in like 96 or 97 when the
big BC contingent came out he had the
long curly hair and he had a broccoli
pipe and I had smoked out of quite a I
smoked out of a carrot and a zucchini
and an apple and oil I had smoked out of
quite a few different fruits and [ __ ]
but when he pulled out the broccoli pipe
with the full head still on it with the
bowl like right in the broccoli head I
was like all right dude that and a thick
stock like it had almost as thick as my
wrist broccoli stock
that was probably the weirdest thing
I've smoked out of
next
no everyone's too afraid when I was
really young we rolled a joint out of a
woman's tampon paper the paper that the
tampon came in looked like rolling paper
to us so we're like oh all right Mark
wins
I'll go next
page out of the Bible
I've heard that one
the page out of the Bible I might even
been there for one of the page out of
the Bibles but
a tampon paper
was it before or after I'm gonna go for
before it was no it was it was not used
I was holding up a human bone pipe
are you kidding me Sam no he doesn't
clown around look at that thing you have
a human but where'd you get that in
with all the knuckles from the monks and
stuff so that makes sense holy [ __ ]
maybe Sam wins Sam wins that's that's uh
that's heavy I've never smoked out of a
human except when they blow into my
mouth
Jesus Christ mine was the least weird
uh my mine isn't that weird mine was
just this uh this pipe at a party I was
at in Berkeley and
um
you you hit the ball this bong and then
it had a release valve that shot a
whippet right behind the smoke and shot
it straight into your lungs
and that was probably the strange most
unique pipe that I've ever hit uh I
would love next time and next time I see
you Sam I want to hit that pipe so it's
a nitrous oxide
uh gravity bong
yeah
I I've hit the nitrous oxide gravity
bong not really a gravity bong it was
more like a nitrous oxide like balloon
that just pushed through you fill the
bong with a rip and then you just
release this little valve that he had
and it blew the nitrous and the rip into
your uh lungs I'm not I wasn't a fan of
it at all I don't like those kind of
alcohol type uh
it was unique but uh okay come on rest
of the panelists this here Dr rise would
it would have uh you're just very
vanilla and you're smoking what
oh
an earth pipe and puffed right out of
Mother Earth what is an earth pipe no
well you just you can make a bowl and a
stem and you the the pipe is the earth
you just dig a hole and you bury the
stem and you create a little pocket you
can puff out of the mark cloaky did a
whole crazy video of like making
everything into pipes in Vancouver he
drilled out benches and trees and like
Signs and then did a whole video on it
where he just walked around he'd be
sitting on a bench and then the next
thing you know he'd be like on beside
the bench stuffing it full of weed
puffing out of a park bench puffing out
of trees puffing out of like a lot of
strange things things that you watch it
you wouldn't puff up have you done an
earth hit with a solar
you know that's the no but I have done
solar bowls but I've never done a solar
Earth Bowl on a windy Beach a solar bowl
is great oh yeah
absolutely solar bowls are awesome if
you like going blind because it's great
because you're staring at this ball of
sunlight in your pipe are you wearing
sunglasses dude even with sunglasses you
got to wear like it's like a solar
eclipse in your bowl every time I ever
hit a solar like trying not to look but
every time because I also my solar bowls
were majorly not but they were full
Mount bubble and with solar bowl with
full Mel bubble the bubble melts and
moves away from the heat so you have to
watch it and move it around it's not
ideal
anyone else with some weird pipes that
they've got Forest anything yeah
no I mean I mean when I was most of them
were probably when I was younger so it's
more white trashy than interesting or
cool but I'm sure there was like a found
recycled can pipe at one time I was the
master of those things nice or some sort
of you know some sort of
trailer park MacGyver sort of nuts and
bolts
where they hit water and that's like a
really common up in New England and in
Vermont so like you'd be basically at a
construction site that would suddenly
just hit water and it would completely
fill up and so there's a lot of these
swimming quarries up in Vermont and this
one in Dorset Vermont actually has a
bowl carved into the side of the cliff
so you could actually go there and hang
out and go diving and whatnot into the
Quarry but there's a bowl carved into
the side of the cliff that you can just
kind of come up and use so that's kind
of cool that's we've smoked out of the
doors Quarry Bowl I like that concept
that that seems like a concept that is
thousands of years old
the concept of creating a pipe to to
leave somewhere and and smoke out of
like when you get carved right into the
Cliffside that you could come right up
and use yeah it was pretty cool it was
pretty cool I think the original one
actually someone had actually broken it
off because it was much smaller and when
we went back years later I think it was
on Grateful Dead tour I want to say in
the late 80s we went there swimming one
day in between shows and yeah I want to
use the bowl and noticed that it was it
was a different bowl that and it would
been replaced by a much larger one but
this is in a place called Dorset Vermont
right off of Route seven in Dorset
marble Quarry where they hit water and a
lot of people go swimming there so it's
cool to have a little bowl built into
the cliff that's awesome dude welcome
people
why God made papayas papaya branches are
natural for filling up with herb or hash
they work really truly great and here's
a 100 year old Chillum that I collected
it's made out of either iron or steel or
I'm not exactly sure the metal it's
maybe a hundred years old and uh the
reason sad who's like this was because
they could hang it on a string and they
wouldn't break it
weird crazy wild hey welcome Peter we're
just talking about crazy whacked out
pipes that we've smoked out of my pipe
was the broccoli uh Mark uh scaldon
rolled a joint in a tampon paper the
420k used the Bible
um Mr Sam uses a human bone yeah yeah
that's literally on his his thing right
now with the 100 year old Chillum that's
a human bone pipe from uh from like the
first person he ever killed I think no
no it's from Tibet
yeah you earlier man
it was already completely stained
did it have any like flesh left on it or
did it just came nice
it was old like maybe 50 or 100 years
old when I got it
it's great when the zombie apocalypse
comes Sam's pipe's gonna wake up so be
on the look at this
human Stone That's Heavy that's like the
nagas do you ever hang out with Naga sad
news like well in Tibet you also see
they use human just the very top top
part of the skull as a little bowl
that's what the nagas well not all of
them but a few that I met had that
little bowl they
dude I was like that's That's Heavy
that's like that's like about as heavy
as the belief system got while I was in
although I did see a guy get murdered at
the Maha Kumba Mela because he went into
the ghats before the uh the Naga sadhus
he thought he would go bathe before them
and the guy just picked up a big Spear
and stabbed him right in the side
and nobody did anything like he just
floated down the river like no Army no
like military yeah the Blessed death he
died in the Holy River well that's what
people were telling me later and I was
like
this is [ __ ] insane whoa yeah of
little belief
visitor I felt like I was in the Star
Wars set
Tatooine or something [ __ ] was Next
Level belief system's wild man yeah I've
seen I've seen mobs go after uh drivers
of automobiles that killed cows and uh
you know every everybody says if you're
out in the Villages don't stop
oh if you hit a cow you mean yes yeah no
doubt
they take it very personal oh I know
there were caves in Nepal that cows were
allowed in but Mark Rose wasn't
think of that for a minute
all through the unique belief system
so uh you it mine is not uh smoking but
uh I've recently started uh eating
cannabis uh flowers putting them in my
lip between my gum and my cheek and
sucking on it for half hour to an hour
and you get a really nice sense of how
those flowers were finished and a really
nice buzz off of it try it sometime it's
not smoking but it's pretty good
I'm gonna try this
you're eating th
and getting a nice Buzz
I'll take that Sam
yeah that's a yes yes
uh I'm enjoying the flavor and a
physical experience more than a
psychoactive Buzz
it's a different Buzz it's a different
Buzz yeah it's not the bus
so when I when I ate uh dried but uh
still in the THC form uh uh buds uh I I
did feel a tiny bit of an effect but if
I take that same Bud that I
decarboxylate it and then eat it I get
whacked
yeah without a doubt well I mean there's
more than just you're gonna have some
breakdown of the acidic thca to THC in
the flowers you're going to get some but
you know the fact I've been doing this a
really long time we're learning that
some of these effects you know we could
be feeling in the chirping profiles as
well so that could have something to
have been depending on the both of our
no this is true sub cools in the house
driving as always probably going to the
garden
sorry I muted you you had your music on
there I just uh I'm always worried about
any outside music in YouTube man they're
crazy it's like three seconds and they
cut your show off so that means if I
sing a song They're Gonna ban it yeah
please don't sing a song Sam
[Music]
whatever you do only Mark's allowed to
sing songs on hash Church
know your place
that's what everyone needs to do is know
their place no you know what actually
today I'm going to be the bacteria guy
Natasha is going to be uh the hash girl
um Wade Wade's going to be running the
BPG d420k while you are Skunk Man Sam
today let's just all be each other it'll
be fun what do I get who would I get to
be uh you get to be dude
you can be Todd McCormick
[Music]
so you know come on everyone's got to
represent I want to be dope featuring
who do you want to be Joe peachy yeah
[Music]
Hey brother I'm uh headed to uh North
Star genetics to pick up some Dead
Lights this morning just had me some
eggs benedict yum yum
and I love that you're just on the
highway I did a wake and bake recently
where I was in my truck the whole time
it was kind of lame
but it was still neat to just be driving
and have my on my magnet you know
definitely don't car accident whenever
you do that would be terrible
be safe out there
[Music]
you don't think we get higher ratings
well you know what I'm not down with the
drama higher ratings I'd rather just
have uh whoever wants to listen can
listen and if it's good information
excellent but uh
we're not going to have sub kill himself
for some uh pasture trading
Not Crash Church exactly and Subs
already been through some [ __ ]
as we all have but maybe Subs been
through a little bit more than most
he's been through a few
live car accident on YouTube yeah they
have them it's called Russian car dash
cams Russian dash cams that's like the
worst YouTube channel ever to watch that
is the craziest [ __ ] dude
I mean you there is just out of left
feet it's out of left field everything
you're like what the
[Music]
watching those videos is definitely not
don't you find Italians drive faster
Italians
what do you mean
yeah what do you mean
I mean what are you talking about drive
faster and crazier and more dangerously
but the Russians are pretty bad
yeah well here's the difference the
Italians don't have to by law have a
dash camera in their car and all the
Russians don't prove
we don't get exactly you don't get to
register your car without those dash
cameras so that's why there's so many
every accident is recorded
pretty ridiculous
and I would say that the in Switzerland
at least in the south
the Italian sort of Swiss Italian are
driving as crazy and fast as in the
north the German uh Swiss they drive
fast
[Music]
well in in Germany 1 through 30
kilometers outside of a city then there
are no speed limits on the on the
highways
know I don't like it I definitely know
as long as there's three lanes and uh
it's 30 kilometers out of a city center
and stay out of the far left lane and
last year literally in a 200 000 dollar
car
[Music]
it just takes 200 kilometers an hour
yeah but man
some of those cars are going way faster
than 200 kilometers an hour that's true
like and when you see them in your
rearview mirror and they're super far
away and then you look down and you look
back up and they are like literally
I got to drive Gypsy Nirvana's brand new
whatever Jaguar he bought that was like
115 000 Euros back in the day I drove
that thing like 250k on uh on the the
German Autobahn there and it was as we
were driving down to Switzerland
together I I on long trips I prefer
higher speeds as long as it's safe uh uh
I mean I drive a Bugatti except that uh
you have to put gas in it every half an
hour
you want to get one of those electric
Bugattis
I haven't seen it have you seen one no
no that's that car is like 1200
horsepower or something although I
wouldn't be surprised if a Tesla p100s
could still take it off the line
well you'll have to admit it would be
fun to drive one time it just beat a
Lamborghini the other day by like a half
second but it's every mile it beats
everything I've never seen anything beat
it and somebody got 664 kilometers in
Europe on one charge the other day off
of a ps100 wow that's you know you know
once they break a thousand
that's
I mean how many freaking kilometers can
you drive in a day
[Music]
Peter's world tell us what's going on
what's new and different Peter
so um well we just uh I was listening to
some amazing uh
stuff that you were blowing my [ __ ]
mind with earlier man and I had to jump
in you were talking about like I think
sustainable Eco Villages or like you
know the Rockets blasting and all that
stuff and I was like I gotta come see
what Marcus is
what's going on in his mind because it's
pretty amazing stuff yeah we were
talking about Elon Musk and sort of you
know a lot of his projects that he's
working on and whatnot with uh
I don't know he's got like three huge
projects going on at any given time the
solar panels the electric vehicles and
the SpaceX program
yeah I've been thinking a lot about
um uh water conservation in Eco Villages
like these sustainable communities
because if we can get well because I'm a
soil nerd right so that's what I do so
that's kind of what goes on in my mind
but if we could get soil to a point of
Competency where you know it's just
super good rich dark soil you know full
of humus in these Eco Villages you could
actually like filter the water
um and allow it to purify through the
biology through the minerals and just
have a really cool system in it in a
super healthy uh you know sustainable
Eco Village it's one of the things I've
been thinking about lately
sounds like a nature septic field yeah
exactly exactly like a nature septic
field
let the water percolate uh through the
through the soil and then almost get
caught in like a funnel where you could
recirculate that and allow it to go back
into the plumbing and just keep using
the water but it's a natural uh really
good carbon filter like the best carbon
filter that you don't have with
nutrients and the correct uh beneficial
bacteria that the soil provides the
plants which the plants provide us well
it's part of what it does it's part of
its design yeah I mean that's [ __ ]
nature dude yeah
go ahead uh
it sounds almost like you're talking
about aquaponics is that a fair
description of what you're talking about
where you're circulating water to your
plant materials and fish are uh their
waste products are feeding the plants
and then anytime you can circulate the
water back to the fish and or into your
garden
etc etc yeah like that but on a larger
scale kind of kind of like for humans
the human version yeah I remember when
breeder Steve first started the he did
aquaponics he had those little mouth
breeder fish I can't remember the name
of them now
the heck were those ones called but yeah
aquaponics is cool yeah it was great it
was but the crazy thing was he could get
a lot of growth out of it but you could
also get like like the same way you
could get like five to ten days of
beautiful growth like in a very like
short period of time like 24 to 36 hours
you could you could kill your whole crop
like equally as fast like just decimate
it like yeah like so dead like it's not
coming back yeah yeah well yeah once the
uh that biology it's like a macro sweet
spot in the sense if anyone understands
macro photography when you shoot macro
photography your depth of field
disappears and you get this like band
that is like nine or eight or seven
millimeters wide and that's your area
that you have to shoot that'll be
that'll be clear everything else will be
out of focus be ahead of it and behind
it so the sweet spot if you will is very
very very very you know if you're not on
it it's it becomes obvious right away
[Music]
so subs subs are green
long awkward silence
mother lovers
bye-bye
peace out
later man so the other thing that was uh
that's pretty new uh in our world with
with our biology is that um we just got
some some preliminary data in from one
of our hemp cultivators and um they've
been testing CBD levels for the last uh
uh six years they spent about forty five
thousand dollars a year they're a big
operation on CBD and THC potency
analysis
um obviously they don't want the THC to
get too high because if it does then the
crop is illegal you know if it goes hot
for these hemp Growers big deal you know
they they come in and they burn their
whole crop so it's a it's a big deal and
um
uh so anyways they've been doing a lot
of analysis on these uh different CBD
levels which I'm not too familiar with
yet I'm still learning a lot about the
CBD levels
um but they said that uh in in analyzing
hundreds of plants over the last uh six
years weekly is how they do their
analysis uh they said that our product
on the bell curve over the last six
years is 30 percent higher in CBD oil
production uh than the non-treated so
they said that was a big thing they also
said that the type of CBD uh was a
really good quality of CBD so I don't
know if there's different you know
another CD cbda and there's cbdva
like if it was a different uh
I don't know what's a better one but uh
but anyways
in our treated plants than the
non-treated over the last six years of
the bell curve so they're obviously
happy with Biology
they're obviously happy with that and
they and this is in the first two weeks
of flowering so now what they're saying
is that if if this keeps trending on the
progression that they're they're used to
seeing on their analysis uh that the uh
it could go up as much as 50 or 60
percent in in the oil production
just from increasing the the biology
exponentially and the guy was like the
guy the guy is a PhD right and he's like
I thought my [ __ ] instruments were
broken man he goes he goes this uh
this is something that I've never seen
before and five generations of uh
cultivating well I think that's proof
that we're on the right track because if
the labs never see anything new then
we're not innovating and we're not
changing anything and all the brilliant
people that are involved in all of this
stuff are doing [ __ ] yes sir it makes
sense that we're going to hear Labs say
things like I've never you know like the
first time I ever had heard it was when
I gave
indra's oil to the labs here in
Vancouver all of them said that they had
never seen numbers that high that they
were they had never tested protein
powder isolate that high they had never
seen oil content that clean and that
high and uh you know it's it's it's good
because if if we're not hearing that
then we're not all doing a very good job
in the world of innovation and you know
pushing this stuff forward and making
and if the CBD levels are increasing
what about the THC levels are they
increasing also no the the THC levels
went down
[Music]
that's unusual
so unusual he said the THC levels were
down in contrast to the uh
to the other ones so our city and our
THC was down in in hemp plants in these
particulars what would the health hemp
plant cultivars do you know thank you
good question you know what I I don't
know but but they're ones that they've
been growing for the last seven years
they said we thought our instruments
were broken because it was you know it
was Zero the THC was Zero
they were like so we kept doing new
instruments but the THC was like zero to
to point well that does not surprise me
at all I mean I'm a firm believer and uh
you're kind of growing so but what does
surprise me is that the CBD would go up
and the THC would go down in the same
crop I mean that's that doesn't follow
logical sense
would it have anything to do with the
fact that the cultivar was being bred to
produce CBD and to produce less THC
was it or was it just a hep variety no
this is for industrial hemp operation
yeah but word hemp varieties inevitably
when you get rid of one cannabinoid
another takes its place I mean are there
I'm not bred for him they're only one or
two percent CBD but there are CBD
varieties which are over 20 right
those are bred for CBT but you got to
think of this guy's growing for CBD and
he's got a PhD and he's got a big
operation and he knows that if he grows
cultivars that are bred for CBD it's
going to make a lot more sense for his
business than to grow like hemp plants
that are two percent CBD no yeah but the
only way you could do that would be by
analyzing huge huge numbers of plants
and eliminating any that had uh THC
levels that were too high it could be
done but that's what the ukrainians did
that's what go to baroco right the
people here are not doing that right
okay it's a simple mess
it depends on what his goal is too right
I mean it's his goal to produce CBD are
they producing fibers and other
byproducts of the hemp plants and CBD is
a nice afternoon there's no
infrastructure for there's no monetary
gain for fiber for for hemp no very very
few people on the planet are doing that
the value is in the seed oil and in the
cannabinoids and the terpenes period
right now I wish they were doing flavor
I wish hospitals this particular grower
yeah and they sell to multitudes of
hospitals uh internationally so they're
growing cannabinoids correct right so it
would make sense that they're probably
CBD cultivars I mean to plant hemp
cultivars that are like two percent CBD
over ones that are you know five times
higher so if the plant here's what might
five times ten times Well
to grow right if if if
[Music]
strain of plant is meant to produce High
CBD and low THC then wouldn't
increasing its its true genetic
expression in those directions uh kind
of makes sense to you guys that was my
kind of question too like if it was just
a hem for if THC had been bred out of it
and that was the sort of what was going
on in that cultivar maybe the bacteria
somehow influenced that same pathway
rather than raising all the cannabinoids
I don't know enough about it but there
is someone in the room asking if you are
talking about Davis herb Farms extreme
scale performances shooting a
documentary on their story right now no
but I'll check that out for sure that
sounds good
usually if you're increasing the uh
flowers the resin the terpenes the uh
cannabinoids it's across the board it's
not just particular cannabinoids to
particular terms it's whatever the plant
normally expresses but to a slightly
higher degree right it's exactly it's
just a slight higher degree with with
the the biodiversity yeah but I like to
jump in with an observation
uh one of the things I found I've not
done nearly as much testing as the folks
you're describing Peter but I have found
that depending on when you harvest some
CBD Rich cultivars you can change the
proportion of CBD to THC pretty
dramatically
uh and it might be that in addition to
soil biology contributing to the
wellness of the plants and their
opportunity to express their genetic
potential the other thing that might be
going on and you said they they were
testing every week what you'll see is
that CBD tends to come on before THC in
the genetic expression of that plant the
biosynthetic process so to speak and
I've seen pretty dramatic differences in
the ratios that are in finished flowers
depending on when you harvest them the
later they go in their cycle the THC
tends to increase and CBD tends to
decrease
yeah I don't know Sam you've probably
seen the same thing I'd love to hear
what you have to say about that I've
seen varieties that did that and I've
seen varieties that did the opposite I
don't know if there's any fixed
situation
interesting
well can I ask a question about
um just following up on what you were
just saying there
um if you were growing a cultivar of
cannabis and say it was a nine week
flowering plant and you
um
and do that at eight weeks like how much
of that final cannabinoid
um development are you losing like is it
five percent is it 20 like how much is
happening in those final weeks of
development does anyone have a different
varieties it really depends on the
variety some varieties really Frost up
the last two three four weeks uh so uh
you don't want to take the plant before
it's done frosting up unless you're
after a more uh maybe terpene Rich
because the longer you let it flour then
you're probably decreasing the terpenes
a little bit
yeah I've been doing some tours over the
last few weeks of some of the different
licensed producers here in Canada and
checking out their Grow rooms and stuff
which has been really interesting and uh
just hearing some of the
um
just Logistics of how people are setting
up their grow and how many growth Cycles
they're anticipating
um it's just interesting hearing the
differences between groups and some
groups are thinking like oh eight weeks
is going to be consistent and we'll just
be able to turn over the room after
every eight weeks and then my husband as
a grower is kind of asking those
questions like well what about because
some of the cultivars he's growing that
he was expecting to be done in eight
weeks he's finding other the longer he
leaves them obviously they're frosting
up more and so we've been just thinking
of those questions of what's up take 24
weeks and if you do it faster you're not
creating the best I want them
for real
where is it
why is that because my personal favorite
okay I have a real affinity for exotic
um tropical grown narrow Leaf drug
cultivars and that's what he's talking
about a hundred percent the terpene
profiles they have different you are
unique terpenes
they're almost gone Forest if you can
imagine prohibition and that's why
they're gone because of prohibition so
when when I see something like
prohibition taking a stab at exotic long
flowering tropical grown narrow Leaf
drug cultivars I think there's got to be
a serious value there so then I start
looking into it my first day they cannot
compete indoors under lights on a
production per gram per hour basis but
a a big giant Greenhouse or Outdoors or
you live far enough South then uh yeah I
grew them in worse I grew 16 and 20
weakers indoors and man people thought I
was nuts but I'll tell you the same
thing happened every single time when it
was time to harvesting they wanted to
smoke your herb oh God did they want to
smoke my herb dude
the haze that's what we called it we
just hired
um you know what it's it was all about
the terpene profile that was for me I
mean it was it's the it was the terpene
profile that was modulating the
cannabinoids so uniquely and differently
like causing anxiety attacks in some
people but for me just the most Blissful
experience like my mind was sharp I was
inspired I wasn't lazy I wanted to do
things I wanted to create I wanted to
innovate I wanted to I just love the
haze so was it a high was it high name
and limonene that we're bringing that or
was it a more
Europeans got to test the terpenes back
in the day I suspect terpenaline had a
lot to do with it as now the more I
learn about these different terpenes
it's one of my favorites for sure
but it's a combination right there's a
whole slew of them in there and I
wouldn't be surprised if in those exotic
narrow Leaf drug cultivars if you
actually tested for how many there were
you would find so many more than 12 or
20 or 30.
different terpenes in different ratios
than you find in widely drug varieties
from uh you know Afghanistan and
Pakistan or the wide Leaf sativa hybrids
which dominate the American California
West Coast Market
yeah
gets my mouth watering talking about
Haze
you know speaking of mouth when you take
like a like a haze and you chew on a
little bud I think the little ringing
that you get sort of in between the
cheek and gum
that we was talking about is partly due
to probably terpening but probably all
the terpenes that are just you know
again being absorbed into the mucosa
there right
it's interesting because probably the
most uniformly beneficial
plant you know when we get into without
going down that rabbit hole but when
you're dealing with specific and rare
neurological conditions and others you
really see the fine differences in the
concept of the Entourage effect but if
we were going to generalize and say okay
we have a broad Target that works for a
lot of neurological regulatory issues
albeit epilepsy or Spectrum Disorder
conditions
it's uh Mary Hayes the first strain that
ever worked for Silas is one that we've
continued to cultivate and has been
universally probably one of the most
beneficial plants that we've worked with
and it is uh it comes out at about one I
Forest isn't that the one where they
found by earthering being produced by
the plant genetically
yeah yeah I've read that I haven't been
able to see it in our own testing but
interesting it is a special plant and
you know it's and I it's unbelievable
profile
force it it's a two to one did you say
yeah yeah
um
but yeah right in that in that window
to CBD to everyone THC yeah yeah
it's it's an amazingly beneficial
profile that it produces um be happy to
send you guys it's got really high in
terpenes for us
um yeah yeah I mean
it uh it is it's got a lot of bags tank
yes yeah at times and what's the
flowering period on that one now for us
I think it's about it's somewhere around
to 12 weeks I believe
um we have some going this year when
Wade Pops in we'll get him to to chime
in because he's uh produced it for me a
couple years now and he's he's kind of
the expert in that world I'm the once
it's grown that's where I take over but
Hayes is one of those that uh is pretty
stable in its ratio uh I found that it's
pretty ideal in about 10 weeks yeah
going from first of August uh for
flowering initiation in our area
so that puts it around the middle of
October for an outdoor Harvest and at
that point uh what I found uh with that
one and a lot of the other cultivars
that uh we're using for the medicine
process uh we Harvest when there are
still some trichomes that are clear on
the flowers and mo the bulk of them have
gone milky but before you start seeing a
lot of Amber trichomes which is more
typically when I would Harvest a THC
variety
have all been yes hairs turned red from
White
uh at that point many Haze is still
producing white hairs
at 10 weeks
they're natural photo period or under
artificial no that's Outdoors
in Northern California
and it's my sense that it could go
longer Sam but it uh we have uh
uh at our elevation and uh whatnot
location in California
in a greenhouse in Santa Cruz I had a
haze that was planted in July and it was
harvested the first of April we called
it April Fool's Haze it took so freaking
long it was insane under natural photo
period in a greenhouse
I love that concept
I've had people with long experiences
with cannabis start to take a daily
supplement of some of the
concentrates and oils that we make from
this and come back and say they've never
experienced something quite like I think
some of that is to do with some of them
haven't used a supplement approach to
cannabis it's just something new to them
and some of that is just its effect uh
beneficial effect on the body I'd be
happy to uh send you guys some at some
point but yeah it's it's a good plan so
when you bring up the unique
personality and unique expression of the
haze Clan I mean they can't help but
think the background is
no I'm not I'm not the guy for that one
dude I love watching Marcus pull monster
[ __ ] rips bro that's a [ __ ] nice
rip dude
uh Sam what I know about Maddie Hayes is
it's from uh uh Jamie in Spain
that's where the seeds that I first
worked with came from yeah we had it
brought over
so if you know Jamie at rosin seeds uh
he could give you more background on it
Amy hi me all right
[Music]
I'll ask him sometime when I'm talking
to him next time well maybe we'll make
it to Spain this uh next uh upcoming
March hey Sam
Maybe
we gotta do it
it's got to be done I can't believe we
missed uh no he's he's done a lot of
work for uh folks that are interested in
CBD I I I had a variety 10 years before
but I licensed it to a big
pharmaceutical company and uh yeah but
they've been working their butts off up
with CBD and they're gonna make it so
there will be legal products but uh you
know how big pharmaceutical companies
are they uh are not real good about open
and sharing they don't like to share do
they
[Music]
yeah Dr Russo talks about a strain that
GW Pharmaceuticals have that I would
really like to get my hands on that is
Express this really high in CBD and CBC
with a really
heavily balanced landline the CBD
variety was developed by me and uh it
was uh not particularly high in CBC we
developed another variety that was
extremely high in CBC
yeah well the one I'm talking about that
they've worked with and have now is high
in CBD and CBC with Atlanta little
dominant chirping profile which is
someone who's interested in
anti-spasmatic properties yeah love to
get my hands on that one
crazy that you just can't it was
licensed to DW I can't give it to
anybody else
that's gotta be like a
for someone like like anyone working for
that company for that matter meeting
people who are like oh I'd really love
to get that cultivar it's like well you
know I can't give it to you all right
no no no but I really need it like this
isn't like it's not a monetary thing I
just need it no no can't do that that's
[ __ ] evil
yeah
little little kids slowly season the
death but you know Money Talks it's so
[ __ ] up
it's like I get capitalism I agree with
what you're saying and I also say that
GW has probably done more than any other
medical company whether intended or not
to
help move medical cannabis forward
because it's obvious that it's real when
people like this are involved and they
were just first I mean there's a lot of
other uh cannabis companies out there
now all I'm saying is is like the
Keystone Cops if you can't share a cut
while you're driving the newest and
latest Ferrari
you're [ __ ] evil
like I'm sorry
there's really no way around it
everyone's like patent coverage on any
of those molecules those molecules are
all in the public domain so that's where
the Folly is
well hopefully you know enough people
work enough people enough Elon musk's
make work that that they put out there
without uh you know trying to control it
right down to the last drop because uh I
mean it started here's the thing this
didn't start in the for you know that
you could take this human nature right
down to the lowest denominator and I I
saw it in prohibition I saw people
absolutely not sharing with one another
because they were like oh I own the
market on this cultivar this is my
strain I'm gonna you know it's like your
stream you've got seeds given to you or
you've got a CD bagweed and now that's
your strain that you've named and you
own and nobody gets and you won't share
it and it's awesome you like to brag
about it but you're not giving it to
anyone but you can buy it for 3 200 a
pound it is their share it is there they
renamed the Clone that they got from
somebody else so it's theirs dude I know
so many people I know people like my
friends that have done that
that's half the that's half the uh
product Market it is marketing to
families with kids you know it's not R4
it's not AC DC it's Hillary's helper you
know and it's our own it's our own
strain and you know if you want to save
your uh child or your loved one you can
only get Hillary's helper from us you
know and it's that's pretty much what
they do to keep people dependent on
their product it's it's they changed
everything eventually everything else
excuse me
go ahead
we see commonly that is in an
intentional move that most people don't
recognize to keep people dependent on
specific products they they take the
name of the strain so it's not something
you can get somewhere else it's
something you can only get from us
because it's our particular strain when
in reality some of them for example we
know and know the people that gave them
the initial acds here are four plants
that they may have bred and called
something new and they don't tell them
how to dose those are the two big tricks
they don't say how many milligrams are
in there they they train people to do so
based on volume right so I don't know
the strain it's only Hillary's Helper
and I only know I get like 0.5
milliliters but nothing on the bottle
tells me exactly what I'm getting and
that's intentional to keep people
dependent on that one product because
you don't have the information necessary
to understand you could move on and
treat yourself or work with other
medicines and it's it's not an a
accidents when we see that with strains
all the time
eventually everything will be marketed
by terpene and cannabity profile and
you'll be able to find a very similar
products yourself very easily
yeah because the names won't be able to
lie anymore then it'll be exactly what
Chimera said make the name the
constituents that make up what it is
terpene profiles that's what makes the
name that's it right the names can be
you know secondary for the people who
existed for all that we can be like oh
man I love the terpenely mercine
delimiting AKA that sour diesel or
whatever right like there's gonna be
ways to still connect those names to
those terpene profiles but for me
personally I'm more interested in people
knowing what they're getting each and
every time accurately
yeah so that's something we do quite a
bit is to just hope
the families develop the right language
you know it's not
um this brand name that's saving your
loved one or your mom or dad or child
it's cannabis and you're not let's learn
about what you're dosing let's learn
about what's in it because that's what's
going to free you to not be dependent on
this one company you know who's maybe
charging you uh somewhere around 25
cents a milligram when in reality you
can really take care of yourself in a
much more affordable way if you learn
exactly what it is you're given in
docent
um I think it's been a lot of trouble
with some people but that's just the way
it is well I love where you're coming
from dude and you know what it's it's
very much where I've come from for the
longest time even when you know
promoting Prana through Tony's company
in Jamaica and they're like we need this
we need this I'm like bro you have
coconuts and you have cannabis make your
own we don't know the recipes I'm like
dude
just start soaking it in coconut oil
using different cultivars bioassaying
you'll find the one that works for you
it's a beautiful thing the cannabis
plant it's not going to kill you you're
trying it you have access to it there's
so much analytical information in
Jamaica because everyone uses it like
everyone just some people don't talk
about it like they get the Grandma using
it for the tea for her cramps and her
arthritis and then she'll go out and
give her grandson a smack in the back of
the head because he's smoking a spliff
and he doesn't know she's using ganja
but she is
yeah yeah I think the last time you know
I've had I do classes where we'll teach
Families how to make man so we just try
to work towards independence as much as
we can and empowering and
um you know last time I got threatened
to be sued was from a company who wanted
to who has a nasal spray product that
they've convinced people that they've
just spent hundreds of hours and all
this money on
um doing and in reality it is just a
it's just MCT oil in an Amazon nasal
sprayer and they are you know wanting to
patent that hey Silas what's up Silas
hi
so
that little guy right there you know
we've when you're dealing with
epileptics there's three forms of rescue
it's it's sublingual it's rectal or it's
nasal spray or we've been messing around
with all those forever and is this
company in Colorado decided they could
do it they had a video go viral and then
all of a sudden they started threatening
to suit organizations like mine the
caladrius network because they wanted
the corner of the market and they just
teach and they just manipulate parents
and say this you can't do this safely we
only we can do it in this High Lab it
was really complicated you could only
get it from us or you're risking your
child's life and when those of us who
are educated have known and been working
with this for a long time know that
they're just putting the same spray they
put in the sublingual drops in a nasal
sprayer and they see big dollars
they're probably into there's some
chemistry to emulsify if it's an
oil-borne one to make it not separate
and you'll probably and that would be
the patent not the method of getting it
why would they want to take away one of
the three ways that you can stop us
[Music]
don't separate an MCT there's there's no
problem there no no no no no but is it
is it a water-based
um nasal spray
it's MCT it's oil
it's oil
yeah yeah it says you know
[Music]
that's pretty wild I would put that
company on major blast man because
that's like that's like the epitome of
evil once again you're coming at it from
the worst place it wouldn't even be
surprised to look at the board of uh of
that company and see it's like the NX
police chief the ex-health minister the
excellent
in particular
that company in particular is one of the
worst at convincing parents and families
that they're good guys by keeping them
in the dark so it's funny when you try
to teach some parents about it they'll
lash out at you
you know and they'll come back at you
know these people are great they're
Saints they're saviors and they just
don't realize how much they're being
exploited but
we're going to keep fighting the good
fight
yeah maybe that's Martin shkreli's uh uh
cannabis company his CBD company that
sounds like a him thing to do Mr uh get
the control of the drug there and raise
the price a thousand percent overnight
remember that right
yes
suspended in MCT oil is not an invention
that's that's open art so you can't
claim and you can't shut down people who
use well no no you can claim and you can
go through court and then you can find
out that you can't but you can do
whatever you want when it comes to these
insane patent flaws dude I'm telling you
I could just start telling I could come
up with a bunch of [ __ ] and and say any
patent is is breaching my thing and it's
like it doesn't often just get wiped off
the table they're like oh good business
let's bring this in let's make let's get
let's see how much money we can suck out
of this we're all lawyers yeah yeah it's
called a slap yeah
this guy went as far to go on silas's
awaren meniscuso syndrome awareness page
and start uh making threats and calling
us Thieves for taking this product in
this case it's got a multi-million
dollar company it's one of the biggest
CBD companies out of Colorado you know
and they know that we're giving it away
so we're not even selling so he has no
ground for any lawsuit because the
collagers network doesn't sell anything
and his his patents are
nonsense that he's saying that he has
but this is just the the level that that
some of these people go to to keep
control on the information and that's
kind of why I brought it up it's not
that it was um we were selling and
cutting into his market share it's that
they don't want people to know that
there's really no magic behind this I
mean though this plant is there for all
of us and as much as you want to inform
yourself and educate yourself you can
take some control into your own hands in
your own life and there's a lot of
people who don't like that about
cannabis it's one of the reasons it's
been so hard to monopolize and
pharmaceutical companies can't take it
now I have the Cannabis industry some of
them trying learning the same hard
lesson as they just try to grasp on the
control as much as they can it's almost
all in the language Forest when you hear
people say I helped I did this I did
that you're like my fire alarms my
Spider Sense goes off but when they say
you know cannabinoids help them I
pointed them in the direction of
cannabinoids and that helped him it's
like yeah exactly it was like it was the
cannabinoids that helped them I mean
let's not take credit for for such silly
things it's such it's so Donald Trump
asked like oh huge crowd in Houston huge
crowd great to see all you people huge
it's like dude that is douchebaggery at
the highest degree that's like you know
what that's like that's like giving a
homeless person half a sandwich or money
and then going home and posting about it
on your social media oh I just want to
let everyone know today I gave a
homeless person some money because I'm
such a good person I want you all to
know that it's like man it was good that
you've maybe gave that person a sandwich
but then you ruined it by talking about
it and having to tell everything about
it and turning it into an ego thing
uh Marcus I love it when you take big
rips because your mind is [ __ ]
awesome dude yeah well big rips
definitely unleash whatever this is in
here I mean some people call it the
opposite of awesome but I'll take that
on a Sunday afternoon thanks thanks
Peter
big rips well
everyone ready for a big rip it's gonna
be huge it's gonna be a huge rip look at
these rips they're huge
um
well that's it so I don't know if they
have any other topic but I know rip dude
you know what I've been ripping is this
uh this little terp vaporizer and um the
the grass that I got man it's got um 10
major types of terpenes
[Music]
what is that like three four percent
terpenes
yeah it's really it's really how I'm in
I don't know the exact percentage but
it's it's three different types with
like
um each each strain one strain has like
seven to nine different types of Majors
right there's so many different terpenes
you could test for but as far as the
major ones this one's got um seven to
nine in each strain I look forward to
the day where we go as deep as the
machines will let us and just go as deep
as we can with because I'm also a firm
believer for whatever reason that the
the terpenes that are in the Lesser
amounts
could be just as important
yeah yeah you're probably I mean it's
just an opinion I have nothing to back
it up right I'm learning too and I agree
100 with you dude like those little
macro doses of the other ones probably
act as like a catalyst to some of the
other ones to maybe make you know that
their efficacy enhanced so without the
one like that perfect balance you know
yeah I have a hard time believing that
they're there for no reason totally
right man
yep
and it's also
I predict right here and now because
when I've tested for terpenes I always
found plus 50. that there might be more
of it I only had a hundred standards of
the 150 terpenes found in cannabis but
uh the the end effects of it is the uh
the the terpenes that we did find uh the
some of them uh have very positive
effects a few of them had negative
effects so there could be terpenes that
you really don't want in in there also
oh really that's interesting wow so
there's there's ones that you don't want
in there
uh at least from a recreational point of
view from a medical point of view might
be completely different but I've seen it
happen I'm talking about flavor
I've seen certain strains terpenes
have absolutely adverse effects so give
an example we've had there's a high CBD
strength called Electra and there's
electric four so so we were using High
CBD strains with a lot of kids and
typically AC DC is like my tried and
true
um it's just stable it's got a good
terpene profile it's what's being used a
lot by a michelin's group I think people
who are doing medical work are really
kind of stuck with it it's been pretty
decent and
I switched over with Silas at one point
to a lecture because we were out of AC
DC exact same CBD
um dose and his seizures went through
the roof they just spiked
incredibly and I was kind of skeptical
like well could it be this could it just
be something in the system that's
causing it and eventually said well we
gotta get the others trained back and
see what happens and they stopped
immediately so something in that
chirping tonight
um had another medicine we gave them
once that I didn't realize had a lecture
in it and both times he had really
adverse reactions and I can only
difference in that is their terpene
profile
when you change these formulations that
you're giving them how quickly do you
see a difference in his symptoms in his
response to it like when you change if
you change his oil this morning he'll
immediately today yeah yeah I think that
has the metabolism rate right just like
when we use it in other ways it's in our
system in its most effective time window
it's in that four to six hour range and
you know I had used High CBD oils with
those stick with silos here but for a
year and never had it we had some
cognitive benefit but never helped with
a seizure he said he sees every single
day on the dot and when we got to more
balanced profiles and it was actually
that strained many Haze the first time
when he tried when we started that he
had like 80 seizures on Friday we
started the medic Haze Saturday morning
and he didn't have a seizure for four
months it was his first time in three
years he hadn't seen so it the onset was
immediate his body immediately had the
tools it needed to correct the problem
and the same with the adverse reactions
when we gave it to him that day it was
like holy crap what has happened you
know so I have heard some parents in Dr
Bonnie Goldstein has talked about this
um a tribute a four to six week period
to just keep trying to implement nation
in the brain so where and I would see
that as maybe something different going
on than an endocannabinoid deficiency
disorder or a regulatory issue but when
you have
constant CBD doses there's the thought
that what could be happening is some of
the swelling starts to go down in the
brain and when it goes down to a certain
point they see all of a sudden the onset
of some kind of efficacy and she's
talked about that quite a bit but in my
personal experience I haven't seen that
I've seen we we see it relatively
quickly immediately like that day or the
next day or we don't what's uh the
longest Silas has ever gone without a
seizure
almost six months yeah well it depends
he has 10 different kinds of seizures so
when we've started him on the medihaze
he went a year and a half without a
single Grand Mall seizure
yeah 10 he has 10 different kinds So
within that window we went almost six
months without any seizures and then we
had some what are called myoclonic
spasms these smaller uh seizures and
but it was a year and a half before we
had what would be considered a dangerous
you know a dangerous or serious teacher
so we saw amazing effects and then that
was from 2500 seizures a month you know
to zero it was I mean and that's really
when I
you can't you can't experience something
like that and not be a hundred percent
convinced of the efficacy of of cannabis
as a medicine so yeah
go ahead
um I just wanted to ask a question so is
uh Silas taking uh is my voice okay
yeah it was a bit robotic for a second
but it's it's good now it's okay now
um I'm just wondering is Forest taking
just a rescue dose with the intranasal
or is he doing like a daily maintenance
dose for those periods when he's gone
seizure free like you mentioned he did
the one
dose and then with seizure free for
three months like is that taking it
every day or is he taking like one
treatment and then feeling that effect
can you do it every four hours yeah and
that's you know that's what we see is a
lot of people ask can cannabis be a cure
you know and I've just I no I don't in
what I've read about how it works in the
body and what we've seen it's it's not
it's more of a supplement you know and
it's it's those spinal cannabinoids are
supplementing in the lack in our
endogenous cannabinoid system as long as
they're there and when they're gone the
body can no longer utilize them and the
problems and consequences sort of
manifest I mean we saved some of our in
our Oedipus tissue so you do get some
residual trickling but for the most part
you know it's it's in the system and
it's therapeutic dose you know I some
people go a couple times a day I've
found that the more consistent I can
keep that level the more effective so we
go every four hours you know just to be
right on that point of uh the metabolism
rate in the body
well every four hours or do you do oral
intranasal is only the breakout of a ton
of chronic seizure so that's meant is
we've a hundred percent been able to use
that as a rescue medication for
toniconics I haven't seen it work really
well with other types of cluster
seizures without we don't have to go
totally in the epilepsy world but you
know you like those Forest what dose is
effective for rescue in a nasal spray
that see that's what's great about
understanding cannabinoids is we've
actually been able to adjust that for
different children um there are certain
children's who are the the stuff that's
on the market is at five milligrams THC
per spray
um and that's just I don't know why they
landed there but what we do is you know
there are some kids who are sensitive to
THC and we've actually seen still
benefit by bringing that down to one
milligram THC or two and then having CBD
and other cannabinoids in there as well
but typically what you're seeing in the
market and we use something similar for
Silas it's about around five milligrams
it's a 0.1 ml sprayer so they last
forever that's another thing about
the nasal spray that's why it's a
sensitive issue for me it's only for
life saving and you're talking 0.1 ml
per spray so with a gram you're offering
you know 500
you know you can offer quite a bit of of
rescue for for a family and what you're
supplementing or what you're relieving
is the need for the pharmaceutical
rescue meds and those are always heavy
benzodiazepines
um Ativan diastat verse said you know so
they're really intense nasty drugs like
they would cause just as much problem as
the seizures in a lot of ways because
you get this benzo withdrawal and dump
afterwards so you have these just
emotional crying kids and you're trying
to console them from the seizures so
we've a hundred percent been able to uh
switch purely to cannabis rescue sprays
and it's they're working really well for
us because we use them for terminal
clonics other types of clusters they I
haven't seen them work you know so kids
who have focal clusters or myoclonic
clusters it doesn't seem to work but
something about when the brain's in that
full ton of chronic seizure mode uh 20
20 seconds or so and it they snap right
out of it I had one more question for
you for us if you didn't mind
sure I was wondering if you went through
the variety of extraction processes to
find the one that you guys are using now
or if you just kind of came across that
one early and it worked and that's the
one you've stuck with
no no we we went through so I've used
well I haven't used all of them
um I've always stayed away from BHO type
of extractions just because you know I
don't know a lot of people down here who
do it super well
um but we have went through this we have
some many days uh rosin right here this
is a good good amount of medication we
went through those processes we went
through CO2 and uh then settled on
the ethanol extraction not because I
want to be 100 solvent free but one the
people that we have doing it are
probably the best I've seen so when you
get really good at your crash you're
able to get the solvents out uh for the
most part but what that did is it and I
wish we had a smell of vision here where
I could have you guys experience it but
it's a process that is able to really
maintain a lot of the whole plant and
and working with it with what I had to
work with the CO2 extractors that I had
it was great it was crystal clear but it
was really there was almost no smell to
it at all it really extracted out a lot
of the the
terpenes I know there are people who are
able to do it with the terpenes but I
didn't have access to it at the time so
we settled on that because it got me the
best whole plant profile from what we
had to work with down here is uh in our
communities
one more question
um
uh what was I gonna say oh with the
types of cultivars you're finding are
you paying attention to the terpene
profiles like have you noticed like Lena
luel has been helpful like I know that
that has some effect efficacy for
um different types of seizures so I'm
just wondering if you have any
experience with that or working with
lavender or other
uh plants that can also be helpful
together with cannabis of course I've
got some test results in front of me
Forest
yeah we're talking about AC DC being of
benefit to Silas and uh how Elektra was
problematic for him so I went and found
uh some of the test results from those
two varieties and uh AC DC uh has uh
in this particular test results it's a
concentrate no this is a tincture
uh three quarters of a percent Premier
lean a little bit of linole less than a
tenth of a percent uh a third of a
percent beta mercine Citronelle
chlorophylline oxide
and then beta chlorophylline is by far
the largest terpene in that test result
and meantime if you go over here to
Electra four
uh the big one by far is terpene
terphenoline is 1.8 percent
and 2.2 percent limiting
in Elektra and uh half a almost a
percent of beta mercine but no beta
chlorophylline
and no
um
[Music]
um what was that other one
significantly reduced amount of uh
terpenoling yeah compared to the electro
four what about uh was there um I said
there was a little bit in the AC DC but
in the election was there any none Nolan
a little in the Elektra
that's interesting because one of my
favorite cultivars being the haze
varieties it seems to be high in
terpenaline really does mess with
certain people's central nervous systems
and just blows them into full-blown
anxiety attack
I've seen like so many times
welcome Alec hey
we're just talking testing we're talking
cannabinoids we're talking terpenes when
are you guys going to start testing for
more terpenes
[Music]
is like one of my favorite terpenes and
it took me a while to get into it um I
when I I used to be in the Navy um I was
in the Navy for five years and and uh
when I first got out of the Navy
terpenolene was actually the terpenish
my buddy shared uh in a bowl with me and
I freaked out um and had such a bad
experience that I had to go kind of
excuse myself from our hangout and I had
to go to sleep and and it set me off on
a path where you know for the first like
10 20 times it gave me incredible
anxiety
so check this out the conversation we're
having right now uh forest was talking
about different CBD cultivars that he
was using for Silas and that the one I
guess what we're figuring out here from
what Wade was saying and correct me if
I'm wrong but one of the main
differences was terpenaline that in the
one that set Silas off there was a
higher level of terpenoline Electra was
it called Electra four had almost four
times the amount uh in a similar
preparation of uh terpenoline as AC DC
but I wonder both have very similar
cannabinoid profiles I wonder if that
mechanism is similar that mechanism that
gives people an anxiety attack and sets
off it seemingly feels like your entire
central nervous system has been just
like
like set off and I can imagine if go
ahead for us let's say we're moving into
speculation or maybe an Italian of
course add to this but I would think you
know if you look at just logic would
lead us to believe that when we're
talking about epilepsy in general and
some other neurological conditions we're
talking about overexcitation at the
presynaptic nerve right an overactive
nerve at the endocannabinoid system is
failing to bring into homeostasis so if
we're feeling these you know effects of
maybe anxiety or things like that that
to me leads me to believe that there's
like a higher level of bonding at that
at that CB1 receptor it would all lead
kind of into the same direction and and
that could be something that would is
interesting someone much smarter than I
should look into that Natasha well I
think that's a really good call on that
too because um you know if you you know
I've seen uh you know quite a few times
you know at different kind of you know
big uh cannabis culture events when when
somebody's on almost you know being
served up with way too big of a dab or
dose you know of cannabis and and you
know kind of it almost looks like they
slightly start to go into a convulsive
type situation you know or like almost
like a mini seizure type thing so it's
interesting in the uh you know overex
excitement of the CB1 receptor over
stimulation the CB1 are separate because
you know when that seems to happen it
seems to you know set people off even if
they're you know once enjoying cannabis
you know into this path of you know kind
of starting to become more anxiety each
time you do it
also a combination of low blood sugar
and low blood pressure that sets people
off like this you would agree but Sam
I'll tell you something okay like
because you've been smoking full melts
the longest so you you might have a a
faded view of the reality of the
situation but by 1999 when I released
Bubble Bags okay and started making full
mail bubble that was new to most people
not to you but to most people it was new
and I'll tell you I knocked out
dozens of people in those days and I did
not give them huge monster rips I'd just
be like here have a rip or up we'd roll
a snake into a joint here have a we go
to a Ben Harper concert five people in
one night unconscious fall down forward
sideways like it was a nightmare I don't
see it anymore I very rarely see anyone
unless it's at some weird cup and
they're dehydrated and they haven't
slept in two days because they've
traveled far you see at the odd time
there but I used to see it I mean it got
so bad
that I wanted to get pads for in front
of my booth at the Cannabis Cup when we
were still at the Pax party house
because so many people collapsed in
front of my booth like completely
collapsed and other people's booths as
well I seen a guy collapse on top of
hams ham brushland had a had a little
glass Booth one year and this this kid
fell literally on Ham's glass and then
rolled over onto the next guy's glass
table just like breaking glass like you
wouldn't believe it was
what I used to see a lot was people
would sort of sit or Squat and take a
hit and then they would stand up
yeah that's a good way to fall down
there's a lot we don't know a lot about
CBD some of these other cannabinoids as
much as we'd like to know but one of the
things we do know is how it modulates
thc's ability to bond to the receptor
and as we learn that and then you take
that to what people explain like oh well
when I have THC or CBD and I introduce
CBD it relieves the anxiety it relieves
some of these negative effects and you
know what is important I think to
realize is that when those when THC
bonds to that CB1 receptor it's not just
a black and white response how long it
bonds is like a a spectrum of what type
of uh effects you're going to see and
it's on the longer end of that bonding
Spectrum where you can see some of that
panic and anxiety and those sort of
things and I think when we hear people
talk about okay you know I used to smoke
in the 60s and 70s and it was a lot
better we used to giggle and that was
just too much I get all these negative
effects it's not just that cannabis is
stronger in THC levels which obviously
it is it's the company it's like it's a
one-two punch of more THC and less of
the cannabinoids that are there to
modulate how THC bonds to that receptor
so you get longer bonding times which
has an intense effect so these then you
compound that by concentrating it in in
other ways and yeah you're going to have
some now you're getting into the thing
yeah
that's therapy right there that's why I
think the future of like General
cannabis oh
hint out there but I think it's in that
um
you know
six to one one to six sort of balanced
Spectrum more in the middle as we we've
really pushed it out to THC but I think
is a craft cannabis becomes more and
more desired is we push those spectrums
maybe back inward we're going to find
more of that effect that has different
bubble leader giggly sort of effects
that people miss and it's not as risky
you know you don't you don't take a hit
and have a bad experience that makes you
never want to come back you know I think
there's going to be a market in the
future for just some you know like the
you know sometimes we want Jack Daniels
and sometimes we want a chorus light you
know you gotta have some a little
storage
can't you get really really high quality
cannabis or or dry sift or whatever the
product is and just take a smaller
amount rather than taking such large
amounts
well I mean that's hard to do when
you're smoking though right isn't that
the hard part about taking a rip is
because I think it's hard for the human
ego but I I constantly am all about
turning people on to taking a rip
without having a bad experience sorry
micro dose people I give them the
smallest tiniest and some people say
it's perfect and others are like oh I
didn't feel anything I said well now you
can take another one instead of being
all Whited out on that chair right now
because you took too big a one well
that's what they say they said this
again they say dose low and titrate slow
you know and and especially when you're
like trying to frame a positive response
with your endocannabinoid system because
I mean especially for people that have
post traumatic stress whether it's a vet
or anybody that's experienced trauma
because from what I've seen is you know
so typically they almost have a higher
propensity to have this like really
negative kind of inner you know kind of
at least at the beginning you know
because what you see with a lot of vets
is you know that are you know the the
you know the um Iraq bets and then the
you know Afghan war vets the ones that
you know come back with post-traumatic
stress you know try to you know start
using cannabis you know have a really
high propensity to have this you know
incredibly negative kind of uh you know
effect from taking THC even in you know
somewhat moderate amounts but but then
what you see is you know that when they
start working with like you guys are
saying like a you know 20 to one six to
one you know have you micro dosing THC
you know having higher doses of CBD
going through the ritual of kind of
rolling up a joint and grinding up some
or you know kind of you know you see it
really start to Prime people's system in
a in a positive way where they can start
to you know tease out the you know
beneficial effects and then over time
start to be able to titrate up the THC
you know and then what you see is a flip
you know once somebody almost like I
really feel like it's a you know
whenever you start working with cannabis
you almost go through this like write a
passage you know because sometimes you
got to feel weird you know you're all in
control of your mind and your ego and
sometimes like you know like you need to
let go and the catastline like really
humbles you out in that way you know and
almost like slabs you into the ground if
you fight it you know and so I think
it's almost something where we all need
to go through at some point another when
we're working with cannabis to truly
have the respect for the plant but but
it's such a service that we have to you
know set it up right for people because
you know we don't know what they're
going through and if they're going
through some really heavy post traumatic
stress or what have you you know they
might be set off forever if we give them
too big of a dose of THC but but then
eventually over time once they've
developed that relationship and
established that you know right if you
know passed through the right of passage
with the plant and their relationship of
the plant you see them typically flip
and you know if you look at the old
Vietnam vets and uh you know Korean war
vets you know typically you know they're
like Sam they're like [ __ ] CBD that's
for you know blah blah you know then
they they smoke like high terpenoline
kind of sativa type feeling strains you
know and so so I think it's it's all
about you know the building up and and
you know that you know those low titrate
slow things so you can you know
experience a maximized positive effect
well I have a question Alec
um so not too long ago I I smoked um
some some hash I think and I started
shaking right like like I wasn't cold
but I felt like I was really cold and I
was just like shaking and I was like I
can handle my grass you know I've ridden
the [ __ ] snake man and I'm okay to
with the plan tuned into mother earth
right but I was shaken I was shaking
like my hand was shaking
I didn't know if I was like channeling a
lot of energy at the time or if I was
just and so I read about it online I
went out and I checked them that so what
that was was that it that was a THC over
but it's it's interesting because that's
happened to me quite a few times it
hasn't happened to me uh anytime in the
most recent time and maybe it's because
I'm down regulated or something but but
I was I used to call the stone chills
because like if I smoked you know
certain types of bed yeah so usually
like full body shakes like I'm almost
like like Teeth chatter and I was like
wow I'm like feel really cold but I'm
not really cold that's a real
interesting thing to study you're not
cold like like you have you could have a
blanket on you know but you're shaking
like like as if you're freezing cold and
you're just so [ __ ] up man you know
that you're like shake out and what I
read was that was a a t-h-c-o-d and that
you if you take a little bit of the
Terps it'll kind of balance it up and I
think talking uh or listening to Marcus
earlier what he was saying about the
fact that he you know as as uh ingested
this comprehensive diversity of terpenes
and what it did was it gave them this
clear crisp [ __ ] Vibe where he was
kind conscious collected and just
refined but really feeling great and he
wasn't
tweak it out so maybe that has something
to do with it no shaking there
your teeth chattering both of those can
also be related to low blood sugar and
low blood pressure which can be brought
on by large amounts of THC quickly
there you go
interesting thought well I just you guys
were talking about people like falling
over and [ __ ] and maybe that that THC
too much of that could have something to
do with it where there isn't a good
balance you know of the uh of the
terpene or the Entourage effect right
the combination of the terpenes with the
church with the THC to really regulate
it if you're just doing straight THC
shots maybe that could that could that
could have something to do with it
help it happens easier if the right
terpenes
you ever get those shakes out uh yes if
but it happens for me all the time if I
have really low blood sugar uh I can't
regulate my body heat so easy or I will
get shakes oh yeah it's the shake and
bake
hey welcome Chimera you had something to
say on this
well not on the shaking part but um just
on the not people being not you know
novel users
um and I think two of the well for me
the ones that come up often are people
that want to try canvas for the first
time after they've been drinking you
know they're conditioned by Society to
be against it then when they've had a
few drinks they've got their inhibitions
down and they'll uh they're a little
more likely to try it and that's not
really a good combination for crossfaded
yeah it's not a good it's not a good
combo for success
um because people get the spins then
they you know then they're off it for
life like I like was saying
um the other thing on dosing
um and I I had this experience
experience with my mom once she came out
to visit and you know I had some some
pounds and kilos and
kilos of seeds and plants and everything
in my house it was all stashed away and
hidden and she came out and I had had a
surgery and she to relax she took a
little bit too much
and uh you know was in my room 15
minutes later trying to call the police
oh no so
so you know and it was like I had to
talk her down and I knew all the signs
it was she had the heart you know she
had that fast heartbeat and uh you know
people when they're stoned they they
feel that fast heartbeat that
tachycardia which is actually an
effective THC and and many of your
friends are ever shaking too much the
best thing to do is to uh give them a
large sifting bowl with a screen at the
bottom with a lot of Herb in it and let
them make cash for you
so any anyway anyway I forgot what I was
saying Ryan did she so she she was was
she trying to call the cops on you was
she turning on you no no no no
she wanted to go to the hospital but she
came in and she was like we need to call
the police you know and it was like
and she had you know she was having that
Panic like I said when you get that
tachycardia
um and you're stoned people
self-interpret that as something
catastrophic right and you know what
Chimera even worse than that first they
react to it and they increase their
heartbeat even more and that's when they
think they're gonna die well yeah it's a
self it's a self feedback loop right
it's like you know High tachycardia they
interpret it as catastrophic their heart
rate goes up even more
here and then they get fear of the fear
yeah and that's what it was but it was
actually pretty easy to bring her down
because you know I recognize the size
and I said okay look you're fine you're
just having tachycardia in 15 minutes
this is going to be gone you know let's
go out I'll make you a glass of tea kind
of thing and you know I was able to walk
her off the ledge so to speak but you
know I think as like the indoctrinated
we need to be we need to be cognitive of
who we're indoctrinated right and how we
indoctrinate them too you don't you
don't line somebody up of their first
time with a [ __ ] grab dab right it's
all about micro dosing cannabis do you
see to a naive user like to a a system
that's never been primed before is a
really strong drug extreme yeah it's
it's irresponsible you know I use a
video there's a video on YouTube you can
look up and I'll I'll find the name and
I'll say it later so I'm not sure the
name but it's a it's just like college
kids in a dorm room and they give this
kid who's never smoked cannabis in his
life this huge ripping dab
too he gets
um cannabinoid induced Paralysis on the
spot which is a real thing Dr
O'Shaughnessy first wrote about it in
the 1800s and finally they go to touch
him and he snaps out of it and he goes
into this I mean just huge panic attack
because he was conscious but couldn't
move yeah I've seen that video it's it's
remarkably funny it's heartbreaking and
I use that video when I have to have the
because I like to have the conversation
about all use is medicinal use you know
because I think that really means that
there's nothing we could ever do wrong
and I think we can we can use this plan
you can use anything irresponsibly and
that video really is a great example
because that kid is likely ruined ruined
from ever having some sort of healthy
relationship with cannabis in his life
because the people who were with him
thought to be funny I thought it would
be cool and we're just using
irresponsible
drugs are a choice like you don't you
can't be dosing people that don't you
can't be sandbagging people we used to
call it we call it sandbagging you know
loading somebody up with a bunch of LSD
when they aren't expecting a hit but I
think it's totally wrong um drugs are a
choice right like your state of mind is
a choice and you have to be prepared for
that state of mind and that altered
state of mind well you know and that's
one of the things that you know because
I I um and I I might have even mentioned
this before on House Church but you know
I do a lot of education training kind of
for Bud tenders and I really try to
impart like how much of a responsibility
is because you know I mean everybody
since they have such varying levels of
endocannabinoid system tone and kind of
Tolerance you know I mean you know
that's you know and doing it drunk and
you get crossfaded or you know just the
slightest bit having such a you know
lighting off effect of all your CB1
receptors but you know one of the
trippiest parts about it is you know I
mean most people that I've you know come
across I mean it's so fascinating how
many people say oh it's not for me you
know or oh the Cannabis these days is so
strong you know I I used to smoke Canada
was back there I loved it you know but
and and so it happens to people that are
first-time users that happens to people
that take you know significant breaks in
between for months or years and then it
happens to people one day that just are
steady users that take all of a sudden a
full gram dab and and then flip the
script and then they're freaking out for
the rest of the time and so it's a
really really interesting interval I
don't know I I really hope that you know
there's a lot of research around this
topic because it seems like it happens
very almost uh
um predictable for so many different
types of these you know you know
patients coming into contact or coming
into use with cannabis and so it's like
of that much more of an importance to
set it up right because well let's face
it I mean it's not supposed to use or
somebody's like intended in their
lifetime to use it for this certain
autoimmune condition that they have you
know but this little 18 year old
bartender gives them like a you know 28
you know High terpening dominant ghost
train Haze or something you know that
person probably won't ever smoke again
you know and then then that person
pretty much has that on his karma or her
karma because that person might have
been intended to kind of come into a
relationship with this plant in a you
know really respectful awesome way to
where they could have you know
eventually gotten to enjoy that type of
a dose or that type of a terpene yeah I
I think partly it's also due to the fact
that we live in a CR an incredibly
amateur market right
um we don't have it's not a complete
Market you don't have all the chemotypes
that are possible in the species on the
market you don't have all these
different you know percentages like you
said like where is there like an eight
percent finding dominant variety on the
market dispensaries wouldn't buy it
right which is really the worst possible
thing because there's a whole class of
people that would really benefit from
that type of product so I think as we
move forward you know even if they're
feeding they're feeding the prohibition
Market yeah well they're it's these are
echoes of the of prohibition right
um but like I said
as we move into a you know a more
developed and mature Marketplace I think
that all these products will have a
place in the market
um we're going to start seeing you know
like these these non-measing dominant
type twos of different types and and
other cannabinoid combinations that are
essentially THC with another cannabinoid
and the other cannabinoid can act as a
buffer
um and and so it's really we're at the
again I get excited by this stuff
because we're at the beginning of this
journey
um getting on these paths and having
these you know more tools that we can
use you know like like we're talking
about when we're indoctrinating new
people into the market or into the into
the the ceremony essentially into the
that's interesting too because with CBD
CBD with THC is kind of almost like a
buffer cannabinoid for the novice or
inexperienced user as opposed to like a
propyl like thcv combined with THC which
might be like blast off uh you know
added freakout or something like that
yeah or CBG or you know maybe even CBC
so
um did you say THC v b
yeah I mean that was speculative you
probably know more about that I was just
saying
like a one-to-one THC
thcb does not get you high at all it's a
CBD one antagonist
really THC doesn't I thought I was I
always heard it was kind of like uh yeah
we all did that's what we always heard
but it's not true so really
and I also created varieties that were
20 30 40 uh 80 89 uh thcv
whoa so and so you said it's it's a CB1
receptor antagonist
it's a neutral as a neutral antagonist
correct it's a neutral antagonist whoa
so it's more similar to CBD
so so micro dosing is the way from what
you guys are saying as professionals
within the industry uh to to kind of uh
bring bring new users into the the
efficacy of the plan don't don't hand a
14 year old a bottle of 151 proof and
not only 14 year olds I wish Hillary was
in the room right now because she works
with elderly people people in their 70s
80s 90s and even 100 year old people who
are using cannabis for the first time
and Hillary black the founder of the BC
Compassion Club who now works uh through
bedroom con through canopy growth that's
what she does she works with uh she
works with a lot of different elderly
people she told the story on the uh
all-female hash Church panel there where
she turned her grandma on to I think her
Grandma's like 101 now
um it's awesome yeah really really cool
cool stories but I mean the same thing
you're not going to take a 90 year old
person or a 100 year old person and give
them a half gram dab like that is or
just some crazy huge edible like
puddling somebody like maniacal no
maniacal for sure dude and even we got
to be careful with experienced users too
because if you've taken a break from
Cannabis and have it consumed in a while
and then think your dose is where it
used to be you're gonna be on your butt
and also with new roots of
administration
um we all know smoking is very different
than eating which is different than
suppositories so again someone being
introduced to a different method of
consumption I know a lot of people don't
want to consume it by smoking and so a
lot of new users their first experience
is with eating it and they're like oh
it's just a cookie it's just a brownie
and then go into full mode panic attack
and yeah you don't think they're dying
and wanna never wanna eat cannabis again
even the smell of it um grosses them out
so yeah Natasha we do not want to give
people that experience yeah that's why I
also like to always try to you know get
people to you know kind of yeah create
like a ritual out of it you know because
you know they see just you know the act
of sitting there and grinding up an herb
and you know kind of going through the
process of you know almost like praying
to it or putting your intentions into it
and you know learning how to roll a
joint you know with it and even though
your maker does a THC you're still going
through all these actions that seem in
some way to you know Prime you know I'm
sure at least with Placebo or something
I'm gonna start to you know do something
with your endocrine system I mean that's
part of speculation but I think you know
the more we bring kind of I guess
ceremony or ritual into most of our
practices you know the federal
experience you know well intention also
if you're if you're using cannabis and
expecting it to go badly it's going to
go badly so if you're have a high
anxious feeling about using it and
Chimera brought up um first users a lot
of the time as a cannabis because the
officer is with alcohol because alcohol
lowers your inhibitions and so you'll
try cannabis where before you wouldn't
have tried it and then you have a bad
experience where you feel too dizzy you
get too sleepy it ruins your party and
and they blame the kids yes they blame
the Cannabis they don't blame them
yes they are going into this experience
with billions upon billions of dollars
of propaganda that have gotten them so
terrified
terrified at the idea of being high that
many people still to this day will
choose massive surgeries chemotherapies
radiation therapies over the even trying
a plant first they're too afraid to get
high they're like I would rather have my
arm removed than get high and that's
serious propaganda that's a serious
[ __ ] propaganda when you have people
that afraid that they will do surgery on
their body before trying a benign herb
that may or may not work
yeah we got to remember too I mean I've
seen this a bunch of times when people
get up there in age
um it's threatening to their whole world
to start believing that the things that
they were told and believed is true are
actually not true because it it makes
them question their whole reality and so
it's uh it's really
it's it's a tough thing to deal with you
know but again I think what Alec was
saying from the beginning is is that
whole start low and go slow thing with
this type of user is really important
because it can be a powerful drug and
you want it to be a nice soft Landing
you don't want it to be like rip roaring
High running down the beach kind of
thing right what's what's so refreshing
and listening to you all of you guys you
Professionals in the industry is that uh
you know to know that there's an
alternative because when I you know when
I first started smoking grass when I was
you know 17 18 years old a long time ago
like 20 years ago or so
um we just smoked the whole joint you
know and got really high really fast and
that's all we did that's what everybody
did so now to really know that the
industry has evolved to a point of
Competency where where people can really
get the education on how exactly to
micro dose to take just a very small
amount so that you're getting the
healing and all the benefits of this of
this plant being able to use it being
able to acclimate it with acclimate to
it correctly to to get to a point where
where you can actually understand it
better instead of being turned off like
I could have been when I was younger yes
and you know another consideration too
which is such a trip you know I've got
such deep uh respect and admiration and
um yeah everything for you know those
that are you know kind of working with
cancer patients working with terminally
ill patients and and it's so crazy you
know kind of in my experience with is
with it without is like Valerie Corral
Wham and you know the experience that
she has in the service that she kind of
embodies to be in service to people that
are sick and poor and dying you know but
when somebody's you know especially uh
you know cancer patient that is you know
trying to you know kind of utilize
cannabis as maybe the number one
resource instead of taking chemo
radiation you know you know kind of that
you know I mean if somebody's never used
cannabis before they have such a virgin
endocannabinoid receptor system and then
this tiniest amount of THC is going to
have such a lighting off effect of the
CB1 receptors that then you know they
almost have this you know kind of you
know mountain of hash oil that's
decarboxylated or you know combined with
CBD or what have you and and it's like
okay well there there's a mountain of
hash oil not you have to eat it all in
in the next hundred days or something
and you know and I know you know people
would
um you know cringe at me saying that but
you know I mean the the way to the most
uh harm reductive space that Valerie has
found that has the most optimal balance
and effect is you know just what we're
talking about it's it's starting on an
oil that you're you know ingesting
that's higher in CBD much higher in CBD
in the ratio of CBD THC and and their
micro dosing THC to build a baseline
tolerance to the psychoactive effect and
then yeah over time start to build up
you know to to where you know there's an
optimal kind of ratio and and you know
Valerie finds for a lot of different
types of cancer you know the ratio
ultimately ends up at a higher THC to
CBD ratio but it's still pretty
significant you know like you know five
to one six to something like that around
THC to CBD but you know to the point
where you know these these these
patients that are like trying to truly
take bring out bring out and invoke the
medicinal benefit of this plant you know
have to go through I mean I could I
could only imagine how heavy of an
experience that is while you're you know
kind of dealing with the existential
crisis of the fact that you know you've
got an appropriate facing death yeah
you're taking cannabis in a way where
you have to just fully let go and
release you know any controls or things
in your ego and and and eventually you
know get to the point where you're
taking you know in excess of 500 to 1000
milligrams of THC a day and same thing I
know people might like cringe you know
that type of a dose but that's you know
it's crazy how you know various and
certain types of people end up getting
to that dose range and and then when
they you know sustain on that dose you
know kind of over you know x amount of
time they they you know these incredible
benefits and you know apoptotic or
anti-proliferative effects et cetera et
cetera but it's just amazing because you
know I mean if you know this entire
panel you know 1500 milligrams of THC
between us would would probably all get
pretty blasted you know maybe with an
exception of a couple of us but it's
just crazy to think of what somebody
asked about there's a couple of us who
who have eaten several times 1500
milligrams in a single day and that
looks for recreational use
it was for cosmonaut years let's be
honest yes I go not
that's definitely psycho
and it's and what's crazy to me is like
I mean I'm more scared of the the the
high-dose THC effects because of what I
felt from that than I am from you know
doing a high dose like psilocybin or
something like that you know
yeah well I like man I get it I gotta
tell you dude thank you for that work
brother thank you
you know and and other organizations you
know like her that are taking on that
level of service I'm very grateful for
the the ability to work with them and to
you know understand and build my
compassion and empathy around you know
what what type of a reality people go
through in that but it just again such a
profound service you know that you know
you you we have
that we can't like mishandle essentially
I first met the Corrals uh Valerie and
is it Mike
yes Valerie Mike Corral yeah I first met
them at Skunk Man Sam's place for a
lovely evening dinner it was a great
great place to meet you yeah yeah
they've been friends for a long long
time well that's what I knew and I could
tell obviously you guys were telling
Amazing Stories and it was just nice to
kind I mean this was years ago this had
to be 12 or 15 years ago I don't know
uh when I first met them but uh yeah I
could tell that you guys even then had
been friends for a long time
it'd be great to have them on at some
point would love to
have just talked to Valerie yesterday
because we're gonna do it cannabis
restored episode here pretty much but I
met her in a speaking event as well and
you can't you can't not be inspired with
what she does when you when you hear her
talk about it well Natasha we have to
put that together and I think when the
correct if we get Valerie and Mike we
definitely got to invite Hillary that
day as well I think uh she was a huge
they were a huge inspiration to Hillary
uh in the starting of the BC Compassion
Club so
that would be really cool love to have
them on
yeah for those who wanted to see that
video that we were talking about it's
Guy's first marijuana experience ends
with freak out so if you want to see how
not to introduce someone to cannabis or
if you want to see what
cannabinoid-induced paralysis looks like
guys first marijuana experience ends
with recap if you want to see what
cannabinoid induced Bliss looks like the
fish's wet free webcast tonight because
they're they're doing a webcast to their
show and it's free yeah it's so so good
you know the the whole like thing the
whole Chris carota that uh dude that
really makes couch cool a thing go ahead
Forest I was just gonna say I'll be
watching I will too I really enjoy like
I mean I'm a fish head at heart for many
many years and I don't get to go to
shows and Trey got busted with oxycodone
so he can't come to Canada very often so
I I uh couch tour is a real thing I will
be enjoying it thank you fish thank you
free link
yeah and it's free
can't go wrong right
well you know it's a good thing I like
it I mean I would pay too there
definitely it's worth the value of
paying like 20 bucks
yeah you can get a package too I think
you can get like the download the MP3
[Music]
America
okay yep and now it's gone just like
that
all right well what a great conversation
today so far man we've got into a whole
bunch of different things I love it I
love when the conversation is just
flowing freely and natural and it's
interesting to see the levels too you
know the way we can go from this there's
it's just always been a plant and
variety it's always been a very long
stick that you can go on either way with
cannabis and even in the conversation
when you're talking about
you know [ __ ] basically inducing
paralysis and seizures upon their
friends and then like Angels like Forest
trying to help people use cannabis as a
medicine to avoid seizures and paralysis
like that's [ __ ] crazy
I think we're in this new we're just
coming into a new time you know we have
the freedom now to really explore the
whole spectrum of types of relationships
we can have with cannabis and I think
prohibition has really robbed us of that
you know we just we have one or a few
different types of relationships with
cannabis because it just wasn't to have
more minor or different sort of
integrated relationships it wasn't worth
the risk involved
to explore it and and you know and so
what was available to be produced was
certain types of cannabis for certain
types of relationships and I think in 10
years from now we're going to see a
completely different
um
set of options and ways we can integrate
cannabis into our life that has just
been you know it's been hindered by
prohibition and for me it's just a
really exciting time you know it's
something that with the podcast that I'm
working on that's 100 of what we're
exploring is what are these different
relationships and stories that we can
have as if you know they have been
hindered by prohibition and it's really
exciting for me and not not just
prohibition hindered by prohibition and
continued by Big Business yeah yeah
which one of our panelists just posted
the uh thcb uh binding article that that
would be me thank you very much
okay well that may be true but try
smoking it then tell me what you think
oh no I'm just pointing out this is
Roger perdue's article so
I'm just telling you you know what's
what's in the literature
Dan would probably know that better than
that I wonder if there's value in the
scientists puffing and understanding the
bioassay versus the test and seeing
whether they are arrived about any
scientists that would not put out of
curiosity to the substance he's been
studying for years and years and years
but uh I I know Roger personally and
he's a really really nice guy
awesome it's a it's a reminded me of
like it does it even lift bro yeah but
does he lift
does he lift Sam we wanna know I'm
joking does he what
well it's metaphor for does he puff it's
like this thing where it's hard to
explain but does he even lift it's like
a meme yeah I I let's turn around
that's what they want to do you would
have loved the sift means Sam because
the do you even lift turned into do you
even sift and it would show like old
minors and like gold sifters in the like
Panhandle with their long beards their
overalls and holding screens over the
water do you even sift bro
foreign
yeah exactly we have a water sifting I
should have used that in the uh
Link in the chat for the YouTube folks
so they could see the paper we're
talking about
which one
the thcv pharmacology paper
[Music]
I should say for the record Roger perch
we is an absolute Gem of a man and I
don't think he does consume but he is
definitely a supporter of people using
cannabis and uh he's a he's an
incredible researcher he's been doing
this longer than almost anybody and he
really is a fantastic person that's
awesome
his papers are very well written and
very easy to read I mean at least I find
them easy and very easy to follow a very
he's a good scientific writer he writes
yeah Roger he's top tier like Rogers uh
top of the Cannabis scientist realm he's
doing amazing work Roger pertwe hertry
is that who I say his last name yeah
there's not me yeah
hahaha
he's at the uh he's at the University of
Aberdeen in uh Northern Scotland
Scotland nice
yeah and like very very knowledgeable
very good at um explaining complex
material into ways that are easy to
understand he always does the
presentation at conferences where he's
like similar to Ethan where they've got
so much material and they're just like
you guys need to know this you need to
know this like he's very he's very um
he wants people to understand his work
even though his work is complicated
that's awesome
isn't Mary abood from aberleen as well
or University Avenue
I'm sorry she's from Temple University
okay who's the other one
sorry never mind is not still active
academically is she
I think so I think she is oh okay she
was Jehan Marcus PhD advisor and then
boss okay Ruth Ross is Ruth Ross one of
them maybe um I think she was another
GPR 55 researcher I think that I really
research nerds I love it they got all
the stats I got her base I got her card
but uh she wrote 37 papers in 2011 alone
[Music]
it reminds me of the drug sniffing dog
cards that Sam and uh Rob had back in
the day with like pictures of these dogs
they've had their name underneath and
then on the back there'd be stats of how
much cocaine and Herb they were
responsible for getting busted at
airports and roadblocks and [ __ ] that's
pretty funny yeah collector's items man
those are like memes before memes or
memes exactly I still have like a drug
sipping card collection
[Music]
that is an unbelievable statement like
just to hear you say that
I still have my drug sniffing dog card
collection that is so ridiculous so did
you guys talk anything about the uh GPR
119 and the bacteria uh affecting the
cannabinoid receptor
no no let's get into it bacteria effects
Natasha did you read that one
no I saw you sent it uh you informed me
of it last night but I haven't had a
chance to read it yet so can you give us
a summary and after that I want to tell
you guys about another study but let's
get into this first
yeah I mean I I didn't actually delve
too deeply into it so I was kind of
hoping that you had
um I'll prep for next week yeah
essentially what it is is that the
they're finding now that gut bacteria
are producing compounds that are
actually stimulating
uh some of the Le the less known 400
receptors yeah orphan receptors that are
associated with the endocannabinoid
system wow that's amazing microbiota
yeah it's the whole right it's the whole
microbiome thing it's the it's this we
have a community of Life of bacteria
that live with us you know in case
people haven't haven't heard you know
there's more cells of of bacteria in
your body than there are cells of you
right so that the interplay of that
community and how that what they have
living in you know as they go about
their daily lives it has a huge impact
on your you know our two our two systems
they cross there's a lot of crosstalk
right they intercommunicate with each
other
so anyhow we're just anyhow we're just
the point is that we're starting to
understand now how
um
these systems interact with each other
to create health
who is the research group that did the
work I I haven't even looked it up yet
I'm sorry I don't I can't say
okay well that's definitely incredible
though
two receptors in the gut right and you
know kind of you know apparently you
know kind of from you know I know that
that uh what John John mcparley and
Karen feeding paper kind of you know got
into how kind of probiotics you know in
you know in your gut like help to you
know upregulate CB2 receptor expression
and and it's crazy how much kind of you
know from you know gut dysbiosis you
know kind of I would imagine comes so
many different types of disease and
disorder and and you know also like uh
with psychosomatic type
you know illness also manifests kind of
from you know your second brain in your
gut being out of balance and not you
know kind of working right to produce
the right kind of you know
neurotransmitters and and now I guess
what also endocannabinoids
or lighting off the endocannabinoid
system that's fascinating
I think it's why it's so important for
cannabis to be cultivated in organic
practices
uh the soil biology contributes to
what's happening on the plant's surfaces
I know that we all work with
concentrates but I think the source
material having a full biota if you will
uh is really an essential part of making
medicine
that's so awesome you said that because
I just I just listened to this podcast
um I'll post it here in a second it's on
this guy Dave asprey's um he has this uh
show called The bulletproof radio and um
there's this doctor Dr Maya
um she treat Klein and she's like a
neurologist herbalist and author of a
book called dirt here healthy food
healthy gut healthy children and um and
yeah in it kind of it's all about how
kind of you know yeah like being out and
I mean not being you know the opposite
of being you know the the hypochondriac
that puts on you know anti-microbial
kind of hand sanitizers you know five
times a day you know but actually from
kids playing out in the dirt and from
you know being out gardening and
consuming organically grown crops that
have you know these probiotic kind of
soil micro kind of you know soil food
web kind of balance you know organisms
you know kind of getting
um small tiny amounts of that actually
does wonders for our own you know
microbiome you know and and even also
like you know what you know in this she
describes how kind of you know almost
being in the dirt and consuming plants
that are organically grown and
um almost have more of a beneficial
um assistance to helping balance our
soil microbiome with the right types of
microbes than even just going to Whole
Foods and popping these like you know
lactobacillus or these different you
know refrigerated probiotics that we get
in stores and pay so much money for you
know it's actually you know you can kind
of get the same and better from just uh
you know actually being in healthy
environment soil and gardening different
bacteria right so like there's all these
different types of bacteria and we also
have to look at bacteria for you can
take certain types of bacteria for
certain purposes but most people don't
understand that there's actual ways that
we're communicating with bacteria so the
lab that I worked in uh during my grad
school who was sorry
exactly but they there's these receptors
on our cells called folic receptors and
so they actually recognize
um basically different sugars on the
surface of bacteria so most like a lot
of people will talk about LPS or
lipopolysaccharide that's a immune
marker or that some that's a bacteria
product that can stimulate your immune
response in a bad way and give you
overactive inflammation and so a lot of
people have uh little bits of this
compound this bacteria compound LPS kind
of floating around under your gut and
kind of talking to your immune cells and
such and so there's this receptor on our
cell called tollec receptor four that
specifically recognizes this bacteria
product and so what's interesting is
it's not only a live bacteria that our
cells can recognize and talk to they
also recognize the bacteria DNA and the
products from when the bacteria are dead
so this even brings up concerns with
like um say pasteurization right so say
you're drinking uh milk and you're not
really sure of the source it's from I
mean we're Lucky in Canada anyway I mean
America is similar you have access to
clean milk that's been properly properly
processed to avoid bacteria but
something that people don't understand
is even if that back that milk or
whatever food product has been
pasteurized or treated and there
actually is no live bacteria just having
that bacterial DNA and the bacterial
byproducts can still cause an immune
activation cause inflammation and so
it's not just live bacteria that can
interact with our body it's also the
Dead
dead bacteria and so we can think of
bacteria again as like good bacteria and
bad bacteria so even the good bacteria
interact through these similar receptors
and what's interesting is they interact
through the same receptors but they can
tell our immune system to calm down and
chill out and everything's okay and so
that's why there's certain
um
studies where they're feeding people
with immune disorders certain types of
bacteria that can Target these
anti-inflammatory processes and actually
get their inflammation under control and
so it's absolutely essential when we
think of the bacteria we're using to
feed our plants our Foods because those
bacteria are getting into US interacting
with us and either providing beneficial
or harmful effects so it all very
holistic right very holistic but so
awesome it's kind of As Above So Below
thing you know it's like the idea of uh
you know recreating the perfect soil
through kind of you teeming with
microbes kind of is I like I like what
you're saying there because if you if
you think of it and even imagine it like
that like the interior living on you you
are their planet and and are you a good
Planet are you feeding them good food
are you encouraging good bacteria to
grow or are you feeding them bad food or
you know let bad lifestyle practices are
you over stressed are you overtired and
I know Tom McCormick talked a lot about
it when he was
um doing his plants and learning how to
feed and nutrition Plant Nutrition and
soil issues and he was realizing that
hey I'm like giving my plant the best
vitamins and the best nutrients why
don't I do that for myself right so it's
great to think about that also yeah and
you know and you know and also kind of
goes then further to that whole you know
Secret Life planting and the fact that
we have implants and or you know even to
that Michael pollen coevolution thing
how much the plants are having effect on
us and so it's like not just you know
how the plants are having Effectiveness
but how the the plants that are made
available through the you know through
the mycorrhizal kind of network
connecting the world and then the
microbes that are like almost inhabiting
all these different plants that we
choose to take or not also then you know
so it's like it's almost like how much
of us is us how much of us is micro our
microbes that we're consuming from the
other plants that we choose to eat or
from living a life that's sterile and uh
you know kind of just being on and off
serious antibiotics all the time and you
know being a product of a factory farm
human system of eating processed [ __ ]
and you know tons of sugar and killing
off all your microbiome and then just
repeatedly kind of just being almost
dull and like you know
yeah you know kind of droned out you
know just kind of further consuming
being a product of a con system of
consumption is almost you know
speaking of poop have you seen the uh
research and the studies about uh people
who are exposed to cat poop
um are exposed to a certain type of
plasmosis yeah and it can actually
affect your mood your behavior I mean
it's it's and cats are necessary for the
breeding cycle so we can make like rats
more
um with which are a natural
um whatever their natural enemies and it
can make the rats
want to be friends with the cats and so
uh there's some really interesting the
virus gets to rats it makes the rats
more impulsive and just like walking
right up to a cat the cat will eat it
the cat will get the virus and then the
cats give it humans from interaction and
kind of the other feces and et cetera
and the original sources cats though I
looked into it one time because there's
also this what's sorry what's the
password the original doctor is cats to
us right yes yes but but it's mice to
cats but the cats if there's something
specific about the cat and how the the
pathogen breeds in the cat because I
went down a rabbit hole looking at it
because it it's also an issue with
certain types of meat and can be
contaminated on other animals and I know
Joe Rogan was tweeting about it and I
was like it's not just cats and then I
looked into it and for some reason the
cats actually are essential to their
breeding cycle you know but that's
what's crazy too is you know it feeds
into that old cat lady thing you know
because or old cat dude you know because
it's like if you are you know um in and
around cats all the time and you know
they actually say one in four people or
something like that in Europe in the
European Union have uh toxoplasmosis and
yeah and it very markedly kind of you
know it uh shifts people's behavior in
certain ways to become more Reckless and
impulsive and higher propensity become
addicted to gambling and certain things
like that but yeah in the podcast I just
sent about you know listen to talking
dirty about spiritual plants and
microbial biodiversity they kind of get
into and it's the first time I'd ever
heard it but this neurologist is getting
into
um viruses and parasites and how
um you know viruses and parasites also
in certain ways all that aren't all bad
um but have certain other weird kind of
down down Trail or Downstream kind of
beneficial effects so I I don't really
know what possibly could be beneficial
about toxoplasmosis but but um they get
into basically these different types of
disease and viruses that you know
um similarly I guess have some type of
weird symbiotic relationship where they
kind of come and take over the host or
or impact us and people have them but
then there is also some other weird
interesting kind of effects from them
that are beneficial I guess also it's a
lot different in people with suppressed
immune system with a strong immune
system you you can pretty much ignore it
when when you have suppressed immune
system it can be uh yeah very very very
dangerous well and that's and that's
actually why um you know because and and
that's that's a really awesome segue I
think Sam um because
you know because everybody's freaked out
about microbes on cannabis and it's like
which ones are good which ones are bad
and should we regulate all of them you
know and and so and and and and I'm
really happy to see kind of you know
Californian you know kind of you
becoming more educated and how they're
approaching targeting um you know uh
what microbes to test for because you
know when you're just testing for you
know total aerobic bacteria total in you
know total yeast and mold certain things
that are more like indicator
microorganisms that you know of things
like shelf life and quality and and uh
stuff like that you know I mean it would
be very almost ignorant to kind of over
regulate those because you know we come
in contact with those every day from
Foods we eat and like the different
things we're in you know um interacting
with in our environment and microbes are
ubiquitous in our environment you know
so it's like what microbes are bad you
know but then yeah I think it's a really
important thing to distinguish is okay
well for your average person that has a
semi quasi-strong or relatively strong
you know microbiome in their gut you
know yeah the presence of kind of you
know any foreign Invader that you know
even is potentially
um pathogenic you know can oftentimes
get crushed out by this Army of microbes
that are you know in your gut ready to
just wage war against anything bad you
know and so so you know but but but such
a quite distinct different situation
whenever somebody's undergone chemo and
radiation and serious after series of
antibiotics and they have no stomach
stomach microbiota you know essentially
and so it's like so those you know those
types of patients should almost choose
their cannabis medicine based more off
sterility you know than they should
um you know anything else uh you know
whether you know that's taste or flavor
or kind of you know terpene I mean
almost in a certain just in a certain
capacity for safety because yeah you
know like you know and that's that's the
difference we try to distinguish is just
you know people that are you know stage
four cancer you know unless their herbs
essentially sterilized and you know or
like tested and you're very confident
that it's very low cfu of anything or
you know or screened and kind of for
mycotoxins and all that stuff they
probably shouldn't they should choose
more off like these you know sterile
extracted oils that are standardized
milligram dose you know so that they can
I mean because those types of patients
are you know almost going to benefit
more from that type of treatment you
know than you know
but better can makes gamma-ray
sterilized material which lowers the
terpenes has no effect on the
cannabinoids but it does slightly lower
the terpene content
that's right gamma radiation that's
right but but but again you know it's
like is is a patient I mean sure if a
patient gets gamma irradiated weed that
slightly turbos apps you know and you
know they're smoking it but they have
stage four Clinic you know stage four
cancer or something I mean again they
should probably be more trying to ramp
up high-dose milligram oils you know
than than you know kind of thinking that
they're going to smoke like a you know
15 total cannabinoid bud in a joint and
burn it and then you know lose half of
it or more you know from the combustion
process you know so so you know that's
the kind of thing I'm trying to try to
differentiate oftentimes whenever you
know I'm working with dispensaries to
train their blood tenders it's like you
know whenever you're assessing and
working with a patient to understand
where they're at and what they're
looking for and how level of you know or
how deep of a you know illness or
disease they're they have it's like you
know it's important to to help guide
people to the right type of thing and if
if you know somebody's looking for
cannabis and they're trying to kind of
take on you know major you know kind of
treatment of a disease I mean you know
you should almost kind of educate them
about the the micro thing the
microbiology thing because you know even
if you know it's just the East and mold
and aerobic bacteria that you know if
somebody has no immune system they
probably shouldn't smoke it you know
they they should choose another way of
ingesting it you know so where they can
maximize the treatment and minimize the
potential pathogenic or harmful you know
things that can be introduced to
and keep in mind also as I was saying
before back with the pasteurization same
with if the plants are treated to kill
all the microbes those um the DNA and
the micro products are still there even
though the bacteria is dead so I also
worry if some and you see the presence
of four of dead DNA or of dead microbes
about DNA on its own has has a negative
effect you're saying right exactly and
so if we're um sometimes I worry about
uh plant producers or Growers thinking
that they can still have a dirty product
and then just irradiate it at the end
and then it's magically okay like that's
not the case we still need especially
for things like mycotoxins too because
they're like byproducts of certain
pathogens they are not destroyed by
gamma-ray sterilization right the
organisms may be but not the microtoxins
they produce so these products almost
have to go through some type of or
anything with these levels I guess to
truly create a significant medicinal
standardized oil it would have to go
through various steps some
post-processing to filter out and
separate out potential mycotoxins or any
other DNA I mean I guess you might not
be able to remove it all but
you almost need to take that on in a
certain capacity if you're trying to
create a product for you know the ultra
sick what about when you're putting soil
microbes in
um are those just staying in the soil or
are the microbes coming up the plant
getting in the flowers like how is that
working
if they're if you know oftentimes
compost teas and you know beneficial
microbes you know are used to you know
as you know as bio fungicides or
bioinsecticides to spray on the foliage
of the plants you know but I mean if
they're being sprayed full you know into
Fuller application then yeah they're
going to inoculate the leaf surfaces
they're going to be present there
um you know but but I mean if they're
not going to necessarily kind of come up
with root drench or you know feed the
the
the inner part of the plant
or the I guess the roots of the plaque
they're not going to kind of yeah
systemically you know kind of transfer
but if you you know but but if to not
use systemic homicides
biological you know inoculants and so so
it's you know so most people are using
at least in veg or you know very very
very very very beginning of flower you
know people will still kind of spray
things like actinovade or forage which
are strepalomyces beneficial fungus or
you know BT or BS or different types of
bacteria
yeah the the rhizobacterias uh will stay
on the root and then there's certain
types of strains that will encumber the
plant itself but rhizobacterias they
just colonize and grow on the root
itself
so yeah you're absolutely right and
Bravo
with uh
that's awesome you've said man you're
you're right on point with so many great
things it's nice to listen to you
brother yeah you've been going off hard
today Alec I gotta say as well I've been
really enjoying everything uh that
you've shared so far
it's a yeah it's a beautiful honor to be
in this group of amazing mentors
the hats he wears are too straight
oh Sam yeah
I like this super straight last time he
was on hash church he was like snuffing
at Pina or something
I love it
I do love it yeah that's great good
conversation guys everyone in the chat
is absolutely enjoying it there was
someone that asked a question to you Sam
and I don't know if I can find it if it
was it was something about what did you
mean by needing a thousand plants to
perverse to preserve genetic diversity
okay well if you're trying to save a
land race
then you have one or two plants picked
out of it and you reproduce it in a
closet under a light all you're doing is
you're reproducing that a a couple of
plants from because from the variety
because uh if you want to keep all of
the traits and save all of the genes in
that land race variety you need at least
a thousand females and a thousand males
if a higher count is better but at least
if you have 2 000 plants you're
preserving 99.9 or some ridiculously
high amount uh percent of the genes are
conserved each time you reproduce the
variety
so we're talking about the genetic
expression so when people who are
watching this when you get a pack of
seeds you'll notice that you get a
different expression of genetics in
those individual seeds even if they're
from the same plant so
that's kind of what
we're talking about there
the plants are not identical it's a soup
of of genes that are compatible and work
together and are reproducible as a as a
collective whole but when you start
breaking up little pieces and
reproducing it it doesn't have
everything that the big suit has you
know you know something pretty pretty
interesting um yeah so I just got back
from Oregon I was up in Oregon for the
past week and uh and there's this big
issue that you know I mean people have
been talking about for a long time that
I think it's just about to like really
popping all over you know in California
too but you know all these producers who
are growing in greenhouse and outdoor
you know are essentially getting seeded
pretty hard by the or Southern Oregon
hemp farms and so so you have all these
like really chronic kind of you know
sense Mia strains that people have been
breeding and working with bring out THC
and to create these really high profile
strains and they're essentially getting
dusted by these feral hemp type
cultivars
um you know which I think you know which
people are super super chapped about but
um I think it's really fascinating
because you know it's almost like you
know again through that like idea of the
you know I guess like uh Botany of
Desire or something you know it's like
the plant itself is kind of almost
through this interesting kind of open
pollination project you know it's gonna
be like receding all these high THC
cultivars you know with novel kind of
because so much in the ha is I think so
many of the minor cannabinoids and you
know even interesting really unique
terpenes so much are are also locked up
in the in The Hemp stock or the feral
kind of cannabis stock and then also in
and you know you know um yeah rare land
race kind of you know cultivars and
stuff on another note how [ __ ]
awesome is your compost hat straight out
of compost crazy I was like Sam is a
little harder for you bro dude that hat
is awesome that is a play on the Compton
hat for those of you who don't know and
that is really really well played holy
[ __ ] my friends uh biologic systems who
are kind of uh proteges of Elaine Ingo
and kind of make this hat I'll totally
dial you guys out with some if you like
I need one I'm gonna wear the compost
pad
yeah you're like you're like the Michael
Jackson of hat lid wardrobe changes yeah
I just did that because Sam was making
fun of me
yeah I got the super trippy hat on he's
like yeah your hats are too straight and
then someone in the Chad is like they're
flat pills they're supposed to be
straight I'm like no dude he means like
Joe stratey like not trippy
if any of you are at the emerald cup
I'll gather a bunch of these um and you
know I'll give you the cup awesome
thanks Alex
on our head
yeah dude that's that's the [ __ ] dude
probiotic hair washes
oh yeah now that's really great that's I
got some great hats but I don't have one
that great that's that's a great hat
dude
I gotta say put a smile on my face so
did today's conversation thank you
everyone for rocking a crazy hash Church
we've almost been going for three hours
I'm glad to continue going if we have
things to talk about them I want to
bring up another study I don't know if
you guys talked about it earlier it was
a new uh human trial double-blind
placebo-controlled trial with oral
uh cannabidiol CBD looking at its effect
on anxiety and so they used healthy
people I didn't read the whole trial I
just saw people tweeting about it and
saying like oh CBD so overrated it's the
biggest Placebo ever and like kind of
you know trolling CBD medicine
um for anxiety anyway
um but some issues with the study is
they looked at healthy people and so
they found no effect and the doses they
were giving were 300 milligrams 600
milligrams or 900 milligrams compared to
uh no CBD and so the trial design was
good but I think spray or oral I think
it was oral I have to read the whole uh
trial I'll post it uh it just came out
or it came to my attention just
yesterday so I haven't had a chance to
read the whole thing yet but I'm just
curious what people think
um I'm wondering if they repeated the
trial with people who actually had
anxiety if they would show the benefits
or
anxiety on people who don't have anxiety
like is that what I'm hearing yeah so
they did they did these different tests
um I'm not totally familiar with the
test so just from the abstract what I
got is their tests where it's like to
evoke
um like Stress and Anxiety in a normal
person and then they kind of test your
responses and so they're looking to see
um and keep in mind this is a clinical
test so they're trying to uh make
comparisons so they can say yes it works
or yes or not so this is so contrived
type of experiment so do they they
basically put a bunch of weed in the
trunk of your car dump Terps on you and
send you through roadblocks is that how
it's yeah
this is why I think it's kind of
[ __ ] is because they did another
study with 300 milligrams oral and they
looked at people and they put them
actually in a test of social anxiety
where they had to public speak just in
front of the group so I think that was a
better test of an anxiety situation
because most people are terrified of
public speaking where this one they kind
of expose them to some imagery and it
looked like they kind of measured like
eye movements and things but I'm just
wondering if they repeated it with
people with actual anxiety or different
tests that they would see an effect and
maybe they're just showing hey CBD
doesn't
alter your Baseline responses in a
normal healthy person so wouldn't that
be a good thing
um but yeah so a lot of people were just
saying oh CBD for anxiety that's
[ __ ] and I don't believe that to be
true
it's caused by too much too too fast THC
then CBD is affected for other things uh
I don't know you know I'm curious
well I mean I I have two things come to
mind one is that this drive for CBD only
I don't even understand I mean for
science yeah let's keep looking at it
the animal studies human trials
everything has shown that CBD by itself
is not as effective as CBD imbalance
with other cannabinoids but you know you
have
um
this
drive to to try this High CBD on people
who you're trying to induce anxiety from
and I would think that someone who has
uh endocannabinoid regulatory issue
chronically where it causes long-term
consequences that may be inducing panic
attacks or or mood shifts is going to
interact differently than somebody with
a healthy functioning endocannabinoid
system where you just try to induce
stress for someone who has a healthy
functioning system I don't understand
why that would seem like it would
correlate when we know enough about the
endocannabinoid system endocannabinoid
deficiency disorders and how some of
these cannabinoids interact with it and
assume that those are
interchangeable because it doesn't seem
like it would be to me so I'm not
surprised at the results
hmm
[Music]
interesting that's my thought yeah and I
totally agree with you that CBD alone
like let's evolve past that because we
all know it works better with even small
amounts of THC with even little bits of
other uh terpenes or I'm assuming other
compounds it works best with other
compounds and I know that especially
from the work that I've looked into with
Crohn's and Colitis I mean they just
came out with a study with 10 milligrams
of CBD only orally for patients with
crohn's disease and showed that it
wasn't helpful which isn't surprising
because a lot of the patients are using
THC and CBD in a one-to-one and I
um totally agree with you forest and I
mean I've seen Bonnie Goldstein do many
talks on her patient population and same
thing that's the thing that people don't
want to know is kids also need THC with
some of these
they don't they absolutely do I mean
every study has shown that take and
let's just stick with peer-reviewed or
double-blind studies the epidiolex
aesthetic right the GW Pharmaceuticals
did on meniscuso and Gervais syndrome
kids we had the doctors coming back to
you know cbd's not as effective as you
parents said it was but none of us were
using purified CBD and they looked at a
clinical dose in those studies at around
10 milligrams per kilogram right huge
doses of CBD before they saw any
efficacy in I was speaking to the head
of pediatric neurology at UCSF and he's
like well see this that's what you need
to do and cbd's not as effective as we
thought and I had to tell him it's like
I'm sorry doc but you guys are years
behind you know awesome that purified
see you're you're having those results
because you're using uh
essentially and it just doesn't work
that way you know you need to have THC
and the other cannabinoids in there that
interact with the receptors differently
than CBD does and that's why we're using
10 and 20 milligram doses for some
people it's saying more uh efficacy than
you're having at 500 and 700 milligram
doses well that and that's what I really
really love kind of about this plant is
it it almost seems like it's
unpharmaceuticalizable in a certain to a
certain level you know because like
because there's so many people that
think that the move is to you know kind
of like and it's weird because like
there's there's a high demand right now
I don't know why people are paying for
it but a lot of people are creating
um these these these these kind of white
powders or crystallits you know so
they're like refining fractionally
distilling thca and they are this thca
Crystal and it looks like a drug it's
like straight white powder and then
people have the white distal it or you
can't distill thca
you can't facilitate to see it well not
distill not just excuse me I mean well
whatever it is they're doing like you
know ethanol and kind of like you know
kind of just doing some type of
distillation or not maybe not
distillation this license with heat I
get it
but a recrystallization from an
extraction yeah or doing it by the rosin
method or yeah
right I just mean like yeah and yeah
excuse me it's like I'm I'm wrong and
how it's being extracted but they're
making the like 98 99 thca Crystal or
you what have you or they're making kind
of you know the CBD
um that's you know fully exactly
the chemist is in me is excited I mean
you're taking the active ingredient from
the plant and you're purifying it I mean
that's heroic and Champion for a whole
different level no it is it is it is you
know and I'm not trying to necessarily
knock on it but I think and I think I
think it's very unique and interesting
and novel to be able to take that and
then you know kind of combine it in
unique amounts and ratios to really you
know in some capacity you know nail
Sometimes some type of a you know you
know because that's that's what doctors
are missing and research University are
missing are the standardized to you know
but if you think you're gonna get it and
have an efficacy just by using one
single molecule isolated compound you
know it's it's it's exciting to me that
it's not working in so many of these
ways and and you know it's having such
low efficacy in comparison to even just
having you know you know a tenth amount
or a 20th the amount of you know a minor
compound in there let's face it uh thca
is the Pavarotti in front of this
Orchestra of other compounds and the
orchestra of other compounds or
flavonoids terpenes some other
cannabinoids other but the star of the
show
is thca sorry that's just the way it is
with this plant right yeah okay now some
plants don't make THC because they have
another synthase that helps them make
cbda and we talked about those earlier
hemp varieties low THC varieties but
yeah I mean thca is the star of the show
so everything else sort of surrounds it
in kind of like the symphony and we were
talking before I love using the symphony
analogy because so so important because
you might hear
you know the trumpet and you might hear
one or two elements of the brass but
then there's the whole undertone of the
brass which brings the whole level of
the orchestra up to a whole different
level that wouldn't be there if you were
just listening to a a trumpet and a and
a trombone player like a small group
Jazz which I told a lot of two and
that's why like Ensemble or sympathy is
almost better than Entourage you know
absolutely The Ensemble effect because
they all work together in creating this
overall fragrance or Essence that you
know attracts humans yeah
but make no bones about it it's not just
you know how you grow it and whether
it's indoors whether it's Sun grown
Outdoors roots in the ground Outdoors is
different in Roots in a pot outdoors
everything makes a difference because as
you very nicely point out we live in a
microbial world like it or not we're
just microbes
everywhere on our plants on us
everywhere everywhere everywhere hey I
wanted to also just throw a wrench in
the works you know that whole number of
how many bugs are on us I've heard that
sort of tend to one there's ten to one
microbial cells for every human cells
that thing is more like about one to one
folks it really really is so because
there's more recent studies that show
it's about 1.1 the 1.9 the one so it's
really close to one to one in terms of
microbial mass and your human body mass
so it's not ten to one as was previously
thought yeah what if you smoke weed
every day in regards to so yeah
I was just gonna say this is the
exception for those of us who are full
of [ __ ] those people have a lot of money
when we lived in caves I'm sure it was
more like ten to one
bacteria within the human body it's like
a ratio of ten to one but it's like no
it's been it's definitely been
overestimated that ten to one because
when I started my grad school program
and I was in a bacteria expert lab like
Leading The Way with toll like receptive
research we were all saying 10 to 1 10
to 1 and by the end we were toning down
because yeah it was overestimated it's
still a significant amount but ten to
one is not the appropriate number yeah I
think that the take-home point is that
there's a significant amount I mean
whether we're saying ten to one or one
to one it really doesn't change the
point that there's a huge interaction
between the microbiome and the body
that's all yeah and what's what's
interesting that is that my best friends
are bacteria 2016 you know and we're
just beginning to actually fully realize
and understand the human microbiome you
know I mean that's when we started it in
2016 is when they started I believe
2015-16 when they began the human body
biome this should and that's just when
they started it yeah I mean so new it's
so new that this data is is trailblazing
right now yeah like how lucky are we
that we can actually sit here and debate
whether it's the Ensemble effect or the
Entourage effect or like if it's ten to
one or one to one I mean we've come a
long way and we've got a lot of
knowledge and I think that you know
sharing that knowledge is the important
thing of getting stuck up on the
semantics of isant is Ensemble versus
Entourage really like much better I mean
to me those points are kind of moved but
have you guys looked into the report Dr
Russo put out this week
The Usual Suspects a few promising leads
yeah that's a paper that he's published
yeah it's a paper paper he published
with jhan Marco that was just published
what's it called it's a book chapter
it's not a paper yeah it's the chapter
but it's a cannabis pharmacology it's on
PubMed uh Usual Suspects and a few
promising leads
um read the abstract they haven't bought
the rest of it yet but has anyone
checked it out yeah but yeah I haven't I
didn't I saw I read the abstract I
didn't even try to look her for it on
the side Hub if you go on Reddit I liked
it okay usually those those type of
Publications aren't shared around when
they're chapters from a book they're not
as easily accessible unless you're Sam
yeah it's 30 bucks I mean it's not too
bad luckily on Sam it's not it's not the
30 bucks for me it's that like that's
one of a thousand articles I'm always
looking for right so I I look I don't
look at it the same as just 30 bucks
it's like it's like is this another one
that I want to buy yeah
another one that came out just to put on
everyone's radar if you're working with
patients is a a new study on
interactions between Canada and commonly
used anti-epileptic drugs so
who are working with people coming in
for seizures and spasms I think it's
really critical that we've known for a
long time how the camera dial working on
cytochrome what is it p450 uh affects
the metabolism of certain
benzodiazepines like uh clove exam and
comfy but now they have a list of like
six other drugs that they've shown that
it interacts the drug levels in the body
so something to look for if you're
working with patients for sure that just
came out earlier this week Boris do you
see uh this is a random quick question
do you see um uh the benefit of
ketogenic diet a lot with the epileptic
kids or patients that you work with yeah
certain kinds I mean you're just it's
all about changing brain chemistry yeah
right so kind of with with those
families certain adults or kids or
anyone dealing with those sort of things
and I think that's too much for Focus
yeah is that a sentence and they too
heavily focus on those sort of things
but just epilepsy I think any
neurological sort of condition albeit
depression or other things we see it
affected with with diet because you're
changing the chemistry in the body but
yeah we go through all diets and
supplements and cannabinoid
phytocannabinoid supplements are really
where we aim for with those kids and you
know you just you get lucky with some
and not with others they're all
individuals
there's also for those who are curious
there's the ketogenic diet is a high
protein high fat site then there's the
gaps diet and modified Atkins all three
of those kind of create different
effects and they can all be really
beneficial they're all similar in low
carb right low processed grain low kind
of bean and legume and all that stuff
yeah yeah yep
yeah and then and you know maybe maybe
this is also a you know topic I guess
for another conversation I don't know if
it seems like it's probably kind of
wrapping up but I would really love at
some point to like have a deep House
Church dive into kind of the
um you know like almost inviting like
you know maybe like Mark Lewis Mike
baucus you know and then maybe some of
the genetic dudes like the phyllo Skies
or motorcycle skies I mean it'd be kind
of a Royal Rumble you know of uh of a
hash church but I think I mean you know
they're you know just with that that
recent kind of article that came out the
great pop Monopoly you know kind of all
around the you know you know the Utility
Patent reality of some of the type 2
stuff happening
you know and then you know on the on the
other end then you have like the people
and the genetic testing Realm of the
world that are you know seeking to kind
of sequence and you know claim to you
know open source a lot of stuff but you
know I just have a lot of questions
about the potential of you know data
aggregating genetic data in the future
you know of all this information that's
being given out just
you know you know to you know from all
these breeding conditions across the
world to all the you know to these
companies that are you know kind of
eventually have a lot of power to
Aggregate and like look at and notice
unique interesting things about the
genetics of the plan just whether or not
it's all like malevolent or benevolent
you know and and you know I just think
it's a really fascinating topic that
most people don't really understand and
so since we don't understand it we
almost take it offensively I think it's
not either malevolent or benevolent it's
just the way it is it's business and
this is now that cannabis is in the
world which is Major like uh
philosophical like kind of ethical
conversation you know yeah yeah I agree
with you but I had this conversation
with Mowgli this week I spent the funnel
with I spent an hour on the phone with
them talking about it and I'd love to
rapidly offline I I think part of this
is that you know these grievances that
people have towards the way this [ __ ] is
playing out are not grievances they have
actually towards a given company or set
of individuals that are carrying out the
way normal business does normal business
really if you have gripes with Pat
utility patents then you need to talk to
the Utility Patent officer the people in
America or the courts and change the way
that the USPTO Works which isn't going
to happen well but that's but that's the
thing though and it's like to take that
hatred that you have or that lack of
respect that you have for a system and
then put it on the shoulders of one
group that is operating within the legal
mechanism of the system I think is
misplaced no I and I agree with that you
know and it's interesting because I I
have uh you know I I'm like this I have
this like Switzerland type thing I'm
trying to represent you know in in
um not you know because I don't
understand really too much of either
side I understand you know pretty vastly
the implications of the the utility
patents you know um you know and I think
you know I have a lot of qualms with it
on its own
um you know just you know
philosophically blah blah but then on
top of that you know then like there's
there's the the claim means you know
purpose and service of the genetic
testing services that are sequencing the
Cannabis genome and and they're also
going to be qualms and concerns with
that too Hey listen they're doing
bioinformatics screening it says it
pretty much right in there yeah your
your your contract that you sign when
you submit a sample yeah and you know
it's not like let's be honest it's no
different from FC Labs I mean SC Labs
gets to sample the market from a
chemical basis and you get to see things
before anybody else even knows they're
going on well but but but if we're but
if we're a specific third-party testing
laboratory that doesn't have Holdings in
genetic development or like you know r d
or you know kind of creating genetics or
kind of making products you know and and
and also it's like a very limited uh
fingerprint of what we're getting you
know the key no no I hear you I'm just
saying I'm just amazed like what could
be pulled out bioinformatically from you
know long sniff sequencing or from you
know whatever let me tell you the honest
truth uh
it has a huge value you can say look at
here's a plant that has lots of THC no
CBD has lots of
and it has uh pinene and uh vital
I mean there's a lot of value that and
not to you at this moment but there will
be people to who that will be a gold
mine because they're looking for
particular things yeah and let me let me
say something else I like on that point
I mean
listen this is the same thing that
happens with with big business like
Monsanto but I'm not saying that you're
Monsanto but but what I am saying is
that you guys are collecting data and I
mean we can take this one end of the
spectrum that you grow old and when
you're 70 you pass the the business down
to your children or potentially you get
bought out right and so all that data
gets bought out too right
um and these are just things that happen
in the world of real business right it's
like there's consequences when we start
providing a service and collecting data
I mean Google makes all their money on
Analytics
right like that's the whole point it's
like you you get to access a whole bunch
of people search data and you understand
what they like and what they want and
then from that you can make decisions
based on their on what you can Market to
them right so it's it's really no
different you know in all of these
perspectives right well well I mean so I
mean I mean I kind of I kind of see what
you're talking about to a certain point
but whenever you know with 98
predictability anything that we test
having one of three or four primary
terpenes an additional like two or three
four you know secondary sesquite
terpenes or you know uh you know
whatever
um you know it's you know most
everything that comes through I mean
yeah there are these you know one
percent outliers that have really rare
Unique Kind of certain
um primary terpenes that never really
show up in any significant statistical
amount but you know most everything kind
of falls into this range of you know
what's there but you know we're talking
about you know one typically one climate
cannabinoid thca and then like you know
two to three collections that are
important because you want to sit
through it to find those little tiny
flakes of gold well well I mean like our
whole like you know kind of vision for
that is the how exciting of a tool that
is than to help people that are breeding
and focusing on genetics to identify
what on the rainbow of what on the
rainbow of uniqueness do they have and
what can they fill in and then from
there what unique combinations can they
breed out through combining this one
from this side of the rainbow to this
one to the side let me call through
breeding people can you know start to
fill in the holes where you know maybe a
lot of the eradication kind of has
happened over the last you know 100
years that might have gotten rid of a
lot of the unique interesting stuff but
it's all for the purpose of further
being able to pull out and breed out and
kind of bring about the diversity that
this planet has but but and then just
real quick then you know because because
I'm like in my opinion that's a you know
that's a small amount of information you
know but it's a lot of ability to help
kind of you know the public value of
data help drive a lot of work kind of
future breeding or or you know
identification
but my question is is how's you know
because I I would think and maybe I'm
just ignorant but I would think that
that amount of data is you know like you
know on a certain level valuable yeah I
feel you but but if you're we're not
taking and sequencing the not entire
genetic kind of expression of the plan
you know so that you know one day
potentially we can notice unique really
trippy synthase genes or or certain
environmental characteristics that might
help explain through reverse engineering
certain Appalachian Tendencies or
qualities let me comment on that
um
this and this is the weakness of all
those genetic tests okay so when Mowgli
was on here he said you know we're doing
this open cannabis product project and
what we need is all the labs to donate
their chemical data right which made me
laugh because essentially they're
charging for their service they're not
giving it away for free and why should
why should SC Labs right or anybody else
that's in that game too
um the second thing is that the genetic
data on its own is completely useless
without understanding what
bioinformatics yeah well no well you can
do the bioinformatics but it's like once
you can if you have the genetic data and
you can't correlate it to a set of
traits so that you can start following
those genetic markers and traits over
Generations you can't tie them together
right so there's an inherent flaw in
only accepting dispensory samples and
trying to do genetic work you have to
have a breeding program that goes along
beside it so that you can understand how
those traits are inherited whether
they're scored phenotypically or scored
hematical leave through a lab so say
they get all that
who are well no no I'm saying I'm saying
so so yeah so it seems like the
chemotherapy data would be incredible
important absolutely it's totally tied
together some of the genetic realities
of the story you can't have it's you
don't have the full story unless you
have both pieces well okay but what I
mean but but if say if like over time
any genetic company were to collect
thousands and thousands of chemotype
data kind of imprints to then overlap
with you know the same genetic kind of
stuff I mean what is what can they come
out with I mean what and and this is
again this is more from a space of
ignorance than it is anything else
because I'm like [ __ ] dude I think like
my ultimate like dystopian view you know
would be you know in the future you have
like some people that figured out how to
[ __ ] you know like bio hack the plant
and then like all of a sudden you know
across the United States you have all
the pharmaceutical companies with
[ __ ] acres carved out of like insulin
growing cannabis through the trichomes
or [ __ ] Obits growing out of the
trichomes of cannabis plants you know or
whatever and I mean that's kind of a
stupid kind of uh Terminator type trip
reality of where it could go but I'm
just not at all I mean listen that's not
a bad thing you remember the Ebola thing
that went off crazy in Africa like about
18 months ago or whatever I'm just fine
yeah they were making they grew the
Ebola vaccine in tobacco
okay it's like it's way faster to
transfect Tobacco than it is to create a
strain and start ramping it up in a a
bioreactor it's like it's actually
tobacco is one of the easiest plants to
transform and you can put proteins into
it and grow them really quick and clone
them up and then extract them so the
future yeah maybe there is to like
produce all kinds of pharmaceutical
drugs through the trichomes absolutely
there's a guy I can't remember if they
do DMT would I be into it there's a guy
on uh
there's a TED Talk and if you if you go
to Google and you search TED Talks homo
evolutists so like think Homo sapiens
but homo evolutists so
evolutis yeah that's awesome and
essentially it's his argument is that
we're no longer Homo sapiens we're now a
different species that are instead of
altering the environment like we have
done over the past 10 000 years we now
alter the genomes of the other organisms
around us and ourselves is inevitably
where it's coming to
um but yeah crispr cannabis is coming
soon there's only people in God there's
already people working on it
um and and you know what cannabis is
actually pretty special because there's
not many plants that produce 30 percent
um of one compound in a given you know
like you said an expression system like
the Tricom so if we find out how to
hijack it then you know what we can
actually use cannabis to produce all
these different things
and then who is I mean and then so I
guess what I mean and what does that do
to bug in Monsanto then
yeah
well I think again it's like that stupid
article it's like they you know they
paint this image that it's monster well
no and well you know well I'm I'm
wondering who did Monsanto the guys the
article is talking about or the guys
that put like the article in the ear of
the journalist you know and that's
what's funny dude they're everybody I
mean everybody's Monsanto don't say that
I'm not yeah they are because I mean in
the article too they talk about Ziggy
right Ziggy and Jeff and jodery up in uh
in Humboldt and uh how they said they'd
patent their stuff too right so it's
like everybody would do it if they could
but I think a lot of people are you know
kind of don't fully understand you know
their people just don't want their [ __ ]
to get jacked you know and and a lot I
think a lot of people have okay but wait
wait a second of the type 2 non-mirison
dominant strains somehow is going to
infringe on their development of their
genetics which it's not okay but what
happens but real quick what happens when
what happens when all these THC
cultivars or thca cultivars that are
grown in Oregon are getting back and
randomly accidentally seated by this
Hemp stock uh these hemp crops that are
in southern Oregon and then like if they
happen to props pop some seeds you know
all of a sudden what if they got like a
terpenolene or like a limonene dominant
type too accidentally from that is is
that now infringing
if you take it and you Market it
intentionally because it's alignment
type too hell yeah that's tricky it's
not gonna accidentally pop up and just
be dominant in the field you might have
one plant that way but it's not going to
happen now these things are these things
are the result of intentional breeding
and it's got kind of you know call me
biased but I kind of laugh at it a
little bit because it's like these
things really are Innovations people
don't they're huge Innovations but they
don't exist on the market so it's like
how can you sit there as a part of the
community and say well it's unfair that
those guys did all that breeding work
and develop something that I didn't do
you know what I mean well and it's
disingenuous and it's also disingenuous
to then try to sell a service like
trying to scare people that this patent
is going to crush their ability to grow
what they've grown all their life
yeah and I mean I talked about this with
my ugly and I talked about it with Kevin
before and it's like it's like I said to
Malibu this week it's I find it a little
bit disingenuous that these guys are
listen Mowgli and Kevin are Super Hyper
intelligent people and and they're good
guys too like they're like I consider
them like I really like both of them
yeah yeah so but I mean again they're
coming into a game that some of us have
been playing a lot longer than they have
and then essentially they're saying so
they're hella paranoid
yeah once it's there I mean dude we're
Rebels and people like the whole the
whole class of us are people that live
on the edge of society so we're
untrusting of the government as it is
right we're untrusting of big
corporations
um
and anyhow I I mean I don't know it's
like I I do also agree with you I feel
it's a little bit disingenuous to be
saying that
they're essentially the Protectors of
They're Gonna Save the Cannabis
Community from the big evil Corporation
well especially when like they have
sponsored and promoted and kind of like
Instagram and Facebook posts with the
great pop Monopoly on the pit on the as
the posting you know as a as a [ __ ]
like almost like a article to sell the
service you know and it's not and it's
not drawing distinction one way or
another good bad whatever I'm just again
trying to just figure it out because
like I think intention matters a lot and
you know I just think a lot of people
don't really understand the whole
reality of what's happening or or you
know and I think there's a lot of um you
know using fears of patents to like kind
of you know just I don't know yeah we
listen we had Newton Malibu on here I
think it's pretty obvious to anybody and
Mark dude uh Mark's not coming but um
Mowgli had a uh you know I think it was
pretty clear from the way he came on
that he's mowgli's an idealist and he's
a beautiful human being and I don't
think that there is evil intent in in
their work I think he truly wants to
um stand the molecular genetics of
cannabis in order to be to be able to
exploit them or help other breeders
exploit them I mean that's clearly their
business plan that's mckernan's business
plan as well too it's anybody's business
plan that's working let them or let
others exploit them or help others
exploit right very exploitive terms well
they're not but I mean exploit I mean um
I mean Expressions
to take advantage of Kevin's coming up
with Hands-On laboratory Diagnostics
that look to be quite useful in the
industry I don't see that happen over at
mabley's uh I don't know I don't want to
get into that conversation I won for I
for one totally disagree with you
they're both they're both in business
they're both in business the smoke could
join and look at the Galaxy yeah but
listen they're both in business they're
both our corporations they're both going
to find any way to take the knowledge
that they gain through their sequencing
um their sequencing foray and find a way
to turn profit about that I mean that's
that's what they do right it's the same
thing that SC Labs does in offering a
service for uh the the lab service that
you guys offer and it's the same thing
that I do and offering seeds to the
market in Europe so
um
I I I I I have a problem when people
start pointing at the other guy's stack
and saying it's unfair that you did this
to make that money
um those are you know and and listen the
reality is Alex that you're talking
about this dystopia
um it is the future and I don't think it
is it's dystopia I think that it's just
these are the tools that exist in the
marketplace and of course those tools
are going to be used to investigate
cannabis and of course people are going
to take that information that they glean
from their experimentation and they're
going to try and find a way to profit
from it and uh and it's going to happen
on the Philo side it's going to happen
on the medicinal genomic side and it's
going to happen on those guys that we're
doing the patent side so
um but if you look at those people I
mean it's like people like Michael
Backus and he's not involved anymore but
he was and you know he's the guy's an
industry leader so he's been doing it
for a long time I mean he's 100 and he's
one of the he's straight he's straight
up oh gee right so
I have a little bit of a hard time this
is my first connection of selling packs
to whenever I first came into the
Cannabis Community they developed one of
the first truly medical dispensaries in
La so I mean come on so I have a hard
time when these other guys to join the
game later say we're gonna save the
industry from these long term it's not
it's not Monsanto it's these are like
old school people that are probably the
most advanced in the field right and
they did some super Kick-Ass work and
then the community is going to get
pissed off because they've created a
bunch of things that nobody else has
ever created before I mean I just I I
can't I can't empathize with it you know
what I mean and uh maybe I'm biased and
maybe it's some too into the genetics to
see it but you know what that's we're in
a different world folks it's no longer a
bunch of hippies up on the hill sharing
medicine we're in a business where
cannabis is legalized and in Canada it's
not just you know legalized like this in
California I mean we got big Banks and
investment Banks throwing
tens if not hundreds of millions of
dollars into these companies to do
research and uh develop proprietary
methods and of course this is the type
of thing that is going to come out of
those forays so being scared of people
collecting data on the genetics dude you
don't want you don't want your DNA
getting out the door that don't sell the
herb right because if you put the herb
out the door I can collect it and take
your DNA or at least look at your DNA if
I have the skills to do that right just
like I can if you give me a butt I can
take it to a lab and have the chemotype
analyzed also explaining that if you let
it out the door then you no longer have
the right to patent it if that's what
you wanted to do well that that is true
but I think that the the way that the
patents and the thing that you think the
people don't like about the patents is
you don't even have to let it at the
door for these people to stake claims to
these chemotypic classes right right and
that's a trip that's a trip because it's
about showing that there hasn't been
anything in existence up to that point
right right but let's flip the script
again for a second it's like this kind
of like me saying I want to develop a
handheld device that sends email I can
watch YouTube make phone calls and text
messages and store music and all these
kind of things and it's going to have a
touch screen and blah blah blah and then
I turn around and I say oh it's unfair
that Google or Apple patented it right
well it's like I'm late to the game I
came up with with the idea too late
right you don't see people freaking out
about oh we're it suppresses innovation
no it doesn't suppress Innovation it
suppresses innovation in the same field
that they're innovating in right that's
the whole point they've developed these
products
right so if you have a problem that
they've gone ahead and developed these
products I I don't know what to say like
I I don't buy the argument that
I can't compete right there's lots of
room to innovate in cannabis and if if
you're going to be like a follower and
you're going to go around and try to do
the same things that other people have
been done and then complain that they've
patented or they've they've secured IP
property in in on on those things I
don't know I just I don't buy it
nice so but yeah it is the world's
Common Man I mean if you let your
flowers out the door and these
bioinformatics companies and the cost of
sequencing is coming down down down down
down every day so it's getting cheaper
for them to do the work
um yeah they're going to start screening
and looking at traits in your plant and
you know trying to figure out how they
can they can benefit them and you know
what to me that's not a bad thing that's
a great thing because we're going to
have more tools upon which to improve
the species that I love you know just
like the labs are the same thing I mean
when I first start getting access to a
lab
well I was able to make significant
progress you know it's a it's an
incredible tool and it's it's having
access to that tool is not something
terrible it's a dream
not only do I agree with you but if you
think of the arch types or uh super
terpene classes whatever you want to
call them right once these all exist
then they can be given to different
patients for different illnesses and we
can find out what helps what that much
quicker right
it's the future this is the future and
it's like the future is already here in
corn and it's already here in wheat and
Mark Sheldon talked about this the first
time I came out of church I think this
episode
66 or something but
um he said the same thing you know like
one day biotechnology is going to be
this tool that we can do all these
things that we do in corn and wheat and
soy and all these other crops and you
know what that world
thankfully thank Jah that we live in a
world where legalization exists
and we as farmers and breeders can
actually access all that information you
know to me I think that that's
incredible I don't think it's something
to be scared of
um
the one thing that I really got to hit
home is this public domain commentary
the art of that article again painted
this image that public domain is good
you know nobody's gonna be able to grow
weed and we're all going to be locked up
by big business that is absolute
[ __ ] there all right good seeing my
question there's nothing true that
there's nothing true there at all if
it's documented in the public domain and
SC Labs has been instrumental in
documenting things in the public domain
by releasing that data out that you guys
were releasing at one point in time and
probably hopefully will again
um
of releasing the chemical data onto the
market and showing what exists like
nobody can come and take blue dreams
nobody can come and take OG nobody can
come and take anything other than the
name of Gorilla Glue floor for nobody
nobody can take train wreck nobody can
take
Jack Herer right Northern Lights Afghani
Juan skunk on and on and on and on these
varieties because they were taken by
people by SL like Sam and you know other
seed breeders that release these things
into the world only that is the basis of
the chemical the the public domain and
it's you know what it's an incredibly
strange situation that we find ourselves
in like there's no other planet in
history that has been sequestered and
prevented from being
like worked on like any other crop right
except for cannabis and everything was
done underground and now it needs to
find its way into the public domain but
what what what these labs are doing in
demonstrating that these chemotypes
exist is they're proving the public
domain you're essentially scribes that
are documenting what exists in the
public domain and anything that exists
in the public domain can't be taken by
another group and patented you just
can't do it that's the way the patent
laws work so that's a bit disagree you
do something new with it like
hydrogenated yeah or make or make type 2
non-measing dominant greater than one
percent terpene plants I mean is it
right well you can do that can you
you're reshuffling the existing deck
chairs and all these are common
molecules that are already known
my example points any direction it's
that the plant has done heavy lifting to
make these molecules what can we do now
to make them better to make them
different to make them you know what how
can we take nature as an inspiration to
make other new molecules yeah well
listen you and I yeah you and I are you
and I are completely in agreement but
also completely at loggerheads one
because you look at it from a chemistry
point of view and I look at it from a
biology genetics point of view so it
puts us at different Vantage points but
I think we're all really saying the same
thing you know when you can get a plant
that can produce 20 uh by weight of a
Target gee whizzakers gee whiskers
you can you can aim it towards whatever
you want I mean THC that's obvious uh
CBD you can get more than 20 percent uh
CBC CBG thcv cbdb all of these things
you can get 10 20 percent of well one
way I mean I don't think
I had the same discussion in regards to
Ohio Lake soybean oil and when they saw
uh levels of oleic acid exceeding 80
percent I'm like oh my God 80 oleic acid
and soybean oil what can we do with that
oh my God it starts to look like yeah
with modern biotechnology we can do just
about anything or teach plants to do
just about anything
yeah really
huh
but you know where plants leave off
where biochemistry leaves off that's
where chemistry starts and as we know
you know a big piece of the industry as
it exists today is is is concentrates
and just to go back to analogies
remember that Vineyards while they rely
on good genetics and good grapes they
don't sell grapes they sell wine
so how you make you know fruit of the
vine work of human hand to get biblical
um it's the work of the human hand where
the value is in creating sort of high
quality cannabis products and Craft
products like you know single malt
scotch I think is you know with a lot of
uh you know the market today going
towards just sort of like a more generic
thing there'll hopefully still be some
value for creating really high value
you know whole plant extracts that have
a lot of good terpenes and everything
that the plant all the heady goodness
from the plant and as as far as I know
flavonoids when they're smoked have no
effect but they the heat destroys them
it I know with oral flavonoids could be
important have you ever heard of anybody
trying to take flavonoids with THC to
understand how they would modify it
orally or or smoke they thermally
degrade right they don't yeah I don't
think yeah well and I think and what's
funny too is about most ingested or
infused products you know where most
people decarboxylate their oils prior to
kind of infusing it into an edible you
know it's like that you know and yeah I
think we've been talking about this on
here before but it's you know it's funny
how many products are labeled Indica
edible or sativa edible you know when in
actuality there's no terpenes or
flavonoids remaining bingo The American
Canadian markets the same way it's all
hilarious that's hilarious because
nobody's nobody's like adding
significant terpenes to orally ingested
kind of products that have been the
thing that's hilarious is that the
market can't even the market still
thinks that they're by that there's a
difference right oh I buy the sativa oil
for the morning and I use the Indica oil
for how much is Placebo well and you
know that that word that a little paper
that uh that really great paper that
Adrian davidley and Martin Lee put out
um through kind of Ocean's project CBD
about like Mind Over Matter over mind
and it's about how the the belief in uh
treatment is going to work Placebo or
the non-belief treatment is not going to
work no sibo you know in in substantial
ways across many different systems are
also mediated or
um enhanced kind of by the
endocannabinoid system releasing off and
firing off in certain ways certain ways
yeah yeah I think most I think most with
animal dose has to do with I mean in you
know the how much is somebody taking on
a full stomach empty stomach overactive
underactive immune system you know
sedentary or active lifestyle where
there's so many different variables in
how the same dose is going to hit
different people
yeah but yeah no um and and and so and
and to something you're saying uh just a
little bit ago Chimera um you know we so
we we had this uh site on our or this
this tab on our website where it was
just it said scl tested and so anytime
um somebody paid it you know because
because anything tested with us is is
the you know the ownership of the people
that are doing the testing and and so if
they make up sample public then back in
the day you know it could be viewed if
you just click on SC Labs tested
um and I mean and you know it can still
be viewed regardless when people use QR
codes or kind of you know print labels
or you know do this or that you know um
you know because it'll take people to
the page but but we have since
essentially taken away the scl tested
side of it because we found out there
was like three or four different groups
that were basically like uh what do they
call it um they were they were speeding
kitties yeah they were they were they
were mining your data yeah there are
mining and yeah scraping anything that
would go um would be public and so so
you know they were kind of like yeah in
their way like you know just like
jacking pirating all our data you know
and and it's like and you know to a
certain extent I don't know how valuable
that data is period because you know
it's just showing kind of you know
what's it out and around but you know no
but again the quest the thing is is
and I I gotta put it back to you in this
in this context when you release
something into the public domain it
becomes available for all to use so it's
it's again if you guys are going to make
the choice to release that information
out there or the or your clients are
making that choice by clicking the box
or checking the Box
um we have to be aware that there's
gonna be people that are going to
aggregate that data and they're going to
use that data to do analysis and try to
understand Trends and find norms and
find uh unique things right yeah
thinking about it it's a great subject a
taping policy right The Grateful Dead
taping policy was not like the favorite
Child of the record industry which says
look if you're trying to stop records
you shouldn't let people come to your
concerts and tape you but by people
coming to the concerts and taping them
all that information got out and all the
tape trading and the whole Grateful Dead
culture grew because they they had this
taping thing so it's kind of like again
putting stuff out in the open domain
Garcia used to say hey man when we're
done playing with it they can have it
you know like they've already played
those notes and it's nothing labels
hated that [ __ ] yeah well and that's I I
gotta point it I gotta point out the big
difference there is that that was an art
and there was a business of Science and
cannabis and and if you if you fail to
recognize that then you're missing the
whole point oh listen it's just like
anything you can choose to give it away
or you can choose to keep it that
doesn't matter what you're involved in
Elon Musk gave his patents away billions
of dollars in value because no no let's
let's be honest he gave some patents
away
but he also kept a bunch for himself
right and it's a business decision I
mean and it's it's listen it's whoever
[ __ ] collects and makes the data's
decision to do that on their own I mean
why are you gonna why are you gonna go
spend a bunch of time figuring something
out for a business purpose right and
then give it away for free to everybody
else that makes no sense I mean Alec
you're not going to come up to Canada
and teach us how to set up a lab with
your protocols and yours
within that mechanism but it makes yeah
we would people
it happens
[Music]
yeah it does happen but I'm just saying
it's again it's a it's a it's a
difference in
business style and yes I think that it's
also one that's like it's heavily argued
by the people that aren't doing this
type of work right I mean everybody was
hey man I really like that shirt that
you weared why don't you make me one of
those shirts or like you know like I
don't know
I I again I find I think a lot of this
hippie stuff comes off as uh as
disingenuous right hey and check this
out in wired they actually posted that
Tesla gave away all of his patents right
yeah they posted that and wired yeah if
you Google it Tesla just gave away all
its patents away to its competitors
using the term all it happens
[Music]
and the guy's still worth what three
four bill
wow I don't think it heard him yet but
then again there's bands like the
Grateful Dead and fish that gave away
their music that at the time they were
doing it the mechanism for profit only
existed in keeping it and selling it
back to the fans they shattered through
that and created something that a lot of
us would argue is better
yeah well they I mean listen bands make
their money bands bands don't make money
through selling records bands make money
by touring no but record labels used to
make money so I know they did but the
bands did themselves I mean you know
I've cut an album and talked to record
companies and I know a little bit about
how it works and it's like where if
you're an artist dealing with the record
companies it's not you don't make any
money you make money on your touring you
make money on on your merchandising
rights and whatever but you might you
know you might be lucky if you get 50 60
70 cents for a compact disc so well I
think they could also shut down a lot of
videos on uh YouTube you know there's
videos just about of every band other
than prince who had his police go
through there and completely take off
all Prince content from YouTube but the
argument is that the people who post
those YouTube videos a lot of them are
pirated are not the owners of that
copyrighted music information but the
people who have the copyright aren't
rushing to take that stuff down because
it provides publicity for them and
ultimately gains and values so if like
you let a strain out or variety out and
it wins a Cannabis Cup and Everyone
likes it and all the Growers want it
and you just decide hey we're just going
to kind of like let this go that can be
a much more powerful business model in
cannabis kind of like in the same way
you know don't you think
yeah I mean there's lots of ways to
protect IP I mean since the Coca-Cola
secret Coca-Cola is never registered the
Coca-Cola secret you know
don't go to the patent office and say
this is how we do it you're gonna get
not a pad yeah yeah you don't teach you
don't teach your competitors how to do
it and the way that cannabis is
regulated and it's so tightly controlled
at least in these regulated systems that
are developing in Germany Australia and
Canada and other countries that are
doing Federal legalization you're not
walking out of a facility with a plan
okay you're just not going to do it
you're not going to be able to do it and
if you're a big company you're also not
going to label it from the production
room you're not going to call it this is
my CD CBG dominant you know type
whatever type 2 terpineline plant you're
not going to label the plant it's going
to be
x7496316 and and the people that are
doing the production they're only going
to know that plant is that tag and
they're never going to know what it is
in the output so because it doesn't
matter to them they're just making a
product they're just a worker in a a
production line so there's lots of ways
that you can protect these things you
don't need to go out and Pad stuff you
can develop unique things and profit
from them without doing that and that's
a choice that every individual business
is going to make on their own yeah
well said Chimera well said
controversial topic awesome appreciate
it yeah yeah it really is I like it it's
uh it's you know what I like having
conversations that people are
uncomfortable to have that in this day
and age and conversations that trigger
uh things that try to shut the
conversation down to me means there's
value in that conversation and it's one
we should be having yeah and you know
what you guys have been very respectful
in the way that that conversation has
played out today I mean I've seen this
conversation unfold online and the
immediate thing is those [ __ ] they
are doing this and that and they're
Monsanto I mean the article the title of
the article is Monsanto it's not
Monsanto these are like all-time
researchers but that's the ultimate
trigger word if you want to shut someone
down and you want people not to look too
deep and you just want to shut it right
down then then Monsanto is your they're
your guys just right so what's the
agenda of the person that started the
article what's the agenda of the author
right I mean it's like we can start
questioning everybody's agenda yeah 100
and and that's the thing it goes back to
that that whole reality that the things
that we don't understand we often
viscerally will reject or you know take
offensively you know and it's so much
more complicated and complex topic you
know and I think a lot of people in the
same positions would would you know
absolutely go that direction of you know
going
to file intellectual property around the
pad you know around their work but yeah
I don't know it's just it's an it's an
it's an interesting thing because you
know my uh you know I mean if they're
smart enough to have done that and
already locked up all the type 2
non-mercine strains you know it's like
we're so it's like is there anybody else
that is gonna go figure out like the pen
tools before them or or all the other
super unique Pathways before them well
think of this Alex think of it this way
imagine they lock up all this stuff and
stuff that people didn't even know
existed but now they do they're late to
the game and now they're looking for
things that are specifically not those
things that got locked up they're gonna
unveil things that are even further and
deeper down the rabbit hole no that's
awesome that's and that that's actually
the perfect answer I think you know
because you know when it all comes down
to it doesn't [ __ ] matter you know
philosophically ethically whatever as
long as it's there and available at some
point even if it's being licensed you
know then then it's still still the
still the move I mean it's still it's
still progressing the whole agenda of
the plant yeah I always have faith in
cannabis listen it's like the bubble
bags I mean the bubble bag you know they
came out and now you pay a licensing fee
to the guy who had the patent on it
right yeah so
you know that's that's what's going to
happen I mean I don't think these guys
are it's it's I think there's actually
laws around you can't patent stuff and
then withhold licensing right yeah so
you have to you have to license it to
people yeah exactly
and it's fine like I I fought it for the
longest time and the more I looked at it
the more I realized as I followed the
history back that it was like listen
this was like the for 100 sure the bags
themselves were developed based on this
machine that Reinhardt had patented
regardless of any other part of the
story the bags that I made my bags from
were created based on reinhardt's
machine literally staring at his machine
watching it work can't really get around
that to me that is the birth of the bags
were the reinhardt's ice cold extractor
machine and
I'm happy to have paid the royalties out
uh from the beginning I didn't just
start in like 2013. I paid from 1999
from the day the company was created all
the way till you know the future next
hundred years plus dude that's
fascinating because you've actually been
through the whole reality dude I went
through a seven year court case with
Reinhardt oh we're like now we're like
partnered up on some projects and I've
paid him his money for the patent and I
try to tell other people that are you
know selling bags and just like look you
know you might want to look into this
it's not worth the litigation that it's
the guy's superly not greedy but he'll
hit you hard if you if you try to [ __ ]
with him for a decade won't his patent
be over in a couple of years he's got an
end to his patent in 2018 but if you
look into patents there's all sorts of
different ways to extend them
yeah
Brave New World they never really end if
they don't want them to
and how much yeah and patents are only
as good as their ability to be enforced
and uh but you know that's the thing
people are getting pretty sophisticated
with that whole set of litigation [ __ ]
too and no what people are used to a
world where you pay a hundred bucks you
get 10 seeds and then you do what you
want with them the rest of your life
yeah well it's wild wild west dude
cannabis industry for the longest time
is like the wild wild west where people
just do whatever they want however they
want and now the legal mechanism says
well actually there's a whole bunch of
things you have to change if you want to
play in the legal mechanism that only
fit in your prohibition based model
you're gonna have to leave a lot of this
stuff behind like these are the
mechanisms of business that are
available they're all different tools
yeah well let's can I can I interject
there too and and extend it to say it's
not even the mechanism of business it's
like guys we got to stop spraying Mike
labutenil on your plants you got to stop
[ __ ] spraying by phenization
forbid 4f and Avid it's like it's these
are also things that we have to learn
leave behind it's it's not okay to
assume and say this is how I've gotten
by for the last 50 years I'm not willing
to change because you know what we have
to accept the new paradigm we have to in
order to be taken seriously and treat
our clients with respect we have to
adapt we have to everybody needs to
raise their game like everybody and and
treat the plant with the most respect
and integrity because otherwise it'll
shake your ass off yep
and the market will too I mean look what
happened with these companies that have
been spanked in Canada for having dude
the microbutanol thing is destroying
some folks I mean to me I mean
organogram I mean that was a brand
killer it was an absolute brand killer
you know wasn't there a huge public
removal of the CEO and everything oh
yeah
yes it wasn't pretty it wasn't pretty
but it wasn't the CEO's fault you know
that they actually they were a little
bit of victim themselves and you know
they're negligent because they didn't
monitor it but they hired a production
company to come in and run their grow oh
wow right I mean that's that's the
reality though it's a really difficult
thing to grow cannabis especially in
like abundance and on huge scale you
know if you don't have incredible
knowledge doing IPM and organic you know
prevention stuff you know yeah and
protocol I think it's going to weed most
people out on their own right based off
their like chasing of Fool's goals you
know to like rap too quick yeah and it's
the same thing with the mites and it
happened to the black market and you're
seeing this and you guys have published
these great graphs that I use on Twitter
um that show you know the level of
contamination but this is what happens
is people they see a past like week two
and they gray and it ends up in the
flowers and it's it's too much of an
investment for that person to lose
they've got their future wrapped up in
their forty thousand dollars or eighty
thousand dollars it's coming down out of
the crop even if it's five thousand
dollars you know people are they're so
counting on that money
so you can't buy they've already spent
it dude or maybe maybe yeah
listen it's not always a problem it's
not always Ferraris sometimes it's rent
you know I mean or food right it's like
to these people this is sometimes it's a
25 000 glass pieces
yeah but sometimes it's like the ability
to eat right or the ability to pay your
rent or your mortgage right so there's
there's heavily heavy incentive to
to protect with your investment and um
and that's why we need regulation right
it's because as we've seen
just leaving it to the market and
letting people do what they want and
expecting that they're gonna act
responsibly has been shown that it
doesn't work right we need regulation we
need to have a set of rules that
everybody has to play by if you want to
participate in the market
there it is you know I know people don't
like hearing that but it's the truth
it's like it's not okay to me I like
hearing it it's it's not okay to put on
um Michael abutinol weed or Avid weed or
by phenocate weed or you know whatever
Flora might wheat on the market it's not
okay
well that's just one of the trippiest
parts kind of you know it's I mean
because a lot of you know because back
in the day before we opened up SC Labs I
worked at uh you know big Hydro Store
kind of chain in Santa Cruz and uh
and yeah I mean you see you really you
know there's a divide you see really
well-intentioned people that are so of
this plat and like this doodle harm and
would never even imagine spraying one of
those things you know but then there's
other people that you know are well
intentioned um and they're trying to do
good but but yeah man this is a this is
a cash crop and you know crop loss you
know even the smallest amounts so huge
to people that are living grow to grow
dude
you know if you go there's even further
the people that just don't give a [ __ ]
because they're trying to make as much
money as they can you know and so I
think I think that that that's
significant spectrum of the type of
person that's working with this plant
it's gonna dude if you go into a Hydra
store pretty much anywhere in Canada not
all of them but almost all of them and
you asked for Nova under the counter
they'll sell it to you no tax cash sale
no receipt
you know and it's they're not allowed to
do that it's like it's against the
[ __ ] pesticide regulations for them
to sell it to anybody that's not you
know that's not a trained most hydro
stores do and are and have it
historically in the past also been the
biggest slangers of like pgrs you know
and and it's because the significant
demand for those exists and if you don't
have them so go to the neighboring Hydro
Store yeah they're beholden to their
customer listen any industry where
they're beholden to the customer you
know like even even doctors writing
prescriptions for uh opioids or whatever
you know the doctor in the states at
least it's not as bad in other countries
where it's not a privatized Health Care
System but it's one thing I definitely
noticed in the states is that the the
doctor is beholden to the client and the
customer is the patient in that case
he's the one that's paying the bill if
you go in and you ask for Zoloft or t3s
or or even Oxycontin yeah they'll give
it to you right because they're beholden
to you it's like they you want you're
their client they're making money off
you you're paying their rent you're
paying their they're putting the bread
on their table oh you're right that's a
significant flaw in the ability for I
don't know yeah no it makes me nervous
about how many dispensaries we have that
aren't forced to test you know if
they're not forced to test will they
test or will a lot of that product get
sold to people that are you know
patients man I'd listen I I Yap about
this on Twitter all the time but like
I'd love to be I'd love to be on side of
the Canadian dispensaries and I
unfortunately can't because most of them
refuse to test roast most of them refuse
to demand testing from their Mar Growers
and uh it's [ __ ] because I've seen
cities like I've seen you know how
California's done it I've seen how
Berkeley California has done it I mean
they have a dispensary Market where it's
it's member patient cultivators it's all
home Growers right it's like the same
type of people that are supplying the
dispensaries in Canada but they demand
they require wire that you test the
medicine to show that it's clean before
it ends up on the shelves and um and it
can be done and those people can produce
and and patients can make money they can
be part of the industry but creating a
situation and calling it a dispensary
where you're allowing untested medicine
on the market I just I'm sorry I can't
get behind it I would never buy
dispensary weed in Canada I wouldn't do
it
right well you know there's also this
really huge kind of thing happening in
California right now um
I mean it's turned into like one of the
biggest like social media like Troll
Wars that I've ever seen take place and
uh you know basically there was this um
you know I don't know if you any of you
are familiar with but there's this uh in
California there's this proposition
called prop 65 and prop 65 uh makes you
basically have to label and put up signs
that say you know this product is known
to the state of California to cause
cancer and birth defects and blah blah
blah and um and and so what you have are
these like ambulance chasing lawyers
that will basically
um go and document like repeated kind of
violations of not having signs in
certain retail spaces you know to say
that type of prop 65 claim and and so
you know in a lot of Industries the prop
65 thing is really it's a really kind of
lame kind of lawyer chasing kind of like
litigation scam kind of thing but but
what they're what just happened is they
they just um on the California attorney
General websites you know they just
published like 650 lawsuits like for
prop 65 to a lot of the biggest [ __ ]
Brands and companies throughout
California because there are all these
samples I guess that were independently
just pulled off shelves and then tested
and then have found to have pesticides
in them and then they basically used the
pesticides as a way to do this prop 65
uh litigation claim in cannabis in
cannabis and uh and so so yeah so it's
it's crazy so you know there's these uh
these spreadsheets basically that have
like almost in all of the biggest like
you know cartridge companies and stuff
in California and they're you know they
just all on the spreadsheet and have
like what pesticides they all failed for
and so so you know you basically people
are like just reposting it reposting
reposting on Instagram when they have
thousands or hundreds of thousands of
followers and uh and you know just
creating these huge kind of Wars where
these trolls are basically then going
and do doing like these Mass attacks on
these different brand Pages you know of
all these people saying you're poisoning
patients you're poisoning patients and
then you know in return you know all
these different companies are you know
posting all these these clean lab
results trying to be like we test clean
we test clean you know and so and it's
funny because you know most people that
you know cast clean you know probably
have more failing tests and they have
clean tests you know but there's um
there's not this uh you know that's one
of the the holes in uh the the way
testing currently exists you know
because whenever and when that's
listening isn't 100 being done by like a
State Certified sampling agent or you
know somebody of non kind of biased
potential you know then you know you
could test anything and then anything
can be posted and you know there's no
kind of necessarily Integrity I guess
based in you know the full testing you
know uh scheme you know but but that's
what it's going to be you know kind of
uh you know definitely you know believe
is going to be fixed with kind of the
regulation of California coming up
because that similar way oriented is
they you know they require you know the
lab or a State Certified sampling lab
um that just does that on its own to
kind of then you know basically do the
statistically valid sampling of the
batches and then you know tamper-proof
ceiling of the packaging and then you
know lab results are then or a lot you
know send samples are going to the lab
you know through the chain of custody
process blah blah results ultimately go
through the quality system to be
ultimately released and then on the
release you know the with the clean like
bill of health or whatever I guess uh
the certificate of analysis of clean
herb then it can go into the regulated
market to be sold yeah and that's you
know that's one thing that California's
done really well Canada has kind of
tried to do this and you have to record
batch numbers and you have to Archive
batch samples even
um so that if there is a future issue
that the the regulator can come in and
access your your archive essentially and
pull it the corresponding sample
um the Canadian failure though is that
they've allowed companies to do first
party lab testing as opposed to
third-party labs for huge problems and
that's a mistake so there are some
companies like Aurora for example that
still choose to do third-party lab
testing
um you know they have an in-house
research lab but the information that
ends up on their package is done by a
third party test of lab and I invest and
I I advise all my clients to always do
third party for your test book about
because it takes that impression out
that you could be manipulating results
right
when we do Educational Services through
the graduates Network it's one of the
first things we teach families is if
there's a company that won't provide
third-party testing or won't share their
test results then you just don't use
them bingo bingo
because clean testing is something to be
proud of so yeah they're either doing it
or they have some value yeah so if you
have clean yes you're showing them
because it's great you know well listen
there's a little bit of a financial
thing at play too I mean in California
there's so many testing Labs that the
prices come down and it's quite
competitive
um in Canada there's not that level of
access and uh there's actually extra
tests that are required like heavy
metals
um that are actually much more expensive
to perform than just but not a thousand
[ __ ] dollars dude there's like
poaching happening up there dude no well
for a full battery of tests like a full
full battery of tests including
aflatoxins and
um you know cannabinoids terpenes
alphotoxins microbial
um heavy metals yeah it cost a thousand
bucks it's still tax though that's
almost like yeah that's that's really I
mean you know that that full thing
our thousand bucks is like 700 of yours
ah oh yeah no that that helps because I
was gonna say like four to five hundred
you know I think is kind of around where
that would be that's where it's kind of
evening out in Oregon like 50 more
expensive up here but we know everything
is 30 more expensive because of the
exchange
and alcohol is like doubly expensive
yeah even more than doubly
no I'm with John Mayer alcohol is a con
yeah he's gone that's awesome use for it
in my life
awesome that's a great answer
there's no spiritual significance though
yeah well that's also why it's twice the
price it's all tax right it's just it's
the government trying to like convince
you not to do it and if you are going to
do it they're going to tax you on it now
so that when you end up in the Health
Care System later on you've already paid
into it oh that's hilarious
it's true it's the reality though I mean
that's the way it works we want those
people drinking booze to pay for our
health care well they pay for their
health care is what they do right well
but they pay for ours too
anyway I think that was a solid four
hours and seven minutes
um great conversation guys wonderful
past church today it was we're too away
from three year anniversary so hopefully
in the next week or so I'll have a plan
set up hopefully with Natasha because
she's much better at plans than I am
plus she's like really good at that sort
of uh don't make the tattoo your
secretary she's a doctor oh gosh no
she's not my secretary but she is a
amazing facilitator of hash church I
think of her more as
um like a producer
she's really helpful she gets great new
people on there she's actually today she
was gonna get the guy who had his bong
taken away in Ontario and then was like
he was standing out in front of the
police station in his underwear puff and
Bong rips and I was kind of like maybe
you should interview him before we just
let him come on
what you know I I listened to a couple
of interviews with him and the guy knows
the rules to the AC MPR and he's he's
well spoken and we'll probably end up
having him on next week at least for a
little while to tell us his insane it's
such a Canadian story like he's
literally yeah bizarre but that's
awesome yes thanks everyone Alex from SC
Labs Forrest from the caladrius network
uh Wade from the house of laughter the
house of harlequin sorry
um Chimera uh and Skunk Man Sam and Dr
Sheldon we have d420k we had Dr Natasha
uh we had we had Peter from the
um soil soil balance and anyone that I
forgot apologies but we've got next
Sunday to make it up we got uh at least
460 people still watching in the show so
I will end it as I do my wake and bakes
with full melt bless all your bowls soon
peace out everybody yeah Big Ups it's an
amazing event thank you so much for
holding the space Marcus
hell yeah dude hell yeah thank you guys
funeral space with me
this was actually one five four not one
five three correct I make mistakes
constantly I'll go back and fix it thank
you Sam