hey what's going on everybody welcome on
this Sunday morning at 9:00 a.m. to
hashed rich 2.0 episode 13 just kind of
tossed one together last night really
quickly sent out an email sort of
last-minute so it'll be a bit of a
hodgepodge of people in conversation
today main inspiration was to get dr.
mark scale down and Chris Baroni in here
have a little chemistry talk so that's
gonna be part of what's going on and let
me just get the links sent out here
there we go
do the email link do the Facebook link
and we should be good to go
there we go make sure that I'm getting
the right email sent out so people
actually receive it and it doesn't go
into their junk mail Wow 268 people in
the first one minute of hashed Church
today that is cool
can you hear me they're doing well oh
hey how are you doing that yeah you can
hear me I can hear you oh good just
making sure I haven't plugged everything
in a while so I Sam don't do that last
oh oh oh I know you are stamp your the
master I've seen your closet I've seen
the closet with broken rulers yes I have
it's always nice when you show Sam like
a really expensive pipe and the first
thing out of his mouth is I'm really
good at breaking glass but no glass
owner wants to hear welcome at yeah I've
missed you brother tell people you hope
you have you have said that as well I
will I will admit that as well so
that's uh that's funny yeah damn it
seems like it's been forever
Etienne you've been you've been busy
sort of sort of yet no I see you see
things going on with you well we had our
we definitely celebrated our 19th
anniversary so thanks everybody to who
made that possible and yeah it was a lot
of fun we had the mayor Berkeley show up
and you can see my pictures I was
dressed up in my scooby-doo outfit and
right I saw that cause if you're gonna
meet the mayor being a scooby-doo outfit
yeah no I agree I think Chris would also
agree if you're gonna meet the mayor you
should be in a scooby-doo outfit don't
you think Chris yeah way to meet your
constituency you know my protege is
gonna be that Rob Ford guy from [ __ ]
Toronto because nothing more honest than
Rob Ford I'll tell you that's that is
the truth I'm just trying to think now
if that's the original one or if that's
the brother I always keep I always mix
them up Rob Rob passed away right yeah
yeah yeah yes so now his brother is like
in politics and got chosen as a position
and he's he's also a ridiculous version
of his brother of just not your average
politician that's for sure
oh well yeah he did pass away Stephen
Simon's has confirmed can't keep up with
this stuff how's everyone doing this
morning we got skunk man Sam we got
Chris brownie we got a tampon tag in the
room and me bubble man as well as 452
viewers wow that's a good amount of
paper for 904 before we start with
everybody I have a question for Chris
what do you like better pure THC
distillate or dirty c or knock your
teeth dry sip that strychnine rich
laughter if you'd only be what 80 85
percent THC but
pretty damn good oh yeah I would say
like right now my go-to are the like THC
products with like basically like as
little Terps as possible if not if like
any Terps I like pretty much just I
don't go lately I've been on kind of
like a hotter hotter dad more THC trip
but you know my friends keep me turfed
up but I say like that's sort of my
go-to keeps me like more stimulated and
less stony it's kind of my experience
with it interesting as times gone by my
I look it's really appreciate the herbs
I feel like physiologically they're a
little bit more harsher than just the
THC products for the higher THC products
because I know when I smoke dry sip
which are still extremely high
intervenes but also I mean last time I
measured it was 83 percent THC a so
respectable teens rest I guess is
probably planted cells if you wax
yeah we've had a kind of a change as
well here in California because
everybody knew market again as its
reemerged
in the legal world and everything that's
coming out right now is all sauces we
can't define shatter or anything else is
near next to impossible and kind of
frustrating and I feel you exactly there
Chris I feel the I feel the harshness of
the Terps so much because my makes I'm
used to a little more waxy or mix and
for me it seems to be more THC I don't
seem to get as high with my mix with as
much with all these you know these
terpene sauces and I know that'll change
in time it's just as the market is
getting up and getting itself
established still it's just the reality
that we face yeah I have honestly I
forget to actually yet to be you go into
a store in California yet to buy
anything I can't I can't tell you
personally about the the atmosphere but
from what I hear that's pretty much
consistent
yeah the reality interesting though that
you'd you know it's true that the Terps
definitely create sort of a more stony
version so if you're if you're kind of
like sitting around and watching movies
or you don't have to do too much you can
really enjoy those turps but if you
might you know potentially be doing some
chemistry or maybe need a little bit
more focus maybe less turps is going to
I agree Marcus I find that third piece
the right one sirs-e one that can
potentiate ghz makes it stronger and it
definitely is like a steering wheel
where it modulates mm-hmm absolutely
welcome chimera in the room I see that
big large bud I think that's chimera
behind that bud temperature yeah he
sounds like he's in a tube like a mile
away
Waldo you all we got 537 people I have
invited a few others I think we're gonna
see Wade laughter in here I'm not sure a
forest is gonna make it dr. mark said he
was gonna make it I did invite Indra he
said he was probably gonna hang out just
in chat but if he feels the conversation
is on point he might come in had a
really good conversation with with
injury yesterday especially hadn't
hadn't spoken with him for a long time I
have to find say I really do quite enjoy
one-on-one conversations with Indra he's
just I that's my favorite Indra the the
one-on-one conversations I get with him
he's just we went pretty deep yesterday
and had some good good retrospective let
me see what mark saying here looking
forward to seeing him I come are you
coming down for the Emerald cup nice
yeah I'm a judge this year so I thought
I was gonna have to actually leave this
morning to go get my judges get but
apparently they're not finished yet so I
they'll go deliver them to us so I don't
have to drive
we up to Layton Vil yeah can barely hear
you chimera you're literally so far back
in the mix it's not even funny yeah it's
like a 1 out of 10 what's your cat's
name Chris so this cat is schmidtty
schmidtty
too but I can ever the appropriate oh my
god I joined it just the exact time to
hear that coughing dabs mark you gotta
hit that mute button oh my god that was
so funny yesterday I had a quick little
google chat with Chris and Mark and
Chris and I are trying to have a
conversation Mark's just like just
ripping hard dabs maybe he was ripping
hot dabs actually who prefers a hot dab
over a cool dab I heard Chris say it
earlier today there's no doubt about
that hot dab rocks you in a way that
that low temp dab just pant punchy but
it definitely doesn't have taste you do
but I'm telling you like that overly hot
damn I took one not too long ago I can't
remember where I was but it ended up
being hot and I was just coughing for
about five plus minutes and afterwards
there was legitimately I was completely
destroyed for like the next 15-20
minutes what I thought yeah exactly what
temperature
Wow hot is hot this was all this you
know where it was it was out of glass
the glass blowing
it wasn't stratospheric glasses I don't
know if you guys know stratosphere he's
doing
it was real nice now Sam's doing it
that's awesome
yeah the spinning stuff right so I was
doing sorry now your mic is as on as on
gets my brother anyway these guys were
heating the [ __ ] up with like an
acetylene torch or whatever you know
like a welding torch not like or or
maybe it was even their their
glassblowing torch I can't remember but
I remember taking the dab and it being
so hot also coil coil condenser was
there as well and I can't remember who
else was there but man I was like for
about 15 20 minutes I went sat out in
the garden and just was like holy smokes
like I am absolutely flying right now
it's straight to the forehead when you
take a hottie
I mean you've toss up between the oxygen
deprivation from coughing so much and
then the addition of an exertion of hard
THC into the bloodstream your brain
categorize don't stand up real fast yeah
it's completely insane it was I think
that bad that the oxygen thing has a lot
to do with it cuz I find every time I
cough after about a five minute mark
every single cough I get like a hundred
feet higher every cough it's just like
this exponential experience of effect
yeah where we see it a lot was imagine
that we used to have wow I saw that the
cannabis cup is happening in Amsterdam
well they had one last year too
sometimes I start again gen dope it put
a picture up that she was there and I
was like wow I got married there back in
what and yeah 20-some odd years ago 98
wasn't it uh 99 no no no 90 90 95 95 I
was definitely
there whatever year was I was definitely
Gaskin did the ceremony and the glass
might was the on stage and the wedding
cake like I said a pound and a half of
trichomes that what he call its mom made
the cake and it was oh my god
destroyed everybody Jack Herer everybody
were all just wasted by this cake it was
amazing yes the infamous wedding cake I
had a memory from about four or five or
six years ago come up today and it's too
bad that I can't find it now because it
was it was me and Rob Clark and we were
walking to the back apartments of the
krasnopolskiy hotel where I always
stayed I never stayed at the front I
walked through the back it looks
beautiful Chris and Rob and I came
across a giant mountain of ice that the
hotel had dumped out so there it's a
funny picture of Rob and I I don't know
who took it there must have been someone
else with us but we're basically holding
up the ice and making this crazy sort of
crazy sort of look but it was good
what's wrong with my mic you want me to
turn it down a bit I can do that
I can turn my mic down a bit if that
works where would you be without ice how
do I see the group comments like a group
chat with the members of the group is
there a way to see the what anyone else
if anyone else is saying anything you
need to open up the YouTube separate
window and then go to this exact channel
to this exact post and on the right
you'll have the chat and make sure it's
muted oh yeah I mean that that goes
wicked can you hear me now a little
better oh that much better oh my god
dude that's like perfect what was going
on you got it he's still got a pooch
Mike I'm glad you did we made it I was
just saying there's some absolute fire
that's been added this year I saw some
of the molecular farm sentries at man
where they
ever beautiful I'm looking forward to it
I'm not I think I'm dead back to doing a
pen I'm not sure exactly what I'm
judging at the moment but I'll find out
when I get it looking forward to it and
seeing you as well sir yeah it'll be
great to see you dude I want to go to
the Emerald cop you do I do
see you there you know what maybe I
don't know I think my worry is that they
won't let me out of America I'm less
worried about don't get me wrong but
some listen American folks are some of
my best friends they're much more acres
in there you go that's actually a good
point I'll have my lawyer bring that up
if I ever get detained at the border and
and kept kept in the country yeah the
big thing is we get rid of you as fast
as ready the big thing is social meeting
here right I mean you don't want to be
saying that you're going down for an
event that involves cannabis they just
banned a couple of people gave them a
lifetime bans for trying to go down to
the to the the mg best card in Las Vegas
yeah that guy was just an investor yeah
well they were invested in a facility in
Nevada they really don't like it when
foreigners are putting money into a
federally illegal space right it's one
thing for Americans to be investing in
their own space but you know it kind of
gives us flavor of cartels would you're
taking foreign money sorry about that I
had to mute you Indra came in pretty
loud with the background noise there
yeah so what anyway what they're saying
for people to do now I know as Terry
booth was speaking of the CEO of Aurora
was speaking at this event if I guess
stay and some of these other folks they
told them just go to LA and tell him
you're going to LA for something
unrelated on business then drive over
you don't want to show at the border and
say we go to this cannabis
my problem is if you punch my name in
for sure for sure for sure bubbleman
[ __ ] comes up like intertwine this
hashed churches and instagrams and all
this
I guess not really easy to get over the
border sort of stuff yeah but if you if
you again if you have one of those
waivers and then you have a purpose that
you're going down for this sure sure of
course I don't I do not have a waiver
the part that I don't like about the
waiver is the part where you have to go
to the US border to get it signed so you
have to go to the US border before you
get your waiver it's the only way to get
the waiver still you're still there like
for me it's always felt like I'm
entering a federal penitentiary that's
what going across the border into the US
and for that matter for that matter it's
the same as coming up into Canada
actually just had 290 in my own country
and hey here's a picture I found from
back then there's me there is old Edie
and there's Hillary and there is Andrew
D'Angelo from Harborside Todd this is
back in Amsterdam we went and saw some
show during the while we were there but
yeah that's from back in 95 you know I
was there for sure it was Hillary
working at the posi tronics of course
right so yes she only worked there that
one year so interesting that was 95 not
yeah that was 95 for sure yeah yeah cuz
she started the club I moved to BC the
next year crazy yeah I stayed with her
at her place it was really cool a lot of
fun I had a booth that year on the top
floor of the PAC's party house smack dab
between Jack Herer and his daughter and
Eagle Bill that's how I got introduced
in the cannabis cup bro Jesus Christ to
ego
oh wow and you're just smacked in
between jeepers dude but it was it was
hilarious I mean you know Jack we didn't
know who eagle was but we had studied
the book of Jack let me tell you I mean
I knew that book like the back of my
hand we were gonna use it in the next
year to get actually we had used it that
year the year private previously 94 we
used it to convince our ministers to let
us grow hemp in the province and nine
months later in 95 we grew our our first
hemp field so that's pretty that's
pretty [ __ ] crazy smack dab to be
able to be beside the guy who literally
turned you on to being able to
acknowledge all of the information and
articulate it back to a Minister of
Finance and a Minister of Agriculture to
be able to convince them to grow
something that had not been grown in
over 73 years the more I look back at
that the more I think that was that was
some incredible [ __ ] I I don't know
would have happened if Jack hadn't have
come to my to West Virginia University
in 1989 if I hadn't gotten a copy if
they're aware is no close I have no idea
what would have happened to my life but
I'm beyond thankful it has and I did
because it changed my entire reality
well you got yours before me we got our
first one in either 90 or 91 is when I
got turned onto that book and just like
annihilated it oh I had a girlfriend
break up with me because I would go to a
party and all I would talk about was the
Emperor's and all these pastas well you
should know about all this pot and hemp
stuff and you take this book with you to
parties and your show people I'm like
that she didn't get it just annoyed this
charity so I was like okay look we're
it's just not getting getting getting
along here so okay I guess I chose the
Emperor wears no clothes over you know
my girlfriend at the time but dude I'm
telling me it changed my life and that
was the first of a long list of women
that went by the way
[Laughter]
well we didn't even go to parties we
literally just straight hung out at our
little hemp exchange hemp store and
people came to us and we puffed and
chuffed and just talked non-stop about
this book I bought one of the hundred
percent pure hemp ones the year that he
did them at the cup there for a hundred
us that was probably 96 or 97 I have one
of those it's funny you know how much
stuff has changed I had an ex girlfriend
that I ran into on social media over the
past couple of weeks and this chick
would we broke up she she threatened to
call the RCMP on me anyway this week she
was throwing up the cannabis community
hashtag so what what's your trip on it
Ryan cuz I know a lot of people and I
sort of see the point
I get it I see the hypocrisy on seeing
you know people from law enforcement and
people in positions of power that fought
this plant for so long and I kinda I can
see that one side of the fence where I'm
like well [ __ ] those guys they shouldn't
be allowed to play they shouldn't be
allowed to be involved and they
certainly shouldn't be allowed to
[ __ ] hold some monopoly over the
people that fought for it for all these
years but then another part of me is
kind of like we got them like they're in
like the the very people that were the
Destroyers for so long now like I mean
really when I think about who I was
preaching to the most over all these
years it was them it was like stop doing
this like just change the laws like
don't keep doing this and now now
they're doing it and even more so doing
it like jumping both feet in like I want
to be involved in this part of me is
like huh we're we flip the script
people aren't like you know if the cops
don't make the laws right the Catholics
by and large I mean like you know the
nature of a police people in a power you
know they're to like do what they think
is right and they're following like
their cue you know obviously there's
cops on the beat that have to make like
the discretionary call but
I think it's kind of unfair I'm like at
the same time it's kind of like [ __ ]
those cops that were the [ __ ] at
the time because now what's to say that
there's not like reasonable police and
folks that are like you bother me how
many of us I'm just as panel own have
dealt with the tops at the at your
inspection and they got the gun and it's
the same cop that would've thrown you
but that's the same power this just
following a different rule book it's
like you kind of got to give them the
benefit of the doubt you know cuz now
there's just that much less [ __ ] for
cops the hassle a spell right every cop
becoming a marijuana grower marijuana
will say look marijuana marijuana
whatever yeah Sam with the harsh
realities you know have the right to be
involved and it's certainly distasteful
that some of these people like you know
Julian Fantino for example or you know
Brian Mulrooney former prime minister
Karen is involved with acreage holdings
in the states that which is going to be
a big play coming out of the East Coast
yeah the house is is in that shenanigan
stew and it sucks to see but at the same
time I feel the same way as Sam all
these prohibitionists deserve to you
know they've changed their realities and
they're gonna change the reality further
for everybody else so you know as stated
before we didn't leave with everything
at once when I can get it back all at
once it takes time well it's not all I
mean when it's an open market it's an
open market and you know a lot of these
people have long term established lives
and connections and money and that's
what helps you get business done in the
real world I think that you know as a
community we definitely point these
people out um you know hopefully people
with ethics will vote with their dollars
and vote support the people that are oh
jeez and I've been doing it for thirty
forty years but you know what our what
are you gonna really gonna do right like
everyone it's legal everybody has a
right to be involved and then you just
have course
and in the end what's going to happen is
you can produces better cheaper
higher-quality more organic more
whatever the customer wants you're going
to sell it yeah and that's what we're
seeing you know in the Canadian
marketplace at least it's true we got
all these corporate guys are producing
you know hundred millions of square feet
of acres of absolute bunk like the
flowers are [ __ ] garbage right so now
they're starting to letting these micro
cultivators in people get in they'll
start small and you know they'll work
there were using the chain the truth of
the matter is you know the the person
with the the best flowers has always won
the market and that's just not gonna
change right correctly that's what the
consumer wants I would add one more
thing to that that the ratio that once
was say in the 90s when I would see an
enormous amount of cannabis every week
and there was only a very small
percentage of it that was exceptional
always it's still to this day it's the
same thing I think it's just gonna line
up in the sense that you said there's
gonna be all these guys growing bunk and
don't get me wrong the world loves bunk
most of the world is just super happy
with bunk food and bunk beer and bunk
everything in their life and of course
they're gonna smoke bunker belong with
their bunk cigarettes and drink their
bunk booze but then there's another
percentage of people that little niche
that you know the IPA breweries sort of
came into existence for and cannabis
craft growing whether it's an LP or
whether it's a small-time grower in my
opinion it's the quality that matters I
don't care the conditions that comes out
of it that it comes from just as long as
the quality is super OnPoint as long as
it was grown properly genetics that were
that were properly bred were used so
that you know the plants gonna be
something special and not just the same
old same old I mean four years in BC it
was curse curse curse curse
it was great if you were you know Johnny
B and loved cush and don't get me wrong
I don't mind cush there's some right
over my shoulder but I like other
cultivars person for what long time BC
was hurting just pumping out the Kush
well right now
we're seeing at you know craft market
has not gone away in California we still
see small craft product and it still
commands its price the market of course
is not to the standards that we set at
BPG because for 18 plus years we bought
at certain ratios and priced at ratios
that we thought were fair and it was
responded by everybody in the market
that's why people continue to come back
if you don't have good pot for good
price and a story they're going
somewhere else and they can go somewhere
else so unfortunately through the
distributor reality that we see in
California it's not to the standards
that we set whereas in Nevada when I
recently visited there it has and was so
in time it will get better but at the
same time the craft market is still here
it's just had to professionalize itself
and not everybody could make the leap or
could afford to make the leaf or
wellington red complete you know yeah I
was just down there and I was actually
quite surprised you know the Cali rags
you know there's all these contamination
issues that have always been in the
market and now they have this regulated
system they've actually really honed
down the amount of weeds that is
available in the market like one of the
suppliers was telling me you know they
wouldn't have a pen company and they
were saying try by a hundred liters of
clean distillate that actually makes the
grade right that actually will pass the
regulations and it's just not available
in the marketplace to the point the
growers are getting three thousand plus
bucks a pound again right for right for
the for the stuff that truly is fire and
and and meets the grade right it makes
it passes the regulation which is well
that's that we're only up to series to
we're getting ready to for phase three
which is happening January 1st which is
adds more microbial testing and more
pesticide testing which I'm afraid we're
gonna see bubble hash go the way for a
while because it fails the microbial
tests just off of Berkeley
municipalities water which is you know
all of these waste water so it shows
also we need different standards for
different products we don't have it
finally refined at the science level
just for something like you know water
hash why don't they just filter that one
i money cause buying coke be lazy they
should also be using like a stainless
steel sort of GMP compliant unit as well
I only have two people currently what's
that Chris I said people out here
wouldn't even be able to spell GM the
city of Flint Michigan right you drink
water in Flint Michigan and you die so
there's bigger infrastructure issues
about water in this country other than
making water house holy [ __ ] of course
but we're in hash Church dude don't get
me wrong if you want to start the water
processing cleanliness chat room on your
channel by all means dude I'll come in
and talk about that but yeah of course
and forget about Flint Michigan that's
just being American there's been
countries in the world that have haven't
had clean water for a very long time
well nobody remembers that hamper
mediates you know have like if you grow
have next to a heavy metals
you know processing plant you're
probably gonna have heavy metals in your
hand oh yeah it definitely does with
radioactive nucleotides there's certain
plants that are fight or remediate of
that pull up heavy metals and stuff I'm
sure cannabis would pull up the majority
of them my other cold
they're called bio accumulators huh what
was that ryan like certain ions will be
pulled up into the bruised but not into
the plant so i think that there's a
whole bunch of that we still have yet to
learn about that whole process of the
bio accumulation of out of the soil and
then it gets stuck in the plant whether
it's on the roots of the fibers or you
know does it go up into the england
flowers we don't really know that yet it
was that was discovered by joe Strobel
and jeff
in Ontario in 19 well maybe 1995 they
they grew their first field in 94 and
Joe was a tobacco farmer and they
sprayed radium-226
on the field which is a radioactive
nucleotide and so I guess they have to
measure the field if you know before
during and after all these different
sort of times they have to measure the
field and they found the numbers to be
like too low after the hemp was cut down
and they they they tested the hemp and
found out that it had pulled a bunch of
this radium-226 out of the soil and had
stored it and I guess in the cellulose
and fibers of the of the stock the oh
[ __ ] I had an actual study that broke it
down they actually grew hemp on a Polish
having metals factory and it just was
yeah my gosh I look back on it now and
see if it was in the roots or in the
stalk or in the flower because that's a
good point chimera yeah well there's
just a man like there's probably a whole
bunch of lessons that we still have to
learn about that I bet there's you know
cannabis is remarkable well did we lose
him okay my poster keeps doing this it's
OCD I should just get a new piece of
tape I actually work what's that mark
right at cannabis was remarkable for
doing right yeah I'm sure he'll be back
in to talk here in a second I I just got
back from Manitoba I was there at a at
the Canadian hemp Alliance hemp trade
Alliance conference welcome back Ryan
yes sorry remarkable remarkable you know
plasticity and traits right on every
single character that you look at the
plant leaf shaped stem width height
yield seed yield seed size whatever
there's a variation right so I bet that
will probably end up seeing that some
varieties are able to bioaccumulate
faster and are more tolerant than other
varieties we just don't know any of that
information yet mm-hmm
yeah you know what this is this is good
stuff I wished I saw more stuff like
this at the hip
since in Manitoba it was there was a lot
of sort of talking but it was all this
sort of delusional CBD talk where they
thought they were gonna you know set up
an entire industry extracting the 1% of
CBD that's in the plant I'm also hearing
with problems in states where it's legal
slash medical and hemp is growing as
cross pollination is happening and
people's crops are getting seated and
people are getting angry and when you're
financially ruined by something is like
that it's gonna bring out a whole bunch
of ethic issues regarding the reality of
what they're doing it in the reality of
what its gonna take to actually be you
know a high grade cannabis farmer you
know it's kind of no different than
having an avocado farmer as a neighbor
in California that's doing the plane or
the helicopter
Ava drop every two weeks and you're like
right next door to them and it's like
what are you gonna do you can't control
that [ __ ] it's going all the way over to
your crop and your crops just absorbing
it yeah well there's nothing yet again
it's the evolution of an industry right
I mean when you start when you turn the
switch on an industry everything doesn't
run right off the bat there's all these
portions of the value chain like seeds
like high CBD seeds with that are less
than 0.3 percent THC yeah there are
actually registered varieties right look
you can't in Canada you can't just if
you begin a clone that's licked you know
say you have a magical clone that's 28%
CBD acid and it produces less than 0.3
percent THC so it's considered hemp you
can't plant that variety underneath it's
got to be in the registry I met the guy
who runs that the seed registry once a
year and do you know what the
regulations are for that they want you
to R&amp;D the strip the cultivar for three
seasons three three years and and bring
them the data that shows the THC and you
know all the sort of things that they
want and basically it's it takes three
years to get a cultivar registered into
the seed registry you could use data
from other countries like they want
three years or the data for sure but
anyway you have years of trials for
example with varieties in the States
which is you might be able to shave a
year off but I'd be surprised if you got
it in in under a year I was talking to
the guy I wish it was something
different that's crazy because I've got
this variety that's you know it's it's
again it's a low cannabinoid producing
plant but it produces like two to three
CBD acid by weight let's get it in the
point but in order to plant it you need
to do it under a research license which
is you know a pain in the ass because
you need special exemptions to be able
to harvest and use the molecules
mm-hmm and it's just pretty sure pretty
sure that if you have a variety register
like a variety or any other yeah they
want trials in Canada always though just
to show that so they're definitely
scared of these plants somehow magically
producing 800 percent THC and staining
an environment right so if they always
want some data it's it's a bit
ridiculous but yeah you're right I think
it does you know like the ones that
we're talking about Sam or you know
related to registered varieties in Kent
in in Europe but man is never a pain in
the ass yeah it sure is you know in the
me in the meantime there's no CVG I said
there's no CVG cannabis Jarrell in the
marketplace right he really could be
using this stuff we've got the varieties
that can grow it with paperwork's
keeping it down it's nice and soon he'll
my state can't tell the difference
between you know hemp th I mean CBD and
you know indica CBD indica pardon me
that's because there is no different CBD
CBD tell that chemically dr. but the
state of California says no and there is
one big difference that mean difference
of course is that
from an indica variety you'll get a lot
of [ __ ] heat and put my hips right
into a little bit well I have a bottle
of Stevie G right here and a number of
them and they're not that hard to come
by so I would submit that you're that's
an erroneous oh not for Canada it isn't
already can't well we're limited there
John yeah there's like there's federal
regulations that are dictating all these
problems it's about the availability of
the of the molecule what's it good for
cannabis Jarrell has a whole bunch of
uses they're finding if they've just
showed that it's a cb1 receptor agonist
it's they've found that it has activity
against like the superbugs like a bar
does not get you high just for you know
rounding purposes right not an argument
you know what I would I would say what's
it good for I would say for producing
the entire cannabinoid and terpene
profile makes a pretty good building
block we're not weak in skin lesions
I've been tearing it with somebody who
had suspicious about and she started
applying this and a week later they
dried up and disappeared
yeah that's not I mean that's cool it's
not really a trial but what they've done
it you know they definitely have it's it
helps suppress things like medicine
resistance triple streptococcus straight
which is mrs a which is one of the
superbugs but they have a hard time
treating with antibiotics and it's able
to suppress that then it's got these
anti-inflammatory properties and you
know I think we're gonna find that it's
like CBD you know like we will find for
all these cannabinoids I'm like we did
for CBD there's not just one thing it's
good for it helps a whole bunch of stuff
but really you can
test that or you can't put that into the
market to start having people do these
you know what it's not really a clinical
trial but it's like collecting community
data until the molecule is out in the
marketplace it's like the issue that
Mark and I run into it the hydrogenated
can have an ID so you can make them but
like who the hell can you really make
them can you really make them somewhere
like we're sort of interesting thing
we're like science and people's interest
is far quicker and far more advanced and
like working handle it's like how do you
I mean you make these products and how
do you even like test for cannabinoids
like will you have to like CBG in
California I remember on the roads but
you know you can 0% active cannabinoids
products and now someone has to know
about it to like oh and especially with
all the available connect actually
pumped out here in quantity over what's
going on with yourself when your your
petri dish studies on all that kind of
stuff
I know you had some of that being sent
over to Aberdeen what's his name dr.
Pertwee did you ever get that study
those studies going to get your receptor
binding studies everything done no not
yet I don't know what I don't know what
mark status is mark Scott's relationship
I'm just making the hexahydrate
you're muted big boy it's still muted
that's weird
here let me go look in the am i unmuted
down oh yeah you are
okay alright yeah we're not working with
Pertwee anymore he wasn't interested
after all and looking at these for some
reasons so we have
enlisted the services of mo says Moreno
who's over in Spain to do those studies
for us and we're working with a couple
other groups I don't know how much I can
talk about cuz I'm under NDA so yeah
we're gonna try to figure out as much as
we possibly can on the safety and
efficacy of these things and understand
what the hydrogenation does to attenuate
the activity of the tetrahydrocannabinol
you know so the plan makes
tetrahydrocannabinol there's another
chemical step to convert them in the
hexahydrate cannabinoids and that's just
in the series of tetrahydrocannabinol
being able to undergo dehydrogenation up
to cannabinol which is just the aromatic
airman cessation of the methyl
cyclohexane ring we've just reduced it
taking it down all the way you know and
and a THC is something that you know has
been previously described and was
previously looked at it's it's known
that it does undergo metabolic oxidation
similar to the THC derivatives but you
know you know generate eleven hydroxy
THC because the the double bonds been
reduced but there's a whole bunch of
other things that we can do you know
hydrogenated some of these minor
cannabinoids as well but just try to
assess you know what is the impact that
hydrogenation extra chemical step has on
the chemical modification of these
already biologically active compounds so
that's really interesting you say that
it won't make eleven hydroxy upon
metabolization on the liver that could
actually be a hugely valuable
pharmacists kinetic property I mean
that's really interesting that's huge
that's the biggest problem I have with
edibles and other people I that I know
that are said to be more sensitive to
edibles is that it turns to the Alexa
hydroxy metabolite in the liver and I
mean
the old hydroxy metalitz unpredictable
you're not used to it you you go from
his master - yeah very uncomfortable if
you can get to knocked out yeah I think
it's completely different for a cannabis
user someone who regularly uses cannabis
and whose body is already sensitized to
that metabolite it's just more
attenuated I guess when it comes through
the digestive tract you know and all in
one burst you know and gets into your
blood it doesn't have the you know does
have the cb1 activity but it's generally
thought of that it's too polar and
doesn't cross the blood-brain barrier
which is why you get that incredible
body hi you know you oversaturate all
the other cannabinoid receptors in your
body not your brain in your body so
that's why I always tell people to keep
edibles in their mouth and suck on it
like a like a cough drop
you know don't ya let it go in your
stomach throw in a little dehydration
and some jet lag from traveling to
Amsterdam and I've seen some people do
some face wallops right on the
cobblestone you know we a lot more
people tried the h8c a you know we're at
the bisque on and so we got a lot more
input on you know how it makes people
feel definitely there's a heaviness and
a high to it I think it's less intense
than THC but definitely something that
is definitely modulated by terpenes just
like you would expect a cannabinoid yeah
the one thing if I draw a little
terpenes as well right well the stuff
that we made a bid on stuff that I made
for biscone was just a from from a
starting material was a THC a crystal
but there was there was you guys gave me
two pens I think the one the first night
that was a year ago man that yeah a year
ago we made pens and those were flavored
with her profiles well we brought that
this year resist stuff which is just you
know this
in addition platinum cookies we made I
took some platinum cookie sauce and and
hydrogenated it and we call the
palladium cookies because it's [ __ ]
genius but the stuff was [ __ ] tasty
and interesting do you shoulda hit me up
I was in the same room I think in the
wind it's gonna be a full week next year
three-day trip I agree but they're
making it a whole week now for the first
time which I've never been down there
and someone from California had given me
a little bit of some psychedelics and
man those the way those analog lights
move at all yeah I actually really liked
old town it was pretty cool there's
these you know these really young card
kids african-american kid that was doing
card tricks it was really actually quite
impressed with such a young kid he
walked away with a bunch of our money
card tricks are you getting caught on
like three-card Monte or whatever like
no no like tricks like we were giving it
to him really he was he was doing some
pretty impressive stuff you know he'd
come up and he'd try to push you the
card and I'd be you know you'd you'd
have her down I'm saying no no no man I
want to hold the card deck I want to do
all this stuff and he was actually
really really talented I was actually
quite impressed with the kid so we gave
him a bunch of money and he walked away
and it was like no I turn around and I
was like man this kid was there with us
for like ten minutes and he walked away
with forty bucks at like 13 you know
pretty impressive got that Vegas hustle
on man it looks like a pretty beautiful
day where you're sitting wait that's
funny and puppy now yes it did the
bright sunlight I had some technical
difficulties getting on and they're
continuing here right yeah just sitting
on the patio man next to a couple of the
trees and enjoying the sunlight
reflecting off the pond and listening to
some beautiful chat here all the farmers
done their weight yeah yeah pretty much
I didn't I did not have many plants this
year I had one I hurt my back this
spring and had to learn how to be
something other than a farmer so but
yeah it's been a beautiful year we
finally got some rain and we'll get in
the donations after the kids in the
khalad Reyes Network we might actually
achieve our goal of being able to
provide for those families by the end of
the year yeah yeah no it's a whole bunch
of people are stepping up and we're not
there yet but yeah it feels like we'll
make it and Wow there was a couple of
things I wanted to talk about you guys
were talking about earlier since we're
talking hash Church one of the things
water process and microbiology that
shows up in trichomes I have a question
for people who know a lot more about
these things than me
if you're trichomes are clean of plant
material if you do some want some sort
of extraction to pull off any plant
material and just have trichomes
are things like fungus or bacterial
growth gonna be a problem because i know
plant material in trichomes if you try
press it up you end up with a bunch of
little pockets of plant material where
moisture can accumulate and fungus can
grow but if it's clean of trichomes
what's what's your story on that Sam
plants are growing super clean and
there's not contamination from other
sources it's fine but very selling well
I've been playing I've been playing with
adding a step to the extraction process
still using water bags where I put an
air stone into the water that's rich in
trichomes but no longer has ice or the
bulk of the plant material in it and by
putting an air stone in it and a little
air you get this wild foaming action
that I've run through the bags and
whatnot there doesn't seem to be much in
the way of trichomes at all but there's
color plant material seems to come off
of it and it and yeah I like the results
I just wanted to throw that out there
because I like water process hash for my
own personal use and it seems really
important that it's just trichomes
nothing else in there so the the plant
material being clean is important and
then meantime yeah water I think is a
huge issue most most municipal most
urban environments I'll say like that if
you've got treated water coming through
pipes that water at the minimum has
chlorine or chlorine in it some sort of
way to keep the biology down and that
turns into a real nightmare when you're
trying to do soil biology if you're
trying to grow your own or have a garden
where you're encouraging soil biology as
soon as you use treated water you're
killing everything it's that's what it's
supposed to do
but meantime to treat water
to get it so you can use it without
killing your biology is really
problematic you're talking reverse
osmosis or extensive introductions of
colonies the biology into the water
until they've used up if you will all
the disinfectants that are in it I don't
know
pardon my rambling here but yeah those
are two things that came really
important to me is is the cleanliness of
the work that you're doing for your
end-users it's really I know I'm talking
to professionals but for people who are
doing your own work for you making your
own medicine however it is the quality
of your plant material is really
important because the plant itself is
not going to do any harm the plant can't
hurt you mmm I think I appreciate your
your airstone concept I've always just
used you know like like forced water and
rinsed it off but that's a very good
idea to just sort of don't you know
bubble up the water and clean any small
little particulate I think that if
you're making water hash a very
important component which I could
personally not imagine not having access
to as someone who makes water hash is a
macro lens or a microscope or something
that allows you to look very carefully
and closely and really blow it up you
know on a 30-inch monitor a 24-inch
monitor so you can see what's going on
in there because there's really nothing
like I mean you can bioassay all day
long and think you know what's going on
but when you look at it you see the
purity of it or the impurity of it for
that matter it really kind of lets you
know what's going on a little bit a
little bit better than assuming do you
micro sixty or a hundred times
magnification the trichomes you know
what I I don't use a microscope like
that I use a camera and it's a it it
works on like true macro which is one
one and then it goes to double that
which is two one
and it goes through three one four one
and five one and then you can crop those
images as well so I never really know
exactly how do
tailed I am when I when I've gone in for
the shot I don't know how magnified I am
you know I don't know if it's 200 or 300
or 150
I just really have no idea I like
getting close though as close as
possible I think the secret also is
start with really clean plants means
really clean water and then when you
when you made the hash and separated
that Earth the resin you have to dry it
quickly so then it doesn't become
contaminated with microbiological you
can't be really slowly life requires
water that's the one thing we know about
life on this planet isn't requires water
so when you're adding water in you're
really giving it it's like germinating a
scene you're kind of kick-starting the
process so it's it's really quick it's
really good to be fast right in getting
that that product dried out well if
you're commercial you're just making it
for a marketplace it's gonna be a lie of
eliezer it's gonna be a freeze dryer
whether it's a pharmaceutical grade or a
laboratory grade or even a home version
it's gonna remove the moisture content
out under vacuum in a way that you can
get that hash really really properly dry
at least void of all moisture and go
from there I mean otherwise microbials
are gonna get you you have water and
those life starts to multiply when
they're doing these you know microbial
tests or they measure the amount of
microbial a microbial activity or the
amount of colony forming units and you
know differentiate between the different
species right that's one of the failures
of these type of testing is that you
could you might have here some kind of
microbiology that's above the you know
the safe for the recognized colony
forming units
but those colonies themselves are toxic
or dangerous hmm right so we need to
have tests that actually accurately
reflect the you know the potential harm
of the species when I was just in
Manitoba I went and visited a one of the
largest hemp processors in Canada he
candy hall 5,000 pounds of hemp parts or
hemp seeds into hemp parts every hour
and the facility was awesome he had like
a hundred thousand liters of oil in the
building he it was very impressive
massive quantities of seed and he he
took them to his lab where they were you
know measuring colony forming units and
they were doing ecoli tests and they
were doing mold and yeast tests it was
cool to walk through and check out and
and just see how how they go about doing
that awesome sounds great you get video
that well you know what he didn't it's a
lot of it is his intellectual property
and so he didn't I got some photos I can
show you personally but I didn't nothing
that I can but I can share around great
facility though this guy had it going on
hey guys I'm just gonna jump in here I
got to I got to bounce a lot got some
some plans so I appreciate you guys
having me I was good talking yeah and I
will see you guys in the future
hopefully you guys punchy let mo see it
have a great day thanks Chris
have a good day always good to have
Chris in like that dude all right
Wow
the hexahydrate cookies yeah it's just
great to have him as a collaborator on
that project so he's able to you know
make some samples to get you know things
you know out there in the market we've
taken we have hydrogenated CBD that
we're actually going to be putting into
dairy products and look for the impact
that it has on shelf-life and stable
in efficacy look at as a functional
ingredient for food as well as
nutritional so that's very cool
yeah all kinds of stuff to do there
what's HAP intro I said are you pouring
it into milk are you feeding it to the
cows for you we're putting it into dairy
fats and stuff like that that's
conceived exactly what it does to
enhance you know resistant to oxidative
breakdown so sorry about that
your dog's wants to be on hash Church
watch out for lecithin that's the the
can be the accelerant that can really
amp up the THD exponentially in the body
so be aware of that because it just
breaks it down so much that the body's
uptake is pretty badass I added that
when I was like I years ago when we're
talking about bond losses that's the
thing that I would add so now that
you're talking about adding it to dairy
and things like that beware of that yeah
I mean that's actually one of the things
we're looking to count on right is an
enhanced uptake so using that effect
that I think that happens you know
across the family of you know a variety
of different things like lessons and you
know fatty acids and triglycerides which
are facilitated transport of these very
hydrophobic molecules into biological
tissues you know I recently met a
scientist the chemistry guy who has some
nano emulsification process using silver
and he uses like these nanites that are
like a seven nanometers in length
colonial so we're just yeah it's a
colloidal silver but what he does is he
can he can turn on or turn off the
hydrophobic or hydrophilic nature of
a molecule he can either make it attract
or repel with this with this process
plus he has claims both with the FDA and
with Health Canada so he has like health
claims that he can make and he's looking
to make deals with you know people that
might want to to engage with
cannabinoids and gain the use of those
claims that are near impossible to get
if you were just to try and get those
claims his the health claims like they
they use this stuff in surgery in open
wounds and they it's in dentistry and
and so all sorts of different things but
very interesting I'm gonna go meet him I
think next week and he might be I would
have to check the email I'm not sure
100% he could be but you're also not
allowed to do it under the Health Canada
regulations right yeah brand so no this
was to this was to put into kit like
cannabinoids and this product to put it
together he had a whole crazy deck I'm
not I can't say the name of his company
but it was a project that embarked was
looking at
I mean colloidal silver has been used in
antimicrobial coatings for a Coon's age
and yeah everything from shopping cart
handles to surfaces at the airport or
you know coated with I think the product
used to be called alpha San or microbe
and and it's yeah it's colloidal silver
now if you're talking nano silver now
it's not colloidal anymore because
you're talking about a particular size
machine colloidal just makes one big
particle of glamour it but I usually
think of those kinds of things as being
not good in general for cannabis
operations because they have very broad
spectrum you know anti microbial
activity and as you know that plant
relies on microbial activity for
fixation of nitrogen and and other
essential you know biochemical reactions
that have to happen where if you knock
out some of the lower runs on the food
ladder which is what those
broad-spectrum things do you just
destabilize the natural balance of
microbes in the soil no need to spray
silver on your plants let's just beyond
yeah I don't think so yeah but this
wasn't that this was something totally
different this was in taking
cannabinoids and then putting them
together after you've grown the plant
after you've extracted it there's all
kinds of people doing nano and all kinds
of different sort of formulations to
there is you know put these very
hydrophobic molecules into you know
water and water based formulations so
you know there's again just many
different ways of doing that
you know 18 mention less it in I mean
less attends one you know sort of
naturally occurring material that can be
used but there's any number of materials
that can be used ultimately no no Sam
that was terrible you really can't you
really really can't help yourself
wash here I will be honest it probably
took me like two or three years to get
into the frequency to to not miss Sam's
jokes because they would often go over
my head or under my feet or beside by I
was just like but then when I got it I
was like man this guy has like the
craziest driest 60 take dry humor and
then take it to a desert no look past
the Oasis
yeah for a year yeah exactly I was gonna
say that as well you got to turn it into
the 99.9 percent dry humor that's
concentrated dry humor and then
hydrogenated I've got some a little bit
of Rods in here that has a lot of smelly
I like it without having to hear that
damn I got some nice full melt rice if
you would like here these two as anybody
called for a br yet you know what I
invited Dee for 20k in he never came in
but what are you gonna do bong rip you
know what he's not even imitatable can't
even imitate them bother lovers mother
lovers exactly don't forget mother
lovers perfect oh my god sometimes I
feel like it's scripted and then I'm
just playing our parts in a movie it's
just so so insane wrote the script oh my
goodness
well hey I want to talk sure that's
great I just came from the hemp
conference so I'm ready to have that
conversation oh by the way Sam I saw
Jase Calloway said to say hello yeah go
ahead
so in California we've just you know
we've got this cannabis set of laws with
insane kinds of regulations for every
sort of activity in the cannabis work
but then we also have this
separate industry called him and
basically they're using similar plants
and yeah there's the whole registry
thing that we were discussing earlier
but in trying to learn how this is going
to work on the in the real world one of
the things that I've realized has become
really important is that cannabis in
California is regulated under the
business and Professions Code where as
him is in the food and agricultural code
and in the food and agricultural code
cannabis as hemp enjoys all the
protections of the right to farm act
which carries all kinds of weight in
California for agriculture and whatnot
and meantime yeah there's all kinds of
questions that come into play for a
person like for myself if I have six
personal use plants growing on my
property if they happen to be hemp type
plants I'm actually breaking the law if
they're high THC plants that don't have
that it that they have more than three
tenths of a percent THC then they are
cannabis and I even allowed to grow them
no that's way it is in California that's
what I'm saying you have to grow at
least 1/10 of an acre of him I'm just
talking about the California food and AG
in him says you have to grow at least
1/10 of an acre whereas if it's if
they're cannabis plants if I call them
cannabis plants I can have 6 on my
property no question I have to be
indoors but that's a whole other
conversation it's it's fascinating to me
that in law we're trying to take the
cannabis plant and say some of them are
gonna be AG products commodities and and
meantime there's the whole question of
most of the people in California who are
doing CBD are doing hemp want to do CBD
but meantime the
the folks who regulate cannabis the BCC
have said you can't sell CBD as hemp to
any human you can't sell it in Canada
California as a cannabis product it has
to go through a dispensary so it has to
go through the track and trace and it's
to me it's just an example of regulation
gone awry it's release it's it's
nonsensical if you will it's almost
Alice in Wonderland kind of stuff that's
all I got for the moment I'm fascinated
to hear any other points of view about
this but yeah the crux of it is in
California is an Ag product and all the
rest of cannabis is a business and
Professions Code side a thing all kinds
of regulations ridiculous for sure
welcome to the dragonfly Earth Medicine
in the room welcome you you all had
talked a little bit about the Canadian
have codes and stuff so I think that you
know that hemp has always been part of
like a bigger AG situation with with the
seeds and the fiber and now it's moving
into a medicinal and now you know you
have farms that are out west that are
mostly concerned on on CBD strains and
then you have hemp farms out in the
prairies like Manitoba where where
Marcus was where they're still totally
focused on fiber and seeds so really I
don't think the government has the
capability of of getting their systems
up-to-date as fast as the plant is
changing and as fast as all the farmers
are making discoveries
yeah we're making all these discoveries
along with you know these amazing
scientists and laboratories that were
working with and and the laws they they
just heard they're like a stagnant
creature that can't keep up with it so
it's almost really difficult to manage
that we're bummed out about it at embark
because we want hemp farmers to be able
to grow high cannabinoid content
cultivars and because we're looking at
processing ten plus thousand
spurred a we need we need large numbers
like we're not just gonna be able to
toll process for for LPS we're more
interested in getting material from
either greenhouse growers relationships
that we make ourselves or you know being
able to get it out of country and
producing crude oil and shipping it in
but ideally getting getting them from
Canadian farmers that are able to
understand because this is another thing
that a lot of Canadian farmers don't
understand right now is that when you're
gonna grow for cannabinoid content
you're not going to grow for seat and
most of them right now think that this
is this cannabinoid thing CBD in
particular is an added value that they
can just process their crops and I
personally like it's it's difficult to
to process hemp that's like 2 and 1
percent returns it's just not you when
you have the ability to process so much
you're better off processing a
cannabinoid content that's you know
above 8% and ideally above 20% well yeah
our brother here in the Eugene area just
grew a strain called the lifter this
year and got 23.5%
on his outdoor lifter and he's really
really stoked now he's that the lab said
it was the highest of the season so
there there's some real it's a beautiful
flower we have a jar but right here and
it's got an incredible flavor highest of
the season I picture there's some huge
heart celebration and he gets to sit in
this hand-carved chair above everyone
house and carried through the a chair
made of hemp stalks of course of course
you have one the highest of the year
there's no but it does have a really
amazing wide variety of terpenes as well
and it's a hybrid of the special sauce
from last year from Crawford Brothers so
yeah it's good a lot of a lot of new
strains happening right now so it's
really interesting to see how they
turned out this year it's funny because
one of my videos went viral
recently on YouTube it's my video of
where I press half a pound of where's my
bike from karma genetics and I make 60
grams of rosin and it's just gone viral
it's got like three or four hundred
thousand views in the last like couple
of days it's well over a million views
now like 1.4 or something but it's it's
an incredible to see people watch a
video where a plant can return
twenty-nine percent dry weight of oil to
bud and have people after person after
person after person say that bud was
bunk that was mid grade herb because
where's my bike doesn't look all shiny
in LA and fake it really it really looks
almost like an outdoor even when grown
indoor it looks even if your what you
trim it well it just kind of looks a
little not that great of a herb but it's
truly a perfect example of herb that you
cannot judge by its cover because the
content of cannabinoid and terpenes that
it produces that are actually on point
and worth hitting like they're strong
and they're clear and they're tasty yeah
it's it's kind of a winning combination
what's that Sam you're a little far away
you're a little far from your mic oh it
sounded I hear you but you cut out a
little bit go ahead
no when I was asking me was did you put
it in and kind of the desiccator or
other there anything to try and dry it
out ah no I did not but it definitely
didn't change much that first batch had
stayed very consistent and sort of pull
and snappy I I did run some recently
that buttered out immediately and we we
weighed it buttered out it so I've got I
made about 400 grams of it recently a
big [ __ ] of there's my bike rosin just
putting it through the the pure pressure
that thing is like a workhorse
I actually have a few bags left here
still I think oh yeah they're over here
a few that I didn't process yet I've got
them in with the Babita so they don't
dry out but I've got about ten bags in
here each with 35 grams there their
heart is a rock this batch was the first
batch whole does it smell oh my god it
was the first batch that I blew bags
with earth I've never had that is so
hard that it glows the bag I've had hash
do it so with these particular batches I
had to close the plates let it sit on
the herb at about 20 psi for a solid
thirty Seconds to a minute and basically
wait until it just started juicing and
then I could apply a higher you know amp
up the the PSI on the on the toggle
switch but if I came down the way I
pressed my last batch of where's my bike
I just came down with full psi it would
squish it and I'd get a 9 to 10 gram
return each time never mind in a sayers
if you pay any attention to them drag
you down to the mud with them ah the
naysayers it's true why am I so like
obsessed with them with replying to the
naysayers I find I get caught up in it
and then I'm like I'm only gonna reply
to positive comments people that are
asking you know information like what
songs on the video or they actually want
to learn something I'm answering them
first not the guys that's that are
slamming well because you're a truth
seer and you can see through it so you
know it's part of the realities of what
we face when you're pioneering and
you're creating your own trail as you
know as interest says you know just
carry on do your own thing don't don't
if everybody listened on this panel to
what everybody else thinks
there would be no panel none of us would
be here so we've all Buck roads within
reality along the way to where we're
like no you're wrong we can make a
better path so we've all established
that many much in many thanks to that
man
therefore establishing a lot of the
reality that we know and Andrea always
thanked me for your medicine because
they still use it daily and your
creation has changed my life for the
better so I think you both well I bet
dr. calzone does he gave me the advice
to get it certified in a bunch of
different ways way back when really
buying into it that that well now our
equipment is fully certified under those
guidelines in every state in the country
and in every country actually right
around the world and it's because I
finally started listening to his advice
about how to go about doing that so the
whole thing the all the stuff that's
happening now by the way there's we have
two installed and they're being used and
people that are using sanely happy with
them and they're using it more than one
thing one of the users of it is actually
spending a few days a week doing hemp
and then a couple days a week doing
other stuff different fragrance stuff
he's doing a lot of speeds and he just
recently did a number of seeds which are
very interesting and it should prove to
be quite the thing and so now we're also
going to come out with the small one
I've got the prototype getting ready to
come and way back when in the beginning
I promised mark one of the small ones he
used for research I haven't forgotten
that just that we don't have one exactly
ready it just gave me the first mock-up
of it wanting to know if I wanted
anything changed on it and I submitted
the drawings to psi psi said it's a go
and so well we're gonna start producing
those ones going to go to Marcus one's
going to go to mark one's going to go to
wait and that whole scenario there
though that's what's going to
to the first three of those small ones
and we're also come out with a double
size 1 and a triple size one but triple
size it
McDonagh oops one go for a quad they're
all certified 200 centigrade 2 plus 224
Fahrenheit that's a good range she got
to admit that should be able to allow
you to get whatever kind of extraction
you're seeking but anyway it's been a
long drawn-out trail and once again I
just say thanks oh it's about time I did
something useful
what do you mean you're hydrogenating
[ __ ] like crazy bro hydrogenation thing
I think it's a very interesting path
myself um something's gonna come out
from me this year one of them I want to
do right here on the show with you I
want you to premiere it and show it
we'll do it I'm always down you've been
very supportive and ever since I met you
which is way the [ __ ] back yeah it
really was and actually if we would have
gotten a little more together things
then instead of just letting everything
go by the wayside you and I probably be
multimillionaires right now they'd stop
what we missed
so really well it would be nice to pay
for plane tickets mostly but I could do
with with or without I'm fine I'm good I
mostly just want at this point in time I
won't lie to be healthy that's up that's
like top notch number uno I hate people
I know who came very wealthy you came
yeah it's true it's true I could I could
I can
sail along the lines although I do know
some great great people that that have
been very successful
hey welcome Daniel you got a mic there
Daniel can you hear me welcome
that's Daniel from Whistler technologies
and whistler medical up in pen B yes
Daniel hey he's muted he's muted I don't
know why he's muted but he'll figure
it's it's you know there we go
there it is welcome dude thank you we
can hear you
so we were talking earlier about
microbials and water hash and ever the
problem down in California actually Wade
the friendly looking bearded fellow in
the corner with the green hat he was he
was talking about it and I was I wasn't
man I wish Daniel was in here right now
we could be talking a little bit about
what we're doing at whistle technologies
and trying to sort of take into account
those those infamous microbials that
love to fail water hashes yeah we we've
been doing some testing with Whistler
medical and we've seen pretty good micro
results for the hash we haven't seen any
hash fail yet we've even seen half past
that the dry the bud from the same lot
had a higher microbial count it seems
the freeze drying did help a lot though
yeah we were talking about that that
freeze drying is gonna be pretty pretty
essential to dividing that water out as
quick as possible we make the ice with
RO water and cleaning your ice machine
regularly because even with the RO water
you get this like pink slime that builds
up in there so cleaning out all your
water at the ice equipment helps a lot
the only time we used commercially
available ice we failed micro like
terribly that's that's saying a lot
right there isn't it yeah the pink
that's in that pink slime is a is iron
from the hardness of your water
so that pink is usually like we see it
every once a while in our ice tray when
we clean it out to that whole apparatus
and there develops what's I I guess it's
not a living biome but it's just what's
called a biofilm right so biofilm into
you know fowl commercial ice makers so
it's definitely worth you know looking
into how you can clean those out yeah
you definitely gonna cut control and
condition your water and your ice
there's I'd like no get it yeah yeah my
friend up in Pemberton has made amazing
bubble for years going up to black tusk
and collecting ice up there and in the
snow I was thinking the other day that
uh all the out bull and Lillooet there
should be a cold storage facility that's
just like up in the alpine so in
November hits you can just like bring it
up to a warehouse that doesn't actually
have cooling and then process into hash
up there be awesome need to do at the
ski Hut's that aren't working out ski
lodges just turn them into hash lodges
and turn on listen I know some good hash
or have already call into the hash Lodge
that have really amazing micro-hydro
situations on them because they're way
up in the mountains next to a giant
Crete so they're making all their own
electricity and stuff to you that would
be amazing
dude I'm picturing a really cool
Whistler technologies sort of commercial
or you know video brochure you know
whipping it up in that little cabin on
the top of the mountain I'll be so sick
you know there is it's a way without
water yes yes we know John we know a lot
of the water problems if you don't use
water for sure but when you're focused
on using water it's it definitely makes
a very good good product there's no
denying that bubble hash is not gonna go
away anytime soon there's always gonna
be new ways that come out that are
that are exceptional and we'll just
we'll we'll adapt along with them for
the last 20 years it's been its it's had
its place it's now I don't I don't feel
that it's going away I love bubble hash
when I was at the cup last year a bunch
of different be hurt me on to their
bubble hash I still have stashes of some
of it because I meet her and out to
myself very sparingly but it's such a
nice high I think there's room for every
kind of way of deriving the natural
products it's in the plant playing a lot
people are gonna find you eight methods
and ways of seeing and understanding how
it all works
I know I made my first extraction my
first gas extraction in 1970 and that
was I first saw thca crystals and it was
a it was literally by serendipity
because when I made that gas extraction
I left gas in the oil in a jar and when
I woke up in the morning I found the THC
a crystals so DHEA crystals
that's no new innovation I saw it
happened in front of my eyes in 1970 and
a bunch of other things because I was
researching a lot and in 1998 I left it
on the web I go so that other people
could experiment and find out
unfortunately a lot of people did the
wrong thing with it but there's a lot of
to be found out yet because I know a lot
of things and I don't hear anybody
talking about yet you know and because
it's number that method or that
particular derivative derivative of it
and so I still wait to see every day
there's so many creative people doing so
many creative things did I expect
everything that I've seen already
up till now to start just naturally
appearing in the biome of all the people
who live on earth because we all share
all these sensations and feelings all
the time and so I'm pretty sure that
some people are just going to get that
vibration and turn into it and these
things will change out the mark the more
people have access to like it's you know
if you're one of those lucky people in
life that you have had an enormous
amount of access to cannabis and to be
able to play around with it you can
discover things it's much harder to
discover things if you don't have an
enormous access to cannabis of quality
cannabis I got started in Vietnam and I
was busy when you were in Vietnam you
were considered in the combat zone you
could send mail back to the USA with no
customs and no inspection so I sent my
mother 37 Sanyal refrigerators those
little coolers he is four drinks
full of Thai steak and blue lipstick and
stuff that I bought while I was in
Vietnam because well before I went to
Vietnam my mom said don't smoke
marijuana and I said okay I won't but by
chance under fire somebody gave me some
when I smoked it and I was become me way
down
I said what's that and he said pot and
I'm like oh [ __ ] I froze mom well anyway
I said mom back 37 of these
refrigerators because I was afraid I
wouldn't be able to find pot back in the
States and I knew that they weren't
expecting it so I you know I had a lot
of it that was very good and I had it
for a long time I had all the seeds from
that in case you're getting ready to ask
and I have a plethora of all that stuff
from that time because mostly out of
paranoia that I wouldn't be completely
get it back in the States
so I did have a lot of that and I did
experiment with it and I did a lot of
extractions at that point in time but it
wasn't conducive to spreading it around
the internet didn't really open up to
Mike in 98 when it did I published
online on several places and I you know
I wish only the best for the community
but I know that there's some things that
nobody has looked at yet because if they
did I would have heard about it if
nowhere else your own hash Church indeed
indeed time for a rip yes before twenty
K screen long rip yeah I can do other
lovers mother lovers lovers that won't
sounded pretty decent you gotta you
gotta get that deep in there gotta get
the grit by the way hello chin hello
Andrew
ant yeah one thing I wanted to say too
is that you know it's really interesting
as a grower a lot of experimentations
and a lot of original thought comes from
failures you know different kind of crop
failures and when you're growing in
thousands of plants you know out in the
bush is where it all started for a lot
of us you know crop failures or maybe
something seeding out or you know you
have a huge massive snow and ice storm
you know in September so it forces you
to really have to think outside of the
box and a lot of extractions and
original thought come from growers you
know that have had different types of
failures and successes along the way
that's right failure is the mother of
invention snowstorms in September yeah
but those snowstorms really helped us
out you know in creating a whole lot of
our different strains that we have going
on and really thankful for them which
which plants made it out of a snowstorm
and which ones didn't is is a really
enlightening thing to find out and I
wouldn't trade Canada for the South for
anything gotta tell you I have a bonsai
teacher who says you won't learn
anything until you kill your first
hundred trees and it goes along that
sentiment you know and it takes seven
years to master each type of tree they
say which is also applicable because
each type of Jeanette
it takes a while for you and a few years
for you to understand by growing it and
it's failing and it parts of it dying
and then getting it nursing it back to
health etc etc so that you learn to see
the signs as well as you know what is
the optimization that you can get from
that particular genetic as well it's
fascinating this planet absolutely and
the other thing you know talking a lot
about microbials you know today and
microbial counts and the DNA and all of
that sort of stuff with it is that a lot
of that testing you know that you start
to figure out comes from failures in
your crops you know it comes from oh
geez I've got something going on and
what can I spray on it what can I spray
on it what kind of recipes can I utilize
what's gonna harm at what's gonna hurt
it you know and that's really where Josh
and I you know thrive is actually from a
lot of our failures you know when we had
our very very first broad might a long
time ago we took that broad might and
then we studied it you know for nine
weeks and really found out everything
there was to find out about it what kind
of sprays worked what didn't you know
and in the end you know as far as
talking about microbials we're back to
heat treatment over and over again so
that microbials really aren't a part of
the conversation as far as cultivation
goes so been really thankful for our
failures to learn a lot and our
successes for sure but through through
our huge successes and failures we've
been able to do a lot of education and
help people out so that they can also be
successful you want to learn a thing
teach it and backward wave from that
will teach you everything there is to
know about that subject I wanted to
learn Anatomy when I was going to
pre-med school and I was utterly failing
it was so difficult and someone gave me
that advice so I started a class
teaching people who even knew less than
I about Anatomy and by a year later I
was a fantastic anatomist I can discuss
everything from the level of the caesium
of the bone all the way out but it took
me wanting to teach
so your effort of teaching is a powerful
back wave to your own learning
there's no that's for sure
I'm in full of greens with that
statement and I could see what it is as
well as he nods his head in affirmation
yes I wanted to jump in and share a
little story I when we're talk about
failure and learning from failure
Harlequin
when Harlequin first happened the group
of patients patients in the collective
that I had in those days it was a
failure virtually every person in the
group that got some of those early
flowers said yeah oh I like the way it
looks loved the way it smells but you
know it doesn't get me stoned man and
that's like what's the point but one
person one person in that whole group
said his shoulder that he had torn up
playing football in school had hurt so
much since he had metal parts put in and
his shoulder hurts so much he'd been in
and out of opioid rehab a bunch of times
trying to kick painkillers and he said
it's the damndest thing I smoked a joint
of this [ __ ] and it doesn't hurt anymore
Wade what the [ __ ] and that's when I got
it tested and because yeah up until the
I got it tested harlequin looked like a
disaster because I had a whole room not
just a room a building just to be honest
a building full of these plants and none
of the people that were so going to be
using them wanted it and yeah in terms
of learning what ender was saying about
teaching trying to share the information
that each of us has learned in this kind
of a context here the hash Church it's
part of what I love about the
opportunity to be here but going out
into your community normalizing our work
helping people understand that we're not
criminals we're not
we're not out to hurt the environment
we're not out to hurt kids were
restoring this plant if you will to its
rightful place that's really what's
going on and part of what I appreciate
about Marcus you framing this
conversation as hash church is Church
implies a certain religious or spiritual
point of view about it and I for one
feel a religious if not passionate
missionary zeal about the fact that this
plant can't hurt you and that as we
learn more about how to work with this
plant we start seeing really remarked my
rock ulis things happen I just it's it
is a miracle plant it is in fact as the
rust assay the healing of the peoples
and we like it's like a fractal medicine
because you know everything that you do
to it it fractals out into you know a
different form and even within the
learning of it you know it's a fractal
of learning because there's it's such an
adaptogenic you know plant that there's
just so much variation to it that is it
it's like a beautiful story that you
know you just keep learning about and
it's just unfolding in front of you and
everything you just said brings to mind
that it's almost in a way now with all
the legalization and stuff that we're
almost going back into a private thing
with IE peas and everything and almost
going into you know a protective way you
know it's almost the opposite of
teaching it was like as recreational and
every and legalization was coming there
was a lot of openness and a lot of
people sharing and everything and now
we're almost moving into a protective
you know IP state and I and I get why
that is on a lot of levels and stuff and
so and there's nothing wrong with that
but I just you know that's part of what
you know we're dealing with the pure
certification is just keeping knowledge
out there and just keeping the
inspiration out there so people can
continue to learn and I agree with you
that thank you
Marcus you know for everything you've
done to keep this going and it's
exciting for us to learn from people all
over you know meeting Daniel and and
Whistler and seeing everything he's
doing and having an opportunity to be in
Nelson and going through Eugene here and
we're on our way to Arcada beneficial
living center and southern humble to out
them low and down to Koval Oh for the
son roots farm and we're just doing a
big to our farm so that we can continue
learning and we can share you know what
we're learning with everyone too so
we're on the mission of you know
connecting good people and good products
and also just the learning train and I
think that the most important thing that
you know sort of to add on to what you
were saying wade is that we are entering
a global market and it absolutely is
imperative for the people and the
businesses who have a really tight
connection with this plant to join
together to you know make a stance when
we go into the global market because
right now in Oregon you know they're
dealing with an island here they can't
sell outside of their island it makes it
very difficult and a lot of people who
have had really long time relationships
with this plant and who have been
cultivating it or concentrating it for a
long time have either had to step out or
had to step way back from their
involvement with the plant and we just
are really encouraging those people to
stay involved with it whether it be
through education or whether it be
through your business because when it
does go to a large global market you
know the people who have had
relationships with the plants are going
to shine and I think that it's
imperative that we continue our
education I like it it sounds all
perfect to me I appreciate all of you
thank you it's great it's great to be
able to gather on a Sunday morning and
sort of just get into this I guess it is
funny because I really chose that church
I mean honestly I named it hashed Church
for the simple reason that I hit this
milestone I was allowed to suddenly
stream and it was like 8 o'clock or 8:30
on a Sunday morning and I was like okay
what would I call my show and I thought
we used to gather for some days and we
call the church not Jesus Church but
actual cannabis Church we used to meet
at my friend Amir's restaurant that was
right across the street from the melting
point my gallery and we called the
church so I thought Here I am all these
years later very focused on hash I'll
call it hash Church I think I even
called the first one like a Sunday
morning hash Church with bubble man or
something and had no idea I would do it
like a hundred and seventy more times in
a row with all of you it was just
ridiculous but yeah it's neat that
church happened to be in the name
because it is very much sort of a
spiritual guiding light that in my life
for for the last 25 years I've
definitely followed it down some pretty
cool corridors down some very cool paths
and there just seems to be an endless
amount of paths it's like this fractal
infinity of amounts of directions it can
take you and regardless of and I'm
always excited about it that's the thing
I like about cannabis is that in in my
work with cannabis I can now start
getting excited about all these other
things whether it's you know growing
acres in Jamaica and processing or
whether it's building this giant lab
here in DC or working with Whistler
technologies to bring new technologies
to light and helping in you know
commercialize that water extraction
process I'm always excited about it
because cannabis is involved and I you
know I end up in some situations that if
cannabis wasn't there I'd be like wow
this would be pretty boring like I'm
just in a big manufacturing plant right
now I wouldn't be super stoked on this
if it wasn't for the fact that they're
manufacturing like hemp products like
oils and protein powder isolates and all
of these different things that suddenly
you know I walk into a room and there's
just like I don't know how many hundreds
of thousands of pounds of seeds just in
these giant totes that are taller than
me and you know huge like five feet
round and he's just got a giant room
full of them I was just like man this is
this is exciting I love I love working
with cannabis and I think I think it's
one of the
we're all very lucky to be involved in
this industry and one of the things
people ask me often is how can I get
involved in this industry and how do you
answer that I mean just get involved I
mean do you guys have good advice for
that because I always I'm like I'm
always like follow your passion bla bla
bla I don't really know what to say in
regards to how do you get into the
industry cuz all I do is just start
growing wheat grow your own well your
own plant but you know don't get
arrested don't get arrested don't get a
felony don't get a felony more than
anything else it's the most important
put together a resume you know go down
to find these distributors find these
people volunteer that's I got I got
involved in this because cannabis Action
Network was an all-volunteer
organization and I just started showing
up and giving my time and my time on the
phone calling people was very boring
initially but that led to me then being
on a street corner than being on the
street corner then allowed me to then be
on rock and roll tours and then doing
hem tour and next thing you know I get
hired by a company who's like hey you've
been out on the road and you know what
you're doing you know about this plant
hemp so come work for me and then
couldn't do that anymore and then came
back to California and have been
involved in medical cannabis ever since
so it just takes the chance be honest
with yourself take the chances you're
gonna fail you're gonna make mistakes
but if you really love and care about it
you'll find a way to plug in but I mean
there's lots of organizations the United
States there's there's College every cup
there's college campuses that have
organizations if there's not one you can
get in contact with
mpps SSDP students for sensible drug
policy maps they'll all help you set up
chapters on a university so you can find
other like-minded people and that's what
we did where we would go around then to
free speech areas on college campuses in
the United States I've been through 47
states doing this I know I've done it
firsthand and I did it wasn't paid for
it I volunteered my time but they paid
our money
our food and our travel and everything
else so it's one of those realities that
you just have to sometimes take the the
chance and get out there and there are
companies hiring all throughout
California even the Bureau of cannabis
control is hiring needs to hire a
thousand people they need inspectors
they need people who go out you know and
and look and regionally so there's all
areas around the the state that they're
gonna need regional coordinators so of
course those may have some sort of
educational requirements but there's
different ways that you can plug in I'm
only giving California as an example
because that's the example that I have
currently and that I've used but find
people get in there be honest be
trustworthy be forthright be honest and
anything can happen I mean you can end
up just like one of us and be on the
panel one day you know I like her at all
I would also say that learn about
something that you're interested in
because that knowledge is really
powerful and that's how you get into a
place you want to be so whatever your
passion is learn about it and then
display that knowledge go meet people in
the industry as everyone else has said
and just get out there because the more
you learn the more you'll be able you're
going to be able to help people or help
yourself and you'll get where you want
to be right there's also regional like
National cannabis Industry Association
now has regional quarterly meetings in
certain states and areas so you can go
down and meet people and rub elbows with
local business owners ask them questions
ask ways how how you can plug in but
most importantly is yes if you want to
get involved seriously if you want to be
a grower then you know you can go to
college and actually get you know
degrees in botany and biology as well as
chemistry as the doctor will tell you
because these are all things that we
need we need researchers we need doctors
we have research enough to last for
generations right Doc's we have
literally generations of of just from
hemp alone I mean high-grade cannabis
all that type of research needs to be
done as well as we need to set up a germ
plasm Institute in North America which
we need stewards and growers and seed
producers
and you know all those realities are
still yet to you know see the light of
day but those are realities that have to
take place in time so if you're watching
there's still ways for you to plug in
and be part of that future in reality I
like I liked all those answers I
definitely they kind of were unique
because they were like each of your
versions of kind of how you went about
doing what you had to do to get into
this industry but I have to say Wade's
was my favorite like grow cannabis grow
it to get to know it it's like really
that is like so simple and yet so
completely accurate of course
grow cannabis now attached to mark who
worked in the non cannabis industry
right for years and it was kind of
boring like you said mark you walk into
a plan and if you're making sneakers or
you're making a rubber for the end of
the sneaker whatever you're you're fit
you're plants making it's not as
exciting as making you know hash or
medicine for people and you know around
the plant we love and so I was just
lucky and fortunate to intersect my
passion with what I can do for a living
and that's always a wonderful thing to
be able to put those two things together
it's like a constructive interference
pattern that where you get a greater
superposition and you'll be farther
along than you would be if you did any
one of those things individually but
together those things push you to places
that you may never have been and in
terms of failure I mean it's kind of
like you'll learn so the scientific
method is like you want to probe
something about some phenomenon so you
design a hypothesis and experiment to
answer the question and then you run the
experiment collect the data and come up
with the conclusion well you know as a
scientist who's run thousands of
experiments that totally failed that's
how you learn and that's how you define
the moment of invention because
as soon as something doesn't fail you
know what failures look like because
you've seen that like a hundred times
but as soon as you put something
together that totally is now you know
something new I mean that's that aha
moment that you know yeah I've done
something completely new that no one has
ever done before and so I think it's
inspiring to have you know some type of
you know educational background so what
you bring to the table is scientifically
grounded and then launching yourself
into this new industry I mean I can
imagine going into so many different
careers and getting so many different
educational experiences whether it's in
botany or chemistry or business or
nowadays I mean geez just go into the MJ
biz Khan there's more engineering and
manufacturing engineering or you know
Industrial Engineering what I'll call
you know packaging automated packaging
automated dispensing if it could be
automated it's coming to the cannabis
industry so there's just so many
different areas where innovation is
happening and imagine what that cannabis
shows is going to look like ten years
from now as opposed to you know where it
is today so it's just it's amazing to
think that this work the dawn of a new
industry that's going to plateau so I'm
at the time out in the future but until
it plateaus we're on a steep learning
curve we're all kinds of new shits
happening all the time yeah that's
amazing man I love that about the plan
everybody was talking about how it's a
fractal medicine and how its adaptogenic
and it's becoming such a large industry
right now that you can almost be
involved in anything and almost have
expertise in anything and it somehow is
going to bring itself back to the
cannabis industry and I think that it's
sort of funny you know like talking
about you know how do you get yourself
involved in the cannabis industry you
know that you're involved in the right
place if every single conversation that
you have
people surrounding you ends up in
cannabis I mean you can start a nuclear
waste yes and it ends up in cannabis and
to talk about the problems of the world
it ends up in cannabis and I think that
is really funny I think you got it you
got you have to have a passion so if you
have a passion you know then you're
gonna find a way into anything because
every everything is really pretty
competitive if you think about just all
any field is and because there's a lot
of humans on the earth but uh so and I
also think that with all the
manufacturing and engineering and all
the farmers and farming that's going on
I think that making products is is a
really huge you know area that we you
know what to do with all this material
so I mean I think the innovation of
being able to even put it in food I
don't understand why all the edibles are
mostly candy you know I mean I I would
eat a CBD sandwich you know or CBD soup
I I kind of want like the full CBD cafe
where the lemonade has CBD in it and
every damn thing in there is so you know
it's just a full medicinal that sounds
that sounds like skunk man Sam's
nightmare am i saying that I wouldn't
want a THC cafe to Cafe oh I'll have a
CBD sandwich with you man that's sweet
you know I mean CBG it doesn't have to
be add we're not you know we're not
cannabinoid us you know we want as many
cannabinoids in there as possible I
truly think your visions gonna come true
but it's not going to be anything weird
it's gonna be CBD will be fortified into
all foods just like vitamin C is it'll
be fortified from baby cereals to
geriatric formulations and everything in
between
all foods will contain CBD ten years
from now it'll just like back in 1873
and you know when when all of the hemp
was fed to the animals and the animals
were producing you know high CBD eggs
and then we were eating the egg
so either there was a there was an
intact cannabinoid system at one time
through all the creatures and also clean
the lands like you know sometimes the
the weed and print you know accumulates
the the heavy metals that means you
can't use that that year so you'd have
to put it back into the land but ya know
it's at least don't you think that the
possibility exists since our bodies are
prepared to use cannabinoids all the
time that the very first edibles were
probably from the stories I've read in
the Bible about this mana that was
available I think it was just mono wanna
and that the seeds were being used for
the oil and the leaves where are the
months the most nutritious things that
were available on earth and so that's
how we got this cannabinoid system in
our bodies from the day one whenever
that stuff was being the rock and now
it's now we're getting around to using
it as that was again but I'm pretty sure
that that's how it started off I want to
believe Indra that it conferred a
evolutionary benefit to any of the
tribes that might have been using it as
a food a portable food source rich in
protein rich in omega-3s which is brain
food and meantime the neuro protective
as well as antibacterial and antifungal
properties that we find in cannabis
probably conferred an evolutionary
advantage to the tribes that figured out
that cannabis might be a benefit to them
whether they were eating it or smoking
it meantime by carrying the seeds along
with them they probably dropped them in
some places and then saw them grow up
the next year in that new place and
maybe learned agriculture from it just
saying our whole entire system is based
off of so shows that evolutionally we
have you know totally grown together to
create a system in our body you know
that works with that plant so much and I
think that there's not a lot of examples
where humans with are willing to step up
for a plant like like we are for this
and also you know being humans on the
planet you know there's a lot of stress
involved there's no way that we can get
around stress we're a species that
creates stress whereas he sees that
brings in stress we're a species that
dissect stress and here's a plant that
can really help us with our stressful
lives and and I think that that it
really has a big play in our evolution
as far as human goes because as soon as
we are able to get rid of that stress
factor that's the way that we're able to
you know have a higher intelligence
that's how we're gonna be able to become
more biologically intelligent to the
planet and I believe that you know the
Mayans say that it's going to be the
flower that saves humanity I truly
believe that because it's gonna give us
different cloth patterns as well as
different types of body patterns that
help get rid of both you know emotional
and physical stress and if you believe
talk John Allegro might be Mahna Mahna
Juanes or Manas sila mana it might be
like there was some psilocybin in the
bread here I'm thinking well I'm pretty
sure that they way they found out that
everything makes you high was by putting
it in their mouth and trying it out and
then relating that experience to
somebody which is again the teaching how
powerful the teaching is because it had
to extend beyond those people and but
you were talking earlier about fractals
and I think our nervous systems and our
dynamic polite systems are fractal why
we so they need thing we can understand
so many different things
millions of little recesses and in the
mind that we're just learning to explore
them plant was here for some good I mean
it just you can't come up with an
explanation for why it's here but it's
here and it has persisted and I think
that persisted and so even persisted and
almost legal not quite yet we're still
being looked at and held up for
examination
so forth but nonetheless it's back when
I started using it was completely
illegal even passing information out
about it was illegal and even in 98 when
I posted vho there was a lot of strange
energy around it and so I know that
authoritarians that we lived with don't
like us exercising the freedom of mine
that being on THC gives you it just
unlocks a bunch of doors you know places
that you might not have looked before
simply because we're prone to being
programmed I mean that's what they call
TV is programming I don't watch it but I
know it's a problem in the world for
real for real for real
[Music]
I was wondering from Daniel how you
liked your new pressure machine that you
had got you had taken some pictures that
I'm not too long ago how's how's all
that working out and how's whistler tech
doing well we're still waiting to to
test the machine the electricians are
supposed to install it next week and
then we have to wait we can do some dry
testing but we have to wait for Health
Canada approval to do the deed with with
cannabis but we've been doing the same
process just on kind of smaller vessels
that weren't custom-designed but the
technology is doing well we're we're
kind of just finishing off all the
research phase and all this equipment
and getting ready to to fully
commercialize it yeah that's exciting I
will be excited when we can compound and
need be able to use the herb with other
you know medicines and that's kind of
like what we feel is the true magic and
healing and we've even seen some patents
that have been given to us by family and
at one of the talks that we did that you
know
about how to cure prostate cancer and
you know using the the fungi and
everything together with with cannabis
and I just know that with Chinese
medicine and Ayurvedic medicine that it
would be really wonderful once we can
start putting the whole medicine
together because really I mean cannabis
is an island almost in a sense right now
in itself you know just being going
through this whole wringer of
legalization so yeah it's all process so
I guess we have to be good with the
journey but yeah and as much of it is it
is dr. Jenna Keeler to ourselves it's
also adaptogenic and its own plant
kingdom
you know cannabis has certain other
master plants that it likes to be
blended with that it likes to be grown
next to and if we're creating it as just
an island that we can't do different
Votan achill compounding with it then
you know we're really doing ourselves
and also the plan to huge just service
it's nice to be able to do all of these
isolates and all this distillates and a
lot of the the concentrates that we're
doing that's all wonderful and well and
good but there's a lot of other plants
that you know really should be coming in
its own you know concentrated value as
well yeah for sure
I mean my are my other venture is
Whistler therapeutics and that is about
taking the whole production of cannabis
and for medicinal purposes and looking
at the holistic perspective and that
your production of the plant has to be
helping the environment because we have
we're producing medicine today but then
it's made from oil and the entire
production process is releasing
pollutants and there's so much transport
so I mean medicine production isn't a
huge pollution compared to everything
else when it's part of the problems as
you say cannabis helps change change
people's perspective to realize that
they're being damaging to the
environment and also opens them up to
more you know plant healers and other
things mushrooms are pretty fun it's
funny because in Canada mushrooms are
like the last unregulated frontier there
is no regulations for buying
or selling wild mushrooms which can be
hallucinogenic and Artic controls like
the Amanita of mushrooms or incredibly
toxic so you're legally allowed to buy
death care or pick Death Cap mushrooms
and sell them to someone else but we
need all this strict regulation on
cannabis to protect the children but
it's just the market the size is so
large that they need that regulation but
I think that you're right about you know
we're gonna have a lot more plant
partners or fungi partners that are
gonna help us out these are some a pair
of matsutake mushrooms I found that have
this heart in the center and they're
permanently bonded together which you
often don't see with with the pine
mushrooms so that was that I really
interested foul fine but um I think you
know the plants have a lot to teach us
about how we can heal ourselves and heal
the planet and more so especially the
mushrooms are so good at bringing the
planet back into balance after a
disturbance so humans go out and destroy
a forest and cut it down and the
mushrooms and the other trees work
together to bring that that ecosystem
back so looking at how we can integrate
our production of medicines into the
natural cycles of the earth is gonna is
gonna bring us forward and you know more
in tune with what we need to do which
really brings us into the work that
we're doing as far as seeing this up as
an opportunity to let small farms heal
the earth you know I mean there is
corporate farming out there and that's a
thing and it's whatever but you know
it's the small farms and things that
have the opportunity to reach a farm
regenerative Li and to take care of the
land and we're coming up to the Emerald
cup and there's a lot of really amazing
farms that you know will be highlighted
at the Emerald cup through the
regenerative farm award and there's
other Institute's like the resource
innovation Institute out of Portland
which analyzes grows with their
electrical output and their water output
and has come up with a way to measure
you know how how efficient they are as a
business and we think that that's really
valuable
and I think that it even even you know
getting down to the very root the root
the root of it all is that you know we
know that we're losing 90 percent of the
species on the planet and that so that
doesn't disclude one giant bacteria that
also means sure we're losing 90 percent
of the large species on the planet but
we're also losing 90 percent of the very
very small species on the planet and if
we start forgetting about what gives us
true intelligence which is from nature
which is the fungi and the bacteria and
if we're starting to lose all of that
and it is more important than ever to
bring back the small farmer because the
small farms are going to be able to host
this biologically intelligent biome that
holds all of these species and brings in
larger amounts of species so it's almost
like you know creating some kind of a
foundation to protect all of these
important species that are on the planet
and I believe that this is our
intelligence and the more that we
cultivate this plant in a natural
process is the more that we're gonna be
able to get out of it you guys go up oh
yeah yes we'll have our tea be there
we're gonna be doing some panels there
and working at the regenerative
agriculture lounge and stuff so yeah if
you're gonna be there be fun to meet and
hang out and etienne and anyone else I
know marks coming down we're gonna see
Wade and you know a lot of the lot of
these good family members here really
what about you Daniel you coming down
not this time but uh I'm gonna be pretty
busy up here for a while but I'm looking
forward to being able to travel around
more I wanted to go back what you're
saying just a minute ago and add in that
I think the cannabis from a medical
perspective is bringing you know
somewhat of a democratization of
medicine rather than having these
pharmaceutical companies that have to be
you know clinical trials are really good
and powerful but everything everybody's
put in the same box and everything has
to be such a large production that
rather than finding if
medicines that work well for small
populations we're going to find whatever
one works best for the average and when
you have small farm cannabis production
on the medical side well you're just
servicing the community and who's going
to be able to better provide the
medicines that that community needs and
someone who's right there and can talk
to those patients and know what the
problems are there so then you don't
have all the transport and all that
waste that we have with these large
systems and that's what you're seeing
with Medical Marijuana right you have
these local dispensaries and production
so I think that the really large
companies are you know I I don't hope
that's gonna be the the main way I think
that small-scale local production where
as you say we spread the knowledge to
everyone else and they can do it within
their own community and service their
own needs
we don't need massive mega producers per
se that are gonna supply everybody with
the same thing and then every
everything's made according to the
economics of where it's being
distributed and it's really easy you
know the technology we're developing can
be applied anywhere in the world really
and it's simple and it's environmentally
friendly and you can set up for not very
much money a pretty robust you know
medical cannabis system and you anywhere
people need it and that's really what
brought this whole thing to legalization
to begin with was the medicinal aspects
of it and if you're in Canada
John Conroy is a cannabis lawyer in
Vancouver who really is you know one of
our main people that's helping us keep
our medical abilities in Canada and we
really you know support him and that
whole group in every way and I also
wonder about mark if you know anything
about you know just the exploration of
endo Finnick fungi within the plant and
what you know how they play a role with
medicine and how that's that's not
really something you hear a lot about
and they're and we'll be able to for the
very first time because we're federally
legal in Canada we'll be able to
actually have the ability for people
that have scientific licenses to be able
to study you know soil grow
fungi inspired bacterial grown cannabis
for the very first time and I'm
wondering yeah mark what do you think
about that do you think that we're going
to be able to step a little bit further
into understanding the plant and its
uptake through its natural cycles bond
written you mean e mark or him Marcus no
you mark
Marcus your mark you know the difference
and welcome T 420k thank you
and bong rep it's nice to jump on and do
a bong rip with the panel do you want to
remind Darin what the other part of it
is thank you mother mother lovers it's
good to see everybody
geek tea on mark well I see um in droids
I see entered in there too yeah hey
Indra are you doing but a long time all
you guys have your knowledge I just love
it you know even when I'm not on here I
watch it and just throw the odd bong rip
in the comments and we all do one you
know what's up I've got told cherry pie
does anybody know about it anything
behind it or anything like that I heard
it's an OG cross with with rod it's
called pi breath what I have now it's an
OG cross with a cherry pie does anybody
know the lineage on any of that sort of
stuff like the cherry pie thing part of
it we've definitely grown it and done it
done a bunch of different blends of it
but I've heard that it's a no G cross
for sure and wondering that breaths is
either am endo breath or hogs breath in
there which is always really nice it's a
thug pug that's what I know about it I
went and met Turk crusher from Instagram
and he had all these thug pug cultivars
and apparently the guy has some good
abilities of selecting I saw a lot of
the different varieties and it was
it looked good it was it was good I
think you've got some kind of an
original Durbin poison in there too
I'm not really sure but love to hear
about that well I'm really enjoying it
I'm squishing some you know some
personal drawers and out of it not sort
of stop it it's tasty very tasty I like
it a lot and I'm glad I got to grow it
we did it from seed we've had it going
for both a year now we're fifth stage of
budding it off real nice and everything
and seeing when it's true potential is I
like it so cherry pie breath long
written more than others
let's do it we a grateful breath cherry
puffs and that was from the that's from
the mend Oh breath - which is a gauge
Green strange but we got it through
mister spliff and yeah I've got amazing
flavor and it's a blue style plant
bluish dark plant with like a super
silvery trichome on it and it has a
really fuel --is-- kind of humulin syrup
inyline kind of flavor to it like the
kind of diesel dog flavor to it it's
it's really really awesome great yield
er - how about pre-soviet heads -
pre-soviet Petrolia heads - cross
Kandahar I've got these seeds I started
two of them off just to see what they do
there's supposed to be like a 80 90 day
finisher but does anybody know anything
about that one you ever heard of it no
I'm fascinated by it
yeah well the name of it of just like
come on like you know my dog my little
dog is a Russian spat nanba Lankan Shih
Tzu I never believed the lady that I
bought it off but that was actually her
heritage until I wanted to breed her I
want to find a mate for her and all I
could find was these big large 15 to 20
pound shih tzus she's an eight pound
little dog she is an actual Russian spit
named Blanc and Shih Tzu she's
the whole name which is weird but this
Russian the pre-soviet Petrolia
headstocks cross Kandahar is what this
is called and I got it from a guy that
really I got it from the same guy I got
the cherry put the pie breath from so
I'm really really curious that three
Soviets that means 70 that's uh huh well
they talked up really nice my question
isn't Tom did it mop up Tommy or okay
okay cool well I'll keep you all up to
date on it anyways
does the Soviet thing I mean not so
large I mean there's the genetics the
autoflowering ruderalis genetics come
from siberia you know and then there's
also like CBD hemp fish cultivars from
Uzbekistan and over in the other you
know East you know western parts of
Russia so it's and when you say
pre-soviet it'd be really hard to know
why would for some reason think it might
be taller but well uh you know they're
both this tall right now that's it
they're just little babies so there's
this little are they widely yes yeah
they're they're Afghan and they're
pretty Soviet asan the pod breath it
wants to get in veg it wants to be in
but it's got the little the little balls
not the balls the the little pods the
seat not the seed stuff but we're you
know the little little bud correlation
there they build up it's like it always
wants to be in but even in veg it's got
the little cowlick hairs on and stuff
like that it's it's pretty good I like
it maybe it has some root maybe not some
of that ruderalis it might be
you know I don't know but I like it nice
brutal
it's just means roadside right Sam but
yeah but the reason people like Marie
rouse is because there's a lot of from
the far north with Your Honor we liked
it up here in the north and BC because
of our summers are shorter right and
they just seemed as soon as it started
to get rootbound
they just bud right off so it they did
that in July sometime they finished off
in September and we're okay good to know
like we grew a lot of those in our
outdoor genetics and British Columbia
back in the day you get throwbacks of
the ruderalis and they were definitely
better for hash I would say a lot of
times they made like a really kind of a
full furry top you know where it was
like a lion's mane or so I mean who
knows what you know what else you could
say but it was definitely not like a bud
in the same way I thought that's what we
found within ours
literally no THC ruderalis they have a
lot of brands but it doesn't it's not
high tea at all is it
can any type of cannabinoid that you
know of like should we be breeding you
know and working listen all to bring in
it cannot me it has more CBD CDC maybe
some TV or things like that but it's not
particularly high it's not even
particularly high in any of those
for example sobriety to tap away Auto is
vanilla which is grown in Canada I think
it's the largest seat reducing variety
growing area and for NOLA it will start
flowering pretty much in even under long
walk or you know the early summer
whereas finishes smiling though whereas
Rockstar cloud and they never really
finished flowering to life support to
like older the environment and their
word photo period doesn't make them stop
hours a box I wanted to mention maybe
just because I will forget otherwise but
my friend James just reminded me that
they have a new their first episode is
coming out highlighting the CPS work by
Sol on outreach in Victoria friend of
mine Jack Phillips is a big part of that
he's helped and run it and it's all
about giving cannabis to to people who
are opioid dependent and people who are
out on the streets they give away many
many many hundreds of packages every
month and his episodes coming out on
their website which is move the movement
dot org and they're like they got a cool
film crew they did a teaser for this
series and they did it at Salome's event
actually that you guys had the booth
that I'm not sure if you guys got
interviewed by those guys but we're
waiting we're going to get together with
them really soon that's a really
excellent movement
yeah great group of guys doing a really
important thing gathering a lot of
awesome individuals stories from the
cannabis culture and beyond really and
move the movement something that's going
to be an important part of this culture
and moving forward absolutely yeah
Darryl Darryl is a big big part of that
as well and he's doing good work and who
knows we'll see we might do more with
him in the future so definitely check
that out move the movement org didn't
mean to hijack the conversation but I
knew I would forget as probably gonna
wrap it up here in the next little bit
half hour maximum see how the
conversation goes well we're probably
gonna hit the high road now we're here
in Eugene gonna go visit evolved
extracts right now and check in with
Marley awesome person beautiful company
and and some other conscious farms in
town here can essentials and everything
so yeah big love to everyone we're gonna
be going to Southern Oregon soon in
Northern California to be checking in
with everyone thanks everyone on the
panel here for everything you do
khalad rias network wade mark indra
skunk its yin d40 dan I just wanted to
mention one more time people in
California who have the ability to
donate CBD flour to khalad Reyes Network
please do that you have until January
1st or December 31st really important
that we're able to get children the
medicine that they need and the families
to be able to sleep well at night and
you know health and harmony is what this
plant is all about so you know farmers
who have excess flour please donate it
to khalad reyes network well I have five
gallons of co2
JPD extract from my amp player and it
came with all the labs on it that's
0.01% of 0.03 or whatever THC in the
rest of it is
that and I've extracted some out of that
because as you know you're gonna
winterize it after co2 extraction which
is a huge joke but anyway it went rise a
bunch of it and it's a very good stuff
it's red as red can be quartz Hammond
distilled it because nothing I hate
worse than applying heat to something to
purify it yeah I mean you can get a
skeleton out of a cow too
I guess that's purification of sorts to
a I don't know I don't eat cows so I am
and I'm not one to comment on that but I
do have that CBD for them wait you guys
kept threatening to come around and pick
it up and though it's in my freezer
soaking in pure ethanol 200 fruits so
are you gonna be in touch Indra we have
be in touch yes thank you thank you hey
when you guys get down to Northern
California ring me up I mean I live in
red way okay yeah we would love that
we're coming right on through we're
doing our dragonfly earth medicine 2018
love tour we're coming to visit
everybody and give hugs and Cher flower
and share a fun time so we'd love to
come by and see ya be great yeah I got a
45 acre spot the Moto River runs along
the edge of it the Moto Indian tribe is
across the river then on Friday and
Saturday night so it's not too cold or
in climate they chant and drum which is
pretty cosmic and it sounds awesome 300
foot tall trees all around the house and
this land was never logged because it
was too close to the Indian Reservation
so they left it alone right out the
front door I've got three hundred sixty
nine foot tall redwood and it's very
commanding and it's very quiet spot I
mean the nearest neighbor I suppose if
you had to eat would throw a hammer over
there if you're really strong but
they're about a thousand feet away
otherwise it's quiet it's
sounds awesome we're on the Sunday
before emerald-cut we're gonna be at up
at alpenglow farms at Craig's house and
ladies there's even the whole humble
high five family and lots of people
there in southern Humboldt so well yeah
we'll get your number through Marcus and
get in touch and stuff so that will give
you a let you know what's going on yeah
you might find it in a peaceful spot to
visit it's bad it sounds amazing it just
for the trees and the river and
everything I mean I love nothing more
than those and we love red were detected
good people good place that roadway yeah
it's a good spot it's quiet you know I I
appreciate being here because it's a
real gift to be able to be and plus I
live alone on this whole thing my sons
live down in Santa Rosa so I'm always
open to visitors because it's just me
the Chihuahua and Roby my parent would
just laid three eggs on my pillow a
couple nights ago I'm gonna looks like
I'm going to ask some other parrots but
yeah it's quiet nice and plays awesome
yes I've got some some this right here
Rasen I've got 40 grams of it and it is
it's this tangerine so nerdy slow cross
snorts people we were just [ __ ] on
some sour tangi that was grown here in
town that's just like really beautiful
straight but now that you show us that
we're for sure I don't know what the
glass because like Sam you know the road
to doing Deb's it's covered in broken
glass so make sure you bring along a
dabbing right that's that's why it's
important to just buy like a five or a
ten thousand dollar pipe so you're just
very very careful with it and you take
good care to not break it we're gonna
get we'll get one of those from little
Bobby Snodgrass yeah we're a noise when
you
when you're going to be traveling with a
Snodgrass clan so we'll be coming with
glass and tow for sure for real yeah
it's not grass families coming to the
Emerald count too this year so and I'll
I I do I somebody broke my last one I
need a study in my collection badly okay
a fantastic pipe but I keep it wrapped
up and put away because the last time I
had it out put me with it
they literally dropped it if it wasn't
for my superior hand-eye coordination
that card it so I don't bring it on
anymore except for Malone they know that
I'm not gonna break it please that
relatively sure this year there's the
Bob Snodgrass award so the Emerald cup
is instilling a Bob Snodgrass award
they're gonna be there at the very front
of the hall of flowers they're going to
be going down with us and hanging out in
the teepee and etienne will be getting
in touch with you for sure got that
covered and also um Carolyn Garcia's
speaking this year and stuff as she's
super excited and yeah we're just really
excited to link up with the family and
have a good time
Grateful Dead families you know hanging
hanging tough they're still on it I like
any drew that for them in their kitchen
on the pieces of a Grateful Dead
stationary on the back way back when in
the day in the day that sounds sweet
yeah well you have to share that story
with Carolyn when you meet her when you
see her and at the show yeah I'm hoping
that she'll come from so last year she
had a triple embolism in her brain and
she woke up surviving and in good
feelings and stuff but she woke up in
1998 and she doesn't remember anything
from 1998 forward till now which is
pretty much our whole relationship and
it's so I don't know she'll come I keep
kind of talked her into it but she's
very hesitant
she sort of treats me like an insurance
salesman on the second call these days
when I talk to her because he just
doesn't remember I can't fault her for I
can't pressure I can't push her all I
can do is just give her support and
that's what I do maybe she'll show up it
would be a great blessing if that
happened because I'm gonna have on a
trailer there a unit that you can pull
into the field harvest and extract in
real time and it's for me it's like you
know a big achievement and I would love
her to be there and see it but she
doesn't really remember me so not much
I'm gonna be able to do about that check
we go forward from here that's it
brother that's it well I think I'm gonna
call it a day here after hanging out for
two and a half hours with all you
wonderful people and just enjoying a
Sunday morning it's been a while since
we had church I was definitely you know
into the conversation I liked that we
talked a little bit about hemp today and
we'll see where that's going in the next
couple of years here in North America I
will just keep on keepin on I do wish I
could be at the Emerald cup I look
forward to all of your social media
posts and whatnot of all the people that
will be there all the little videos and
all the little photos I hope you guys
have a great time
Kuban enjoy puffing on that hash wish I
could be there puffing it with you but a
last brother will have to do it in
another country sometime soon everyone
else Daniel D for 20 K at T is Gotham
and Sam Indra dr. mark shelled own and
Wade thank you all for coming in I
really appreciate it well maybe we'll
see you guys in the near future
perfect thank you Marcus I guess my dog
barking no I can't hear that
[Laughter]
peace out everybody