record on this
computer all right let's go live to
YouTube all right this meeting is being
live streamed got it all right so what
do we say we say welcome welcome
everybody this is uh episode 25 of hash
Church
3.0 so let me just put that I need to
copy and paste the new link and then go
over to our old link and let it everyone
know we are now
live with skunkman Sam it's been a 100
days almost a hundred days since the
last time we did a hash church if you
can imagine it was a bit of a long break
I know that everyone's been busy doing
all sorts of different things and uh I
just thought it was a good time to throw
one been talking a lot with Addison
Deora and the 800 pounds Mantra these
guys are throwing the legends of hash
dinner down in California and I thought
well let's do a little hash church we
can talk about that a little bit maybe
talk about some past Legends of hashes
and really most importantly just to see
your smiling faces well your puppet Sam
and etan's smiling face I hope you're
doing well eten how are
you that's what's up doing good I'm
doing well sir uh I've been working hard
with my veterans Action Council dude
I've been seeing you all over the place
it's been awesome yeah we had had a
wonderful conversation with gome Chomsky
last Friday which dude I saw
that just crazy I I watched that bro
manufacturing consent was one of my
favorite books back in the day that [ __ ]
is no joke yeah one of our members
Ricardo pra uh basically went to one of
his classes there in Arizona at the
college and um he's one of our members
so he asked him and he said yeah so we
were very fortunate to have that
discussion and literally we spent some
time crafting the questions because we
didn't want to come off um you know not
prepared gnome chsky bro gnome Chomsky I
know it's have you read manufacturing
consent of course
dude I mean I've been reading gnome
since I was
teenager so to actually sit down and
have a conversation with him was
humbling beyond all measure but it also
validated our work that we're doing at
the national and international level I'm
working with Michael crowz I actually
spoke at the UN in April and uh we're
preparing to go to Vienna uh in the
spring as well as we're preparing for a
Lobby day in Washington DC so we vets
are really putting on the pressure
really trying to put the US VA system
and the Canadian VA system together
because we want what you have in Canada
which is the access as the availability
to literally order on your cell phone
right now and have your medicine within
three days you get a rating per certain
amount of grams per day so I won't go
all into it I see we've got our other
guest in here but uh yeah needless to
say we're doing a lot of good work for
veterans internationally and they're
welcome to join us at veterans action
council.com
we're going to get back to it and talk
more about it later because I I just got
to tell you man and obviously you've
been doing this for your whole life
everything that has led you to this but
I I'm really proud of you man it's it it
makes me happy to see you out there
shining helping people in the most
incredible way I know what you do is not
light for the people that you do it this
is life or death [ __ ] for these guys
this is not light re you know side
reading so you know we're all proud of
you etan you're [ __ ] awesome you're
inspirational and uh it's great it's
great to see you and hear from you again
uh here's here's Johnny B in the grow
room looking like a goddamn
hippie oh yeah yeah I I just said I was
never gonna cut my hair put the
headphones in I've been working away
this morning good morning everybody
happy hash
Sunday happy hash Sunday yeah let's
welcome Kevin and Addison from uh 800
pound Mantra these are uh well you guys
know Addison he's been on hash Church
plenty of times um his history you guys
have seen him from screaming at DEA
agents out in front of uh dispensaries
into you know founding the company steep
hill and you know now uh has a bunch of
really cool stuff that they're going to
tell us about uh today as well as we
kind of welcome everyone and yeah
welcome guys welcome Kevin welcome
Addison welcome Edie Mark in here up
guys what's up how's it
going good to see you everybody
nice to meet you guys yeah man good to
be seen good to be seen good to be seen
good to be seen it's good to have a hash
church I'm not going to lie I've been
watching all these Zoom things happen
like at T with Nome Chomsky on the zoom
meeting and I was kind of like d like
gotta step it up we got this platform
here you know anytime you guys feel that
you want to do a hash Church hit me up
it's kind of spur the moment I know that
I hit you guys up last minute and I do
thank all of you for showing up uh
welcome Dr Mark with the fish shirt
guy's just been crushing [ __ ] fish
shows left right and Center every time I
look at his Facebook it's either his
daughter going off to college or him
[ __ ] tripping balls at a fish show
with all his amazing friends so good for
you buddy like good for
you you know at live music large live
music events again kind of I don't know
it was it was strange in many ways but
you know yeah it was great great to be
back
great to be back here too
awesome hell yeah good to have you back
here dude good good to have best friend
farms in the house I know you got
chopped over at Instagram there recently
do you want to give your new Instagram
account
up oh yeah thank you uh back up on best
friend Farm space
2.0 uh the second version here so thanks
for shouting that out I already I
already I already saw you posted what
did you post like some crazy [ __ ]
like it was like this this Dome of hash
covered in like grease or something like
I I didn't even I just caught it really
quick your last post like right back to
it oh that one today
yeah yeah that one I just did this
morning uh before this was some some
flower R and that was that uh gas mask
Shi I just kind of whipped it up and
played with it before the before the
show dude Callie Callie nice to be here
presenting East Coast that's what you
are dude you're like the Cali dude
that's just like on the East Coast
crushing it so we're happy to have you
of course we're GNA be talking a little
bit about Legends of hash today on the
show we got Addison and uh oh did I
freeze out he froze okay now that Marcus
is gone I'm taking over the
show thank God thank you Sam wait that
wasn't
Marcus whoops
you know what I'll be honest I have
starlink and every once in a while
starlink just glitches for about like
five five 10 seconds otherwise it's
incredible shout out to Elon Musk for
putting satellites out into space and
creating the internet where you know I
live in an area that doesn't have good
internet so when he first put up his
first 2,000 satellites he put it up into
an area where a lot of indigenous people
live a lot of people that live that
don't have access that's where he put up
the first thousand or so and so I guess
he's eventually going to get to 60,000
uh eventually he'll eliminate cell phone
services because everything will be
WhatsApp and Wi-Fi calling because
you'll have Wi-Fi literally everywhere
you go in the world kind of scary kind
of awesome I figured I'd get on the beta
and support someone who's thinking
outside of the box because uh I don't
know I really appreciate thinking
outside of the box uh that's that's my
trip kind of all of our trips if we all
stayed within the Box we all wouldn't be
here
correct no exactly we're trying to get
the star get the office we're trying to
get the star link at the office for 800
because we have terrible internet over
there so and we have no good
options actually you don't need a box
anymore because the most pot is seedless
you needed a box when you wanted to uh
you know clean your seeds out of your
weed but those days are gone no you're
right I fought for a long time to get
out of the box so I'm glad to be on this
side for
sure definitely I got to uh I'm gonna
take a dab
guys I was just thinking we need to take
a dab I'm already heated up fellas I
don't know okay I'm getting to my dab D
I got an I got an email in so I'm
already heated up
too we've got the octaves and the uh and
and you know regular quartz nails but
the octaves where it's at shout out to P
shout out to P nail those are great
shout out to Dil I got my I got my
denail P nail combo going right now and
shout out to Mother Ship for the eggs I
have a dabinator which I can honestly
say has been plugged in and on for the
last three years I never turn it off yes
dude I you know what shout out shout out
to Max amillion from dabinator because
honestly I kept my I actually helped Sam
get his dabinator through Max because
Max is such a [ __ ] awesome guy but
when I first got mine and I don't I
finally killed mine but it took me
almost four
years left it on pretty much every
single day and when Sam says he's left
his on every single day I can promise
you I bet you
that or it's probably rusted into place
because it's never been used uh I've
also took it to Jamaica with me and it
works fine with uh Jamaican electricity
and you could even use it with
motorcycle
battery so how did you keep it on on the
way to Jamaica on the yeah exactly on
the plugged into a cigarette lighter no
I'm joking I didn't have it on it was in
my
suitcase aha so there's proof that
you're full of
[ __ ] no I haven't been in Jamaica in
three years think about
it they don't want you putting that
stuff in your suitcase you're supposed
to carry it on Checkmate that was
good dude come on as if I would ever get
one over on
Sam is completely clean them first
spotless all right everybody's G to tell
us what their smoking so we can't just
uh it's show and tell
time cookies and
hash R forcing me to move upstairs hold
on I got some muted
Kevin we got some Grease Monkey 9120
press get you so [ __ ]
lit I got the
73 90 press of the medic cush it's trips
on this is 7.6
got the
uh got some
resin resin this is the
90u uh fresh press that uh looks like
it's actually this is whipped but this
is some glue oh my
goodness and jam oh I got some ra and
diamonds yeah I got some Z with the KX
this
is garlic some uh I've actually been
liting this cold cure after I did the
the Diamond separation for about four
weeks and just going to send it off
testing see what
happen look at that what's up Collins
nice J yeah man good to see
you how's everyone doing nice getting
high Colin I'm loving that synth setup
in the back there
bu I'm I'm digging Dr Mark's pup setup
over here on the
dude that dog is
[Laughter]
awesome yeah that dog his [ __ ] his
skin is so thin you can see his
pinkness look at that belly that's
what's up it's like pude and what you've
been coming to Hash church for seven
years with those SNS behind you I've
never heard you hit a
key well uh we can change that anytime
you want um these I can turn them on
maybe maybe towards the end maybe
towards the end you and Dr Mark can
recreate the hash church song we can do
space we'll do our version of
space I like it I like it I like it um I
like for yeah for for many years
so you know today's hash church was
really sort of inspired by um well it
was really inspired by Addison reaching
out about a month ago maybe more maybe
less I have no idea I have three
children
um he reached out he was like dude like
what the [ __ ] like what about Legends
like what are you gonna like should we
do a Legends in California I was like
dude I mean obviously does the bear [ __ ]
in the woods and uh I did find out that
indeed um the bear does [ __ ] in the
woods I'm not sure if you guys have seen
this but uh yeah it's been proven guys
the bear does [ __ ] in the woods right
there that's proof I need a I need a
picture of
talking I need a picture of the Pope
[ __ ] in the woods that's the other
one I
need that's a good oh yeah does the pope
[ __ ] in the woods there you go the pope
represents Faith but drives around in a
bulletproof vehicle enough said God
willing who's he really trust so anyway
we started yeah exactly he doesn't trust
anyone um so we started talking about it
you know he he's you know and for me I
wasn't avidly searching Legends has
always been the most organic thing and
for those of you that are living under a
rock and don't know what Legends of hash
is and maybe Sam I would love to hear
your perspective as well because I bet
you we have slightly different memories
or perspectives of how it came to be but
from my sense I kind of remember sitting
around with you at your place and and
Rob probably was there um Michael
definitely wasn't there I don't think
for the first conversation but we sort
of started talking about you know well I
think it started really with Sam talking
about how he'd been at every Cannabis
Cup from day one and that him and Rob
always got gifted tickets from Hagar and
they would show up at everyone and kind
of walk
around kind of talking a little bit
about some of the stuff we didn't like
about it you know it was always it was
always a cool thing to bash on high
times for whatever reason even though at
the time it was the only gig in town and
really it was amazing you know the fact
that they pulled off what they pulled
off it was amazing and it was really
also the birth of Legends because we
sort of I remember us talking like hey
like if we could just get the best kind
of 50 hash afficionados out of this
group of I don't know how many went to
the cup like a thousand or 2,000 people
maybe between a, and 1500 in those early
days I don't really remember uh and for
me it became a metaphor of like yeah
let's run all these people through the
Bubble Bags filter out all the 220s and
the 190s and the 160s and we'll just
collect a party of 90 I just want 50 90
Micron people at this party and uh is
that how you remember the first
conversation going Sam or what's your
memory of it I I remember that uh our
Focus was really can people didn't have
to be
necessarily maker in the very very
beginning
canvas industry you know and you were a
heavyweight and uh appreciated smoking
then you got an invite because it was
Invitation
Only it definitely wasn't the first year
that I was asking to see people's hashes
that Modified by the second or third
year I it turned into this like you know
because we had this incredible group of
people in there the first year it was
really an amazing group of people truly
like
it's almost sad that we didn't have just
one person videographing and have that
tape locked in a vault somewhere because
to open that in 30 or 40
years would have really been something
uh incredible to leave behind but at the
time for you know of various reasons uh
we and we've always stuck with this that
cameras just should not be allowed um at
Legends in Barcelona the last year uh I
did allow one guy to come in to
videograph and we controlled those audio
and videos and there was no you know
everyone was let know at the known at
the door it kind of got to the point too
where you know cannabis is becoming more
and more legal and there's less and less
illegal activity you know in the first
years you know there were some people
that that moved large amounts of hash
that ended up at the party and in
respect to them because not that you
know me and Sam were smoking on that
hash or whatever but it was important
that that hash went to where it needed
to go and it was important that those
people that would smoke that hash like I
was talking to Addison earlier on the
different you know compounds that we
consume and if you read Michael Poland's
newest book uh this is your mind on
plants or this is your brain on Plants
great yeah great book caffeine and he
goes all into the I liked when he talked
about how conversations were created
that shaped the world after work beers
at the bar turned into tea houses and
caffeine coffee coffee houses new people
intellectuals started having different
conversations in those environments and
those conversations started to shape the
world and now you know what Legends
could potentially really become and
maybe it even was a little bit back in
the day is to have an event where real
chusy people hashish people get together
and now in rooms where we're allowed to
get together it's not illegal and we can
have conversations that now shape the
future future world that we're going to
leave to our children and that [ __ ]
excites me and that's why when you hit
me up Addison and has this not just been
super easy too Addison like has this
been difficult has there been like lots
of obstacles or is to me it's just felt
really flowing and smooth you know
everything you guys keep bringing to the
table I've talked enough why don't you
and Kevin uh mention a little bit about
your perspective on this and the plan
for Legends of hash California one
definitely thank you man um I think
first thing to speak to what you just
said one of the things that I think
nowadays is that we all have phones
those phones are cameras and bringing
the whole tradition of not having phones
or cameras is is something that I think
is really important we're allowed to do
what we do but technically to throw this
event in California we're not allowed to
do it so it's still kind of at that not
allowed phase in that place and that's
why that's why we have to outwardly
build this thing as a dinner which I
think though adds to all of adds to what
makes this thing so great and makes it
so unique compared to any other event
you're never told I mean most of these
guys these makers um you know they're
they're sort of been if it was Legends
they were being invited because they had
the hash what we tried to incorporate
here is when we invite a maker your plus
one we we recommend that your plus one
is either the breeder or the farmer and
that way we're putting everybody in the
room together on this one and and we're
also now Marcus and I were talking
earlier and it's like hash makers are
awesome you know they're forensic
they're guys that are doing forensic
work that are separating things and and
able to like really get it down to the
point where it's pure where it's
completely isolated that's that's hard
work but in order for them to do their
job they can't do it without great
material it's just it's how many people
are coming to your event do you have any
idea yes so we have I'll break it down
real quick there's 25 makers those
makers each get a plus one which will be
either the farmer or the breeder then
there's 20 guests that are industry you
know people that we think those 20
makers would benefit from being in the
room with industry guys guys that are
hash that are hash guys guys that are
literally legitimately have a reason to
be in the room with them whether it's
you know being in the room with uh Brian
from vital Garden Supply which is one of
you know Brian has put more organic
inputs into the Cannabis Supply
production for California than probably
most people over the years we just want
them to be a room full of guys like that
so those 20 will be those type of cats
not necessarily influencers but just
people who have really lent to the
production of good material good hash
and and a lot of guys too that have
of one before but we're we're hoping
that there's going to be more of these
and we want to just get that those those
acers to be guys that might have not
been invited the 20 are people that are
pretty much you know industry guys that
really should be there and then we have
15 spaces um that are that are staff and
uh sponsorship so that's where we're
kind of fitting fitting that all
together putting it together so it'll be
85 people total
um lebanes dinner it's going to be uh
you know I knew that this thing was I
knew that this thing was green lit and
by the culture and everyone else when I
reached out to deppy and I invited him
as a guest and deppy came back and was
like well we want to do a Mothership
drop during your event um so now what's
cool is he's he's producing glass that's
specifically designed and and and sort
of the Aesthetics he did a he did a
series called um uh Botanicals which was
a series that kind of not did a nod back
to to Hash which was kind of cool
solventless hash now he's going to
incorporate chemistry with Botanicals
and they're going to do that drop at
Legends which is kind of cool so
specifically for hash makers kind of um
he was pretty stoked about it so it's
it's I knew that it was going to be
something different uh as soon as we got
his Blessing and as soon as we started
to see uh you know the the the biggest
guys that we reached out to I I was
calling everyone we wanted to keep keep
this thing in line with Legends and I
figured you know in my mind I'm like
what would Marcus do would Marcus would
Marcus send you an email with all the
information in it probably not I was
like Marcus would would just message you
and be like I need to give do a call
with you you know like an old drug deal
so we wanted to make sure that every one
of the contacts that go on for Legends
is just like an old drug deal it's a
phone call you know it's it's a hey bro
if I text you just call this number back
so everything's done in in line with the
old way and it's like a phone call uh no
cameras no phones we're making sure that
uh you know it's secretive in that sense
we're making sure that anyone talks
about it talks about it as a dinner so
it's cloaked in that original sort of
secret you know how it was back in the
day which I think is helping the event a
bunch because um it it's just kind of
making people understand that it's an
exclusive event that it's that it's
invite only um and that it's going to be
a celebration of hashes you know we
wanted to this year incorporate after
Afghanistan as the cultural sort of
focus for it with what's going on there
and I think it's a good time to kind of
to to let everybody know that the United
States is gonna get a bunch of Afghan
refugees uh a bunch of people from
Afghanistan and hopefully we get some
guys that make great hash that we can uh
that can come and show us and teach us
some other cool stuff so um yeah it's
it's G to be an event that or not even
an event it's a dinner we're we're
really just honored to be able to put it
on and and there's not a day goes by
that I I don't wake up and be like all
right is this going to fall apart today
you know is this going to and and it
it's done the complete opposite every
person that's wanted to be involved has
reached out um we've got big guys behind
it that want to help with it and it was
really hard for us to kind of figure out
how to pay for it how to take care of it
because we don't want to bring in just
any sponsor um but it is a dinner it is
you know when we when we've gone to
other events and we've seen other things
uh what's going on we just looked at it
uh one of the big conversations that
Marcus and I had was you know how do you
take Legends which has been so secretive
and so protected and bring it out to the
public now and put it into a
recreational State how do you do that
you know and it's like well there's
certain components that have to transfer
and one of them is going to be you know
it has to be marketed in some way it has
to be we want to eventually open this
thing up to a larger Community uh and be
able to allow people to sort of enjoy
hashish at the same level and
appreciation for hashish at level may
never be at like the geeked out you know
nerdy level that we are at but at the
same time to educate them on hash and to
get them open to like what the [ __ ] is
Hash you know I I I talk to some people
and they think hash is like opium or
something they don't even [ __ ] know
like they they still to this day are
like oh that's weed mixed with Heroin
right and I'm like what the [ __ ] are you
talking about so the broader public
really doesn't understand you know what
hash is about me and Marcus talked about
it and and the big picture the big dream
would be to throw a massive hash event
in California recreationally legal and
invite all kinds of people and educate
them and then within that event on one
of the nights we we tuck Legends into
that night because now we've got
everyone there we can bring you know
glass culture everything to this and
then at some point now you know I was
thinking Marcus can finally monetize
this thing and actually take it to other
places and build something so other
people can start to enjoy it because
weed's legal now it's not illegal it's
not what it used to be and it's not like
uh you know in some places we still have
brothers that are you know sitting
behind bars we still have brothers that
are that are you know having to duck and
run but we all know the fun of the duck
and run like I I I honestly in a lot of
ways miss the duck and run days of of
hammering it and and you know the bank
of the earth and all this cool [ __ ] that
we lived a part of um nowadays it's like
you know we can [ __ ] legally do [ __ ]
and it's sort of some of the taste has
been taken out of it so um I don't know
I think this we want to keep this so
that taste is still there but then at
the same time how the [ __ ] do you bring
this thing to the bigger public there's
a lot of nerves and kind of doing that
so um love that you I love that you guys
are connecting it to the Farms that it's
really all about like let's get hash
cultiv ours like where all these new
people in Cali and old folks that have
been growing forever that produce
something really special one year where
can we put that where it's on display
and gets the attention it deserves to
get by the people that it needs to get
from so not only is it promoting
promoting hash makers and and the love
of hash but of course the root which is
you know that organic regenerative
biodynamic farmer who's producing and
loving this resin into being and they
you know it's all just like a really we
never did that at Legends it was always
kind of individuals and Independence and
you could even go buy great hah if you
wanted to uh you know end up at a legend
you know if you had what was nice about
Legends what was nice about Legends was
because it was in Amsterdam at the high
times we had such an international
selection of people it it I mean except
for there was a lot of Canadians there
more than anybody I'm joking mostly
Californians and then
Canadians oh yeah dude it was awesome it
was I remember literally counting people
from over 20 countries at a Legends
dinner yeah like there's people
representing for from so many countries
right now and uh you know one thing I
will say about Legends as well is I I
never left the Legends and got the
Cannabis co uh
cough that was always uh at other places
so no but there were several times when
the uh uh restaurant arti the Lebanese
restaurant where we used to hold the
event was so filled with smoke that I
had to go outside and breathe some fresh
air yeah yeah I know that was
gnarly that wobbly is uh that that thing
is unlike anything I've ever hit in my
entire life I remember that I waited
every time I went I would wait as long
as I could to hit that thing because I
knew that after I hit it it was just
[ __ ] space used to blow my mind where
was that girl from Denmark or something
that used to Marcus that used to hit on
it like crazy oh she even lit a few for
us that's right oh my God I almost
forgot about her she was from Denmark
that's
right unbelievable listen it wasn't just
that Hubbly Bubbly either Addison it was
it was it was Sam's hash like that hash
is not normal and it wasn't back then
even when I had already been smoking
full m and I felt like oh yeah dude I
know what quality is I went to his house
and the first time I smoked a bowl of
his cash and I'm [ __ ] you not this
is not a lie I literally got so high so
fast I I was like oh no what if I [ __ ]
myself or vomit or I just went through
all these crazy thoughts and then he fed
me like 20 more no joke while he himself
took
50 like over the course of a couple
hours I left that guy's house so [ __ ]
up in my head I was just
like I remember Rob saying like oh yeah
I was really stoned last night I was
like I mean how stoned could you be Rob
I mean come on what did you eat like an
ounce of resin and then I found myself
in that position walking home from Sam's
one late night in Amsterdam and just
being absolutely floored at how strong
that man hash was and then of course I'm
like oh okay so he went and lived in the
hash producing country collected the
seeds grew hundreds of thousands to pick
the varieties bred them with his Savant
like capabilities then processed them
with his own [ __ ] incredible
processing methods uh that's a full meal
deal that's like a a full house if it's
the deck of cards I remember to Marcus
that the first couple events it was
mostly my house we were smoking then
everybody started bringing better and
better and better especially with water
has that's what really changed the world
first water has came in and and really
lots of people had really high quality
water hash and then it just kept growing
growing and growing and
growing which you could also tell based
on on Sam's level of utter and complete
snobbery it was like at a level back
then that was like you couldn't even
[ __ ] imagine it it was palpable he
would just not smoke anyone's hash he
would only smoke his own hash I would
smoke anybody's hash I would smoke
anybody's that was as good or better
than mine and there wasn't any is what
I'm saying back back back I know that
you were just fing your own I was like
this [ __ ] won't take like a hit
of my five
star oh I wish I had po the
seven could you imagine Marcus if if um
there was a selection of hash from each
of the legends that would have been put
away and saved stored cryogenically for
uh for someday to come out and get
smoked could you imagine I mean that's
that would have been better than any
footage of anything I think just the
taste do it at California 1 at the first
annual California Legends you can do
that very thing this is what happens you
get together with your
friends what you need to do is put put a
kilo away of each of the winners it's
it's gonna be tough
yeah Kevin I think we just raed we're
gonna need a kilo and 40 grams to make
this thing sorry guys kilo and a 40 gr
but I mean thinking of that like that
like a hash ball like that would be
incredible and the Legends you know
event really could uh I guarantee if you
keep it from oxygen and you freeze it
and you keep it out of the light and it
does not change in a decade or two
really or if changes so little you could
barely notice it
even well built root seller would store
it very well
too a freezer 1 years old
because tpin dissipate you know you've
got to freeze tpin or you
lose 13 years old how's
that wow what batch is that
from that's from Master
Kush oh you can't even believe how good
it smells it's been at room temperature
for 13 years really and it still turine
rich
dude I'm telling you listen I remember
when I smoked the whatever that 91 year
batch was from the you know that that
that Michael had that was like 10 years
and then 13 and 16 I think the last time
I hit it it was like 19 or 20 and it had
no taste whatsoever like it was stale
all the heads were this is the
opposite yeah yeah red too oh dude I
have pictures of it trust me this is the
exact same way but instead of powder
it's this is 13 years
oldy yep it's incredible that's so red
like isn't that [ __ ]
crazy sorry I'm doing a shitty job on
getting the camera to focus on
it no I could you could it looks like
looks like I tried that what three years
ago and it was
far I take dude didn't it taste like
perfume John yeah like I said it tastes
like like old
PK how could these tpes still be present
after that
long
heav interesting to
see what Andoid which are less volatile
there's probably no merine left but I
bet you you got hashen and probably
other degraded Tes part it would be
really interesting to see the entire
tpine profile and
percentages originally and today yeah oh
wow look at you good Lord look at that
that's
aged this is from dragonfly Earth
medicine's farm this is the Mendo breath
bubble and it when you light it and
exhale it it literally tastes and smells
like a beautiful like natural perfume in
the air almost Jasmine like but not
Jasmine interesting oh my God and this
is also like ah they must have given
this to me like a year or two
ago so
nice if we're gonna talk about hash we
might as well see some hey Colin how do
you uh how do you store those those 12
grams every time so I break them up and
I induction seal the jars and then I put
those into into you know you know uh a
minus 40 freezer and keep them there and
I take them out one at a time as I need
and you know per H how's your uh how's
your collection looking what do you got
there oh boy I've got a lot here um I've
got some California Orange Bud here that
I'm trying right now I've got some c99
here to the right um some uh some
GMO
um got there's watermelon zum zom
as well there's a bunch there's like
over 100 different varietal that I have
that I have kept
and California Orange you have is it
citrusy yes it is Sam it's the it's the
Eric 77 cut
actually that's a rare one 877 cut or if
that's if the kids are even calling it
that these
days many people have told me that I
made a hybrid with skunk number one and
California Orange two of my favorite
indicia sativa hybrids back in the
80s and uh that's what I've been told
Tangi was selected
from I think that's the same cut Sam
Actually I think it's the California
Orange that that's uh that's the
surviving cut might be that same one Sam
from what I understand that's it's
believed to be that yeah because not all
California Orange was uh citrusy uh some
of them were barely citry and some of
them were really pronounced citry and
those are the ones I liked yeah this is
that was yeah that's the one Shanty Baba
had Shanty Baba had the super citrusy
one and he had like a multi-acre
greenhouse in bellan Zona in the south
of Switzerland and I remember walking
into it and they were all about six to
seven feet tall Christmas trees Citrus
had my eyes watering because I was
literally crying it was one of the most
beautiful things I'd ever seen I asked
him right away I said how who grew these
plants this is incredible then he told
me it was their first year growing them
and they were the local Swiss Rose
gardeners that he just took and said
okay listen this is just like roses
except uh instead of thorns it's a resin
that you can get in your eyes so don't
rub your eyes while you're working on
the plant and these [ __ ] Rose
gardeners just crushed it like I could
not believe it shout out to Shanti Baba
and his Rose Garder crew in Bellona
2001 and welcome
Josh and
Josh dragonfly regenerative welcome guys
sorry we got to welcome these guys
they've been here for a while and we're
just talking over them terrible people
who grow the resin that we love oh my
goodness
I
have hey good morning everyone glad to
hear about the legends of hash and
everything that's going on you know who
doesn't like hash you know and Rosen if
Frenchie was here he would tell us rosin
is not hash so I have to bring that into
the into the onto the table I I I would
say the same
thing we we included in the Legends for
this year say what rosin is not hash but
hash rosin is Hash rosin yeah so we we
included Rosen into res into uh the
Legends for uh California 1 nice I I I
would let rosin into any contest because
technically it's not old school hash for
sure but it can be just as clean as
potent and as beautiful and tpping rich
as any of the dry sit I ever made in my
life we let it in because of how it
makes us
feel are you uh requiring that it's only
hash rosin or you letting letting flower
stuff in um no they get to they can
select either melt or rosin so it's
their choice if they want to do flower
rosin they're more than welcome to um we
don't really see a bunch of guys that
are doing flower rosin it's mainly it's
all gone to um hash rosin at this point
but um yeah I mean it's it's we wanted
to incorporate the grower on this one
for the main reason that when I got into
cannabis it it I was a grower at first
and I grew some plants and I didn't
become a hash maker till I became a
grower and it was that lifestyle of
hiding in there and you know trimming my
own [ __ ] and I'd get the finger has then
then i' Mark I was Mark's rep for bubble
bags in uh Northern California when I
was a sales rep in the snowboard
industry and that's how Mark and I met
so I was running around meeting people
at snowboard shops and at night I'd come
home from being a rep and I'd work my
grow room and i' you know Saturday I'd
make hash and [ __ ] you know so we
wanted to make sure that the grower was
there because we feel like there
wouldn't be a hash maker without the
grower it wouldn't exist and some of us
the way we got into it was through that
door was through like that lonely lify
you know also too for for resin there's
actually dry shift rosin there's water
has rosin there's fresh frozen rosin
there's from plant so I mean it just
goes on and on but uh to me it's all
good if at the end you like it yeah hey
somebody can blast and you know what
this
isn't this isn't an Instagram post this
isn't for clout this is just for how it
makes you feel and wouldn't it be
amazing at some crazy Legend dinner if
someone came in with hash r or flower
rosin and SM mashed everyone off the
we're open to that I'm open you got to
chuckle to exactly you got to be open to
anything or I even think I think hash
makers out there make sure that doesn't
happen maybe I mean I think if someone
enters with with real sift like actual
sift quality made sift instead of melt
instead of some of these other things I
think that's something a lot of people
don't see is actual sift like you know
[ __ ] you can look at SI long enough
and it turns to [ __ ] melt that's how
sensitive that [ __ ] is so it's you're
talking the purest of the pure and when
I talk to a lot of people they don't
know they're like oh yeah sift and I'm
like that's not sift like that's sift is
so different you know like someone could
slap you in the face with CFT and you
would just be happy no matter what
because there's something about CFT
compared to any of those other moves
like like you know Dave was saying it's
it's just I'm really I'm excited and we
did this in a way because where I would
I would be blown away if I saw real sift
and someone brings that to the table I
hope they do and I'd be blown away if
someone does actually turn heads with
flower rosin not that it can't be done
it's just I think the cultivar has to be
specific the grower has to be specific
um in order to make it happen you know
can I ask this question it might be a
little little off but this is a good
panel of folks to ask because I'm I'm
not as experienced in hash as all you
folks um I'm a grower but uh do you see
difference in in hash made with made
sensia versus Mia um with seeds you know
I'm breing so I have a lot of pollen
flying around no
absolutely it's it's not as good it's
not as it could still be great but the
turpine levels are the are down by about
25% or more and the uh canono can be
slightly down and there's less yield for
the plant of course sure because you're
making
seeds we had we had I had done a bunch I
mean I've been doing a lot of this
because I have a lot of pollen flying so
it's kind of like only thing I can do is
to to to make process it that way and it
ends up coming out really good I mean
compare it's not like the [ __ ] stuff
that you're G to remember for the rest
of your life but it's good A minus
quality stuff and I put on the market
and people are you know really happy
about and and I've actually had some
people come up to me and be be curious
like you know something extra that's
getting me high in there and that's why
I asked because I smoke so much goddamn
I don't have sense to pet you know you
do understand that all of the important
sifted hash in the world is from seed
plants right right
right of
course makes sense but those but those
those entries are not generally winning
sure either you know it's my whole brain
has really gotten onto this in the last
like two months I've been thinking a lot
about hash because I am breeding and
when I have someone process my material
I lose 50% 40% of my work and so I've
been I finally got myself a freeze dryer
and I was like holy [ __ ] it dawned on me
I just what you guys were talking about
I could store this stuff freeze dried
and sell it and hold it you know I could
do a big run of this one thing that's
really cool right now and save the whole
thing or half whatever and and 10 years
later open that up and be like yo I got
some GMO anybody
doing it you know on a bigger level
where you're bringing in super highend
producers and washers and um being able
to you know hold it that
way yeah it's crazy it's it's the where
it's gone too like just looking at it
from we get the we get the privilege to
visit all these facilities and we're
going into them and and my favorite part
is when you walk through their setup and
my second or probably my favorite part
is when they bring you to the freezer
and they open that freezer and you're
looking
at400 $500,000 worth of [ __ ] melt
like jars massive and everyone has this
this is you know and and we joke about
it we're like oh that's actually where
their money is it's in that freezer that
they've got stored there but the other
the other nutty part is when you walk
through their processing areas and I can
sit there and and it's Marcus's you know
those those kokos those these machines
these [ __ ] freeze dryers all this new
equipment that you see wasn't here
before and now it's like finally Nick
can have dry hash right like you know
it'll be
dry available and uh uh the fact that
it's not cheap to produce this stuff
like some of the big stuff at Whistler
Tech is insane you know we're trying to
get to get us a large machine just to
have at the event or something you know
so people can be like what the [ __ ]
because this thing is gone so far I can
see behind you like the dehydrators it's
just there's so much that's now here and
present for guys to be able to you know
process and and it's it's I like
California you can have six plants right
you could take those six plants you can
you can flower that year your six plants
you could take that flower you could
sell all of it I always joke that like
you could move move a you can move a box
and [ __ ] open a a solventless lab
well that's that's where that's where my
brain was going because I'm paying all
these people to process I'm paying all
these people and I'm like wait a sec I I
have you know a couple big 30 by 96 I
run the whole thing by myself and I'm
like I could hire a crew to come in for
five days bring it down and if I got a
big machine like Marcus's or the
Whistler Tech um I could watch the whole
goddamn thing in three or four days by
myself and then I'm done you know and
I've wrapped up I saved some for
long-term storage and I can sell a
little bit and move on I was just like
holy [ __ ] dude then you could at least
you could rent out your machine too
right once I've seriously put a ton of
time into this I've just been wanting to
call you on it you know but um it would
change my game entirely as as a breeder
because then I can just focus on my
plants you know and I can and I can sip
through everything and melt really easy
and like God damn it I took me a long
time to get here I feel kind of stupid
because I was
actually you know but um I just kind
took a break on it for years because of
it sorry I didn't hear now you can breed
specifically for hash dumping totally
I'm been working on that yeah for sure
man and that's you know I think it's not
so easy but yes it can be done uh
there's a path yeah yeah you have to
spend the time and and really focus on
on all the data points and you know just
where the loss is and isn't through the
process but it's you know I I I find it
really rewarding and I recommend
everyone to do it um it's something that
I've found I was a grower first and then
I wanted to make hash like most of of
you on here and it's you know look you
you hone in on what's important and to
me it was it was tping profile and yield
and I just knew that if I didn't do that
I'd just be looking at you know less
than 2% yields all the time and and can
you know always wonder why right
so with dry sift if you really want just
your heads you only get about 3% from a
kilo of weed with water you can get you
know 10 maybe even 12 or whatever with
uh rosin you you got a similar number so
I mean economically if you just growing
a few plants you want to make your own
rosin or water has makes more
sense the highest I've ever gotten with
rosin and water hat is it's close to
30% those are rare but they they did
happen I did that where is my that's
tremendous that's CRA it's tremendous
tremendous get
20% not many people are gonna hit those
numbers no milk four to 5% fresh frozen
like Sam when he was talking um uh three
uh those low percentages four or five
percent he's talking fresh frozen which
four or 5% is like 16 to 20% dry yield
yep when Sam's saying 3% he's talking
dry
yield I start with dry plants
correct and I get rid of all the crap
and all the crap and all the crap to
finally all that's left is little resin
heads and I never have more than two or
three% yeah makes sense good company
that's good compy is hard to to
accomplish all the
time you know if you're hitting % that's
a really amazing place to be you know
hone in on on whatever ritols and parent
stock that's doing that the GMO root
beer man I'm telling you guys this [ __ ]
is [ __ ] fire I'll have test numbers
on all the varieties here in a few days
but it's taen that for sure so I don't
like GMO players well fair enough they
weird no that's a joke don't you get it
GMO plants
hey since we're since we're talking
numbers and
yields Kevin and I have been working at
at uh 800 for the last probably like 18
months selling fresh frozen in the
market pretty much being a broker to the
fresh frozen and you know what we saw
was disappointment sadness anger deceit
uh you know bad stuff going on you what
you saw was Farmers that had these
ingenuitive cats that would come in
logistics guys that would come in with
Reaper trucks and they had the grand old
idea of you know what uh we're going to
come in here we can use your staff we're
going to harvest and freeze all this and
when we freeze it you can get your
Harvest you can get your next grow going
and we're going to sell it
all so they kind of duped a lot of the
farmers into thinking that this was the
way to do it what happens then is the
stuff's not selling the reaper truck's
sitting there on the Farmers land at
1,600 bucks a month all the profit
starts to get eaten away and then the
farmers literally has a bunch of [ __ ]
material that the reaper truck leaves
and they have to either drop the price
to the point where they didn't make
anything and lost a bunch of money so we
saw this everywhere we're just like and
the other thing we saw as hash consumers
was that it was the same [ __ ] 16 to
22 strains over and over and over and
over and then these [ __ ] started to
[ __ ] us again because they started
taking the same six to 22 strains and
mixing the Melt and pressing that and
calling it a modified and making a new
skew which is good for business but
shitty for my [ __ ] receptors so hey
Addison hey Addison I gotta ask a
question so what you say about hashing
is certainly true I think with cultivars
but not necessarily extends over to
solvent-based extraction and so as you
know there's an incredible market for
fresh frozen in for solvent based
extracts especially in I mean just the
way
that it doesn't really it's most
production is not based on vertical
integration where you have control of
the grow and certainly if you're making
if you're making live resin and you're
doing fresh frozen extraction just like
with hash you can't you can't make a
good extract out of bad starting
material right you could certainly
certainly turn good starting material
into a bad ract but not the other way
around so I think that the the pressure
on those Growers now is that you know
they could easily dump that stuff um
probably at a much lower cost higher
volumes to the guys who are just buying
it and extracting it as much as they
possibly can to make sauce and diamonds
on the solvent side and they and they do
and from what we're talking about within
that 18-month period we saw that there
was some you know we'll call them Bottom
Feeders like guys that didn't give a
[ __ ] and they would buy it up but even
the BHO guys were only getting
1.8% so you're talking about [ __ ]
material and what it was was now this
system was concentrating [ __ ] material
that was then trying to be sold in the
market so we looked at that and we're
like this is kind of [ __ ] up we're
lucky enough that a lot lot of our
friends are big breeders so we would go
and be with our buddies and we'd be
smoking hash and they would have this
[ __ ] strain or something and they'd
be like oh this is my blah blah blah and
we'd be like well how come this isn't in
the hash market and this happened
multiple times oh well you know I put it
out and 710 grabbed it and they do it in
like limited runs but that's like the
only big you know guy that grabbed it
and it's out there and we were just like
what the [ __ ] is wrong with you and then
we realized oh you're a breeder not a
marketer you're a breeder not a this
you're a breeder not of that and so your
focus is to breed to just be in there
making genetics and and love your life
in that place and so we were like okay
it's our job to now figure out how to
fix this so we went to those breeders
and said listen I've got a network of a
hundred you know of uh 36 40 something
Farms that are going to be able to
produce this you know these specific
cultivars that you have that are hash
specific solventless specific we can get
those into production if we get them
into the washrooms and we can help
popularize the strains would you be
willing to just take these genetics
whatever you have that you think are
right and give them to us and we'll make
sure that your name is you know
recognized the whole time and that
there's Integrity in what we do with the
with the Farms that we work with so we
got breeders to agree to that we then
went and we know we knew that we needed
a a an actual Nursery so we went and
found a nursery we have about right now
we have seven or eight breeders we got
about 40 45 or 46 strains that are all
brand new for solventless hash according
to the breeder and they're all producing
at least at four % for solventless
production so that's kind of the that it
has to produce at least 15% THC dried
weight and it has to be at least a 4% to
get into pipeline as a brand new strain
that's going to come in from a breeder
now what we did was we also realized
that we had to figure out how to take
the plant material from the farm within
the farmer's model and what he's doing
in harvesting so the farmer knows when
it's ready pulls it starts to dry it and
cures it that's what they do what we did
was built a system that fits into their
model and allows us to take a test wash
at the right time specifically at the
right time we have a network of buyers
that we're already shopping the list of
strains to and the the harvest dates
once we do that the guys that are that
are buying they can look at that list
based on strains or cultivars and say oh
these are coming down on these dates let
me set up my test washes on that date
and we've been doing this over the last
two months and orchestrating this and
it's been perfect the test washes so if
we have a lab that test washes with us
if they like the product they get first
right to refuse it so we're moving
through 2,000 3,000 pounds of material
at a time the farmers stoked because
we're like hey pull the leaves 12 hours
before then come in apply this this pull
you know this Harvest bucking method
make sure that they're frozen and stored
this way so this whole entire thing is
all done specifically for the process
because now if we do it that way we can
advertise to the B to the makers hey we
followed all these protocols and Sops
we're using these strains here's the
Harvest dates and this thing is knocking
off now doing so well that we already
have guys that we went to and pitched it
to that were so stoned that they came
back and pitched it to us which I think
is awesome and you know we had to remind
them that look we built this in a way
where you can't really do this without
the relationship with the Breeders
without a relationship with a really
great Nursery that you can trust and
without the relationship then with
existing makers that you're already
selling material to and a lot of these
guys that are trying to copy us are the
guys the logistics guys that came in and
[ __ ] everybody the last couple years
um so we just like we approach it with
loving kindness we approach it with
logic and we just look at it and say
very selfishly how the [ __ ] do we make
it so that there's better strains for us
to smoke Ash that was really the selfish
approach to it and then we figured it
would there clear you're talking about
clones yes not seeds seeds seeds from
seed well there's got to be variation
every got to be yeah there will be so
that's why the nursery partner that we
have we selected a very specific Nursery
partner that's very good at propagation
and very good at communication so we can
have them work directly with the breeder
that bred it and help them understand
what characteristics they're looking for
through the process and that's that it
took a long time it took a lot of
looking but we did find a partner that's
willing to take the genetics but then we
also have a very rich uh scene in
California with tissue culture so we
have access to the genetics in Clone
form that we can tissue culture and
bring those labts in and be able to also
uh then use the specific strain that the
breeder talking about the actual one
that they selected um but it's also fun
for the for the the nursery to be able
to get in there and open it up and see
because they may see one that's a great
flower version they may see one that's a
great hash version and that's why we
want to start defining things
differently that
way I I I'm in favor of colonal
production I mean I I'm a seed guy that
that's honest truth but what I do is I
grow thousands of seeds to select out
the one or two that I want to clone yeah
yeah so you know I I don't use clones
for production per se I oh clones clones
are the way not seedlings because
seedlings are just too variable and uh
that's both good and bad for the reason
you're saying but uh when you're
producing a product you don't really
want variability you want it to be
consistent yeah and that's why we have
the cult the the guys that we're working
with at the nursery they're very good at
doing selection they've done they do
selection with compound they do
selection with some really big guys and
they they've got an eye for it they know
what they're doing and they they they
tend to be able to lean a little more
toward hash as well so we figure some of
it will come through in Clone form you
know because some of it's rare you know
it's they don't have it in seed form yet
or they haven't produced it that
way but we just we we look at it as uh
if we're able to give these great guys
at the nursery these great Growers the
ability to pop the beans and find what's
in there um then we're it's a good start
at least it's going to give us a strin
or a cul ofar that we can narrow down on
and run test washed and hey if the test
washed come back and it's at five six
seven percent we got a winner what's
crazy about what's going on now that
we're seeing we we just watched Taylor f
tasel um we watched him you know start a
brand new seed company he's been working
on for the last two and a half years and
out of the seeds that he bred he started
to put out test batches that went out
that are now coming back and and guys
have had time to mess with them there's
one of them called twins um which is
fully
purple uh you know coming out at%
yield doing these what he's doing is
he's making crosses with his shallot
shashimi and his fana and both of those
are Bas base as what he's using for
progenitors for hash breeding the shalot
shashimi is a GMO cross the fofana is a
banana cross which are both you know
well known for dumping heavy heavy snow
um so what he did was is created cross
crossbreed and created some versions of
those that he then bred in and did what
you're saying you know did a thousand
crosses it's not so it's not so easy
believe me I've been breeding for resin
longer than anybody I know but for
example two two of the easiest ones to
drop resin after you dried the plants is
SLE stack from DNA boys oh yeah and uh
skunk number one from me I made a hybrid
between the two in fact I made a bunch
of them and none of them dropped resin
as
easy it goes
but it takes so long for those guys to
be able to put stuff out sometimes what
we're trying to do is accelerate that
process by getting a lot you know this
Nursery that we're talking about this
group that we're talking about they're
$150 million company but they're owned
by a Mendo grower a single guy that's a
Mendo grower that that you can hang out
with and talk with and he's and he's
also a generational strawberry and
tomato Farm
so what this guy's able to do what I've
seen in terms of quality control on a
large scale you know understanding what
steep hill and quality control and
testing what this guy's able to do I've
never seen anyone do I've seen him was
he a strawberry grower or a strawberry
breeder he was
a strawberry uh grower with with
generational family members that were
breeders of both tomatoes and
strawberries yeah because strawberries
are so similar to cannabis with
strawberries you start at 20,000 seeds
or
more the maybe the 10 best for whatever
criteria that you're interested in
selecting for and then you uh use that
both selections maybe to breed one step
further then what you do is you make
Runners you basically clone it and
that's what you deliver to the
strawberry Farmers the runners the
Clones yeah he's he's uh this guy's very
impressive man we we were pretty
selective on who we would even work with
and we work we were looking with and
talking with a number of big nurseries
and what we like about him is that he
owns the whole thing himself he has one
partner who's a big Tech guy that
handles a lot of the tech end of
everything and then Tristan handles all
of the grow um we've met his entire
staff we love the vibe of everyone so we
trust them um and and the idea again is
to get them to put them in a position
where they're in a well enough
relationship with the Breeders and
pipeline that were able to get that
information to them and do some
selection and get to see what that
selection delivers but we also have a
lot of clones that have come from the
Breeders as well that have gone into
tissue culture and we have labts of
those in original format that are proven
uh for genetic stuff that they've done a
lot of these guys they breed stuff and
they don't put it out it only stays to
themselves or in their small circle so
we've got them to give us the Clones now
and we can start pop popularizing their
genetics if they're hash dumpers um and
it's working it's actually doing really
well it's in phase one now what we've
done in phase one is we've gone to the
farm and the nursery that we're working
with we as hash guys have reviewed their
lists of genetics that they have um and
also recognize that they work with some
really big breeders in the state they're
very close with compound uh they're
really close with a couple other guys so
we know that they're uh they're they're
in it they know what they're doing and
phase one is to look at the genetics
that have and we're starting to do that
Harvest scheduling based on the genetics
that they have and we found some you
know we just found some really amazing
Grease Monkey we just found some really
great Sunday driver uh and what I mean
by found is we are able to get a hold of
the plant we're able to do a test wash
on it that Sunday driver came back I
think at um four four and a half
4.48% the the Sunday driver um the
Grease Monkey was it gree monkey was 4.4
and the Sunday driver was uh
3.8%
so those are gravimetric isolated yields
of hash you're talking about correct
that's a fresh frozen yeah so from fresh
Frozen um to the dried the dried
material so so what what would those if
you if you tested those plants and got a
COA based on on dried uh plant material
what what would they analyze for in
terms of total canono
content and the dry weight of uh for
most stuff here in California the
highest you ever see is maybe up to 20
you know uh in a concentrate or in a
flower yeah no I'm just trying to
qualify like the potency of that
material versus what you would normally
see on a COA for dried
flour oh it's going to be you know the
dried flour like we said is roughly most
of the time in California you're about
15 to 22% THC realistically a lot of
guys here like to take thca
THC and some other THC and add it up and
say that their stuff is 30% THC which is
total [ __ ] I mean in my wait wait
you can have cannabis that's 30% TC you
absolutely can Delta 9 THC absolutely
especially the acid especially the acid
form because it's a little bit heavier
you're talking about thca you're not
talking about THC
Del either and or I've looked at more ta
I've looked at more Cannabis Testing
data than any other person in the United
States easily I've looked at more I
honestly I have my doubts because sced
through more than anybody
else I've had my own lab for the last 30
plus years how many samp have you run
thousands and thousands we were breeders
we've done at Steep Hill in one year
we've done over I'd say 150,000
runs and at one location who's doing the
analysis for you
150,000 um the final analysis Paul
Daly and what lab is that that's Steep
Hill so when it comes to data I've
looked at the data I've seen it you're
telling me now that if I had a grand of
that dried flour in my hand 30% of that
gram in dried flour in my hand is pure
THC well actually the highest that I've
ever run in myself was
29.6 of dried of Delta 9 THC dried
material and it was a Delta 9 THC not
thca because I ran it on my DC yeah 30
30% THC would equate to
38.5%
thca and yeah I I call I call [ __ ]
on that you can't have plant material I
mean if you're if you're plucking the
top of your of your colas and you're
testing nothing else and there's no
other stem material in there because any
non-t trcom producing material is going
to dilute that but in a typical biomass
sample what you would do is you would an
at knows this because I'm sure he sees
this all the time and this purchasing is
that there are sampling protocols for
basically sampling large sums of
cannabis for uh an accurate COA that
then atn's price on that material is B I
understand all of this Mark I've been
doing this a really long time I know but
what we did was we used a sample that
was heavily manicured the way it would
be as a consumer would smoke so we
wasn't unmanicured it was very manicured
but it was
29.6% THC I just know that is that is
rare Sam and I have to say we are not
seeing anything like that that's why I'm
mentioning it no no no I understand it's
the highest I've ever seen most of mine
was in the range of 22 25 was high yeah
for you I would say I would I I you
would probably be the only one but for
us on the ground in the market we do not
see that here on the ground we have not
never never seen close to that we have
people come up and say that we've seen
Laboratories that aren't reputable spike
samples in that we even saw in the
categories when I did the emerald cup
how they were actually mixing in the
live rosin Etc to try to spike the
numbers so they hit certain THC ranges
so it is happening there's manipulation
in the scene but at the same time I just
got to give a shout out Addison proud of
you really proud of you because uh
you're one of the ogs in the sense of
what California for those who don't know
Addison had one of the early
dispensaries got busted fought the
system started Steep Hill Laboratories
and has just stayed in and stayed true
because I worked with him back in 07 and
'08 actually on the original testing
here in the United States so much love
great respect and I I don't see it as a
pissing contest between you guys number
wise it's just you've seen rare air Sam
and we on the ground do not see re
anything close that rir we're lucky to
see the 20% besides the 22 to 25 you
know what I'm saying that's more common
to see in the under 20 then you're gonna
see anything over 20 unless I'm mistaken
Addison yeah when I tested all the
samples that were entered into the High
Times Cannabis Cup here in the
Netherlands which I did each year uh
yeah they they sell them were 20
22 maybe one or two were 25 maybe but uh
they there was no uh 29.6 ones there
what varietal was that
29% and it just
[ __ ] M [ __ ] yep that's the
word you know what wow you know what ATN
when we first when we first started and
and we first got into everything we
learned pretty quickly that Sigma
aldrich's standards are trash and that
they weren't correct um and here's you
know Sigma [ __ ] Aldrich right you're
like come on and then when you got it's
not only Sigma Aldrich it's
also if you if you order theyy them they
buy them so they they Sigma Aldrich is
just a middleman they don't make
anything they just have a chemical
warehouse and Shuffle around one
purchase order from one uh client to
another so you're buying basically the
quality of what Cayman and other people
are able to produce yeah Addison that's
not a problem today I mean as you know
you need a DEA license to basically
delve out those standards so those
standards cost an awful lot of money
they do end up spoiling especially the
cannaboid acid standards they only good
for like I don't know I think they're
good for just a couple months and you
have to keep them Frozen but
we're not handling nuclear waste we're
just handling pure compounds here so
it but it's an unnecessary tax just like
the tax on 200 proof ethanol that
handicaps the industry just like 280e
and all the other [ __ ] right you are
correct about the problem with getting
analytical samples when we set up our
lab 30 years years ago what we did was
we got our standards both from Geneva
United Nations drugs and we got them
from uh Sigma also and one other place I
forget but what we did was we sent the
sample to Dr mum we sent the sample to
Dr bran Eisen and Dr El solle and all
four of our results came back we felt
pretty good except for that the results
were
88% instead of
99 hey Sam just turn Sam just turn away
from your mic slightly you're you're
breathing directly into your mic okay
I'm
sorry yeah it's interesting how we we
eventually got to the point where we
were just making standards because we
couldn't trust um what we were getting
we were just using a preparative hplc
and just making our own [ __ ] at that
point um what's funny is Sigma Aldrich
is one of the best places to buy LSD
from so if you go to Sigma Aldrich you
can get their standard for LSD and just
eat it and get lit it's actually a
really [ __ ] cool trick that you can
pull so anybody who has access Sigma
Aldrich has some pretty dope
LSD I speak from you gotta fill out a
pretty extensive questionnaire before
you get an account with Sigma Aldridge
to make sure that you know you're
licensed to handle anything that you get
from them and if they smell anything
fishy you can't buy from Sig Aldridge
but there's plenty of chemical vendors I
mean you can go up to Amazon these days
and buy chemicals so I mean there's lots
of places that you can buy you know
stuff from also stands Sigma sold me
with no problem so they ate that clever
yeah they sold the Steep Hill we didn't
know what the [ __ ] we were doing in the
beginning yeah now they're they they
they're they're pretty careful I I've
had to I've had to get reapproved and
approved and reapproved again with
yeah well you're on a special list Mark
let's be honest yeah exactly there
there's a company that actually sells
sells the uh The Columns that are widely
used in the shimadzu system so a company
called resc up here in bont Pennsylvania
has a schedule one license and their
standards are right on the [ __ ] money
and I've had to rely on their standards
now for machines for for several labs
and so rese re s TK and their Raptor
column is one of the best columns that's
out there for doing reverse pH also
several companies in Europe that uh well
and in Europe the only thing that's
controlled is THC 9 and uh uh delta8
everything else is
available how it should including
including
thcp Weir that's a that's very
interesting the what's odd too is that
we ended up getting standards from El
soy and then um I think uh we we settled
on what you were just saying we ended up
just getting them from uh digipath or no
from uh resch resc yeah is kind of where
they've gone at this point and and to be
honest with everyone I I had a great
time at steep pill I learned so much it
was it was a great opportunity it was
really something that like it it was
training that allowed me to to to to
understand [ __ ] when I heard it in
the scientific area and it helped me
also you know it was cool because I went
back and through the Cannabis industry
learned chemistry you know organic chem
every one of the organic chem schedules
you could get because we had phds there
and oddly enough I was their boss which
was [ __ ] weird and I just absorbed
all that information and learned so much
I got educated on it I think testing's
great I just think right now in our
industry the testing industry is just
rampant with [ __ ] it's you're trying
to fit and monetize a business um I
would agree with you that and coupled
with the simple fact that okay the stuff
that tested the highest both the 28
29 uh 61 and the other ones that were
even 25 or something they weren't the
preferred smoke of people people liked
the stuff that was really Turing rich
and had a really loud flavor and had the
right effects that's what they
wanted DC works you'll know that there
can be very subtle changes in the method
used to make the sample that can give
you very vastly different results and so
it's it's probably more about sample
prep and the the individual operator
that's running the hlc other than the
machine it's itself the machine is
basically going to the concentration of
the sample that you put in there but if
the tech is not you know knowledgeable
enough on on how to make a sample and
how to do a reproducible measurement and
make sure that s sample is run on a
machine that's properly calibrated and
their Baseline is nice and flat and
doesn't like drop off a cliff at the end
and they're not just running some quick
method I mean hlc can be very very
accurate and what I will say is that I'm
actually uh on the other side of the
coin Addison I think the testing
industry on the Cannabis side has come a
long way in the last handful of years
compared to where it was say like four
or five years ago where yeah you send a
similar sample to 10 different labs and
you're going to get 10 different results
because everyone runs a different method
I think there's been a lot more
standardization you know I said on that
group of people ATM that's trying to
standardize a set of tests and there's a
lot of you know Cooks in the kitchen on
that but ultimately at the end of the
day there are very reliable methods for
quantifying
canab that are present in delta8 that's
made from CBD are not Baseline resolved
by hlc and there needs to be a GC
measurement to basically look at uh the
purity of of d8 that's derived from from
CBD and so the folks at KCA labs are
actually working on that and so yeah
Addison definitely like Steep Hill was
one of the first you know uh Labs that
sort of you know carry the flag of we
really need to do standardized good
measurements there's a lot of innovation
and a lot of people who have basically
entered the testing industry
and I do a lot of testing now Sam I
don't know how much testing you do
lately I don't do nothing anymore and
what I can tell you is when I send
samples to five or six different Labs I
see correlation of results I see that
labs are actually getting their acts
together and when I send one sample to a
lab and I get one measurement I can
basically predict that measurement based
on the own hplc measurement that we've
made in our own lab and so the last
thing is that I think the more and more
testing happens the more and more weak
sisters are going to be knocked out
because producers have to rely on a good
COA so their product is sellable and if
their COA is not good that means they
can't sell their product so there are
are relationships that are starting to
stratify between producers and testing
labs in the industry because they're
getting more reproducible results
they're selling more product and I think
that the needle is moving closer to
actually characterizing these samples
more accurately than they were say just
three or four or five years ago you're
right Mark and it's even more than that
because the industry only started in
2008 you know
right the fact is is that is that
there's nothing unique about cannabis
that makes it different than of the
other foods that we eat and if you look
at any food product or any FDA label
required you could see that there are
Labs like Euro fins and other labs that
basically do measurements of food you
know products all the time and and part
of that is not only you know just the
the the standard regulation but it's
just also you know part of the marketing
thing you know and you know Addison what
I would say too you know is again you
know like I I think that where you guys
were in in assessing that there needed
to be a testing industry parallel with
the producing of cannabis products I
think that's where the vision was I mean
it's like you can't just produce stuff
and not have third-party testing you
have to produce it and then you have to
throw it over the fence to a lab that's
hopefully certified and it you know that
means that their hlc's are all
appropriately calibrated and they've
hired you know good people to run those
hlc's so the results you're going to get
are actually meaningful hopefully that
Loop is becoming more and more
productive and we could ask aten because
atn's business is basically a a catalyst
for that Loop between producers and
testing labs to produce products that
are legal and compliant under the law
you know you know what's interesting the
biggest problem is accurate labs and
I'll explain why the more accurate that
a lab is the better that they're going
to reveal the issues that Growers are
having in getting their potency up now
etan will tell you this if if a lab if a
The Growers will shop their product to
different labs to get the highest THC
percentage so that it sells better
they'll they'll run the same sample at
five different labs and when they find
that lab that's a little Loosey Goosey
that bumps the higher numbers that's
their [ __ ] lab and when you're
selecting BAS B on that there's a
problem with the system itself it's not
regulated enough on the laboratory side
to make sure that they know what they're
doing the main problem there is the BCC
in California doesn't know what the [ __ ]
Cannabis Testing is so you've got people
in there that don't know what they're
doing when those guys are the ones that
are setting the rule it creates this
environment and that's our environment
right now we have lab the more accurate
you are when I talk to Labs they're like
the more accurate that we are the less
customers we have when we send them the
test result right that's the lowest of
of of their and they tell them this the
the the company tells the lab oh man we
love you guys you have great pricing but
we can't you I mean the test results
come back fast everything's good but
you're everything we run with you guys
is low and then these guys they take a
little longer to get it back but we get
higher numbers there so they're there
there's a system that allows [ __ ] to
in Washington that happened and they
actually called it out
and they closed down one one whole Lab
was running like 80% of the
state um every single lab in Oregon went
away pretty
much it's hard guys labat hard from the
beginning and and in
can British Columbia last week I'm
talking to Labs over in in in Calgary
and they're talking about they have to
fit 6% THC on your rosin in order to
have it available to the market and if
you don't fit if you make so they have
to buy the the herb from a producer in
faith then bring it to their laboratory
wash it and then find a lab and maybe
it's the one lab they work with and it
has to fit within that threshold window
so everything that you're saying is
unbelievably disheartening to a family
farmer or a family grer you know maybe
if you have like an investor business
that you can just fold and start a new
one you know it might be okay to you
know play in that game but a lot of the
Breeders you're talking about Addison
and California Are Family Farm breeders
and they can't just fold up because of
that and it's the same here in the cies
in British Columbia so you know I would
appreciate less regulation on us if they
don't have a system that's viable for us
to play in because otherwise it's
just ah it's that it's a waste of energy
well and again you're only dealing with
this snapshot in time and that's is also
the problem I have with California
Cannabis is because once you have that
snap snapshot in time you have a year to
get rid of that product and of course
what we're seeing now is we're about to
see a huge glut here in California we're
seeing price is plummet from last year's
Harvest because it's now harvest season
we haven't seen this type of event we
saw it with Oregon but it was right
after they harvested now we're seeing
the opposite end in the sense here in
California is that we now have so much
now old cannabis two it's a snapshot of
that cannabis in that form not how it
actually comes in that form so even in
the form that it's tested at doesn't
mean that's that's what I'm selling it
at in the dispensary because even this
wonderful you know water hash Etc that I
get still has so much oxygen uh trapped
in the container etc etc there's still
degradation that's happening and
especially if you look at the jars of a
in the amount of oxygen nobody's taking
the time and do an 8020 nitrogen CO2
shoot in to actually protect the flow so
that it doesn't actually degrade you
know and they're definitely not doing
that at the concentrate level no way
shape or form to actually stabilize the
product so even the system itself is
kind of [ __ ] because only dealing
with that snapshot in time when that
particular representative sample was
tested not what the actual person is
receiving at the time of their
purchasing which is the real market and
the real reality and the big problem
then it goes beyond just the you know
the testing and the instability of
testing you know it's the also
maintaining that product consistently
through the distribution centers and
points all the way till it gets to the
individual person at the counter and
that's a huge problem issue being
ignored yeah it happens here all these
things that you guys have discussed have
happened here are happening here in
Canada as well like people with their
fresh frozen CRS in containers paying
1,700 a month from and they still have
last year's CRS that still fresh frozen
that's going on we have Labs that are
pumping numbers and giving people better
numbers than other labs you know we have
a whole situation where we have an
industry of people selling produce that
doesn't realize it's produce and is like
first question is your Vault cooled oh
man I'm like oh so all of your Tarpin
are currently off gasing in your Vault
right now and you're representing
companies that are only in the one to
1.5 tpine range in the first place
instead of the three to five exceptional
range so you don't have any movement you
have no movement you need to keep this
[ __ ] cold I was telling people in the
Prairies dude build a [ __ ] tunnel
through the center of your building that
goes into your Vault and pull the minus
40° Canadian Air uh out there into your
Vault because to keep all of this stuff
at room temperature is absolutely
batshit you imagine hey Addison I'm
going to send you a container of spinach
but I'm not going to be cooling it it
would get to Addison and it would be
liquid we're in the produce business
here right yeah I think Marcus is
bringing up a really good point in into
what ATN and also Dr Mark was talking
about and all of us really I think like
from a formulation standpoint it's
really important to have this snapshot
but that snapshot is really limited so
there's only so much is telling me so I
can only you know be so educated to make
products that are based on a system that
yes to atn's point is inherently broken
Mark's you know working really hard hard
behind the scenes to try to fill those
holes and try to fix it but then we have
the responsibility of everyone else
including ourselves for supply chain
which Marcus just just out line which is
super important because once it leaves
our hands it's really up to everyone
else now to then have that same care and
compassion to make sure that this this
you know these chemicals or this these
products I should
say seems to be like walking on the moon
these days but you know I think it's
it's important that you know if we can
just agree on something at the at the
testing level I think that would really
help and then again then I think we
should hold people to accountability on
the supply chain aspect if you don't
have a freezer and you're a you know a
distribution center maybe you know there
should be fines for that you know maybe
there should be some consequences for
for these people that are not taking the
care that you are the advantage Colin
yeah Advantage right I always told
people if you want an advantage freeze
your [ __ ] make it cold make it as cold
as possible some of it won't be able to
be frozen you'll just want to keep it
really kind of refrigerator cold and
you're going to have to pay a couple of
prices by learning which ones are the
right ones to freeze and which ones
aren't the right ones to freeze and so
right yeah it is what it is people are
gonna have to get on it I mean Supply
Chain's critical and I think in every
part of this business like
was pound they go from 85 to 200 bucks
depending on their viability that hasn't
changed everything else arounds It
Changes Everything Changes except for
that price and when we saw that we were
just like you know wait a minute I can
still go to a grower and go hey look I
can get you 950 bucks for a k you know
for the the for the 2008 grams or
whatever the hell we need and a lot of
guys you know when we go into these
girls and talk to them um if we're if
we're offering a farm $60 a pound for
wet material they're profiting they're
making money they're making money
because they're not having to dry it
they're making money because it it it's
out of there very quickly and it and
that model works now if they're getting
60 and we're able to sell it for 85
there's room for us to do that with our
partners if we're getting if they're
getting 60 and we're able to sell it for
200 there's even more so we give them
more than 60 we now bring them up with
us and say hey here's how you can get
$80 a pound wet and you add up those 80
pound those five 80 you know wet pounds
they equal more than what you'd get for
a dry pound when you start showing that
and you show that model and you
understand the supply chain that way
that's where you want to be and that's
where hash is that's that's the only
thing in our business that's doing it
right now is is that and that's the only
place that it's left now BHO there's
room in BHO at the highest end of the
market at the diamond end of the market
but there's only room at the highest end
of the market for BHO there's no other
room at the bottom you got to see where
the room is and then be able to do it
and it's like you know a maker can buy
Frozen pounds at
$200 wet and and put them out and sell
them and and still make really great
money they don't know that or understand
it they're they're they're just not
educated to the point where they have to
trust and commit and what we've done has
introduced the ability to say hey on
those 2,000 pounds that are in the
ground right there let me apply this
model to it and see if it works it does
work um and and it's G it'll move more
material it'll actually what we think is
that good work is going to lower the
price of hash
slowly um and make it more affordable uh
I see BHO as a lower barrier of Entry to
Hash consumption you know it costs less
it's easier to get into um and then
you'll see guys sort of start to step up
their glass game because they start to
understand that they have a piece of
tpine analysis equipment in front of
them and how do I use that oh what nail
do I have what's the surface area and
nail how much air is coming through here
how can I cap that air and control the
flow to get it to use my column that I
have here to get you know it's like you
accelerate your understanding to the
point where you start to only want to
smoke very good rosin because it's easy
to clean up or melt because it has a
different taste and a different approach
that's really where and we know this we
all know this because we're here we've
been doing this but the public and
opening the public up to this and
starting to get them into it there's a
lot of profit there's a lot of money to
be made the biggest problem in our
industry is that people don't use their
brain and logic to figure out how to
work with one another and make things
and so we all make money everyone wants
to crook
and everyone wants to control and be the
and it's like what I love about hash is
we as a community are starting to teach
everybody else collectively not as a
master but just as a learning a learning
entity that's moving forward that if we
work together and we approach things in
an open source way and we make it so
everyone can make money we can do this
for longer and we can do this forever
and and we all do really [ __ ] well
like I'm sick and tired of these small
growers in California coming out that a
wreck and being like I can't I'm not
making it I can't make any money stop
[ __ ] lying dude you're you're selling
50% of your Harvest on the black market
you're selling 50% the other way and you
have to look this way in order to
continue to do what you do you can
either go full wreck or I I honestly I
think do both I did both I did one
before and I think do both until you get
caught right until you get in trouble
because that's always been our thing but
it look it there's more [ __ ] material
being sold for fresh frozen in
California then there is then there if
you produce all of that fresh frozen
into hash you'd have five times the
amount of [ __ ] hash it's being
sold whose fault is that it's not my
fault it's the bcc's issue and and
honestly I think a lawyer would be able
to prove in court that the BCC is
complicit in drug smuggling and and
because of this reason for this purpose
because they're the ones that are
watching it if you see the numbers and
you just made $887 million on tax okay
that you're allowing more production to
occur more sale to occur than what's
going out into the into the actual
dispensary then you know where that's
going and you're complicit in that
you're actually a part of that and
that's what's happening in our industry
so just to correct Addison it's now the
DCC it's the department now it's being
Consolidated into one so it's no longer
just BCC we have to change our
nomenclature so people are where we're
talking about now the department of
cannabis control which we are now
currently under 90-day emergency RS
bigger and Blinder than ever before like
I just also just agree with the
community aspect and that's what I love
about Rosen and with h the the pure
certification that we created you know
we have a lot of farms and also
producers in California and that's been
our whole entire model from the
beginning was not a mon monetary model
but more of a community model and how we
can all survive and be a business in
five our our whole thing is like are we
a business in five more years from now
because if not all we're doing is just
everything we're doing is just Folly so
and we recognized from the beginning
that you know solventless and and
non-chemical extractions were more
valuable and more heady so part of our
certification from the beginning was
only solventless so all of our Farms the
only thing they could have produced all
these years was solventless and they are
really amazing companies coming out and
working solely with pure certified farms
and getting it out to the market that
definitely doesn't solve the the the DCC
or the BCC issue because the bottleneck
is a huge problem but um you know being
able to you know have the fresh frozen
pounds is also sort of the beginning of
starting a product it's taking it out of
the biomass it's like you know having
vegetables fresh at the market and
getting a penny per pound or a dollar
per pound or freezing them or beginning
to preserve them it's the beginning of
preserving them and making a value added
product so it's nice that those you know
it's and obviously the tpin are
something that you know people really
resonate with and I like that resonate
has resin in it but you know resonating
with the tpin and one of the you know
early tpine mind expansion times was
going to steep steep hill back in the
day and talking to Dr kimron and uh Dr
Kim on that you know Steve pill was just
such an amazing uh mind at the time and
just like a freaky hippie I I really
loved his uh his depth and his his his
dedication and also you know Reggie
godino is is also a really amazing
person and uh you know everyone that
came out of that and went went in in
different directions is something really
valuable in fact Dr kimron would be
really interesting to have on here I'm
not sure if he's where where he's at
these days but he's he's not a doctor at
all okay he does not have a PhD I do not
believe he was a a uh a a research
instructor at one of the local
universities right Davis he's actually
he's not a PhD but I
think um I you know what I I don't think
he's a PhD but he was a research
instructor with Don who is a PhD PhD so
don kind of gets the the bulk of the
doctor comes in but kimron is without
question one of the most brilliant
[ __ ] Minds uh I mean never mind just
a great dude to hang out with and I when
I talked earlier about learning I
learned so much from kimron I learned so
much from Don like we would be sitting
in my office smoking hash with some of
the biggest you know hash makers in the
country in this country or in the state
and then I would we would just be high
and we'd be talking about something and
we'd knock on the wall and we'd invite
kimron in and then Don would come in and
then Reggie be in there and and these
weed guys would be asking questions
directly and you were getting this
really amazing kind of uh build of of
understanding but I think you're right
Mark I I don't think kimron is a doctor
per se but I think he is a uh I think he
does have a doctorate in something yeah
so I think he he wor he worked at UC
Davis and I think he was the guy that
basically made all the reagents for all
the undergrad and graduate laborator so
he's got an incredible wealth of
experience at doing solution phase
chemistry in terms of like diluting
stuff and knowing like what the right
strengths are and stuff like that and
yeah I I met him so Pinsky introduced me
to him early on I think he's like oh
okay here's a weed nerd that you can go
like talk with and everything and so we
chatted at a high times Cannabis Cup
booth for several hours and yeah I mean
I I think that you know what you guys
started there certainly I think you guys
were U maybe a little bit ahead of like
where SC was because I know
know what they're doing I love their
customer interface you know when you we
set up an account at SC it's a it's an
HTML interface and so you can look at
your data in real time and see when it
really comes in and so yeah there's been
a lot of I think Innovation on the
customer service side of testing and you
know when comes to uh just for your to
to speak back to your point SC lab's
founder Josh was our chemist at Steep
Hill yeah Josh wer right so we hired
Josh wer gave him his gave him his first
job in cannabis and then after being
with us for about five or six months he
started to slow down the ability for our
test results to go out because he had
started to found an investor to help
work with him to start another lab to
compete with us so steill was actually
the first Cannabis Testing Lab in the
United States um you can you can you can
go back to a article in uh the East Bay
Express that David that David Watson
wrote or no uh what's his name David uh
uh David the journalist I can't remember
his name but he he wrote the first
article because everyone always comes to
me and they're like oh this lab was the
first or this lab and I'm like listen
when we opened Steep Hill that was when
that was when um um Paul dy's uh guy
there uh that and that did L what's that
were you were you working with David
lampack wasn't he one of the original
folks David David lampac and I um I was
the the head of the medical cannabis
Association the director of the medical
cannabis Association I had just got
raided I had a dispensary in the Central
Valley very very aggressive area for
cannabis at the time um I woke up one
morning and I saw an article in the
newspaper that said that uh that the
city of Oakdale that I lived
um was was in danger of uh someone being
able to open a dispensary because they
didn't have the laws on the books to
protect them and by the time I put the
[ __ ] newspaper down I was in the car
going over to the city to get a business
license for a dispensary and I got the
license I had the dispensary the
sheriff's came in hard and heavy I got
right I know you're in a pretty [ __ ]
up position um you know the only money I
had was from like six pounds of weed I
had inside of the inside of the fck
um the lawnmower bag the the the grass
bag of the lawnmower I had six pounds of
weed stashed in there and that was the
only money I had and I had I think I had
like 35 grand out and that someone owed
me um so I took all of that I was you
know [ __ ] at that point um because I'm
getting raid it was the DEA was all this
[ __ ] um Rob ra goes hey if you want to
work I can give you a job at the medical
cannabis Association as a director so I
said [ __ ] it you know I got to turn to
activism at this point right I need to
get some attention on my case I got to
draw some attention so went and started
working with Rob there as the Director
and David lampack was on the board um
David lampac and I Rob was like hey you
guys should brainstorm about finding
ways to create revenue for the for the
medical Canabis Association me and Dave
sat down um I went up to Dave's Farm in
mesino met with them sat down and kind
of just came up with some ideas one of
them was why don't we introduce quality
control to cannabis and the reason was
is because I had just got in an argument
with the sheriff because he was doing a
a news conference and saying that you
know cannabis is dangerous because it's
tainted it could have other drugs in it
so in me and Dave's conversation I'm
like you know and this [ __ ] sheriff
is saying there's other drugs and he's
like you know what there's no other
[ __ ] drugs in weed like who the [ __ ]
gives you other free drugs in your weed
like that's [ __ ] you know and and
and Dave's like well the only way we
could prove it is if we did testing and
I'm like H so I walk up to the dryer
race board and I'm like testing and that
was on the board you know and and and I
think I actually have in a phone
somewhere I think I actually have it on
one of my computers that picture of that
dry erase board that says testing it
says all these different ideas on it so
when we left there um we kind of just
said hey you know let's try to do some
testing uh I I left Dave and said that's
what we need to do well that [ __ ]
about five days later calls me up and he
says hey I got us a space in Emoryville
we're going down to [ __ ] uh we're
going down to pick a GC up up in the bay
at the at the maker and I think it was
uh I don't know who our first GC was
from but um we go and we we literally
yeah it's agilant we drove down to
agilant and I'm like what the [ __ ]
going on he picks me up we I'm in the
bay he picks me up we drive to agilant
we pick up this [ __ ] machine we don't
know what the [ __ ] we're doing he brings
me back to this spot that we leased
which ended up being the original steep
hill we brought the machine in we found
a chemist on um on Craigslist and then
lo and behold etn and Debbie got
involved and uh uh what was his name
John Gilmore yeah yeah John Gilmore just
put up the money and approach John
Gilmore went to Paul daily and said
these guys have a good idea um I'll put
the money behind it would you be willing
to help these guys and Paul Daly who was
working with uh Sasha shulan at the time
Paul Dy came over and that's how we met
Sasha and sha Sasha came and they both
were like oh you guys are sweet little
kids have a seat and they sat us down
and they looked at all of our [ __ ] and
and thank you etn because our numbers
were trash etn was paying us to do tests
and our numbers were trash right so etn
Ln ultimately seated Ste pill Steve
D'Angelo at Harbor Side seated Ste
seated Ste pill these guys we didn't
know what we were doing but then once
Paul got involved and Paul came in we
had the equipment Paul was able to reach
out to the rest of the community um at
that point you know we got everybody
involved I mean I think every single
cannabis chemist of any type at that
point were so interested from mulam all
the way into Eli and we had the network
to kind of get these guys involved every
one of those guys got involved in one
way or another at thean a lot of people
um and I always say that that it's crazy
that Microsoft essentially seated Steep
Hill because the money that John Gilmore
made from selling Sun systems is what
funded Steep Hill facts so facts we
oddly enough Microsoft funded the
quality control component of cannabis in
the entire industry like Steep Hill came
in and also a
Sasha Sasha shulan um component is very
significant very significant really cool
can't I mean I can't even I'm so I'm
more honored to be name to be thanked in
those books that Paul wrote than
anything else that I've ever done in my
career ever you know that to me like
having those books up there and I take
those out and I'm like just seeing my
stupid little name in there as like a
shout out of somebody involved that to
me and it's serendipitous it's like how
would it have come together and then
after that when I would take MDA I'd be
like yeah you know like the molecule so
like all this comes so full circle and
and even with the fresh frozen thing
even even with the Legends thing now I
feel like it's just an energy that's
that's outside of all of and we all know
it it's the plant it's feeding us this
energy we're just a conduit to this [ __ ]
because I don't know where I get the
energy to do half this stuff so it's
it's definitely you know when I look at
we look at the last year how the [ __ ]
did we survive that year and come
out talking to Kevin who was here with
me you know we both were sitting here
struggling working our asses off and
then somehow some way it happens and it
clicks and everything's moving and the
work that you did before happens and I I
mean I'm just rambling but this is the
plant this is that compound that made
this happen and that and it's done it
with other compounds because the group
of people are compound guys which is
really
weird was Jeffrey rer and Samantha
Miller in there or is Jeffrey rurn and
Samantha Miller came after a little
after that or je Jeffrey came in um so
it where it went from it went from from
Paul Daly then Jan Maru got involved on
the micro side because he was at a UCSF
so then we were able to expand micro
testing um and it was about the at about
the same time that those asilis patients
had died from consuming medical cannabis
and the and the the people that were
researching the death went back to the
person's house got the Cannabis tested
it saw that it had aspergillosis and
fusarium and then they figured out that
that's how the immune deficient patient
died that was one of the things that
actually allowed us to get a lot of
support from San Francisco to be able to
push Cannabis Testing forward when we
did this this is when dispensaries were
getting raided left and right you know
so we kind of came out and we're like ah
[ __ ] you know me and Dave sat there one
day and I'm like if you think being a
grower is a Target and if I think being
a dispensary owner was a Target we just
made the biggest [ __ ] Target because
we're dragging mulam into this we're
dragging all these other chemists into
this now and the government hates them
and and I for a minute there I thought
we were going to get raided and wiped
out I thought they were going to hit the
chemist with a $10,000 per sample and
they were going to wipe the whole thing
the [ __ ] out but luckily for us they
were too focused on other things and I
think that the fact that testing got
through not because of steep hill
because of everybody that got involved
you know SE Labs later on um you know um
Halen all these guys that got the lab I
worked with the lab I worked with
stopped working because it was just so
risky their investors didn't want to
take the risks on their 6 uvh plc's
because they were the least etc etc you
know how it goes and that's an ungodly
amount of money so I mean I brought Arno
over and the the reason that I worked on
a suspended solution was because of the
$10,000 fine per test and so we worked
with Arno who did the testing solutions
for the Dutch government brought him
stat side and worked with our lab after
we invert we fired Steve Hill because we
weren't happy with the numbers so you
know I worked then with uh Ethan Russo
helped find me Arno and then Arno we
worked on actually getting cannabis
suspended in 100% alcohol so that now it
was a testing solution so now it was
legal to take into a dispensary I mean
pardon me into a laboratory and you
would no longer be subject to that
$110,000 fine per test so there were
mental steps along the way once you took
those initial steps that many of us
around saw that we needed to fill that
or now
standards no it took it took a village
man it took
everybody we were there I'll go ahead
Sam Addison what was the name of the
other lab besides Steep Hill that
eventually fused together T Talent yeah
Halen that's where that's where Hal
that's right
yeah Halen that's where kimron and Dawn
came from which was sort of a it was
built out of UC Davis which was
interesting um you know they were a UC
Davis lab that came in a bit after SC uh
and they they pushed things very far
like they they were the the one main
reason why I think the merger the merger
with them is what helped Steep Hill
survive to the point where he was able
to rip off all of the founders and be
the company that is
now that's that's really the juice that
they had there right after that was when
we started our certification because we
started our certification based off the
testing that was happening and one of
the early you guys at Steve pill did a
sleeper study I believe where you went
out and bought a bunch of pens and
then and then you know there was like
you know talk about people getting
lesions and their you know in their
their you know when it was really bad
and and getting lesions in their their
lungs and whatnot and uh clean green
started you know a certification down
there Chris and then we started it right
after that and ours was free because we
were farmers and producers and we just
recognized that people that were caring
for the Earth and bringing in living
soils and putting their plants into the
Earth and being a positive impact on
their it was kind of like the revelation
of finding out cannabis was good for you
the revelation of real realizing that
you could grow cannabis in harmony with
the Earth and then produce resin that
was of higher quality than anything else
it was this amazing full circle thing so
the revelation of Laboratories and
testing as ill as they are as we stated
earlier you know did help bring cannabis
forward and then when you add in heavy
metals now and uh um uh pesticide
residues and glyphosate residues you
know that that really also completes the
picture I would love for you know Canada
to learn how to uh get rid of their
microbial testing up here and get more
towards just human pathogenic testing
and I think that might be one of the
things that actually saves the Cannabis
industry up here in Canada because
you'll be hard pressed to find quality
cannabis coming out of any licensed
producer in Canada because of the
microbial testing that's required which
is even more stringent than when it
started so now you have all kinds of
different different things that they can
do and gamma radiation is one and light
light therapy is another and every
single one of those things diminishes
the turpins and the whole entire purpose
of this conversation and rosin and
everything is how to bring tpin up so
it's it's almost like bringing
everything up so that we can get smacked
in the face with a brick wall so I I
would love for you know the intelligence
of this community to continue to reach
out to people in Canada and to different
policy makers as we you know continue to
form our federal legislation or make
sure in America you know as as those
Federal uh uh legislations get formed
that you know you don't get crushed with
the microbial um you know dilemma let's
say so I you know that's just one of the
things in one of the things in our in
our area also packaging and trash and
all those types of things so yeah yeah
there's a lot to Community regulation is
tough it's it's they try to use uh an
approach where you know they're
protecting the people but at the same
time it it never translates into that
it's always it's always so limiting I
mean who the [ __ ] in their right mind
would limit microbes in a growroom the
[ __ ] are you
doing like in the have to there's tons
of biological inputs that you can't use
legally in your grow as far as soil
inputs too you have to have everything
uh approved every single input which in
some cases can be extremely difficult
you know things like em and mic or risal
fungi and those things for for a long
time were not allowed over the Border a
lot of them are becoming available and
are being used and there there are some
really Forward Thinking LPS in Canada
doing doing work to make it happen so
big up to them and uh and so yeah I know
there's there and moving forward it's
it's important I mean I think that uh
like you said we're we're trying to find
as much as we can in the plant and that
leads us to to to rosin that leads us to
melt in the most purest form um and it's
and it's just in order to get there for
so many years it was just isolation and
now that it's so open and there's so
many distractions and there's so much
going on the the cream is rising to the
top like you're when I you know I'm on
Instagram all the time just posting
stupid [ __ ] and just kind of you know
it's it's a distraction that allows me
to kind of take away from the work and
the other stuff but in the same time you
see people that are so invested that
think that our industry is in there and
it's like if anyone thinks our industry
is in Instagram you're out of your
[ __ ] mind because you may see one
thing but for us what our industry is to
me is when I drive up and and I'm trying
to find my way to this piece of property
and when I get to the property and I get
there and I see the green houses and I
see the plants and I you know and you
get the tour and you see everything and
then you get to the lab tour maybe and
you see the the material and you're with
the people it's like that's what this
industry is about it's and that's what I
love about Legends and I love about what
we're going to do we're going to put
those 25 makers with their with their
guests in a room with no [ __ ] phone
no camera and and that to me is like
every person I've talked to on the phone
that when I call them to tell them about
the event they're like oh [ __ ] thank God
and you know the only place where we get
that nowadays is at a comedy show
because when you go to a comedy show
they take your phone now because they
don't want you filming and showing the
person's comedy before they're ready to
release it and I think that by taking
that away from it and removing that from
it and putting people more in front of
each
other of love and kindness to push the
message of working together because the
more that and and of health and people
Health you know gut health uh foot
Health uh all those things that [ __ ] is
going to make it so you can keep doing
what you're doing for longer you're
going to be here and be able to give
these blessings to everybody else do you
know how many hash makers I talk to now
that are like oh what's up bro I'm just
getting ready to go to the gym we didn't
hear that years ago you know these guys
are biohacking these guys are work you
know straight straight or straight
Organics just started a whole thing with
uh straight you you know working out and
everything we're seeing it come into our
industry we're seeing Health become more
important and it's starting to align
with what we've always known is that
cannabis is healthy and it's a healthy
way of life and that's like we're
getting to sit in that position we sit
now as cannabis guys I sit now with like
biohackers dudes that are like oh and
they know cannabis is good for for your
health and those dudes are are you know
making a bunch of Splash and a bunch of
money and their Industries are in line
with our industry we're guys that that
sell compound
industry do you know how many guys we
look at and talk to that are that are
the top fitness guys in the country and
they dab or they use ures or they use
cannabis or they're using CBD so it's
all growing you
know yeah like it's because the you know
it's because it it touches the you know
the EC right it's just let's face it
it's it's the same you know when you're
when you're running you're you're the
same receptors are firing off and you're
you're feeling these same exact things
and and that's why we're we're drawn to
them and you're right I think um you
know I've always looked at cannabis as
some sort of a biohacking agent like
you're you're you're isolating these
compounds and you can put them back
together or you can allow the you know
Nature's chemist as I call it to kind of
guide you and let specific cultivars um
do it for you so totally agree I think
there's a lot to to look at and and you
know explore in that alone you know it's
cool to see people you know excited
about cannaboids and cannaboid therapy
in general it's it's been I mean I can't
imagine what Sam has seen through his
time you know let alone what we're
seeing right now in contemporary times
you know I think weed workouts are are
key and and I think the ganja has to be
regeneratively grown and and healthy to
begin with otherwise you know just
processing the residue chemicals and
that really doesn't serve you so in in
moving forward like health and ganja go
together we also started demm pure
athletes so we have a whole other realm
called deure athletes where you know a
lot of you know top athletes in the
world don't really understand nutrition
and they don't really understand
detoxing specifically injury
healing injury heal and unfortunately in
a lot of professional sports you can't
bring in cannabis because they still
testing THC levels for performance which
is totally ridiculous but a lot of uh
top athletes are turning towards
cannabis during their downtime knowing
that it's going to out of their system
within two months so they're turning to
anything that they can to be able to
utilize plant medicine because they know
that their healing is going to be in
half they know that when they go back
into the doctor check that bone injury
when they're going to be putting on
another cast those don't have to go on
and get that second cast they can go and
start working on their livelihood which
absolutely imperative and I just think
it's crazy that many doctors don't even
ask about that fast healing or how they
even got there nor do their sponsors
even want to know or Chinese bone break
soup and Bone knitting and Bone healing
together bones actually come together
pretty fast which comes back into the
compound of plant medicine which is
exactly what you all are just talking
about I've been listening but I've been
doing a lot of work so been really
awesome listening to how ironic is it
that the only sport that allows cannabis
now is the most brutal sport that you
could be involved in so the UFC is the
only sport that allows you to test
positive for THC and you're and you're
not banned from the sport what how come
and when I think about it I'm like how
come well it's a neuroprotectant
cannabis is a [ __ ] neuroprotectant
it's been proven to be a neuroprotectant
I've had six concussions in my life from
being a professional snowboarder from
being an athlete in my life six times
I've had concussions my brain shouldn't
be working the way that it does but
cannabis as a
neuro big money Grabbers you know huge
moneyers also the military
the military we could be using CBD Rich
components right after a TBI a traumatic
brain injury for those who aren't aware
which is a huge component of the most
recent Wars is the uh large explosions
that cause immediate concussive and huge
uh injuries and costs overtime which if
they were given something CBD Rich right
out the gate like they would give some
of the other medications like I was
given morphine when I went down I mean
think you would see a significant change
and we want to see and so that's one of
the thresholds we're pushing for but
that's a different methodology which I
think it may permeate through the
private Market of an NFL or a UFC before
unfortunately it will make that uh crack
hole through the veteran situation but
but it's happening and that's where it's
going to happen I think that that's
where because if you look at the NBA and
you look at there's a weird thing going
on where the NBA is very popular in
China very popular in Japan in those
places and you look at what Kobe BR or
what is it uh um you know the greatest
basketball player in the world got into
a weird situation when he was
criticizing some stuff the my point is
is that when you look at big Sports if
big Sports start to allow cannabis to
come in that's the acceptance level
that's the Breakthrough for the rest of
it because there's so much money behind
that end of it and that entertainment
value it's it's happening that's the
point is that we're seeing it and I
think
do well from it um and and that's my
biggest fear is that like you know when
Johnson and Johnson uh decides to
compete with us uh it becomes a
different story you know it'll be a
different thing but um you know hey if I
have to go live in the woods in in
[ __ ] Alaska or something somewhere so
I can grow and enjoy can or even a
better region and have gun and protect
myself I will I don't give a [ __ ] and I
think we have enough veterans in our
country that will nothing's going to
change in that way in a sense um I think
we're all you know heading in the right
direction but these are the signs like
the when I saw the UFC make that
decision and then I'm watching postf
fight conferences and [ __ ] Nate Diaz
is smoking joints on the stage I'm
like you have that golden hour once you
hit that that TPI to actually you know
stop as much Dam D AG as you possibly
can so it's really critical that you
know they find or start to create those
specific types of uh uh uh point of
attack mechanisms specifically with
cannaboids um and I think that's a new
frontier I mean I'm saying it's most
likely through the private scenario but
I mean the VA is the largest you know
medical system in the world currently so
and you know government does hold a
patent you know so at the same time
there's a lot of big things at play here
and uh you know let's not forget we
still got a lot of work to do and also
you know one of the Forbidden cures in a
in being healthy is the medicinal
mushrooms you know and it it gets talked
about and then you gets forgotten about
and then talked and forgotten and then
you start realizing you know wow when
you put the two I mean Corps for one was
one of the russan I think it was the
Russian wrestling team or something or
the weightlifting team that couldn't be
beaten through the 80s and one of their
big things was you know taking Corps and
and chaga as a as a daily nutritional
supplement and
now Mar has put up our micro canic caps
and and putting their polyes are for the
most part you know of course there's
tons of people that understand but the
poly medicine is not written about it's
not a thing that's studied and we're
here getting ready for for
yeah a lockdown you know and we have
this magical
medicinal compounds in the forest which
they want to fire smart and get rid of
all the branches and get rid of the
polypores I feel like I'm I don't know
what world I live in right now and I
think that it's really important you
know as we're talking about isolating
cannabis we also need to recognize that
if we're going to be isolating a lot of
things we could be getting into
detriment so I hear a lot about like
like isolating you know parts of the
industry and what what the federal
government is going to start wanting us
to do is not talking to each other is
that the distributor is not talking to
the to the grower and that the grower is
not talking to the breeder but our
success in our industry has been
holistic in a manner the reason why
we've been so successful and the reason
why we still have our health and
well-being and we're still having
beautiful relationships with this plant
is because we've looked at all
attributes of it you know Addison what
you were saying before is that you know
um a grower before had to have the
knowing of what was going on with their
distributor they had to know what was
going on and now it's like Yay you know
it's going out the door it doesn't
matter where it goes you don't even have
to look at it and it creates sort of
this isolating feeling and a disconnect
that is not going to help out the Legacy
Growers or the Legacy breeders or the
Legacy uh you know extractors or even
the canabo or the health and well-being
or the message of the plant if we don't
always have full access and full
communication with all parts of this you
know uh uh industry and and
unfortunately right now I call it an
outdry because I feel like we could do
so much better but these conversations
are really helping people say oh you
know on that and oh that's really
interesting that's something that's been
uncovered by today or or has been
uncovered you know consistently by Mark
and so you know continuing to uncover
the veils of separatism that they want
to put us into these different
compartments is going to be the death of
the industry competition with each other
is going to be the deaths of the
industry so we have to know what's going
on and bring each other up with the good
practices that are happening of course
surrounding health and
well-being and um I just did I just had
my 48th birthday the other day and did
48 push-ups in a
row while smoking's up you know what I'm
saying hey and happy birthday happy 48
yeah and Happy Birthday to you and
getting the kid out and everything and
stuff and you know just family birthdays
going on in your world too so I just and
also Mike big up to Mike and his happy
birthday happy birthday dude and happy
belated birthday to Sam I think it was
what three weeks ago or four five weeks
ago Sam
yep hey and also while we're at it holy
[ __ ] shout out to [ __ ] Frenchie
canoli this is the first hash Church
we've had since Frenchie's passing it
would be rough it would be rough for us
to not mention uh Frenchie canoli a true
hash afficionado and and lover of hash
and you know I I've known Frenchie for
quite a few years and bumped into him
many times and he's been on hash Church
we kind of saw things a little
differently but we're always able to get
together through our love of hashish and
it was just nice to see everyone talk so
nice about him and you know all the
pictures that circulated about of him I
realized I don't even think I have a
picture where Frenchie wasn't just like
this like just with a huge [ __ ] grin
on his face like bigest smile and then
you know I also I got to speak French
with Frenchie because uh I am French and
that's my other language that I speak so
I always had that going with Frenchie
that a lot of people uh didn't really
have which was I could speak his his
native tongue so shout out to Frenchie
anyone else that wants to say beautiful
things about Frenchie of course please
do uh it was a beautiful ceremony I was
honored by his wife to
be there's a lot of good people I've met
in this movement and there's very
yeah he was one of those people who made
me smile made me laugh always had the
most [ __ ] eating grin on his face and as
much of his love for cannabis he had a
love for chocolate so he and I would
speak and love chocolate and uh you know
I got to uh ask him my 200 cannabis
questions of which a lot of you I'd love
to get on at some point and also love to
get you on our vac round tables but um
you know I got to ask him 200 questions
about cannabis and just they're all
specific and it was just such a fun time
and we were went over to get high and we
just got so engrossed in the
conversation and his wife was recording
us so it was very small and intimate and
very fun and it wasn't until I was like
on 150th question that we're like we
should probably get high I think we
forgot to get high and you know we Sheed
up and you know we finally arrived there
but you know from the first time he came
and met me which is over a decade ago uh
I was one of the first people we came in
the bay and talked to and he was you
know because of you know the the know of
BPG and I looked at his hash and said
we're not ready for this the industry is
not ready for this we can't afford this
uh compared to the realities of what we
were seeing at the time and I just kind
of gave him the honest lay of the land
and I told him his hash was great and he
always appreciated that he's like I
always appreciated your honesty you know
we've all tried the Frenchy accent you
know it is so thick it is so French it
is so so amazing and I uh every time I
even you know I'm from Louisiana I'm
cinjun and I had a hard time hearing him
and his French depending was I mean I
don't know about you I speak French too
but it was definitely Sometimes some
words depending on how they were stated
you were like what the [ __ ] was that try
that in another way yeah it was
certainly not it was certainly not KCA
French it was very very f
f but his stories and especially to hear
over the years all the different his
travels were amazing I mean there the
incredible risks that he took I don't
think an American couldn't could have
gotten away with some of the [ __ ] that
he did it's definitely had agree but uh
he was just an amazing spirit and I was
just I I it's it hurt to lose him um it
still hurts I will miss him I will miss
him especially when I see him at the um
when I don't see him at the emerald cup
and I'm gonna stop because I'm about to
cry
sorry you know uh we just uh we're just
did a strain review for the upcoming
skunk magazine and we had talked to
Kimberly and ocn if we could name an
incredible hasham that we've been
working on for about three uh four years
now um after him and and we went on and
on about what the name was going to be
and so we're just launching the new
strain called Frenchie
Force why it's called Frenchie's force
is because he was such a force such an
incredible force of tenacity and what I
had said and we were also so incredibly
honored thank you so much Kimberly for
allowing us to speak so honored to speak
at his uh at his memorial and I just
feel like tenacity was it man when he
was coming up to you and he was coming
for you you better have your aame on you
better wipe those you know eye boogers
out of your eyes you better because you
because he's coming for you and he's
gonna be talking about what you know
you're up to what we need to do in the
future all the 10 billion things that
need to be checked off the list to get
the farmer was up there to make sure
that the industry was still working to
where it was Community built and
Community monitored and Community run I
just and if you could and if you can die
with all of that work seriously being
put out to the universal flow and it
being circulated to where it's actually
regenerative and it's growing new ideas
and new Bounty and and it's creating all
of this health and wealth and knowledge
um for all of us I just you know that's
all that we can ever ask for so you know
if you only got One Life to Live [ __ ]
live it like Frenchie because he just
really took every single day and it's
not surprising to me
you know maybe he did die too young
because every single day was like three
days every single day maybe it was like
six days you know the brother was G and
he also really brought home you know
that connection to the farmer and the
resin you know and he always said from
the beginning you know I cannot do any
of this without the farmer and also
bringing
in and bringing in the Appalachia and
terroir and that whole flavor pallet you
know that whole like true connoisseur
you know way of connecting with the
plant and the resin and and you know we
were really blessed because he really
took on the pure the pure certification
and the farmers and really recognized
you know how how having a connection
with them was like he came to our Hive
gathering at Hartwood um a couple years
ago and he was like I thought I was
coming here for you here to just make it
awesome and be Frenchy and then after
the weekend at The Hive Gathering he was
just like oh my God I did this this was
for me he just felt so full in his heart
and it wasn't an industry thing it was a
heart thing like you're talking about we
aru it wasn't a thing of you know
content and
stuff and then also at the regenerative
cannabis uh you know events that we did
we had some also some really beautiful
conversations with him and he was always
ready to rock the boat and and in that
and and in that I want to say somehow
there was still heart and soul and there
was still room
for uh being wrong yeah being wrong
trying to find the right way out and
even and even in his way of being like
so steadfast on his path he even evolved
and started using freeze dryers and
started using you know mechanical
separators and all these different
things so and even recognizing rosin so
you know huge love to fr you know for
upholding the Ruth but also evolving
with the community he was a true legend
of
hashish he was a passionate disruptor
for sure like he had such like I
remember my my my memories of him are
more Visual and like he would always
he'd have like a something rolled up and
he'd kind of be leaning in he'd always
be close to you because he always wanted
to communicate like and it was just like
anytime I ever saw him I didn't know him
very well but we knew each other but
anytime I ever saw him he always like
came to you give you a hug and then
you'd see him like float away and do the
same thing to every booth in the place
with every and like he just shared space
even to like I'd be at the High Times
company it would be like let's see
Frenchie
or you know like La gangster grow dudes
and [ __ ] and he'd be like ah see those
dudes and then I'd see him went to the
next booth and it was just such a person
that that I mean p his passion was tough
to to to beat because he the but also
just when it comes to leaving a legacy
every hash maker that I talk to now
that's whether it's a tryhard a guy
who's just kind of getting into it and
figuring it out or like a legendary
person that they always um when it comes
to to you know they know who Frenchie is
and and they and they all know about
Temple balls and the reason is because
he was such an educator like the dude
was always teaching people all the time
and and and he would argue with you you
know M me mine and his argument was that
like I call everything that's a
concentrate hash I'm like that's hash
like they even have a food that's kind
of named after it because it's a mix of
things like and we would have this great
argument of stuff but like he's just
such such a beautiful person and to to
finish off we're going to be doing a
moment of silence for Frenchie at the
Legends dinner we're gonna we've invited
Heritage we've invited uh his family to
come
so it's going to be uh it'll be dope so
I'm looking forward to it but yeah they
they'll be involved so and big Lu to ELA
who's carrying on his traditions and you
know one of his number one helpers and
of course you know there's the Dank
Duchess all these other people that have
been you know a huge part of his realm
and have continued on but you know big
love to Lena and Kim really and
ocen
yeah no it'll it'll be fun I think it'll
be uh Legends will be great in the sense
where we're able to you know take a
moment to to to show him some love but
then also include include his guys with
us
there to that Addison thank you so much
for continuing to bring the conversation
back to community to bring the
conversation back to the heart center
it's just um it's so important and it's
The Guiding Light here just so much
gratit
to yeah it is you know as we're oh go
ahead Addison it is Hash
that's like I I get that from
hash I was just going to shout out
subcool who is definitely kind of how I
heard about first Matt rise and then
eventually sub cool and bity dank just
had written this in the chat room I
hadn't heard of Frenchie until he hooked
up with subcool and cannabis afficionado
and did the hunters of the Dank with
TC so yeah that was kind of how I heard
about Frenchy for the first time was
through subol who I had known like
really since like gez I don't know Colin
when were we on those chats was that
like in the like
90 n or
something yeah I mean like up
remember can you hear
me yeah yeah yeah it was true Stoners
right yeah like true Stoners and then
also Laughing Moon and then Laughing
Moon eventually became
overgrow and you know so on and so forth
right but yeah I
mean he was like one of the first guys
that I think as a breeder that was
working with different varieties I mean
all of his stuff was like just I mean
not all of it yielded well but it was
like the resin was incredible you know
like all of the resin was just like
always really
topnotch I know it's one of the things I
always had to give up to sub and why I
always had a good relationship with sub
even as he was kind of having his own
internet dramas and all there was always
people like oh [ __ ] I'm some cool and I
was like I don't know man I you know I
don't have a relationship with them
other than the fact when I get together
with because resident killer and every
time I run [ __ ] no matter who Brew it
it's also killer Super Sub subcool was
one of the first ones to sell
dispensaries seeds too in the early days
you know he was the fir one of the first
because earlier on it was clones I know
because I worked for Ed I was Ed's
general manager I was pushing out 5,000
clones a week in the Bay Area so there
were no seed and it wasn't until I was
then finally working at BPG that you
know uh people like him actually would
come in and actually have seeds or take
the chance to come in and actually have
seeds available so that people could
grow something besides the standard
genetics that we had and as you people
were talking early about Cali orange we
were the main peret perpetrators of that
genetic in the Bay Area for years so you
know get up but subcool was the one of
the early ogs for us here in the
California Dispensary scene to get see
genetics out there because none of the
Europe EU seeders were you know playing
in America or trying to until you know
decades later you know it was subcool
and it was bog those were the the two
that I remember you could get in like
the
dispensaries and and funny enough those
were two of my first like customers it
was actually highgrade who was from
overgrow and he did these bubbler
buckets he was like like if you were on
those sites back then you knew knew who
highgrade was and in fact he was my
first customer and and afterwards I
think about a year into it he ended up
getting busted and going to jail and I
kept I would like send him magazines and
commissary money and stuff to kind of
keep them going but then you had subcool
you had bog you had all these guys that
were growing the Dank strains and the
way I was selling it to them was I was
like listen everyone thinks their shit's
the best but these bags are going to be
like the word of God even if you don't
believe in God they'll be the word of
whatever you do believe in because when
you run your material through these bags
your resin will not be able to hide from
you once you've unveiled it from
everything else that was present and uh
subcool and you know I was talking to
this uh about this with Addison today
when you know I first started doing this
I caught Sam's attention because not
many people were doing what I was doing
you know then when Matt rise came out
and then eventually Nick they caught my
attention I was like oh what are these
guys doing what I've learned over the
years from all of these unique
characters sure yeah we might be able to
follow clean Sops and have Chef likee
standards but really what we have is an
old factory that allows us to track down
incredible breeders and Growers and
suddenly when you're running material
like that because I remember the first
four five six times I
ran material through bags it was
terrible and it wasn't until breeder
Steve was like I got some uh shisha
Berry the yellow line I was like o the
yellow line that was my favorite line of
the red and the yellow afan that were
used to produce the two phenos of
shishka
berry anyway the first time I ran that
and actually saw full melt and prior to
that I had only ever seen full melt in
like Sam's bong when Rob puffed me down
in this Thai restaurant in Amsterdam and
said if it don't bubble it ain't worth
the trouble and I watched it all boiling
and bubbling I was like oh my God I have
to find that it took
me it took me almost four years to find
that because I saw it in 95 and then I
didn't have it myself till around like
the end of 98 the start of 99 which is
when fresh Hades and Bubble Bags was uh
was
founded you know I gotta I gotta come in
and and put in a beautiful word because
we were talking so much about Frenchie
and then came on with sub you know talk
about someone who was out there
incredibly passionate also about the
soil and not something I say very often
but he didn't give a [ __ ] and I really
appreciated that about him because that
was sort of the energy that needed to
push forward for the genetics to be able
to get out there for the information to
get out there and he came up with his uh
you know subsoil recipe which was
organic he did start to bring the term
organic to to the World flavor and as
much you
know I became and the Rev a little bit
yeah you know we always say that people
can't change or that you know we we
stick with something and we may stay
with it our whole lives I I became
really close to sub um after his house
burned down and the heart and
soul that he came
to um in his life was just astounding
and I just had so much love for the life
that he lived you know um big up to miss
Jill because we're talking a lot about
his genetics but she was a big part of
that as well and you know just just so
much love for for being human and and
ending with with heart and soul so you
know Big Ups
to now he had a great impact he
definitely I mean subcool was that was
like the first
real you know um like a a laser point
focus on a specific flavor that for me
for like to some of the stuff that I had
tasted from him it was like so different
from like an Afghan or anything else
because it had such like a a really
interesting flavor to all of his stuff
and then and then when it came to like I
think maybe the first purple hash I ever
saw was was was when Matt rise ran some
of his stuff and it was and I was just
like holy [ __ ] what's hash can be purple
like what the [ __ ] is this and like so
he he definitely had a strong influence
on on everything and I think other guys
at the same time were like that I was
just thinking were like DJ Short you
know his stuff was was cracking at the
same time Soma you know I was I was
nothing changed my life I was an indoor
grower that was setting up houses my
buddies were were real estate dudes that
were loan officers so they were just
they were building track houses in the
in the Central Valley and I would just
go and they'd get a new house and I'd go
in and rip the thing apart and boom set
up the growing and I had a landscape
company and I would just go there and
mow the lawn and tend I had this system
set up and I did that and my life
changed when I found New York City
Diesel because it was so thick and so
citrusy and that was like s stuff at the
same time and it was just like that that
whole that whole era that we're talking
about like BPG and you know what the
other one I thought about the other day
was
Romulan like I would love to wash
Romulan right now and just see what
goes I was cuts too you know how I got I
was telling somebody this is how o OG it
was back in the day this is how I got
Romulan I was working for Ed and he said
we're going to a clone exchange we go to
an undisclosed location a van meets us
we put on blindfolds we put hoods on we
get in the van and we are driven around
for an hour then we are we arrive
wherever we arrive we take our boxes get
out we led into a house when we got in
the house then we took our hoods then we
were allowed to take our our I I eye
masks off and then we got high we showed
each other our plants and uh I got
Romulan and that's when we got
grapefruit as well but grapefruit was
what year was that uh that was
2000 yeah 2000 dude I'll tell you I'll
tell you the fact that you got
grapefruit and Romulan lends a lot to
your story that you got those
simultaneously because and I go way back
with Romulan since who I I don't know
who Romulan Joe got it from but I knew
Romulan Joe and how I met Romulan Joe
was Hillary hit me up one day and was
like listen one of you know the Growers
this was at the club and I was like how
many Growers can you possibly have it's
been like six months she might she might
have had three of us and I was one of
them and so the other one was this dude
Romulan Joe I didn't know it at the time
but she was like can you help out and
get this guy back set up I was like yeah
of course so I invested some money to
get his grow built up met him eventually
giant of a man teddy bear of a man
incredible but I got turned on to that
true true Romulan and it was just like
my god dude we could not get enough of
that [ __ ] someone's got to it's got to
and yeah it's funny enough I saw ramula
I saw ramul and Joe years later and he
just he was walking with a big jar of
weed and he gave it to me and I was like
what's this he's like oh it's freeder
Steve's old grapefruit cut you know I've
been I've been growing it you know the
Romulan and the grapefruit those have
always been my go-to so when you said
you got the Romulan and the grapefruit
that could very well have been from
Romulan Joe it would have to be if it
was the deal
anyway was huge I do remember he was
huge so this was 90 this was 90 uh
97 yeah so this I met ramul and Joe yeah
this was 2000 at an undisclosed location
in an area where I don't know so it's
just one of those actually actually it's
99 because I came in 99 so it was
actually in 99 because I worked from Ed
from uh 99 to uh just before an
01 um so yeah yeah and so then the same
thing once we did our exchange we then
had to put the mask on then put the
hoods back on we were LED back outside
and then driven back to our undisclosed
location of which we then just all
dispersed so be thankful you can
actually go to a store and actually get
your [ __ ] cuz that [ __ ] was
nerve-wracking dog I'm not going to deny
dude they never he didn't give it away
to anyone just just so you know like
that had to have come like from a very
strong source to say hey you need to
give this to these people over here like
that people could have done that it was
By Invitation Only and Ed Rosenthal was
a genetics known guy in Northern
California so it could very well have
been I I it was so long ago I can't
recall
would we'd have to ask Hillary about
that yeah but it would have to have come
from Joe if it was the real ROM oh that
was the the the Romulan at BPG was
definitely the real ROM that [ __ ] was
great fire that [ __ ] was so good I
remember that stuff hey you know I was
thinking at the end I I would bet money
right now that K from triome
Technologies was at that undisclosed
location uh where he
was definitely he he has that same he
has a a funny ass story I think he told
it to High Times about like haraldo
Rivera didn't he like blindfold Heraldo
or something like that yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah that's just how it was done
you know because you didn't want people
to remember a location where you were
you didn't want a picture of an angle
because people could figure out at night
where triangulation of a star was I mean
get robbed like that's right and Romulan
got lost because of the white powdery
milde surge of the early o and it was
just one of those plants that was just a
[ __ ] magnet for it unfor fortunately
and it just you know that's why it kind
of made its way out and but I've yet to
find a genetic with that type of flavor
profile that it had it was Wonder
there's there's a cat in Sacramento
right now that has a genetics company
called Romulan genetics and they and
they have some crosses and some other
stuff and I've been communicating with
them but I want to see if it's actually
uh if it's actually the Romulan I
haven't I haven't gotten in touch with
them you you could tell a that's the
thing about the Romulan
if he gets
mold oh really yeah exactly everyone
that said they had the Romulan since
Romulan Joe stopped growing it just did
not have the Romulan I met one guy on
overgrow that had some Romulan cross and
I was like that has Romulan in it
because it's kind of the Romulan is kind
of like the Shish ber in that sense
anything you put the Shish Berry into
I'm not sure if it was osine or what
profile it was but it just had this you
just always knew that the shishka berry
was in there it's in the Nicole from
marinos it's in the the Barb from uh uh
Matt the great Gardener you know you can
taste it in those cultivars that shishka
Berry and yes shout out to DJ Short
because he was uh yeah he was also a big
uh you know just producing fire uh at
that time you know early 90s late 90s
early 2000s and that yeah we were a big
part of those those growing you know you
know and Eugene in that
area mid 90s we were definitely I was
early 90s early early blueberry
everywhere blueberry and Trinity huge
strains in those times kind on
tour the kind on tour and that was all
DJ Short stuff out of Eugene also and
that was being all put on to tour also s
lived in Eugene before he moved to
Holland and then there was kind of cray
crazy stuff behind that what's
that did you know
Seuss Seuss s and Seuss they yeah s and
Seuss he was the parrot guy he had all
the birds he also the same area
abolutely yeah yeah that's those guys go
back the Blue Dream the Blue Dream the
flow and the blueberry were all created
right around the same time what do you
got there you got is that a is that a is
that a blueberry no this is Flo this is
actually Flo I actually
a bud of the flow that I grew when I was
living in La when I when I was had moved
to LA was working with Todd McCormack
there and I was growing on my own at
home and I grew this flow I loved it so
much I literally brought it into my
tattoo artists and said I want that here
he's like
okay and then it the genetic disappeared
the flow made great hash too yeah he's
still make seeds of it I I have a few
packs of it actually I've good I gotta
say that DJ shortz genetics you know
really made a stance on dead tour
anytime that those genetics were brought
out on to shake down you could smell it
you know before it even even hit the
street and it was what everybody was
looking for so his genetics really spoke
volumes without you know having a name
attached to it at that time so yeah yeah
so many
different it's like now I look at it and
it's it's crazy because you have
different types of breeders now there's
like so big now so much so open that
it's crazy and it's like I just love
going to the the Breeders that aren't
hash breeders and looking at those
genetics and being like I wonder wonder
how that would be in hash or I wonder
this or or looking at the old school
stuff and thinking that's that's the
most painful thing to do to yourself is
to think of old school ICS and then how
good it would have been in like in like
rosin form or something like that it's a
good way to torture yourself right there
oh can you imagine the Romulan and rosin
oh that's what I'm saying that grape
flavor it keeps me up at night at the
end right that's what it
is original ha good grave we need a germ
plasm Institute of North America we need
a germ plasm of North America so that
all these genetics are saved so that
they're kept for posterity so that we
can't continue to have these stories of
lore so that they're actually protected
so whoever's watching this get on it we
need that [ __ ]
yesterday I'd be okay for some of my
taxes going to pay for stuff like that
in society you know it's like well you
know we pay a certain amount for all the
philosophy strains that have been found
in the twi we pay a certain amount for a
things stuck in there that have to be
bio remediated that Serra and others
have found out via genetics that they
have to pull out so if you you can TC
them but if you don't actually clean the
genetic out of those bio problems you're
just perpetuating those issues and
inconsistency so there's yes it's just
it's a step further so we have we have
to get Reggie involved is what you're
telling me yeah pretty
much we gotta call on the flip side of
that you know also regener generating
old strains through really deep soil
multi- diversity
multi-species uh you know biome is
another great way to do it because then
you're just flooding that that that
plant's Endo fidic system and and and
flooding it with different microbiology
and then that really also cleans it so
just the opposite spectrum of when it
comes by utilizing our Farmers when it
comes out of tissue culture you got to
make inoculation Point
yeah out of retirement get you to to
bring skunk back
Sam yeah what up one back we need it
like the yeah that's very important
there's there's some I'll wait another
few years until people really appreciate
it because why didn't anybody keep a
clone
good again
about the skunk one or the fruit one
because the skunk one all those people
got busted and they couldn't keep
skunk skunk one was originally skunky I
bred it sweeter I like the sweet version
had a better High flavor and effects to
me but uh yeah uh you gotta remember
skunk was never more than about 177% THC
it was not no ball buster but people
consistently pick it over stuff that was
2025 because they liked it better yeah
yeah when I worked for Richard Lee who
did the Bulldog here in America I was
the guy who worked in his Gardens
because he was in a chair he loves skunk
number one but he liked that cut cut at
six and a half weeks that's where he
liked it as opposed to letting it go to
eight
weeks Rob liked it a bit earlier than me
too but I liked it maxed out because I'm
a resin producer I don't smoke weed what
was your max for
skunk
uh maybe 10
weeks
wow could you imagine skunky uh uh
rosing right
now I like the road I can remember
skunk that's what all skunk was it was
Roadkill in the
beginning didn't Todd McCormack just do
a big skunk number one seed release that
he he did from like last year I heard I
heard that myth in that rumor Todd's a
good friend of mine I don't know what
that means
did
yes I heard that he may be at
Legends Todd Todd's a serious smoker so
I I've never seen him smoke a Hubbly
Bubbly though
Sam are you gonna come to
Legends no I'm not GNA come to
California uh first of all I don't think
it's safe to travel are you gonna do the
uh The Telecast with us so that we can
say
hi I'll consider it we can talk about it
but uh
yeah as soon as we can travel I'll be
glad to come to California and I'll be
glad to go many other places in the
world uh awesome but uh it it's still a
bit iffy to me there's just not enough
people are vaccinated in the world or
have had it already to make me feel safe
enough Y no it's true it's a definite
Factor at this point for sure for travel
I mean Mark can can people or Canada
just opened up I think but it's can we
can Americans go to Canada I don't think
we can yet right yeah I think the I
think the ones that have had their their
Jabs are allowed to come here I think we
opened actually to all International
Travelers recently that have uh their
vaccination which I get that the
vaccination keeps them from getting uh
really deathly ill or dying doesn't keep
them from getting the the virus so that
seems kind of strange it's like okay so
you're vaccinated or not you you can
bring the virus into the country my
brother-in-law was vaccinated twice
and he got the
virus so he was he had already had it he
was vaccinated twice and he got it
again also in British Columbia on no
comment no comment I'll leave that alone
as well um but I'll just
just so if you come to British columb
colia and for British Colombians
now some people who do believe in true
health and have other ways of healing
themselves will be banned from society
so you will not be able to go to any
restaurant no Club no music no uh you
can't have weddings public
transportation public transportation
public transportation um and from
September 13th till January 30th so it
might be a long time where you see a
good amount of people from British
Columbia CU some people need to stay at
their house he that's
ridiculous oh I suspect it'll end up
being like Austria where they just have
these really fast tests and if you don't
have that jab or whatever they'll just
get you to do the quick test and then
it's like yeah there you go I I don't
think it's going to be quite like uh
we're going to be a segregated apar tide
uh you know uh
obviously the conspiracy freaking me is
always like oh overbearing powers of
governments are somewhat terrifying
these guys do tend to [ __ ] it up more
often than
not on Marcus tell the truth what you
want is you want people to wear a little
yellow uh vaccination star on their
shoulder dude that's what they did in
North Vancouver near where I lived they
were giving gold stars away to people
who got two vaccines and I guess an
elderly woman um from like Poland was in
there and she lost it she was just like
what the what what are you what are you
doing it's interesting too because
someone someone I spoke to the other day
was like you know this is terrible to
make these correlations between like a
vaccine passport and the Holocaust and
I'm like okay but like this did happen
and it was in our paper and it was kind
of a connection between the vaccine
passport and you know the Hol cost
because the gold star was the thing that
got her it was a gold star now it wasn't
a six-pointed gold star it was
five-pointed gold star which of course
people in the comments section started
having huge arguments about but you
could imagine from someone from the
perspective of someone that lived
through the Holocaust that that would
leave a bad taste in their mouth and
maybe just do it a different way
thinkink Americans come to most places
in Europe unless they can prove they've
been vaccinated
yeah I think Canada's the same thing
oh yeah I'm lucky that I'm happy right
here yeah I mean I live in a forest with
the ocean out in front and I got some
food growing on my deck and some
cannabis PLS I'm feeling pretty good in
the in the area that I'm that I'm in and
I feel pretty healthy too I don't feel
that I'm you know yeah but it's fun to
travel and I haven't traveled a long
time
yeah know that's why be that's when I
see you Sam when I travel anywhere I go
in Europe boom into Amsterdam boom over
to Sam if I go to Spain well [ __ ] he's
like I'll come to Spain let's get a
place but he used to wear a mask and
just suck it up you know I've been
traveling you know it's not that bad
important sorry Marcus I think that it's
really important no matter how you feel
about the vaccine or or not the vaccine
that we all still need to come together
on um you know separatist uh ideology
and separatist roll out like this I
think that it's incredibly dangerous
those people who are showing vaccine
passports to get into a restaurant and
think that it's okay for them to sit
down and eat food it's not okay because
there's a lot of people out there who
cannot be vaccinated because of their
health and well-being of all different
kinds of reasons maybe they don't
believe in it because of of their
religion and that's a true thing maybe
they've had trauma with it we all need
to recognize that there is one major
sort of energy that's bearing down on us
right now and joining together is of
utmost importance it doesn't matter how
you feel about the vaccine or what your
Visions are about it we cannot be
separating out people people like this
it's not good it's just not good for all
different uh facets of humanity and nor
for our future generations and nor for
our health and well-being come on people
never have we been more sick than from
this and I'm not talking about just
sickness of covid I'm talking about
mental emotional illness that people are
having with separations of their family
because some people might feel that the
vaccine is okay other people are feeling
it's not okay when has it ever been that
somebody got a m measles vaccine and
then another person didn't but they went
to war with each other and they don't
speak with each other anymore this is
happening everywhere if we don't rise
above this then we lose all of us lose
vaccinated or not vaccinated so that's
my high horse and I hope that you all
hear this out of love and out of
kindness and out of togetherness this is
not about separatism this is not about a
vir our communing species that we need
need each other to be able to have a
healthy species into the
future yeah well you need to be able to
have dialogue we need dialogue and
that's the key what they did was you
know a little while ago they started to
compel speech and you know they did it
here in Canada where they went through
the universities and they were like hey
we've now made some new rules you got to
call uh people what they want to be
called and here's a bunch of pronouns
that come into play and there was like
there was this dude in Toronto a
university Professor was like no no you
can't compel speech and then of course
everyone was like oh you're against
Jordan Peterson they're like you're
against the transgender Community he's
like no I'm not against the trans you're
an anti-semite no I've actually tght
about the Holocaust they're throwing all
this [ __ ] at this guy and really all he
ever stood up for was the compel of
speech and who see who controls speech
controls what is defined as hate and
it's a very slippery slope you can
create um you know these discussions
that are now one-sided because and I
kind of try to remind people cannabis
was one of those things for a very long
time the people in the Cannabis World sh
I'll wait till I come
back am I
back Eland am I back you're back sorry
you're back the whole time yes
you you did one of these entire time I
was saying I was saying some good stuff
I don't know if I'll pull it back out
but um yeah I guess uh I guess that's
gone uh what were you smoking
again uh the last thing I hit was some
strawana 120 Micron F out
six-star okay don't expound in strawana
ladies and okay no I was you know what I
was gonna say I was just gonna say about
that they've removed the dialogue there
it's like through this Jordan Peterson
conversation of compelling speech now
they're controlling what you can and
can't talk about and it's reminiscent of
of the pot days where it was Prohibition
only the gnarly of us were willing to
speak we all seemed like we were kind of
insane no one really had to listen to us
because we were just crackpots and now
they've done the same thing for you know
whe could even get high
times no that's what I mean and so now
they're doing this similar thing on this
other discussion it's like look okay I'm
not going to choose a side right now
here but I'll tell you that at least let
both sides have a dialogue because if
you make one side so afraid 90% of
people won't be speaking that group
anymore and the people who do navigate
that group might come across this as
being a bit uh off thewall so you have a
better quality and a better caliber
dialogue if you can allow everyone to
not have to feel afraid for their
lives they want to have a discussion
about something so that's where I stand
and that's what I wanted to say yeah my
my opinion is it's not that I it's not
that I uh don't care about it it's it's
just that there are so many other things
that I care more about it's really what
it comes down to I'm just like it's sure
it's a conversation but it's just a
conversation if someone tells me that
they got the vaccine or not I don't
think any differently it's more you know
I'm like do whatever the [ __ ] you want
man I never and that's why I love being
a cannabis person because it's like I've
always wanted everyone to feel that way
about us so I don't [ __ ] care I'm
like I mean I like seeing people get
fired up I think that's interesting but
at the same time I I also think think
that it's like yeah we're losing we're
losing an understanding and and that
understanding is that like people should
have an opinion like let them have their
opinion you should ask yourself why you
get so worked up about someone else's
[ __ ] opinion that really should be
the question like you know why do you
care so why is it why is it that it
always becomes so political and it's
pretty interesting that the entire world
is dealing with this but yet American
politics comes into every single
conversation like I I really think we
separating our own medical freedoms own
body freedoms from politics people this
isn't about American politics they're
just making you believe it is yeah so I
think that really important that our
owns and our own medical
freedoms look at different things and
the information to be able to look at
all sides of it we need to be able to
gain education by looking at all
different facets of it and if we don't
have all different facets then we have a
very small conversation going that just
goes around in circles and that's what
happens when you politicize anything so
when you politicize things that's what
you do you politicize it so come
On's president of the United States
elect the clown expect the circus this
is all part of that circus ladies and
gentlemen sorry yeah I mean elect a
reality star as the President of the
United States end of story how about
don't allow who's the to affect what
we're trying not to talk about politics
right
now yeah you guys went there so I went
there too right I look at it from a
health perspective I take care of
patients I've been dealing with patients
the whole reason Addis and I knew each
other that got me an upper respiratory
infection because there was something I
couldn't see okay so that's still
ongoing you know even though the the
traditional Market is still going going
strong and going stronger than the legal
Market it's it's still not testing and
doing the things that need to be done to
protect the consumer at the end of the
day and that's the whole reason we did
it now the overabundance and the
overregulation has kind of ruined the
idea and thought but you know I am a
medical patient for one I have golf War
syndrome so I have my own sensitivity to
whatever however I have employees that I
have to take care of that we've worked
through we were declared actual people
who could actually go out in the world
and serve
others and we were also the first one to
allow the vaccine and I want to continue
to see people and take care of people so
yeah I don't believe there's two kinds
of science I believe there's one science
which is the replicatable science that
anyone could do which I think Dr Mark
and of course I would call him Dr Deora
because
he uh you know it's just one of those
things that science is replicatable and
you know let's fall upon science belief
is one thing but when you cross over
your door and effect and kill people who
I know which I know I just had multiple
friends die in Louisiana because they
decided Ed not to get the vaccine and
they had their obituaries and it's
terrible it's painful to watch it hurts
but at the same time you know I'm in
favor of vaccines but I'm not in favor
of mandatorily seizing people's ability
to speak or have their choice but at
what point do it cross over and it
affect other people when you're out and
about and going because that's the
reality is I have enough deaths on my
conscience from war try not to add any
more scalps to my reality sorry to use
that terminology it wasn't meant any
type of uh of attack of any one shape or
form it's just a reality of War
sometimes uh that's just the reality
that we face so uh I agree that
everybody has their right but I also
agree with science but at the same time
when we're out as a society and we're
seeing worldwide situation you know we
have to realize that we all have a
responsibility to our fellow fellow
brothers and sisters and what that is is
your choice to decide however I know
I've made my choices and I'm double
vaxed at the moment yeah and I just
wanted to I just wanted to add to that
that we all do have our own choices and
we also have a responsibility that when
we're sick with the flu or anyone has a
cold that you stay home everybody does
that you don't feel good you stay home
but we're not out there you know asking
for people's records on whether they
have HIV or whether they have syphilis
or whether they have Hepatitis A B or C
because all of those things are actually
contractable in restaurants so you know
I I think that it's really important
that if we're just going to be
separating out this one thing that we
need to really truly have the science
and the science is not just
hyperfocusing on this one virus let's
talk about all of it and all of the
contagion that humans are walking around
with so you know to be focusing on one
just really I'm sorry it doesn't truly
make sense if we're looking at the
science and if we do look at science we
can find lots of GMO style agricultureal
which creates super bugs and super
sicknesses so there's no guarantee that
everyone's going to get fully vaccinated
the whole thing's going to go away what
there is a guarantee is that it's going
to transform
and it's going to become something
different so if we're going to get into
mandating things let's get
mandating chemicals out of our packaging
and garbage going away and and and
acting health and well-being regimens
because uh the government's not
responsible for our health and
well-being we we are responsible for our
health and wellbeing or maybe instead of
spending billions of dollars on hand
sanitizers and masks that really po
possibly if we are doing the science
then we're actually recognizing that
that may not be to the best of our
health and well-being and actually
fighting this virus that we're all
dealing with if we spent billions of
dollars on actual knowledge and actual
science that when people get out into
the air and out in in into nature that
they're they're uptaking a healthier
microbiome when we laugh with people
when we share a joint in a circle are we
really truly passing more negativity or
are we passing more positivity so really
and truly Gathering and at and I hear
everything that you're saying I totally
want to respect what you're saying and
you're saying freedom of choice and I'm
saying right on brother thank you so
much for saying that but also I just
wanted to speak that there is science
and other facets that we aren't testing
for that we aren't isolating people out
for for providing their medical tests at
restaurants or in public Gatherings
because it doesn't make sense oh it's
illogical but speaking of science this
one goes to Sam specifically I just got
the iacm bulletin and apparently they've
gone under and are restructuring which
is the International Association of
cannaboid medicines do you know anything
about this or the
restructuring and how to try to do this
online thing which I believe they
cancelled for this October and uh I
think all the weight was on frano and
just a few people and so they're trying
to spread it out and reorganize it and
and also they're going to be more of an
umbrella Organization for all the
national versions of
them thank you for that clarification I
was Cannabis curious
I really like the work they do and fro
is a very special
friend and I appreciate what they do and
I hope they're able to continue because
they're stay at the Forefront of
cannabis research and getting asked to
us canaban nerds out here who you know
just want to see what's going
on and you know we're of course we're
hyperfocused on cannabis and because
it's a cannabis uh you know talk and
because we're also so totally entrenched
in cannabis and thinks it's the best
thing in the world and also the reason
why the endocannabinoid system was even
discovered is because there started to
be a little bit of money you know Sam as
you know money started to be flowing
into you know hemp and and cannabis
research for us to be able to even find
that but I wanted to open up the
conversation of you know there's all
facets of nature that are corresponding
within our body that are communic ating
within our body that have yet to be
discovered what about the herbal
cannaboid system so we talk about you
know compounding you know cannabis but
we have such a connection with all
different types of plants it's why we're
able to get high off of peyote it's why
we're able to get high off of cannabis
it's not just an endocannabinoid system
that's
just knowledge of us to understand
how Herbal Remedies are such a huge
factor in our health and well-being um
all the way down to you know repairing
our cellular DNA well into into future
Generations that's like what I was
saying earlier about health and and like
optimizing Health through biohacking you
know focusing on gut health focusing on
these other things so that you can enjoy
life like once I started on focusing on
gut health and and understanding that
all of this mitochondria is built in the
gut and and all your body's made of
cells which is mitochondria driven like
once you figure that [ __ ] out and you
start eating correctly to whoever you
are and I just say that because people
can eat you know there's food that's
served everywhere but have you ever sat
down and kind of figured out what you
eat best like what your what's best for
you like listen a lot of people aren't
listening they're not slowing down
they're not taking the time to do the
research to figure out what that post
really meant and and they want to speak
about it and that's the I mean you would
think that more people would smoke hash
because it slows you down and and it and
it makes you focus on little different
things and like my whole my whole J
everything I'm doing my whole Mantra in
my whole life is Hash it's simple it's
one thing it's that
direction and that exactly cream hash
that direction that one thing and all my
business falls into that everything else
falls into that and it makes everything
much more simple and anything outside of
that doesn't attract my attention that's
all you know it's like that's why I
called and was like
laugh because you're saying that all I
got to do is just you know focus on hash
it's going to be so simple but what
you're focusing on is a fractal medicine
that has 10 billion possibilities so
that's on that becoming so simplified
life work it's I like it it's working
out incredibly well up to this point
so staying in my Lane I'm just
continuing to do this and I'm grateful
that like how many people get to do what
they really [ __ ] love and I think all
of us get to do what we [ __ ] love I
mean Mark loves what he does Mark has
the fish thing and we all have this [ __ ]
in our life that we get to do because of
this because we understand that like
this is what we love this is what we do
but we're so blessed for that too we're
so much more we're that's why that's why
I started giving weed away when I did
because I would meet people that weren't
in such a good position and you'd Stoke
them out with weed and they'd be like
[ __ ] yeah and then you changed their day
and you had an impact on that
so it it was it's just that that's the
type of [ __ ] that I think people need to
understand that simplify first but start
with your health and then figure out
what you love and run in that direction
and be brave
and that's what life's about and do that
and all this [ __ ] falls into place and
be kind and loving and do that [ __ ]
right you know and that's the note we're
leaving it on right there that's the one
I like that I we you know we got into
some good stuff there for a bit but I
was going to crush this out at 12 I let
us go 13 minutes over got my little guy
looking at me through the
door big do eyes wanting to go out
electric
skateboarding thank you everyone for
coming out I really appreciate it it was
awesome as always it's been almost a
hundred days since we had a hash church
so uh we'll see if maybe we can uh make
another one happen next week I'm not
sure yet but uh I do really appreciate
everyone for coming and sharing their
truths and uh yeah fan Legends of hash
next month talk about that again some
more
thanks Big luck peace
out take carebody
in