make sure we're all good here make sure
everyone can
hear I think we're good I think no sound
no no no
no I'll fix it I'll fix
it can you hear
me I can hear the sound
I can hear sound okay excellent all
right listen welcome everyone that was a
little bit of a mild heart attack it was
telling me that I wasn't able to stream
on YouTube today and I had to restart
that little bit freaky uh going to start
letting people in welcome to uh hash
Church 4.0 episode 8 Legends of hash
sponsorship episode uh pretty stoked to
have this episode nice to always talk
with some new folks uh not that everyone
will be new definitely a nice new group
of folks what's going on agrotech you
guys were on the
ball well you know we want to make sure
our our connection worked you know what
I dude I just had a heart attack I went
to go stream I basically there's a bunch
of stuff I have to do when I do this
because we're streaming through you uh
Zoom that ends up going through YouTube
well for the first time ever when I went
go live on YouTube it said you do not
have permission to live stream that was
at 8:59 so I was just like okay I've
done this a couple hundred times I'm not
going to freak out but I did text
Addison and he was like what the [ __ ] so
glad to uh I'm going to just be letting
people in as we go here um Reese Puffs
in the background with the pipe to match
little Wormhole JP Wormhole
there what we got going on here all
right Alex Oh beautiful I love those
pipes dude absolutely love them this one
sh for sure oh my
goodness where to start this is great
faces that I don't necessarily recognize
I'm stoked to have all of you guys in
here first of all um super super stoked
that you guys uh you know sponsored
Legends of hash got my old Legends of
hash from 2016 in Barcelona t-shirt on
right now this is one of the last
legends that I actually uh threw in
Europe and so considering we started in
like ooh I don't know 20 2001 maybe 2001
might have been the first Legends of
hash we'll talk a little bit about
Legends history as we slowly get in here
I love also the fact that everyone's
rolling up with uh with rigs all set up
and ready to go rocking my JP Toro
that's what's up right there little turp
slurping in the house eight oh [ __ ]
there we go I got that right there
tattooed on my body can't get that off
maybe you can nowadays what's going on
Addie what's up buddy dude I'm just
getting uh you know getting to know some
of the boys here these agrotech boys
were on the ball like 30 minutes ago
they came in and I was like mik he
doesn't play he's not missing out you
know Mike you know Mike and the boys I'm
just meeting Mike and the boys right now
well respected very uh loved and revered
in the industry and definitely one of
the guys that hunted us down to make
sure that he could sponsor the event so
that's what's up good good dudes man
they really really are all about it and
you know definitely wanted to make sure
that we had everything that we needed to
uh to make this thing a [ __ ] Banger
so we we love those cats for sure you
know for us um part of the reason why it
was such such a big deal to do that was
because um you know we're we're really
about um trying to give back you know
we've been pretty blessed to be in
business for 15 years
um and you know everything we do comes
from the Cannabis community so being
able to sponsor an event like this and
and directly give back to the ca
cannabis Community specifically the hash
Community um you know meant a lot to us
and was something that uh you know is is
right up our alley and we we love
smoking hash and getting high so it it
worked out really
good that's perfect yeah no we're we're
grateful man I think that uh it was like
I think you guys were one of the first
ones to reach out to us and uh it meant
a lot you know made it made it easier
for us to get it started and get
everything going you guys in Mills came
forward and just like you know pretty
much lined us up so we could get started
and get everything going so we're super
grateful we appreciate it well and for
the few people out there they're like
whoa what's going on with Legends now
you got cameras and you're having
sponsors you know when Addison hit me up
a couple years ago and said hey you know
I think we should do Legends you know in
California I think I think you know
Kevin and I can pull it off and uh you
know one of the first things he said to
me was and I'm not sure how you've been
doing this out of pocket man but uh you
know we're not going to be able to do
that I'm not sure how you just been
paying for Legends out of pocket because
that's how I rolled with Legends for you
know the first almost 20 years I I there
were no there was no monetization there
was no sponsorships I paid for
everything out of my own pocket and uh
you know just kind of tried to make it
go that way and it was uh it got
expensive fast so I am definitely very
thankful uh to all of the sponsors and
also to you know the team uh at 800 that
we're also not just willing to we're not
just take willing to take anyone's money
for sponsorship like it's almost like
the same way you know you're curating
the products that you use on a daily
basis well you don't want to be curating
products that you don't use on a daily
basis and bring so we there were people
we said no to um there was there was a
substantial amount of people that we
said no to so you know you've been
curated you you know when you get
accepted to this sponsorship it's not
just by giving money it means that you
have the whole background the cool the
coolness Factor the factor that you have
integrity the factor that you know that
you've been curated by Legends of hash
and there's there's something to be said
by that as well because um you know I
just chose to have zero sponsors for
like 20 years because I thought the same
way with hash church this is the first
time I've ever had a kind of episode
like this where you know I've never
monetized hash church I've never taken
any sponsorship money I've never taken
anything for hash church because I was
worried that if I did that it would
affect the Integrity of hash church and
you know for me I was so stuck in hash
church not really realizing what it
meant to the community but after
listening to the community and realizing
like this is really important this is a
conversation that drives our industry
and our community uh it's very important
that we don't bastardize or or or [ __ ]
this up so uh it's been a bit of a nerve
wracker um you know having having the
monetization aspect for for um for
Legends and I told both Kevin and
Addison like all right let's try it out
but whatever you do don't [ __ ] it up
because this is uh this is a this is a
this is a this is a long time thing
going you know like I I sometimes can't
even believe that Legends has been
happening for you know for 20 plus years
but indeed it has it's happened in
Amsterdam God like 14 plus times it's
happened in Barcelona a few times it's
happened in Vancouver a few times it's
happened in Jamaica once uh and now
we're going to be doing the second one
in Los Angeles so it's uh it's a it's a
special thing to be a part of and I'm
just uh very welcoming to all of you and
stoked that you're here and we only have
a couple of hours today but I want to
hear from each and every one of you I
want to hear kind of your backgrounds
and where you came to this and why
Legends is something that you wanted to
be a part of maybe hopefully a little
bit differently than uh than than any
other event that's happening and just uh
yeah puff some bowls with you guys and
uh enjoy the afternoon we got a couple
of hours to get high here well we're
happy to be here and we're humbled to be
here so you know thank you for allowing
us to be here and participate um you
know I'm sure I speak for a lot of the
the other sponsors and people involved
when I say that um it's it's a good
Circle to be in and it's a good group of
people to support um all the all the
makers and people that have been invited
are all very high level so again for us
uh it's really easy event to give back
to and participate
with oh yeah what's up
J hey how you doing good man good to see
you you too J JP's three hours ahead of
us he's mad ripped
already he's been ripping since 9:00
a.m. on his side Fu go five I know me I
W up at five start at five hu huge
pleasure to have you JP all you guys
especially um but JP I think it's uh you
know I I love the idea and the whole
story behind how the slurper came to
life and how Marcus has something to do
with it and I kind of feel like now it's
sort of Full Circle and and just kind of
brings everybody closer together
together and uh I don't know if if
everyone knows that story but um you
know JP you could tell it Marcus you
could tell it I think it's uh an
interesting story that's kind of you
know when it comes to dabbing when it
comes to solventless especially I think
the slurpers kind of added this whole
different component you could take a guy
who could dab super hard on a 30 mil
Banger and and rip the [ __ ] out of that
thing and then you put a slurper in
front of them and it's a totally
different hit it you need a different
set of lungs to rip that thing get a
different flavor different taste you can
[ __ ] with the temp um you need a temp
temperature gauge you need all these
different things to do it you need some
pearls you need a [ __ ] assistant an
ISO dip you need all these different
things but the the you know the
development of the slurper I think has
changed the [ __ ] game so heavily uh
and and that's you know we wouldn't have
it if it weren't for you and Marcus
inspiring and uh so yeah it's it's a
huge pleasure to have you with us and uh
really makes me kind of a little a
little uh fanish to kind of have you
here but at the same time um you know I
think you deserve it
so oh thank you thank you very much I
appreciate all that that that's a it's a
hell of an introduction thank you it's a
lot to follow up
with I appreciate that thank you I I'm
you know I'm just I'm just I'm just glad
to be here man be just glad to be a part
of it all you know and uh I think uh you
know if it wasn't for you guys out there
you know doing your thing and making
some really good
um hash and showing other people how to
do it you know what I mean and like the
the pioneering of it all I mean 20
something years I mean it's probably
longer than that but you
know cheers
I yeah thank you man no dude I didn't
even know I had anything to do with this
he like wrote he sent me one one day and
was like oh by the way here's article I
I I was interviewed in the Northeast
magazine and yeah I was I telling the
story about your part in the tur slurper
and I was like my part in the TP slur
what the [ __ ] did what did I do and then
he he told me this story and I was like
oh [ __ ] awesome I mean feel free I mean
feel free to tell the story I mean it's
I mean it's like folklore
here uh so so many people like you know
uh really you inspire a lot of people
people a lot of my homies and they check
you out and um you know they're always
like yo did you see that episode of blow
or did you see how he's like burping
turps did you see how like they're doing
all this stuff and like trying to like
and I was like oh no and then it was
like a thing where you know we were just
like I was like just trying to make a
nail that you could just burp turps with
but not for dabbing almost just for
flavor and then all sudden it turned
into oh let's let's let's make it let's
actually make it percolate let's
actually like make it so that it
percolates and then I don't know six
seven designs later here we are you know
the different tweaks of it all and then
uh you know the fog you know because you
have to test it then you got to go and
make another one and it's just like you
know before you know it you're
really really really high but you're
still like working with hydrogen and gas
and and and working on a la and you burn
yourself and you get injured and you
because you're just like how you know
you're still alive it I mean really I
mean that's just like I mean it's just
like you know talk about like
working while super you know messed up
it's you know now I can just you know
now I can do it it's like no no problem
you know I'm so used to testing out
prototypes and just going back to the
tourch I think a lot of us glass blowers
do do that like I think that's like our
thing you know what I mean um at least
in in in my world
anyway good to know that you were it's
good to know that you were sacrificing
turps to create the slurper it was like
a sacrifice you know like throwing a
virgin into a [ __ ] volcano or
something well I mean I mean that it was
so long ago that I mean you know things
sometimes take a little time to to pick
up and to like you know get out there
and and you
know uh but at the same time you know
there's technology that also helps other
things also Blossom so to speak you know
what I mean like if it wasn't for like
you know the the dab right the temptech
all those devices that people are using
to
to to you know figure out their their
flavor Zone their heat temp you know I
think that really helps and I think that
you know before that we were just timing
it out and sometimes you know uh certain
quartzes hit differently with different
you know it's it's a game you know what
I mean you got to figure it out and then
it's like oh well how do we clean it and
then it's like oh we can dunk tank it
you know and I think all these things
happen and then it makes a product not
seem so intimidating or so hard to
um you know
because the turf slurper took
off in in
Hawaii and you know I mean it happened
in the in the
states and I think that you know like I
had some fan base in the states people
that weren't afraid to like you know go
outside the box a little bit and try
something
new um and but in Hawai I mean such a
huge fan base in
Hawaii and I guess there was like a
couple that were like floating around
the island that actually spun the turps
or spun the Pearl when it was in there
and at the time people were just like
throwing like logs of like you know um
shatter in there and it was like
spinning and slowly evaporating as it
was spinning and then um before you knew
it
uh some of these Islanders reached out
and we're like yo did you know that some
of these nails some of these some of
these you know Spin and we were just
like No And so then we started like
developing more about that and almost
kind of like getting the The Vortex or
the spinning motion because anything
that spins is a longer distance than
straight
so that was that next thing you know
here we are I don't want to take up too
much time here dude people are loving
this conversation trust me it's uh what
do you think go ahead Addie oh go ahead
what do you think it was like where you
said that those guys were running around
the island kind of pushing it what was
that turning point that you think that
sort of blew it the [ __ ] up to where it
is now was it some sort of development
in the pipe or was it just the pearls
coming in what kind of blew it up
because now it's like you know to to to
give you the credit everyone in their
mom is putting out a slurper or slurp or
type column thing what do you think that
was uh
um I don't know I mean you know this
industry
is like just so like ancestral and we're
all just like feeding off each other
really it's like you know yeah the TP
serer is great but it wouldn't be there
if it wasn't for the dab r or dab Tech
it wouldn't be there if it wasn't for
people like actually like oh we're
actually G to start soaking
now um like or dunk tanking or what you
know there's so many different
terminologies that people have but you
get what I'm saying
and I think that when you can like look
outside the thing because back in the
day it was like oh let's just Q-tip it
out and keep going you know what I mean
I was like oh wait a minute if you put
fingerprints on it that's going to burn
into the quartz too oh okay so now we're
now we're taking care of it inside and
out you know what I mean okay now we're
having some interesting design some
interesting airf flow it's a little bit
unique there's an inside and outside
that's all weird that has to be clean so
now what is it you just dunk it in a
tank sometimes you have three tanks one
for dirty one you know like kind of like
um Camp back in the day when there
wasn't a lot of water you know what I
mean and you had like three or four tubs
one had soap and then you just rinse one
and you just kept on going and then at
the end that was clean you know I'm not
saying that's covid clean now or any
kind of like you know whatever but back
in my day uh that was Camp so
um I have a little dunk tank system like
that I also mess around with ultrasonic
cleaners just to figure out different
ways how to keep the quartz and the
product itself clean and does anyone
make like a Ultra like a mini Ultras
sunic cleaner yeah because that that's
the best way to clean ultrasound
cleaning when when we were um you know
not a lot of people know but we used to
make well we still make enails but we
used to like really be heavy in the enil
space and uh
yeah ultrasonic cleaning is the best for
Titanium or any type of surface really
so does anyone have like a little a
little like a ultrasonic bath kit yet
that's all I use I've been doing that
for like the last four weeks now five
weeks I I've been using it with my
actual glass work for years right um and
then I just recently switched over to um
doing it this way especially uh the ones
that actually actually have a heating
Source on them as well so that you're
also getting a little I mean you know
you do get a little
evaporation a little quicker but I think
it you know I feel like when you pull it
out it kind of dries quicker because
it's a little hot you know a little
warm
um my test is more to see the longevity
of the nail to see how long I can keep
it from clouding up or chazzing or you
know doing all
the things that sometimes courtz gets to
a certain point with if you're like
neglected with it um but I keep I keep
having people coming in here and say
like to mention that you know um another
thing with the the slurpers flavor that
was one of our biggest things and I
think that's where bubble man came in
was trying to capture that flavor that
like the actual flavor of the of that's
coming off of of of of the hash you know
what I'm saying say and that's like
where
um you know uh burping turps slurping
any kind of thing like that like sipping
wine you know the way you get the turps
is by all that Iration and all that um
sipping that's how you get you know it's
like the best way to get flavor and I
think that's where um that in between
getting it to spin and everyone coming
up with these really cool um units to to
to to to figure out heat zones and
cleaning and um all these like dunk
tanks and all this stuff I mean and the
Q-tips and everything it's just been all
just like one thing led to another to
get to this point
really I'll tell you the the flavor
aspect ties into anyone that's ever hit
one of these turp slurpers especially
the first time you hit it it's like
you're getting high for the first time
especially if you're ahead and you're
hardcore you're not hitting something
through your first tur slurper that
you've never hit before you're pulling
out one of your favorites that you've
hit like 10,000 times through 10,000
different ways at 10,000 different
temperatures and now you're hitting the
turp slurper with the pearls and you got
your temperature gauge and it was I mean
it was like uh you know you get high for
the first time and then you spend the
rest of your life sort of chasing that
Dragon well that like that caught the
dragon that was the dragon catcher that
turp slurper it was like Boop blew that
out and was like literally like it was
grade eight again and I was borderline
on the brink of being more High than I
wanted to be which I have to admit
nowadays is exactly where I want to be
um but um that was that was I won't I
will never forget that I mean I've I've
never gotten high like that off of it
again but I also just like got those
pearls spinning and created a crazy
suction and uh yeah the the the it's to
me it's all about the preservation of
the volatile organic compounds getting
them from your product into your lungs
as preserved as possible you know so the
more the more of these buffers that you
put in like not letting it sit in one
corner of a banger versus painting the
entire tube of the turp slurper like a
like a rising film
evaporator this is on a completely
different level and I've uh you
definitely are a massive influence in
this whole aspect and I got to give a
shout out and I I don't even know if you
guys uh get along or if he's like a
mortal enemy or whatnot but I I do got
to get G give a shout out to Brian from
denail as well because he's also really
just geeked out on focusing on these
shapes and the you know the way the
surface area preserves and releases heat
and so been doing quartz and been doing
silicon carbide and been doing Sapphire
and all these different surfaces which
uh I find subtle nuances for certain but
uh nothing like the difference between
hitting out of a banger and then hitting
out of of a tur slurper and dude thank
you so much for this because uh it's uh
it's changed the way I puffed for sure
that's awesome thank you so much I
appreciate that yeah dude and so now
that Jameson's here let's talk about the
cleanliness of our Banger basket the
cleanliness of our Banger basket I've
never seen a darker yellow solvent than
when I'm puffing with Jameson this
[ __ ] Puffs the biggest dabs like
it like just the most outrageously huge
dabs you don't even have to be puffing
when he's dabbing in front of you you
are puffing more than you would be
puffing if you were inhaling your dabs
directly into uh your lungs so shout out
to the [ __ ] Banyon tree in the house
here with h show us your yellow [ __ ]
solvent W uh uh Banger bath I know it's
[ __ ] you
[Music]
could dude here's the OCD guys
uh yo thanks so much for having me Mark
what's up
everybody F it's time to do some some
dabs I'm guessing here and shout out to
[ __ ] Alex with the method seven hat
on that is a [ __ ] really great
company I don't know if you guys know
too much about method 7 James is like a
surreal character really interesting
fellow have to have him on one day and
tell his crazy Paul Newman watch story
because it's [ __ ] super out there if
you've never heard that story it is out
there uh and just shout out to Method 7
I'm an ambassador for that company and
uh I think they're doing good things I
like the idea of people coming up with
ways to preserve our bodies you know in
this you know no one thinking that being
under those High Press sodium lights for
all those years was going to affect
their light uh their eyes but uh yeah it
does get those get those shades on you
and avoid the headache true human
optimization like it allows you to to
view something without you know with you
didn't have the ability before but you
can do your work better and it's more
healthy for you too in intake of light
is really important stuff so well I'll
tell you and I'll lead that right into
photography which is what photography is
the intake and manipulation of light so
when I'm in a grow room and I'm taking
pictures with my phone and it's just
orange I don't even want to post those
pictures they just look terrible but to
have Shades that you can pull off your
head I mean I've got the little the
little clips now that Olo Clips or
whatever that go over my phone um but to
be able to take the shades off and take
a picture through the blue lens and just
turn actually I was wearing my blue
lenses yesterday I was in the forest up
north here in Squamish and I was picking
mushrooms edible mushrooms and it was
literally helping me see the forest
floor better because it was so dark in
there and the BL blue the blue Shades
just like lighten everything up so yeah
I'm definitely uh I'm a fan what where
are you from Alex
hashte yeah hey can you guys hear me
yeah absolutely dude absolutely marus
thanks a lot for thanks a lot for having
me on here humbled to be hanging out
with all you guys here and now this this
is going to be an awesome Sunday yeah
absolutely man well welcome yeah so Alex
makes a um a stainless steel hash maker
uh called the hashtech and they have a
bunch of different sizes I'm sure he
could tell us about it in in a little
bit uh here for sure and uh yeah I mean
the world needs more hash so the more
hash the marrier needs more um companies
sort of pushing these boundaries you
know you get uh you get a Pioneer like
like JP who sort of pioneers a concept
but then you get all these other people
who come along and they're just they're
they want to they want fit in there
somehow and so they start playing around
and changing and you know so it's like
we stand on the shoulders of giants uh
when we're not insecure uh and worried
that people doing similar things than
what we're doing is taking away from our
pie last I heard John made enough for
everyone um whose music is on someone
playing [ __ ] theme music or what yeah
oh it was Alex that was awesome it was
while we were talking about him too that
was amazing that was
I thought that was Mark I thought you
were setting a setting a tone that
wasn't on purpose my my bad the ladies
are watching a movie here that's that's
not that good but the timing was so good
dude it was really just this like
Perfect theme
music someone playing them
music that was so good oh my god dude
that is
awesome I have a question about legends
about the first Legends um how did that
happen like how did that materialize was
that something that you sat down and
consciously created or or did it happen
more or less organically to a point
where you saw it happen and you were
like we need to we need to continue this
well like everything that's awesome in
our community it was created by skunkman
Sam you know I was a part of it we were
we were having that conversation I
couldn't say listen first of all this
guy's hash when he was like okay who the
[ __ ] lived in all the hash producing
countries collected all the cult of ours
brought them back to his Greenhouse with
Federal licensing and bred genetics for
15 years straight who who who is puffing
weed and saying that that is how they
got the weed like that is just like what
the [ __ ] so that's the start and so the
first time I ever went over to his place
and I remember Rob Clark kind of be like
oh I could barely walk home from Sam's
last night I was I was so [ __ ] stoned
and I would kind of be like well really
man like come on like I can drive on
four grams of mushrooms like how stoned
could you have possibly been you know I
was kind of young bucking it being all
[ __ ] confident and cocky and he was
like whatever dude you know whatever and
uh I ended up getting invited over there
one time finally and he you know he
pulled out this this skunk number one
full melt dry sift that he cleaned up to
Perfection and it was I'd never seen
hash melt like that not even 6star like
this was like another level it was just
like right through the screen H and he's
just like ALS also puffing like I I'd
say he puffed about 150 Bowls in the in
the three hours that I hung out there
for when I smoked this hash it was like
someone strapped me to a rocket and I
took off and I was so anxius I thought I
was gonna [ __ ] myself throw up piss
myself pass out unconscious all the big
four fears that you would have if you
got like I just I i' gotten people high
like that before but no one had ever
gotten me high like that before I was
humbled and so and that was the first
rip he gave me like oh I want to say 20
or 30 more when I left his house that
night the whole right side of my body
wasn't working and I was walking and I
was kind of lifting my right leg and
then walking normal with my left leg and
I'm I'm being very serious I'm not
exaggerating in any way shape or form I
was
destroyed and I finally understood what
Rob was saying like oh yeah I got really
really high at at Sam's really high at
Sam's could mean that he gave you a goo
ball with one gram of his dry sift in
the goo ball like he'd eat two of those
and go walk around for Queen's Day in
Amsterdam and it was just like dude like
two of those would knock any normal
human being out for about 48 hours it's
a lot and so that was the basis for the
conversation and I've talked a little
bit about this before when you know
alcohol went into bars and you had your
laborers going and drinking
and those conversations they had really
sort of shaped the future and that
turned into tea houses where now they
were more intellectual people getting
together not so much laborers and they
started having conversations that
started shaping the world and then
coffee came in and coffee was all about
productivity and efficiency and those
conversations shaped the world and made
us much more productive and much more
efficient and the conversation that
they're the most scared for us to have
which is why in all of these states and
countries where there's legal cannabis
there's very few places to actually
smoke it like actual lounges because
once we get that and that's what hash
church is and everyone's like oh hash
church is amazing it's like really hash
church is just a place where you let
people who use cannabis have
conversation and direct their
communities with that conversation and
we will have that when we eventually can
have these gatherings and so that's the
basis in the foundation and I think I
might have started it by saying to Sam
you know know the Cannabis Cup has so
there were a lot of people back then as
well that were just pissed off at High
Times and upset with high times and I
was always kind of like listen like I
think your expectations are too high the
fact that they're making this happen and
we can come here and we can all meet up
and filter out the people you don't want
to know but meet these amazing people
that were like otherwise were hiding
from the police in every state and
country that they lived in and now they
were just outing themselves at the
Cannabis Cup with video cameras and
cameras and it was just it was
absolutely mental but there was a lot of
people that I was like I don't a lot of
people just smoking cigarettes and just
kind of being like oh I wish I could run
all these heads through my bags and just
collect the 90 Micron heads and that
will be the the you know this Gathering
that we would have and that was what the
conversation started with me and Sam he
was probably 60 dabs in and I was
probably 15 or 20 dabs in absolutely
destroyed and now we're like uh oh if we
could just run everyone through the High
Times cup through our bags man and catch
them all in the 90 like just Bakery talk
but it turned into Legends of hash it
turned into um you know keep in mind
those guys at the time too were very um
removed from the community and the scene
like they were a part of it but they
were also like they knew the only way
they could get what they were wanting to
do done would be if they isolated
themselves and a lot of people that were
on the other side of things those guys
those guys meaning Sam and yourself of
farm ho of farm that would be Clark
David Pate Michael Rich um skunkman Sam
uh and you know a group Michael uh David
Pate was the chemist who who did all the
chemistry work but they they were doing
things that we started doing in like the
late 2000s like the 2010s and the 2015s
they were doing it in like the 80s and
so um and doing it right and so because
of that they were always you know there
was always oh those guys are like
they're the they're the DEA they're the
CIA there were all these rumors r that
Sam was a DEA agent and then a CIA agent
when I first went in '95 I remember
someone pointing him out across the
street and saying that guy's a CIA agent
and you know I was like oh my God like
whoa crazy and then as I got to know him
and invited into his Circle he's a very
private man and meeting his wife of like
I don't know 35 or 40 years or something
maybe 50 maybe they've been together for
50 years now very long time seeing all
the old photos hearing all the old
stories and seeing how the you know s
sedy uh was his was the name that he
original originally picked well that was
because he back in the 60s when he was a
big acid head and a big Tripper they all
called him jingles and Jingles backwards
is Cy so to think that all these other
people were like he's a CIA agent but
then to go to go to his house and hear
him and his wife chuckling about it like
they're just like oh my God like you
know and being able to meet and become
friends with his wife um and hearing the
stories from her perspective she's such
a sweet and honest and and really
wonderful woman um there's no fibery
there's no lies and there's still these
stories going around to this day that
this guy is in the DEA because what did
he do he did what no one else in
Amsterdam could do he got a license to
to to have and grow cannabis and then he
had a DEA export license so he could
send it to different labs in different
countries for them to do the redundancy
work to test against the work that they
were doing in their lab because back in
the day the the the the the standards
for THC and canono were super sketched
out and they weren't well done and he
they all he had to create his own
standards if you can imagine so
basically that was the conversation that
started hash church and we you know they
were very removed and he was kind of
like well do you think you could sell 50
tickets like you know and here I am
going dude I don't think you realize
what the community really like thinks of
you and Rob and the work that you've
done like you guys are [ __ ] rock
stars and so it was kind of up to me by
him allowing me in and to kind of come
under and and and be mentored by him he
also gave me permission in that sense to
shine a light on him and Rob and the
marijuana botney and the hashes and all
these I was just like these guys have
done it all and so they weren't sure
that we could sell the tickets but they
did have a restaurant a good friend of
of of both of robs and Sam's uh by the
name of Simone good friend of all of
ours now and he owned a restaurant
called the artiste in Amsterdam it was a
Lebanese restaurant and I remember being
there before
Legends and we would go there and Dave
would or Sam would bring his bong and we
would basically puff bowls in this guy's
restaurant and I was and people would
get there'd be Dutch people in the
restaurant kind of getting mad about it
uh and he would kick them out he'd be
like look if you don't like it you know
get the [ __ ] out which was just like
amazing to us we were just like listen
if we ever do throw a party it has to be
at Simone's restaurant so Simone's
restaurant was small and the ceiling was
low and it was very it got very smoky
very fast but that is part of the reason
why we always uh through the rest
through the party at Simone's through
that money in that business his way
because he was so righteous and he he
was a non-p puffer that stood behind
puffers in a way that very few non-p
puffers ever have you know putting his
license on the on the line putting his
whole restaurant like yeah you can smoke
bong rips after your meal come on so we
ended up uh you know creating the the
first laminant we created uh we rented
the restaurant out and uh I basically
went out and basically tra sold Legends
of hash tickets to anyone that would
show me a beautiful piece of hash I
figured you know what this isn't about
status this isn't about who you are in
the industry this isn't about going and
promising DNA 12 tickets and then going
and giving s his 16 for his Entourage it
was about bringing in people who loved
hashish regardless of who they were so
the only real prejudism was that you had
to show me a beautiful piece of hash and
it was interesting back in the day
because people were like oh how much do
I give you and I was like you don't give
me any you know I thought like [ __ ] of
course I wanted the hash I would have
loved to have been like oh you know you
give me 10 grams and then then then then
then you can come to Legends so right
from the get-go there was this
temptation to bastardize the Integrity
of the of the whole thing right from the
start which i' I refused to do I'm like
plus I'm not hurting for hash like I've
got lots so I just I would smell the has
I wouldn't even often dab it but if I
looked at it and smelled it and felt it
I was like you know what that g that
will gain you entry to buy a ticket so
then you ended up with these there was
always one or two that snuck in and got
you know got in when they really
shouldn't have got in and those people
turned white very early on left the
building they were out of there within
an hour this is hashish abuse to the
greatest level I mean this is where you
take people like Jameson who like oh
yeah I abuse hash every day it's like oh
yeah well you'll be higher than you've
ever [ __ ] been after Legends of hash
I promise you that's just the facts it's
the highest I've ever been in my entire
life and that's kind of the the basis of
what I set up Legends for you know Sam
turned it into a contest and that's
awesome I think that it was I think
that's why it survived there's this sort
of got to be this this level of
self-preservation and self-promotion
there has to be for people to really get
into it even though I will say for a
long time you know Legends was just this
elusive event we didn't try to make it a
hard to get ticket the hash heads just
grew in the early days there were less
of them and of course there was no
cameras allowed because some of the
people at the first Legends were very
very very very hardcore people uh doing
the good work of getting the hash out
all over Europe and uh North America and
that was very illegal work back then you
know dealing with uh with cartels
basically to buy this hash in certain
countries and then trying to move it
around all around these guys were like
this was one of the first times they got
to have a party and enjoy hash because
they had to be invisible in the real
world and so to have like three or four
of those guys at the first Legends I
mean the nose from Amsterdam if any of
you have been to Amsterdam you got to
know the nose the nose nose that's uh
Steve Hayes um he was out front at one
point pale white big hashish guy in
Amsterdam and he was pale and I was like
wow did you smoke too much he's like no
man I looked around the room and
realized who was in there and so he was
only one one of the only people who
really understood who was at the first
Legends of hashish and that came through
one of our friends uh who's since passed
away he just happen to know all these
different guys because I guess he was
you know kind of involved in those
things for for for a very long time so
for me there's no shame in that like I
wanted to Legends to pay homage to that
the same way I wanted to pay hom to the
TP slurpers and the temp teex and the TP
timers and all of these new things that
we've done I also wanted to always hold
a root or an anchor in the foundation of
Legends and even going way far back
before these guys were smuggling hash
around the the world but going even
hundreds of years further to the sufis
and to these different Afghan Gardens
and you know these storylines of
different people that have been
promoting and using Hashi for all of
these centuries I also wanted to stay
rooted in that and pay homage to that so
when you become part of a Legends of
hashish it's really where old meets new
and you want to uh not necessarily in
the Cannabis industry it's always
division right and maybe that's just in
life in general it's always like oh I
only smoke BHO I only smoke full melt
bubble and there's just every little
piece is divided and and and divisive
and at Legends you could be like yeah I
smoke my dabs but I'm going to go hit
that 110 year-old Hubbly Bubbly that
Sam's dumping a gram and a half of his
60 uh% gland heads into so it was pretty
special the first one and everyone since
then uh and I have zero doubts that Los
Angeles will not be Beyond uh anything
that we've ever done uh because there's
a team there's Addison and Kevin and a
whole team of people doing what I just
couldn't do on my own and you guys the
sponsors are a part of that team so I'm
very glad to uh be sharing BS with you
here on a Sunday uh on a Sunday morning
on the west coast 100% 100% was it the
first legends that Sam turned it into a
competition or did that happen after you
know I think it happened pretty much
right there you know and and it was
brilliant from Sam's perspective it was
kind of like look I I I earned this and
you know people and I think part of the
first Legends no doubt part of the first
many Legends
was just being in a room with Sam he was
that elusive to be able to just be in a
room with Sam and SM and then see him as
like a as a excited small child on
Christmas morning like Sam was a very
serious guy very much like that sort of
like Beyond serious Professor that just
knows everything that you can't ever get
it right because he's already done it
all and uh you know the way he used to
call people out and the way he'd you
know it was hard it was hard being under
his wing those first years but as
Legends progressed and as he started
having fun and just really doing what he
loved and trust me this guy loves
puffing like the fact that people would
call him a DEA agent or a CIA agent when
really truly he was the the biggest
cannabis Warrior I've ever I've never
met a guy that is more excited about
cannabis and more
importantly um less excited about who
makes the profit off of it he never
cared from the day that I met him he's
like I just want it to be legal and
available to everyone
everyone else can fight about who gets
to make the money so when you know that
about Sam and that's not something he
posted a lot online but when you know
that about him uh you know that it would
make no sense for him to go around and
and rat people out uh when he's truly I
don't know anyone that loves cannabis
more than this guy um and he doesn't
love it in a way that's going to just
pay him he just he's really like in the
TR in the truest form I mean he's done a
lot for our community a lot of us us are
you know dabbing on these full melts
thanks to some of the work that that guy
did so I won't go on forever about Sam
but uh he's a big part of Legends of
Hashi she's one of the founders and uh
yeah he's just
done for all Sam yeah for sure hey I
wanted to uh welcome Sam with h show and
and Ros and Tech and dab Nation
Anda and focus and all the stuff and Sam
and uh there with him as well want to
welcome those guys at Focus V is their
label there but um definitely wouldn't
be able to put uh a lot of the stuff we
did for the gift bags and a lot of the
judges kits and stuff without uh without
those guys' help as well as of support
so want to say what's up thank you guys
how you been what up guys what's up
Marcus welcome man welcome it's a good
morning getting baked with friends yeah
what up Drew what's up
Kev
boys I I had to go and take a take a dab
with the saber and the uh the ca too I
had to show the people what was up man
let's go that thing's awesome we love
the saber
man I told uh I told Addison to send me
a cter because tasel doesn't like he
drives like a maniac and he doesn't stop
so like unless you have a rig to smoke
in the car you're you're you're waiting
they fit in a cup holder perfect
yeah no I'm I'm I'm looking forward to
having one for this
trip yeah it's one of the benefits of
using a uh a device like this that's
designed by a company that actually
makes s hatch so that's very grateful
guys yeah exactly it's a little
different you know no it's definitely uh
very very pleased to have you blessed to
have you guys Drew rips a slurper
[Laughter]
but you know what I love about you guys
is that you're not against that you know
you understand that the carda is a tool
that's used you know within our day and
and you know in between transitionally
between
things and it's not like you know you're
all against you know using a slurp or
using anything else it's it's like you
guys are about to happen I use a lot of
glass uh in my day-to- day honestly yeah
all different sty check out all the ways
that you know you can taste the
your ab sizes
it's yeah I'll smoke a hot knife right
now you know I just I just like getting
high
know exactly I'm not I'm
not I can tell you're telling the truth
because I see that titanium
nail yeah I saw that
yeah ra you got a mini nail yeah that's
an enail uh we used to well we still
make them we we make enails um so yeah
titanium since day one man you know [ __ ]
it's always ready you know it's always
on you know I I hear a lot about um like
temperature regulation and stuff and one
of the things that you know my thought
process always was with the nail and I'm
interested to ask some of you guys that
are at the the very top end of this is
you know the way the way this enil works
is it's constantly taking the
temperature of um you know the nail and
then it's constantly modulating how much
power it's giving it so when the
temperature drops the power goes up so
right now it's staying at a perfect 500
and even as like the air conditioning
and stuff kicks on I can see it dropping
and changing and it changes how much
power so when I'm drawing on it when I'm
you know ripping it um it it it
throttles up the power and stuff so it
really keeps it a consistent temperature
the whole way through and I see like you
know him with the Banger as soon as he
starts drawing on it it's changing the
temperature you know like from the start
of the dab to the end of the dab so it's
pretty it's pretty significant the when
you start pulling the air cools it down
pretty quickly right dab cools it down
pretty quickly too before you even pull
you drop that dab on there and you're
you're cooling things down down
substantially and every sub and every
compound like releases and holds heat
differently so you know the quartz
ability for thermal shock is very unique
Sapphire not so much there's you know
you dip hot Sapphire into any liquid or
even use like a a Q-tip with ISO and you
can crack the sapphire it's super
delicate but the way it releases heat is
just a little more preservative than
quartz not quite enough to warranty
paying like $600 for a sapphire thing
that's going to break almost uh every
time you try to clean it but um I I do
find it very interesting that uh there's
a whole science you could get a a PhD on
this of just how different substances
release and retain heat and how that
either preserves or destroys and I'll
say volatile organic compounds because
we're not just talking about tpin some
of the flavor profiles that we love the
most are thols and they're very very
small percentages but they really do you
know throw the smell and flavor profile
to a great angle with a with a very very
very small amount and I think that they
have such small amounts we don't give
them as much credit as where credit is
due but I mean skunk for instant is
definitely a combination of two or three
THS and butane thle one I believe is one
of them so uh let's not forget our thil
when we're talking about our volatile
organic
compounds very good point I don't know
if anyone else is trying to do this but
I've been trying to keep up with JP it
is not [ __ ] easy he's just I've been
lit I literally he's ahead of me but
I've been like trying to just because
coming into this I was like all right
I'm gonna pick somebody and I'm just
gonna you know that's that's how take my
dabs and that's who you pick JP I picked
[ __ ] JP and for Christ's sake I'm two
behind hey I got a funny story me and
Kevin went to dinner with deppy and we
went over to was up Mikey's house and
and uh uh we're all there I think it was
Jay from Professor Sith a bunch of us
all go to dinner and we get there and
Mikey's got the table just laid out like
an m on the table just splashed out with
every you know the illis of the craziest
[ __ ] and we all start dabbing and I
didn't notice it till later Kevin
noticed it but deppy was hitting every
single rig and he went through while we
were there and dabbed every single rig
and then started going back through the
rigs he Gauntlet he did The Gauntlet all
the way through and was coming back 11
rigs he did 11 and he went
more yeah repeat the first time I the
first time I met deppy was at mother
ship two years ago and Addison took me
there and deie ran the hash competition
at the end of the night L like we
started late we did 52 dabs he served
them all he cleaned every Banger he
heated every Banger and then when we
finished he started up a pingpong
tournament that went for no less than
three hours like with all the people
that were watching that weren't dabbing
while the rest of the dabbers were just
like sitting at that table recovering he
was literally playing pingpong within a
minute of finishing the comp and
announcing and announcing the winners so
like dude is he's a wizard he's the
wizard he's a wizard he we had a video
game system that had uh what was it
Street Fighter 2 and he played as Chun
Lee and wrecked every person in the room
be the [ __ ] out of all the gauntlet on
wrecking us all in Chun Lee and then
went back and then I wound up beating
him the second time by like a hair it
was so funny it was insane that's that's
that's some skunkman Sam [ __ ] right
there for real oh yeah Legend some of
the Legends some of the Legends were
like 30 to 40 entries and we'd have to
smoke them all in in a couple of hours
you know and the this one in Barcelona
which was at certified uh when flux was
a part of it flux kind of got us in
there and we were in this crazy back
room that looked like Cambodia there was
Holes in the Floor and the walls were
all gnarly and it was just like I'll
never forget that group of people flux
was at the table and Rick delisi was at
the table Flav was at the table uh and
we just went through Ramone was at the
table just went through like you know 40
plus uh entries uh smoking one dab after
another that is a gauntlet of gauntlets
I used to love Tech at the time what was
like the tech at the time what was it a
titanium nail no no this was this was
2016 so we were definitely hitting out
of quartz yep we were definitely hitting
out of quartz yeah there's no uh
titanium Nails on that table do people
really hate on titanium nails like am I
really jamming up the program dude
people no no no listen this is this yes
yes and no the problem is Instagram has
created an enormous amount of [ __ ] boys
and so you know the [ __ ] boy thing is oh
you're hit yeah you know hold on hold on
hold on you're talking about using all
these different surfaces to to keep the
same temperature I'm watching the SC
when it's ambient right now it's 500
Degrees when I'm ripping it like full
bore it only drops to 480 that's right
but that's just the temperature if you
did the same thing out of a quartz
Banger side by side you'd notice the
preservation of the volatile organic
compounds would be different the when it
hits the titanium even at that low
temperature it's not the same as when it
hits quartz and that has nothing to do
with the temperature as much as the the
component that you're hitting off of
they all are different titanium
generally is looked at as kind of one of
the first ones that you know branded
many of us many of us wear our titanium
brands for Life uh on our arms and on
our wherever's but but then people you
know like oh and it's kind of like this
you know it's it's real but it's also
like built up like people that don't
even know will watch this and suddenly
be like oh yeah man I would never hit
off a titanium nail I would hit off a
titanium nail if I didn't have a quartz
nail if I didn't have a quartz or a
titanium nail I'd hit off a pen or I'd
hit off I just thought quartz is about
how the hash moves the hash moves
differently on quartz in a way that it
can't move on titanium because titanium
slows it down where if you allow it to
move it can hit more surface area and
vaporize more quickly more evenly so
it's quartz has that that quality it to
move more quickly and dance around that
[ __ ] and then you know the cap is adding
Spin and everything else to push it in
different directions and we're trying to
make it move we're trying to vaporize as
much as we can and get a good hit and
keep temp because temp is good is
important part you can add pearls for
that you can do other things for that
and it's like you know that that all
kind of comes to the picture the but the
email has its [ __ ] place if you got a
bunch of people coming over light them
up because it's like yo I'm not gonna
sit here [ __ ] I'm not trying to argue
anybody but like I mean we take all that
in consideration like this cap is rifled
so when you pull the air through it's
spinning it's designed to spin I mean we
we did all kinds of airflow simulations
and stuff when we design this snail so
um you know I don't know like I'm
I think it's cool you know [ __ ] I just
want I'm not trying Rock the
Boat [ __ ] no they work man there you're
definitely not rocking the boat like I
said it's an Instagram [ __ ] boy thing if
you posted you know it's just someone
would jump on that [ __ ] in an oh he's
[ __ ] puffing off a titanium nail [ __ ]
him okay well [ __ ] you too I'm getting
high they'd also [ __ ] [ __ ] at you if
your hash was too dark so don't take it
with a grain of salt dude like it's
whatever you're puffing out of
is perfect and if you want to travel in
a different direction listen everyone in
this room I would almost guarantee has
puffed off of a titanium nail and in
fact I have puffed off many of [ __ ]
stainless steel knives hot knifing you
know probably even aloys and Coke cans
and all this other [ __ ]
so it
is rip on a screen on a
denail titanium nail like back in the
day doing that screen Tech
yeah the best hits back in the day that
allows a
lot no it is good I mean it's the the
hardest part about dils and I think what
kicked their ass or the electric Nails
you couldn't really bring them in the
car unless you had something correct for
that and like you know but everything
has its [ __ ] purpose I mean if I show
up somewhere and all they have is X
we're using X you know what I mean that
that it's a [ __ ] that's that's
doesn't matter at all at that point it's
like let's go that that's what's great
about hash too is that you can do it so
many different ways but no shout out to
the I mean just remember when we were
torching and then the d nails came out
the electric nails came out how [ __ ]
much that changed the game like how you
know when you went to a session now it
was like we're all getting [ __ ] lit
in 10 minutes you know it's like that
changed the [ __ ] game so it
definitely still has its home and has
its place and I think you know the
internet everyone's at different levels
well that was all Sam before jar Michael
before any of that it was Sam that
turned me onto those screams in fact how
I met Sam was someone told me that he
used a new screen for every single bowl
that he puffed out of so he'd like soak
these screens and get the coding off of
them and then he had a b a big bag of
brand new screens like a thousand of
them and he just walk around and you
could when the first time I went to the
Pack's party house I saw screens and
matches like on the floor like if he
stood anywhere even for like five
minutes there'd be like 5050 matches and
like 10 or 15
screens and so I was like oh W and start
and and in fact I remember picking one
up and realizing he's not even finishing
these the hashes melted into the screen
and he's I was just like this is not how
I'm going to try his hash for the first
time so I threw it back down but I
definitely saw people picking those up
and hitting them and being like that was
the best hash that I hit in Amsterdam
was the screens that I picked up at the
Pack's Party House think of how [ __ ]
mental that is dude yeah so I found him
on the third floor with his [ __ ]
Birkenstock sandals on which was another
uh look for the guy in the Birkenstock
sandals uh and that's kind of yeah sort
of met him and walked over he was very
you know standoffish and it took a
little while it wasn't until he found
out that I used his saying if it don't
bubble it ain't worth the trouble for
the Bubble Bag company that he reached
out to me and was like do you know who I
am and that's really how we ended up
linking up but uh thank God because
without Sam and his hack and all that
like many many decades of work that he
did uh we would not be having a Legends
of hash in Los Angeles here in the next
in the next month so we can we can thank
Sam for that too so true yeah no he's uh
he is yeah we we needed to talk about
actually reaching out to him and and
getting him to uh to say hello to US
during the event if we could' be
awesome that would be great I mean I
don't know if we'll get to see him we'll
probably get to see Dr Seuss but yeah no
one gets to see him he's
elusive very elusive very uh very
secretive man now it's definitely uh I
can't I I really can't wait to see
what's entered this year because I've
kind of started to get a bit of an
understanding if you guys don't know we
have a blockchain that we're going to be
using for the judging uh so that
everything's on there um and and it
allows us to have uh ability to to see
all the judging in real time but then to
be able to publish everything afterward
in case anyone tries to say somebody
bought a win and in fact it makes it
impossible to do that so anyhow um that
whole system is there it's all put
together and we've uh we needed to now
we need to understand like what some of
the strain names are because they're
putting together the program that's
gonna you know that's going to be able
to allow us to do this so some guys have
been sending us some information um on
what their entries might be and and what
they're doing and it's this is
definitely going to be a [ __ ] why
wild uh Kev how many entries is it it's
uh 6 I think three 62 or 63 yeah
somewhere somewhere in that vicinity
let's say just North of 60 yeah and in
order to in order to land the plane you
know like touch down and be able to get
everything moving forward we really have
to have 41 makers instead of 40 because
if somebody backs out or you have to
have a couple more makers just in case
because things always happen um so this
year it was at 41 makers last year I
think we had 24 makers so you never know
really where that number is going to
fall either right below or just above um
but this year we're able to you know
because of the contingency and how it
went through we have 41 makers so um I
think we'll be posting an update of the
new list on Monday uh that'll show you
know all Corrections and all the and who
all the makers are so but what that
means is that you know now you have uh
what Mark like what Marcus was talking
about you have Legends you know you're
able to to have a lot of hash there you
know from different types of hash there
because you have so many makers
so everybody like hey the next the next
for the next hour you guys can buy
tickets these are all 250 selected
people from our industry from the hash
industry from the glass industry that
are you know very very very in cash and
about the culture and want to be there
so that's kind of one of the cool things
too is that it's all selected people
that are there um you'll see old friends
you'll see new friends uh and you know
the the idea of having makers from the
East Coast be able to sit down with
makers from the west coast and I know
there's other events that do this I mean
OB obviously but to have it in this
environment in this setting and have it
be a part of this event uh you know the
best people the best hash uh you know
and and all the best uh you know company
so it's uh yeah it should be you know
great food everything like that that's
kind of we just went we wanted to go
overboard on every little bit from the
gift bags to the sponsors to The Venue
to everything that's there we want
people to just be like oh [ __ ] okay you
know and it's and it's we run a lower
risk of having a blowout with like you
know the wrong kind of people together
or you know taking a chance on like oh
this this guy is gonna have an issue or
something else like we've really gone
through and made sure that it's a great
mix of people coming together people
that have known each other for a long
time and and you know and then there's
some young companies there's some new
companies some new guys because you
always got to be able to give a you know
give respect to somebody who's who's
doing it and just elevated themselves
because their stuff so good or you know
there's some of those guys in there so
you know I catch these complaints from
people being like Oh I should be on that
list there's there's 40 dudes on that
list that I'm better than and it's like
yeah but maybe just this wasn't your
year to be a guy of that level coming
into it and you know we have to cap it
at something and you know let's give
everyone the respect and but you know
there's always people who instead of you
know the the anger that comes from not
being involved comes out and uh you know
it's it's you know just is what it is
but there's a lot less of that than
there is of people just hitting us up
and being super stoked and you know
everyone [ __ ] fired up for this thing
so about the glass
Addie oh man I mean you know the whole I
mean what's great is that you do have
Mothership bringing you know the heat
always I mean Scott's always got
something crazy up his sleeve but we got
lucky enough where this is the Jeezy one
drop the herem drop
uh so it's you know H very hash specific
art art specific and culturally specific
so it's kind of cool to have that at
Legends and to have them be willing to
to put that there but then you know JP's
coming I know he's bringing some great
glass I know uh there's a a you know
task is sending stuff out from Highly
Educated there's uh you know a um Dom is
going to come and do a cap drop uh and
his stuff is just always you know so
solventless perfect specific uh great
stuff he'll have like slurper sets and
different stuff like that and um you
know a lot of glass and then just people
with glass on the table uh I think
there's going to be quite a bit of
heaters you know because of who's
invited and what they have for a
collection and you know so yeah but I
think tomorrow we get to see some of the
first sneak peeks of the gzy one drop so
we'll we'll have a little better
understanding of some of that stuff and
then we've been trying to
look at the sponsor list and give Scott
ideas and give those guys ideas of like
any way we can lend to you know what we
know that crowd's going to be really
into so that we have uh a lot of great
stuff there that way but then there's
also you know the art component you know
having lot there and you know Mike be
there and have him be able to to uh you
know share you know his whole take on
the culture and and deliver what he does
that's kind of a cool ass [ __ ] thing
so there'll be some surprises uh that
pop up for everybody to enjoy there uh
that kind of come from Mike come from
lot comedy what's up
mace yo what's Craig what's up buddy
good to have
you so we're also gonna have a seed
breeders Lounge where we'll have four
seed breeders who work specifically
making genetics for hash uh production
and they'll have a
lounge um with the four breeders and Mas
Sonic's going to be one of those
yep Lake Valley and uh Ross Kyo with uh
Pacific Northwest Roots they'll have
some of their genetic stuff R we also
yeah Rare Earth genomics out of Texas
which is a really cool story and a cool
ass group of cats yeah yeah they'll have
their own Lounge which is kind of cool
so I know these guys all dab super hard
so we wanted to give them an area where
people could come in and sit down and
kind of hang out with the Breeders and
check out their gear uh and uh be able
to kind of swap stuff too
so that's hashte will have uh hashte
will have a unit there which would be
pretty dope right I think
there's we we'll have an AER 50a there
that's been our bestselling unit kind of
bridges the gap between craft producers
and and large scale license license
production excited to show that off to
the
boys about the unit Alex what is it does
it tip or is it stationary no this is
the tabletop
version yeah yeah you know this show
we're real excited about sponsoring
Kelly and I uh my partner who we started
the company with we're both going to be
down there and just like with with
Jameson's uh Le melting of the heads you
know what we really want to get out of
Legends is talking to Hash makers and
you know seeing that list of hash makers
that were there that are coming this
year it's very impressive and
prestigious and that's how we're going
to make our equipment better is getting
feedback from hash makers and that
that's that's really what we look
forward to for Legends I I really agree
with that um that's something that was
pretty important to us about um being a
part of Legends as a sponsor was getting
feedback um we we do a lot on the
cultivation side and and we work with a
lot of um large scale facilities and
stuff and as of late we're starting to
see a lot
of a lot of focus on like temperature
control and stuff in the room while the
wash process is going on uh when you
know we we were with somebody on the
west coast and they were saying that
they wanted different temperatures and
humidities um during different stages of
the process you know when they're first
bringing in product when they're you
know screening it different you know
things whatever they they wanted
advanced environmental stuff um so for
us as equipment manufacturers as
controls manufacturers that's that's
really important feedback to get and
hash the hash Community is you know um
usually the most demanding customers
that's why I think um there's so much
Innovation there's so much Hardware
there's so many um odds and ends and
things to consume hash with is because
hash makers are just very hash users are
just very demanding so that type of
feedback is really valuable and and
those type of producers that can provide
that type of feedback is really
valuable oh
yeah yeah that's one thing I never
really thought about is the is you know
if you do have Savvy sponsors that are
taking you know you know they they they
take the event seriously and they go
there with these you know with different
you know objectives what some of those
objectives are because it is you know
you do have an opportunity to be in the
room with that many people at that level
and get that feedback and I think it's
probably the same for the Breeders you
know to be there in the room with that
many makers and kind of have you know
and that's like you know it's it it
tells me that we're doing it correctly
because now we are kind of curating that
room in the right way you know to make
it add value to the to the sponsors but
then add as much value as possible to
the makers because now they're getting
heard by the the you know the guys that
are making different products and
putting things out there for them them
so and then sometimes you see those guys
themselves kind of turn into that like
if you look at simply Adam uh with his
dial the resin dial that new unit that
he put together for uh test washing and
kind of checking material but no it's uh
it's always cool to see the industry
moving forward and just see it kind of
you know like Legends is uh you know
gonna be to me uh just a party man it's
like get to be in the room with all
these people all these friends and all
these different guys and and then get to
eat great food and the [ __ ] hash
alone so you know that's it's to
simplify all of it it's it's a party you
know it's really just a time to get
together and put all that [ __ ] down
and just [ __ ] have fun you know
because the the fomo is really going to
come from not being able to be in that
party and like you know Marcus said when
they walked around and they and they
gave out those lanyards you know the
laminates it was really hard to get one
of those things you had to have great
hash and you had to kind of run into
them and that stole to this day like
Legends is it's it's a tough ticket to
get like Kevin and I are are are sitting
there with like a great Rolodex of
people that we know because we've been
in the industry a long time but then
they come out of the woodwork when
Legends comes because everyone wants to
be in that room and be at that party and
that's what's you know we take it
seriously like to throw the best [ __ ]
party and now we get to make it two days
because we listen to the makers you know
we listen to the feedback it was a
little dark in there I didn't get to
have my phone I felt a little rushed you
know there was no judging so who really
won and and you know all those things
and we had the opportunity to change
that stuff to actually make it evolve
but then how do you do it you know you
need the help of sponsors you need the
help of companies to come forward and
say Hey I want to get the value out of
being in that room to get to talk to
just Cur the list of people and and help
push things forward but you know we're
willing to exchange you know you know
value for us that we can then use and
turn into this event and we really try
not to spare any expense like we try to
you know just the judge kit boxes alone
that you'll get as a judge you know for
the makers that they'll get that box
alone is is a piece of art you know it's
a really cool piece of art that a ton of
energy and effort went into creating um
at and at a at a cost you know so it's
we try to create all these things and
it's you know Marcus and those guys
never monetized and never did anything
and we have the website now we have the
e-commerce component and that's the idea
is to create you know something that
allows people to to to you know to hold
a piece of that culture and to and to
look more into it and figure more about
it and make it a part of like them and
and hash and and and build that
Community stronger like put people
together you know it's not about like
you know uh if you don't get into
Legends this year it doesn't mean you're
not getting into Legends it's like you
know we're just getting off the ground
and we're we're trying to get it so that
we can do maybe two events a year in
different places you know we always
wanted to do it in LA we feel like
that's kind of the epicenter of uh you
know putting on things like that and
making things like that you know a lot
of people want to go there it's easy to
go there so we we we're grateful for
that component but you know as we get it
moving forward we'll you know the we
don't want to make it you know me and
Marcus agree it's like you know Kevin
says the same thing we don't want to
make it where there's too much Legends
you know and that's what the website's
for so that you know when it's not a
legend event you can go get a piece of
merch or something from it and and then
be able to represent
and have it you know be that rare
product or something you know it's it's
like there is marketing involved in
everything that we do it's it's sad that
like you know the hey boy culture
sometimes doesn't want you to monetize
something uh but it's like that's how
things are innovated because people make
money and they can make things better
and as long as the people are ethically
correct and they're doing the right
thing yeah the sky's the [ __ ] limit
man you can really push a lot of things
and you know make make a lot more happen
but it's it's really just about a
[ __ ] party a [ __ ] party and that's
what I'm like super stoked as we get
closer to it I get more excited about
that part there's a lot of work you know
Kevin I think we got 11,000 jars from
kaix and we had to uh we had to cap and
build kits of for 11,000 jars to go out
to you know uh 61 or 60 63 kits going
out to these makers you know so that
they're able to bring a uniform uh a
uniform off offing so that we're able to
then put it out with with standardized
delivery to every person that's there
and there's and there's a a ton of
problems that we had to solve behind the
scenes to make all of this stuff
deliverable to the culture and put out
there you know in open hashbar and all
these different things um and then using
our friends you know that that help
design the the blockchain and all those
things to bring that into it you know we
had a call with Mothership the other day
about the nfts that Mothership are going
to drop at the event uh and what's
relevant about that is that every ticket
is an nft so you'll have a wallet you'll
be able to you know make the agreement
and and get an nft and start that kind
of part of your you know of your resume
or whatever the [ __ ] you call it like
have that in Your Arsenal uh but that's
kind of where things are going and that
nft will allow you to um you know go to
any one of the mothership parties and be
a judge for the hash competition and do
these different things and like you know
Sam and those
directly to the consumer that you're
trying to Market to that you have more
information about that's part of a
community and It ultimately makes it a
lot more easier like mace is [ __ ]
Jesus Christ on this stuff D when it
comes to Discord and marketing but what
it is is it's marketing to you know a
younger crowd a more technically Savvy
crowd that knows how to use these things
and wants to use them and and you know
you if you don't adjust and have that in
Your Arsenal but the point is this year
we do have uh the nft component and some
of the stuff mother ships bring in with
jezy is just going to be ridiculous so
if people are into nfts uh and they're
coming you know have your your your
wallet and all your stuff ready have
some some dough in there and those
things like that but you know it's not
going to limit people but it is kind of
opening the door to that stuff which is
also you know kind of [ __ ] cool I
mean it's kind of like a whole different
approach um but it allows you know the
judging it allows the ticketing uh it
allows us to know who's going to be in
the building before they get there and
uh you know and like monitor everything
but that kind of blows my mind that like
this is now a part of it you know I a
year ago I didn't know anything you know
and now to see how we can integrate it
and how it works and what it can do and
it's kind of [ __ ] cool actually it's
it's it's I mean I don't know how is
everybody's ticket a nft yeah everybody
it is an nft so we're going to create a
Kepler wallet we have all the Kepler
wallets created we're going to send them
out to everybody airdrop their ticket to
them and then there's also an app that
uh our partners at glass flow has built
and so that app is where the judging
portal is going to be there's going to
be event information your ticket is
going to be represented there the nft um
oh and uh yeah
just crypto
curious so yeah no we're we're gonna be
um it's about transparency right so the
judging is fully transparent um it's
going to be really cool so um and if it
sounds daunting or like some future [ __ ]
or like whatever don't worry like we're
setting everything upward so it's just
very easy for everybody um and you're
all going to get an email going to tell
you exactly how to you know access the
app um we've built an app for this
legitimately we've put it on a
blockchain we've done all of this to
have a level of transparency that you
just don't get at events ever um so yeah
we're really excited and we were able to
do it because almost ready to talk there
brother well we were able to do it
because of you sponsors like that's the
other thing we wouldn't be able to
create that stuff and have that stuff
and incorporate that team without having
sponsors and like the big picture of
what we put together it really is
possible because of you guys so we're
super
grateful that is pretty
cool mace what do you got planned buddy
you got some drops or or anything or oh
man I just want to go smoke hash and
kick it with the homies you already know
I got on me every day but that's that's
the that's the grand scheme of of
Legends is to go party you said you know
yep definitely well yeah no there's I
wasn't sure if you had any drops or
anything close to that time oh you know
I I could sell some [ __ ] but I'm you
know I want to go party you know [ __ ]
I got some stuff I always got like I'll
probably bring in the Wilson fem S1 line
with me like straight Wilson fem I
haven't dropped those yet I might dig in
the vault break out some uh the sour
diesels that won a couple cups here and
there and break out some awardwinning
genetics like straight up genetics that
have either been nominated to win an
award you know or or like you know
placed or can be showcased better I'm
just going to bring out the heat to the
hash I wouldn't expect anything less my
friend we give you guys a nice Lounge
area too so you'd be able to dab and
kind of sit and chill with people as
well so with it with it looking forward
to it yeah the food will be nuts it's uh
the brunch is a prime rib brunch so
they'll be cutting prime rib there uh
there's coffee cart with uh all the
tasty coffee everything pastries and you
just Sash and eat and [ __ ] have fun
so yeah try to get every little amenity
little little bit that you can have in
so no doubt coffee is a must hella hash
oh espresso and hash come on now there's
no [ __ ] those two go hand in hand
right there yeah like an adult not be
Legends of hashish branded coffee
lattes yeah that pretty rad there's some
cool [ __ ] they can do with those now too
so but yeah I need to take a dab so I
just took a huge dab right now I don't
know if you seen like really B it was
milky I'm uh I'm super stoked I'm gonna
be in there mixing it up with all these
guys smoking all the hash but also
overseeing all the cameras so Addison uh
Kev and and Marcus who's an incredible
photographer have uh brought in three
camera videographers to shoot the event
so it's going to be really cool to be a
part of documenting something that was
not allowed to be documented for so so
long so I'm super stoked about that I'm
incredibly excited about all the flavors
I know a lot of these makers are working
really hard on on either securing or
finding that that last minute perfect
entry and I'm just incredibly stoked for
it and to be able to to to like see
what happens once we put this out to the
public more because this has been so
behind the scenes for so long it's
almost been lore and now to kind of
showcase it document it and put it out
and just really excited to see what
happens yeah dude I'm stoked on seeing
some of that footage for sure we'll get
that out here on Bubble man's world and
uh it's going to be a pretty special
event for sure it's been uh too long for
myself
we think that you know if if we're going
to represent the culture we need to
represent the culture all the way and we
need to and the best way to do that is
to get that footage out and put it in a
way that's palatable and um catches
people's attention and and lets them
understand like the true Prestige of the
legends of hashish and and what it is
and we want to build that fomo we want
everybody to be like holy [ __ ] I want to
go to that party like I want I want I
want to provide things I want us to
provide things for people that like when
I was a kid and I was reading in High
Times going [ __ ] I want to go to that
like we could do that and I think that
we're we're we're doing
that oh
yeah we're definitely uh definitely
aiding and edding in the consumption of
quite a bit of [ __ ] hash that's
pretty much what it comes down to that's
a good uh that's a good foundation right
there no matter what as long as that's
the
foundation it can't collapse can't go
wrong people's desires are what makes
the world spin and the desire to smoke
and enjoy hash is uh well look how
[ __ ] far we've taken it like it's
ridiculous we're [ __ ] measuring our
bangers with thermometers and or you
know all of our bangers are specifically
made by slur yeah slurp and tpps and
[ __ ] Banger basketing and all this
it's it's really quite incredible and I
get that it's not for everyone I get
that we're a small group of people um
but it's kind of why I also look forward
to one day someone designing the perfect
micro
dab unit because we need to turn people
on to how great this is but not with
monster dabs not even with a normal siiz
dab not even with a small dab K somebody
Mar yeah of course
dude yeah you gota you gotta be careful
it's it it it's what I'll be honest for
a long time and it's it sort of speaks
to to our culture of these you know
heady boys as Addison put it you know
the the the the roots of that were let's
destroy him ha haa and I can take the
biggest dab it really was like this
really testosterone driven like I can
take a bigger dab than you and I'm gonna
destroy you and I knocked countless
people out I'll be honest show up I want
to play Devil's Advocate to that
it was like for me I lose sight of
reality and and what is a
non-consumers acceptable dose and I'm
just a generous sharing person so like
we were in uh British Columbia together
at an and an event and this really nice
elderly lady was sitting with us me and
Marcus and we were just dabbing and this
elderly lady was so nice and she's
asking all these questions and talking
she asked me she's like can I have a dab
and I was like Absol [ __ ] lutely you
can have a dab like and so like slur I
go to like my dab and I'm like no half
that half that Jame come on and so I go
to
half Marcus looks over at me and he's
like dude is that for her and I'm like
yeah man she's she's a delightful lady
she's just looking at and she he's like
no no and he like he went and served her
up one of these micro dabs was like
what's left on my dab when I'm done
dabbing L and and she was like she loved
it she had such a great time she she
asked him for another one and I
immediately realized I was like oh that
would have played out completely
differently if Marcus were not to have
intervened so all heroes don't
wear I've seen it too many times I'll be
honest and I did it too many times I'll
be honest too like I just thought it was
great too cuz when you get humbled and
you're a hard smoker you want to go
share that with other hardcore smokers
so you're out there looking to Humble
people this was also 20 years ago I
haven't been you know doing this for
more than 10 plus years I'm more
interested in gently letting people come
into what we find is special about
cannabis and these extracts and bringing
them in nice and gently and being like
listen this is a real this could really
get you as high as you want what I'd
rather do is give you the tiniest little
bit take away the fear give you the
taste give you a bit of a buzz
and if that's nice you can always take
more but you can never untake any so if
you take a big half Jameson dab H you
can't untake it you're gonna be like
uncomfortably high for probably at least
an hour and I don't want to babysit
people that and I also don't want to
knock people unconscious anymore I hated
it watching people hit the ground flump
for everybody you
know not everybody who goes to the rodeo
wants to ride the F bull you know but I
think it could be if you sedate the bull
and put them up there and go just take
them for a short walk they'll be like
that was actually really nice pet him
pet look his balls like Co [ __ ]
getting on there that's it man I'm
telling you because um it doesn't have
to be a rocket ship to the Moon it can
literally be like a couple of Puffs off
a joint but I also enjoy the pleasure of
ninja dabbing the [ __ ] out of somebody
with a giant dab that can handle it of
course like jam
like I I never see anyone ninja dab
Jameson and he's a [ __ ] Sasquatch
because there's no need to ninja he's
ninja dabbing
himself good point but no that's that's
and I I I wish there was more Ninja
dabbing you know that's what I hope
Legends is like a a rebirth of ninja
dabbing let's bring back ninja people
are just like could totally [ __ ] I think
there's a good reason for it I like
it giving your friend more than they for
that's all you need to that's that's
different that's good I support that
giving regular people like just like R
random people off the street like oh
what is he you're doing over there young
man that looks interesting that's
requires a micro dab I want them to
leave feeling super good and having a
good experience and being like I'm gonna
look into this dabbing thing that was
quite Pleasant smells good yeah not to
mention if you could get high off a
micro daab can you imagine like that
Graham's lasting James in like seven
minutes minutes it's lasting this woman
like 42
days yeah a month and [ __ ] three
weeks I think we should get some special
Ninja dabbers for Legends made like that
are given out during the the the
shenanigans like you know those really
long dabbers like I a couple sessions
some guys show up with them where it's
just so easy you could just like ninja
dab a guy from
afar dude I I always go ahead I'm gonna
make sure now that
I pick a few volunteers that are just
there to ninja dab people right that'll
be their job be in the crowd and just
[ __ ] oh you're taking a dab well
here's another one and that'll be you
know a thing and that's kind of in the
it's almost like it's in the in the
spirit of Sam because you know Sam was
like pre-loading CBD and then [ __ ]
going out and dabbing with everyone and
like you know there's stories about Sam
about him and his like you know
understanding of of like the endoc
canabo system and saturating a system
with CBD and then going and [ __ ] like
dabbing all these people out and and
actually being able to like use the CBD
as a barrier for the the endoc canabo or
the receptor so that he didn't get his
loaded as everybody else and like you
know this is in the spirit of that I
think that's Sam would be proud of
us we got to mention that like a
prankster kind of a thing is like the
the ninja dab like a jingle
yeah because you could be like I'm just
busting balls bro with the [ __ ] 60
milligrams that's all I'm doing here
it's the original busting your balls
I'll tell you the ultimate dabs though I
mean these these uh these take it away
but when you had this kind of carb
cap pretty slow that that is oh you just
load it up it's like all right here you
go hey this is just never ending what
the [ __ ] that tip well you know what I'm
going to just load the cap I'm GNA load
the tip of the cap
and be like I got you dog and then
that's how we'll do it I got you bro we
got to bring it back man and and what I
also forget you forget too is when you
ninja dab someone as you cap it you can
gently hug them and just bring them in
close for like the hug the hug ninja dab
it's true they are paralyzed they're
paralyzed at that moment you're
hugging yeah you hug them all around
inside out it's it's a it's a gentle a
gentle hug of turs for their entire body
and the whole experience watch L was
going to be a bunch of dudes hugging
each other in a [ __ ] weird room like
this is this is not heading in the right
direction we need the wonders of hash
yeah and the uh spin this back around
did you mention the uh the connection
with Fidel and the food and that going
down oh the Le stuff yeah we ended up we
we grew too large for
uh
Carousel because they can't cater an
event uh of the size that we need the
way we need it cat because we have to
have catering service so we had to you
know find a restaurant that could do
that that is just as you know well-loved
and respected and and then luckily there
is one at Long Beach um so we have those
guys Kev what's the name of the
restaurant Long Beach uh it's called
open sesame in Long Beach um their food
is
incredible um and the spread is going to
be nuts for the first night it's gonna
be nuts yeah um I
mean just to put it into perspective uh
we're spending about the same amount on
the food this year that we did on our
entire budget last year that's that's a
reality so we're stepping it up in every
way yeah yes and for the dabbers for me
and everybody that I know who who really
dabs you're gonna have fresh fruit at
everywhere which for me is
like da like FR fruit and I'm a happy
boy so like I think that that's huge I
there's a station both days the entire
time that has tea water fresh fruit and
honey so that you can go up and get that
all the time during the entire event
The Oasis the honey hat roots and that's
that's the Oasis to like you know you
took too big of a dab go up there get a
scoop of honey get some water do a t-bo
on the ground there for a second [ __ ]
get back into it you know put yourself
back in
so that's amazing but yeah it'll be uh
it'll be it's cool because we also have
you know we looked at like the High
Times origins of everything and how High
Times was and the way High Times events
were set up and how everyone kind of got
together and how the sponsors were
involved so we wanted to kind of
throwback to that in a way and we do
have an outdoor area that will have the
sponsorship booths with all the vendors
out there and it's kind of a throwback
to like that High Times experience that
you could have but then when you come
inside um it has the sit down you know
like the restaurant kind of feel um so
we try to create that and sort of
incorporate that into it and then the
whole entire design is all all Middle
Eastern so like you know like [ __ ]
pillows and and Carpets on the floor
with pillows and sitting areas and you
know easy comfortable [ __ ] for you know
for taking dabs and chilling
so what we
need yeah and then there's you know the
sponsors come through too with a ton of
stuff that'll be on the table so there's
like Apex ancillary with you know
there's uh Q-tip stations there's
dunking stations from uh banger basket
there's uh I mean just a ton of
different stuff that's there uh you know
Salon those guys are providing Mystic
Timbers you know salmon those guys are
providing torches and you know other
tools and other equipment that we have
and you know things use
for yeah Fusion you know so we have a
bunch of stuff that's there that makes
it work all you really need is your rig
your personal items and his team are for
everybody it's G to be for all the
judges anyway
nutty yeah those would be crazy you know
so we have a lot of product we have
about 25 or so other product sponsors I
wish we could have had like you know 40
people that we this might have been a
little much but um you know these guys
has stepped up and some of them are
making like custom Legends of Hashi
stuff for us that's really awesome and
really our gift bags our gift bags are
val valued probably at the same price if
not more than like everybody's ticket
cost like we're throwing so much value
at people who are going to be there it's
going to be stupid and and you know it's
because of the product sponsors it's
because of all of you here and every
other sponsor that came in and did a
120u 990u 73u or stepped up and and and
came like without all you guys like we
really couldn't throw this kind value at
everybody um because I I we want it to
be a great marketing platform and I
think that this is a great way to do
that and and I think we're uh
succeeding you know very well the other
thing too you know what I always loved
about Legends is that there was no
trophy There's No Award you you had to
like you know you could tell your
stories and say you won Legends but then
Marcus and Sam had to kind of confirm
that and it's and it's still in that
same place you know where you know
there's there's we don't want to have
like a a trophy that sits in a room
somewhere that's like oh I won Legends
you know second place
2023 you know it just makes much more
sense to to give the sponsors the
opportunity to put products in those
winners hands um that they can use every
day that kind of make the experience
better that kind of brings the community
closer together uh and that was kind of
the idea so that's what what we did this
year um mother ship's going to be making
an award first second and third for each
category for all three three categories
and I think there will be some uh some
dry sift that's being entered because we
added that we added the dry sift
category for Sam because we thought it
would be kind of a cool a cool throwback
to that
so yeah I'm excited trust me that's the
Holy Grail you know what 90% of people
will enter rosin and a small percentage
of oh I
froze mark just went cold room I did
yeah I froze I stopped talking the
minute I freeze but um you wouldn't know
that anyway cuz I was
Frozen um I don't know what I was
saying you saying the dry sift is the
Holy Grail oh yeah yeah it's a listen
anytime you're hanging out with Hardcore
puffers they'll all have rosin a smaller
percentage of them will have full melt
bubble and almost almost none of them
will have full mouth dry sift and it's
just how it goes so you know I'd love to
see that category grow you know enter
your rosin and do well and maybe even
you know win a win a placing but then
try to bring in full melt bubble next
time and then try to bring in full melt
dry sift because to me that's like
bringing in rosin is the easiest thing
bringing in full melt bubble is the next
hardest thing bringing in full melt dry
sift is like holy
[ __ ] that's uh that's that's that's
another reality completely uh there's
something to be said for it it's very
different than I mean the highest grade
full melt bubble is on par with the
highest grade full melt dry sift they're
both uh spectacular oh yeah I mean
there's a lot of people that have never
tried dry sift I think they course you
know because dry sift is six-star that's
it you know that's hard very rare that's
like yeah only the greatest this is the
thing only the greatest material will
actually work and turn out the way you
want it to work out so it's kind of like
there's this word of God going on
whereas with like with oil products
whether it's a BHO or rosin if you're
making it into rosin I mean listen we
all know what great rosin is we know
what that is but there's a lot of people
who are deceived by what they think
great rosin is by just making it look
you know if it can if it can kind of
trick them with the way it looks uh
they'll be like oh this must be a great
rosin it's uh it's not that easy you
know to take to take and make great hash
and then press it into rosin
that's that's hardcore you know most
people are pressing uh their hash into
rosin because it doesn't melt and it
can't be dabbed so they you know it's
kind of like a lot of rosin hash rosin
is from mediocre hash uh not saying your
guys's is but I'm just saying out in the
world there a lot of people are taking
hash they're taking yeah they're taking
hash that can't be uh you know and then
there's the the there's the hardcore few
that are just like taking the most
ridiculous quality hash and pressing
that which uh I'm on the sh I'm on the
fence with that I'm like well if it was
six-star bubble I don't know if I would
press it it's going to dab just as nice
it's already in form in heads like
protected and there is something to be
said for the laboratory where
everything's going down you know where
all of the cannabinoids and volatile
organic compounds like filtering that
out is is different than not filtering
it out I like uh I like the mop up trip
that uh hash offers and I do see oil as
different myself I see rosin as a as a
hash oil but not a hash itself um just
because it's the heads have been melted
and it seems like it's it's oil now it's
always going to melt whereas only the
highest qualties hat of hashes dry
sifted or whitewashed will
melt boom is that a melty Darth
Vader oh yeah he says on mute
JP's 27 dabs in he's thinking I'm
probably going to have to hit another
dab here
soon I wasn't counting somebody counting
is somebody counting JP's dabs no I was
just joking around but I suspect it's a
lot are we all showing what we're
dabbing right now he's at like nine nine
or 10 dabs so far I think is what I've
got
damn be a high eight
yeah the high
AIDS start counting now we weren't
counting we'll start
counting little 9u pressed into
rosin I like that
too Canadian the legal Canadian Market
makes it very hard to sell a 90 Micron
into
Market um it's uh you have to COA every
grade that you keep separate so it's
like adds $1,000 which shrinks your
margin drastically especially test in in
Canada in Canada yeah and then also test
every Micron separately you if you want
to keep them separate so I've done it
it's like it can be like $8,000 just for
the COA for that batch so you want you
have to do big batches if you're also
only releasing 90 Micron well that's
another like you know you're going to
have to uh basic
what are you going to do with the other
grades you know like if and if you put
too many SKS on the market 90 120 like
you might find the 90 sells really well
but the other ones are like oh these
ones aren't selling quite as well oh
yeah that looks
nice so they make it hard here in Canada
also the lot size I mean yeah the lot
size and Ontario used to be the worst
because if you sell if they ordered like
five kilos and then they sold it really
fast and wanted another five kilos you
had to have it or you would be punished
and put down lower on their ordering
order the next time they ordered product
and so imagine like that's a whole
Province so and that's 10 kilos imagine
just making 10 kilos of just 90
Micron uh live hash rosin you know like
if you're making just 10 kilos of that
you have quite a bit of other material
that and it's also the because of the
tax the higher price you put on it the
the more ridiculous the tax will be on
it so it ends up there's a few things
that work against us up here but we're
doing the best we can with what we've
got how much diversion is in the
Canadian Market what's that how much
diversion like in the black
market well that all comes from stat
statistics so it's like um they there's
this alcohol and tobacco board they get
information from there's like they their
own uh questions you know with people
throughout the countries but it's all
kind of like in my opinion the people
who would know the real numbers they're
not talking to so it's all really just
[ __ ] the whole all of what they say
I mean the black market is for sure
alive and well um less so for flower my
friends that were just growing and
making money they find it very hard to
make money now because it's yeah may be
expensive or whatnot but it's like if
you can go to the store and like pick
out between like 30 30 or 40 flavors and
then when you buy it have it be the
flavor that you wanted it to be I mean
sure there's shitty brands that sell M
dried pre-rolled joints or whatever that
are that are that are shitty but there's
also you could navigate it if you needed
to it wouldn't take you long Addison to
find some decent product where you were
like yeah I found my dabs these pre-roll
joints are actually pretty good this bag
of weed is there there's products that
are doing well they're the same people
from the Legacy industry that have moved
into the legal industry and it's just uh
pushing these very large companies
slowly out of market share because uh
their whole game was to suck and to
short the entire industry and if they
can suck long enough and short the
entire industry long enough they just
end up being the last guys standing and
own a multi-billion dollar industry so I
think that's what canopy and tillay and
you know some of these big companies are
are potentially doing it's kind of
unfortunate but yeah I was wondering how
much if any gets diverted from the
traditional Market into the black market
I think it happens for sure that's
happening as well absolutely 100% I I
don't think it's so much diversion I
think that just the black market like
competes at a much higher level like on
the level of legal operators I mean
there's black market facilities that are
operating you know on the same Block in
the same building you know this that
whatever the way some of these places
work down here in in the US us so I I'm
not sure like that it's the the licensed
producers that are necessarily putting
stuff out the back door I think it's
like the guy who's running next to
doesn't have a license doesn't give a
[ __ ] and going there anyways so they
have billion grams over a billion grams
just sitting in vaults like thousands
and thousands and thousands of kgs
remember remember Indiana Jones remember
that remember the end of Indiana Jones
when they're pushing the CR through the
warehouse oh yeah yeah exactly that's
that's Canadian wreck Warehouse mids and
it is going out the back door we are
seeing in the market um I'm here it's
happening um but to answer your question
Adam Addison what's interesting about
like the dichotomy between Canada and
the US markets is that in the US it's
the the the term diversion and sort of
that concept is much more clearly
defined and quantifiable whereas in
Canada
the market is still new you know we're
less than five years into this thing
it's happening how everybody's doing it
is a little bit different but the mids
Market of the traditional Market uh it's
specifically like uh Marcus said in
flower is just gone and that's not
because all those consumers are now
going to recreational retail stores that
are licensed it's because these
consumers are off-putting these Bates
that they have to write off for whatever
reason and destructing them the same way
it happens in California but it's not as
it's not as easily and openly discussed
as as it is in California
yet well maybe Canadians are just more
private yeah we're more polite about it
you know so it'll it'll it'll happen
more but you know guys like Marcus
coming in and and really getting control
and and getting products out guys who
came up under Marcus like you know slurm
and and brindle and all these guys like
I mean not coming up under but um you
know in following in his footsteps um
you know these guys are coming to Market
kind selections is coming to Market like
real real people real smokers and that's
what we didn't have in Canada that was
always present in the US because when
the US legalized it wasn't Federal
legalization so you always had to have a
little bit of an appetite for risk to be
involved in cannabis whereas in Canada
it was like the lights are on there's no
risk come raise all the money and do all
the things and so there there was no uh
the the individual a high Chad Factor
there's a high higher Chad Factor here
than than in the US yes absolutely no
risk yeah that uh made a shiver go up my
spine I was like yeah that is pretty
interesting how um
legalization you know went very
different um between US and Canada and
and you know kind of lights on all at
once and you know fundraising all at
once right away um you know really did
make things different you really did
have a lot of um shitty operators go
there you really did have a lot of
frauders go there you really did have a
lot of scumbags go there so um to raise
money just just to raise money because
the regulatory environment was different
so um you know here in the US every
state is different um you know and some
of these msos one of the things that
they are good at is you know they
they're able to take advantage of
different regulatory patterns and things
in individual markets and and play
things like that um you know play the
tax in in Michigan against California
against Oregon against Nevada this that
whatever and it's it's a strategy that
some of these brands rely on to survive
so um I do think that um you know the
the regulat the difference in the
regulatory environment definitely
changes what the end user is able to get
the the end user in the United States is
able to access way more different um
products and and and services and things
like that than up in Canada because
there's way more people operating
there's way more lure there's way more
guys making hash so um you know I think
I think that is definitely part of it
and I think that is definitely something
that um the black market does a good job
of people that bring stuff in from can I
mean that's that's how a lot of people
in the US survived for a long time was
bringing [ __ ] in from Canada so now um
there's a lot of high-end stuff that
that comes from here and goes back up
there so you know I think the black
market um kind of bridges the Gap I
think for the culture and I think that's
why it's important to protect the black
market and respect the black market and
remember that a lot of these people that
um you know have been here for 15 years
20 years 30 years Etc um had to do it a
lot differently and and again for us
that's why an event like this was
important to to give back to is because
a lot of these people have been here for
20 years and you know it it it was just
a lot different back then um you know
we're we've been making controls for 15
years and and the way that people grew
at scale 15 years ago versus at scale
today is way different um and and you
and just like the the risk people would
assume back then and today so to respect
um kind of the the older crowd and the
people that had to do it when there was
way more risk um is really important
because at the end of the day um our
culture is at risk every single day um
every single day there there's companies
coming in there's operators coming in
there's people starting up that that
aren't about the culture don't respect
about the don't respect the culture
don't care about the culture so um you
know for us um that's that's a big thing
I love getting high I love using
cannabis cannabis is really important to
me cannabis has done a lot for me we
were able to have a business that Sur
for coming on 16 years because guys are
growing cannabis so um it's a big deal
and and it does matter to me that there
are people that operate in cannabis at
any level that don't even get high uh
there it it it does kind of bother me
that there's people that operate stores
or brands or companies or this that
whatever that are comfortable making
money off of cannabis but won't use
cannabis or or you know look down on
using cannabis so um culture is very
much on the line the more that industry
progresses the more [ __ ] we create the
more things we monetize the more money
we wethink about trying to get out of it
the the more we we we lose like our
culture whatever it is so um you know
for us that's why participating and
being able to to help Empower you guys
to do it how you want to do it and and
give back to the community that you guys
know best was really important to us so
um you know we love getting high and
that's that's really important to us
that um that's able to still be a
thing yep no and that's you know those
those people that you were talking about
the you know the Chads the [ __ ]
like they they can't sponsor Legends and
they won't be at Legends and they they
literally can't be in the room just
based off the amount of culture and
consumption and what's there and and
it's all you know that's why it's rad to
have sponsors that are in line with that
that are down and understand that that
is a big part of the culture you know
there are people that are you know Mega
do consumption people that just happen
to fall into the the hash world and hey
if you want to talk you know you know
actual [ __ ] milligrams like BHO
typically has more milligrams but I
think because solventless is is you know
a little less harsh on people you can
consume a lot more it and get even more
milligrams but you know that's uh that's
a whole other story but no it's it's
Legends is all about you know what
Marcus and those guys you know created
and it's get getting all the best people
together and being able to like
celebrate in this way and and now you
know having it on a bigger scale but
still throwing back as much as possible
to the old school stuff is has kind of
been been it's been one of the bigger
challenges because you do have to
monetize it you do have to figure it out
and and do it correctly and then make it
so that at the same time while you're
doing that and balancing that you have
to deal with the the politics and the
culture itself and and you know how all
that stuff works so it's I don't know
it's it's it's been good because you
know at the same time you're so [ __ ]
busy with organizing this I mean last
year there was a 100 people so that's
manageable right that's like oh okay you
know you can kind of Juggle that but
this year it's 250 people at Max and and
you're just kind of expanding that list
and bringing in these other you know
figuring out the the proper you know
list of of sponsors and everyone that's
there so you know it's still a Juggle
but at the same time pounds of
hash yeah apparently supposedly alleged
allegedly allegedly
allegedly allegedly but yeah I mean you
know a private it's that's what's great
about that too is that you still have
the right to have a private dinner and
the private get together in an event
where people come together all invite
only um you know there's no open sale of
anything and it's it's it's nice to
still have that right to be able to do
that because that's kind of you know you
can't do it in a restaurant because
obviously um it would it would just
cause an issue but luckily you know
there are guys that have some spaces and
that we work with that are capable of
putting it on and helping us do it so it
should be a [ __ ] Blast for sure man
well it certainly won't be the last time
we speak on it that's for sure I've uh I
know that Addison's got a head out here
soon at 11 o'clock I also have to uh go
off with my eight-year-old son today and
uh go check him out skating he doing
some skating lessons today so that's a g
to be a highlight for me today but I
definitely want to thank everyone that
uh showed up I definitely uh appreciate
each and every one of you and we'll have
to uh have you guys back on hash Church
another day for sure when we're talking
for a longer amount of time JP we
definitely want to have you back and
just like talk about like for an hour go
into the turp slurper and the all of the
you're on mute and all of the uh all of
that sort of information because uh
people love that
dude yeah that sounds great man love
love love to come
back absolutely well thank you all for
coming out and uh we'll uh we'll have
some more we'll be talking about Legends
right until the day that it happens it's
about 3 weeks away now so we've uh we've
got 20s something days and uh I guess uh
continue on have a great day everybody
and smoke much hash May the full melt
bless your bowl sooner than later if it
hasn't already and uh we'll talk really
soon everybody peace guys thanks marus
later guys every