hey everybody welcome back to hash
Church 2.0 episode 1 the past the
present and the future of hashish I'm
pretty pretty excited to have everyone
here Wow and how lucky did I get my my
my YouTube was on mute I totally dropped
the ball I should have heard myself
reverberating anyway I'm gonna send the
invite out today we got a really cool
panel we got some of the regulars we got
some new folks and we're gonna be
discussing hashish today from start to
finish I'm not gonna let the
conversation sway into anything other
than that beautiful beautiful glandular
trichomes heads that we also love in
particular micro encapsulated and of
course let me get the link out here to
everyone right now I got myself a new
way of doing it so I don't have to send
it to through Facebook to make sure we
hear that right swoosh sound which we
didn't so I'll go to the other server
are we hearing it where's the sweet the
sweet so everyone should have gotten
that link now and it's okay if you're if
you're a little bit hazy I could
potentially make this a little bit
darker let me see here let me see here
webcam settings webcam settings I think
we're good we're good
so yeah I've got a good group invited in
today to have a discussion about hashish
it was a long time coming look at that
Johnny be number one better punch these
in what's up Johnny be gotta be I see
Jessica and Andrew anyone that has a
house the closest place here my yeah
it's the dopest family you guys got to
figure out your microphone it's just
reverberating you might have to leave it
on mute when you're not talking welcome
to
Astrix 2.0 guys we've got some Frenchy
cannoli in the room we got Johnny B in
the room and we got mr. Chris Bennett in
the room hitting his VAP bag already
nice and early all right how's it going
Chris
can you hear me Chris all right I
couldn't carry you back going on drew
hey can you hear me I can hear you
perfectly bro came in with you came in
with headphones yeah that's the way to
do it yeah yeah all right well we got
513 people out there waiting anxiously
for Hastur
all right Chris if you have the YouTube
channel if any of you have the YouTube
channel open just mute it completely
because we don't want to hear we only
want the the panelists to be in the
Google chat it's kind of like when you
phone in on the radio station you got to
turn the radio down it's just like that
so try to make sure that you don't have
any feedback going on there we got mr.
skunk man Sam in the room what's going
on skunk man oh all right Oh see how he
have been why did she not get the link
let's try this again great to see
everybody this morning right great to be
seen I'm sorry for the technical
difficulties everyone we just want to
get the room on point here we got seven
people so we got room for three more
hash Warriors and then we'll get things
started a Balaji
in the room what's going on dad logic
hey not sure if you can hear me great
this is actually why I sent the
etiquette out three or four days early
to for us to try to check on everyone's
cam and microphone and whatnot just in
case if you're not talking just leave
here we can hear you dab logic
absolutely etiquette out there useful
that's the the YouTube channel is on
your you just have to close YouTube and
only keep the Google Chat open unless
you want a new
you tube and keep an eye on the chat
that's going on and dank Duchess I just
sent you the link again make sure that I
got the right email for you I just
replied back to the email you sent me so
it should absolutely be the right email
and just in case I always a little bit
of technical difficulties that's not too
bad I think a nice
I can't once the hash oh yeah hey Donna
look at them it's like Merrill all over
it like fresh-made nice come on I know
you just jumped up here he's like okay
this is about hash let's talk about hash
guys good for ya yeah
bubbleman so seedy it's true you know
what though it's part of hashed Church
and I think it's okay to have
difficulties hey so we got nine folks in
we got some his mind just dropped into
the chat room what's going on buddy
not too much what's going on with you
guys well it sounds like we're about to
get down and have a little conversation
about hah sheesh sounds good to me let's
do yeah let's do it I think we're gonna
start off with mr. Chris Bennett he had
a little bit of a thing put together
just a little overview whatever he wants
to say and then once we've done that
we'll do we'll we'll introduce each
person and sort of a quick little who
you are how long you've been involved in
cannabis when you got involved with
hashish and then we'll move forward into
the presence of hashish after that well
hello everybody hi and glad to see
another season of hash Church going on
yeah you know definitely I've had a
long-standing interest in the history of
cannabis most of that has been about how
it affects culture via magic and
religion and that type of stuff so
consciousness that type of stuff but of
course in my corner Santeria by looking
into that I've come across much on
hashish and stuff like that by no claim
to be an expert in the history like
Robert C Clark but I'll go over some of
the basic kind of information about it
you know much is unknown when it comes
to hashish when we started separating it
but the earliest possible reference to
separating Cronk homes
from the Leafs and flowers is the Syrian
reference pointed to by Ethan Rousseau
from about 2600 years ago and in it the
instructions require that 16 drugs thou
shalt pound dry pound and strain and
then fumigate there so they're obviously
straining it now whether this was a
full-on separation that's my bird in the
background sorry whether it's a full-on
separation of trichomes from the leaves
and flowers I don't know
could just be pulverized cannabis but
that's the earliest probably have to you
like strain type of cannabis and there's
also lots of references in the ancient
world to Kuna boo incense which is a
cannabis incense and many people have
suggested that this was a form of
hashish as well and some books printed
as a form of hashish in ancient Assyria
unclear a lot of ancient incense was
simply ground up plants mixed together a
powdered and you'd have to actually put
oil on it and stuff like that to be able
to light it so it's not clear if it was
a full-on resin extract however there
are references the oil of kanabi which
is oil of cannabis and this does sound
like some sort of oil product that has
been extracted
although the extraction methods used to
attain this are unknown in his book the
rig Vedic soma the Indian scholar worm
Cod suggests that their agent Sanskrit
names for cannabis leaves flowers and
resin which seems to indicate that there
would have been means of separating it
from the flowers and stocks back then
even so chair ass is pretty old in
Indian literature and it may go back to
Vedic references according to where up
on deck in the turn hashish itself first
starts to appear in the Muslim world is
thought to be just mean the heard and
kind of like the heard in relation to
cannabis like kind of the herb of herbs
and although other suggestions have been
made the night at nineteenth-century
biblical scholar John Quito suggested
that ashy
actually came from a Hebrew word as she
shot which was related to both a plant
that provided some sort of resin that
was mixed with wine and shesh a plant
that was a fiber plant so we have here a
resinous and a fiber plant and he says
that as shisha likely became hashish as
it carried on into the Islamic world and
in India as well like you know a lot of
people say that hashish didn't start
until the Islamic world in a cannabis
use even but that's not the case Persian
use of cannabis was going on long before
Islamic use took place amongst its
irrational religion and and right up
until the Islamic period we have a
ration relation references to the terms
manga and Banga which have been
suggested as cannabis and have also been
suggested as hashish by some people and
like the references to Kido this was a
resin that was mixed with wines
according to some sources and there's a
before hashish appears in the 10th
century in the Islamic world there's
another plant dotty which again is a
resin plant intoxicating but mixed with
one you know it's important to remember
that a lot of the hashish in the
medieval period was ingested or prayer
prepared with drinks and not smoke
smoking cannabis and hashish is
something that's thought to be
relatively new to take place after the
time of discovery of the new world habit
of tobacco smoking and then this was
incorporated with cannabis although it
was burned as an incense this was
generally in a fumigation type of
situation where they would capture the
smoke and inhale it but not have pipes
and things like that to smoke although
there's debate about this even right and
then hashish we start to see it
appearing in the medieval period the
alchemists Cardno makes reference to as
CSAT which is thought to be hashish from
the description and other references
like that start to appear in the
medieval muscle in the medieval period
in Europe after the Crusades and some of
the first European literature novels and
things like that actually make reference
to hashish Marco Polo's famous escapades
into
the Islamic world was really led in a
big way to the Crusades as well as that
the Cameron there's an accountant the
camera on one of the first novels in
Europe and it also has a story of
hashish so it was pretty much taken up
right away you know and it's interesting
that it appears in fiction because after
Napoleon's war in the 18th century an
invasion of the Mideast hashish became
increasingly popular in Europe and we
see this taking place particularly among
literary circles like that of Victor
Hugo Alexandre Dumas defiled de Balzac
Gerardi interval and other writers who
gathered together in a group known as
lek Club the hash machines and in Paris
France and many of these authors
although they wrote over a hundred and
fifty years ago their books are still in
print movies remain about their books
these are some of the best authors of
the world and they all gathered together
regularly to consume hashish ingested
oftentimes a mixture of a gooey hashish
into some coffee and then they would
take up more of a psychedelic type of
amount of dose not the more casual
social amount that that most of us are
used to and one of the really
interesting things about this period
when hashish first starts to come up is
some really interesting psychological
advancement started to take place and
the 18th century a doctor Thomas Arnold
and in the 19th century hashish club
member and co-founder dr. JJ Moreau they
started to look at the hashish
intoxication and compared to things like
insanity as well as the ability to dream
at night and are dreaming because many
people when they were taking these
larger amounts we're having sort of
astral type voyages and coming back and
telling tales of what they saw in these
realms and this all led to the mapping
out of what became known as the
subconscious in the unconscious mind and
how she played a pivotal role in that
layout and understanding of that through
psychiatrists like and doctors like dr.
Thomas Arnold and dr. JJ Moreau so this
is a really
important thing and I think it's
comparable to the role that cannabinoids
have played today in understanding the
endocannabinoid system in the body of
man and this is equal importance because
really led to our understanding of the
human mind and I think that's a you know
a pretty good overview of the whole
thing you know there's all sorts of
different names I could list off for
five minutes probably all the different
names that hashish is acquired like
cannabis over the years it's one of the
most named things but I'll save the
audience that open it up to other
stoppers thank you very much boom Sheba
boom Shiva that was great thank you so
much for the breakdown see who we got
here oh yeah we're good so yeah that was
wonderful we got a I'm sure maybe skunk
man Sam has a few things he wants to
mention in regards to the history of
hashish or perhaps just in regards to
his history in hashish what do you say
Sam are you there for a little chatty
chat or did you leave the room to puff
holes you know I pay maybe that in the
Islamic world a lot of it was filtered
like you know it rained hash keeps up
stuff like that and in India a lot of
that was hand pressure skin press
there's the famous stain L of the naked
virgins running through the cannabis
fields and getting pressing cannabis
plants all over their bodies and skin
and then scraping it off of night now
that could be mythology but definitely
pressed together on hands and rubbed
into little balls that's probably the
earliest way I would think as opposed to
separating Keith I've always felt like
the running through the fields and
collecting hash on your body although
was a beautiful vision it was probably
more of a mythology than than reality
ident I think so my thinks though you
know it's a lot of like romantic
imagination went into hashish and
there's all sorts of misinformation out
there in the historical record you know
and I mean people writing about it it's
secondhand accounts third hand accounts
that sort of thing well I like that he
finished it off with a boom Shiva I mean
that was I will say after traveling to
India and kind of linking up you know at
the at the at the Maha kumbhamela in
Haridwar when I where I went in 1998
which is a very large gathering in India
it's almost like like it's almost like a
Lola Palooza of siddhu's where you have
all the different sects are hanging out
with what you know with themselves the
Nagas and the Krishna's and the Brahmas
and the Shiites and I went and hung out
with the majority of them and puffed
bowls with the ones that would puff
bowls and hung out and drank teas with
the ones that wouldn't puff bowls and
man if I didn't navigate and and direct
myself right into the XI vite
Baba's man were those guys the chillest
siddhu's to hang out with and I'm
talking
we hung out with the Nagas who are have
apparently lived this intensely hard
life and don't own clothes or really
anything and so they often get to bathe
in the gaps prior to you know
high-ranking military and political
officials they have this sort of you
know they get to bathe first because of
the life that they live but hanging out
and puffing bowls with them was just not
on the same level as hanging out in
puffing bulls with Pashupati the sheave
eyed Bubba that I met on the banks of
the Ganges and spent two to three weeks
straight just smoking chilling after
chilling after chilling I can still hear
him almost 20 years later or 20 years
actually later saying one more Chilam we
are making one more Chilam we are making
it was just such a wonderful thing to
hear every 7 to 8 minutes for you know
18 hours at a time one more Chilam we
are making oh yes one more chilling we
are making I know that puts a smile on
your face Frenchy and as it should
because yes smoking kilims is pretty
darn fun if you really want before I
smoked the hubbly bubbly at the first
legends of hash dinner
just throw Duchess on mute there that
was pretty crazy sounded like a vacuum
got turned on before I smoke the hubbly
bubbly from the Afghans I truly had
never you know the Chilam was the first
like serious serious serious pounding of
hashish that my lungs had ever taken and
I wasn't that old I guess I was probably
25 or 26 years old at the time and only
really maybe ten years into my journey
as a hashish in' I got into hashish I'll
start why not with myself back in
probably 89 90 I had been smoking
cannabis but being from Winnipeg we also
saw some of the import hash that came in
via Montreal which is where most of the
hash in Canada was ex imported into
whether it was Moroccan which we saw
very little of we saw a lot of Afghani
and we saw the odd brick of Lebanese so
I was able to at a very young age
experienced the red Lebanese which was a
little more sedated and the white
Lebanese which was a little bit more
energetic I guess just the difference
really was cutting it down a little bit
earlier or even maybe the red lab sat on
the field probably more likely for a
little bit longer of a time and cured
out that resin and the Sun could also
have been a different timeline of summer
to winter I don't know for sure
maybe Sam or someone else on the panel
has an idea in regards to that anyone
else have some history of hashish they
want to share before we get into
introducing ourselves and giving our own
history I just wanted to show these
antique Chile's I got here real quick
with an old postcard from about 1910 of
a sadhu who's held his arm up until it's
actually lost the ability to move out of
act of devotion but these are old 19th
the early 20th century fancy chill ohms
that were used by sad news you know I
met a guy at the Maha kumbhamela I met a
bunch of guys I'm
guy that was holding his arm up and he
had been holding it up for something
like 31 or 32 years that was in 1998 and
then I met another guy who was kind of
propped up on this stand and he was
holding his leg up I met a guy that had
closed his fist and grown his
fingernails through the top of his hand
he was just holding his fist closed for
like I think he was like also over 20
years and then there was a gentleman who
had stuck a knife right through his
forearm and had a bucket collecting the
blood that was dripping down and he was
pretty sure that he was going to be okay
definitely a different sort of mentality
the fakir mentality that removing the
the mind from the body
removing pain and the existence of pain
from the experience definitely tripped
me out it was one of the things that I
always tell people you know India is
like an adventure it's not really like a
vacation and that was kind of the main
reason was some of these guys at the
khumba mela were just they were doing
some next-level stuff i was just a hash
aficionado that wanted to smoke some
bowls with some side use on the side of
the road and exchange information but I
got exposed to a lot more through that
the culture of the khumba mela than i
could have ever anticipated that is for
sure thanks for sharing those chillings
I will say that most of the children's I
smoked while they're in the 90s were of
Italian creation really smooth beautiful
Italian chillens all the Saudis kind of
agreed that I met at least that the
Italian chillins were you know the ones
that they wanted to be smoking on well
why don't we go through the list we'll
start with dab logic and then we'll move
on to Jessica and Dru and then we'll
move on to the other drew and and we'll
go through I'll let you know each time
what I want you guys to do is basically
give us dabbe logic you can start it off
give us a little history as to yourself
and to you know where you're at right
now and how you got there in particular
with hashish what was your inspirations
everybody hear me yes sir
yeah I guess I got in a hashish from my
grandfather and reduced it to me first
he was big in the hashish and hashish
oil the way back and first offense then
I had a really big interest in it and
kind of devoted starting at like mm2
researching hashish and learning about
it and trying to was the biggest you
know kind of hurdle for me was quality
hash long enough time actually met some
people and good we eaten from it and
eventually that led into a switch I
passed you know sure so man I'm
with a company Verde natural they're all
organic all soil growing attics and
awesome things to work with so I'm sure
kind of going through all their
different ends and those different
things and finding out what works and
what doesn't cuz that's kind of a big
thing with hash as well is that be able
glad down on something you think is
gonna be really amazing just because
it's not the right lineage or the right
variety that true true can you give a
timeline in regards to what the year was
when you were 15 and got turned on to
hash just to give us an idea mm 25 right
now so I mean that was about ten years
ago 2008 I mean bubbleman was a huge
part I mean I honestly I've been
watching your videos since I was young
so interesting thing do you have it
I'll say one thing your photos have me
drooling on the regular dude it's you
you're you're the growers and the
genetics and the hash making is
absolutely on point for dab logic I'm
always looking in fact all of you are on
this panel for almost that one main
reason of course a lot of you are
well-known but for me it's as simple as
does your photos of your hash make my
mouth water because I can't make that
[ __ ] up and I can say that everyone on
this panel has hash that makes my mouth
water and so that's really where the
invitations came out people like well
how did you come up with this panel it's
like well I came up with this panel
based on the fact that my mouth watered
when I looked at their hash which means
to me that they took that pathway of
instead of you know which is a really
important thing that you said learning
about the genetics because it's true you
know I got very lucky when I started the
bubble bag company in 1999 because the
first couple of materials I made or just
like it's hash tag hash bubble hash in
1998-99 was not really something a lot
of people loved people were pressing it
together
wets people were using genetics that
weren't really the ideal genetics and it
wasn't until I put some a breeder Steve
shish-kabob
into my bags and actually saw something
come out that was full melt and then of
course I lucked out into rene which was
a beautiful cultivar that I mean the
first time I made hash with it I picked
it up off of the ground it was it was
swept into the corner with dust and hair
and dirt and I and I remember at first
just picking up a little bit because
there was so much resin along the bottom
in a rolling paper just off the top that
was under tea and I put it in the
rolling paper and rolled it up and when
I got home I opened the paper up and the
hash was just in a tube and it was shiny
and I thought wow that looks like it's
really nice resin so I asked for all of
the material off of the floor I ran a
batch and basically got stained glass
window beautiful unbelievable Renee and
Renee really was the whole reason why
bubbleman as a character was able to in
the early days inspire people such as
yourself because that hash that's the
real magic for a hash maker getting
either growing the proper material which
my hats off to all of you that are doing
that and also even those that are going
around and finding the material it takes
a real hashish aficionados olfactory to
to remove all of the bad it's almost
like being a broker for cannabis in the
90s in Vancouver and saying no to 90% of
the material that broker had the highest
integrity and that broker got the best
contracts because the brokers that just
wanted to make their hundred bucks on
every pound and accepted everything that
people showed them you know I think I
hope you're getting the metaphor it's
just it was the wrong path to take which
was the greed path and so with the
hashish path you know we're constantly
running things and seeing at the end
while this isn't really what I wanted
this isn't the resin that I wanted so
hats off to the hash makers that you
know to the rosin press with the subpar
melts and to Frenchie's hands for the
full melt six stars so let's let's move
on with Jessica and Andrew the beautiful
young couple here who are expecting a
child and
near future and some hashish aficionados
in the room they got their rosin press
they got their hash out and why don't
you guys tell us a little bit about
yourselves
thank you for that well I started I
started seeing plants when I was about
12 I don't know a year that was 2000
2001 2002 my uncle was growing up in
NorCal I was around plants before I was
making hash I was small-time selling
weed and smoking flour up until about
eighteen year old I started to work hard
to grow for myself and making
concentrates a lot more than the flower
and just started making passion beautifu
BHO from there we my one light turned
into four lights four lights turned into
ten lights and ten lights turned into a
job in with some commercial grows in the
Bay Area and from there I started taking
him material and making hash from that
and I had to hash in let's say early
2011-2012 wasn't as hyped as it was now
there wasn't a lot of people behind hash
and so it was a lot of using using the
BHO money to make my own hash so I can
smoke the hash and kind of you know make
money off the BHO from there we built
milk the hash brand up until I can
afford to not make pho anymore and I
sold all my pho question equipment but
condenser and refrigerator the
refrigeration unit set up a hash room
and from then on it's just been hash you
know that's all we make now and but now
we started from started from growing for
people and now we have a permit ranch up
in Calaveras County that were growing
our own material to make our own hash so
nice now I met Jessica about three and a
half years ago and she joined the team
and she's been a blessing ever since
helping me with everything
got introduced the hash in around 2013
and through that was how I learned about
hash was through Instagram seeing it on
profiles such as yourself and mica tea
and and then I I found her YouTube
channel bubbleman and I started watching
your videos you're making hash I believe
with Sam I'm not sure but but yeah that
was a great resource for me and I was so
intrigued but there was a way to
separate the trichomes without using a
chemical just ice and water and I
started reading forums and yeah just I
started I was a house consumer and then
I met Andrew 2014 the end of 2014
mm the early 2015 and then you became a
half and she suited up in the colder in
the start they can have me and that's
our story
yeah that's awesome about as well oh let
me put you in the road so I'm even gonna
get a read I got you I put a smile on my
face to see the giant bags of herb that
are like sitting on the counter behind
you guys right now I was just like damn
these guys are like seriously coming in
with like 25 30 pounds of weed the hash
makers it's neat to hear that you got
turned on to it through Instagram
because wow you know it was probably
only four and a half to five years ago I
broke my collarbone quite badly
thus it's sticking out very ugly
snowboarding up in Whistler and I was
crippled I was just like couldn't move I
was on my couch and I was very much on
to this sort of phone thing I got onto
Twitter within two or three weeks of it
coming out Instagram I got on within the
first month but it was an on cannabis
account it was mostly Asian people that
were on Instagram at the time a lot of
people from Hong Kong and I you know I
couldn't even read what they were saying
but it was a real photography app
sharing photography and as a
photographer I had a real affinity and
love for that and the way to be able to
kind of link up with people from the
other side of the world and see what
they're shooting and getting ideas and
inspirations through them it was being
crippled on my back that I finally
picked up my iPad and I thought you know
I have like 10 years of images epic
cache images 10 years of images that
I've been taking so I compiled them all
onto my iPad and I just started posting
like five or six of these images every
day you know probably for close to a
year or six months whatever it was I
think I posted eight hundred plus images
in a very short period of time and
that's how I built the BC bubbleman
account on Instagram so and I also was
inspired I mean solid 'less mind your
guys itself dab logic soil groan dr.
ladybug who i've invited in later when
we get a little bit of maybe in an hour
and a bit we'll do a little switch and
we'll get some new some new folks in the
full-blown inspiration to just be able
to look on your phone and see hash of
the utmost highest quality the six star
where you just know just by looking at
it there's not really any way to fake
that and so I've had a real appreciation
for Instagram it's neat to hear about
the past of hashish and these authors
meeting and eating hashish and now in
the future you have well which is now
the present I think they call it a
present because it is indeed a gift you
have all of us sharing our information
and our photos and growing cannabis and
sharing genetics and just sharing tips
and tricks on in ways to get this
product even cleaner and cleaner of
course one of my huge inspirations way
before Instagram existed and even way
before overgrow and sites like that was
with skunk man Sam even though he's very
very private man and he wasn't exactly
posting it out there if you were on that
underground scene if he went to the
cannabis cut back in the early to mid
90s you could maybe cross paths with Sam
maybe you'd see him speak at a large
cannabis and hemp conference and kind of
just be like
that stuntman Sam like there he is over
there and what a huge inspiration to be
able to finally meet him to come good
friends with him become beyond inspired
from his how she's processing even at
first just from photographing it I think
that that was a game-changer when the
first 99.999% gland heads was
photographed at his place in Amsterdam
that that that was as effective as
changing the way people thought about
hashish as the first water hash that was
being shared with people which made it
very easy for regular people you know
that had no knowledge whatsoever to
become along you know I can say for
perfect example is my mother who worked
for the police for 35 years and has no
cannabis knowledge whatsoever
I sat her down and she made some full
melts on her first batch ever of bubble
bags just because I gave her the simple
instructions and it's kind of like when
you don't have this huge ego thinking
that it's really a lot more being done
than it's being done and you're just
like okay so I mix it up and make sure
it's cold I filter it through the bags i
spoon it out I break it up and it's sort
of sort of anyone can kind of do it
whereas you know Sam's art form was a
little bit different
getting glands that are dry sifted
removed and cleaned to that level it
just did not exist in our community and
even now today with a few people
learning the DVD carding static trick
and some other tricks it's still very
very much what I would consider the holy
grail of hashish I don't put water hash
down I think the highest level of water
hash the highest highest level six star
is is right on point with the highest
level of dry sifted resin but that's
going to be you know the alcohol soluble
terpenes the ones that don't wash out
and water the ones that stay present
right till the end and of course behind
me you can see some pictures I think
this one's from Cuban I think we got one
from Sam right here and yeah dry sifting
there's some large amounts of resin
being sifted almost 4,000 grams in about
ten minutes dry sifted farmers grade
hash
but it would be a good idea to put up
some fun pictures behind me so that we
could scare a beautiful hashish and the
cannabis plant that we love so much so
that was a wonderful history lesson from
Andrew and Jessica and I guess we're
gonna move up to Drew who's next in line
what do you say drew unmute your mic and
give us give us give us that history
what what name do you go under is it is
it dr. ladybug yeah that's cool that's
what I thought you know but you came on
under drew so dr. ladybug was an account
that I just came across he's kind of the
wild card I knew nothing about him but I
knew that his hash was 100% on point and
that alone is you know it's kind of like
how people used to ask me about legends
of hashish how do I get a ticket to
legends of hashish
you know I'm soma or I know soma or I'm
a well-known person in the industry I'm
like well that doesn't actually get you
a ticket what gets you a ticket is
having great hashish and so that's how
you got your golden ticket into this
room so give us a little history lesson
on - thank you yeah so my first exposure
to hash was when I was in high school I
was probably 14 or 15 and the alert we
were smoking a lot of weed and even at
that age and then my buddy went to
Europe we went to Amsterdam for about
two weeks or so and he brought back some
hash in a little shampoo bottle he
wrapped wrapped in cellophane ah the
classic shampoo bottle PS it's not safe
to smuggle in shampoo bottles anymore
all right yeah so he brought something
that back and was really it was really
nice-looking it was like it was blond it
was like no the old style hash of like
pressed as she - it was really nice it
was who's pretty melty - and but you
know that we don't really like know like
what it was like the process how to make
it really all we knew is that it was you
know made with ice of water and it was
you know a natural extract
we don't really see too much of it other
than that so I didn't see it for a while
but then when I started growing totally
after high school when I was about 19 my
growing mentor he would make hash from
his trim he had he actually had the bone
bags he had the one gallon bags you know
back then we were just throwing him like
you know like little 4x4 tents so and
you know we weren't move the concept of
washing cool flowers back then never
even crossed our mind it was offered
includes like I'll trim run but um so I
started making hash because I preferred
smoking hash they I pretty much didn't
smoke any of the flower that I threw all
that stuff was sold and I just ran all
my trim and just like smoked that and
the rest is nothing stages hash is a
good really big part of my life that's
what sure did take it a small break from
it for a while over I've been doing this
on and off for about twelve years now
and right in the middle I did take a
break stepped away for a little while
went back to school but um you know ever
since 2013 or so I got a job in the
industry as a delivery driver and just
to make some connections and I made some
connections and you know made some
things happen and you know now now I'm
here and it's actually really crazy just
surreal moment to you be here beauty
honor and so when in 2013 where the
connections you made growers are you
also growing your own resin for the
house that you're making so yeah you
know we do grow we have we have like an
outdoor spot and I have a buddy that I
work with in Southern California who
does a lot of our indoor cultivation but
uh yeah yeah well your your product is
absolutely on point so for anyone that
wants to check them out I'm sure
everyone has Instagram accounts so maybe
we'll go through the whole thing and
then we'll all drop the Instagram
accounts for everyone as well
all right well we'll move on to Frenchie
and French she's gonna tell us how he
fell in love with hashish because this
guy absolutely is in love with hashish
gotta unmute you gotta unmute Frenchie
you're muted here muted push that mute
button there we go there we go
we'll get him on we'll get him on no
he's still muted
I can't unmute him for some reason but
he can if he goes and pushes the
microphone at the top there should be a
microphone and a little guy sometimes
you got to click here your mouse on top
of the box to bring it back
it did yes there you are okay so she
should Club you where turkey looks that
Zeus right there where some of my fellow
leech writer when I was a kid I grew up
reading Thousand and One Nights and
before even speaking ash I was he
dreaming of time being in juice County
your answer about Jana Cooper oh and our
Zoo Story so that the first time when I
smoked which was like it like in I was
17 I smoked with special
lebanese-american kids and I was
introduced to their family so that I was
like I was I've always been in that
future flower for me it's just was just
the materials that all the pleasures
raised in everything was in Elysium and
when I was a kid that didn't believe
that it would become illegal in my
lifetime so to feel like I wasn't really
the stem of the world I want and I've
earned into country where it was not
illegal but accepted you know what I
mean so I can eat a bunch of ash funky
and then I went to India where it's
religious
it's part of the body journey its
machina Shalom is dedicated to the card
the grant was born in the drop of the
a-league seal of realize that fall from
from the sky una in the Himalaya is like
it sir
it takes a good dimension that was much
bigger than what they had experienced
before you know what I mean and and then
when I came here to the states I
realized that it was actually also
medi-cal it was discoveries like I'm so
much in love it because it's a long
story I was 17 years old I'm 61 and I've
been smoking a short that time like my
life is truly dedicated to it I didn't
really know it until lately but it's
what it is beautiful beautiful I love to
hear it I love to hear the histories I
think I was just D jazzing my banger
from a mildly hot rip I took while you
were talking about your love of hashish
I was actually looking for a little
piece of hash that I had from Roshan
that you guys made together on the
Sunshine Coast I was gonna smoke some
Frenchy hash while you were talking
about your love for hashish but I wish I
would have gotten over and seen you guys
I felt kind of bad that I never that I
never made it over I was pretty hurt
what when you came over here I was quite
injured so I wasn't really uh along to
me yeah I wasn't traveling you know it
was it was kind of the first time I got
so hurt that hashish just wasn't enough
I needed to I needed I needed the time
to heal so we cheat a little bit yeah I
was eating it exactly I had some
capsules made with some CBD and some no
no but I mean that it instead of smoking
yo OH
chewing just right on the hash just
nothing else you don't you don't do
nothing but eat eat Acharya no idea how
much
thankfully I did a little bit of that in
India with facade do the she vide side
you would always make we make us eat a
little piece of the Nepali cream that we
had while we were drinking our chai tea
out of the cups that were literally
handmade that morning and then they they
would smash the cups every time they
finished drinking like a Mazel Tov boom
big giant pile of clay cups pour a
little water on it at night next morning
the guys forming cups out of the clay
again that [ __ ] blew my mind actually
the simplicity and the beautifulness and
the lack of waste in being able to just
recycle your clay cups over and over and
over again was was just too much for my
young men India before it was open to
the outside world when everything was
made in India it was understand place
like I'm afraid to go back to India
because when I was in India at ski type
of cows it's like every single amino
coca-cola no nothing from the outside
world it was like that little bubble of
I'd of tiny place
it was still like that when I went as
well Sam and I were talking about it
just the other day that India really is
the new China that it's that it's very
very different from the way it was I'm
sure that those bubbles can still be
located but they're probably a lot
smaller than they were I'm writing story
about when I was in the eighties in a
mountain in India they were but asked me
to tell the story of my life and it's
odd but I can write it an adventure that
I remember in the mountain or doing
stuff left and like this is much easier
and I've talked with people while they
are now and I see the hope that goes to
Malin Aziz count is chaser when I was in
nine eighties or when Mila was in Milan
I know in the late 60s early 70s that
was like under the world is where you
were in the middle of nowhere it field
of
canidius it like if they were no
connection you were like to us he days
walk from the closer's hood then it
takes a dimension where regimes of
plants where you are the terroir where
you stick it in your honey make it that
value the collecting it's not you making
it it's you getting Zaire doing it you
know what I mean it's like what I'm
trying to explain to the keyboardist
that yeah people kind of appreciated
that I'd made it myself
but the question was when did you make
that Chavez in India when did you go in
my Hawker to make your art show in
Pakistan or in Nepal that the value of
the regime the value of the reason it's
your genetic and your farmer and when
it's in horns the knowledge that is put
and the dedication behind that's the
value of the listen I cannot make
quality if I have not not given the
quality or the picture of my own my ig
that so credit to my father I'm good at
what I do but I received that quality I
don't make it I can and and sit in a
certain way and thought storm it into
ashes and age it and make something
difference
Thunder actually lose the regime that I
collected but I need that quality of
lose regime to get to what I can create
waves you know what I mean like who
might make her like no I agree 100% in
fact what it reminds me of is a quote
that I came up up with a long time ago
which sort of boils down everything you
just said which is we are the unveil
errs of the flame we unveil the flame we
can't unveil it if it's not flame we're
just gonna unveil some other thing but
we are the unveil errs of the flame the
hash makers and that's what we do and I
think it's very liked that you mentioned
that we don't you know in so many words
that it's not really a great idea to get
a big ego about you know
being a hash maker it's great if you're
great at what you do but really you're
receiving something you're unveiling
something it's not like you're making
anything yeah we will Dwain make her
name on the bottle of wine even two
delicious wine maker in Bordeaux didn't
have their name didn't need to have
their name on the bottle everybody knows
they made your wine because it was true
in another time yeah that the name of
the game clay now that is the name of
the game well put great I'm I'm really
looking forward to more conversation
with you today Frenchy we're gonna get
more stories out of you for certain and
we're gonna talk about how she shared a
bit too we are now up to solvent --less
mind who's next up to bat to give us an
idea on you know how he got into JA
herbs how I got into hash the history
the years we want to know all right so
when I was a young kid my dad was in the
cannabis industry he was making
paraphernalia he was making different
products and um I mean just growing up
around him and pretty much I mean he
made like like containers like these
right here that are waterproof and
crushproof or you can like put some
doobies in it throw it in your back
pocket you don't got to worry about it
you know what I mean but um other than
that I just you know when I was 14 15
years old
one of my friends Dan we found a bottle
of alcohol sitting at his house and
there was a bunch of stems in it and you
got a mind I'm from Florida
so we didn't have access to the most
chronic ganja that you can get on earth
so we had to you know use alcohol and
other methods like these extraction
methods to get high you know what I mean
the ganja was just so garbage that you
had to do an alcohol wash on it to get
high so this dude's dad pretty much
taught us the way of doing alcohol
washes and then after alcohol washes
came to BHO that was about 17 18 years
old and I've only been making ice water
extracts since I'm like 26 so about four
years now and um it's life changing man
honestly like back in the day I didn't
really believe it you know I always
thought it was like a gimmick all make
ice water hash don't make that BHO like
you always fridge did man like you
always preach it like I remember back in
the day you always appreciate you didn't
even want to hear about [ __ ] BHO and
we would still talk about be
Joe you know but you didn't like that
[ __ ] you didn't you didn't support it
none of that so you know ventually I got
a battle instead of your bags once I got
your bags dude that was it I got your
bags I got a [ __ ] machine a 20 gallon
bubble now machine and we started
running as much material as we could
find here at humble you know and it
literally changed my life man it made it
so where like I realized you could get a
bomb-ass product without even
endangering your life at all at all you
don't got to worry about a fire you
gotta worry about exploding you're gonna
worry about [ __ ] you just turn the
[ __ ] dial of the Machine and [ __ ]
you're safe you're good to go so
thatthat to me was like life-changing so
I mean I don't know like as far as the
history goes it starts with just trying
to get as high as I could because the
Ganju is garbage moving on so you know
better ganja I grew up back in in
Florida too so I had access to my own
ganja that I could blast with butane but
there was no way when I lived in Florida
that I could ever wash it we just simply
couldn't grow we couldn't produce enough
to make it worth washing but now that
I'm in Humboldt County let's be real
there's [ __ ] ganja everywhere there's
like six thousand gardens around me you
know it's [ __ ] everywhere it's like
water here so you can have access to
anything clean material shitty material
trim nug Drive fresh frozen whatever so
now it's like you know what else is
there to do
damn straight dude I loved all of that
that was I love that your dad was into
making paraphernalia and like and so
when you were growing up were you kind
of like looking up to him or kind of
like whoa looking up to honor percent
man like I'm doing it for him like he's
not here anymore he passed away in 2011
for Parkinson's
he always told me get the county man you
know do something with it so we're
trying nice well mad respect to your old
man for real
inspiring you to get into all of this
[ __ ] go to Cali and I love that Humboldt
is like it's water everywhere I remember
that that was BC in the 90s now sure I
mean I could find it for a lot of places
but there's definitely not 6000 gardens
around me yeah literally is everywhere
up here man but it's nice it's nice that
access you play with a lot of different
present you don't just get one you know
you don't just get one girl
where's perspective of resident you get
greenhouse you get outdoor you get
indoor you get all these different
varieties of resin and you get to work
with them so you get to learn dry resin
grease you resin what's really better
what's really better you know the greasy
[ __ ] that turns into oil in your jar as
soon as you step outside
is it the drier stuff that stays more of
a hash but when you touch it to the nail
it still melts like six star you know
you start to understand like what foods
they're feeding the environments they're
growing in its colder climate better is
hotter climate better are salts better
or are organics better you know you
start to oh yeah prison to kind of get
grasp on it you know you get an overview
that almost no one else has and that's
what another part of my lock was when I
started running Renee back in the in the
late 90s that that suddenly you know my
buddy had a ten liner then he had a 30
lighter then he had a hundred lighter
than he had two hundred lighters and he
was just as nice a resin and as
high-yield as he giving his bud and that
was the beginning of you know then all
of a sudden I just started selling
everyone bags and before I sold the bags
I'd make hash with their material so I
also got to make people's hash with with
so many different growers so many
different genetics every one of them
thinking that they had the best [ __ ] on
the planet but in reality just like you
said they were all growing in in
different enough ways that the resin
itself was completely different and once
you see like six to ten different resins
then you realize whoa this is wait no
wonder the numbers are the way they are
for me the numbers were simple I wanted
people to be inspired to use these bags
to make great hash and the fact of the
matter is most people ran schwag most
people didn't get excited you can hear
around 2012 and 2013 from just the
stories on the panel there seemed to
become a shift into making water hash
again because you know the majority of
people that are involved in cannabis and
this isn't a diss against oil because
you've seen me have BHO makers and
sellers and buyers here on hash Church I
think if it's done at the highest level
you know I certainly don't want to
prohibit it just like you said I don't
necessarily want to personally support
it and do it so I prefer these methods
I've been pushing it on people for so
long but the numbers are that I would
work all these different batches to find
the really great ones and the majority
of people out in the world didn't have
that luxury they just had what they had
and if it didn't hit that water hash
lottery it wasn't gonna be nice yeah
100% man I figure girl to get a lot more
experience working with different
growers materials if you just work with
one growers material I mean you can be
put on the spot one day where you got to
watch someone stuff and you look like a
noob you look like a dumbass cuz you
have no idea what to do with this
material because you've only watched
like fresh frozen right out of the
garden nugs and you've only got this
result you don't know what it is to have
this result like what is it to have 40%
rosin from your house or 60% bras and
instead of 75 80 % on everything you
press and I don't believe whole plant
fresh frozen it's honestly the best way
like I don't believe that's the best way
man like I've done enough washes now to
where you can watch hopefully a fresh
frozen and still not get 6 star and your
yields are suffering like a [ __ ]
so it's like if you really think about
it if you watch the same material let's
say you get the same grower you watched
a 20 pound bag of this [ __ ] fresh frozen
let me watch a 20 pound bag of meat [ __ ]
dry if you can achieve the same melt
from dry material how the [ __ ] is that
not better when you yield almost 1/2
path more let's just say you you look
like half more of what you would have
got had you stopped on the French froze
and watches how is that not better dude
like I don't understand that well this
is because their perspective the
majority of people are coming from a
different perspective they're coming
from the I just want my three and a half
star to look like four star and I want
to sheet that melt effect so I'm gonna
microplane my hash and I'm also going to
run it fresh frozen so I can save any
sort of terpenes that might be lost plus
potentially even get a little moisture
in my hash so when people hold a flame
to it it looks like it's bubbling but
that's not really the right path to take
that's not the passionate you're not
being truthful to yourself
you're you're allowing yourself to be
you know it's crazy how profit margin
always creates deception and how when
you make it about almost like spiritual
I won't say religion but spiritual or
your passion your love that you want to
do better than just make money you know
and and we all know that you can make
money blasting anything and turning it
into distillate and adding fruit turps
and throwing it into sheep pens that are
probably in themselves not very healthy
to inhale through yeah sure I mean like
I've seen finger press hash stuff that
you can put on a paper finger press it
out completely ready for that and as
soon as you touch it to the nail it's
just char all over the [ __ ] place
like it's not six star but like people
they don't understand it just because
you can finger press it and it's greasy
does not make it six star melt qualities
like and taking a note ed dab that's not
justified either you can't take four
star at [ __ ] 250 degrees and go yo
look at the six star because as soon as
I take a real dab of it I'm gonna see
the real char and that's I don't I don't
know man I figures a lot of gimmicks out
there right now well we used to just
call it full melt and when it was not
full mouth it was foment and so that's
yeah the foam mount that's good [ __ ]
right there yeah all right well we're
gonna move over to I just can't wait to
get into an actual conversation with
everyone involved so let's get through
the last three folks on the panel here
we got skunk man Sam howdy howdy howdy
howdy howdy howdy you gonna tell us when
you got into your love of cannabis and
how well you should not when I first
started smoking hashish was actually
quite a while ago it was in 1965 I lived
in Hollywood and I I was able to obtain
some red Lebanese we what we normally
saw there of course was Mexican which
was quite inexpensive that was fifty
dollars a kilo at the time whereas red
Lebanese was like a hundred dollars an
ounce I think it was $80 an ounce and
that was a bit rich for my blood but I
wanted to try
and I did and the first time I tried it
it is I just well Wow
but trying to get it for my in poverty
status it wasn't very easy to to keep it
but then in 1970 I traveled to Morocco
specifically to check out hashish and at
the time in 1970 hashish was maybe $20
to $100 a kilo for the very super-super
in Morocco and depending on the quality
and quality 20 to 100 bucks akela
doesn't seem expensive today it really
started my journey how they made it in
Morocco and within a year I had
continued my travels and over the hippy
hashish trail had made it through Turkey
Afghanistan Pakistan India and Nepal
where hashish was made in like Manali
Kulu Kashmir also up in Kathmandu and
their surrounding areas in Nepal later
in nineteen the mid 1980s we were
growing cannabis here in Amsterdam
and we noticed or I noticed actually
that resin was falling off a little bit
of the really really good buds so dried
buds so I went out and bought a silk
screen and did all the manicuring on top
of it just to see what would happen and
I was able to collect dry set that was
good enough to melt and bubble I
couldn't even believe that the first
time I smoked it in a melting bubbles
but once I had collected resin that was
really really clean like that and I saw
it melting bubble it really changed
what I started smoking because I had
been smoking the herb in massive amounts
and after that I really switched over to
my own resin and it also helped my lungs
quite a bit because I had a tendency
just to spit when I woke up in the
morning and sort of dark discolored [ __ ]
would come out and after I started
smoking resin only that cleared up
really really good the other thing I
wanted to mention
besides how I got into it was why
different kinds of hashish traditional
production is fundamentally different
for example in Afghanistan they make dry
cept as in Lebanon Morocco and Turkey
and several other countries and whereas
in Nepal they make hand rub from more
ganja plants than hashish plants and
what why is it that ganja like Thai weed
and other countries like in Colombia and
other countries is mostly just THC well
whereas Afghan often has significant
amounts of ever to have Knights the
basic reason is that ganja farmers can
smoke each plant or the best looking
plants they grow and save the seeds for
the next year of the best most resinous
plants that have the effects in potency
they prefer and over years and years and
years of the farmers doing this the
plants eventually are really just THC
and the terpenes that they prefer
whereas hashish farmers for imported
rice hashish farmers like in Afghanistan
they don't really smoke individual
plants they never do they smoke resin
made from a whole field of plants and
what they do is they save the seeds from
the plants with the most
but that resin can be THC or it can be a
THC CBD mix or it can even be just CBD
they have no way to judge what the resin
of a single plant is so they save the
seeds from all the plants that have lots
of resin regardless of what that resin
is and over the years of doing this with
the farmers end up with this 25% of the
plants are high in THC 25% of Myr high
in CBD and 50% of them are high in THC
CBD so it makes the dry scent in
Afghanistan quite different from the
Himalayan hand rub ganja plants which
are predominantly THC oh it's funny
though some some smokers actually prefer
Afghan with CBD and I guarantee you if
you smoke Afghan resin you get high as a
kite but it's a bit different and some
of the old traditional smokers used to
say that they preferred Himalayan hand
rub because it was higher and more Airy
and Afghan was more physical and more
stoned even though the Afghan was a bit
cleaner resin the hand rub was a
different cannabinoid makeup so it was
different
also all traditional dry said - was made
from seeded plants not unseated cincy
and seeding plants will reduce the
cannabinoids interpreting percentages in
the case of terpenes by even slightly
more than half so it fundamentally
changes the nature of the resin well I
will say thank you Sam because I enjoyed
all of that thoroughly from the
ridiculous amount of hashish producing
countries that you visited early on in
your hash smoking career right into the
knowledge that he dropped right at the
end
that I'm sure a lot of people haven't
really considered choosing from a field
to grow seed from versus single plants
over many many generations a very cool
topic to to consider maybe we'll get
more into that when we talk about
hashish making here in the near future
after we go through the last two
panelists and we are at Johnny B welcome
Johnny B welcome you guys how is
everybody today
I'm surrounded by hash I got half stuck
to two knees from like Afghan old house
I got big balls a hash I got dry sift
that's some of the first hash we ever
made together in 2012 but it came back
from Amsterdam and I met you but that
means my straight house [ __ ] started
smoking probably in the early 80s and
that was that Lebanese blonde hash that
he picked up the SkyTrain
or you got some box score P and black
cash and with a cold snap on it
sometimes it was like wow and you know
what he's smokin hash for a long time
and what really came down to it and was
everyone's people don't know I think I
fell about injured really bad I started
using different concentrates from my
pain control and I was using a lot of a
lot of ganja for that then in 2012 when
I met you on the plane we were chatting
I came back and I wanted to bring you
some of that cyst that I just made you
show me here to clean it yeah we carted
that we carted that [ __ ] for an hour in
oh my god and you know what we put that
on that screen and that stuff bubbled
like I've never seen before
and it was just like it was a life
changer at the same time what it did for
me you saw how it changed smells like
that one man did everything you know
then I mean I've been growing my own
because of what happened and I've always
been doing my concentrates but I never
made any pho with any of my products
east always me was all about this first
balance which I talked about I would
trim my plants above my screens it hit
the screen that would clean that up and
then when I met you I had different
screens then I started getting different
things and then I started washing my
house differently and you know what it
changed my life it totally changed my
life on how it would be able to affect
me on a daily level for my pain and
stuff like that so I realized how much
that concentrates we're working better
than the flowers
how much cleaner it was than using the
be a chose or anything like that
today it's uh it's a boat like I ran out
to the garage half an hour before church
grab some sip from a trim been through
it on the screens I did the static
little sip that we're talking about with
the DVD cleaned up some beautiful blonde
foam elm hash they do work with you guys
talk about hash because it's just like I
don't know it's been around my life for
thirty years and I've been growing for
since late 80s and I've always had
different ways of being able to have
that try clone and really learning and
seeing the difference over the years and
how it came and being on the panel here
and talking to you guys about what is
where they were talking about here today
is this plant and how we're able to
extract it and get some fun medicine
yeah awesome awesome Johnny be awesome
give thanks
well we'll finish it off well actually
we won't finish it off because I'm
pretty sure soil groans Sal and Cuban
grower are waiting in the ranks for you
know in the next maybe thirty or so
minutes we'll get them in but right now
we've got the dank Duchess who's who
wasn't finding the link but we made it
work
okay don't you see what I lost the link
somewhere it just lost in the ether but
hello good morning everybody my name is
ink that is so the way I got into
hashish was okay oh wait one sec one sec
sorry I think you might need to play
with your mic it's it's am I the only
one that's hearing that the way it's
coming through did other people hear
that as well it's a little choppy for me
yeah choppy exactly so it might just be
the unplug and plug your mic into the
computer sometimes that helps
how's that I don't know hello it's still
a little bit choppy it's not too bad I
can deal with it if everyone else can
deal with it look at that the lat Villa
we get to the last one and it's like
technical difficulties we'll figure it
out is it like working out not working
it seems to have a little bit of a
feedback towards the end of your speech
I'm sure that's not just my cadence
could I think it's your mic take your
mic away from your mouth oh you push
your mouse into the center of the screen
so those icons at the top appear and
then you go to the one that looks like a
Wi-Fi one yeah when you put the mouse
over it'll say a just bandwidth about
medium how's me yeah I don't know if
it's a I think it's this is super
unfortunate I know I'm super bummed
maybe you can restart your computer and
go seriously
well I don't know I don't know any other
troubleshooting other than unplugging a
few times a few times it's happened in
the past people have unplugged their mic
plug it in and it's been better yeah I
got a mute sorry it's so loud and bad I
don't know I guess we're gonna have to I
think it's gonna have to be a unbootable
thing that's what I'm reading about in
the chat or try other headphones it's
really bad without headphones for sure
but Rakesh just go to the next speaker
and come to her next all right well the
next speaker was her she was the last in
the whole group but we could we could
talk about how she
so she gets you know she's welcome to
join in anytime she can just text into
the chat room say hey let's try this
again and we will break up what we're
saying and get right back to her cuz
it's definitely can we talk sorry
can we talk about raising a bit fills in
the difference between the Indu cushions
in the feet of the Himalaya yeah it goes
it's like you know the French we are
talking about the tale of the Lord bring
your lunch to the plot the plot in the
mountain in India it's all green there
is a lot of insect life the plant have
to add a lot of protection the reason is
very sticky with it when you go when you
go into the window coos well it's very
windy days little vegetation and a lot
of dust the reason cannot be sticky
because otherwise it would it would have
a lot of dust on it and I was a function
of it so that the plant not only became
the short brown because it's windy with
big fan live because it's further from
the Sun they need more surface to absorb
the Sun but the reason itself turns and
you can literally make the difference
between large leaf type genetic of a
single type genetic by zone by the
stickiness of it for you here Nichols
degrees and ambit Sam but it's literally
the genetic sewing who's the reason as
much as you can recognize is generated
by the flower you can recognize a
genetic by the vision
awesome yeah I love the conversation I
love where Sam was going with it with
the difference between choosing from a
field Oh turn that down
soil groan what's up guys what's up dude
welcome where someone must have left for
you to get in yeah I guess I just
clicked the button to hop down in I'm in
I'm about ready to make some awesome
control all right well do you think that
just is trying to get her microphone
working I guess in the meantime why
don't you do a little introduction dude
how'd you get into the jaw herbs and
hash and of course so girls in the house
is that for me that is for you okay um
so let's see cannabis I've been uh been
passionate about cannabis since about
high school really got into it with one
of my buddies in football and I'd say
just throughout high school I was really
in search of always finding the best and
that was really it was just finding the
best herbs and then about 2009 I went to
Amsterdam and that's where I really was
stoked about all the hash that was
available so it's really all I got when
I was in Amsterdam just hash hash hash
and I actually brought some home with me
that's how stuff that was about it so
around that time I moved back or I moved
back to California and I didn't really
know much of what to do so I started
growing and start a little clone
business selling clones and stuff and
from there you know I made some
connections got into the cannabis
industry working for dispensaries and
running through different strains and
flowers and hash and what seemed to be
popular at the time was a lot of BHO not
too much water hash or sift so I
actually got into the BHO extraction
unfortunately but I mean it was a path I
needed to take in order to get me to
where I am now we actually had some
problems got a little hurt doing it and
promised my family that I'd never do BHO
extraction again and started studying
like water extraction dry sipped
and really fell in love with the water
hash once I realized that I was able to
produce an incredible product with just
water and ice just that was it for me
and then yeah just from there we set up
a little cold room and hash lab and just
started doing a lot of washing and just
stuck with it you know haven't really
played with too much other things just
mostly water hash and then you know the
rosin tech which came came from water
hash it wasn't for me making water hash
probably would have never stumbled upon
rosin tech so pretty much that says
symbiotic relationship right there dude
yeah did you fire through that fast I
was in peril
I loved it all I loved people's stories
cuz that's how they got where they're
where they are and I agree 100% with you
dude that the way you get to where you
are is by doing exactly what you did not
regretting the things you did it's you
do them to lead you to where you're
headed and you know that's that's Noble
100% put me on the path to where I am
now I can't complain about it you know
well I love that rosin and bubble bubble
bubble hash are intimately linked yeah
I'd agree with that that's very cool
yes no nobody said he invented rosin
dabby
DeVito or maybe they did in the room but
what he actually did was he
re-established and popularized the way
that is used today because rosin
originally was a double boiler with like
a silver or a glass bowl that you milked
your hash with with a spoon and what
what's oil grown came up with was you
know squishing first hash and then
eventually a bud in his parchment paper
and seeing oil come off of it imagine
how lucky you were to get the right
temperature with the right bud at the
right time to see that so that you could
be like wait a minute oh oh I was not
lucky at first actually the the first
way that I press rosin out was with the
piece of hash on an email so actually
put a piece of hash into a piece of
parchment and I pressed it with my
come on to the email and I pulled it off
and that's when I seen a small amount of
oil on the side of the paper and that's
where my idea that I had
it proved to me that it could work so I
did it I did it I did it and I was able
to give my father-in-law the first stab
of rosin within our garage and we were
just in awe flipping out couldn't
believe it happened I don't I say for
about two weeks I was giving friends
dabs and stuff just pressing hash on the
email burning my thumb and that's when
one of my bodies he told me about a
t-shirt press well actually no actually
I had a hair curler so I was using the
hair curler after that and it wasn't
working out too well and the hash would
pop out sometimes it would work and my
wife had come into the garage and she
flipped out because I was using her
expensive hair curler I guess she
brought me some broken up there's like a
rundown hair straightener but that
worked perfect so once I use that to
flat plate to hot flat plates worked way
better than a round hair curler dude
it's always the wife because I'm telling
you bubble bags wouldn't exist if it
weren't for my wife she sold all the
first ones that was like I couldn't find
anyone to sew them they all wanted like
15 or 20 dollars per bag I was like oh
man I gotta figure this out right it was
it was my wife who was like also the
first bags and it was your wife who
brought you the rundown hair
straightener yep yep dude to the wives
to the wives all right I'm gonna try
that Mike again dank Dutchess I don't
know that's not so bad
better okay I think it's what I think
it's good that's her thing cuz I wasn't
good sad and I do the onion cries in any
case the way that I got into weed I was
just say no Nancy Reagan had taught me
so very well I was very very anti
cannabis all the way into into my
twenties and it was a happenstance
beautiful piece of glass that made me
feel like to try the weed and as soon as
I
tried to read and I did calculus I was a
math major in college I did some
calculus and I realized that they live
after that I was just a big pot head and
like Thomas I was in Florida so who
knows what kind of crap you were getting
and my husband would get like some weed
and I got this that we could be better
so he started growing in the closet
maybe in 2004 I think in 2004 we've got
in the closet super kind like for ten
years because I live next door to a cop
and the police station so every single
time the cops would come back to their
station I knew this is the time that
they were going to get me this is the
time I was gonna get arrested today
today today and in fact the day that
before we left for California and the
other guy it's a huge fight and I said
this is the universe saying get the [ __ ]
out of Florida so in 2014 he moved
across the coast to California and on
happened since I met Frenchy I knew
about dabbing but I went to a high times
and Frenchy had all this hash in front
of him and I thought it was chocolate
but I asked it to be dads and he said
with a course and then I dabbed it and
that was awesome a month later I saw him
at another event and I was lamenting
about how I couldn't find like a
[ __ ] budtender job I would come over
there just to do media I'm a writer and
I wanted to do video and all kinds of
things like that and Frenchy at least
have lunch with me I may have coffee
with me and in doing a max he asked me
to write for read well magazine so I got
it to hash because he wanted me to write
for we world magazine but I didn't know
anything about hash and frankly I didn't
even want to learn how to make hash but
I did because the man said absolutely
you know I need still I didn't know he
was any big deal or anything like that
so I learned how to make cash and just
so I could write about it and explain
other people's process and stuff like
that but then I continued later - behind
his back didn't let him know started
posting on Instagram eating it on
Instagram - a couple months later and
you know from then I've just been
accumulating information from various
people and interestingly on this panel
right here I written about you
markets for hash Church I've written
about Frenchy I've written about Thomas
I'm writing about Drew's hash right now
and that's what I specialize in really
bringing light to other people's hash
because I get to smoke a whole lot of
hash
so my experience with class is a little
bit different because I came in late but
I smoked a lot a lot of hash just for
the whole purpose of making stories and
of course I don't make as you see you
see what I was like so that's right and
I'm obviously awesome well that's
wonderful that's very cool everyone has
such unique different stories it's so
awesome I definitely hear a lot around
the 2012 2013 timeline of people getting
reintroduced to water hash it's
definitely taken on another sort of a
full revolution in the sense it's come
full around to where people are getting
inspired to you know what at least one
way dry sifting is another great way I'm
not particular I love both of them at
their highest levels it's just which one
is the most accessible and the easiest
at the time to make is usually the path
that I travel so I guess we've pretty
much linked with everyone I know Cuban
is waiting to get in let's see if maybe
I could drop out if you guys want I
don't want a chance with you you got
some great knowledge on hash and all
that stuff you got going on over there
I'm just you know I'll throw that out
there except he wants to come in and
whatnot he's gonna come in soon I just
sent a message I say we get into a
little bit of a hashish discussion I
definitely like the idea here in the
presence of hashish at least the
presence in North America and I wouldn't
say most of Europe because they still
have a decent import market there we
definitely are on the path of making you
know hash from from plants that are
specifically you know bred over time to
be hash makers to be resin to be
extracted and so that does definitely
make a very very different hash
then if you were to make it from like a
field you know somewhere near the
equator like Sam was talking about the
different profiles you don't cut out all
the other cannabinoids and it is
interesting how you know prohibition and
I guess the love of smoking and the love
of THC really led us down this path that
a lot of these you know genetics have
they don't really exist in the higher
numbers that they did back in the day
not saying that they don't exist at all
not saying that they can't be bred back
into existence if they don't but it
definitely would seem that the
cannabinoid profiles that we're making
hash with these days are mostly in the
high THC realm not necessarily with the
majority of other you know cannabinoid
rich options anyone all right well I'll
just keep topping that thank you
everyone
well I was I wanted to mention one thing
I wanted to go into maybe a little bit
about fresh frozen and kind of the
difference between that and dry run be
everyone's opinion on max I know you
know you know I've had weed in the
freezer for a year and a half it was
fresh and frozen and I've done a lot of
fresh frozen and me and mark we've
talked about it quite a bit
[Music]
certain people Frenchy please for me
series to peak of quality in a region
when you are when you collect it live on
a ground me each of us the first ever
concentrate was on sister touching a
bird for the first time to get some
seeds that way since token on his hand
was the first concentrate ever and it is
a very good shot at that dude exact in
his mouth to experience what it was
because
open sister to invent agriculture went
to 200,000 plants just one that make
seeds and foot comes to these 200,000
there is maybe a thousand Eddie Bauer
hundred that you can domesticate and
I've dozen that fit the world the people
who invented agriculture passed down
generation after generation Oh Holly
over 200,000 plant and empty potential
everyone of zoos not had they had
knowledge of the plant killer that was
pretty amazing that means that that the
first time one of the ancestor touch
that plantain and address in amis and
can go back so far in town it's it's
like he can be as far as two million
years ago when humanity moved from
Africa on the Eurasian continent two
million years ago you had news from
Papua New Guinea to Europe at that time
we may already have discovered and move
around the blood it can be that far the
relation we have with that Conger is no
plant like that that I've been so it is
that I've been neglecting with humanity
so far back in time that we cannot
pinpoint the best place it definitely
goes back very very far in time there's
no doubt about it
I suspect much budget listen how come
it's always the flower but there is
nothing about raising pigs it is a huge
mystery about sucking in history of
humanity because it must have been a
huge part of it somewhere somebody did
you cozy that what was happening in
China where they breathe in that plant
to make out
to make fiber and see that blood was
born bus on user side because when you
bleed for something you know that the
potential of the plant somebody was
bleeding that plant fell way default a
thousand years ago somewhere in the
mountains of the Hindu Kush so
traditionally Malaya but this is a huge
block that we are not know naturally at
all interesting can't keep this plant
down we always maintain some some form
of connection with it like you said what
other plant has companioned humans for
that far back it's a pretty incredible
relationship if you haven't read Michael
Poland's the botany of desire he gets
into it a little bit it's a really great
book for anyone watching that wants to
read a great book from today's lecture
today's talk it's it's one that's worth
checking out
go ahead Sam did you have something you
wanted to say I was just could have
mentioned that cannabis evolution in
ethnobotany by Robert Clark is also a
brilliant tube and hashish by Robert
Clark absolutely we put an invitation
out to rob for today's episode but he
was in a very very different time zone
and it was just gonna be too difficult
for him so we definitely will blow smoke
towards the Vatican for you sir Rob and
those are great books absolutely alright
I think Cuban said he was gonna pop in
in a bit and he can do his introduction
in the meantime we can just get into
talking about still the presence of
hashish where we are with hashish right
now today fine Guruji we do first to
everyone
are we expecting Oh are we seeing
because I have really huge
well we're for sure sieving okay thank
you very much I mean there's no doubt
about that
maybe the extracting part could be
argued depending on the definition of
what you think extracting means or
isolating or whatever you want to call
it but there's definitely it's a two
part we're breaking those heads off and
then we're letting them see and sink
through the sieve from my perspective
anyway it's kind of one of the things
that makes hash hash for me to dig deep
because for me it's the only to
evolution in the game that is thousand
and thousand and thousand years old
doctor the tool of add an evolution but
being a change in methodology of
cannabis resin see be water change
everything it brings a lot on the table
and I don't believe that you lose any
syllable happened because it happened I
found inside that mum rang as long as
the mum line is not broken you cannot
reduce what's inside well you use it's
at that breaking point of the reason and
breaking from from the stock and that's
why this that's what we're doing we're
breaking those heads and that's because
there's no denying that there's terpenes
left in the water after a good wash the
water's anything that is not a penny in
the air of the drying room when you see
it
of course yeah we have never done
default theme i sieve ice water and we
really really need to do that oh I've
done it know what I mean yeah didn't
love oh yeah well I tested it in my bio
acid I did it with no many fine the
different independent he different
between dry Steven iced water to define
the best methodology to retain the most
steps my things again I think depending
on the cultivar you use what I saw
through my own by
which is a pretty fine-tuned machine I
will have you know is that I found a
great deal of closeness when it was a
cultivar like Rene that didn't wash its
terpenes into the water the water had a
mild smell and taste and color but at
the end the hash still stunk like the
herb and that can't that can be said for
some cultivars but it can't be said for
all some cultivars just don't have a lot
of flavor at the end of the of the hash
making process and some hold like almost
all of it and so I always as a water
hash maker looked for cultivars that
would preserve water soluble or water
soluble terpenes to try our alcohol
soluble terpenes to try and find ones
that weren't being washed into the water
and if you know the lab one day says
something differently then i'll change
the way I think but for now it's just
it's the X flavor and taste I can taste
it when I drink the water I can smell it
when I smell the water I know that
they're the terpenes because I recognize
their smell from the plant I absolutely
agree with you Marcus that terpenes do
wash away with some varieties in water
note absolutely no doubt not all no and
if you're not all terpenes not all
varieties but it can happen that's all I
mean yeah so I have a question for you
guys
if commences a stock its peak yourself
Stefan that I think the tiger cub then
the take yourself Stefan is told is that
was it not under the baby of the tyke on
the vaca then then it come inside the
[ __ ] on where do you how can you use
defend that that inside the Chi kana i I
can explain it to you okay you you use
water to sit plants and you've collected
the resin
now a wet resin even though it's covered
with the natural wax cover each of those
little resin heads the resin is now wet
the water got into it and if the water
can get in the terpenes can get out it's
that simple yeah it definitely some of
its hydrophilic and some of its
hydrophobic some of it just seems to
pull water in we've seen it with the
buttering cultivars I'm sure it's the
same with rosin quit so preaching about
becoming to play hmm just seek native of
genomic a and then you write hey welcome
my Cuban grower in the house what's
going on Holmes what up hey sounded like
everybody stopped talking what I got in
no well it was just a natural end of a
conversation that was a good
conversation that Frenchy brought up in
regards to or someone brought up about
fresh frozen yeah man I forgot how good
I looked on camera yeah you're home
you're looking good with that camera
it's like clean and clear I'm gonna I'm
gonna handsome guy but I'm within a
group of handsome people here it looks
like much I hash guys hash women what's
up
thank God cheese this is going soil
grown Frenchy you shinato's in the house
man so yeah we've all kind of done our
little introduction on who we are and
how we got into JA herbs and hash and
whatnot so maybe we'll have you go
through it where you want to start where
I got into the ash game or yeah well you
know start with how you got into herb
and how that led you into hash whether
it was the game or just the love so to
me I mean it was the love I started
smoking weed when I was 11
it's part of our culture in Florida
we're a bunch of big smokers out there
especially what we call the creepy which
is since Amida so from a young age you
know we definitely weed snobs but that
carried on to a fascination and growing
it because I got tired of when I moved
in crappy quality so I started going
from smoking no seeds to smoking seeds
germinating the seeds
figuring out how to select a female and
a male
I do uh two females in a closet and I
went from probably 150 bucks overhead to
selling $300 ounces like a good stack
out for that I was like man this is a
good business got to smoke make money
not bad so when I went back to South
Florida and I brought my little my
little 400 water and stuff like that you
know and I was moving it I felt cool
with that light but what I didn't know
is that my cousin that was helping me
had grow operations all across Dade
County
so he's there like looking at me like
what do you know about this bulb well
like now what do you know about this
bulb is a bro I'll show you what I know
about these bulbs and from dad that
changed my life now my cousin put me
under his wing taught me everything that
started the foundation for me in
commercial growing and we did that for a
couple years but like anything in the
Prohibition era especially a city and
state like Florida doesn't last very
long you know so we started seeing our
partners catching charges losing houses
and money going from going up to
starting to crash during that time I had
got divorced and my cousin was real
strict about it you know he told me that
if I got the worst I had to get out of
the game as I knew it then and I did I
got out got with the Cuban hash queen
and we started our life from there spent
a couple years in Florida I'm not
growing fixing cell phones and stuff
like that it just wasn't happy in my
life I was like man I remember the days
well he used to grow and my wife
encouraged me we sold everything we had
my cars our TVs I mean everything we
took that money it wasn't much how much
how much was it like $8,000
$7,000 they took Whitney when like Cade
and my wife and I feel the Washington
not knowing anybody because I knew that
I had it in me to make it happen and
yeah we went in there fixing phones my
wife was working a job and I was trying
to get trim jobs and there
how to make extracts into I met the
right guy that decided to listen to my
story about what I didn't date and
believed in what I could do and he
invested in me and he really blew me up
I was able to start growing and that
that's all before I even started my
Cuban grower Accountants around that
point so I used to smoke a lot of hash
would spend my weed money on hash but I
wasn't happy with the quality that I was
buying you see when you're spending
thousands of dollars to smoke anything
at home it isn't like what it is on the
youtubes and stuff you kind of you kind
of I don't know get motivated and make
your own so I bought myself a full Amana
washer set a bubbleman bags and my first
wash was better than anything I had
bought and smoked that year I was
convinced you were one of the lucky ones
dude you were you weren't you were the
ones that I wished everyone was the
people that already had dank but just
needed to unveil it in a way that they'd
never seen
yeah well that [ __ ] my life up raw be
honest because I had like seven
different strings six of them didn't
know bro I thought I was the worst hash
maker ever I'm like why is my house
coming up around why is it half mil I
almost want to quit I'm like man this
isn't for me
but when I will go back to that one
string which was my haze it would treat
me right and dump it would melt and I
started figuring out okay maybe I'm not
growing the right cultivars
so I started switching stuff up if he
didn't melt it was gone still the whole
room of haze until stuff started to fill
its place and now it made me realize
that the material really is what
dictates the final product absolutely
dude we have all been giving mad
blessings to the prod the producers and
the product whether it be us that are
growing in ourselves or whether it be
someone that we've you know connected
with through our extra-special olfactory
in regards to cannabis and cannabis
terpenes yeah yeah hold on trying to
like position the chat and the live chat
same time so I don't miss them that's
what I got going on right now the
viewers there yeah you have two monitors
but now I just have one gaming one it's
got a heart there we go much better yeah
I have a long one but it's just a single
one but it's long enough I can make the
boxes small and still get mine yeah so
dry 16 I got into it it was a it was
crazy so I was washing first right and
it was the summer in Washington but we
had a farm right he had a property on
the parcel where we grew and then we had
our residence in Washington most houses
don't have air conditioning so in the
summer there's like two weeks that are
hot as balls right and my tremors
they didn't want to sweat one and two I
didn't want my weekend trimmed in 100
degree weather any loss under hassle I
converted my washroom into a true moon
so I couldn't make hash and I was kind
of running out but I had so much Keith
and I decided to see what I could do
with it because I got motivated by Sam
the skunk man and I got motivated by you
and pictures so I was like no no I want
to see if I can make this stuff and yeah
ended up learning and it's I was happy I
didn't have a washer it has so much
Keith so much material to make it to
sift
so much in fact that I was selling jars
for $35 a gram to my friends because
they liked it but then I was getting
hustled at the time but uh they were
definitely happy to gets it from me for
sure we're gonna be talking about hash
making here I guess now that we've gone
through the entire panel everyone's
excited I suppose I did invite a TM but
he was super busy with the whole new rec
laws that have passed in Cali so his
dispensary I guess it was Chris Conrad
and his wife Mickey who who were the
first customers of BPG the other day for
Rex oh we won't be talking about that
too much today because we're gonna be
talking about hash making so you know
what you lose that when you got when you
started what's
year was that summer off Cuban so the
first time the
first year I started making Dreyse it
was the first year that I won an award
which was what 2014 said yes I started
dry sifting around March or April of
2014 and I entered my first Cup in
September with that haze dry suit
yeah the haze was just powerful dude
it's my son's middle name hey it's a
cool one so I had two strings at the
time I had an OG that's that melted so
good so this is I'm always conflicted if
I make the right decision but you know
what I got a third so I'm happy with it
but I had an OG those super white chirpy
melty was really multi-force it's
awesome and then a hat but the thing is
that you can smoke that [ __ ] all day and
not you know if you wouldn't get tired
and you wouldn't get too high Oh what
would happened with the haze is like
have you ever looked out the window
looking for the cops and stuff after
smoking or like been like hammered on
the couch just thinking and daydreaming
[ __ ] that's what happens to me so I was
like man I want to get these judges
I want they're hard to feel like it's
about to rip out of your chest when they
take a bath with this stuff
because they're gonna be smoking so much
and we've got your boy in there third
place yeah the haze is no joke I'm
surprised that if they had any like real
like posh aficionado missing them they
would be like holy [ __ ]
this is the first place right here
because I love the racing heart I love
the intense like I've definitely as you
said as you told that story I pictured
my friend Myles flushing all his [ __ ]
down the toilet because cops pulled
someone over in a Safeway parking lot
across the street from where he lived
after puffing the haze he was just um
don't finish it down the toilet
Hawkins Street Portland for those that
no no that's wild yo so at first I
wasn't getting third because it just
looked like some regular hash you know I
was the only dry six entry out of like
30 entries and there was a recreational
one and a medical one but nobody knew
what it was it just thought it was like
some hash but it took the connoisseur to
be like guys I don't think this is water
- this might be dry see
so they started considering it as dry
safe than a
and the raita double points just cool I
notice there's a big appreciation for
dry sift you even though I had not been
introduced into the US market in a
competitive sense like that they were
excited to see it yeah for sure
it had definitely been in winning the
legends of hash every year since like
wouldn't you say Sam I think one year
water hash one bye-bye
what was it it was the clone from it was
one of my old clones but it was grown
like this gummy stack yeah no it was a
skunk Hindukush
yes the skunk Hindu Kush yeah every
other year was dry sift that took first
place for rice it is the gold standard
for most varieties of plants or clones
you can make the very best water hash
from it and the best dry sip but also
it's hard for most people to make dry
cept that as pure as clean as they can
water - yeah it's harder for most people
for sure well all I know is Sam's been
puffin on it for maybe 30 years which is
insane yeah I made my first dry sip
maybe in 86 and that year or the next
year I figured out how to make it 99.9%
resin heads and that's what really
changed it because once you've had resin
melt and bubble in front of you the
first time it's just like that's hashish
I'll never forget it ever it's it's a
hard to forget experience especially
even in this day and age still to this
day because you know most people they
have to figure out a way for it to be
either to make sense for their brand
to profit for their company like
either-or it's hard to do and just the
loss you know you have it's it's not
hard to understand why this is because
if you test most hashish in the coffee
shops it's it's got less THC then good
bud can 20% it's got less than that
which means most of it is something else
whereas you can make it 99.9% pure resin
heads and then it's in the low 80s of
THC and it's chirping rich naturally
yeah no I agree 100% I remember the
first time I bought dry sipped from the
gray area and I cleaned it up and it was
like 13% heads what can I say I don't
know man you live in Amsterdam what the
hell this is on you
yeah but I don't ever go to coffee shops
no it's true I can honestly say I don't
think I've ever been in a coffee shop
with you yes I just want to say that it
may have been 13% heads but right here
Kuban I don't love you too remember when
he gave this to me back in 2015 this is
Miami haters I think this is like the
first day that I met you better have a
rip of that right now
oh yeah that's tight I saw blue ice had
sent me a picture tag we can I saw on
that only I think one little medal on it
huh yeah this is a third-place 2014
Seattle HC high chronic scary stuff so
yeah I've been saving it all this time I
save a lot of highs Siri to smoke with
us girl or ticket down okay I think that
what I like about sick is that
so some drugs it's hard to see the
quality of it visually right there's a
lot of mystery stuff like weed is one
that you can really tell it's good or
not
visually and you smile in his ways to
tell his quality
I feel like sift is one of those two by
the way shines by the sudden refraction
of the size of the heads the smell I
mean there's a lot of ways but in answer
them they're not even really down with
dry see if they're done with that
pollinator spinning it for like 24 hours
before they take the material out hi
farmer grain sift I throw that type of
stuff away farmer great it's step one
yeah there's nothing wrong with it you
got to remember Cuban that when I make
what I want resin and I end up with 99.9
I start with whole dried plants that are
completely completely unmanned occurred
and I grind them up with a machine to
get the resin free word iives in my
experience I realized that I can get the
majority of the trichome heads off of
the strings that I'm working with
typically by hand is best over the
screens but I can break down a pound
within like 15 minutes and and from a
pound if it's a good strain you know we
could pull like 60 grams of sift out of
it majority of them are like 30 to 40
but I've noticed that over agitation it
takes me longer to finish my work I got
more and more green and things that I
have to work out what I've seen is that
when I measure the THC level before I
start with the plants the plants are
about 15 percent THC after I'm done
working with them at least five or so
percent of the THC is still left in the
ground up material so no matter what I
do I can't get it all but once I I do
grind it up and I do get I can get about
from a kilo I can get it by the hundred
grams farmers ash but then I can clean
that up to ninety-nine point nine pair
Lisl II yeah and you're also you're
making like four or five thousand grams
of farmers great sift in a shot that's
correct it takes me like you've seen it
what maybe a half an hour to make a kilo
oh all I saw was about seven to eight
minutes to cover the floor maybe maybe
it was seven or eight minutes tequila or
four thousand plus grams in a shot and I
was like well you just have to train
your resin to when you whistle that it
immediately falls off and rolls up in
little ball at your beat yeah well all I
know is that was one of my most prideful
moments of getting to play around with
you and resin at that point in time in
my life and to just just to be there
with the rake and being a part of it was
awesome yes over a thousand viewers
right now look at that that's that had
not happened for a long time at the end
of hashtag 1.0 I will say that we almost
drove that train right off the tracks
but it was good to take a little break
and you will be seeing all of the rest
of the panelists that you've come to
love over the years I just want to do
specific shows where I invite specific
people who are really knowledgeable in
the in the one topic that we're gonna be
talking about which today is hashish
I still think we're in the presence of
hashish it seems like a lot of
conversation really I mean there's
there's water hash and there's dry sift
but really as friend she said there's
sieving and they're both sieving
regardless of whether you use water to
aid you in your isolating procedure
which it really does quite a job in a
quick way it's that there's something to
be said for that if there was a way to
do that with sifting that fast and easy
like water hash does to get that much of
a percentage back a yield
I'm sure that it would it would exist
right now
it's it sure would would be nice
another question for you guys lightness
we all under melt the melt is how much
resin is formed inside the reason and
when you are burst if you libel is in or
killed resin it doesn't change the
quality of the melt yes much fun in the
resin I did say what you lose when you
cure you lose their pain but you
transformed them into something
different to at the same time so you
have used to pick but have you ever
experienced clones that have been
invested too early you have a lot of
resin there is a motive Canobie know it
inside but there is no way there is no
reason from inside and the further you
go from the kick the least reason that
is inside that resin and even if the
flowers show like 2026 and tha have you
ever experienced that
do you mean like a really like a really
low yield from a flower a talking about
yield I'm talking about the yield that
has no weight compared to because it's
been arrested normally compared to the
blonde that is arrested at the peak of
the time when releasing is suitably when
the resin head is full of regime there
is a wage to be so friendly do you mean
that the resin is a different size or
just like how heavy it feels when you
take the the hash out of the freeze
dryer when it's early you can feel that
like the resin looks pretty but it
doesn't have actual substantive weight
it's not about the size of the head it's
about the fact that like the resin
hasn't been fully formed within men
that's inside so I have experience with
that first time because I've been
cropping at different periods in washing
my
tire harvest 80-plus lights you know -
I've done it a day 77 I've done it at a
70 I've washed stuff before at day 45
and then let the entire crop go to day
63 and actually saw a degradation of
quality as opposed to wait I saw better
yields on there earlier pulled on my
strings bigger one 20s and 90s
melty or 70s less residue on on the nail
and cleaner separations almost tartar
turps and just still a strong high
weight-wise I mean you never know CBG
tight I'm not exactly sure if it has CBG
but it definitely has a nicer opacity to
the to the resin head when it's washed I
feel like for washing it's almost as if
the resin hits a peak maturity before
the flower does that the heads are all a
big size they have a thinner cuticle
around and a higher content of oil and
then I still the plant reaches its its
term for flower a lot of those heads
down once big they become they fall down
to the 70 micron they become a writer
shade less melt but that for now for
washing I've been pulling a day 45 to 50
because I just see way better ease also
II and I came from growing 1314 we cases
so it's hard for me to even make that
adjustment by see a superior product and
with dry city I've always seen
I like the plants to be pretty much
maximum mature and that gives me what I
consider the most resin and then I make
it as clean as I can yeah the first time
I photographed your resin it was very
red you can see the color of Sam's resin
versus the color of Cubans just these
are two different batches they've
obviously made more hash than just that
but this was very red and what I was
most surprised that when I first smoked
Sam's hash and I've smoked both of them
they're awesome melts liquefied
beautiful flavor everything
samms hash the first time I smoked it it
was like what Cuban said like I almost
had an anxiety attack it was so intense
like I just couldn't believe how high I
got and how fast I got that high and I'd
never experienced that in my life before
that [ __ ] was like an anxiety attack and
then it was like another anxiety attack
and then ten more anxiety attacks which
was great once you're stacking anxiety
attacks and you love being on the brink
of highness then you're right where you
want to be you know I'm honored to have
a picture of my house on your wall bro
that's cool dude your hash is one of the
most beautiful pictures I ever took are
you kidding me it is it is your hush
well that's my wife sis did that that
was actually the Kimbell and it was at
the Kimball that you took a photograph
of I was from Jamaica yeah I believe
that was Kim oh there was two two
batches yeah sometimes I take credit but
you know what the real sift master here
and our family is my wife for sure it's
always the wife dude both soil grown and
myself have already propped out our
wives today so you may as well as well
it's it's always the lives I can
honestly say my wife will doesn't make
cash for me and I wish she did but she
doesn't she tried it one time she was
okay at it but she said I know what I
like and I can do it
nice that's okay my wife doesn't make
cash for me there although she has in
the past as has my mother which is
always great to get your mom whipping up
a batch of that full mount
I enjoyed it that's for sure where we're
putting in an entry into spannabis some
dry sifted water - nice I think you'll
be pleasantly surprised because every
time we went to Spain last year remember
that dry sip that la colada or two years
ago Sam oh no Spain has made enormous
strides towards a resin and not just and
not just bubble but like I usually see
half a dozen to a dozen full melt dry
sips while I'm in Spain which is
surprising and and like 30 to 40 plus
water hash like
Oh God you got to remember Europe comes
from hashish tradition not a ganja
tradition I know the west coast it's
it's a ganja tradition spannabis isn't
old like it's been happening a long time
I think I first went in like 2003 or
four and and now it's like it'll even
Sola said it to me he said in 2012 was
the first time I started seeing hash
he stopped bringing his own in 2013 that
was the first year he was like I don't
have to bring my own resin to Barcelona
because there is great resin in
Barcelona I can name off like at least
half a dozen dudes that just make fire
every time like it's beautiful outdoor
Catalonian sun-grown you know reddish
dark resin that still has a really nice
like awake sort of energy to it not that
narcotic thing that you might think that
red or orange resin means when thinking
about from a North American perspective
that's another game oh sorry excuse me
okay what I was gonna say was how you
can really see the progression of hash
making is at Legends I mean the first
year what we really did was we smoked my
dry set yeah you know different kinds
but that's pretty much what we smoked
within a few years of having legends we
had twelve of them in a row in
Afghanistan in in Amsterdam timed with
the High Times Cannabis Cup but not
connected to it and what we found was
after a few years we started having to
get together and everybody started
bringing their best and then we
eventually made an informal contest out
of it where every year the resin got
better
I mean entries just got better and
better and better till finally but last
year we had it there was 27 entries and
we could barely even finish them all I
mean it was just like a it was an
unbelievable
job but I decided we needed three days
if we're ever gonna do this again well
then we better plan it soon for
Barcelona 2018 in March for spannabis
because we need to do another Legends we
need a three-day screening period before
the night's announcement of the judging
right don't you think so
so then we need a legends house that
everyone can come to it whenever they
need not an apartment but a house I
think it's a great idea I'm down I'm
announcing it right now we're gonna do
the legends of hash in Barcelona this
was the legends of hash in Barcelona in
2016 and we're gonna do it again we got
to do it I can honestly say that the
entries at the legends of hash in
Barcelona were consistently as good or
better than the legends in Amsterdam
yeah I would agree as well it got really
good so I think that that's a great idea
just you know for me it's not about that
I mean it from the hash maker's
perspective like Chinquapin and the
other guys Matt the great gardener and
all these guys that love to enter these
things it's awesome to have a legends
under your belt for me I just want to be
there with all the people and
potentially even like figure out a way
to get Sid down there with the hubbly
bubbly because Legends is it's hard to
be legends without the hundred year olds
hubbly bubbly Afghani pipe that we just
crush you know grams and grams and grams
of full health dry sift out of when Sam
said the first year we were smoking his
dry sift what he didn't say was he was
dumping it in one and two grams at a
time onto a huge bowl of Afghani hash
that was our screen this big giant
hundred-year-old Afghani Bowl that he
was putting two grams at a time I'm
telling you you could take a rip out of
this thing and then your lungs would
seize right up like you'd be like I
would put in a two gram hit dry set and
then somebody would take it on the
then I put in another two grams and
somebody else would take duh it was
insane in the flames I mean a high flame
can jump a meter tall yeah for doing it
in our friends restaurant then it had a
low ceiling
it's kind of funny
props to uh Simone we're hooking it up
salt I'm hot about the dry suit the the
distinct difference I guess in between
dry suit and water harshness this to be
any abrasive and the fact that even
though it could be taken long it still
has a really nice light look because of
the way that the light reflects off of a
resonator when it reaches is when you
start seeing the darker colors and I
know friend she doesn't like that word
grease collar moment so when it greases
it will show the essential oil layer
there'll be darker
amber etc with in the California senior
exigency in the North American have seen
it has been erased to the lightest
colors so Waterhouse has been not with
freeze dryers not only been able to
achieve the look of dry sift when it's
called Curie but when you have a resin
that was 45 days it's essential oil is
light yellow almost you know colorless
color it's more attractive grant program
which is why I've also been going
towards your polls on the material
because it's what the people want
yeah I definitely see people wanting a
lighter color nowadays which is for me I
just want great hash if it's great
lighter hash then great if it's great
darker house then great but I really
don't have a big preference as you can
even see from the past that's behind me
the majority of it has like nice amber
color to it knowledge lovely I need to
say this you know I also have working in
a cold environment we are always
stressing to keep it as light as
possible because like you said that is
what the that's what a lot of the
customers wants what I
is important to stress though because we
have a lot of things going through the
realtor with regard to us and that's
just really not true that darker hashed
if you choose to pull lighter I mean
later if you choose to press I'm there
for this not even that even if you just
choose to pay later
this is an idea that somehow the hash is
not as good so there's this prejudice
toward lighter hash and I like all types
of I have very light - I've had darker
hash but this is prejudice and you know
information spreads really quickly so
can you put something about you know say
something toward that well I agree I
hear that you know I see it all the time
that people just get lost people almost
always want to be told what they like
and thus thus grows the hype train and
so the hype train sometimes has accurate
things on it and sometimes it has
inaccurate things on it for me I have
smoked incredible light colored resin
I've smoked just as incredible dark
colored resin so I personally and I'm
not trying to produce you know if if I'm
in a business and my marketplace is that
we want darker or we want lighter the
market that always speaks to what they
want and then the people produce what
they want it was kind of it's always
been like that what people want is what
people will produce because it just
makes sense the hustle is already hard
enough to have to hinder yourself by
being like [ __ ] what they want I'll just
I'll tell them what they want which is
sometimes not really as efficient as
just producing you know if you're in a
business for a market that wants a
particular thing so I see both sides
really especially now in the
recreational market where your product
is gonna be on a shelf and you can't
necessarily try to market it and sell it
it's gonna be a lot of people walking in
and seeing something visually and at
least in California but the lighted
resin is what they pull towards so when
I consult with guardians that I'll be
working with you know I'm gonna try to
pull towards that 45 15 now do I have
appreciation for dark resin of course
that's what I started making for the
first like four years in my house
like I said I've just been experimenting
with different pools and I wouldn't sift
anything that has been floured to full
maturity that's for sure but water hatch
is just it's easier to make a different
product unless you do things that are
impossible to be as diverse as a plant I
have seen blown that offer
miracle is in at three weeks well he
liberated and never did amber so it's
like you cannot judge 3d lightness of
the his in AD by the color but you since
Liz in Eddie's made like a foot there is
it fun at maturity series you can the
it's made like a food to fall at
maturity when so high first of the
Hyper's just fall by itself like Sam was
saying when you collect Mike just for
exclusive the drying and then the after
you shake the lube oils and maturity of
the raising the lower lightness the high
post which would fall as soon as you
shake a little bit and then you shake a
little bit stronger you have that's the
single available on and so on because of
the weights kuchela teammates literati
this is how Reinhardt's original machine
was designed the triple extract
extractor ice-cold extractor he came up
with this thing I think in 98 he showed
up at the cop and first or maybe 97 sore
it was 97 he showed up at the Cannabis
Cup and made a little deal with Miele
about the ice-cold extractor and this
was a machine that really was like a
brewer a 5-gallon brewer with the
triangular base and it came with a glass
collector and so his design was really
to sin
terrifically spin with a linear actuator
and get the resin only the most mature
resins to fall and then collect them in
a single screen rather than to separate
them out like isolator bags and bags
meet I've seen action action even ideas
here in candy yeah but we know today at
ice-water see the noise factor and it's
it's pretty amazing to see the that
ancestor of it yeah how do I do it is
truly the ancestor of it as well because
it was it was a friend of ours Eldon who
was sitting on Milla's couch when she
when he saw that machine he came up with
the isolator bags right then and there
he said two five-gallon buckets with a
fight with a five gallon screen bag with
this screen bottom you've got the same
concept and he literally and he was
marty was next to mark rose my current
manufacturer and Mark Rose came up with
the name and so between Eldon and Mark
and Miele the isolator company was born
and it was only a few months later that
I would start bubble bags based on the
isolator bags that I had seen so it was
definitely the true ancestor they sue
deeper than that mess that machine
didn't push the new legend receiving to
these steps well the use of you sieving
and could simple hey joko system
agitation and sieving in a bag and
that's the beauty of it we that depth
elite yeah and the travel ease of it
like to throw those in your backpack or
your pocket for that matter and just
like heading off into the mountains to
go make some hash it's nice and portable
oh yeah
so what else should we be talking about
here the future while the future of hash
I wanted to hear what everyone thinks
will be the heat future of hash but we
can wait a little bit for that I'd say
we got a good 40 more minutes to still
talk about you know what you're learning
from doing the the methods that you're
doing whether its water hash or dry
sifting you know if you've got little
tips that you've learned along
the way or little things that you feel
are important I definitely have half a
few I share them all the time try to
anyway one big one for water hash is
that when you're seething water hash
it's gonna be it's the the the talent in
that moment is knowing how much moisture
to leave in the small pock before going
right to a sieve if you don't want to be
forced into itself pressing itself and
having to micro plane which rips open
the heads and for some of us we don't
like that I'm not judging those that
like it by all means do it it's one more
option that you can do and that's the
beauty of cannabis I like to sieve and
so learning how much water to leave
present and and what I mean by that is
low quality bubble anything under four
star you can almost like squeeze water
out of that thing and it you'll still
see beautifully but for high-grade resin
you can't touch the paddy it can only
really be whipped from the bottom and if
you wick too much water out of a really
high-grade resin and you're in an
environment that say not very cold but
much warmer than it should be
maybe over seventy degrees Fahrenheit or
80 yeah 70 degrees Fahrenheit the resin
can start self pressing and then it just
won't seem nicely it won't break up like
sand and fall nice and evenly on
whatever surface you choose to drop it
on so that's that's kind of a little tip
that I would share if anyone else has
one they want to share by all means
step up yeah that that's funny because
sieving sieving of patty's is almost
like a art yes a and every resin is
different some resin is a dream
you can see a thousand grams after
wicking that paddy and it will be like a
15 minute 20 minute process other resin
well the dryer gets it becomes like
almost harder where you really have to
work the spoon and sometimes with the
the greasiest tur piest
of resin if you don't have the coldest
area to wake on and you're forced to
take out the microplane and I don't like
using the microplane very much but
sometimes it it has to happen
thank Duchess wanted for me to talk
about drying yeah she asked me if I
freeze dry so I don't freeze dry I use a
a I oven with cold trap in line and a
vacuum pump and a room that is cold so
these guys aren't even plugged in I wake
my patties on the drying pads with a lot
of paper towels and I use a Munda is
about 40 degrees my cold surface is
above freezing so my patties don't get
frozen if they freeze it's almost as bad
as then greasing so you have to always
keep them just cold and stable so you
can hate them with the strainer
I'll make layers on these AI oven trees
with paper towel and parchment and I'll
sieve the hash onto there and it doesn't
have to be thin you can see it pretty
thick and I'll pull the back now what
happens is at a cold temperature about
45 degrees the moisture escapes the hash
as a vapor or gas and it'll run through
the cold trap a cold trap is a device
that has it's like a bucket on a bucket
type of thing the inside one has a dry
ice and and alcohol slurry and when this
water hits that cold trap it'll freeze
the ice of the water house over and it
won't hit the pump so I can visually see
as the hash is drying you when it's done
drying and I also discovered that it
seems like I'm capturing these water
soluble terpenes that maybe would escape
when hash gets AirDroid I don't know cuz
I have never aired right hatch but my
heart still comes off soon paternity but
it gives me an indicator of when it's
dry now it doesn't come out like rice if
like the freeze dried a
so whatever sublimation is going on
between freezing it and the way I'm
doing it is different it ends up looking
a lot like an air dry but perfectly dry
so one day I sat down with nicotine he
had told me that he was micro clean and
this is like one of the guys that
inspired me to see my hash and asked him
why and he told me that some of the
stuff they
Colorado was so greasy that it would
take him like two weeks to dry on a rack
and he had to break it down even easier
when I told him that uh he's seen my
house before that I was drying my seat
Bosch in eighteen hours about 300 grams
of ninety micron he was pretty surprised
so I stuck with that method it's not an
easy method to teach it really takes
some knowledge of like you were speaking
waking and all that's like an advanced
drying method it's a lot easier too now
that we're going into the recreational
cannabis and this is what I've been
dealing with for the last couple months
is scaling my hashish production right
so I've chosen that I'm gonna try to
focus my scaling on water hash and I'm
trying to train people and some of these
people don't even have much knowledge to
do so some of the people I'm training
don't have a lot of knowledge on hash
and it's hard to explain to them what
the process is when things are waking
and etc so I'm gonna make a transition
over to freeze dryers and I haven't yet
but I think it's an easier method to
teach how to dry hash to a technician
than the way I'm doing I don't know what
are your guys thoughts on scanning
hashish production I think it'll be
easier for you yes to teach but I think
that you will like for me I always the
freeze-dried hash just seems almost like
an artifact of its former self like it's
it's so dry it's so like almost fluffy
instead of dense and and I've seen good
freeze-dried hash another thing I just
prefer I prefer the look and the and the
the feel and the smoke of a naturally
you know the way I've always old-school
cured I still will do both under my
brand because people they you know I
understand that people like more than
what just I like but what my preferences
are is non freeze-dried and I suspect
that with the vac of and you're probably
able to produce a dry hash without
affecting it the same way that the
freezer
seems to do with that extreme cold so
buddy of mine that I thought I brought
him from Florida he goes online as LD
Aggie I taught him how to make hash when
we made hash together for a couple years
so he marries my technique and he was
curious about the freeze dryer and he's
stopped using it because he thinks that
the process is inefficient in the sense
that it will freeze a patty and then
thought I'll it takes about 24 hours or
more to - to drive versus the the vacuum
oven being almost like an accelerated
air drag and I can control the the
moisture but I try to get it as dry as
possible but I like the look of the of
like a fish egg looking sieve when you
have that resin that especially when the
resin has a nice translucency I think
that's beautiful and it's hard to
achieve something like that with a
freeze dryer
I think freeze drivers make hash that
look like like Fugazi dresses and then
when it grease is over it all doesn't
know how to grease over and it looks
like a weird brown compared to a sieve
grab or even a microplane grab looks
pretty nice too compared to the way a
freeze dryer vents yeah well keep a
letter to say something so you know I
can't fake more than something like
grease up because I'll press my house so
and I use the freeze dryer and yeah I
know what you're talking about that
fluffy look and that fluffy look is not
great but its conception here we do not
at all go from cells into trying to foil
it out in fact that's what makes that
fluffy look because that's a mistake
what you're trying to do is sublimation
we're going from it being totally frozen
and staying under a particular pressure
which is four point five eight four to
go into the completely in today position
if you make it into that liquid phase
then your hash is [ __ ] just flat out
it's fun it has to say from frozen the
entire way so one of the things I talk
to other hash makers about is putting it
in the deep freezer overnight that's
that way you know
and what that is frozen frozen frozen
all the way through but if at any point
you get to the liquid phase that whole
freeze drying process is completely
though not good freeze-dried hash
because like I said I have an entire
counter and once come to my house knows
that I have a counter of a huge counter
patch I just leave everything out I have
things in the refrigerator and things on
the counter basically to see how things
are going to react and freeze-dried hash
just washes wet in general no matter how
good it looks
you will know that it is not all the way
dry it probably had a mistake in the
process which people have not dialed
that in quite as well oh it is super
better oh gosh that's what happens when
you get that fluffy it almost looks like
um almost it's a shade snow and it feels
very ungentlemanly
because when you freeze dry it is still
supposed to make that same spring clean
oiz not with the greasiest stuff but you
know drop value dry hash air drive it
couple years ago when they made that
clinking noise over the parchment your
freeze-dried hash is supposed to make
that same type of noise and have that
same type of fear if any way it feels
kind of moist like you're pushing a
little bit into play your hash is not
dry no matter how nice the exam believe
me it's not dry hey welcome at ya and
that was well said Duchess I also feel
that you know there the freeze dryer is
easy in a sense to teach people basics
but if you want to get like what you've
got with your vac oven that you're doing
like more tuned in then it just becomes
more like just once again it's know how
it's simple know-how that is not easily
transferred to people that you're
teaching things to they're like oh yeah
I know how to do it it's like do you
know how to do it because if you do it a
lip I think the freeze dryer I think
we'll see new tools specifically
designed for the freeze dryer in 2018
and those tools will make exactly what
Duchess was just mentioning a lot easier
to happen than having you know this wet
sopping resin sitting in a
in a metal pan like there's what's going
on that Chan hey everybody um happy hash
Church 2.0 I'm on I'm at work it's a new
legal world here in California so I'm
sitting here stickering and packaging
trying to keep up with the fun demand of
all the things that are out there so I
didn't have a chance to pop on earlier
so I just wanted to pop in and wish
everybody the best and I'll try to be
back more regular next week it's just
kind of crazy here right now everybody
realizes what all these patients have
been saying for these 18 plus years at
my dispensary and now they all want to
come in and have the experience and
we're welcoming it and we have everybody
ready for it it's just a lot of people I
can only imagine well hopefully those
people are purchasing hashish today
because that's what today's episodes
about hash hash and more hash in fact
that kind of leads us into the future of
hash right then and there you know you
you're kind of in the future of hash
right now as well as the future of
recreational cannabis sales yeah it's
it's fascinating it's it's been
interesting to watch California learn
from Colorado and Washington and Oregon
and Alaska's experiments and figure out
what works best for us here in
California and fortunately you know
people are still grow so you know it's
making sure that we have plants
available making sure there's seat and
of course rights it's what I'm doing
right now is I'm actually snickering
hashish because it's very popular right
now and it's one of those things that's
needed on the floor so I've yesterday I
packaged bubble hash and cartridges are
also popular people are very interested
in all the new things that are out there
so they're not there they're not aware
of bubble hash they're not aware of just
what hashish is even for the most part
they've heard rumor of it they've not
necessarily seen it so then you come in
and here's 40 types of hash before you
it a a learning curve so it's you know
to explain the different types because
you know we have carry the co2 we carry
the BHO and we care of course lots of
different types of bubble
and names of variety and of course we've
had the Duchess's wonderful products in
here in the past and thank you very much
you dank touches you and of course
Frenchy and others have definitely come
through would love to someday see your
stuff down here Cuban but I know you're
a busy busy man so it's just the reality
of you know now trying to figure out
what the demand is make people aware of
the different types of hash so it's
literally it's starting at the beginning
of course starting from you know all the
way back thanks to Sam and everybody
else who perfected the flours and help
made those available and of course
thanks to you bubble man for a bubble
hash as I was sitting there I was
giggling all days I was packaging
yesterday going hehehe Thank You bubble
man for making this product even
possible so that people have it know it
know that it's out there and it's
available because you know before then
you know it was a few and far between to
find good hashish as you know back in
the day was finding something that was
black or stamped not many of us had
French cheese knowledge or experience of
going around rubbing etc etc so the
majority of us found out you know when
we go to Amsterdam right yeah you go to
Amsterdam for hash you don't go there
for grass you come to California for
grass but you go to Amsterdam definitely
for the plethora those dog nee of the
day you can get a full trip around the
world an Amsterdam from Nepalese temple
balls to double zero to all the
different types of issues that are out
there that you can find in conglomerated
areas that you would never thought were
even possible or have only read about or
heard legend of there you could actually
go into all these coffee shops and you
know find it and smoke it and so we took
a lot of that idea and over the years of
you know perpetuated that here in
California with our medical industry
which of course needless to say is 20
plus years now and now that we're at
this new recreational world we
fortunately have the Bureau of cannabis
control which is allowing for BHO and
Pho and other types of extractions and
water hash which is key for the consumer
so that they can experience as many
different variety
of preparations of cannabis as possible
that we what we have currently and I
thank everybody on the panel of and for
many years of their hard work and
dedication to make that a reality for
this this new public that's now touching
base yeah I also in your thanks of me I
always have to give thanks to the people
that helped and inspired me along the
way which would be skunk man Sam
initially with Saudi Sam's water
extraction and if it don't bubble it
ain't worth the trouble and really the
inspiration behind wanting to isolate
gland heads to 99.9% and then a thanks
to Reinhardt Delp who came up with the
Machine years later like literally ten
years later from Sam doing the Saudi
Sam's water extraction
ten years later Reinhardt would come up
with the ice-cold extractor it would be
shown to Miele and Mark rose and Eldon
and the three of them would on the spot
come up with name and sell the product
as we know the isolator bags and that
was the birth of the bubble bags just
four or five months after that so that
was in 1999 when bubble bags were
birthed and I think the real difference
in the importance of why when someone's
doing a product that other people should
be allowed to innovate and create that
better product is because you know it's
it's it's all about hitting it with a
full house of cards and I got lucky in
the sense that not only did I have the
love and the passion and the olfactory
tune to cannabis but I also had the
willingness to share in a highly illegal
market in us in a not really very legal
place online debt you know information
pictures of hash and process and
basically making hash okay in the late
90s and putting it on the internet that
was really the beginning of an overgrown
cannabis culture cannabis world all of
those web sites really made it possible
for us to share we were all kind of
outlaws but there we were sharing our
information kind of hoping that it
couldn't be traced back to us even
though most people were probably not
masking their IPS we still did it and it
was it was really a part of the civil
disobedience you know that fear of
making us all split up and not
in communication with one another that
was the real damage that was done and so
now as we are able to network again back
then especially through those websites
and now today through social media like
Instagram and YouTube and Facebook and
Twitter these are just new ways for us
to stay connected with one another share
our information and realize that we're
much stronger allied together as we are
broken and separated apart
speaking of Instagram kik Berkeley
patients groups they kicked out our
Instagram so we have a new Instagram so
people if you could do me a favor at
some point if you happen to go through
Instagram go to Berkeley patients group
and hit a like we would love to get our
patients back we don't know why they
kicked it off it was just random and we
were kicked so again you know the
prohibition and the fun that goes with
the allottee still continues so but it
doesn't stop any we single one of those
I see everybody here looks to be working
and driving on and making the future
continue so we drive on yeah exactly
well said at 10:00 thank you for coming
in and sharing that and yeah
everyone in the room has instagrams as
well so at one point maybe towards the
end we'll try to go through the whole
well everyone but Sam as an Instagram
although I have seen a skunk man Sam but
it's not you it's not an obscene several
struct man Sam's and know them for me
but have you ever seen your own skunk
man Sam and thought him I know no no
problem he still denies him to in the
mirror exactly the future of Kent of
hashish to me a lot of it is dependent
on the cost of the raw materials in
other words when plants cost seven
thousand dollars a pound for manicured
dry buds
it doesn't make economical sense to make
resin for commercial production when
plants cost a hundred kilos I mean
excuse me a hundred dollars a kilo for a
dried plant and
Richard then it the commercial hashish
market would take off both water set dry
cept in all kinds of other ways because
the raw materials are fundamentally
cheap then and you want to make
value-added products out of them and
people will afford and want the very
best mm-hmm I think it's why you have a
passion to drive down the price of
manicured flowers to teach people that
they can grow field grown cannabis with
the Sun and still produce six star
resins well we are absolutely true we
also saw you know as Sam said 20 years
ago 20 plus years ago that's was the
price of cannabis here in California but
over time that is now dropped two words
it swelled to five to six hundred of
pounds therefore it makes hashish much
more readily available to actually be
made as opposed to in the past it was
economically unsound as I said and that
was the reality situation but one did
take $7,000 Tom weed and then turn it
into hash you know only unless you were
an exceptional head everybody else it
was just Tuesday right true novel soil
girls got a split on us hopefully he's
got one more little thing to share about
his inspirations his loves his passion
of cannabis I love the stories dude I
wish you got to talk more what do you
say yeah I mean I'm looking forward to
the next hash Church I mean I think we
should really dig into a lot more of
these topics and yeah I mean keep
washing perfect Dave very cool well
thanks for coming out dude we are
definitely going to dig into more of
these topics someone asked what the if I
could sort of tell them a little bit
about what I plan on doing with hash
Church 2.0 and really he wants to know
the direction that I'm going with the
hash search in the future and the rules
different panelists will have and
basically it's pretty simple I want to
do specific talks where I invite
specific people not get too complacent
and inviting the whole panel in over and
over and over again
which was great for hash trips 1.0 but I
think it's a little bit of what kind of
killed our vibe with was that it was the
same people talking every week that we
were just having a hard time even coming
up with new conversation obviously
inviting new blood in people that are
passionate about the discussion is gonna
be important and I look forward to all
the panelists that are on the show today
and all the panelists that have been on
the show if you have any great ideas for
shows like definitely get to me and we
can produce it together over the course
of the week that's before the show I
don't even mind starting a month before
and getting some shows locked up and
I've been doing it a little differently
in the sense of creating an agenda and
creating a contact sheet with emails and
and making it just a little bit easier I
never did any of this for hash Church
1.0 that [ __ ] was like by the seat of my
pants and I just think that it was such
a great concept and it blew up for a
little while so great that I would love
to see hash Church 2.0 do even do even
bigger things and of course it's not
anything without all of you showing up
on the panel and sharing sharing all
your great stories and your perspectives
and and you know what every once in
awhile if we don't see eye to eye and we
argue that's okay too I think that it's
something that we want to maintain and
hash Church is not always agreeing with
everyone but at least respecting
everyone and listening to what they have
to say I'm stoked that the conversation
today I'm ready to go for a little while
longer if you guys want to talk hashish
maybe we should smoke some hashish I
mean my goodness I think what we need to
do is organize that everybody promises
to grow 1,000 plants grind it up make a
sheesh out of it so that hashish will be
everywhere with everybody I'm telling
you you have the most unique perspective
Sam because you've grown the fields
you've grown the huge greenhouses you
know you've had material on a level that
most have not had access to like you
said the whole plants ground up and just
sitting waiting for you to to bounce
over screens or to to do whatever you
need to get done to get that resin off
of it's it's incredible man definitely
hats off
you have had a passion and a love for
this that really kind of kid I think
that you were one of the few people
holding the flame for a long time
especially in regards to hash dry
sifting knowledge and taking it to the
next level there was really you know
every year at the Cannabis Cup for I
can't remember what year I asked this
but I asked the audience like how many
people have full melt dry sift how many
people have full melt water hash how
many people have oil oil was always the
majority of the crowds full melt water
hash in the early days was less but grew
as time went on and dry sift was always
Sam just the one hand in the audience
it's awesome I've been so grown has
split so say goodbye to him lots of
people produce very very high quality
dry set now it's no longer uncommon I
mean you don't see it in large amounts
and you don't see it everywhere but it
is there it's true it's absolutely there
you can put it in the hashtag on
Instagram and see it we've got there's
at least a few people producing very
nice resin and making it available
there's no doubt that when we're in
Barcelona this year for spannabis and
I'll try to come up with some dates
maybe by next week for hash Church to
let people know it'll be probably a two
to three day event where we just you
know maybe we'll finish it off with the
dinner and the whole ticketed thing and
then the first couple of days can be us
meeting around Barcelona to just have
have a have a nice session maybe have a
house for one day where everyone comes
to I think it's a really good idea that
the samples have to be admitted three
days before the event yeah it's just
always been harder because I always
chose the people who are coming to the
event based on people that came to my
booth at spannabis and showed me
beautiful hash that's right but it's
either got to be harder for the
organization of the event or harder I
less judged to the point of
impossibility right so let's make it
harder on the organization of the event
I agree
I'm in IBO so anyone else got some takes
on whether they see the future of
hashish going maybe some of the people
we haven't heard from as much like
Andrew and Jessica or dr. ladybug or dab
logic I know that a lot of us are have
loud voices and we're very like non-stop
but I want to give you guys the
opportunity to say more as well people
want to hear from you I actually like to
ask you guys what about collecting the
non-water the not water-soluble terpenes
from hash water after washes because
obviously most of us soon are doing
production washes and we have so much
water left over like what I cubed you
have a cold trap so I'm sure you're
collecting some of the Terps yeah I am
with a bulk amount of water that we have
what is there to do and what could we
possibly do with it so I have okay all
right sweet there we go
so I have the Turk water from the drying
of the hash and I have a lot of it right
I personally didn't know what to do with
it because I put it in a separation
funnel and I didn't separate like the
still Terps you know like two to an
amount that would it be worth spending
time trying to extracted so when I saw
Tony at the emerald-cut I asked him
because he's a smart guy how you know
like yo what can I do with this he told
me that you can make woman's fragrance
from the Turks from the hydrosols so I
think that's tight I'm gonna have
everybody sweating like Kimble and
cookies and cream oh geez so that's what
I'm hoping that I'm gonna do with my ice
water but I'm also curious because like
you I do have a lot
yeah dude Tony was that was that one of
his first ins to terpenes back in
Colorado pre the conversation I had with
K from trichome technologies who I guess
maybe a year into hash Church said to me
listen you should figure out how to get
the terpenes out of the water from
bubble water and that's gonna be your
future and I was kind of busy at the
time not really thinking that I was
going to focus on that but what I did do
is I mentioned it to two people
I mentioned it to Tony who was in
Florida at the time at a very high-end
lab and I think he was able to kind of
bounce things off of some pretty smart
people between him and them they he was
able to come up with I mean he had blue
river terpenes less than a month after
that conversation then Horatio was the
second person I mentioned it to and he
kind of just it went over his head he
wasn't interested but once Tony was
making terpenes and I called him out on
hash Church one time I said dude I told
you guys both on the same day about the
terpenes and Tony's had terpenes since
like two or three weeks later where's
yours
Horatio had them the next day so it's it
was definitely that trichome technology
k you know he's been doing terpenes for
a while now as well extracting them and
he had Alexander Shulgin helping him and
whatnot so I'm sure we're gonna see more
from him in the near future
unfortunately things went a little bit
south in regards to me telling those
guys about you know what they should do
just in conversation it's he was a
little upset about them both having
terpenes on the market before he did so
apologies Takei definitely didn't mean
to step on anyone's toes but at the same
time you know sometimes it's not the
person that wants to come up with
something and release it but it's the
person who's actually gonna do it and I
know that hurts the person who wants to
be the person to do it but it's like
guess what it just happens the way it
happens now and with things like
Instagram and it's like it can happen
fast with with just someone stepping
into the right timing they become the
person you know and it's people just
gotta respect that I just look at rosin
alone what you know a few years ago we
did it the first rosin episode over at
the Ashe museum in Barcelona and now
it's just at the Emerald cup and there's
a whole rosin section now so I mean is
the squishers there's every kind of
possible outlet now I mean it's it's
rather fascinating how things can gather
steam and roll forward rather quickly as
you stay progress waits for no man right
well particularly why there's an open
dialogue about it particularly when
there's an open dialogue happening and
information is being shared because when
did that hash Church with soil grown I
think it was number 25 and he was
talking about it we were all like maybe
we could do machines wouldn't be cool if
there were these big machines with
plates and it's like that's all a
reality now it's a no yeah I remember
when when I saw rosin for the first time
it looked like witchcraft or wizardry
I couldn't believe that you could take
half note and make it something you
could smoke and I was like well I'm
making edibles with this stuff because I
have nothing to do with it
that should change my life so big up
soil grown we haven't seen yet is a
continuous operation rosin machine where
you just constantly feed it and it
constantly produces revs and 24/7 like a
wish like a conveyor yeah maybe some
rollers let's get the conversation going
someone out there it's going to happen
I'm sure it's happening already I can
hear someone tapping away with a hammer
working in the background
that [ __ ] was legit somebody just got
the idea and is patenting it right now
aren't you there Sam he's already
copyrighted it see he's on it well it's
interesting to see where the future of
hash will be whether you know dry sift
will pick up steam with new found
methods that allow for quicker
extraction if bubble hash is gonna have
a bigger comeback than it's already
having or if oil is just going to
continue to you know kind of own the the
marketplace I'd like to speak on with
the prices going down in in California
specifically like Sam was saying the
cost is is going to make a lot more
people jump on to making hash because
even if the yields are low the cost
isn't there anymore so you can still
produce get a low yield and make your
money back so it's going to intrigue a
lot more farmers that were you know
normally sending their stuff off to be
Ram of butane to turn into ice water
because a lot of a lot of the farmers I
work with would rather go solve unless
an organic method so if it cost if it's
cost-effective like it's happening in
California then we're gonna have I see a
lot more ash a lot love perhaps just
almost I would see to be competitive
with solvent extractions
yeah well or in some conjunction because
to make water extraction really work you
really should have a plan B for added
value for the bulbous heads that aren't
extracting through the sieving process
they can make up sometimes 10% of the
yield and so that's a lot of heads to be
leaving behind whether you're doing a
plant fat extract and producing products
like piranha whether you're doing a a
chemical extraction or a co2 extraction
producing distillate or whether you're
you know figuring out another method may
be a rosin method to produce oil for
edibles either way getting that resin
off of the plant after you've washed it
is definitely going to be sort of a key
thing if you want to have that added
value make up for you know the actual
potential loss that you'll see if you
just go from making oil to go to making
hash and the truth is water hash is much
more efficient at extracting all the
resin than dry city dry city is not
particularly efficient yeah I hope to
see a greater demand for non solvent
concentrates but I still think that this
solvent abstracts mean to dominate the
market merely I mean just because
traditionally speaking we look at other
industries whatever is the most
efficient process he tends to dominate
and I mean you know let's face it like
you making it the beauty and guys are
putting out numbers that urges you know
I mean incredible amounts of oil can be
made from one person just you know in
the day and maybe they got like dual ten
pound
laughing columns like I mean you know we
have to we have to run a lot of material
to to make like those kind of numbers
but um yeah I mean you know with it's
all about economics and if the price
gets if the price drops and it's more
accessible for us then I think you know
so we'll be able to to have a place in
the market for sure
because you know a lot of people they do
want more like natural everything now
you know there's a big push for health
in general and you know I was reading
somewhere that the demand for vegan and
vegetarian food is increased a thousand
percent in the past 40 years you know so
I mean just not alone right there says
that there there should be a big market
for us you know moving forward but um
you know we'll see
yeah did you want to go ahead dank
touches oh I actually want to say the
same thing that drew said what she was
like um I can't really speak to it being
a Chow I don't know so much about the
pho my kids but the push toward health
is something that is in a trend that's
not gonna reverse so like was the
financial devs once we have once the
price comes down like I mean I'm a
grower so it doesn't affect me like that
because I'm not buying materials I run
my own guitar and then I became a cash
in that but once the price comes down
and it is much easier to actually make
cash because a lot of people don't
understand that making house is not a
millionaires game no matter what you
think nobody I know who's making hash I
know a lot of hash tables a like rolling
in the dough so when you're buying
material you're buying really really
quality material but the numbers just
don't add up so I could totally
understand why you would take that
superfly your in door and then make it
into the intro but if it's all about
money but if price comes down then this
is something that's more feasible for
more of us and we can get to the market
more you know turkey or things that
taste murder and there are on that same
level that people who want that who have
that fine glass while their dad's to be
only I would only add to this in regards
to the difference of what dr. ladybug
was
in regards to the difference between the
oil yields and the bubble hash yields
the real real difference and I've told a
lot of my friends that are have
preference in oil that you know if you
if you have a preference in oil then
tricep bring it up separating the bland
heads out by micron size and seeing if
you can't make some oil with just 73 or
just 90 or just 120 and see what that
oil is like compared to because I know
as a hash maker if I took my 25 through
190 and put them all together and I've
ruined my 90 in 120 like if someone did
that I would smack their face so hard it
would be like I'm not a violent guy but
I'm telling you you put all my ashes
together when a bunch of them are shady
and some of them are really great you're
definitely getting at least like a a
waft of my hand because it's it's it's
there it's special you can see it with
the naked eye where the magic lies
sometimes in these cultivars with
specific micron diameters and I'm not
against people mixing them up and doing
whatever they want but for me I really
love having them separate and I always
told my friends that had a preference
for oil I said man if you could see all
those shaggy bulbous heads that you're
melting off into you're 90 120 and 73
you would make hash first and make oil
with your with your hash and some did
some did it and they were just like holy
[ __ ] that made my oil like 5 times
stronger than it was and then it
separates and it creates a difference
out in the marketplace with the that the
normal everyday Joe who's buying this
stuff can understand like this is
farmers grade oil in a sense it's the
full spectrum of all of the gland heads
from the bulbous which I personally as a
hash smoker don't want to smoke right up
to the the capitate stocks and sessile
stocked so that's a point I wanted to
make yeah that's a good point I get
asked a lot sometimes when I go on
livestream sometimes I'll do it to smoke
me join and get talk to the people and
they like to ask me Kuban would
especially know that that I've been
working and managing my homies garden
he's a hydrocarbon extractor he goes by
critical they like to ask me Cuban what
do you like oil or hash it's your
favorite and it's the same thing it's
like man I got a selection of heads
you make rasa with the 45 verses rasa
with a 90 then you already know what
what we're talking about there's a
totally different league there yeah well
that was that literally I don't know
when episode 25 on hash Church was but I
bet you it was very close to March
because we ended up ended up in Spain
for Barcelona right after that episode
and we were showing people Jeff Church
and myself at my booth which was
actually Xavier from medical seeds booth
he was letting me work out of a corner
we had a little mini hair straightener
and we were we were making rosin and
showing you know DNA I've never seen it
before
urban grower Remo had never seen it we
had all these incredible people in the
industry coming over and learning about
it and great gardener walked over and I
had cleaned a bunch of barbed dry sift
for him it was 6/3 dry sift it was
literally like 99.999 heads grown
absolutely beautifully and cured
beautifully over the course of like
almost six months and he was like we'll
try some of this and that was the first
time and DNA was there and urban grower
was there and I think Cushman or some
High Times guys were there and it was
just like squishing out that six-hour
drive shaft was insane when we wrapped
it in the screen just with our hand and
it started dripping out of the screen
just with our hands like that [ __ ] was
insane yeah there's a hole in
California's where I see it mostly but
now people are pressing the best hash
that they can get into rosin just
because they think it's that much better
and to me as a hash guy at first I think
it's crazy until you see the type of
rosin that these guys are making excites
me stupid fire and to be able to press a
six-star and in a production sense and
then Grandma what you're making and make
up any sort of profit is crazy as hell
so shout out to people like the rosin
Brothers yeah for real so they're doing
that and do you think that if you have
99.9
percent resin heads and you squash it
and you make Rossum do you think the
rosin is really significantly any better
at all and can it be preserved as good
as the dry cept well I don't think that
it would be any better if you're asking
me because I love smoking hash in its
raw form so I'm happy with it but there
are people that believe that just a waxy
layer of the head enough being able to
separate that from the essential oil and
purify it that much further they'll take
that step because to them they do
believe that it is a better quality
smoke if you do it at the right
temperatures it's almost as if per gram
and / way you're concentrating the THC
and the turps and everything but I would
just slope the dry season I like dry sip
better I've never had anything I like
better but if somebody thinks they can
take my best dry set and make it into
rosin that's better I want to try it
let's do it I'm jumping on a plane yeah
so on another note of going back a
little bit on production costs there
already are farms that are producing
fresh frozen at about a $50 per unit
cost for twenty two hundred grams frozen
like that and then at that price now I
might not be the best material to wash
and make six star but for a hydrocarbon
extractor they're able to buy that
material and bring down their wholesale
price and hit the market with a decent
product you know what I mean
and it kind of not only this stabilizes
everything but it makes it makes it hard
to compete I think with hash because you
kind of do that with how should it be
hard I think I don't know well but one
of the futures of hashish will be
automated processing where you take
dried plants you
put them in the machine it grinds them
up and then has the ability to separate
the resin to 99.9 with little or no loss
of any of the resin it it is possible it
will be will all be replaced by robots
bro it I I went to a facility on Friday
and these guys they're bigger than life
like huge awesome indoor grows awesome
you know the way they scaled this
quality was mind-boggling to me as a
grower Ellison alright prop so I'm
locking their stuff and they have like
this area with like 70 trimmers it
almost looks like the classroom people
with their heads down put on the trim
bins and then I walked to another room
and they just have shelves of trimming
teeth I'm like holy [ __ ] if there is a
machine that you could just dump that
raw Keef into it and it could make you
hash the guy that made that machine
would be rich as hell for sure is that
that has to be a solution for everybody
I wonder how much Keith is sitting on
shows from big trimming operations to be
a lot and I'll tell you back in the day
they just used to like not even make it
but throw it away with the trim back in
Florida we'd throw away all our trim and
so I figured out I could get like a
pantyhose and do some sort of keeping it
was a little ghetto but it worked but
anyways men I gotta get going like he's
getting a little rambunctious probably
gonna go out to breakfast I appreciate
you guys inviting thanks for coming out
we appreciate having you it was awesome
yeah yeah thank you
and I hope you guys enjoy the rest of
the day
happy 2018 oh no it's January Sarah
happy Sunday too man thank you and bye
peace out man thanks thank you thank
your wife thank your son don't have fun
it's always good to focus on children
but not here in hashed Church cuz we're
focused on hash and so we're gonna stick
with it we're gonna stay on it did you
hear that pun stick with it good hash
can put up posters that was what I
always thought back when I first saw
melty hash I thought man I could
poster up with this and then I find that
I got real Mountie hash and I was like
damn I could put like anything up with
this like a framed wooden picture maybe
my friend after he falls asleep at night
I could plug a hole in a boat with it
plug a hole in a boat with it in fact I
did one time get locked in a bathroom
cheering I think it was one of Bob
Marley's birthday I think it might have
been the one I was with you skunk man
Sam and your lovely wife in Negril
Jamaica and we're at Bob's birthday
concert and I got locked in the bathroom
the little thing that I went to open
broke off of the little sliding piece of
metal that keeps the door locked it
broke right off so and I had a match at
the time I was at the school of Sam
puffing all my Bulls with matches on
fresh greens and so I used a match and I
used some full melt hash that we had
made in Jamaica and I stuck it up
against the little pin and it just
opened up no problem and I was like damn
I'm like hashed MacGyver right now and
there's like nobody even like it was
before social media you that before you
shared all the stupid [ __ ] in your life
that happened it was like when when when
moments were just for you and not for
the whole world not for likes
although chronic says we do it for the
love not for the likes I agree
well played my friend well played well
that's something that you want to share
dab logic from the future I think you
know technology is gonna be a huge role
in that kind of upgrading our systems
and your production going that's gonna
be able to compete with BHO and things
like that I think as we you know mounted
breeders begin to bring back that
varieties and things like that we're
gonna definitely see a lot more high
yielding hash strains you know like
everything we run here we lead with all
fresh frozen and we don't do anything
that does that gets us under 20% like
things like the chemi Jones typically do
like 30% makan millenia doing
oil that's hash and then when we press
that down it's probably like 24% oil or
including the six star and uh you don't
press all your hash down though right
you guys sell hash as well so a lot of
hash mainly 5050 so well rosin but we
make 5050 so we have about every pound
60 grams of oil or of EDS and then
another 60 grams or so of rosin grade or
whatever like that I'm a firm believer
on separating the two and identifying
them as separate rosin pho pho sio2
those are oils and you know see
mechanical sieve water hash finger rub
those are hashes to me it's my
definition of them I think that there
seems to be quite a difference in the
two just from a perspective of smoking
go ahead a lot a lot of hash if it's--if
high-quality hash typically melts fairly
oily consistency it's not necessarily
like a runny oil or something like that
but it's it's definitely uh gooey greasy
you know like to it and you listen you
named a cultivar can you name a few more
of what your favorites are for hash
making I know Gigi for was popular in
Colorado it always pumped up 20% plus
yeah Gigi you know the gorilla glue is
awesome
you know cookies varieties are great
Kemeny aged diesel lineage that's
typically what I find to be the best as
far as for fresh frozen on a skunk
lineage that that's around that is
actually very good hash making material
is large heads and very nice color with
a very psychedelic type high to it I
mean there's there's there's a lot of
varieties that you can go to but you
could say that most of them fall into
those lineage that at least are those 20
plus percent strains yeah and that's
another one of the most important
factors that you're gonna have access to
genetics if you're trying to get into
this in a commercial level and trying to
make it available and accessible for
people the reason that people have a
hard time doing it is a acquiring the
right cultivars and even be knowing what
the right cultivars are so I think now
would be a really great time for their
left for the few people that are still
left on the panel to share you know like
dab logic just did what their favorite
cultivars are that produce not
necessarily high yields but produce
unique cannabinoid profiles unique
terpene profiles or high yields whatever
whatever your favorite is that I'm also
a fan of the skunk number one and the
Sleestak and the gorilla glues and the
oh geez and the where is my bike which
is you know probably a 23 to 25 percent
water hash and a 30 percent rosin
yielder with very unique terpene content
higher high levels of terpene allene
which is that very exotic sort of haze
terpene that we all know and love about
you guys Jessica and Andrew what are you
what are some of your favorites we
worked with is very like cookie cherry
pie kind of those kind of genetics we
get it you know hi it was a very high
quality I kind of got popular with the
pink champagne a couple years ago that
was a cherry pie and a GD P cross that
high-yield and just tasted like grape
and melted amazing but a lot of stuff
that we work with is like I feel like in
that cookie family whether it be like
the sherbert or any kind of cookie cross
and cherry pie that kind of stuff
well cool thank you for sharing what
about you doctor ladybug yeah we
actually all so lately we've been
running a lot of cookies I'm like cookie
crosses lately but we also run this
variety a 12 THC bomb things been around
for a while I really like that one it's
like a pig pen um the turn profile it's
kind of reminds me of those own
Flintstone Flintstone vitamins it kind
of has like a chalky through B but
there's like a funk and also I mean the
resin is really nice it doesn't even if
you let it go to full maturity it's it's
still dumped and it's very light color
and the the resin is very stable it's
really nice and like Gradius it but
it'll when in greece is it'll grease it
like an oil puddle but but I like that
resin that's that's really gritty and
stable probably though my favorite
terpene profile was came from this
variety called kc 36 it's white widow
across to casey 606 it's a it's like a
fruity funky it's like really hard to
describe I can't really like place it
it's kind of one of those you know that
kind of leaves you like it lingers in
your mouth and you kind of like
scratching your head like what is that
like it just like jumps all over the
place but um it's just also a a variety
called Lucy it's very similar we ran
that this year dad it was incredible
lost the cut didn't clone it it wasn't
sure really what it was just like threw
a couple outside last year and yeah and
then that unfortunately the nursery lost
the genetics during the Santa Rosa fire
so I'm not sure we're gonna get that one
back again look pretty sad well that's
two more stories in a row that reminds
me to tell everyone that sharing is
caring and giving away your genetics
won't probably hurt you I'm not talking
about Sam who spent millions of dollars
breeding and this that the other thing
but if you just acquired your genetics
through gift which I'm sure you probably
have sharing something that you made
from that gift is not going to be the
end of the world it's good to get it out
there at least try to share it with a
few people I like to share
a lot and I'll tell you I never lose
cultivars because of it it's always the
same story oh [ __ ] that combo I had is
dying
thank God I gave it to 47 people the
reason I have TGA seeds right now is
because that wonderful man spread his
genetics and love around and he lost
everything in the fire unfortunately
people had it and gave back to him
otherwise I wouldn't have some of the
seeds I have on the floor right now it's
true he got a lot of seeds give him back
to him because he gave away so many
seeds it's like hello sharing is caring
the loaf comes back always I'm kind of
the anomaly though when you're going
back talking about the hash because ever
since I did bubble hash back in the late
90s it was actually my tattoo here's of
the flow is my favorite genetic and
horrible unfortunately that got lost
along the way but I literally brought it
in and laid it on you know the but on on
the thing my tattoo artist drew it on me
and it was just one of my favorites but
ever since then I'm a sinner to you
bubbleman because I've kind of always
taken my bubble and I put it in a
grinder and I grind it all together and
I pressed it all together I love the
different flavors for me I go for
effects so for me for my medical
condition I like the full spectrum so
I've kind of always have been repressed
my water hash back into my own hash
which is of course net needless to say
is full milk but I get the full spectrum
of need that I enjoy I also do the same
thing with my BHO I take all my BA chose
that I get of course I get it here at 4
b PG and they're all tested so they're
clean and I put them in a little oven at
a hundred and twenty degrees Fahrenheit
and I literally put them in a little
autoclave and I mix them all together
and so again I get the full spectrum I
get some funky flavors as they blend
together don't get me wrong but again
it's not so much for me for flavor as
much as it is for the effect for my
medical condition I have go for syndrome
I have I've nerve issues I've got
chronic pain and all kinds of things
that I deal with so I do love the
individual flavors you know
dank touches had some beautiful stuff
come through lately and it was
absolutely wonderful and I love again
the different flavors that for in the
end I still kind of mix it all together
you know because Jett just works for me
and I respect you and I won't when I'm
with you I make sure that it is
separated into the individuals so that I
don't share my mud with you but that I
pop your mud I puff your mud dude and
honestly you remind me of my old buddy
David Esau from like hockey when we were
11 years old showing me about the swamp
water you know I like all the individual
tastes but I'm really more about the
effect of bouncing off the walls from
all the different sugars that are in
this drink root beer ginger ale Coca
Cola Orange Crush yeah I was 11
yeah it probably wasn't good for my
teeth but you brought me back at ten I
appreciate that so and flow was the bomb
that was also breeder Steve's favorite
plant back in the day when he was
growing in Lugano Switzerland in 2003
2004 he he had some some incredible flow
genetics props to DJ short for making
that one I heard it was a real mutant
and I I don't know that it exists
anymore but if it ever does I really
wanted again anyway I loved it so much
and the bud that I grew is the one
that's on my arm so I grew it and grew
wonderfully and it made beautiful water
hash because I had the original machine
before your bags I had one of the
original Isolators back in the day and
that was challenging and you had to
always automatically clean it out
because as as people and who have dealt
with bubble no do not let your water sit
we all know the sin that happens if
somebody anybody accidentally let their
water sit was sometime in the stink
nastiness that you have to do with that
toxic what what would you call that that
transpires they I call it tent funk
it's like lending your tent to your
[ __ ] bro that never dried it out but
he just wrapped it up and put it in the
bag and then gave it back to you I call
it the tent funk not to be confused with
the funk from the west coast but the
tent funk it's no bueno and it happens
to bubble bags
it'll pass on to your hash each and
every batch you make and it's it's like
it's one of the like deadly sins against
the hash maker thou shalt not lend thy
bubble bags shalt not put my foot about
legs away wet
don't do it yeah - take that funk it's
it's just funk it's a lot like cherry
used condoms I think that is the most
disturbing thing that anyone said on
hash chairs and of course it has to be
Scott man Sam we accept you for all that
you are and that is definitely
definitely made my skin crawl okay Sam
when did that happen no I got to avoid
it yeah yeah okay all right but she
brought it up so we're just stuff oh my
gosh that was shocking
I think first it was shocking that I I
was looking right at the Duchess when I
saw her expression change and then I was
like oh no like I'm embarrassed for all
men everywhere we've done this before
then the last time I was here it was
just like size matters oh yeah we're not
gonna do that you know go into that but
you know I would rather have a bigger
piece of hash than a smaller is that
what you're saying that is exactly it
that's exactly what I was going here
well I know my hash never runs out and
I'm talking about hash 100% which I
probably should take a little rip of I
think I don't know I feel pretty good we
did three hours and 20 minutes so far if
anyone has anything else they want to
really for sure mention and say by all
means now it would be a great time to
step up to the plate if you have a
conversation that we want brought up or
one thing I have to say is the future of
hash we are the future of hash we will
make the future of ash all of us
together all of our ideas and it's going
to happen and it's gonna get better well
that is very well said Sam I was gonna
say the youth myself but you know what
who are the youth if they can't stand on
the shoulders of giants
which we've been lucky enough to do and
some of us have been lucky enough to
offer to be the shoulders to stand on
like Sam and other great hashish
aficionados over the years and that's
what we celebrate at legends of hash we
celebrate legends of past and so you
know we were never celebrating ourselves
at legends of hash that was never an
option unless one of us dies off but it
was always celebrating the true legends
of hash and I don't know maybe
wouldn't it be a cool thing to read one
of those cards if we had access to it
Sam I've got I've got the gardens of
Koffler so maybe I'll read that real
quick and that's how well we'll finish
off hash Church today this was from
legends of hash Roman numeral 10 not to
be confused with the iPhone but it's the
legends of hash 10 this was the 10 year
anniversary and it was the the Garden of
khufu or the garden or the green plant
which grows in the gardens of Khufu
replaces in our hearts the effects of
old and noble wine in the 12th century
Cairo the favorite meeting place for the
hashish connoisseurs was the legendary
gardens of Khufu islamic law forbade the
drinking of wine but mez many Muslims
especially Sufis were great proponents
of hashish eating and its legality was
hotly debated by Islamic courts by the
14th century conservative mother Muslim
leaders won out and came down hard by
destroying kafirs gardens burning
surrounding hashish field and starving
out the farmers shops and cafes selling
hashish were closed and the owners
hunted down and killed but hashish use
still continued in 1378 the frustrated
Cairo government forced all known how
sheesh users into the main square where
soldiers wrenched out their teeth
a decade later how she's eating still
thrived in Egypt as it had become too
much a part of the Arab way of life to
be forsaken may the gardens of Khufu
serve as an ancient reminder that
cannabis prohibition will never succeed
give me this green plants from the
gardens of Khufu and that's a wrap
everyone thank you so much for being a
part of hashtag
2.0 the past the present and the future
of hashish we'll do it again soon I want
to have a lot more conversations about
hashish so you guys will all be hearing
from me in the near future and yeah
legends of hashish barcelona 2018 peace
out everybody