too because
wow got it got it welcome everybody to
oh gez I don't even know is it episode
27 it is it's hash Church 3.0 episode 27
and all I have to do quickly is grab the
the link I'm going to grab the link and
send it over to the folks that are in
the wrong one because for whatever
reason when I create a YouTube link and
then I go live it creates a totally
different one so awesome I just want to
welcome the few people that have arrived
already we got the dragonfly Earth
medicine in the house we got Mr skunkman
Sam in the house who God it's it was a
while ago but you celebrated a birthday
didn't
you yeah no I my birthday's in
July okay well what was it I thought I
missed something I feel like I missed
something that was some months ago so
much happened people have passed away
and people have celebrated birthdays and
there's all sorts of things going on in
the world right now and I can't really
keep up but uh hopefully you guys are
all doing really well over in Amsterdam
and over in the
CPS oh oh although things are blowing up
here they had riots in the Del last
night and they had riots in
roddam because a lot of people they
don't want to be vaccinated but yet they
want to be able to freely travel and uh
they're demonstrating to the point of
extremity damn yeah it's going on all
over right
now yeah I heard that there a lot of
people are not necessarily uh
um you know out there in the streets
because they're against vaccines they're
out there in the streets because they're
against the
mandates and there's a lot of people who
are fully vaccinated are against the ma
mandates and I think there's a really
big difference between being pro-choice
and then being mandated so I think
that's what a lot of people are ups and
then there's a lot of Dutch anarchists
who just like to stir up
[ __ ] and for that we're
thankful well unless they're harming
things and that's not cool we understand
no no exactly I just changed my mic cuz
someone told me I sounded like a phone
call so hopefully that's a little bit
better there uh oh Johnny B's coming in
you guys might not recognize Johnny B
there's only two-thirds of Johnny B uh
that used to be here I think he's lost
like 70 pounds or some ridiculous thing
rocking the push-ups rocking the situps
doing the walking and the healthy eating
Johnny [ __ ] B in Toronto at Lyft dude
you do your push-ups today or what
you're muted I got I'm 50 done I'm down
I'm I'm finished I did I did 15 push-ups
in on of the Roger Center I did 15
push-ups in front of the CN tower then I
did another 15 push-ups overlooking the
CN Tower and everything else and then I
did another 10 so I'm past that point um
I feel fantastic good morning everybody
well I what I like about it is that
means I don't have to do any exercise
you did it for me see that's the whole
idea you got me going you got me going
I've been doing 50 push-ups for the last
10 days or however long it's been since
you uh challenged me it's a 50-day
challenge we're doing we're pushing into
2022 with just a new push of life and
you know what a little healthiness a
little bit of exercise just nothing
major just 50 a day you could do five 10
times a day 10 five times a day I'm up
to 18 then I have to break and then I
could do another five and three that's
my Max and I have to rest well your
timing is perfect brother because uh we
were just kind of talking about
something we probably won't get too deep
in talking to today because it's such a
triggering and de divisive conversation
but I love that you came in right at the
time to show people that you know during
this hectic kind of crazy time there are
other ways to improve one's Health which
is to focus on what you put in your
mouth what you breathe into your lungs
what you uh you know put into your mind
because consuming CNN all day isn't the
healthiest of things to do and uh yeah
just kind of figuring out other ways to
be healthy and happy and uh you know
kind kind of going down that pathway
Johnny B and no one can deny you've been
doing
it yeah morning
walks oh sorry on that I wanted to tell
you guys that we're on uh day seven of
our liquid cleanse of a 20day cleanse
right now so we're on day seven of our
liquid cleanse and it's been totally
amazing like you know talk about
changing your frequency and upping your
health and really stimulating your
immune stimulus response it's like once
you start getting rid of digestion then
you reach an entire whole level of of
healing and immune boost so it's been
really great over here too and I love it
that we're talking about health and
well-being and Johnny B way to go buddy
up we've been doing a 10 minute planks
five minut and another awesome what we
do is we and I'll tell you this really
quick Alec Dixon big love to you yeah
welcome Alec bro
long than 30
seconds other
arm that in plank elbows and then do 30
pushup words and it's and you do it to
the song TW song so it's a six minute
workout and you can I can do it with a
doobie in my mouth I can do the whole
thing smoking a Dobie in my mouth and
that makes me stoked so I I'm with you
I'm with you on the the weed workouts
and the feeling good because I'm 48 I'm
I'm gonna be 50 soon so you know what
that's good to hear
and you guys look great so I take advice
take advice healthwise from people that
look healthy I remember this giant man
one time in in Amsterdam giving me
Health advice and I was kind of like
dude like no offense but like I I can't
take Health advice from someone that's
clearly not showing me a healthy
lifestyle and you guys are definitely
looking good uh for any age let alone
for you know getting into the 50s and
stuff that's awesome welcome to Dr Mark
scalone and the cats Down Under The
[Music]
starbody Dude one of my
favorites couldn't couldn't miss
it so disg did we invite Jonah Hill onto
the show today just kidding just
kidding I'm bum they didn't pick me dude
I've seen some funny [ __ ] I seen someone
say that Iggy Pop is going to be playing
naked guy on the pole remember that you
remember talking I was talking to
Sunshine Sunshine Key at the last Oregon
Country Fair and they like re
reconnected with that guy yeah he's
really healthy he's oh yeah he's great
he's like a super good guy out in the
woods of Oregon
still that's so good that is so good oh
my god did he ever think when he was up
on that pole on that threatful day that
he would be known infamously as the
naked guy on the pole at the Bonita show
every dead head in the world it's like
oh yeah naked guy on the pole yeah yeah
that guy P playing him oh my god dude I
don't know I feel like he hung out with
Bear right before that show it it was
hotter than hell that day so there were
a lot of naked people in the audience
and just so that he got
right but there are there are hundreds
of naked people there that day I think
I'm pretty sure there were 20,000 people
there that day and minimal cars in the
parking lot because everyone hitchhiked
out on buses to the country that year
because there was no the gas prices were
so Inc high they charged $3 to get into
the show and the crazy thing is that
there was no water so when we talked to
everybody who ran that show they were
trying to literally bring in Water by
gallon jugs it was jugs and it was like
over 105 degrees totally insane so yeah
naked people gay lore well and they were
supposed to be making money for the
Springfield creary which is Ken Key's
brother Chuck key who started the
Springfield crey the very first yogurt
with probiotics in America chuckes ny's
yogurt they were trying to to to do a a
benefit for the Springfield Creamery in
1972 that's what that show's about they
didn't make any money because they only
charged $3 a ticket but I'm pretty sure
the dead gave him $10,000 afterwards and
obviously the business is still still
going and everything but and I love that
the kids getting licked in the face by
the dog the dirty dirty ass kids getting
licked in the face by the dog we we also
those kids in the realm so lots of love
you they came back in 82 right they did
another one 10 years later in 82 didn't
think H classic 1982 show of course so
good the yeah oh my God the I have the
songs playing in my head right now that
was out at Tower as well out at the
Oregon Country Fair so the
parking parking and then they tried to
do it again in 92 and we were all set
ready to do it and I was gonna help be
backstage manager and we had a whole
bunch of Oregon Country Fair running
that but then Jerry got got uh you know
he went into a coma so everything was
canell he got sick but there was also he
he heard his hand I think scuba
diving scuba diving but he also actually
was sick then too yeah he got really
sick he was super sick and then the
first show that he uh the Halloween show
at Oakland Jerry Garcia banned Oakland
Coliseum
1992 so he didn't smoke one cigarette
during the show yeah which has never
happened you know and it was just anyone
should go listen to that show but
basically tore the roof off and we were
roller skating in the parking lot right
because you roller skate from one side
to the other at the Oakland shows
because the base this is too much
information for everyone now but the guy
at the top between used to play wine
glasses with water in them and it
sounded like an organ because he would
put his hands on the on the wine glasses
with water at different levels and you
would play total total songs on the on
the wine glasses it was kind of
spectacular [ __ ] hippies I just love
it
all big up Colin you're awesome we've
been seeing you on our lives doing the
doing the health things and stuff love
you big love
guys yeah welcome Colin Big Love thanks
for having me I'm in h sunny California
right now
I'm smack dab in uh down in Venice in
that area right now Co so just uh thanks
man just here setting up this lab and
getting things cranking and it's
exciting but stressful
times you know I'm gonna jump out of
here guys peace and love hope you have a
fantastic day and uh I'll see you again
yeah if you want to jump in on lift if
there's some good stuff Johnny just uh
you know jump in on your phone later I'm
going to jump on down there and then I'm
jumping in my car for a nice little four
four 49 kilometers away four hours and
20 minutes I'm trying to get there for
710 for an awesome dinner so that's
when's your birthday brother right now
happy birthday Johnny V happy birthday
happy birthday happy birthday
Johnny yeah I'm I'm having just an a
awesome day today I did my 50 push-ups
today uh I I've just accomplished so
many things I wanted to today and and
now I'm on a 419 kilometer drive and you
know Mark I love number 419 so because
that's one minute warning before 420 so
I'm just off for a beautiful day and
then I get to spend five days of smoking
hash that's all we're smoking I got
everybody's hash across the country
waiting for me to try and just enjoy and
indulge in and I I you'll be seeing it
through the Instagram posts all week of
all the different all the different
greatness I get to try from all you guys
under there making amazing products and
it's just so rewarding being here at lft
and the amount of people Mark and amount
of people have been Shouting Out House
Church and have learned one guy came
down this morning having breakfast goes
I watch you and Mark and everybody on
hash church he had some rare disease he
makes his own bubble he gave me some raw
in the try everything has changed as
life you know what hashers changes
people's lives you guys are awesome and
I love you all and
we'll see
you so I'm excited as you can see I'll
see you have a great day Johnny B thanks
guys you guys thinking of you guys
Johnny happy birthday buddy you're the
best thanks for the
inspiration 72 pounds lighter today guys
that's your morning walks dedication and
committing to what you want never give
up never surrender and you'll get where
you want in life we'll talk to you soon
peace Johnny B that guy's a [ __ ]
inspiration I gotta
say just a good dude all around I knew
it was his birthday like in the near
future because when I first met the guy
I met him in Amsterdam and he was like
and and I think I met him on his
birthday like today like in 2012 or
whatever and uh so yeah that's uh that's
awesome good that we can all kind of
celebrate Johnny B's birthday maybe with
a little dab I think we got all sorts of
good things here I'm going to load up
the Dustin Riv little TP
slurper uh hello everybody yeah this is
uh our 11th year deep kind of in tenure
with SC labs and so yeah I mean it's
never a dull moment it's been you know
one of the most educational it has been
by far the most educational experience
of my life um but yeah lots of
fascinating Trends I'm super stoked to
be part of this conversation today hope
everybody's doing really wonderful
so is it nice is it sort of a different
fall for SC Labs right now hey you
guys this is our this is our 10th
Harvest uh kind of season you know and
as a laboratory you know each Harvest
year really kind of puts a lab is a
lab's capabilities you know as far as
quality once things get busy you know
and so so you know 10 years incremental
progress you know each Harvest we've
been able to optimize a little bit more
and yeah I mean we've um we we we have
like lab staff that run seven days a
week you know five days a week we have
an overnight shift you know so we've
just kind of started we just moved our
entire system to like a two-day Rush
three-day standard turn around so you
know kind of just working on optimizing
standardizing yeah I was actually
talking about the emerald cup samples
just that you guys aren't over inundated
with that oh totally yeah that right now
for sure yeah well so we we um the
emerald cup kind of Entry window is is
the month of January um so that's when
samples uh entries will be entered for
the emerald cup and then we are also
kind of right in the middle of um doing
testing for the California State Fair um
so the California State Fair you know
from um November 1st to March 1st is um
there's an entry window open for flowers
um across categories from sungrown mixed
light to indoor and yeah essentially
everything is um really primarily based
off the data for testing this year
there's not um it's just such an ordeal
to run a contest and to have you know
judges that entries are distributed to
and so um the State Fair this year they
they originally going to do an indicia
category into sta category but they kind
of caught wind of this cool kind of
turpine classification work we've been
doing and you know with the emerald cup
and so essentially everything's going to
be tested and sorted into the primary
turpine archetypes and then judged head
up against each other so you know ja
train re Sage deran everything
terpinolene will Jud be judging against
terpinolene and then the things that
really weigh the winners are going to be
around total turpine content and the
canabo so really like celebrating the
diversity of what this plant represents
on a turpine level as well as you know
kind of helping to you know push and um
educate around these kind of other
metrics you know to help determine and
judge quality Beyond you know this THC
number that everybody so focused on but
you know I think of the future you know
kind of total tpine content then you
know what the canab to turpine ratio is
is really going to be one of the more
important metrics that you know people
use to understand both you know quality
as well as how well something you know
how how well Turpin have been preserved
in it and then also how well that
Entourage effect kind of influence is
going to happen from that ratio of
cannaboid at turine you
know are you guys going to be testing
for the new uh sulfur containing
compounds that were recently discovered
yeah I don't think they were new
personally just my statement people have
known about them for a long time Nick
zegler said he's known for 25 years he
sent me that paper and was like he was
like whoa that's like I we studied that
25 years ago he said the beer industry
has such a deep understanding of these
thol and thoits that it's not even funny
how much more we have to learn in
cannabis that's because they don't like
them well they study them big time I
mean they studi them to avoid no that's
not true not not not yakam ma Chief hops
anyway and not the work that Nick zler
did they they were the one company that
instead of trying to um avoid their
unique differences they decided to
celebrate them and so that's why Nick
did all the work he did with thol and
thoits and Esther 1440 th he discovered
alone in hops which I've invited him
here today because it would would be
amazing to have him here uh on this
conversation because we have kind of
been discussing lately about trying to
get a group together that can discuss
these things kind of maybe create a
shared lexicon and create this sort of
sensory evaluation program that we can
all kind of you know feed into to create
something that uh could take us away
from you know these these coas that are
basically simply THC and and and
tpin yeah hear sorry no no problem I'm
I'm really curious we've been studying
these for a long time we've been aware
of them of course for a very long time
but uh it it'll be very interesting to
see how many of them are founding
cannabis how many did you just say 200
or 400 in hops
1440 is what he said Jes
Christ if there's that many in cannabis
then think about it uh and especially if
they're they act synergistically with
the cannabinoids like
THC uh it's everything just got way more
complex way more complex and when you
think of like at least from what Nick
was saying he was suggesting that some
of these thols uh are responsible for
the shift in the modulation of the
profile and so most people aren't even
paying attention to these these
compounds right now we're sort of on the
surface with canabo and Turpin so it's
exciting that the rabbit hole goes
deeper and that there are people like
you guys on the panel who will jump
right in with both feet into that rabbit
hole so I appreciate you all for
that excuse me Alex for
interrupting
speaking sorry
sorry sorry I was just gonna say we've
been doing a ton of
decarbing uh in the house and just like
putting together this amazing Sav and uh
the decarbing has been really in the
upper floors of the house has been like
full on like turpine Haven and it's been
a really interesting experiment because
we've got two cats and the cats are
fully addicted to the third floor of the
house where the Turpin are the most
proom predominant col chamber it's like
the collection chamber and they're only
getting tpin and walking
around acting so totally
crazy on all of the Persian rugs they're
like differentiating all of the
different colors on the rug FR out on
the carpet they're getting fracted out
super high just on the tping so just
wanted
to that's awesome and one one thing I
was I was just going to add kind of um
um to to Sam Sam's question or original
question on the thol yeah so you know
we've known about thol for quite some
time really Nick Ziggler put put it that
much more on my map um from the work
that they've done in on hops with uh
testing thols um we we've been we've
been working on kind of a method to kind
of be able to start adding certain uh
sueric type compounds um so we are kind
of going to be developing to that
direction but um you know even without
kind of you know THS to help do the you
know really fine Nuance sorting uh
towards the end of all the different
subgroupings that happen um we have
found that you know tracking the primary
mono Andes turpins and using them as a
as a tool to sort kind of can really
capture for the most part all the
primary smells or groups um but yeah I
think once you start getting into thols
and some of these other Trace compounds
that really kind of Define some of the
Nuance of how the subgroupings kind of
open up um you know there's so much more
to be kind of uh to be learned from that
and I'm definitely really excited for
it they're extremely potent I mean the
the human ol Factory senses are very
tuned to these molecules at extremely
low concentrations so you know that they
put an odorant in natural gas because
natural gas has no odor at all and I
think what they're putting in natural
gas Captain yeah butane th and so you
can imagine that these things are are
basically sensitive at really I think
it's like almost part per trillion
levels right so that human olda Factory
is so uh sensitive to those that these
things could be in there in just very
very Trace quantities fleeting
quantities that essentially make them
not quantifiable or not measurable on a
GC but you could certainly taste the
difference when you when you consume it
does anybody know if these compounds act
do they modulate THC or act uh do they
potentiate THC anybody
know I have a feeling Nick knows but
he's not here yet and I have invited him
and welcome to wuce who is in the house
with girls in green
Booyaka Alice will be here
shortly I knew she would if she
wasn't yeah just handling some stuff
with the do
gearing up for Legends of
hash I am I'm waiting patiently for my
jars to get here so I can get everything
packed up and send it on down with the
homies to uh get the entries in and
stuff I'm I'm pretty excited it's gonna
be a good event dude I'm not even going
and I'm pretty excited I got to admit
the amount of energy that Addison and
Kevin have put into this and the stuff
that they've kind of organized around it
I mean getting Caleb
getting KX jars for Legends of hash was
like it's just so much different and
grown out from what we created it as and
I'm uh and I'm pretty excited that
they've maintained the Integrity they've
said no to all sorts of companies that
tried to sponsor because Legends just
didn't line up with those companies and
I thought that was amazing as well so I
I kind of got to give those guys a shout
out for uh for really doing a great job
I can't wait for the event to to kind of
to get
here me too I'm can't wait to meet all
the hash makers that end up going
everyone that I've seen is going is
pretty amazing and it's gonna be a great
night I'm
excited hell yeah
absolutely I'm freezing up a little bit
so when when you guys Notice Me freeze
up just kind of keep talking as you as
you do I've got the uh the beta uh Elon
Musk starlink internet going on and we
we get a little cut out here and there
so have patience with me
everyone fair enough fair enough we'll
jump in that and Flynn I was just
wondering you you might be still be
around or not but I was just wonder what
and what some of stum strains you might
be putting in to the event or just you
know bringing some strains or how about
this Alec what are some uh new trends
and smells and flavors that you're
seeing see out of the Farms this year
that are kind of dominating or just kind
of going off this
year um well well well what's dominating
is definitely that carry offing lming
like pair like the co carry offline Ling
co- balance kind of all the desserts
that um you know in the emerald Cup last
year we saw that profile was about 54%
of all the entries across categories um
and and that and you know that the the
popularity of that profile hasn't really
slowed down and so I would you know
believe it to be close to 60 65% of the
Canabis grown in California um was
probably that profile or close to it so
you know you do
see homogenate of profiles that's kind
of happening as people are just like
kind of chasing the THC number you know
and kind of going for these Kling
dominant type um Carling lining combos
um you know it's an amazing profile but
you know it's also you know the most
over kind of grown profile at this point
so you know that's kind of where I'm
really excited for kind of the work we
do with the emerald cup and then what
we're doing this year with the state
fair which is kind of presenting
cannabis to a whole new audience of
cannabis you know novice people to kind
of really show the range of diversity of
what this plant offers and you know kind
of honor it in that way so that you know
kind of it's not just you know kind of
the you know popularity bias doesn't
just kind of sweep the cup and then have
a you know that much more of an effect
on homogenizing the herb in the market
very good our early our early research
showed that lolene definitely
potentiated
THC and modulated the
effects and with carry Al did not
particularly
yeah but that's a a different issue that
I'm talking
about Sam I had a quick question on that
you know I'm curious as to like um you
know how you kind of controlled some of
those variables did you take strains
that were high in these you know tping
profiles or equal
like P we got pure
THC 25 milligrams put in a volcano every
time uh and then we spiked it with just
a single
turpy so uh when I did that experiment
at your house I did it through a rure
bong okay yeah well I used Roars a few
times you're right but ba mostly what we
used was both thick like Brill pad pad
things that were available with the
volcano and we measured it out with a
very precise scale and we Vaped them all
identically and uh P pure THC gets you
high but with the right tpes you get way
higher how much turine did you
add oh as small as we could add a a
really tiny SP I mean we were using
pipets the smallest ones we we had and
uh we made it so that they were really
really uh uh tiny tiny
amounts well you know and and and
something I would mention too that's
where I feel like in the future there's
you know such you know such value in
this idea of the canab turp ratio right
because because what we see you know
five of the six primary Turpin cannabis
or monot turpins you know which begin to
boil off a room temperature so there
therefore the biggest spoilage indicator
of you know kind of you know cannabis
that's lost its turpine content right
and you know in so much of what we see
in the state in California you know
farmer puts their best Foote forward you
know and has all the controls to
preserve tpin in their supply chain to
the point where they pass it off but
then it goes to a distributor and in the
possession of the distributor and their
chain of custody you know pretty much
loses 60 80% of the tping content that
was there and you know in a lot of ways
is indistinguishable to the eye you know
or sided coin boat Alex because for
examp example
tpin the most you're right the monot
Turpin can be incredibly volatile and uh
significant amounts can be lost between
a living plant at Harvest and two weeks
later or even a month later after curing
Etc but uh the truth of it is I found
that cannabis is fresh it's been dried
for two weeks it could the retically be
smoked but it's really super fresh that
uh I found some really high Turing
content stuff actually gives me
laryngitis well you know and I think you
yeah I'm sorry go no no I'm just saying
so I I think some of the more volatile
ones you have to be careful about
extreme amounts of uh and
I got laryngitis every year for like
five or six years in a row when I was
living in California growing herb and
then uh I moved over here and started
making dry sift and I never got
laryngitis
again well the one thing the one thing I
was going to mention and and Sam you're
very right I think and I think that's
where you know kind of
um translation from smell to flavor and
and uh and and and the character of a
profile how it kind of translates to
smoke I mean you know certain certain
examples of an awesome IND dominant
strain kind yeah burn your send your
throat you know and so I think you know
there's a lot there to what you're
saying but but my main point around this
canab turp ratio right because so you
know so much of what we see is um you
know the the average of Turing content
flour across everything we've ever
tested over 200,000 samples is is like
1.4% average whereas the potential of
what we see whenever it's done most
optimally is three to 5 and a half% in
dried flour so you know so from what we
see the market average of tpine content
flour is is 100% to 200% of that do you
think the majority of that low 1.5
percentage is driven by genetics or by
growing or processing or all three I
think all three yeah I think all three
for sure um you know but but but my but
but the big point that I was just going
to make right is you know if you had you
know a you know just speaking in terms
of this idea of the Entourage effect and
the nuanced uniqueness that strains have
to offer whenever they are preserved
right because you know if you had a a
strain that tested like legitimately 30
35% thca but it was dried and cured like
[ __ ] and it smells like hay and it has 0
2% turpine content that's like a 90 to1
canono DET turpine ratio right and in my
opinion that's in the future what really
defines biomass right there's no other
value for that to be represented as a
flow for connoisseur consumption
purposes handy isolating THC yeah
exactly exactly well yeah and so so and
so so yeah so in an instance where all
the turpine cont is gone and the 90 to1
T canab turp ratio is there you know
there's not really an Entourage effect
that's going to be present whether if if
the tpine was originally terpinolene to
make it more stimulating or creative or
if it was higher in Meine you know it
doesn't really matter anymore because
it's 90 to1 so it's kind of absent
Turing or Entourage and so really it's
just a very THC base effect you know so
it's like the most value for that would
be to distill it you know add Turpin or
something at the end but but from what
we see right like you know kind of you
could have a strain say you know that
test 15% THC but it was dried and cured
immaculately like with tpping
preservation and ultimate like kind of
focus you know and it might have three
to five and a half percent you know
tpping content dried flow that's a 3 to1
canopo DET turpine ratio right so
whether that turpine was loning whether
that tpine was terpinolene whether that
tpine was mirene right that the
significance and the uniqueness of that
entage effect is going to be pronounced
right as opposed to that
one other question with all this
analysis
edes that
with they hav't they're not damaged
samples but they're they're done
properly and they're really primarily
just one
turpy um I mean with on on certain on
the on the end spectrums of the rainbow
with turpening or with like miring you
you see you know so many examples where
it's just really primary amounts of that
one turp you know with very subsequent
you know secondary or tertiary kind of
tpping presence but you know you'll see
the vast majority of the representation
of that of that profile would be one a
singular TP tpine but um but you know so
so again though in this example you know
I think kind of uh
um you know the the yeah just the ratio
is I think going to be one of the most
important things I'm sorry I kind of
like slightly like missed missed the
point I was going to just hit on but
that's perfectly all right yeah no I I
can I can explain why the ratio is
important is because what you're
changing when you take freshly picked
cannabis to dried cannabis is the amount
of water that's in there and so the the
percentage of the relative percentage of
tpes to to overall mass of plant changes
drastically when you go from freshly
Frozen or freshly harvested cannabis to
dried can
and so because that Ratio or yes because
that ratio change is the percent tpes
which is the percent of the valal tpin
versus everything else that's in there
well remember you're wholesaling a whole
lot of water out of there so everything
else that's in there that denominator
changes that's why you have to pay
attention to the ratio that Alec is
talking about and and and that's thank
you for bringing that up actually
because that that totally triggered my
mind right and and so you know because
and Sam that's where I kind of was going
to bring up because I mean you know I
think the translation or carryover of
like what total tarpine content might
have been
present you know kind of is totally
dependent on you know all these
conditions right like you know time of
or temp you
know being harvested under you it's like
if it's in the middle of the day versus
the middle of the night you know there's
like 20% turpine content off the top
just because of the heat of the sun and
the temperatures you're you're
harvesting under you know so many people
that Harvest commercial cannabis then
like they harvest in the middle of the
day and then they load box trucks up
with masses of herb that then kind of
sit for like 45 minutes to hours until
they kind of get transported to a place
where they can be put under temperature
control conditions you know but in so
many ways so much of what we see because
of the volatilization of these you know
really precious monot turpins you know
it's like Cann ofis really in my in my
opinion believe it it it deserves a cold
supply chain continuous Cold Supply
Chain anywhere where it's going to be in
the chain of custody of somebody that's
caring for the this par able good you
know and and and in this record year of
harvest in California and over
production you know I think it's going
to be it's very reminiscent of what
happened in Oregon a couple years back
and what really in a big way happened is
you know once everything goes to a
standstill you know kind of it's really
it really becomes that much more
apparent who has infrastructure and who
doesn't have infrastructure to even have
you know do what is the carrying
capacity of your situation to preserve
Turing content and what you're holding
in your possession because if you don't
have that ability you know then you're
kind of going to get like dusted you
know because because in in the time of
the great flood you know kind of the
averages of the or the Extremes in
quality really start dividing because if
the average is about one and a half% of
the state you know everything sitting
around it kind of really goes down to
about 1% or less you know so then if
you're at three to five and a half
percent you know you're kind of dunking
on fols you know in a big way of just I
mean I think you it's always that thing
if it's really bomb and it's really tur
preserved and it's bombing a room you
know it's always going to have the
ability to fly but if it's anything less
than that you know it's this
commoditized kind avonoid race to the
bottom game you know so I think it's
like those are the separate kind of
sides of the market it's like the
commoditized canono market and then th
those that are on the ultra Ultra side
of you know the tpine preservation game
and you know just being able to
immaculately care for what's in their
possession dude you called it with the
supply chain needing to be cold from
start to finish when I saw the cryo can
come out I thought well that's it that
if the cryo can isn't it something
exactly like it needs to be it needs to
be uh be able to be rolled into the
fields it needs to be able to you know
very quickly and very cold REM remove
and and mitigate 90 or 85% of that
biomass and just preserve the the
glandular triome heads in which case now
that becomes your feed input for any
process you're doing whether you're
doing CO2 extraction or butane
extraction or water extraction you're
pouring in resin into your reactors not
plant matter and you've kept it cold
since you took it off the field that's
my
dream yeah I think that's really
nitrogen hopefully too underground
underground containers in California I
mean are the only way you can like do it
without using crazy grid you know issues
because anything above ground in
California is just subjected to you know
so much heat and so much movement and
everything that it's and then you know
to try and put a refrigerator or units
on there it just becomes like a wild
amount of electricity and and it just
and I don't know that that's what we're
going for is like ultimate electricity
use so there's like this weird balance
of like you know trying to find passive
systems to to to flow into these modern
needs you know because we do want high
grade yeah ancient meets future though
and that's what's funny is the old
school cats always knew all along you
bury your read you know it's like I mean
funny how much it's funny how much the
old kind of knowledge really is proving
that much more true today you know just
around Farmers like all wives tales are
in Harvest times around the full moon or
just like you know times where I they're
not harvesting in the middle of the day
I mean or I mean just there was just
there's always just there's so much deep
wisdom kind of in a lot of these older
practices that I think now we getting
that much more Val idated yeah and I
just wanted to make the bridge again to
the old practices is that all of the
temperatures and the humidities that
everybody is talking about to preserve
these troms and also these plants and
herbalism is exactly what the Earth you
know below the Earth's surface and
geothermal is what it holds constant and
continuous so Mother Nature has a plan
there's a deep understanding she has she
has a knowing of how to preserve these
plants and I think that all we have to
do is very easily tap into it rather
than try to overthink it so it
is and we know that it's always the
basements of our homes that have always
dried the best flour and made the best
uh concentrate and consistent
temperatures to where the door is not
opening and it's oh it's hot it's cold
you know has to be consistent and then
you sometimes will find some herb gets
more potent in some cases after you know
four six months of not being opened and
whatnot totally big love to Mojave
Richmond in the house hey yeah welcome
Mojave brother hey everyone Thanks for
uh thanks for the invite stok to be here
yeah a good conversation I can't believe
you're here moabi I know Sam it's good
to see
you hey um guys with with the cryo
freezing you know I I've seen a lot of
uh hemp flour dried with cryo and it
kind of reminds me of
Cheetos uh when it's dried um now I I I
I understand the resin and I think we
can we can think about that in a in a
more methodical way but I I understand
where everyone's coming from we need to
preserve things but there is an optimal
temperature in range in like the time
that the flower will actually
encapsulate some of these these monot
Turpin and and really hold them in and
and I think there is a perfect place for
that to happen I I just think it's not
talked enough about and studied enough
as to when a varietal should and how
long
it found is that if you do a tpine
profile say the top 50 tpin of uh a
fresh skunk number one for example and
then you dry it for two weeks test it
again
then box it cure it for a month or so uh
test it again and then finally turine
test the resin after it's been extracted
from that same clone the you see a
decrease in the profile of
monoterpenes and uh you know the more
it's been handled processed and hung
around the more volatile ones are gone
yep yeah we see that exact same thing
you know and that's where I think really
that simple yeah and I think that's
where it's so much of the like
uh long-term preservation that people
have in for build building out their
business model you know instead of um
people kind of you know racing to grow
as much as the neighbor you know being
able to just preserve as as the highest
potential and quality you know cuz you
know even yields you know it's like if
you you know Harvest and kind of are
able to control temperatures you know
from the entirety from you know kind of
what time temperatures were being plants
were being harvested under how quickly
those plants were able to get below
temperature control conditions how
quickly or how long you know kind of
those temperatures able to be maintained
you know because that was one of the big
failed kind of uh experiments around
nitrogen packaging you know people with
nitrogen pack everybody seemed to bail
on that all at the same time you know
but it was kind of failed experiment
because everybody nitrogen packag their
herb but then just let it sit in
warehouses you know to like fluctuating
day-to-day temperature humidity all
these things you know and a year later
sure you open it up and you know it's
bomb but then it catches up in five
minutes you know but there was no there
was no continuity in the you know that
that temperature humidity you know
tained custody and so you know I think
that one added variable would have
actually probably you know given that
technology a lot of props and Alex like
what you're kind of alluding to is like
there is an amount that is too much
right that you right so I think that
that's something
that's a cold chain event all the way to
a consumer right and that's that's
something as this moves forward I I'm
starting to think about a whole lot in
terms of just resin right but at the
same time on the flip side of it the
flour is a is super problematic because
you know it's just old like you don't
want old you don't want old herb you
want fresh herb so what is that time
frame I guess is what I'm asking and and
uh you know because I've never really
looked into it I've just kind of you
know my bioassay tells me like oh this
is this is fresh this is you're right
like there's no beyond that I have
looked into it a bit never had pot that
I froze for more than a year or two so I
can't really speak on herb but resin
heads both cleaned and uncleaned so
farmers grade has it's about 30% THC
it's just resin heads but with other uh
trash in with it and then there's a
cleaned up resin that's you know in the
low 80s and it's just resin heads
nothing else
and for a decade Frozen minus
30 and you can either flush it with
nitrogen or not and uh it doesn't really
change not at
all that makes sense to me Sam but but
now we we bring bring in plant you know
we bring in a living breathing organism
right that's
drying and that it's decaying at a
faster rate than the resin toer point so
what is the you know I guess I'm just
asking that's why secret is to get it to
the point of resin I mean that is the
active whether it's recreational or
medical or whatever that is what you're
after so uh if you if you have any
way we lost you Sam least I did yeah
that's why that's why get it as cold as
possible like you said Colin we don't
want old weed we want fresh weed it's
like exactly get it as fresh as possible
do these processes so you preserve
everything and then only then make the
decision through your bioassay where you
know you have everything where you enjoy
it at different rates and because here's
the thing like someone said earlier oh
sometimes there's it's too much yeah too
much of a specific ratio but a different
ratio may not be too much so we can't
get into these generalizations of like
well I had 9% tpin one time and it was
way too too much well yeah it might have
been super high in delimine or another
costic tpine that you know osine burned
the throat or
whatever what do you got there
Mojave forgot about them Botanical tpin
non-cannabis derived and when I pulled
them out it was pretty far out they were
all the same amount inside each
container for the most part and a lot of
it volatilized you know there's
definitely it's a gummy kind of resin
left over but some of the tops were
completely corroded versus other this is
aamine and this is
lenol um and all the way across some of
them were just like here's terpinolene
which is a little bit more
corroded um here's alha pinene Which is
less corroded anyway I just think it's a
really interesting conversation about
packaging longevity you know as as our
good buddy Rob Clark always said not all
Tarpin are good tpen that they're I
think there is something with fresh weed
that is a little bit like there's this
anthropological concept of cultural
relativism which says like if a culture
decides to do something whether it's
batshit crazy or not they did it for a
reason and people traditionally really
went through a lot of effort to age
cannabis and to kind of De TP the flower
before they consumed it and I think that
that was you know definitely it was a
different world a different Market a
different ver different types of
products that are being consumed but I
think it's really interesting I think
that there are certain profiles that
improve more with age and certain
products that are more stable i' I've
froze flour for gez probably 10 years
and pulled it out of the freezer and
it's still pretty damn fresh like I've
seen stuff that was you know on the
market that was a few months old that
had been abused and abused is and the
tur profile definitely changes even in
the freezer you know and it's hard to
keep it you know completely Frozen and
sealed for that long but I think it's an
interesting conversation like right now
in California we've got this big blut
and all this flour from last year that
no one could sell and it expired and you
know they had to you have to turn it
into distillate and get a new COA on it
to extend its life and I think that
there's there's no reason why we can't
store flour for a long time and I think
that there's you know quite possibly a
good reason to not smoke fresh flour for
certain varieties and for certain you
know it's it's kind of like the Aged
wine aged cheese thing it definitely
turn it it changes in a profound way but
for some some varieties I've just
noticed you know like these these um you
know like high terpinolene varieties
seem to be more stable for instance and
then maybe that's just because the
effect of tpine on aged flour seems to
not diminish as much
um as these other higher carry offine
higher Mir scene varieties and stuff
that seem to like you get no effect
after a while or the effect is
completely diminished anyway I just
think it's an interesting conversation I
posted this thing on on Instagram and I
rarely do memes and it got a number of
people freaked out like you know you
know what's it doing to our packages and
and since Sam dude what's it doing to
your throat like when you held that up I
was like whoa that's what my throat
looks like when I take a dab of osam
well I've always Haven you always
noticed that like when you
dab residue is it's creating a corrosion
like what's well so these are also pure
tpin right okay I don't know it's this
but most Turpin are good solvents a lot
of those rubbers are are plasticized
with things called plasticizers and a
lot of times what happens is the turpine
gets into the rubber leeches out the
plasticizer there PL izers or nasty
compounds are like dioctyl phalate and
phalates and [ __ ] like that but what you
might be seeing there is just the
precipitation of the phet plasticizer
from the rubber so what what what I mean
to say is that it's nothing inherent in
the tpine it's just the tpine
interacting with this rubber that's not
suited for for but why would some tures
react that way the way osam is reacting
and others wouldn't it's just
interesting because osine is literally
one of the harshest turps on the throat
and it looks like it has the most
breakdown whatever it's breaking down
solent for the plasticizer and it's able
to draw it out or something I I I don't
know Mark it's weird interesting hey
welcome to Debbie Debbie's in the house
good morning everyone whoa really
interesting stuff to wander into talking
about this uh tpine plastic interaction
did not know that little sensory
evaluation at 955 am. Pacific Central
Time Pacific Standard Time Mojave can
you scrape off like is it like a powder
or a white residue or something or does
it is it like you say there's corrosion
like what is the material what does it
look like no it is kind of feels like
it's just gummy almost like it
precipitated like almost it feels like
it like it pass through the
Rubber and then
yeah and I can hardly open the
containers oh this one opened yeah it
would be interesting to see over a
prolonged period of time if the rubber
becomes brittle then that tells you it's
leeching out the plasticizer a a rubber
without a plasticizer in there will turn
brittle it'll it'll turn brittle and
it'll break
one no I'm saying if you've ever seen
the ball jars on certain varieties the
ball jars the Rubber seal on ball jars
starts to crack and I seem to remember
this from a tip from I don't know Sam I
don't know if I got this from you but
this is something way back in Amsterdam
I think I learned but was to throw the
rubber band in a in a jar of
flour and then pull a month later pull
it out it's the right variety like a
high Haze variety uh yes I've seen them
melt those rubber bands easily
yeah well and that's the one thing I was
going to say real quick on the test side
because we um you know um around 2018 we
we invested in like a smoking robot as
well so that that could kind of um te
you know basically pull the aerosol Vape
from a vape Partridge that's already
been aerosolized and then is capturing
that aerosol and then we're running
further testing on it so we're working
with the groups to help in like just
long-term shelf life type studies if
they're either using kind of natural
kind of derived cannabis turbines kind
of Blended at whatever proportions or
ratios um or or and or kind of groups
that are kind of just adding these
different Botanical or otherwise T other
type of turbines but we we definitely
you know I mean we have seen some really
interesting things on the corrosion side
of things with like in with with with
regard to releasing and increasing high
levels of heavy metals kind of over time
you know kind of from cartridges various
cartridges I mean there's there's all
these unknown variables about what is
actually you know in the hardware that's
leading to that but it's also this
combination of okay at what high you
know what concentration of turpine are
in these you know if you have kind of
10% lyine in there you know kind of over
time you know is it going to be leading
to more corrosion than others um you
know especially with certain types of
Hardware but these are definitely all
really fascinating questions that I
think people need to you know just take
into consideration especially if they're
formulating products and putting them
out you you might be familiar with Amber
Weiss's study that was recently
published so Amber Weiss I think is a
professor up in up in Washington and she
studied an uh a a Well published the
results of a study of something that
you're exactly addressing which is the
leeching of heavy metals in through Vape
Hardware into the uh Vape cartridge
fluid and and what impact that could
have on human safety is this actually
putting lead and cadmium and tin and all
these other nasty metals because you got
to think of any shiny metal product most
likely coming from the same Factory in
China
uh any shiny metal could be contaminated
with these other metals which you
probably don't want to have in Vape
cartridges where you're inhaling the
stuff into your into your lungs and so
Amber Weiss just recently published
paper maybe what I could do is post a
link to it
in also brings back you know again the
need to really have uh not only
oversight but the analytical method
methods like ICP and whatnot so you can
look at you know maybe what storing
cartridge fluid in these tanks for
prolonged periods of time does in terms
of introducing metal content to the
fluid themselves because vape pens
aren't going away anytime soon so the
real question is is what's the best way
to manufacture that to make sure that
not only the thing works but it works in
a way that doesn't leech heavy metals
into what you're inhaling because God
knows what the long-term impact of that
could
be I think not getting so tricky with
everything you know with the old old
school apothecaries you know have have
been dealing with essential oils for you
know hundreds thousands of years and and
they also volatize you know and and
people have used glass and glass
syringes and glass jars with glass lids
and copper and silver and these metals
are proven to be good for us and gold in
some cases you know um so we we continue
to get these new products from
modernization and then wow we found out
they're all tainted and then now all of
a sudden they're well what a shocker you
know they all these new new items coming
that are cheap and stuff are now toxic
so I think that we look towards again
you know let's not we we this the way we
get educated
nowadays forget about the past and think
that we you know we're only learning now
and there's ways that we can build from
the past and bring that into our future
packaging and stuff so you know let's
just it's pretty cool if you look at old
school Apothecary um you know boxes the
one the herbs that had the volatile oil
in it that were very aromatic also had
um um each one of those drawers was a
glass and they were kept inside glass
and then the ones that were less
volatile were kept inside of the wooden
drawers so and certain hers were kept in
the basement that they had to go down
into the basement to get it you know
depending on what it was so you know I
think it's important for us to just
remember that and also that you know um
regenerative and organically grown
cannabis and Earth grown cannabis tends
to keep its it's it's trines longer you
know than things that are aeroponically
or or hydroponically grown in some cases
maybe Alec you you you could maybe
dispute that and I I would be open you
know but I you find that a lot of times
that you know the soil grown cannabis
tends to keep its its flavor has more
Integrity in it longer and then the
medicine out of it you know can be and
that's only because of mic more
microbiology may be present and I think
that that's going to be the real bridge
that you know us as regenerative farmers
and as regenerative medicine makers are
really interested to see the science of
you know tpine all uh secondary
metabolites that are profound inside of
the plant and then what is profound
inside of the soil and what's profound
inside of the plant's endophytic system
and you know its own microbiome so
that's going our biome and our brain
blood brain barrier and the way that it
well that's one thing I've been really
really
FAS you know because with all things
equal you know like you grow the same
strain same plant different conditions
hydroponically versus regenerative
organic you know like with Elaine ing's
you know soil food web research and all
the stuff she's shown you know whenever
you do that side by-side study you can
track whenever the microbiome of the
soil is balanced to what the plant wants
you know you can track the doubling of
the secondary metabolite that that F
produces and you see that with lopen and
tomatoes you see that with various
vitamins and berries and you know with
cannibis turpins are the secondary
metabolite so you know that would go to
you know suggest that you know there's
the potential for you know regenerating
Organic Grown you know kind of optimally
organic grown cannabis potentially being
able to produce doubling of the you know
secondary metabolites you know that's
like you know there needs you know some
you know a lot of side by side to kind
of be able to demonstrate but that that
but that's really really fascinating to
me because you know from you know
there's everything you could do as a
farmer to grow the plant most optimally
and then from that point on then it's
okay then it's all about you know post
Harvest handling temperatures all these
things that you do to kind of lock in
and preserve like you know what you were
able to kind of produce you know um and
everything's working against you you
know kind of if you're working with you
know harvesting and higher temperatures
versus you know because we we've seen
groups that will kind of you know
Harvest you know kind of Frozen material
in the field you know in the middle of
the day kind of an 80 plus degree
temperatures and then you know do the
same thing at in the middle of the night
you know zombie Harvest and kind of do
that and track kind of the you know a
resin um essential oil return off the
off the extract in the yield and you see
substantial kind of difference you know
20 plus percent you know is you know up
to 20% or more kind of turb content loss
just in that you know kind of decision
of harvest time temperature so here's a
question here's a question question some
of the turpi and most ridiculous hash
I've ever made in my life has been in
Jamaica where it's like literally like a
100 degrees in the field I can't even go
in the field for more than like 20 or 30
minutes at a time or my P pasty white
ass just turns Lobster red and then I
then I can't you know enjoy myself
anymore so I'm like going in and out of
the fields every 15 to 20 minutes and
and I'm just looking at these plants and
they're so stinky and the field is so
stinky and I'm just thinking like like
holy [ __ ] like these things are off
gassing an insane amount of Tarpin right
now is it because of that process that
it's producing more because at the end
of it when I like Harve when we
harvested that [ __ ] and then ran it
through the bags and trust me we were
not keeping it cold all the way to till
they got into the bags they just they
were in like warm plastic bags or
whatever it was so turpy and I mean dude
Sam even you can acknowledge because
this was at a time where this was the
first time Sam ever smoked anything I
had okay prior to that because we were
in Jamaica together prior to that he
only smoked his own [ __ ] like it just it
was it was that good and I I'm not like
saying that he shouldn't have because
truly like that [ __ ] was from another
planet but this stuff in Jamaica was
like I want to say it was almost on
point wouldn't you agree Sam do you
remember the stuff we made from well
there was two points
number one I didn't have enough to keep
smoking just mine so but number two the
stuff we made was outrageously
good agreed it was really good I still
have pictures of it no it it was really
it it was also a a darker redder color
than the stuff grown in my Greenhouse
for example H so I I I you know Marcus I
have some thoughts on that I mean you
know Alec was bringing up like
biotransformation through enzimatic
uptake and all these things that can
happen through you know Target feedings
and kind of you know there's there's the
term you know uh just driving crop crop
steering right but you can do crop
steering with in many different ways and
it's just an ideology and then there's
the stress responses right you have
stress response that plant's giving off
in combating the environment that it's
in in most cases that is going to
directly result in the resin and that
could go good or bad that could go both
sides right you could have AET response
that stresses the plan out so bad that
it just like goes the wrong direction or
it stress response in the right
direction and it allows it to express a
profile that it hasn't really expressed
before um and I've seen that firsthand
over the years a lot um so you know I
think there's there's two ways to go
about this and there's two ideologies
here but they all kind of end up the
same place if you do the right things um
so that I think there's there's that to
think about so I don't know if anyone
has any thoughts on that as well but I
think that's you know from my experience
targeting and then also going the other
way and stressing them out um you get
some equally amazing results yeah I
frankly I agree with that and you know
one thing i' would say too is you know
kind of Marcus to the point you were
just bringing up you know know I mean
certain strains genetics have the
potential to put out certain amounts you
know just inherently like before the you
know optimal feeding and you know kind
of cultivation side of things happen you
know I mean you could have certain
strains that sure are really really high
and can aloid content but they might not
ever have the potential to put out more
than two to 3% tpine content in the
dried flour you know as opposed to other
kind of strains that might be you know
lower overall in canabo content or or
overall THC but you know might you know
kind of be able to readily pump out five
plus potential percent you know and
that's where I'm really fascinated too
about um what Colin was just bringing up
you know I think there's all these you
know like uh I don't know if hormesis
environmental hormesis or something but
just like the the plant's ability to
kind of adapt um to the kind of given
you know kind of stress responses that
that environment GR in provides you know
um and so you I think there's all these
different fascinating things to track
but and then you know but you know but
you
all things given you know each unique
cultivar has its potential of what it
can put out and you know who knows maybe
the potential or
the might be environments across the
world where it might be more optimally
you know uh able to be expressed in
certain areas but all things considered
you know strain has the potential you
know to put out a certain amount and
then like I think there's a future study
to understand okay well if it's you know
one to one so you know fungal bacterial
ratio and microbes in the soil and kind
of optimally kind of regenerate
organically grown versus hydroponic you
know can can there be this increase or
doubling of secondary metabolites you
know because then from there it's okay
the the plant is able to produce its
potential you know maybe through
cultivation methods it can be
drastically doubled or increased ver is
not but then from that point it's like
post Harvest handling is where kind of
you know we see 60 to 80% of the like
devaluation or you know kind of Step you
know and and that's what just what's
really fascinating to see you know when
we we've been on kind of bit of a not
Public Service Announcement like
sometimes I feel like chick and little
but not screaming about the skies
falling but about the turps are
volatilizing you know and you know
trying to kind of help just Empower
those we work with on this understanding
of how how like how much they need to
vet their their supply chain partners
because they could be putting the most
premium bomb herb forward you know that
they preserved 5% tping content in it
but then the time it gets the
distributor sits around a month before
it goes to be packaged you know
processed put into jars and then driven
in non-refrigerated kind of
transportation to a dispensary well now
it's at a dispensary getting rejected
because it might have like 70% less
Turing content and now now the
distributor is going back to the farmer
to try to renegotiate price you know if
it's not going if it's if it's not
getting sent back it's going into a
non-cooled vault yeah exactly into a
non-cooled vault I'm in the same boat
with you and I think in the future I
think the farmers and the the and
consumers are going to be most outraged
by how lacking T you know because people
are paying me paying premium prices for
like top you know top shelf quality herb
but if you actually look at it you know
on the you know kind of phytochemical
standpoint it's like you know 60 70%
less actually bomb than when it was uh
able to be preserved or yeah and what
does that do what does that do to not
bomb herb the stuff that the majority of
people are actually growing how about
that now now put that into that
non-cooled Supply chain and you end up
with done be way below mediocre welcome
I like that's not a good place to
compete in right now you know really
quickly I just wanted to bring up um
just the definition of secondary
metabolites it has the word metabolism
in it so when we're talking about
secondary metabolites we're actually
talking about the metabolism of the
plant and when we compare the metabolism
of a human being in warm weather warm
climates or we actually look at the
metabolism of soil when we have year
round warmth we have very high
metabolism rates the soil is constantly
metabolizing we've got tremendous
amounts of microbiology that's
tremendously metabolizing so the actual
endophytic system of the plant is going
to be at a much higher rate a much
higher metabolism and those people
understand and who are coming from the
north where it isn't sunny all of the
time that we have slower metabolism in
our soil we have slower growth cycles
and when we go to the warm weather our
metabolism kicks up and a lot of people
say hey I actually lost a lot of weight
when I went to warmer weather well that
reaction is your metabolism which is
your
microbiome so of course we're going to
have higher secondary metabolites
because when we go to warmer weather
where it's warm year round and sunny
year round we're going to have
continuous metabolizing so I just wanted
to add that damn nailed it that's
awesome thank you Alex what was the
highest T content that You' guys
found um we we see in a very small
percentage of the data for dried flour
three to five and a half% is really kind
of the the the range in that really
unique subset of data you know again one
about one and a half percent is the
average of every everything you tested
you know three to five and a half
percent is this in this other league we
see in the data this like really high
percentile of dried flower I'm pretty
sure that uh the folks at Neo showed me
something that was eight or 10 Jesus
I've definitely had that conversation
with Mark as well not I didn't see it
but he was like yeah yeah 8 to 10 I was
8 to 10 I I wouldn't want to concentrate
that is that r or dried plant
material dried plant material wow
dried Ella a quick question for you and
I'm happy to see you
hey good to see you here um what about
the difference in the turpine profiles
of Trikes and
rosin do you see much difference
um I well I mean I I don't think
I I'd be able to really speak to I mean
because we see kind of um concentrates
across you know not I haven't been able
to see kind of the divide in kind of
types you know because like a lot of
people you know submit as just a name
you know of the strain not kind of
differentiating what type of kind of
extraction it is um but okay we see it
we see that at Embark because we get
when we buy if we buy if we make flower
rosin for instance we'll get a COA from
the flower before we can bring it into
our facility oh I
froze an amount of heat for an amount of
time there is going to be amount of
alization that happens um you know but
so each each step through kind of you
know the the process of whether you're
doing solvent list or kind solvent you
know there's all these things internally
best practices that can be done to kind
of just try to optimize or minimize
optimize kind of preservation or
minimize kind of loss um but but yeah I
would wouldn't know much more about that
Marcus you had froze up if you you're
back yeah I'm not sure if I'm going to
end up freezing up again but at Embark
we have to get coas for the flower then
we make the bubble we have to get a COA
for the bubble if we want to make the
Rosen then we'll get a COA for the rosin
so we have seen we've seen all sorts of
different things from cultivars that
change very little to cultivars that
change a lot and that Tarpin that
weren't there in the beginning are there
in the end especially from like non
rosin to rosin heating them up I guess
changes them uh in in ways but um yeah
nothing that's been shocking one thing I
would say to that real quick where you
were just mentioning Marcus and you know
U I might have mentioned this before
kind of on hash church but um you know
from what we see you know kind of in the
in the you know ranking of most present
to least present and you know over 40
tpin were we're actively testing for
every time we do a test um you know
really it's these five to six primary
monot Turpin you know then there's a few
sasquat turpins like beta carene and
humulene um you know um you know some
some of these other um type compounds um
but but you know essentially what we see
is you know in in the total potential of
the plant whenever it's ripe or kind of
not nothing's volatilized you know kind
of it'll show in the rank order these
monot Turpin eses Turpin you know on but
but whenever all the primary monot
Turpin boil off as well as the sesat
Turpin boil off you know we see that you
know there basically there's a a
concentration of these really small
present turpins that were there that are
all of a sudden the the primary things
on the on the profile you know and
they're the higher boiling point tpin
that end in an O like neurol bolol guol
phol you know and so these profile these
turpins became become the profile
whenever there's an absence of the
primary compounds that are now
gone TP noids right they're not tpes
anymore sure sure yeah yeah yeah that
yeah I appreciate that yeah they're like
higher alcohol kind of based type
compounds right or you know and so but
but we we we deem this this artifact
kind of tpine profile as the swag we
call it the swag flag and the swag flag
is essentially anytime that there's you
know like about 75% total tpine content
or less and all the mono incestual tpin
are gone and the only tpin that remain
in the profile like bis blol mol gu and
phol that's pretty much the artifact
swag and the hay smell from what we can
gather swag that's wild dude that's wild
that is absolutely is that what what
you're testing due to the anerobic
decomposition that's happening whatever
the cannabis is put in is right yeah
it's it's the it's it's the artifact of
uh Pro it's the artifact Turing profile
that remains whenever you know the the
lacking uh kind of prep or the lacking
quality and kind of how it was dried and
cured stored kind of you know is you
know it's it yeah it's what you know
whenever it goes flat everything else is
boiled off and volatilized kind of those
kind of very repeatedly stay behind and
now and how we kind of came across that
is we had this outlier flag you know
that you know anytime there was a unique
turine profile that didn't kind
of that we we see with really high
accuracy and predictability it would get
flagged
for was going through all that data and
was really fast going through all that
data because I was like oh these are
where all the really unique land race
like super rare profiles are going to be
and albe it though there was you know
very unique rare amounts of profiles in
there there was a very small amount the
data and a vast majority of the data in
that outlying data set was this artifact
of schwag and you just see it so
repeatedly across thousands of samples
you know you're like oh yeah that's for
sure what that is you know so you you
literally have a profile for a cannabis
corpse yeah
totally what not to
do I if it's related but anecdotally I
have a story where a friend of mine um
resurrected some seeds that his parents
took away from him like 30 years ago and
he found them after his his dad had
passed away because they were going
through his stuff and he found this old
bag of weed that his dad had took from
like 30 years ago so he popped some of
these beans and yeah it was actually a
Panama Red uh variety and um this older
cat uh that we hang out with who doesn't
really like
you know back in the 70s and 80s before
Grateful Dead tour brought kind bud from
NorCal across the country so um I think
there is something to that to that
profile that you were talking about Alec
that that um uh uh what the mostly most
of those compounds again are turine
alcohols so so again maybe there was
something about the Aging of that and
maybe again about the way that you know
cannabis back in the 70s and 80s were
smuggled up from Mexico or wherever up
into you know where we lived in in in
Northeast and some way that flavor that
Essence that swag flag you're talking
about took this guy right back to the
60s oh man that's how we used to taste
you know he loved it
I don't miss the taste of dirt remember
when all the Cannabis just actually
tasted like dirt that was crazy or like
mold right yeah exactly with with hints
of diesel
fuel right because sometimes it packed
in in cartons inside gas tanks right and
parat yeah you know when talking when
talking about these tarpine profiles
that repeat over and over again that
Alec was me I just wonder how much the
impact of prohibition and the mentality
of how much can I get and how fast can I
get it bottlenecked us into these
particular dominant tpin what do you
guys have to think about that well I
mean it's also been subjective of the
farmer himself or herself because even
Sam has stated time and time again how
he selected certain phenotypes based on
the flavor profiles that he liked
specifically so there's also other types
of genetics that were also lost due to
our propagators who are actually
perpetrating the genetics based on what
they liked also based off of the growing
environments that they were successful
in they were so much more rare than the
how much can I get and how fast can I
get IT Crowd
though also people were consuming large
amounts you know if you think about the
volume that they were smoking in a big
giant cone or a big giant ball of hash
so the turpine to cannaboid ratios were
you know completely different than what
you're getting in a joint right and
maybe that had to do with one of the
reasons why they were kind of actively
seeking to volatilize a lot of those
monot turps was because they were going
to get a a certain volume in there and
then they're going to even higher
because they had extra THC so it's I
think it's a really interesting question
and and why they selected those
varieties for their own particular you
know their own particular needs versus
why we select varieties for our the
market um well if if you look at several
hundred years ago Mojave they were
selecting just by smoking and saving the
seeds of the varieties that got them the
highest or they like the effects or the
taste or the smell of and uh they were
incredibly successful actually if you
think about it all kinds of recreational
varieties are really
just THC only until the CBD craze
started uh it was really common to find
th only varieties especially in
Equatorial tropical varieties it was was
really extremely
common you know it's it's fascinating to
kind of you know think about the ancient
practices and selection and how you know
kind of how much I guess Brilliance of
there there was kind of through the
plant that was cultivated by the people
you know and then so much was lost in a
lot of ways from the global kind of
prohibition against this plant and
persecution against this plant and kind
of paraqua and kind of just uh you know
I'm really curious on you know what that
those eradication efforts did to you
know the the Rarity kind of of of
cannabis certain profiles that might
have kind of been lost forever that you
know could have potentially provided
medicine for the future of you know
needs that we don't even know we need
yet you know and so it's really crazy to
see how much that prohibition and kind
of uh you know um to be honest Alex to
be truly honest I think we've lost more
by
D types who think they're doing a favor
by taking equatorial seeds to
Afghanistan or Afghani SE genetics to uh
tropical
equator BAS
although neither one of them canis any
good right well I guess I guess it's
kind of like planting like eucalyptus
and random areas and it becoming an
invasive species kind of thing is that
what you're saying it's tainting the
gene pools of the
unique now because under
supposed to share it with the government
there the the same government for the
last 50 years is have been Prosecuting
cannabis Growers and destroying cannabis
so I mean what is the world I really
don't know
anymore and I think that that really
could be bringing in the conversation of
like what's invasive and what's being
traveled and what you know like there's
certain areas and
region species because a bird brought it
there and because the soil and the area
and the environment were perfect and
because the nature called that
particular plant to that area and Zone
and it just so happens that a lot of the
hippie types from the 60s and 70s that
were trading the seeds were the ones
that were in and humans have always
traveled and we've always had
relationships with seeds and especially
especially with psychoactive plants so
whenever something Sparks us then of
course we want to share it it's part of
our Collective Consciousness as human
beings so I think it would be hard to
say just the hippie types if we look at
all of humanity because then we're
looking at the cannabis plant having
changed multiple times into multiple
different facets for multiple different
reasons that are unbeknownst to us
because it wasn't even scribed at that
time so I think just to pick aside just
one
particular generation of the plant
really isn't giving the plant its full
volume million years understanding of of
its full potential I appreciate that I
just real quick I just wanted to say I
really appreciate that and I was gonna
say God bless Terence M for bringing the
iosa vine bopis CA to Hawaii and how
much that uh that plant loves growing in
that environment and how much it's now
really helping in the kind of global
kind of re replanting and kind of you
know kind of and just the idea of
sustainably how we kind of are able to
grow these plants you know without
depleting you know um various regions of
the world and the Amazon and um but just
uh from a biocultural conservational uh
effort you know how you know be you know
yeah I appreciate that perspective well
I think you know we're stewards of the
plants you know helping the plants
spread it's it's
maybe sorry I say it's maybe not it's
not the hippies it's what the other
thing Sam mentioned it's the airplanes
we can blame it on the
airplanes airplanes right and also I'm
not sure cannabis is 400 million years
old I mean it may be it's possible but
uh iors are scientific proof for that
400 million year old age the endoc
canabo system is older than the the
endoc canabo system came before the
cannabis plant right but another point I
just wanted to make on on this whole
hybridization is that um it's the
Natural Evolution of organisms to want
to spread themselves and disperse
themselves as far as they can to be as
as as successful and but at the same
time it's the isolation that creates
diversity you know they had this right
and you want to try to preserve that
diversity if possible exactly there's a
really great movie or documentary and
book called the um the Journey of man
about 10 years ago or so and it was
about collecting you know the the data
on the human genome and the the point
that was really interesting at the end
of this documentary they they kind of
you know they they went around the world
and they found all these points where
where um human populations would diverge
and and and um come together and they
they they literally found the story of
how our genetics moved around the earth
right we now know that we know we came
from Africa into Central Asia Europe
blah blah blah in North America but they
couldn't have gotten that
data any later than when they did
because all those populations had all
Blended and there was no original
pockets of all these different um
genes and and that's what happened with
cannabis you know we we spread out but
then all of a sudden we spread out and
we we isolated and became um unique but
then we all Blended up again you know
and it's kind of like the and you best
examples of that is Mexico Jamaica and
Morocco there are no land races left in
those dogs right dogs we have we have
all these muts in the world running
around right right it's nice to have
Afghans and
Chihuahua yeah and it's important to
think about for culture and for just uh
you know diversity in our own biology
how important it was for us to stay
separate for so long before we started
blending you know and the blending part
is kind of inevitable because of the
airplanes and because of the way our
culture is connected and stuff like that
but were we ever separate if we were
supposedly all from
Africa back together and now we're
mixing again because Evolution needs it
I think it doesn't work to be isolated
that's the whole entire point of
isolation like
isolation is not life even in the case
of well I mean you know cultures living
in certain areas for thousands
obviously that's successful and
beautiful but then you know
modernization happens people travel they
move the world changes so I think that
you know bringing right now we're at a
point of you know needing biodiversity
and cultural polyculture and you know I
guarantee a bunch of the Afghanistan
families that came over you know in this
last flux probably have maybe some ganja
seeds on them and you know what I
wouldn't say we're mad about it
I'm not sure that the Neanderthal people
would agree with
you well I don't know you
know I think that I think that the
intuition here is that we are trying to
explain something that a plant has been
doing so we are trying to take this
human idea of what is best for the plant
through our own experiences of what is
best for the plant
and it's just very interesting of our
explanations of Natural Science and what
we think is best in our own relationship
with this plant and that's really what
it comes down to because so many of us
have these different relationships with
the plant whether it be only science or
whether it be only nature and it's like
this human brain expansion that is us
trying to explain it in our language so
that we can have a good experience with
it so prop it so we can have a good
experience with it and it's all just
really interesting and I just wanted to
say that all of it is so incredibly
valid because our brain is like the
filtration system of how it's all going
to be spit out and how we're all going
to understand this great microcosm of uh
nature basically and how it interacts
with us definitely in favor of saving
biodiversity both in plants animals
people I mean I I I can think of nothing
more boring as us all being the same
there's even a song I think it goes
wouldn't it be real drag if we were all
the
same dude now that's an episode where
both skunkman Sam and I have
sung you don't get that every hash
church I also have one other thing to
say um shout out to Terence McKenna I
heard Alec drop his name earlier I was
in the other room cutting my kids some
apples and cucumbers but it was just uh
terence's would have just been terence's
75th birthday on November
16th uh huge inspiration in my life you
know like really set me off on a path
and I always drop this whenever
terrence's name gets brought up my
all-time favorite lecture by him uh is
called psilocybin in the sands of time
uh I'll put it into the description link
so uh anyone that wants to go check that
out can it is uh a doozy oh I I was
hoping to get a screenshot of that
picture you shared I I'll send it to you
bro thank you that's really rad I
appreciate that it I wanted say
something to uh Sam you were saying that
you know that we're all the same I think
that it's pretty interesting just a
little fact is that when you look at our
DNA we're like
99.9% all the same when you look at our
microbiome we're
99.9% different so I think as long as
microbiology is going to be alive on the
planet there's always going to be you
know incredible amounts of
divers I agree V love
differance Viv differ hey if you all
allow me I would like to just shine a
light on the subject that is the passing
of Antonio Scot I don't know if you all
know who he is but he was one of my
favorite drug researches he wrote the
history of the the the general history
of drugs he was a philosopher a Spanish
philosopher and he just passed away I
just read the news he was 80 so if you
could all just like send some love to
him he was one of the people and when I
read his book that I realized that I
wanted to study drugs I'm not kidding so
if you could just share some love to the
guy he was one of the first well-known
anti- prohibitionists that really spread
words about
it all right thank you for
that what was his name again Antonio
escohotado he wrote a book on the 80s
and 70s about the general history of
drugs like I remember that I used a
bunch of my in my thesis and it's very
nice like it's ve it's very nice to read
it like it's a very good flow of on all
the substances and definitely he did one
of the big Publications on anti-
prohibitionism so he was was a real
fighter and he passed away with 80 today
so we're very thankful for his existence
I'm sure that without him a bunch of
other people wouldn't have been fighting
against prohibitionism
our our condolences as a collective to
the great and hard work that they do and
perpetuate much love and great
respect yeah absolutely I raised my pipe
to all the Fallen Soldiers and uh all
the ones that are still
here it is this someone just mentioned
someone just mentioned in chat these
these Church episodes is how wisdom can
propagate I do love when you guys share
you know any type Dr you know drop the
people of the names of the people that
have inspired you books that have
inspired you it's just a great uh source
of information for people and sorry
whoever was about to go can speak now
all good all good I was wondering what
varietal uh you will be bringing down
that you really liked this year uh Flynn
and Alice to the legends of hash and
also I was wondering what you thought
about the five degree shelf temp on the
freeze dryer and if you guys have gone
for that or or you
seen FN talk about the freeze
Dryer no I I don't usually go that low
on the freeze dryer I don't know I like
to keep my Cycles so that they're done
in like about 24 hours because usually
we got more trays to put in there and
how much can you max out on a freeze
dryer like that in 24 hours what will
you pull out of the freeze dryer in
total
weight uh I mean it depends on the
freeze dryer like the XL Pharmaceuticals
actually take a little bit longer than
24 hours sometimes they're a little bit
more like 30 but uh usually you can get
like 8 to 1200 grams in there pretty
well and get it all dry kind of depends
on the strain though too if you're going
to get it dry in that amount of time
some things take a bit
longer or if you don't load it perfectly
and you get a little thickness in one
corner because your trays aren't even on
the thing or they're not level and then
it takes longer to all that type of
stuff totally I always found I couldn't
get much more than a kilo uh into those
freeze dryers lab conco a little bit
more but lab conco is not really a
freeze dryer you want to leave overnight
because once it Cycles it dries much
much faster than the other ones but it
doesn't hold a cold temperature like uh
Harvest RS and freeze dry Co and uh you
know those other those other units it's
an interesting game the freeze dryer
game because I thought initially I
wanted big freeze dryers and then I
realized no I want to be specific to
cultivars the regulations in Canada I
can't mix cultivars I could never wash
two different things and put in the same
freeze dryer so suddenly it became
really not that valuable of having a
giant mil Rock freeze dryer that I could
fit 50 kilos of bubble into because I'm
not going to be making 50 kilos of any
one variety any anytime soon so it's
kind of what I found at home we never
ever feel the whole fridge I feel like
it at least because what we wash in the
house is different than like in a up up
in Humble when we watch like 15 to in a
day we'll watch 40
kilos of wet material so that ends up
being a hash on a you know three to 5%
yield so yep yeah we do the same thing
with I mean we're getting now into fresh
frozen but the same equivalent amount of
of cured and dried flour which would
probably be you know eight or
nine and Josh asked about the variety
we're taking down I don't know I don't
know if we can speak about it can we
yeah I don't know I guess say so we can
I mean I think we're okay okay that
makes
sense I'm not sure can we tell you one
thing we're definitely not bringing
rosin and anyone who does hey you're
gonna hear from me I'll tell you
that we make fun of it because it's
Legends of Hesh right I'm like it's
funny when people bring Ros into a
Legends of hes it's better to well you
know what we just have to create
division no matter how good and anything
is we have to create division where
human beings it's impossible not to do
and so if we didn't if we didn't build a
fence and then look over and be like
your grass is different than my grass we
wouldn't be human
beings that's true that's true it's all
in good
fun oh yeah trust me it's not it
actually gets violent and insane and
some people have made it their mission
to make that a big deal like believe it
or not there's there's some people that
are absolutely not just in good fun
they're actually up sat and and
borderline uh raging uh Karen Style no
offense to anyone Nam Karen that isn't
we are here just making jokes nothing
being serious no no I I I get the be I
get all the behind the scenes stuff so I
can let you know that that particular
joke has more depth than you may know uh
to to it I'm just letting you know I I
personally what I said to Addison when
he was telling me about a couple of
people who were quite upset about it uh
because they you know people love to
think they know what Legends of hash is
about but there's only two people in
this room that actually founded the
legends of hash dinner so there's really
only two people that know what it's
about and it can be about whatever we
want it to be about because it's our
event and we'll miss you you won't be
there well I'll be there on video only
and I'm hoping Sam's going to appear as
well well at least uh uh Sam I am
there yeah we're so sad that we're not
going to be down to and I just wanted to
say like because you know the the the
word division was brought up and I felt
like it was an opportunity to jump in
and I feel like if we're going to be
bringing uh you know the word cannabis
into this and we're going to be
partaking in cannabis and you know we
talk about poly culture and we talk
with this plant Med medicine to evolve
out of separatism to evolve out of this
Division and diversity I I just think
that we can be done with that and I
think that no no not a reflection at all
to what talked about just a just an idea
that humanity is using division so much
right now and I just felt like a good
opportunity to come in and say that
polyculture and inclusion with diversity
is absolutely important on this planet
and we see that in in beautiful farms
and we see that where plants just don't
have any maladies or any sicknesses we
see it where there's full health and
balance and I feel like that's where all
of humanity needs to head to and when we
look at nature that's what's happening
and I think that we can do away with
that diversity and we can start division
do away with the div division diversity
sorry do away with the division and I I
would just like to add like I we've seen
natural people and herbalists and people
that do herbal medicine that are really
really healthy
and you don't really get to be that
person and go in society in certain
places right now I find that hard to
understand but I give thanks for the
journey yeah and we're just anyway just
let's let's let's let's come together
people that's the next Evolution the
plant has Evolution we talk about the
plants Evolution all the time and we
need to talk about our human evolution
in this time as well love y'all very
well put Kelly thank you and I certainly
didn't mean any offense to Flynn or
Alice I just uh that that joke does have
more depth to it than most will know and
I let I say that to people just so they
can know that there are people kind of
behind the scenes in anything and
everything that just want to stir [ __ ]
up and so yeah do with that as you will
I'm uh going to enjoy a
dab of some beautiful hash Rosen I hope
that uh it's uh I hope that it'll be
accepted here on hash Church even though
it's not rosin you got to
remember you got to remember that you
can make rosin out of both dry sift
hash or dry sift resin or water sifted
resin and you can make rosin out of that
so I guess we've got two categories dry
sift rosin and water shift rosin and
fresh frozen rosin and and fresh plant
rosin you can just take it off and wish
it I thought he was you can make rosin
out of hash but you can't make hash out
of Ros
[Laughter]
oh Dr Mark with the mic drop nailed it
well if Frenchie was here he would find
a way for
you uh very much in accent
much love Kim much love Frenchie we miss
you we miss you a lot indeed I was
actually um when we when you were all
discussing the turps and I was asking if
there was a difference between the
rousing the turs in rousing and the
turps in hash I was thinking of what
Frenchie was always saying about press
to activate and going back to the
history of hash that everyone presses
hash before they smoke like everyone
just like making that little ball in
their hand or creating calluses in their
hand just like pressing the hash before
smoke before putting it in a Chillum
before putting it in a pipe and US
pressing Flags nowadays like before we
dab so this culture was still lingers
and I was wondering if you could test
that like if you could just test the
sample like the fresh sample and then
after the hand press what is the brief
change that that would happen I would
love to know that like I I could tell
you this much that both uh and I'm
speaking for Marcus but I think I'm
speaking correctly both Marcus and I
like can avonoid
content and it increase the surface
vaporization
area one thing I would add to um just uh
as a thought you know um something that
we see in fresh plant material before
it's gone through drying and curing um
you there's actually some like there's
almost like a very Trace signature of
various residual solvents that are
endogenously produced solvents that the
plant kind of puts out um kind of things
like even acetone at very Trace levels
but um you know I I you know we've we've
been um we've been we've been internally
discussing kind creating kind of like a
a live resin live Rin type um you know
kind of uh you know you know
certification type I not certification
just almost like stamp you
[Music]
know people are trying to you know I the
whole the whole Market is is um yeah
there's just people that want to
authenticate basically whenever
something's been live or fresh extracted
from the plant and so we've been we've
been like looking at we're starting to
kind of look at side by sides of um and
and doing trials with various groups of
um basically measuring kind of tpine
content and residual solvent content um
across um various extraction and harvest
batches to measure um you know basically
what kind of happens and and what what
kind of certain things are being
expressed in live plant as opposed to
once the drying process happens because
even though in the drying process if you
optimally do it you know you very much
minimalize and lock in the total you
know tarpine preservation or profile but
there are these other things that you
know seem to be happening like the these
Trace solvent levels ball flies to go
away you know kind of in this drwing
process and so you know trying to
understand more about that you know what
part of plant is actually producing is
it is it the uh the uh tricomes that are
producing them or is it other parts of
the
plant it's a really good question um but
you know it does seem like uh you know
kind of even human body kind of we we
you know I mean just a natural you know
physiological process within the plant
or process with human to kind of you
know generating these various kind of
Trace kind of
solvents I'm not a scientist sorry
malbergs work says that uh triome
accumulation is after it's synthesized
in the in the triome itself so he kind
of broke down where the cells are that
the the tpes are made where the cells
are that the phenols are made and how
they come together in the cannaboid
biosynthetic pathways I think most of
that is actually pretty well worked
out as as far as I know that's true it
was Kim and malberg who did that work
yep yeah Professor Kim that's right
that's right and I think Markus re or
mentioned an interesting little
structure in there these things called
vacul which are basically little storage
vesicles within the cell that uh that
migrate to the surface of the triome are
are Plastics and vacols both not
organel uh no I believe they are yeah
that's what I thought so one produces
phenols one produces the hydrocarbons
the Tarpin these are the building blocks
for cannaboid
production right well it's again the
isoprenoid pathway is endogenous in most
plants it's it's how the plant builds
cell walls there's so many different
other structures that it uses it just
you know it's it's an economy of carbon
that you know the plant has figured out
over the time course of evolution how to
make exactly all the structures that it
needs to survive thve tank J for that Al
in terms like cure going from hash to
rosin to to cured Rosen you know I would
I would say that there's a there's a
distinct difference from one another
however they resemble one another at the
same time and it's not only in texture
but also the chemical properties that
are present because of the curing that's
happening and whatever path you choose
on that curing process whether you you
choose to add heat or not will also
contribute to those things so I think
there is Nuance however like art it's uh
you know these these mediums are are
very similar to one another they just
it's on how you approach it awesome I
want to say this about pressing hash in
your hand it's so fun you guys to have a
little bit of hash and to be able to
press it in a ball and squeeze it and
feel it and smell it I think that that
Joy of doing that gets me more high when
I smoke it you know what I mean I become
intimate with my product and I start to
really get excited so I think I yeah I
think I just surf off that so maybe
that's why people do it because we like
it it's fun I'm more like did you wash
your hands did
you endoc canabo system that when we
chew our food the saliva is the very
first parts of absorbing it and when
we're working with our our herb and
we're touching it and we're putting our
DNA into it and maybe we're softening it
not even only intentions you know who
knows what science will do but of course
it's the first part of
metabolizing that particular plant and
that the that
gonna like devote a couple of big trees
to just Charing all
day he like you know it's a lot of work
and we were talking about for a while
and just you know really cherishing
that that hash and that resin that you
get after so you know in your you know
Endeavor there's a lot of really special
things you can do to keep the Cannabis
medicine sacred for you in your
community I will say this about that um
hashtag never touched I'll never forget
being at a Legends of hash dinner and
this guy before the dinner came up to my
booth and showed me this beautiful piece
of like glistening caramel I was just
like oh my God it looked like full melt
he had hand rubbed it right so he I'm
like dude with that you get in you get
to buy a ticket so he ended up at
Legends I never knew this guy he was a
total random stranger I met and just was
like this guy needs to be at Legends he
hand rubbed like 10 grams of [ __ ]
hash so we go to Legends I'm sitting
with Todd McCormick and his buddy amelo
who owns the Trippy Stick company the
vaporizer company so these guys are like
they meet him right away because he sits
at our table he doesn't know anyone else
there except me and he's like hey guys
try some of this and so they put a
little bit in their Trippy Stick and and
I also tasted it and I have to admit
like I don't know if he was warm and
sweaty but it tasted like feet like it
was the we laugh about it to this day
like it was so bad I was just like oh my
God like you probably might have been
there and you you if not you definitely
have heard this story but well I've I've
heard the story of it tasting like
absolute human dude trust me and I am
not like making this up I was like
stoked for the guy the hash looked
beautiful it was completely void of any
plant matter contaminant but I'm telling
you this was not a turpine profile like
this was this was some human interaction
low in tpin but it was low in THC yeah
but it was high in uh
bo well I'd like to take my and my ke
together and smoke them together so I
kind of like why not
both you know what I I can appreciate
Debbie's making the hash I used to love
playing with hash and you know that's a
great way to sort of put nervous energy
into just rolling up a piece of hash but
I'll tell you that guy at that Legends
ruined it for me now I'm just like o
don't touch the hash like hashtag never
touch don't touch it oh can I touch that
no you can't touch the hash that's just
me I appreciate what Jos and Kelly were
saying too I I don't know when you were
in India Marcus if the Indian police
were checking we were up in the
Himalayas and they were checking the
sadu hands to see if they had hash
calluses on them if you've been rubbing
hash and you had a horseshoe shaped
callus on both your hands then they
would uh uh hassle you and maybe
threaten to arrest you or you know
brutal use the well and I had one for I
don't know six
months growing up in rural Louisiana
when I was a kid we' get pulled over by
the cops and they would ask to smell our
fingers I didn't know why because I
didn't smoke pot because it was all
joints back in the day turns out they
were smelling our fingers to smell if we
were out in the cane field smoking
joints
damn guys living under and
big to not love well two things about
India I mean they repealed the farm bill
in India which is really huge the
farmers have been fighting for their
rights as farmers and food producers in
India for well over a year now and it's
it's a
phenomenal um movement of hu of human
power to and vanana Shiva and all the
work that that's gone into you know
small farmers producing better quality
stuff at a at a larger rate you know
there's a lot of really good teachings
in there um so that's really important
but also on the Cannabis front in India
it's really bad right now and they're
just mowing down Fields all over India
right now and trapping people and um the
the laws are really really bad in India
and we're we're goingon to have a
conversation with hemp FTI um later on
tonight or in the next couple days she
lives in Milana she's been in Milana for
the last two years uh beautiful woman
you know doing incredible work and uh
you know she's just been really wanting
to get people's attention on to you know
what's happening in India is pretty
severe on the Cannabis front right now
so everyone heads up if there's anything
you can do out there you know to make
some change or someone you know in the
realm you know it's it's an important
thing right now because we're talking
about Origins and we're talking about
respecting your elders and and cultures
of where it came from and now some of
those places are Under Fire and they're
just taking brush Cutters and just
mowing down giant fields and stuff and
it's pretty hardcore
so sorry there they're targeting Indian
uh celebrities too I see that they're
taking down all these people at the high
levels to just scare the crap out of
everyone in India it makes no sense when
the rest of the globe is moving in
another Direction yet here one of our
places of origin for the cannabis plant
is behaving like that it's
anti-scientific anical as far as I'm
concerned and Germany this week let mean
look at Germany Germany's going to
legalize cannabis which is a huge
signifier for the EU uh but at the same
time going back to what uh Michael crowz
and and a group I'm working with that
the United Nations are doing I mean we
already uh got uh cannabis removed from
schedule 4 so actually medical cannabis
is legal and Indians could be fighting
at the UN regarding International uh
specifically and medical cannabis groups
in
India and we will also be back in Vienna
in March uh working on drug policy as
well we're going to have a group of us
in New York and a group of us in Vienna
so we're working on
that other country that we hear about in
the news a lot these days China do you
know what China's policy is towards
cannabis not friendly don't get don't
get caught with it yeah they they got in
touch with Canada's government and said
we don't want our citizens using medical
marijuana using recreational marijuana
like made a statement government to
government about Chinese kids okay for
the synthetic Labs over there there to
basically be making fentel and dumping
it in Mexico where it basically comes
through the border and ends up in in
basic well yeah it it there's a lot of
things that don't make sense like when
we were had that Chinese or the Japanese
fella there who was looking at what like
30 years for smoking a joint or
something like that makes no sense at
all when you consider all of the
business the picks and shovels
businesses that are in China and that
are in Japan that are greatly benefiting
from what's happening with can cannabis
across the
globe 30 years for a joint it's a good
thing he wasn't smoken a bong they would
have given him
50 and and
it's in Singapore just got two I think a
a death penalty for two pounds of weed
just just
recently that's fascinating that China
right don't you think that I think
that's really fascinating that China
took that approach as as such a like
autocratic in control kind of you know
the I mean because cannabis and I would
imagine all the other psychoactive
entheogenic plants and plant medicines
of the of you know around the world are
so subversive to their narrative
and see how
much in an autocracy they need to
control the way people think and if
people can basically grow own medicine
and think for themselves and autocracy
can't exist so it does get political but
what makes you like when you're just
kind of looking at the world cannabis
economy right you're looking at the
world cannabis economy you're like I
need to make a bit of money what makes
you think like you know what I'm going
for Singapore it's the biggest bang for
my buck it's like no listen just not
even making a joke these [ __ ]
are not [ __ ] around they have giant
Zero Tolerance you know signs death
Penal like the whole n yard like I
wouldn't even go renew my Visa there
when I was in Thailand people were like
we're all going down to Singapore to
renew our visas and I'm like oh well
have fun with that like I smoke hash
every single day like it's probably on
me right now stuck to me somewhere that
I don't even know if not for sure I have
enough in my bloodstream to get like 20
or 30 years so I never fcking Mar the
whole world is changing who knows before
long even Malaysia might be growing
marijuana for people as medicine
anything's
possible at at the at the MJ biscon in
Vegas a couple weeks ago I did meet a
couple uh folks from mainland China who
are mostly over looking at uh CBD and
CBD type products but they were
absolutely floored I don't think they
expected to see the level of THC
products that there are available and so
these guys I I think think if I had them
characterized right they own a bunch of
bodegas in in New York City the New York
City area I think mostly like queens and
Brooklyn and these bodegas are basically
you know small little uh you know uh
shops to get sandwiches you know sodas
you know bags of chips and stuff like
that but they sell everything they sell
newspapers they sell all kinds of stuff
and so now they want to basically start
selling CBD but they were totally Adam
it like it's been put into their head
that you know any THC associated with
these products is totally bad and I
think it's because of their culture and
it's because of where they come from but
I think now they recognize the financial
opportunity that exists and now they're
probably going to go back to their folks
and say hey man we can make CBD and or
sell CBD products but ultimately people
see let's you know people want
and so they were really interested in
hhc and Delta 8 and all these other you
know non THC canabo but as soon as you
mention THC it's like oh put the brakes
on that we're not into can't no no no no
can't do that no full spectrum anything
only these other things so well that's
that's what's so magical about this
plant too it's so subversive just by its
nature you know and and so are luring
for all these ways that you know all you
know are you know ultimately kind
persuade one one group or another but
you know I think like whenever it really
comes to so much of the potential of
this plant the greatness really comes in
the phyto remediation that this plant
can do and and and and potentiate and
accelerate and and I think as a
strategic National resource and
strategic Global Resource as you know as
this you know just information comes
more and more I mean just the you know
the necessity that every country you
know for their own sustainability has to
kind of clean up and you know restore
their soil is you know I mean you know
ultimately hemp's going to
win and hopefully help subvert the whole
kind of brainwash out there free a free
enterprise itself these are Chinese
businessmen they just want to make money
that's all they care about is return on
investment return on and so I think in
their mind they're re-educating
themselves based on what they see in the
US market they have people walking into
those stores asking for Delta a products
asking for CBD products so all they know
is that there's a market we better go to
this trade show line up some supply
chain agreement start getting those
products into our 150 bodegas that we
have in around the New York City area
because this is just going to be like
this isn't going away right and the
interesting thing again is that if you
look at what's happening with some of
the minor cannaboids it's really it's
taking a different route in every state
because some states are outright Banning
you know Delta 8 and and and banning hhc
and all these other things that you can
make but other states are are choosing
to regulate those underneath their Delta
n licenses and so it'll be interesting
to see how that shakes out because it's
almost like there's a different program
a different regulatory structure in in
every state hey Dr Mark um since you
know so we we hung out at mjbiz and I I
wanted to ask you because I knew that
that the Del to8 was going to come down
in the federal ruling and they were
going to start to allow this and we we
both kind of share the same ideology it
seems that it's extremely dangerous to
do things like that um how do you
feel that ruling affects where you know
the hemp industry is at today allowing
Delta a to be now now in the the supply
chain well first of all it's only made
possible through the Ridiculousness of
prohibition itself right so if Delta 9
wasn't prohibited there would be no
market for Delta eight y Delta eight is
just because well okay people want to
get
high CBD but these people could
basically make CBD like there's no
tomorrow finding out that there's no
market for it they convert it now to THC
in this case Delta 8 and now you can get
people high here's an interesting Trend
you're starting to see people making
Delta 9 from hemp and they think it's
legal but in in in my mind and again
maybe not just my mind but I think the
way the the law works is that you know
the exclusion of THC in the uh
controlled dangerous substance act has
tetrahydro canabidol including Delta 8
including dronabinol including Delta 9
they're all categorized under code
7370 and while I don't agree with first
or schedule one listing of of THC
because it's not dangerous so it doesn't
need to be controlled that's where the
government has it like it or not and
until they move it out of there you need
a THC license to sell these products
legally now the the conundrum is is that
they're all being made from hemp derived
starting material so you have hemp
processors largely operating in an
unregulated environment with no
regulatory oversight whatsoever in the
most cannabis unfriendly States like
Tennessee and Alabama and Mississippi
but even in cannabis friendly States in
Colorado for example there are a lot of
hemp processors now who are making these
other can avonoids because there's a
market for but a lot of that market
again I don't think it was ever the
attention of Congress when they passed
the farm bill to enable the production
of a psychoactive substance that's why
they put the whole thing about THC it
had to be 3% I don't think the
intellectual furnaces were burning hot
enough to understand that mulam and
Adams and all these other people well
they figured out you could convert CBT
to THC we knew that because we knew the
literature and I was like well this is
just waiting to happen I started seeing
then hhc and everybody started bringing
my phone off the hook saying hey aren't
you the guy that patented hydrogenation
how could these guys be hydr you know
how so what they were doing is they're
now converting their Delta 8 which again
remember is code 7370 on control
dangerous substance it says you need a
license the license of those those
businesses is all under mostly
vertically integrated Delta 9 B
Delta Eight's probably fine and hhc is
probably fine too but the way it's being
produced right now is probably not the
safest for for human consumption I think
that things are moving along pretty
quickly but we we have a patent on hhca
not on hhc and so all these hhc
producers I think are just taking their
Delta 8 which again is listed in the
control danger substance act
hydrogenating it converting it to
hhc and people seem to really like hhc
the hhc introduction at least across the
hemp markets have been pretty successful
these guys are making a lot of money
selling it and um yeah that's it well
out here we're not seeing a in the Bay
Area at least those CBD shops all around
like I've seen other places when I've
left town um because we got dispensaries
everywhere and they just changed the uh
state law that's going to say now we can
sell at dispensaries the hemp derived
CBD and uh T what what's other Delta 8
um but they haven't finished putting the
regulations in but I'm pretty sure
that's just because they want to take
the tax off the top of that but that's
pretty big that's a pretty big decision
right Debby that's kind of like I think
from what I understand tell me if I'm
correct here so the thing that the um
the charlott's web people tried to do
federally with the FDA in allowing
CBD from Industrial Hemp to be allowed
as a new dietary ingredient
or no I think Gavin new said [ __ ] you
yeah
that in California to get these minor
con avonoids uh to Market is is that
right yeah I think that is right they
just haven't put the regulatory scheme
together yet so we don't know what it's
going to look like when they start
showing up at our shops or how we're
going to be able to sell it or anything
like that yet but yeah I think
California is doing the smart decision
um bucking sort of that Federal Trend
and just doing what needs to be done so
we were I didn't even know it was
happening so just one day the ruling
came out yeah you know and a little
background on that too and before get
into that like Mark one point you were
me bringing up though because there's
all the CBD shops you know kind of that
are everywhere but like Delta 8
cartridges and hhc CES and stuff you
could go into most head shops kind of
just like random kind
of style kind of like some vape shops or
head shops and you find them pretty
accessibly Way Beyond kind of just the
centralized CBD shops that pop up just
really selling CBD type products you
know so that's that's a whole
fascinating issue and dilemma um that's
that's you know going to play out
interesting ways but but on the hemp
bill um you know it's been really
fascinating because you know for the
last you know um many years now two
three years there's um you know been
basically the hemp bill that tried to
get pushed through you know kind of
really without any regard to public
health and safety under the guise of
industrial hemp kind of just kind of
having testing regulations around TC
which seemed really as a Trippy kind of
big a subversion type of the whole Space
and uh California farmers in the
licensed space were like Homie don't
play that and um basically shot it down
each year you know because you know how
why do people growing the same plant you
know because most people who growing
Industrial Hemp aren't gr are not
growing industrial H 95% of those people
are going type three drug cultivars of
cannabis you know and under the guise of
industrial hemp but are growing it that
much more in industrial agricultural
areas where there's that much more
contamination potential of pesticides
and metals and all these things and so
you know kind of there's this wildly
kind of unregulated use of the word hemp
and what it's actually being used for
whether it's medicine drug supply chain
or whether it's like actual industrial
fiber for you know processing into all
these other things um and so California
kind of this year passed you know AB 45
to establish um uh you know kind of For
the First Time Cannabis you know or hemp
um products in the licensed supply chain
and kind of essentially allowing for you
know kind of other states to get you
know kind of CBD products into the state
but they put in place a level of parity
with the can you know Cannabis Testing
regulations for licensed cannabis you
know with regard to all these points on
public health and safety um you know and
so so it's a huge step forward and there
you know that's going to be you know
playing out and I think that's really
going to help set a national standard
for at which hemp should be tested um
you know um especially if it's going to
be making you know made into like
medicine supply chain for Pediatric
epilepsy kids cancer patients dietary
supplement world of you know kind of you
know this canabo these cannaboids but um
but the you know it's it's it's it's
it's hardly kind of on the same playing
field or level with regard to you know
kind of um you know batch a requirement
I mean there's there's um you know kind
of testing requirements in place but
there's not really a you know supply
chain regulated supply chain you know in
any way for
him do you guys have an analytical
standard for hhc
Alec no um I would love would love to
talk with you more about that really
apprciate I appreciate your Insight also
you you you have a very very nuanced
very specific understanding of this
whole thing that is really far beyond
I've been running around the internet
basically correcting all these bogus
articles that people are writing on
right hopefully it'll set the ground
straight and you know people will will
say okay yeah this guy knows what he's
talking about here's here here's what
this is right because there's all kinds
of speculation on what it is out there
and people just don't know one thing I
wanted to say real quick um and I'm
sorry Colin if you were about to speak
speak up but um you know it's it's funny
this whole conversation around these
conversions um you know you know we from
the whole community of of extract
artists you know we we we we've been
catching a lot of [ __ ] for a long time
and losing a lot of really good business
for PE with people that you know kind of
uh you know we you know we would show a
test result with accuracy chro accurate
chromatography and and and show people
at like 40% delta9 and their distillate
or you know kind of whatever but you see
these huge peaks of these PS Beyond
Delta eight because we identify delta8
but you know Delta 10 all these other
kind of you know what other you know
state-ofthe-art isomer that there are
but now there's a
whole no I was just going to say now
there's a like I mean we're catching
[ __ ] about like you know not doing it
right and people kind of you know just
going to Labs that would misidentify
those Peaks as Delta 9 you know but now
like it's just funny because now there's
this like starting to be widespread
understanding of oh you could actually
through distillation process create all
these iers and now there's these
widespread like
you know these other you
know yeah I I I was just going to say
the funny thing is that you hear
fear-mongering in the in the blogs of
people who don't know what they're
talking about talking about all these
unknowns in there all unknowns unknowns
unknowns it's like well if you read the
chemical Literature Like I Do I can tell
you that they're not unknown at all in
fact they're quite known it's known
exactly what's made in this reaction and
so like when you do this conversion of
CBD to THC it generates non-natural
isomers that aren't formed in the plant
they all have the same molecular weight
314 and certainly in the the the testing
Labs that I've talked to about this and
the samples that I've seen those
compounds are in every they're they're
unless you have this figured out they're
in they're in all of these mixtures and
we really don't know what their
long-term impact is uh to human safety
so we we just don't know because they're
not made by the plant and this is the
first time they're being made for human
consumption and so it'll be interesting
to see if um folks who are producing
this are able to not only quantify what
those isomers are but basically set
product specification limits so you know
that if a batch has got 2% well 2% is no
good but we need to be down at05 or what
whatever the cut off is on some of these
but they until they do the safety
assessments on these compounds this is
just a guessing game so that was kind of
my my question to Alec I guess was was
do we have the ability to even test for
these these isomers and and
differentiate them from one another to
then call them out right say okay well
this is now present so this is this is
most likely
um so so you know it's um I think the
burden of proving these compounds is on
the manufacturers creating them more
than it's on the lab to like identify
these novel compounds and Chase see like
the you know kind of the trends of where
the Market's creating isomer be able to
quantify you know I think that requires
a lot of R&amp;D work in you know with a
laboratory to help you know be able to
you know identify what the compounds are
that the group's creating you
know then like what you know we Labs can
kind of you know stay up to date on kind
of having these compounds added into
their their methods and validated um you
know but but again I think you know it's
funny because in in the past we've kind
of caught so much [ __ ] from clients you
know that that that basically are like
my this distillate is 40% THC you know
you're wrong you know why what is this
other 60% and it's like dude it's a it's
a novel compound it's like this ghost
canabo isomer that you've created I have
no idea what it is there's not a
standard for it um like I can show you a
chromatogram that it's clearly that and
it's not built in nine you know but but
we're testing for these compounds like
Delta 9 that we have validated and
tested hundreds of thousands of times
you know and so so I think that work
there's like you know novel work that
needs to be done with kind of
Manufacturers that are making these
compounds to be able to kind of you know
again do that stage when they've just
made 20 kilos of this stuff they want it
to be 40 or 80% or they want it to be
exactly it's some ungodly low percent
and it's got all this other crap in
there like oh let's just you know white
film distill it and put it in gummies
you know and and I I think again I'd
like to think that there's a place for
chemists to play inry and I
think it's like if your process doesn't
make something that's greater than 90%
yield it ain't ready for Prime Time
unless you know what that other 10% is
and you could ascribe that other 10% to
known compounds or brid to known
compounds of known safety then you don't
have a safe product there so whether
it's Delta 8 or whether it's hhc these
are no longer naturally occurring in a
plant and you can't refine a plant
extract to get those compounds you're
talking about a reaction product of a
chemical reaction and I don't know about
you I hope that it's a chemist like me
running that chemical reaction that
knows what the hell it is they're doing
yeah truth truth
yeah yeah I think sort of the hilarity
of all of this and if we look at it from
you know a you know an outward
standpoint of how you know the brains of
human beings we've fractal this medicine
so much we've created so many different
laws and so many different regulations
and because humans are adaptogens then
we're always trying to jump through the
Hoops of the regulations and I just
think it's so hilarious that this plant
continues to be fractal out in all of
these different ways so we can jump
through all the Hoops that we're
creating so that we can even create
Hoops that we can't jump through anymore
I just think that it's pretty funny that
this plant is so adaptogenic in the way
that we are in our thinking that we've
come up with all these different ways
that just really don't make any sense
but hey they got through a hoop I I
really appreciate that thought you know
it reminds me um of I was at an
international canid research Society
conference one year and um you know
there's all these amazing you know you
know presentations and knowledge
transfer and all this and then and then
there was this like you know PhD like
super tenur DEA like chemist that was
presenting about this like cat and mouse
game that the DEA is having and this
really big problem that there all these
synthetic cannaboids that are hitting
the market and like they'll you know
spice and K2 and all these things and
then like the you know the only way
they'll even kind of find out about them
is through some widespread kind of
outbreak of like some really adverse
reaction and then they all of a sudden
kind of test that Supply identify this
way crazy new compound sythetic canono
and then they schedule it and then it
and then by the time they've scheduled
it then there's new compounds on the
market and it's and and it's this whole
cat and they're like presenting this
dilemma this cat and mouse game that
they're having and so hard and it's like
in the whole time the whole kind of
people everybody in the audience is just
like staring at him like pissed because
it's like it's the prohibition on this
plant that's creating the market for all
these super fractal kind of like you
know almost like um dystopian like just
like off way off the plants kind of path
of of what this you know of cannaboids
to hit the market but you know they're
doing it anyway and it's making it out
there you know some a lot some of
synthetic ones are like really gnarly
you know I you know I'd be curious about
like long-term efficacy for Delta 8 or
hhc and all that you know and it's
probably it's probably good it's
probably fine you know compared to some
of these crazy synthetic canavs but um
but again yes like it's just so trippy
because it's the prohibition on this
plant that's like leading to all this
Divergence from the path you know
instead of you know being able to
actually cherish the like magic that the
plant actually presents if you just give
it the chance yeah but the feds have
that law the blanket law the analog law
that says that anything that is a
spin-off from a drug schedule one is a
schedule one drug but the thing is is
it's like that uh toothpaste out of the
tube thing what are they going to do
come after everyone at this point that
like we've literally outnumbered the DEA
and the Fed so hardcore they can never
get it back in the toothpaste will never
ever go back in tube at this point never
it's over I think this is just all part
of the movement to deschedule the plant
and to take THC off the list you know
again it it flies in the face of
conventional knowledge that there are
several FDA approved drugs where canabo
that are from the plant are the active
ingredients in those drugs they have a
good therapeutic index they have low
toxicity yet the plant from which
they're derived has no medical value
come
on and that's been happening since you
know even LSD and and Hoffman and and
lley
Stanley and Nick sand who were making
LSD and the Tim Scully and Tim Scully a
lot of people don't know about Tim
Scully which is not rock
Scully and uh you know just talking
about how you know there's early um
Crystal that was made you know during a
time when it was legal and then they the
FDA or the government started going
after it and then they said oh we were
trying to produce a what was it
al52 you know and they're like hey hey
come on this was LSD 25 you know so you
know and these people went on to like do
other amazing Labs all over the place so
for sure you know that's that's the the
chemist you know you just just heat it
up
and realm and it's also that's been a
very
area I just gonna I just gonna say it's
been a very fruitful area
in in general to look at inspiration
from biology so when you look at the
compounds that biology produces that's
where a lot of our Pharmaceuticals and
drugs are discovered they're discovered
by making analoges around those
pharmaceutical or th those what what we
what typically in drug Discovery they
call privileged platforms so a
privileged platform is just a molecule
like a canono that no matter what group
you decorate on it it's going to have
some level of activity the great thing
about canono just in terms of their
therapeutic index is that they're
ultimately not toxic so a lot of these
compounds especially the compounds that
were developed by pharmaceutical
companies to act on the cannabinoid
receptors not only are they toxic as
hell but they have a a lot of
non-specific interactions they interact
not just with the cannaboid receptors
but with every receptor in the body and
so you can't just throw a mon wrench
into the engine of your body and expect
it not to have any deleterious impact
that's the great thing about the phyto
canabidol in general is that you know
it's very lipid soluble and so because
our bodies have a lot of fat especially
my body um th those those that fat is
basically reservoirs to hold just like a
dirty bong those canabo inside your body
as long as we possibly can so our body
has actually evolved mechanisms to hold
on to these compounds because they're so
beneficial and the last thing I'll say
is that unlike most antioxidants in our
diet like the polyphenols and coffee and
grape juice and [ __ ] like that unlike
those types of
antioxidants those are water soluble
canono are not water soluble so in
definitely they they protect the fatty
tissues of your body from oxidative d
damage caused by free radicals so again
it's been said many times before
cannabis use all use is medical because
you're protecting the fatty tissues of
your body including your pancreas your
brain and your kidneys against from
radical mediated oxidative damage so
these things are going to be looked as a
new supplement in the future because
it's going to lead to healthier
humans jump in about you said uh
something about a monkey wrench and I
just wanted to say that when we're
talking about pharmaceuticals and them
extracting certain compounds and those
compounds that have been maybe isolated
and studied and then that's what's being
put inside of the human well that lacks
the full spectrum that lacks the full
thing so what we're also finding is when
we're synthesizing and when we're
isolating that like that without the
full absorption of the full plant we're
actually creating more maladies and more
side effects with these drugs because we
failed to look at the whole
integration of all of the different
compounds within the drugs and that's
just pointing out you know more Hoops
that we like to put up for ourselves and
how funny that is and how
it I'm sorry um yeah I actually wanted
to follow up on both both of those great
points um you know like
um you know and and and a big shout out
to ethnobotany and the legendary
ethnobotanists of the past you know that
have kind of really helped to carry the
these this this coveted wisdom about the
medicinal properties of plants to
Western World which has kind of been the
foundation of so much of the modern
pharmaceutical kind of compounds created
you so many of the anti-histamines that
we use and around really kind of
foundationally kind of tied to like
datura and toi and Ania and kind of
Scopolamine kind of related type
compounds and stuff and there's and it
goes so far beyond that you know aspirin
and you know just and just the root of
so much of the medicines that
pharmaceutical uses is pretty much all
is is you know found in in plant you
know foundations and so you know I
there's this really amazing podcast I
would highly recommend from um the great
ethnobotanist Dr Mark Plotkin um called
plants of the Gods you know kind of name
and tribute to you great uh Albert
Hoffman and Richard Evan schulties that
wrote the book together the back in the
day but there's a podcast um called
plants of the gods that kind of you know
from a really amazing kind of
biocultural conservational aspect kind
of tributes plants and the people where
these plants kind of uh you know kind of
come from um and and you know and just
really really beautiful narrative
is over time and you know a lot more uh
in in in uh Allin and in service to that
path than you know the pharmaceutical
Discovery path you know to start just
like randomly kind of start plugging out
receptors you know in that way of of
hacking into the systems that are
already perfectly figured out um but
anyway just wanted to share
that I'm glad you did just went and
followed that
podcast it's an amazing podcast it
really is and if you ever get a chance I
think he's he's either got a TED talk or
there's a YouTube of a talk that he gave
his photographs are [ __ ]
amazing he he has some of the most
amazing photographs of the Amazon that
I've ever
seen sweet it's just sort of cool too to
remind ourselves that no matter what we
have created in the name of science or
whatever we have manipulated as far as
carbon or as far as any kind of
compounds it's all of the
earth everything that we have
manipulated and it's all come from the
earth even like the Plastics yes they're
not naturally occurring but everything
as of the Earth and I just think that
that's just a really interesting thing
that of course all of our medicinals
would would come from the plants because
they're of the earth everything would be
coming of the earth so of course we've
figured out ways to synthesize it and
make it unhealthy for us and that's been
um really
awesome in
pharmacopia you're blowing my my secret
ingredients Stardust right
who put Stardust in the really special
stuff right we're not importing feed
stocks from Mars not yet
right not yet although who knows right
and I love the work of Alexander Sasha
shulan and all of the compounds
blessings all for sure yeah blessings on
him of course you if you're G to talk
about psychoactive drugs and different
you know I mean how many did he make and
I think he was into you know trying them
all and just really
supporting all of the doctors throughout
all these years you don't know it but
like Alexander schan is just right there
you know in court cases and uh um
studies and stuff and you know give
thanks for some of the medicines that
you know were created there for sure he
wasn't there's still a whole lot of work
to do there really there is
right his two textbooks right
tryptamines and and phenethylamines
these are again privileged platforms
that you could decorate with just about
any molecular spinach you want you're
only limited by the imagination of the
chemist right and so you could put a
group over here see what it does take a
few pills oh that makes me feel tired
and he did put another group over here
you know really do your own s
yep pcal and tal um you know and that
you know what's fascinating is I think
those are the two Divergent paths really
with the plants you know it's like this
ethnobotanical like biocultural
conservation like supporting the
communities where medicines come from
and understanding how to use them most
effectively in reverence to the to the
plant to the people where they come from
and then also this this world of
Discovery and kind of like being able to
kind of you know create these novel
compounds in this shulan kind of uh
tribute and path you know and and some
of my favorite you know medicin like 2cv
you know kind of our our sh gun
compounds um and and um you know and I
think I think in the in this other kind
of side of this compound you know which
is relevant to our conversations
synthetic cannabinoids and all these hhc
kind of Delta 8 Delta 10 kind of stuff
you know it's you know kind of there's
this and this this creation you
potential of you know kind of being able
to you know hack the you know kind of
the you the molecular you know kind of
understanding of the endoc avonoid
system and tryptamines and you know
dopamine system and all this and be able
to create compounds that can fit into
these Pathways but I do also believe
that very strongly that there's an
incredible again burden of proof that is
on those people that are making these
compounds and especially if they're
going to be made them making them
readily and ra you know accessibly
available to to prove efficacy and qual
and and efficacy and safety you know
first and foremost um before kind of
there's this just as rapid release you
know
because you I think you know there's you
know Shan's really the only dude that
did it really right you know I think in
in in in his world and I think people
that took kind of shulan kind of paths
with the endoc cannaboid system to
create all these novel you know kind of
synthetic canids that have kind of gone
to lead to all these outbreaks of just
public health issues you know kind of
did shulan a disservice you know kind of
in in that because they were just they
they weren't they weren't creating the
molecule and dosing them eles and
figuring out the thing and then like
putting that out very responsibly they
were just like critting batches and like
dosing the population you know and
that's the other thing the other thing
is is that uh we don't look at the
long-term effects of this you know what
shogan put out is you definitely had
Mass peer studies but he's just one man
in an adult life creating pretty
phenomenal things and massive peer
review studies that were on his own and
I just feel like like here it is again
that we're putting Shackles on the
possibility and the educational
attributes of plant medicine when we
continuously try to regulate them
because what would it be like what kind
of a society would we be if we were
readily able to use cocoa leaves every
day in our teas that would help uh you
know Lift us for our days rather than
have to party on the weekends with this
super sythetic extract and we don't look
at the longevity of that if we were able
to totally free that up I feel like it
would lessen the the need for us to
continue to synthesize these things that
would be more normalized in our own tea
cabinet that we would have you know
concentrated sassafras bark that we were
taking every day especially for the
rainy days that you know MDMA is made
out of that we could get that maybe in a
chewing canary grass or San Pedro
cactuses I you know what I mean like
there's it's just interesting straight
to the te straight to the old world you
know what I mean that's and I think that
that creates more regevity yeah that's
the longevity that's the Blue Zone you
know that's the that's the the ultimate
you
know lift of the spirit I think C leaf
cocaine is such a good example you know
COC leaf that is revered for thousands
of years as one of the highest pray upon
appreciated plants across the Andes you
know is the Divine Leaf of immortality
you know and kind of the the longevity
of that is real you know and and and how
and how you know how much that medicine
of a of a of a plant it is you know as
opposed to the cursed kind of extracted
way overused way overly kind of
self-gratifying way like ego building I
mean it's it's totally different it's a
totally different days those are not the
same things at all yeah it's like um
they what like I've heard it described
as um Coca is to potato as cocaine is to
vodka right that's about right when I
was uh married which was long ago I was
married to an andian man he was Peruvian
and and coko is actually symbiotic with
their bodies they they're one the plant
and their body are the same and lately
I've been thinking about um for example
mushrooms because here I live in Oakland
it's it's legalized here locally and
I've been doing micro does so great but
I did a micro do and I didn't take time
to develop my set and setting and my
mindset because I've been doing it
regular right and I was like oh I'll
just do a micro do and I did it on the
fly it bit me in the butt so hard
because that is a sacred plant and you
really have to watch your head space and
you have to use it in a certain way so
I'm curious as we unveil these things
how are people how how many people are
going to get in trouble sort of
physically or mentally not treating
these plants with the kind of respect
like the andian peruvians do where
they're symbiotic with the Coca plant
it's part of their body and their whole
life View and the same with mushrooms
that's a sacred plant that's that's not
something you take just like aspirin
that is different
soach of us finds out in our own way
right you found out in your way oh I got
my but it's been a while believe way the
same way as they find find out by eating
cannabis you know start off small and
work your way up it's not something
where you
just I couldn't believe it novice
mistake I was thinking I'm a
professional 30 years doing this what
the hell and it got me but yeah it did
it did get my brain wrapped around this
kind of sacred plant um set and setting
thing a lot clearer so I was very
appreciative for the lesson I think
people's definitions of a micro do is is
is not all on the same cuz like to me I
hear people going well a micro do is
like 0.1 and I'm like 0.1 hey like
that's okay I guess I think you could
catch a buzz off that though like and
other people are doing much smaller
amounts so I think uh I think that data
needs to get put together so people can
kind of all be on the same page what is
an accurate micro do because to me a
micro do is there's no psychedelic
effect there's no like butterflies in
your stomach there's no nothing you
could literally like honestly just go
about your day but what you're talking
about is like something different the
the old uh I thought I was a
professional and now I'm like how long
is this gonna be for again you know no I
app I really appreciate that thought
actually too because that's one of you
know with with in the with within the
world of cannabis you know kind of when
testing came along the biggest thing it
really helped to change and level the
game up on was being able to start to
get towards a standardized dose
especially when you're making
manufactured products or edibles or
micro doing things you know because
that's such a great point you know kind
of you know was it a 0.1 or point two
was it you know kind of albino penis
envy or was it this other type variety
you know and and so I think you know the
the identification of what even might I
mean or just you know if there's an
agreeance on micro do is 0.1 you know
it's like there's that you know there's
that could vary very much between
varieties you know and so so kind of you
I think um you know cannabis in such a
way you know it's what's really cool
just a random thought I've been working
on for a minute is you know everybody's
freaking out like we're in the
apocalypse you know and and in the
apocalypse the literal definition of the
word is time of Revelation or the great
unveiling you know and and so many ways
I can't help but feel the plants are the
horsemen of this apocalypse you know
with cannabis and hemp at the lead you
know that are helping set the path
forward you know because you just see
this rapid path of these other compounds
and these other plants and fungi kind of
following lead in an accelerated way you
know but there you know these plants and
compounds and you know kind of companion
partner teacher plants you know that are
helping to empower us with all the tools
we need to make it through this time of
Revelation you know in the most
empowered and lifted way towards this
Ascension path you know well Alec you
really that that that's really important
and thank you for bringing that up
because I think that there's something
you know we're trying to unwrap in the
Cannabis industry this discussion around
potency you know that we we all know
it's not just THC we know there's a
whole synergistic thing going but I feel
like the the the
the missing conversation there is the
set and setting is endogenous
count setting means we think of set and
setting as all these things that are
around us but it's how the things around
US influence our own internal chemistry
right and certain certain certain um
certain cannabinoids and certain
compounds certain psychedelics and stuff
really stimulate our own I mean anyone
who's taken psychedelics knows that as
soon as you it already starts right you
start building that up because you that
anticipation and the same thing with
cannabis there's certain cannabis
varieties that stimulate your
endogenous chemical Factory and they
interact like I feel like there's these
three intersecting lines of cannaboids
tpes and endogenous compounds and where
they intersect is where the potency lies
and a big part of that is knowing like
hey there's a certain set and setting
that is going to react to these
particular chemicals and create this
other high and now that we're in the the
pandemic the set and setting has changed
so much and for me in my life my set and
setting around cannabis completely
shifted because for one I'm not with my
homies anymore I'm in my home office
with my family on the other side of the
wall you know it's a totally different
relationship with the same plant and I
think that there's something there that
there's certain varieties that really
trigger anxiety and C certain people if
their set and setting isn't right you
know but at the same time those same
varieties are the ones that are
stimulate that intense psychoactive
experience if your set and setting is
right and people have kind of steered
away from those varieties because they
don't want to take the chance of having
a adverse reaction where they need to
really you know that's like riding that
Razor's Edge of where you're the
chemicals outside and the chemicals
inside are in complete Harmony that's
that whole human plant
experience that's really brilant honest
to be honest there is no one
potency because some people some people
old world oh sorry some people think
potency is physical some people think
it's mental so there there is no one
potency anymore than there's one
cannabis for everybody there isn't it's
I mean there can be things that people
prefer and uh a lot of people prefer
very different things the most misc
commmon ask people reach out to me for
specifically when looking for something
medically is they're looking for a
cannabis that works specifically for
their issue it is still a dominant
misinformation that's being perpetuated
because when I make them aware that it's
completely subjective and what if you
and I can have the same condition what
works for you won't work for me and vice
versa that's mindblowing to them they
can't understand that we have to go
along the same process of trial and
error for you to find out what works for
you there's no magic one of Sam and all
those guys have not created that one
magic asthma Bud the one cancer can
that's the one they what's specifically
for this cancer that I could use and the
most frustrating thing that I have to
tell them is don't know we don't
understand you're going to have to try
it by trial and error document and I
have them definitely write it down in a
notebook and you know document how they
feel when they take it you know uh what
did they eat what were they feeling when
was on set and when did it finish so
that later on they can get
an because they're in the experience
later they need to understand or their
caretaker or person working with them or
their doctor is very helpful to take
that information so they can show what
you're using how much you're using what
you're using it for how much dosage and
uh how much is and how long is it
lasting for those are all very helpful
and all decision makers that you find in
what works for you so I I agree that
psycho dos are just as subjective as
cannabis and what would work for Debbie
for a micro do could be a potential
heroic dose for someone else and a micro
do from turns out to be a heroic dose
for Debbie so you know it's it's still
rather fascinating but the most
frustrating thing to say is even after
all this and honestly is we don't know
and I think that Mo you were just saying
and also Alec is that this has always
been known because even when you go to
traditional people that dish out the
medicine that prepare the medicine for
you they hold the space they clear the
energy they CL they cast the spell all
of that is protection for your spirit
it's protection
for organism with this plant so they're
they're creating a space for you to be
able to have a safe relationship you
know for lack of better words they're
creating soft padding so that your
relationship and and and they create a
mediation so the epigenetics and and the
situation and the cast and and the set
and setting is just all a part of that
same thing that we talk about with the
ancient settings of casting a spell and
Maria Sabina Mexico can look up Maria
Sabina for as one person who's done a
amazing work with uh with you know cubus
and and pan in that whole Zone um also
just you know compounding medicines is
really crucial and I think with with
micro doing especially you know it's the
it's the compound in uh psychedelic you
know the mushrooms with other supportive
herbs in a capsule form you know so you
can kind of say oh I'm going to take the
same amount of capsule with all these
other supportive herbs so that my liver
is not too tuxed out if I'm going to
take it you know for a whole year or you
know the kidneys
don't setting which is the is the
protection as well you want to be able
to look towards not only the elders who
have held the medicine but also the
Elder the Elder herbs who have also been
compounded together forever and ever
they also help hold the set and setting
of what you're taking to create more of
a protection of you having a
relationship with that
plan I I really appreciate that um you
know something I'd love to add in kind
of which it's a good conversation you
know kind of ties both of these topics
in with what you were bringing up Mojave
kind of about that like the endogenous
lead up to the kind of overall potency
of an experience you know CU it's so
true across kind of plants and kind of
the you know the Traditions were using
these context of they were using these
plants and and you know to Debbie your
point of kind of the you know just this
that experience you know kind of uh you
know it's you know just using cannabis
as an example you know it's fascinating
because um um you know like you know I'm
veteran in the Navy at T I know you're a
veteran too as your soul um you know
I've worked with a lot of veterans over
the years to help kind of reframe their
experience with cannabis you know
because you know there's this thing that
can happen if you don't come to cannabis
correct it can slap you in a way that
you'll creates such a Negative response
that you might not ever do it again and
so there's a lot of people that are
first-time users that you know take some
long break in between that start back uh
or people that kind of one day it just
shifts from taking way too big of a dose
but it's kind of a respect and kind of
set and setting type Factor but it'll
create this super negative reaction that
you you know kind of leads to this oh
it's maybe it's not for me anymore you
know and and you hear all these
different people say oh the Canabis D is
so strong it's
it's and part of it is you know kind of
immediately start micro doing THC and
you know having really elevated levels
of CBD or say CBG or something but then
it's it's the whole kind of the the the
ritual of like taking a bud and grinding
it up and you know kind of you know
going through the process of rolling it
you know and starting kind of almost set
your endogenous path kind of forward
with it and you know kind of then you
know kind of taking that you know that
you rolled ritually in that way or
whatever the ritual is that you do with
it but it's putting attention into it in
that way and then it's doing something
that's associated with vable you know
like going and eating uh your favorite
dessert or going on a walk with your
sweetie or going kind of you know out in
the water or whatever it is that you
know you would like but you know and
then over time with cannabis you know
kind of from this protocol you know you
can kind of over time you know like
keeping this ritual going you know this
same process you know kind of over time
you can start eventually titrating
slowly titrating up your THC that's in
that blend um and then all of a sudden
you're bble to Puff tough with the best
of them you know like and start to
really reshift your experience with
cannabis to appreciate and enjoy THC and
all the medicine it brings you know and
and so I think kind of there's that's
such a big process with you know how
we're you know it's like like I used to
do a lot of Bud tedar educational
seminars at retail dispensaries and I
would almost like I try to lecture them
about like you know how how sacred of a
role and acted is to be able to be this
person to help share this experience
with somebody that's new that's never
done it before and how if you do that
wrong that could be on your karma you
know because you might have like just
dabbed out that old lady or like just
blasted them on that like chibu thousand
milligram edible you know that they
might not ever smoke cannabis because
again even though it might have been in
their Destiny to heal their cancer with
this plant that you just did that dude
you know so take that responsibly and so
so just like kind of that understanding
with canvas I think goes triple so with
kind of all these like new kind of
emerging in
is plants and and yeah just not taking
it I mean taking it not taking for
granted and taking it seriously just in
you know how we do it and just the
reverence we do it in and just knowing
you know what we're doing it hey happy
belated Armistice Day to you I don't
considered Veterans Day because that's
more propaganda for the industrial
military complex but having day belated
and respect but with the veterans that
we're working with uh we all consider
cannabis our daily pallative because you
know we have a daily acclimation to it
and after 30 days arriving at regular
cognitive levels whereas we see
psychedelics and mushroom as the next
front for our veterans to really hit at
the Deep issues even micro doing and
working with therapists and psychologist
to work through their post-traumatic
stress injury it's no longer PTSD people
it's that's considered post-traumatic
stress damage it is an injury so that's
why it's called ptsi now so that we can
realize that we can heal past these
injuries um once we have the proper
tools and tool sets in mind and we're
finding a lot of Psych colle is willing
to now step over that line to work with
psychedelics to help a lot of these
people access their deeper traumas
through psychedelics so it's a new and
beautiful Frontier so if you're out
there in Psychology now look into this
new uh front so that you can educate
yourself and become one of those
therapists because there's millions of
people who need psychedelic healing not
just our veterans we're just a small
subset are trying to prove fact as the
culture that we are and we are
establishing that and we're doing so so
that the larger society at General can
benefit from it much love I love it at
thank you for sharing that um it's funny
because I've been kind of bubbling about
trying to do a show more based on this
psychedelic conversation and I've been
talking to a business partner of mine uh
who who runs an account called inoculate
the world and inoculate the West his
name is Drew super awesome guy deep in
the mushroom uh world and we're I we're
sort of trying to put together a hash
Church you know mushroom Church kind of
version a mushroom dialogue or a
psychedelic dialogue more so than just
mushrooms so uh some of you for sure
will have to get invited to that um I
want to thank everyone for coming out
today it is noon now so we've been
rocking it for three hours and my uh my
son Tanner is like anxious uh to go uh
you know maybe pick mushrooms or go play
or something so uh we're going to go do
that but yeah it was awesome awesome to
see all of you and hear all of your
voices and I really enjoyed the
conversation today I want to thank the
300 plus people that watched uh and sort
of streamed along with us the entire
time and uh we in the chat the entire
time keeping dialogue going on in there
so did I freeze I
froze button I needed to wrap it
up I needed that WP W it up wrap it up
love you all great
dayone blessings peace and love peace
good love tons of
hash exactly