hey welcome everybody welcome to hash
Church episode 155 Wow
I was we were gonna make this one better
in the middle of Toronto literally six
minutes ago somehow I managed to make it
I'm here let's hope for the best when it
comes to the connection I'm a wonderful
the connection is gonna be today but
when we try our best everyone I'm gonna
send out the links here soon and
scenario maybe I have a bad connection
but left for a second past Church link
and all right we are live sounds good
well good to hear guys I'm really
thought this was in three years because
next week is our three year anniversary
I almost thought yeah it's gonna be
choppy it's gonna be choppy today is
gonna be very choppy so oh I would say
don't tell me how choppy it is because
if I see too many people posting how
choppy it is I'll stop and I'll and
shirt so if you guys want church to go
and a little bit of choppy let's let's
try our best
good morning it's yeah good morning sir
how are you well you know I'm on a
computer that guaranteed gonna fail me I
barely made the start of hash Church
today I thought I was hoping to Tash
today but she's actually getting you as
the moderator Etienne and helping out
sometimes when I'm just absolutely
unable to pull in I can do that
I somehow pulled a scenario I don't get
to be a part of the conversation today
good morning Sam good morning or good
evening how are things there it's accent
in the Amsterdam quite a sunny day today
nice good to have good weather in the
Amsterdam so where are you in the world
there I mean but when morning guys
morning John hanging out on Victoria
hang it on the island today and just
gonna sign in and say good morning how
is karma cup hallmark the karma cup is
going very well
I was busy day lots of people lots of
many people I heard had done 10 and
$15,000 in sales us included lots lots
of great people are lots of happy
however this morning I was out front
waiting for my uber to come pick up the
to go do past church and I saw Josh and
he was coming out
this is people police and I was like
what you guys are worried about the
police and he said yeah they just
announced yesterday that the police have
240 million new dog oh and legal
cannabis things in the City of Toronto
so there was about five or six cops up
the road but I think
passing the karmic up I think this is
more about the business of dispensaries
versus somehow controlled you know I
guess Ontario announced the doing like
LC like liquor type stores but for
cannabis and they're gonna do like a
hundred and fifty of them province
anything like this as you can imagine
the majority of people were not overly
happy about it all
ich hair if they open a hundred and
fifty shops to sell weed to people what
you care about is being able to have
a dispenser in 50 new access points
because hey the more the merrier in my
opinion there is not enough places to
buy great weed
hopefully out of these 150 there might
be where you had Johnny be I'm I'm on
the malahat right now Ashley yeah we're
just kind of hang it over here and
alright going over the stuff and it's
interesting to say where you're saying
that mark and what they're gonna be
doing and and I remember I listened to
the whole like 45 minute kind of little
presentation they were talking about on
the crackdowns and how they're gonna
start implementing a whole new system
when they say by 2020 they'll have 20
stores available within the first year
or two I don't know how they plan on
putting in 150 stores overnight and how
that problem is gonna happen
I mean what's what's gonna happen I mean
how many stores are gonna go you don't
know well that's an interesting way that
they're going about it seems almost like
they're going about it the route of in
the states here we have with things
called ABC stores which before you had
individual stores selling liquor they
had which basically a state store which
is basically owned by the state as only
holds you know mMmmm
State hours you know something like nine
till like 7:00 or something like that
where it's just not an only place you
could buy liquor back in the day until
they actually had distribution and
things like that in fact it just changed
in Pennsylvania you couldn't you
couldn't buy a six-pack of beer I'm just
giving call you know just a causality
sort of situation there you couldn't buy
beer on a Sunday in a store you would
have to go to a bar to actually get it
and you could you wouldn't you pay for
an individual beer if you bought a
six-pack you wouldn't buy you know just
a regular six-pack that you buy
currently in a store anywhere so I see
why they're doing something like that
that's a tried-and-true model that has
worked with alcohol so I can see why
they're they're pushing in that round
but what negative effects is that going
to what immediate negative things do you
see the negative well
well I guess the negative effects that
we're looking at right now are going to
be the people like that our friends that
are open up dispensaries have spent
their lives fighting for this plant and
then educating the bud tenders and the
knowledge behind the people that they're
helping the patients that are being
helped in these countries that we have
when they've establish relationships
with the bud tenders as the way all
these patients that have been relying on
these compassionate Cubs who are
compassion do you help me do give back
who do follow the events who do you
support
other people in the industry who do give
that I think they don't do they like the
liquor stores didn't they they give away
free alcohol they support groups or they
put on big events and stuff like that
it's a different industry with the
cannabis industry is more supportive
work and alcohol industry is more about
money just looking at comparative
industries and how they're actually I
don't want to please no one take this as
anyway is alcohol in the same line as
cannabis I'm just looking at
distribution models and how they've gone
and I agree it's very frustrating land
they've taken this large overwhelming
model which of course is better for
consumers however it leaves out all
those that have been spending decades
busting their ass and risking their
freedoms and challenging local City as
well as you know those federal laws
there in Canada I mean you love for LPS
it's it's rather surprising they're
going in this direction as opposed to
letting the free market because they're
allowing the free market actually
produced cannabis it's surprising
they're not going to allow the free
market to actually distribute it to
Canadians can add something to this
conversation always you know there if
there's the there's the line of um the
government's trying to move in and like
johnny was saying and take the jobs ever
that have been given to people that are
actually caring about people and and
showing the Compassion's and everything
like that that is all needed and the
support groups and you know all the
support that is that is that these
compassion centers with the bud tenders
with people behind the desk with the
people that are supplying those centers
now the now once once we've got
once every all of that is in place we
don't have any of those bud tenders or
any of those people putting any of those
special time special needs into anybody
else and it's just simply go to the
[ __ ] thing grab your bottle your bag
go to the counter pay for it leave now
once that factor is taken away in that
personal factors been taken away from
everybody not just guys that are
drinking booze or anything like that or
shooting drugs I think but everybody is
gonna it's not gonna have that
compassion or that level of human being
effect that really makes a difference
people go into clubs and just talking to
somebody about what they've been smoking
because it's not the right thing for
them to be smoking because it's an
indica it's it's a tea nerves or if it's
an indica sativa hybrid dominance
whatever they're smoking the wrong stuff
they're not getting the right right the
right treatment so what do they do then
they go back and to the internet
research it off or go to the black
market place that has maybe just room in
the back it's a head shop it's a it's a
hangout Center whatever it's a it's an
arcade they're gonna think oh then
they're trying to bring this black
market factor out of it but this black
market is actually the market that is
helping everybody that is you know I'm
not saying the LPS are helping people
there I've got nothing against anybody
but this [ __ ] of everybody that's
been doing this industry and part of
this industry and helping people and
crying with people about the good things
that are happening and the bad things
that are happening now now we're gonna
have that whole factor eliminated and
then where do we go from there and what
happens to the patients then what do the
peso speak up and so we want that back
or what well why do you guys think
Canada has gone in this direction as
opposed to stated before letting the
free market as as it its created from
the free market the you know the whole
you know dispensary seeing as it is so
why do you think they've gone in this
direction I don't know Johnny can you
answer anything like that
oh well pretty much what you're looking
at is you're looking at a system so
they're trying to legalize cannabis and
the biggest thing about Justin Trudeau
is talking about
how they getting rid of the black market
so by them putting him all of these
stores they got an open up distribution
center so if I go into other places and
other friends that have like say
multiple stores they have distribution
centers to supply those stores so now
we're gonna start seeing these models as
it's like I was talking with Darren it's
like when I go to like a grocery store
they have it's like a distribution
center for all the supplies or if I go
to if no matter where we go we're always
will get more than one or two products
back in the days you know we're not go
see my buddy he have one type of wheel
with dispensaries we have ten different
types of weed I think the government is
taking a look at the Spencer II model I
think they're gonna put in that type of
a system how they gonna start hiring
around that will be interesting I mean
there's no schooling for this there's no
education on how to cope cannabis and
diggities pharmacist there's so many
different things with us now as inform
the people the people have the voice and
and I really see it like with
prohibition we we had we had there was
harsh like laws that were enforced in
beginning in as times grew we started
getting more craft kind of breweries and
stuff like that we're not the same with
marijuana I'm gonna see more of like the
independent grower who's got that
certain strain or they're gonna have
that certain rosin or there'll be
something they'll be Teke about every
individual that has their own little
thing I think as the system changes I
think that we tikis will fight hard
enough in courts and because this will
turn into a court battle huge and we
already know that Daniel Larson's
posting on it Jason there's a lot of
people ready talking about what things
that we have to do as patients as people
and as Canadians to be able to be able
to ensure we get safe access and at the
same time start a new industry and we're
gonna we defy and I'm all about access
so for me 150 stores in Ontario when I
get off the plane and I can walk into a
place and get what I need because I need
it now that's access that's what we can
fighting for can you clarify more about
what Dana Larson is saying that patients
can do to get involved oh you know just
reading some stuff he's putting on this
morning what was going on here the
government wants to clothe expenses and
all black market is
just make legal cannabis higher quality
and lower price than the dispensaries
with a wider selection of high quality
and lower price extracts and edibles
that's really Galatian the government is
going to rely on the race to shut down
the current market they will fail just
like they failed for the past century of
prohibition and that's what dan Larson
says 51 men's go on his Facebook page so
okay so there's what you know so so go
look people if you're on Facebook go to
Dana Larson's page if you want to learn
more because you know I know there's
quite a few Canadians who must be
concerned at least you know hearing this
sort of situation that especially those
that actively run or dealing with
dispensaries I mean it's always
nerve-racking to hear that your
distribution access point could be you
know shut down completely and that
causes a great deal of anxiety to people
you know locally so it's very
interesting situation there that the you
know Canada's gone in that direction
it's really just in the state of Ontario
right yes that's the state of Ontario
yeah are they looking to go national
with it as like the Ontario they're
they're sort of the incubation point for
this situation I'm not sure Johnny are
you listening to that I think Johnny
froze up on us so that's just where
we're what do you think about this Sam
have you heard about this going on in
Canada before well I'm what I'm for is
that individuals should be able to grow
it as much as they want for their own
use and family use for if they sell it I
am then somewhere I'd like it to be
taxed regulated and needed like an entry
if it's passed want to sell it Epis one
so if individuals want to sell it it's
it's it clean and my mind I think acts
are regulated if we really want the
wanna Prohibition to be gone dead and
buried then we have to pay our part just
like any other industry well this is the
reality that we're seeing we've taken it
past that idea of that what we always
said you know we want it legal or we
want it tax well this is part of those
realities that transpires that you know
we didn't I mean it get some of us have
thought about but you know the
government's taken further it's very
interesting to see you know Canada go
this direction for really thought they
would go the dispensary model for some
reason allowing individuals so do you
think this will be like a tweed canopy
distribution centers or at the Canadian
distribution centers what do you think
it will be not a clue well you know what
then I think we should do a bomber it
absolutely welcome dr. Tsao down hey
everybody how's everyone doing today
we're doing good we're have a little
technical difficulty unfortunately with
bubble man so we're kind of running the
show a bit here today we were talking
about the new distribution centers in
Canada and I was kind of curious about
pants so lucky how's it going they're in
pencil talkie I know their harvest
didn't happen they're working on yeah
working on your growing distribution
centers there what's the status yeah I
think there's there's a so again the
Hamptons is a only experimental research
plot so I think they're only allowed to
grow somewhere between 3 to 5 acres and
I asked a couple of the people who are
involved to maybe be panelists on a
coming hashed Church so they can give us
a little bit of you know poop on what's
going on but there's also medical
licenses for grower processors that have
been awarded in Pennsylvania as well so
there's
you know groundbreaking ceremonies to
open facilities and facilities you know
coming online and popping in in a
neighboring state of Maryland too as
well so yeah I mean there's a every day
every week there's more and more
progress being made on establishing
programs in these states so it's good
it's a positive movement movement
forward you know that's what we all want
to see and you know it's one thing to
hear you know states move saying they're
gonna do something it's another thing
that actually transpired so I mean it's
very positive for Pennsylvania do you
know them when you walk approximately
when Pennsylvanians look at having
actual distribution centers to go
purchase cannabis at is there yeah I see
yeah so the facilities are just you know
in the process is starting up right now
doctors are being trained because they
have to go through some mandatory
training in order to be able to have the
the ability to prescribe and they're
trying to again increase the education
of medical professionals so they can
understand what are the right conditions
that they should you know look for to
prescribe medical cannabis and yeah
there's clinical applicants as well so
these are applicants that are associated
with large research universities that
have hospitals and I'm associated with a
group that's working with the Thomas
Jefferson University in Philadelphia and
this is again I guess the notion is that
they're going to do a lot of sort of
outpatient open-ended clinical type
research to try to develop some type of
understanding of clinical efficacy
amongst patient population groups by by
volunteering you know so just
a patient that would have a particular
medical condition would basically
volunteer some information through a
medical questionnaire on how effective a
particular strain or product or oil or
take sure is and be able to develop you
know information and databases based on
you know real patient experience with
the medicine do you have patients lined
up or is there a way that no I think
that's getting involved if they want you
yeah this is you know you know building
the plane while you're flying it this is
all happening while it's that I think
the legislation is new everything is new
about it that you know universities
haven't done this yet so yeah it's a
it's a big new unknown thing so no not
yet are the universities embracing it or
are they still kind of at arms-length
with it well it's interesting because
the Pennsylvania Medical Society is now
you know sort of looking at it and it's
established like best practices and
rules and as is the Pennsylvania Bar
Association again giving guidance to
attorneys because if it's you know if
something's federally against the law
theoretically an attorney can't give you
any information to help you you know
break federal law so that's always been
sort of a quandary for attorneys because
they can't advise you know and play the
necessary of roles that legal folks and
attorneys play in the startup of new
businesses and be able to give clients
advice in the cannabis business world
has been always a tricky thing for
attorneys because they're they can be
disbarred for giving information that
can lead to their clients breaking the
law and so if you read that
as that they can't give help to anyone
in the cannabis industry it's useful for
the Pennsylvania Bar Association and all
the other State Bar Association's to
establish a set of rules and guidelines
that attorneys can follow well the
Pennsylvania Medical Association has
done the same thing for physicians and
so again it's giving the legitimate
legitimacy of having a set of standards
and a set of code of ethics that this is
how you apply this for for this patient
population or in case of attorneys for
you know all the aspects that they
interact on you know business
development and securing contracts and
everything that attorneys need to do to
be able to you know see this industry
you know become established and that's a
huge step in the direction of allowing
you know the market to you know to reign
you know it's key that they're allowing
this type of discussion at those points
because those are key any of the type of
business people are gonna need
counseling and you know you're in the
Commonwealth so you know Pennsylvania
has the Commonwealth it's interesting to
see how that shall all shake out for ya
in a Commonwealth I don't think we can
pass stuff by referendum so like you
know Colorado and Oregon like a lot of
these states that have voted in things
that's been voted in by public
referendum and I think for some reason
goes back to the 1600s or William Penn
days and a Commonwealth you can't vote
in stuff by referendum you have to you
know I guess the the legislators know
best you know well that's just it it's
how it is it's what's happening here in
California you know we passed our laws
but no they get a hold of it because
they now have to regulate it so I
totally get that but I wonder how long
before we'll see the ltp tax on cannabis
because it's gonna come in time you know
people don't know every can of soda and
anything that goes through Pennsylvania
once state you know I guess interstate
commerce is a
that will finally take place but I know
that you know Pennsylvania does well off
that taxation off of thing yeah well
there's a lot of there's been a lot of
talk about the privatization of that of
that state-run liquor authority and and
and actually I think like in Washington
State for example it's sometimes it's
the Liquor Control Board that ends up
taking the role of regulating cannabis
and the can in the new cannabis industry
and I guess they figured while these
people sold booze I guess or regulated
regulated the selling of booze then they
must be good at regulating the sell of
weed but if you think about it if the
state wanted to have dispensaries or
state-owned buildings of facilities
there they have a network and a
distribution network within the state to
get a controlled dangerous substance to
a you know place for right I was talking
about that right before you came on the
agency stores because what I was in in
Louisiana when I grew up but they didn't
have ABC stores I could go to a 7-eleven
and pick up a pint or up to a fifth of
Jack Daniels or beer etc etc whereas
when I went to West Virginia I learned
that they and in Pennsylvania back in
the day they had state stores so yes you
already have that distribution so that's
actually happening in Canada and Darren
and and the other Canadians were making
us aware of what's actually transpiring
up there so it made me immediately think
of Pennsylvania because in you know and
West Virginia because it was such a
foreign idea to me but now as a
distribution set up for the state I get
it and understand why it is that it is
but that model of course seems to have
become outdated over time and they've
allowed the free market to finally you
know reign but I mean how long did it
take for Pennsylvania to come around I
mean only what last year did it pass
regarding buying a six-pack on a Sunday
you know I'm saying at a bar
so I mean it's to take that long for
that type of change so it's interesting
to see what each state is going to do
I would rather surprise by Canada taking
this turn of going to that sort of ABC
set up as opposed to letting the free
market access or those that have spent
years as activists risking their
freedoms etc you know pushing things you
know pushing the agenda forward and
being allowed to be players in the you
know the new world as opposed to being
shut out and excluded that it looks to
Canada is doing do you think Canada is
gonna go in that direction or I mean
part of me do you think Pennsylvania is
going to go in that direction like the
ABC stores for initially or do you think
it will allow the free market no I mean
it sounds like it's gonna be free market
it sounds like that's the way they're
gonna go at first I mean again there's a
there's a large number of dispensaries
there's a lesser number of grower
processors so there's and some of those
grower processors have their own
dispensaries so there will be a
wholesale market between the grower
processors and the dispensers dispensers
are sort of the licenses were given out
according to population centers and
basically where people live so you know
in the Philadelphia region in the
Pittsburgh region and in Harrisburg
Scranton areas the areas where there's
heavy population they awarded more
licenses and in the area but the grower
processors are distributed throughout
the state it's kind of like a six
sections divvied up state kind of thing
but um yeah we'll see because the
clinical applicants to the clinical
folks can also sell I think into the
wholesale market so the clinical
licenses are also going to be you know
valuable commercially as well excited to
see what happens they're finding that's
you you have a opportunity there to
really how the East Coast yeah the
one-wheel I guess advantage in
Pennsylvania is why won't say advantage
I mean it's kind of like a rare thing is
autism is a qualifying condition and you
know I don't know I've heard numbers
like 1 in 5 people are somewhere on the
autistic spectrum or autism spectrum so
the fact that autism is a qualifying
condition is pretty big I mean that
means the patient count for at least
that condition could potentially be you
know in the millions without a doubt so
yeah I'm you know again I've heard some
stories about the effectiveness of
cannabis with autism and you know things
like Asperger's or Tourette's
neurological disorders and I'm not
really sure that again there's a sort of
one-size-fits-all solution to how how
effective cannabis is for autism well I
I know it helps me focus whenever I'm in
situations or stressful situations where
other people were like alright you can
smoke cannabis and that helps me you
know in those types of situations but I
am one of those where were some of the
rare ones on here who can fully function
well you know hmm you know on cannabis
whereas we've all come across people who
can't unfortunately and that that's you
know just nor here nor there it just is
what it is pencil let's see there are
some stories and people I mean cannabis
bringing autistic patients alive I mean
completely like people talking for the
first time putting sentences together I
mean like they've lived in a very you
know different world before they started
being treated with cannabis and and you
know again I'm not exactly sure I think
autism is
kind of a manifestation of several
potential neurological conditions and
you they may not all be the same but
certainly given the prevalence of the
cb1 receptor human brain you would think
that again cannabis would would have
some impact on on what it does and maybe
it's related to the same way that it
works with epilepsy but you'd think that
again there's there's some kind of magic
combination of using cannabis or being
able to their illness to give good end
up cannabinoid responses to maybe some
of these conditions lead to seizures and
whatnot well it's been known as the tree
of knowledge you know it brings you know
wisdom to those who imbibe in it correct
Sam I've read that and history books
regarding hashish and cannabis
I'm sure lots of people consider it the
tree of knowledge and tree of wisdom and
tree of medicine and tree of money I
mean all different kinds of things
Touche but I'm talking through history
I've actually read you know manuscripts
and things like that that seem to
reference I agree with you so I
definitely dr. I definitely see there's
aspects of cannabis bringing you know
affecting you know but of course it also
depends on what string went genetic to
that individual you know that's the
thing we also have to work on as well is
to find those those combinations that
work and yes you know it's
individualistic you know it's very hard
to come up with a swath recommendation
Darius has started on Kepner writes for
the last couple decades but now we're
starting to focus on not only single or
combination cannabinoid Suites in the
particular profile but the terpenes that
goes on with it or terpenes I should say
and that the amount of differ
profiles that can be presented from just
a hundred and fifty terpenes and some
hundred cannabinoids is already hundreds
of thousands but when you consider that
you can alter the profiles just by
increasing one of those terpenes or two
of them or there's an infinite variety
as as we all know from practical use of
cannabis for four decades you know each
cannabis that you get is a little bit
different and that's a fact it's mostly
just THC I'm talking about the past not
the future where we've got a lot of CBD
and we'll start to get other things out
there too yeah we're definitely looking
at you know new aspects of without a
doubt those of those ratios have you
know always altered and that's kind of
always been the frustration of some
patients when they finally find
something that works for them is that
works for that batch and then the next
batch that comes through it's either
slightly slightly altered in one way
shape or form and that's definitely you
know how it's grown how its maintained
how its harvested all those things and
consistency all the way through are one
of the most important things to do and
one of the reasons why bedrock an is so
successful with the Dutch government
because they just grow consistently and
they get consistent results which is not
only just better can't do that but once
they start flowering in the room have no
entrance by human beings it's untouched
by human hands that was one of the most
interesting things when I was there to
actually see one how far the lights were
from the canopy from when they put them
in because I saw a room that they just
put the plants in and I saw rooms with
full canopy of course to see the
evenness of the canopy was that was
interest it was nice to see I don't
usually see that but to see
that the rhone are completely sealed and
no one goes in once they're flowered was
something in a concept I have never
heard of much less seen in application
and to see it with doing it protecting
Everett patented it's called untouched
by human hands of course we did use
monkeys harvesting monkeys are yeah
special harvesting monkeys or beneficial
monkeys coconut monkeys that would twist
the coconuts but these guys twist the
bud job so are you training by monkey
see monkey do you got it that's med
Vance Avery but that's the only that
I've ever seen I've ever seen as the
bedrick can do that I've not seen my
whole life
it was rather surprising and to see some
of the problems that happen in there on
the floor etc I photographed that and
then so what happens in the ceilings and
things like that yeah I was rather
surprised by that grow all together but
it it was fascinating to see that
yeah then walking that all in so I don't
recommend that people so don't lock your
things in a room and walk away yeah
which may or may not be beneficial some
people but I doubt for everybody is they
gamma ray nuke it and sterilize it and
that reduces the terpenes up to 30% and
we know after seeing that facility why
they do that I'll leave it at that to
get rid of the traces of robots at their
ease grow
I know they should transfer over to
monkeys apparently he'd probably well
there you go and that's not fair to the
monkeys yeah yes because I keep half
past they collected on their face Sam
did the the monkeys eat cannabis when
you were in D in India did you see them
eat or attack the plants or the hash I
never saw it but not that I know of you
know part of the reason might be that
when you eat a plant it's mostly THC a
and you're gonna have very little effect
right it'll just pass through the body
yes other animals yes I've heard of it
yeah I've seen a pair of birds and you
know other other animal animals I've had
deer eat plants in Pennsylvania that I
grew it back in the day so I mean I've
seen wood rats just strip the bark off
the plants because they wanted it for
nest oh they took all the so they
literally rented the plant alive yeah
that wasn't healthy for the plan no I
don't recommend that
hmm yeah I've early early growing it
always had to put mesh screens over the
plants to make sure rats or any small
rodents don't want to not much on the
little tender shoots but yeah deer yeah
I had literally 41 out of 42 plants
eaten by deer so I yeah what was that
pre flowering or after flowering after
flowering really yeah
sometimes I'll eat the leaves and stuff
for the moisture because they can't find
water
they were the plants were destroyed they
were you could tell it was chewed is you
know they were still you know hanging on
the plants etc uh but they were lay
marks everywhere apparently they must
have come through his group
just got the game on and then crashed
then moved on but yeah there was lay
marks everywhere yeah so it was biker
gear yeah it was it was white tail is
Pennsylvania they have whitetail they
don't have mule deer like out here in
the West Coast well deer are serious
problem but I think wood rats might even
be worse and if you're in a civilized
area Gophers people been having problems
out here with sudden oak death attacking
cannabis plants and what just happens is
their plants just die and they can't
figure out why and I'm not your scene
problems with it so I can't really
comment it call causes the machinist of
the cellulose and it destroys any type
of movement of fluids so basically it
causes a machinist right as the the
roots and the stalk separate right in
there and the plank just literally
collapse it's under their own weight so
a friend of oil born seems to be
airborne I had a friend of mine who
grows in the Central Valley and he lost
last year he lost his entire crop in
greenhouse due to it so it's becoming a
yeah his entire greenhouse so actually
it was two years ago wasn't last year
because he got a successful project in
it identified yeah because he's a he's a
fourth-generation farmer in Central
Valley so he knows what he's doing and
has access to familiar with it and I
grew in the Central Valley for a decade
but yeah it's a recent phenomenon it's
it's a type of rod that is said know
death is kind of appeared in the last
five
- ten years and there it's a main
problem here in Auckland because there's
an Auckland oak and if they're trying to
preserve it as best as they can and
they've been susceptible to it I have an
Auckland oak in my backyard I have an
Oakland oak actually outside my window
in front of me here so I keep an eye on
them all the time and they've been you
know without any problem but it's been
unfortunately throughout the California
and moving up and around the west coast
that's a drag
I like coke priests because if you look
you can find chanterelles right I grew
up in Louisiana with huge live oaks I
used to play on you know live oaks the
size is almost the size of some of these
sequoias in diameter etcetera etcetera
so because these are you know there's
Evangeline Oaks etcetera it's so I've
always had a fondness for them and you
know how deep their roots are I was you
know rather surprised how shallow the
roots are of the Sequoias here in
California they're really well known for
having such however but says they make
for they make up for it in age and size
and girth well as well as being
fireproof I mean you know fire resistant
as well you know that's a lot of people
I know who use you know redwoods on
their houses out here in California for
but also insect resistant to the houses
the head as well net ski but yeah
there's a lot of problems right now out
here in California and throughout the
West because everything's on fire you
know up there daran up there BC and
stuff it's so you know the fires are
going and I know a lot of outdoor people
are you know upset because their crops
are being ash Don as well as you know
those particulates that are burning or
falling and you know getting into the
you know your crystals and everything on
your plants and you can't wash that sort
of thing off so it's causing a lot of
problems for people literally from
California to Missouri right now that
are growing outdoors so we feel for you
everybody
any suggestions a more what people could
do regarding if they're in fallout areas
of a fire as best as they can do to
protect them honestly I mean if you're
inside of a greenhouse or a building you
could try to filter the air that comes
in that your feet your supply and your
plants - so you're not spreading any
contaminants to them and that would
protect them if you can whereas in a
greenhouse it's it can be harder if
you're because most greenhouses have
open ventilation up on the roof so yeah
and outdoors what the hell can you do
yeah I honestly honestly don't know
maybe prayed the fires go away well
isn't it like any other natural disaster
areas it's basically [ __ ] taken as it
comes in if it's a [ __ ] up crop it's a
[ __ ] up crop I wonder if the yeah if
the hail comes or a flood comes or
hurricane comes you lose your crop and
you grow again next year yeah my buddy
up north
he had a hailstorm just tear through
parts of poo scoopy as the town called
there may be a thousand people living
there 500 please know how much a
hailstorm hits so hard that it caught it
killed my buddy's whole garden it
smashed it smashed Sun roofs out of
houses windows out of houses his 19 was
1977 GMC pickup mint-condition 70 pickup
smashed and dented all holding like
someone went over with golf balls golf
ball hammer and smashed everywhere on
the truck smashed windows wreaked havoc
like house insurance the siding on his
house smashed garden destroyed
everything it's a natural disaster while
nature was mad and she laid her [ __ ]
havoc across the lands that was that
pickup and move on that's the shitty
part but that's the reality of it and
that's the same with her and I'm sure in
Vancouver also it's true I mean there
was an before there was man nature had a
natural cycle but there would be a lot
of rain lightning would hit something
just repeated over and over and over
yeah they've just they've realized that
as I go to national parks all the time
they finally realized as opposed to
trying to control these fires that it's
best to just let them go because it's
they've realized after all these years
of conservation that it's really the
best thing that they can do is allow
nature to do what it does because that
type of burning clears the brush and
clears all the Arts undergrowth right
right but they've also realized to stop
doing that so much in recent history and
just allowing those houses to burn as
opposed they still try to save them as
they can but you know there's pine cones
that you know are triggered by fires
when they come through so they release
you know their seeds there's the whole
eco structure to you know these fires
that they have now come down I was a
villager
after a fire there's new life that's
right the fires created as well fire it
would not be that's it those seeds
wouldn't sprout or do anything without
the fire for most pinecones
that's what germinate summer activates
and we're something I don't know it's
also why you don't have those types of
old-growth forests because you don't
have that type of undergrowth as talking
we were talking last week about
old-growth forests and there's things
about old-growth forests all the
different layers of canopy and you know
flora that are there that exists that
you know they don't exist out here in
the West because of fires and how they
come through and they clear all that out
and you know natural selection becomes
the winner of the day out here in the
Sierras you know all the way up into
Canada you know those big areas up in
California and where the Sequoias are
they had small fires go through there
every 10 20 50 whatever years but the
squares were there for up a thousand and
most of them did just fine
it's very interesting to see out in the
series right now because of the fires
and we send our best of the lists that
are out there doing that the dirty work
and the fire jumpers and the
firefighters that are protecting
people's houses and everything right now
because they're doing work that
definitely needs to be done and we
respect what they're doing and that
stuff's crazy because I know a lot of
people rely on their hard work and
dedication so I'm gonna send a bong rip
out to those hard-working individuals or
just trying to save other people's lives
selflessly so shout out to them hey can
we get a bong rip they're down what are
you smoking on Sam
tangey you like it the tangi a lot
lately higher that's just that jab
around both tangi is very popular out
here in California right now and of
course they're mixing that with now
everything and you've got all kinds of
different strains coming out from it so
which of course comes from the Cali oh
and yeah so it's interesting to see all
these different sounds good you know
people should try to get not only the
taste they like but the effects a like
then I would also suggest in the
strength they prefer because you can
smoke smaller amounts to adjust but it's
nice if you can get what
right now I'm smoking some fresh off the
bud good guy out of SoCal some og
lemonade live resin fresh the bird yeah
yeah his uh as you can see it's uh I
want to start competing with this
company I'm gonna start one called fresh
from the bud pretty much smoking some
West Coast concentrates bubble hash what
flavor there D is purple crush PK
because she's the popular yes a while
ago a good one heard of any new strains
out and Amsterdam their Sam semi-retired
and not really very active so III hear
about him when people bringing to my
attention but I'm not out there looking
like I used to
gadget yeah you said your finger on the
pulse always that's why I was asking I
mean now there's just these multi poly
complex hybrids that you know they're
they're so complicated they're genetic
backgrounds that and they everybody just
takes really really really good female
clones and crosses them with other
really really really good that that
seems to be the fastest way to achieve
something that's probably going to be
really really really good yeah we live
in definitely a very poly world well it
was interesting to see it I would love
to fully originally we're doing testing
it was so interesting to see how very
close and ratios of course all these
cannabis were that I would say that 96%
of them all had very similar profiles of
THC
two other ratio so we didn't really have
terpene testing originally and I would
love to see that in comparison cuz you
know that's the difference between each
one of those strains when you grow a
hundred plants from some modern pop poly
multi complex hybrid you've got a
hundred plants the I sorry you're that
one expression you're you're gonna get a
diverse selection of expression and
that's a fun part selecting and finding
out which one of those is the the
reigning champ
you know because usually just gone off
of vigor you know or you know how fast
it grew its strength its overall health
you know as opposed to growing out I
mean have you ever did you ever go out
every hundred one of those and try every
single hundred of them to figure out
which profile was bass or you what did
you do for your selection just off of
smell taste well in the beginning I used
how bigger estimate was because if it
wasn't vigorous I wasn't so interested
but also smell flavor resin production
flower to leaf ratio and you know really
important things like the effect and
they were all shaped by your palate cuz
you even said you went toward the more
sweeter as opposed to the more of the
same amount I but I was also selecting
not just for myself but yes in general I
used my values of the judgments yes
because there's all kinds of strains
that have been lost that are different
you know flavor profiles that you know
and this is just the reality of just you
know farming as you were saying you know
it's it's a lot of experimentation as
long as you have the genes for that
cannabinoid which I don't see that as a
problem they're all out there
and as long as you have the genes for
the particular terpene synthases
only 150 that we've ID'd in cannabis so
far then you can breed any chemical
profile combination of a particular
cannabinoid profile matched with the
particular Turner P bro it's just a
matter of doing the work and things like
patient surveys like you were talking
about that gives a kind of feedback for
what particular group of cannabinoids
or cannabinoids work best with which
carpets for which medical indications
and it's a combination
what's that information is available
then breeders can target that
combination so start your germination
people get your seeds going find this
genetics mm-hmm find what works because
you know that's a great thing we all
have different flavors and we all have
different flavor tastes so I'm excited
to see what's gonna happen when these
you know with these legal markets and as
these different type of aspects of
genetics come online of you know this
next generation that you know puts
forward I'm very excited to see over the
horizon cannabis wise because it's gonna
go all kinds of directions not only from
the different states but also from you
know different international countries I
I can't wait till it's legal worldwide
and it's just like buying a bottle of
wine from which you can count from 100
150 different countries easy oh I'd love
to order my turban from South Africa oh
absolutely and yeah various other you
know Jack's but as well Sam though I
mean how many of these old-world
genetics are still out there that are
being you know I mean there's small X in
the world they're still patches of but
they had the best chance
find some pure for example Durban South
African genetics would be there I mean
I've got some but I'm sure there are
people there and they can grow it in the
best way for that area so that they can
produce in other words it'll be like
boutique cannabis produced for export
not like the way it used to be but way
better right because they've been
growing it already for generations so
they already know what they're using
conventional genetics right but I mean
I'm I'm curious as to how much of those
traditional genetics are still out there
because we know that the world's been
flood with these quasi euro kali
genetics over the past couple of decades
absolutely true and and till cannabis is
really legal we can't answer that
because nobody knows for sure right and
that has to be that research and that
gene mapping to actually break that
although the worst obvious examples of
what you're talking about is Mexico
Jamaica Morocco those three they're so
flooded I don't think you can find any
untouched land race genetics from those
three countries its unless somebody took
it as it
what about Thailand or Indonesia or
somewhere like that well III don't think
it's as bad but probably the worst
actually is Morocco because in Morocco
they don't call nails they allow males
to pollinate because they produced and
all of it is seeded so that means any
male introduction gets spread through
the community within a few years
everywhere the first generation it's
pure male pollen from an important
genetic the second year there's
thousands of plants that are half that
foreign genetic and the third generation
there's millions of plants that are a
quarter of that genetic so it gets
through the whole population one thing I
I doubt you can fine
untouched land races in Morocco it just
it's doesn't does it wouldn't be like
Jacobi ether it doesn't seem like it
would be so it's the same way for you
know people have always asked if I could
like go to Maui do you ever see real
Maui Wowi is like I don't think there
ever was real Maui Wowi and if it was
it's been eradicated a long time ago
from you know the helicopters and
harassment so all that's there is what's
brought to the islands you know that's
just the reality of the situation and
those matter the county there's a lot of
commercial production except for medical
in Hawaii now there used to be but
there's I mean there was enough
marijuana that who I was support in the
in the late sixties early seventies they
were an exporting but yeah it's reversed
and it's they're an important country
area they were so they wanted to make
itself to the turret yeah everybody I
know that was local before the the
medical that they have growing I mean
just gross and very small one to outdoor
tops and couple plants indoor tops
because you know they have to discretion
is key and they still fly helicopters or
their government staff legally and in
Hawaii you give them your GPS address
whether you're allowed to grow five or
something you have to tell them the
location and Ali did yes correct now and
I know that there's I want to go in
December I hope to check out the
facility there in Maui go through
they're producing but I think there
already had just a short production run
and they already ran out so it's one of
those initial situations that we've seen
way when you they've got vertically
integrated setups like that that it
takes time for the grow to catch up to
the consumer so it's definitely they're
going through that growing pain as we
speak
well I used to in the early 70s I
thought Hawaiian
and the reason was was because they were
using narrowly drug genetics in Hawaii
and was some really really really
interesting psychedelic trippy tech
cannabis but that that's cannabis and
again that was brought to the island
there doesn't seem to be any type of was
it quiet variety snow grown in Hawaii by
you know people who would bet on the
hash trail and stuff and pretty much any
cannabis from Maui was just called Maui
Wowi correct it wasn't necessarily the
same I would not be surprised if that
was true for sure
yeah it's that's the rumor I've been
told because again they were growing you
know I have artists renditions I even
have one here for artists thing for Maui
gold you know Molly's finest cannabis
grown on that mountain Haleakala and its
hold on here it's being brought over and
it's it's just it's from the 70s it's
kind of a it's just one of those it's a
print so yeah that's one of those crazy
things fine Canada set apart for the
price harvester done on slopes of
Haleakala yeah they just it was more of
just advertising and and just things
like that it wasn't any type of specific
genetic from even people that I've
talked to they were just as you stated
Sam they were long leaf equatorial
genetics that were brought to the
islands and grown apparently very well
it grew
you know those equatorial 's apparently
yeah because they're resistant to the
kind of problems that you get in wet hot
earth photo period environment and them
sure a lot of them did super nice and
how would you rate the quality at
cannabis because you got
you had tried some of that Maui back in
the day yes oh yeah I thought some of it
was almost as good as the haze almost as
good as the best Thai sticks it was
really really really good excellent
yeah the first time I saw Thai stick so
I didn't believe that was actually
canvas will grow Hayes and his hybrids
in Hawaii two that came out really
really really nice they didn't want to
grow super big giant plants because they
didn't wanna Thebes to see it they
weren't afraid of the police because
they were legal under that program but
they could only grow I think it was five
plants or something but yeah they they
thought the quality came out super nice
here's somebody if they won't they want
to see this again the the marigold so I
got this in place of that I started
smoking that yes it's Einstein holding a
pipe which if he was you know tobacco
pipe but yeah it's definitely I picked
that up ten years ago and Maui and PI oh
yeah no I understand went to Maui yeah
yeah you know it was this place to hang
out over the guilt of the atomic bomb I
guess who knows I don't think he's ever
been there but of course somebody will
produce a picture of him in Hawaii and I
you know with a lay around his neck and
some Bermuda shorts I
all stunned over your bone pipe last
week there Sam I have to say that was
definitely the mic drop of the month for
quite a few people who have the very top
half of a human skull and they use it
for you you know when you break up buds
you make the joint with passion and weed
or with passion tobacco some Europeans
do and they have like a little a hash
bowl that they use well the heat is
these a kissing skull as a rolling tray
yeah but it's a rolling bowl yeah that's
a whole other level a whole other level
that's yeah that that's some hunter s
Thompson in his briefcase sort of [ __ ]
they were all either a polar Trebek yeah
I've seen Tibetan monks that have you
know the knuckle necklaces that are
carved into little skulls they actually
take the knuckles from the dead monks
and actually carve them into skulls and
make them into I guess kind of prayer
beads I guess you've seen that as well I
saw that kind of stuff when I was there
I liked the Nepali people and the
Tibetan people
I like them too very interesting had to
be kind of culturals you know submersion
that you were in but to look around and
see all that eat with the Tibetans I was
dealing with were in Ladakh which is
what's commonly called Indian Tibet and
China got most of Tibet but part of
Tibet was the Indians took control of
and that's but but capital city is leh
and it's Ladakh and yeah it was
very very Tibetan when me and my wife
went there but now I've heard there's
more and more and more Indian business
people you know moving up there to
control the this is a lot of torment
it's unbelievable place if you ever get
a chance to visit but don't don't go if
you are expecting a lot of
infrastructure what they've got is just
age-old tradition it's Tibetan and it's
not screwed over the way it has been in
China by yeah China would say just to
you know modern world and that's better
someone might disagree hey bubble man
how we doing over here I know you're I
see you in chat I'm doing okay I didn't
okay I'm listening I'm enjoying it's
hard because I've got a bit of a choppy
connection but yeah dude you guys are
saying in the day for sure I've I've
eventually got to get back to the event
here but I want to stay as long as I can
and hang out listen to church okay we
can see you know I nominate new pope
Pope at church and I say long live that
Jen and bubble man if he can't be here
that's the way it goes that's it can't
claim any type of Pope - dude there we
go bong rip I can do that outstanding I
don't even have my gmail here up and I
have no way of puffing for house Church
so I'll just pour you Marcus we will
puff when our adversary blow right your
direction thank you well I'm in Toronto
don't forget and so don't be blowing it
in the wrong
let's play a little catch-up oh yeah oh
sorry
you say some no problem excuse me oh
this is my cat scotch captured a bird
just today or last night some time and I
come up my hallway and there's some
feathers in the floor and I might go and
catch another burden here to eat I'm
looking for the carcass and there's no
carcass so I'm thinking they ate the
whole thing and they're just the
feathers leftover couple hours later I'm
looking on my windowsill in the kitchen
getting a drink for making my coffee and
there's a little bird on my windowsill
hiding behind the vitamins so I grabbed
a towel and I grab this I put it over
the thing and I move the vitamins out so
delicately so nicely they save this
little bird I can feel a little
heartbeat just pounding away in the
cloth and the towel
I bring him outside halfway down my
driveway to the tail end in my trunk and
I put him on the back of the truck and a
little [ __ ] [ __ ] flies directly back
into the [ __ ] Lois it goes and hides
behind the couch it's like you're free
man [ __ ] so now I can't find him you
can't get him on from under the couch
and the cats are gonna probably eat them
so mother nature is running its course
once again natural selection happening
it is I tried to save it man it was
saying right back in that's why you got
to close the door behind you when you go
outside what's the first thing I just
had him in the towel oh I just wanted to
get him out there yeah that reminds yeah
I had my own that reminds me I was like
11 years old and I caught us caught a
garter snake and it was wrapped around
my arm and I brought it into the kitchen
and my mom was asleep and I'm I get I
got a jar and I got its tail in and I
tried
throw its head down and then put the cap
on and it just springs straight out of
the jar goes right behind everything on
the counter and I'm just frantically you
know looking for it I was like just grab
it I turn around and there's my mom with
her arms aren't what the hell are you do
I have a snake in the house you brought
a snake in there oh yeah so what you
should have said was you found a snake
in your house and you wanted to get rid
of it so your mom wouldn't get up to
that I wasn't that bright in the moment
back then I was I was a deer in the
headlights I was like I was a good
little Catholic boy so you know I
confessed immediately I was yeah I
learned a lighter that's y'all knew you
couldn't last without us I like the
picture of bubble man it kind of looks
like he's pointing this finger down that
you saying don't tell lies well I
learned that along you know you know in
my adulthood
you know don't lie that way you don't
have to cover up your own tracks you
don't have to remember what you said you
know it's one of those life lessons you
know this little white lies sometimes
you have to say in life but you know in
the short term lies are better or easier
but in the long the truth is yeah you
gotta always play the long game in that
result you know you're only selling
yourself short well who the hell wants
to be deceived
I mean how lame is that let's just
deceive our friends in the play the
American public apparently like it
because look what we keep electing you
know we keep electing the fools and
people go to Las Vegas
that's what is it for
what is it for to be deceived you mean
that's not really the Eiffel Tower
you're on mute there
bubbleman that pen looks really good man
how's it working
dude it's delicious I gotta say and you
Jam like a ridiculous amount of terpenes
into like any type of cannabinoid
mixture and inhale it it's generally
gonna taste pretty now we sold out of
the pens and the cartridges today and
yesterday so it's been wonderful my
friends actually we beans and then they
filled them up with roses so they we
were actually selling rosin filled pens
at my booth but really it was them
selling Rafi fill bullpens but I'd just
like to be a part of that I like
watching people come up and you know we
I'd watch them like get it going and
kind of teach them how to use it and
that was really exciting it's a repeat
yeah I gotta get hold of Tony he's got
one for me I gotta try it looks too good
to have to it looks like finally one
that will work for me yeah I think
you're in for us some luck at yeah I
think he has the California smoothie for
you which is like strawberry banana goo
mixed with climates ridiculous oh my god
my tongue will be so confused by flavor
and that's okay there's worse things I'm
not worried about well I do appreciate
ya know it's a little choppy for me here
and it was a little bit rough to try and
get a church going but even if we can
pull off a couple hours I'm super stoked
man and you appreciate we're beautiful
email the other day and I meant to reply
to you wait I've just been traveling and
I've been busy I read it on my phone
when I landed actually yes and we also
love to have you here on hash Church but
as often as we can yes wait hi and
welcome and thank you Marcus who's gonna
be our special guest spur for next week
I mean
I can think of all kinds of people but
just whose make a promise to show I
haven't really asked too many people but
a promise send out an email today and
it's gonna be a very long email list and
in fact I would ask you guys as well if
you can compile any emails or contact
info for people that have been on the
skinny I want to invite Jessica back I
want to invite Samantha LV back I want
to get like you know put an invitation
out to die after Grinspoon and all these
different people that have been shown
over the years it would be uh it'd be
pretty awesome to have just like a nice
flow of people and and Natasha said she
would also help out with that so looking
forward to it
as much as I want to be here next week I
will not be here I will be sitting in my
seats in the stadium in New Orleans so I
will not be able to be on board so I'll
miss you it that's all good I'll be back
the week after for sure and continue
onward it goes to New Orleans well the
one behind it is what we're concerned
about and the one behind that as well so
we're keeping an eye and that's happened
before that's happen to me for Katrina I
actually bought actually my sister and
her kids and myself tickets to that game
and I had to cancel the game so if that
was the reality I still have those
tickets by the way and that's just the
reality of being from the south is you
know when hurricanes happen you cancel
you don't fight the system you can't
fight the system mother end of story so
if that happens then I will be here you
know for sure next week I won't fly out
on Friday to New Orleans so but follow
by then and I'll keep you posted
Maldon yeah and I love to be here and if
that's a opportunity for me to be here
then I'll enjoy that as well but I yeah
these hurricanes are just man that that
that I mean harvey was bad enough for
houston i mean
there's no municipality I know could
survive four foot of water falling on it
I mean anywhere much less now you know
or am i coming right behind which is
just absolutely devastated the Bahamas I
mean beyond some some places beyond
recognition I saw a video today of
somebody on a beach in the Bahamas and
there's no water at the beach they had
literally the storm had sucked all the
water four miles off the Atlantic
completely so it's just the amount of
force that that thing is generating and
the strength it's not even funny so I
have people that are actually in the
path of that so I send my love and I
wish the best for you because people
can't afford to get out that's the
reality and I wish them nothing but the
best and we got other ones right behind
that so I don't know how after seeing
these storms that are considered
once-in-a-lifetime once in a century
we've had five of them in the last you
know 10 years or so I before humans or
at least Americans who deny climate
change start to believe that we're
actually having effect on the reality
that we're seeing and I can't see with
this type of evidence out there that
people still deny it it's amazing
doc it's got to be absolutely
dumbfounding for you to mean it from a
man of science to watch constant denial
of actual science replicated science and
for them to go off of [ __ ] papers
that have actually been debunked to
continue to deny a man's influence on on
its on the weather that's happening is I
don't get it yeah by Senators who states
need billions of dollars in government
aid right but it's a it's amazing
well not amazing but imagine if there
would have been a cannabis industry in
Houston I mean it would it if there was
an industry like cannabis on the
in industrial areas of you know large
cities like Houston like it is in Denver
it would have been completely wiped out
Oh hands down there's no way I could
survive the week without light
no way well just all the water and then
the you know the water is filled with
all kinds of runoff and toxins and it
would basically just wipe out your
entire crop and you'd lose you know a
lot of equipment and your facilities
would just become completely fouled with
all that mucky water yeah I mean you see
what what people are doing is they're
coming in and you know gutting their
house at the water line right so you see
everyone removing their there the
sheetrock and I guess it would be a good
time to be georgia-pacific selling
sheetrock her Louisiana these sheetrock
companies are probably making a bundle
but you'd have to imagine again that you
know like with a something as
devastating as this I mean it's like not
only something like this like if this
were to happen if there were cannabis
industry in there all the people who
work there while right away their houses
are flooded right their jobs are
basically on hold right because they're
whole you know operations is completely
fun I mean your whole life is just
completely devastated
just because of a hurricane and you know
and then out in Oregon you know I mean
the whole states on fire for Christ's
sakes it's unbelievable I mean we're
gonna find again someone had made this
comment and chat earlier that outdoor
Oregon and in 2017 is going to be the
year of the concentrate because
everyone's gonna have to distill there's
stuff to make it not smoky I mean III
don't know what the impact of follow the
all the smoke in the air is going to be
on on these these plants but um
certainly all the ash good thing not
good yeah we were talking about before
you came on Doc it was half without the
smoke in the ash and it not only you
know coats the plants but also you know
coats to the rosin you know and that
that you know it you can taste it you
have actually if anybody has smoked
cannabis that's been around a fire you
can taste it I mean there's no doubt
about it it alters the flavor and
everything so it's very I as Sam was
saying and unfortunate reality is you
know it's not good cannabis and that's
just the reality of farming you know
it's you've lost that year yeah is it
translated into the concentrates that
you make from it to like you say you
didn't taste it in the cannabis is that
like smoking flour but you know your
tree yeah because it gets them that gets
in the glands you know and it stores it
doesn't stay and I mean if it does stay
I mean the plant continues to build
around it so it's actually inside the
crystals themselves correct Sam it's no
bueno
yeah it's no bueno that's with it in
Jamaica often they try to dry herb
around fires and certain people do it
and it's like you just smoke out the bud
what's that sin I said it's a no-no
enough said it's a no-no it's bad and
unfortunately as we're saying you know
the entire western United States is on
fire right now now as well as I mean
you're dealing with that all up in DC I
mean fires are going like mad out there
as well right all right the whole
province seems to be on fire right now
and I can't imagine it not affecting
damn near everyone's crop so is it just
dry right now is our rains not coming
through is that why it's continuing to
burn up their pine beetle kill yeah see
we have that problem here in California
from the last year's drought there's
millions of trees throughout the Sierras
right now that are just dead they're
trying to cut them out I mean you can
literally see them brown against the
green all summer long and it's so
spotted without you could see why you
know something like that would continue
and why there's such you know kindling
out there for these fires but I hate to
hear of you know that type of beetle
breakout that's cause I mean that's
you're losing tons of forests mother
nature's doing a purge that forest needs
to regrow and everything because it's
dead now but it's just unfortunate
there's human populations in the path
without sort of stuff like I drove from
that goo right up to Prince George and
fir about six seven hundred kilometres
it was so smoky you couldn't see the
valley you know a bunch of miles ahead
Ian because the smoke would cover the
mountains and then of both the last
hundred or sold two hundred kilometers
it cleared up but it also caught up this
way I'd say the whole province was the
lower province was hit for sure with all
the smoke I toward the upper province in
the mid summer when all the fires were
happening and there was no fires up
there and no smoke or anything had
reached up there but there's no dad
beetle kill up there it's all plush
beautiful green forest first far as you
can see it's quite nice to see but down
this way the lower province is just
devastated with pine beetle kill and
it's a matchbook
storms and you get one lightning strike
and it just goes yep that's look lights
off and just [ __ ] rips it's it's
killed a lot of wildlife the whole works
devastated this whole province in one
way or another then you can do about
either just is what it is
well hopefully it rains come through and
quiets it down there makes it a little
better
damn beetles yeah pine beetle used to be
cold enough that'd kill him but man-made
lakes and all that sort of stop has
changed weather patterns up here and
everything so the winter winters are not
as long as well and of course the global
changing pattern weather and all that
kind of stuff right as well we don't get
the winters like we used to get here
even close not even close
by Halloween we'd have snow that stayed
right through till April you know we
have 20 to 40 below months two three
months maybe sometimes but yeah this is
so [ __ ] tasty and what flavor is that
this one is the Viper with Jamaican Sour
Diesel terpenes
but the really tasty one is at my booth
right now which is the where is my bike
no wooden swiss things yeah I like I
like just the name where is my bike I
can't wait to try this string it sounds
so it is so Amiga Haze it's a super old
cut of an amnesia but some type of
kushai think it was great
unique definitely nice but to say I wish
I had the news they usually would send
me the ICRS news for some reason it's
coming later in the day now so I don't
get it to give all the update on what's
the latest stuff on the news because
some people asked what's up
so I'm sorry it just depends on when it
comes out when it comes out in early
morning when we do the show I can
actually read it and but for some reason
it's coming out in the afternoons now so
I don't have it sometimes that's how it
was
yep exactly so I just try to go with the
flow of it that was why I guess we lost
Wade yeah he texted me he said that he
was having a hard time getting a
connection I'm running connections of
it's spotty so it might make it more
difficult for you guys not to sure you
do come in choppy but everybody else
seems to come in as normal
Sam's as usual choppy self you guys are
usually pretty good for me well a fat at
home but well I still you know it was
Natasha earlier was like oh maybe you
could just skip the day and I thought
about us me I could skip it to Ava like
a week before the three year anniversary
when we've never missed a single day
we're gonna take a day off before the
three-year anniversary
uber and I raced back so this event what
is the event you're at saris sundaes
karma cups so it is it's pretty roots
but I'll tell you you know like poor
Sara gets a lot of hate I mean I seen
one guy posting the other day hey lying
all the math and he's saying that so she
sold this many passes for for this much
money you know of these for this much
money oh look at Mattie private it his
account that's funny and then added up
like a million boxer half a million
marks are four hundred thousand dollars
and it's just you know people are trying
to make it seem like she's just killing
it and crushing it when really she's so
stressed out there's so many logistics
there's so much work and she's done a
good job in my opinion the venue is not
the best venue in the world it's a it's
a parking lot
hole in the ground type of thing with
booths in it but she's bring there are
people rocking through this thing left
right and center weenie we're non-stop
for 10-plus hours yesterday we didn't
get a break and that's home but because
there's Pat I barely know the size of a
parking lot maybe a half an acre a
quarter of an acre even maybe smaller
but good well hey what's up like haters
are always gonna hate but you know it
costs and takes a lot of time and energy
and people don't realize the logistics I
mean back when we would throw events I
mean just the cost of insurance alone we
had just one event you had to have over
a million dollars in insurance just to
hold the event you know I'm saying so
III don't get off where people start to
start throwing that type and unless
they're actually on the inside and see
what actually goes down you'd be amazed
how actually thin those margins actually
are you know you know bubbleman but it's
it's amazing when I see people on the
outside starts you know punching bag on
people and stuff like that it's just
unfair unless you've actually done it
and throwing these types
things you know there's no need for you
to comment just either go and enjoy and
rate the event for exactly what it is
you know or isn't you know and if you
don't like it go through your event you
know people's energy in trying to do
something on their own event they wanted
the event that someone else is throwing
it's just like easier to criticize what
people are doing and I spoke at the
normal part of the conference yesterday
normally I spoke on a panel of growers
and we were just kind of talking about
that very thing and it's uh it's people
yeah people are a bit funny I've
complained about access there's a
hundred and fifty new stores that are
gonna open up in Ontario to sell Canada
this and everyone's upset about it
they're gonna call they're gonna control
intimate because like what they tried to
do the same thing with booze when booze
was legalized but they can't control it
it's available on every street corner
restaurants can you [ __ ] sell it like
for God's sakes there's bars they're
just places where people go and drink
booze and the exact same thing will
happen with cannabis LCB types stores
that are government-run will never be
able to control it
they'll just be one part of it and I
think people are so limited in their
ability to see the bigger picture they
only see their slice of their pie that
they want and it's like well that's
great but you know there's a lot of
people out there and they require all
the slices of the pie to be taken care
of evenly so I think that with the
normalization and the acceptance of
cannabis as a medicine and a
recreational drug in society all of
those things are gonna come to fruition
vapor lounges aren't gonna go away vapor
lounges are the new bars for cannabis
away I can promise you no matter what
any government does it will never go
away
we tell them what we want that's how
good government works everyone should
remind themselves of that but the
government is what's going on we decide
as a society and then we make it happen
and you know it's been slow in Canada
but nonetheless it's exactly what's been
happening we say and we wanted to we got
hep growing we said we wanted to grow
our own personal licenses slowly but
surely we got exemption 56 isn't a MMAR
ours
the end of May our system so badly they
tried to get rid of it we fought in
court and we won under charter breaches
so in my opinion fight for what you and
the things out there that you might not
see as being the way it should be then
make it away and take a giant steaming
[ __ ] on someone else's dream well we
almost had that happen to us this week
actually in the United States we had the
war backer blue an hour was originally
the word bakka Farr amendment was
initially pulled and we thought we were
going to be without federal protection
anymore which basically the Rohrabacher
bloomin our prohibited the federal
government from going into any state
where there is a legal cannabis market
be it medical or recreational and could
not you spend any money it's the whole
reason of one why I won my case against
the federal government is because after
a certain amount of time the federal
prosecutor could could not take me into
court because they would have to pay him
to go into court and by doing so they
would have violated this amendment that
has been passed alongside with the
budget amendments so there was some
budget shenanigans this past week where
Democrats and Republicans didn't think
they were going to have anything go
through positively but for some reason
Pelosi and the Democrats put up a sort
of a coup and educated 45 who is the
current president and he capitulated and
went along with Democrats and initially
it's made sure that any type of
amendments were that were controversial
amendments were pulled and therefore it
looked like the Rohrabacher blew an hour
was dead and it was for about 12 hours
until the next business day when the
house in the Senate passed their own
amendments of the word backward bloom in
our therefore reaffirming our
protections and passed the House and the
Senate so it's attached to the current
budget that is funded through December
and it looks like it will be continually
added to each successful budget because
our successful lobbying has got enough
Republican senators on board that we
have a momentum that we haven't seen
before and this is many years of hard
work and I have to thank a lot of
activists that it made this a reality
from you know eight years of failure of
the Blum and I were for amendment before
it actually got passed and now it went
from something that we never thought was
the possibility to now becoming a
mainstay addition to each budget and
budget amendment which is as best as we
can get until federal prohibition
changes this is the best type of
protection that we have currently to
stave off any type of federal
interference into our individual liberty
situations that are happening in these
individual states via the Tenth
Amendment we're allowed to you know
exist and be our own little democracies
even in the face of you know federal law
and of course that interference would be
very costly to the industry needless to
say and we were all initially in our
industry pretty worried for that you
know 24 12 to 24 hours until they
actually passed this amendment if we
were wondering if this was the we were
we part of a backdoor deal that throw us
to the wolves or to sessions and you
know the DEA and I'm coming in so
fortunately they the momentum that we
have has been continued and it seems
it's going to continue further because
we're continued to lobby these
Republican and Democratic senators were
having meet and greets with them
constantly those that are voted against
us in the past this is how we built the
momentum to get them to vote for us
consistently so congratulations to many
hard-working people and many staffers in
Rohrabacher and Blum an hour for their
very hard determination but this is also
a friendly reminder people wake the [ __ ]
up we have to still get involved this is
still very fragile if they want to take
us down this is one way that they could
have easily reopened the floodgate so
you are still watching and if you're a
US citizen you can call your
representative and your senator and tell
them to stop this federal interference
and still make your voice heard you're
an individual citizen and each voice
that calls represents a hundred to a
thousand even up to ten thousand people
per phone call so go out to your town
hall meetings talk to your Senators your
representatives make them aware that you
are an informed citizen and that you
need to be aware of how you feel
regarding cannabis and what's going on
you can still get out there and get
involved so you know don't complain get
off your ass and do something about it
you know contact your representative
your senator and make them aware of the
changes and get involved locally again
remember 2018 s next year these
elections that are happening if you want
to see change get behind Canada get
behind cannabis you know support of
candidates out there because there are
out there and you know go out there go
support them right now they could use
your phone banking they could use your
dollars they could use your you know
ability to pitch in in any way shape or
form you may have a talent maybe you can
only talk on a phone well go down and
phone bank volunteer get yourself
actively involved you know you have a
chance to be active in this democracy to
make us make the future easier at for us
because we could have quickly found this
we
ourselves all back behind the gun again
and having the federal government
gunning for us so it is still that
fragile so our voices still have to be
active so don't forget that people we
love you but we still can get more
involved Tony good to see you buddy yeah
welcome Tony I was just uh pontificating
yeah that was like that was actually a
conversation I think you were talking
about the same thing where they were
trying to pass something in the budget
bill where it was the point that's
exactly it yeah and so we were worried
they were you know we were possibly as
an industry thrown under the bus but
they amended it and it's continued and
moving forward so again that's credit to
the momentum that we've built but we
still have more momentum to move yeah
but it's just a stopgap measurement
until December the 8th so you know I
mean it's [ __ ] I mean the way that
you know this government and it's run
you know is that you know again raising
the debt ceiling and doing what they
need to do to have all their bills paid
this amendment is just a rider on the
appropriations that basically the House
Appropriations Committee has to approve
the spending of all you know years and
i's tax dollar right and god knows
they're not the best stewards of that
money well until we have a law or
something actually changes this is the
best we have and so we're trying to get
behind that but that's why we also why I
was ranting is we need people involved
so that would they if enough of these
people hear from their constituency
regarding this issue they're going to
leave us alone
and we're already affecting some of
these Republican and Democratic senators
but there's still many out there we
still have to affect change so this is
Hill it's number the 8th right I mean
well and then it will be continued on
with the next the same way with the
night
I mean this is unfortunately the game
the government's playing and yes they
are punting everything and it is you
mean they've got everything from Dhaka
to you know the wall and all that on top
of that tax cuts that they're gonna try
and all pass all in this time in
December I mean that's too much to punt
and on top of that you've got 45
insulting the Republicans daily now so
even those that her his supporters he's
pissing on no pun intended and I mean I
just the cohesiveness is not going away
however we have enough Republican and
Democratic support and continue to
maintain that that any continuing budget
in the future this continues to get
added to and will continue to be added
towards so yes it is up until December
eighth but they will either there will
be a slight time between where they will
take the budget and they will be either
shut down the government temporarily
which they won't do in December because
it's the holidays they're not going to
do that to their government employees so
it's gonna be just another continuation
until you know remember the government's
fiscal year starts October to October so
we're already emergency funding for the
year so they have to resolve the
situation however they're still going to
use all these political realities doc of
the wall etc as you know negotiation
point or at least 45 is going to sorry
this we should get out of politics and
getting up back onto cannabis but that's
sorry sorry people that's just a
separation of church and state sorry
sorry blaming that's that's me trying to
fill space here great at yeah I
appreciate it 70s mama in the chatroom
saying that a bubble man pan is
currently ripping her head off
good to hear 70s mama I'm glad
like 70s mama I like the name of it
she's got a podcast called Sisterhood of
the Traveling plants I like the name
very very very funny that's awesome
I am Samurai Sam really was kind of the
inspiration behind the the penny
inadvertently by ash flaming all about
the shitty things that are in behind the
pens and how dangerous they can be and
how inexpensive and non sustainable and
fun now
Omicron introduced me to Gary turn me on
to the whole up tech family so shout out
to samurais Sam for for helping us out
big time because he and I and Gary
wouldn't be here where we are with this
pen right now without you brother so
good thanks for your your part well and
his knowledge drop has still got to be
one of the most epic ones own you know
hash Church where he broke all those
down because that seemed to be the the
way things are going and I mean look
what has changed you know across the
industry you know look how everything is
really improved so it's really made
consumers aware of what's actually there
inhaling and it made them realize what
they need to look for in these types of
devices you know it's why a lot of us
have back to our either manual or
electric way of imbibing as opposed to
now you from those frustrations look
what you know do you and Tony have
created along with you know alacrán you
know you've taken it to the next steps
because now we know what was bad and
what's out there so we know then what we
wanted to see so now you're creating one
of those aspects of things that people
want to see you need apparatus that you
can utilize and make viscous things like
Rosen through that you can inhale what
that you're on the go and you know that
didn't exist so again kudos
I still owe you yours Etienne just think
I just need to draw it to you today no
problem are you in the Oakland are you
yeah I'm in Oakland I'm just chillin
we're gonna go for a bike ride and I
gotta go see Edie check in with him
honey what are you going on that get me
probably after breakfast some breakfast
after this and although it looks to be
kind of hot today so we may want to ride
later in the afternoon so maybe this
afternoon
alright well let me know when you're
done biking I'm gonna I'm gonna go visit
think Duchess his garden nice never seen
what I've seen pictures of it looks nice
looks pretty good right and she she
plays her steel drum to her plants did
you see that yeah yeah she did a video
the other day it's really cool yeah I
had no idea this was like a professional
steel drum player but she played like a
Beethoven or something just show me the
goods the inventor of that actually
actually teaches at West Virginia
University oh yeah he came on a few
years ago as a musical teacher and of
course I still have friends that are
musicians they're in Morgantown because
it's still a strong music scene and yeah
so he's he's doing that and that's
that's that's quite a talent that's
quite a musical sound all unto itself
so kudos there what does that the last
the thing I remember about that was when
I was a kid we used to watch like Sesame
Street or there's some show that we
watched and it was like the make they
showed like a real cool like after kids
program or something it was like they
showed like people rolling out a barrel
like a trash can and they would show
them cutting off the bottom it would
show forming it you know what is this
and they're like forming the whole steel
drum
from from just throw away material
repurposing that's what it was that a
musical instruments out of the Castaway
oil containers and look now it's a
complete musical instrument that's world
round you know but it was all made from
throw away and I need to have a
percussion and it made such a beautiful
unique sound that yeah it's still
continues to this day but she's quite
talented as a grower as well as a hash
maker but as well as the musician so
good job there
goddess keep it up just very good very
very good at the steel drum and I'm and
I'm a big believer in having music in my
gardens I always had classical or jazz
always 24/7 going on you know in my
Gardens when I was growing because I
always found a good response I know some
people like heavy metal or any types of
things but I've always been a yeah I've
always found plants respond to music how
do you know I don't know who ever talked
about this before how did have you ever
heard of where you've seen anyone use
like just like you can in your house in
my house has these little ultrasound pet
devices pest device that like pushes all
kind of hits a frequency that we can't
hear sometimes can be harmful for dogs
but it pushes bugs you know out of the
room and we don't really talk about
using sound for in the gardens but I've
you sound before anyone else has or if
there's any like great device out there
that it wouldn't just raves about that
maybe should be shared out there you
know I had a sound device tried
something like that but it didn't work
for ants ants it did not work for at all
but there's some hearty kind of ants
around here as well in the Bay Area well
I think I think that's the one field
that we've got everything else to UV
lighting the scrubbing yeah filtration
air filters and I think that that's
still open you know because there are
frequencies so we could if we could test
the different types of spider mites and
kinds of bugs and then kind of bring
them into more of a study of it about
we'd find a frequency that push them out
of the garden right sonica frequencies
that would make them uncomfortable so
that they wouldn't want to nest you know
or lay eggs you know that's the that's
what you want any type of you know
preventing but at the same time you
would think that they would if that type
of situation would exist that would
exist on the large scale agricultural
you know reality you know I'm saying
like large scale nft systems would what
do you think of that Sam sonic pest
control
what are you aware of I've never tried
it I I can't really comment but I in
Sector domes to attract them to traps
either for monitoring or for destroying
them but no I've never used vibrations
of any kind and we know plants are
affected by vibrations and things like
that
maybe they're affect by good ones
the insects don't seem to be affected by
them well I guess they're either good
vibrations or bad preparations to put
out what you doing yeah I think you look
this up because I'm pretty sure that one
if it's a beach boys we know it's good
vibrations that's funny so I had these
things that I bought on Amazon these
little pest control thing since there
was a lot of spiders actually in the
house and I was like kind of allergic to
them so people say spiders don't fight
but they love to bite me for whatever
reason but as soon as I put these in
each one of the rooms
no one bugs on I'll tell you what the
frequency is because I was worried about
my dog and they said something about
cats do you have any plants at the house
I do
it said something about there was a
certain way that's a look ultrasonic
electronic pest insect repellent device
planned or hybrid sound so good plugin
women and your pest woes probably have
to be really intense but there's
probably a reason why it hadn't been
developed before but I see 20 Hertz mice
will run they've got different sounds if
you kind of google it some of the some
of the stuff out there is [ __ ]
but there's definitely it set the
frequencies are you dial it in depending
on your pests see that's the thing it's
just set to free the only cell devices
that are set to certain things like it's
a certain frequency of range like 20 I'm
looking at where that was some of it's
some of us kind of scammy
see here what is the name of the brand
just out of curiosity sorry I thought
you may have known up top of your head
either you already forgot anti Prabang
right people that's an easy one pests
reject all right well on Wikipedia they
have you kind of call out the [ __ ]
ones the good ones or whatever does it
work on mother-in-law's it allowed two
weeks it does not work on
mother-in-law's well you could change if
you could change your frequency I bet it
would
two weeks for sound waves to affect pets
past with an established I just think
it's unjust just like it sits in its
really early stage but I bet you
somebody out there
yeah they've got all kinds of Gophers
safe for pets if you've got Gophers in
your house but they do throw those they
throw those I'm sure they throw like you
know if you've see Gophers in your house
they're in the attic our honest review
okay yeah there's a bunch of them out
there this one's a micro and corporate
it's funny there's one from a micron
corporation and so these are just direct
plug in the wall type of modules yeah it
takes it says takes a few weeks to build
up the frequency or I put a bunch of my
I put one in every room let it all
bounce around it takes two weeks for
them to get so [ __ ] tired of the
noise yeah that's what I think it is but
I think if you started with your garden
with a frequency that was really like
annoying it'd be like it's just a
horrible like rock concert that was just
just no one was in tune and like they
came to a party and they were like looks
like a good party in the tank like all
horrible combinations of sounds and like
almost like an MRI probably for them you
know MRI skin and how long have you been
using it a few months there's a couple
of months online there's some having it
more expensive so I'm looking for
cheaper this one I found the Guardian
this is for outdoor this has control for
this has raccoons deer squirrels cats
Chipmunks bats mice and rats and you can
actually dial it in on the back and then
you could say predator volume this is
pretty cool well so that one you can
directly dial into your okay that makes
sense if you had deer
like a Turkey's so it does that a turkey
setting um it does not have a turkey
sitting this one does have a
mother-in-law said it now ah well there
you guys a lower frequency humming bass
really would play some drum and bass
your mother-in-law will go away crank on
Bassnectar at five in the morning that's
great
just show me ready for the door so yes
serious [ __ ] going on with this
hurricane Oh
everyone that's in Florida my prayers
and thoughts out to you my family is
their mother dad brother everyone in
Miami Broward I haven't turned on the TV
this morning but I was watching it till
I 2 in the morning I said my best man
and I don't miss that you grew up with
that right yep I was in New Orleans
Florida I was actually in Kansas so I
have had tornadoes hurricanes floods
I've got I would say probably PTSD from
storms but I don't know it's always a I
always have this fear now that I'm I
thought I was okay from earthquakes
where I'm at and then I realize like I'm
like right on a fault line like whoa
okay and that's the only thing I haven't
experienced it I've actually seen a
volcano to erupting it's it's very
humbling the first time I remember it
was the first time I actually did speed
haha and yeah it was back in 1992 and
yeah
I was literally everybody left the house
and I was playing my bass and then the
earth just gave the nice big old jolt
and I never felt so small or miniscule
but I can't look
honestly I my whole life
growing up in dealing with hurricanes I
would rather be out here and deal with
an earthquake any day than to deal with
having to board up the windows and you
know hunker down and loss of signal and
you know all that she now deal with this
Reed dealing with refrigerators and all
that [ __ ] you have to deal with when you
should get flooded earthquakes can be
bad though I mean you saw a Mexico man
that's 8.1 you can study the Richter
scale
most people don't realize that every
time he goes from like a 5 or 6 or 6 or
7 it's not just one unit it's a
multitude of things that I mean a
difference between like a 7 and 8 is
50/50 nuclear bombs or something you
know the size of it would be like 50
nuclear bombs between the two gadgets or
something
Oh in the amount yeah because the amount
of shifting that's happening and I mean
look at the last huge when that was here
the Loma Prieta one I mean I mean it
shifted things by feet so I mean an
eight point one would definitely move
things by yards
yeah eight point one serious there's
like so anyone out in Mexico again
thoughts and prayers with you got people
in Puerto Rico they said that they just
lost some power but they were okay just
crazy out there and there's a lot of
storms a lot of tell extraordinary
London anything you know yeah you know
there's that back in the day watch this
guy great something they took him off
for YouTube but he's to be with NASA is
it good he's like I forget what his
background was as a scientist but he did
I don't know if you've ever talked about
Net Zero before like when the planet
gets to Net Zero now we have it you ever
heard of that before I've heard of it
you may want to explain to
what he said but essentially what
happens is our North and South Poles
they they flip and this is evident on
the where our plates touch and then
bottom the ocean you see lines that go
this way and then you give this way and
it's 3,600 month 3,600 years or so I
don't know there's an average in there
where it happens
Einstein says that our planet goes
through kind of a bigger shift every
eighty six thousand mile eighty six
thousand years but doesn't mean our
planet light goes off or anything it's
just the way that our magnetics work and
our North and South worth but there's a
point that we get to that's like a net
zero when that happens all kinds of like
different theories have spawned off from
that of what happened just you know does
the ice age happen when the north and
you know when we hit a NetZero point and
we cycle through as a planet every so
often and we're just kind of riding it
like a wave and you know depends if
we're good or bad we influence that ride
differently but there is a resonant
frequency of things that exist and all
things in the planet has one and I think
who's Einstein that was laughed at when
he first talked about it but the planet
has a pulse frequency or a resonant
frequency and so our frequency if you
look at like our planet as a grouping of
the time a bunch of different tiny
little marbles that makes up a sphere
that and they think of it as a vibration
think of those things being held
together by and by a grab gravitational
pull and our rotational pull with the
star all this is very important to keep
these little marbles together but
there's a frequency a resonant
frequencies of vibration just like
that's why they use quartz for like
turntables and for watches because what
she put a frequency or vibration on it
it holds it perpetually like that very
good at holding and responding to
frequencies where other and it's in it's
a neutral quartz is neutral so it's one
of the only elements it's actually
neutral but everything has these tones
and frequencies that's where people
talked about chakras and open them with
tuning forks or bowls tie bowls those
sound effects kind of help tune you
could tune crystals as well in stones
people do it all the time
and so there's that frequency that's out
there and our planet is too said to be
speeding up since we've been monitoring
it which kind of makes sense so if
you're going through a North and South
flip and you're getting to a NetZero
point that frequent that that vibration
would be more and more intense you
follow me and so then that's what would
lead to that in contributing to like our
saline count in the water of the
greenhouse gas is different things that
you know affect the planet on a whole
fukushima dumping nuclear waste into our
ocean things like that that doesn't go
away you know those things will affect
have an influence on storms as well so
you would see more earthquakes you would
see more storms you would see more more
activity then maybe you would see in the
last under 200 years that's been
documented does that makes any sense so
I think we I think we as humans and we
can trip we we contribute to that change
in these experiences but I also do think
that it happens it happens naturally and
it occurs in cycles and kind of how our
planet recycles kinda like the forest
burns down you know and read and read
without a doubt it actually I mean the
poles are gonna switch I mean
when I was in the military wherever we
were in the world we always had to
Declan ate our compasses too you know
true north and we always we were taught
in there that there's you know there's
there's a kind of a shifting that's
happening that it was already happening
back when I was in the military in the
90s you know in the eighties and the
nineties that showed that there's you
know already a degree change due to the
the polls and it was continuing and you
know was gonna get more extreme until
the actual polls flip so there's no
doubt about it it's gonna happen the
thing is is it should have already
happened already by those calculations
so either we're about to go through a
polar flip or it's currently happening
as we speak yeah it's also a great point
because think about all the the
travelers that set sail and all the
devices that existed that allow you to
see true north you know well birds have
birds have iron a sliver of iron in
their beaks that helps them find true
north as well so it would affect
migrations yeah they found that out
through biology is that's why they're
able to find north and south so Ellis
they actually have a bit of iron in
their beak that points him magnetically
in the right direction
dinosaurs they've kind of evolved on us
[Laughter]
so all right sound looks like we're
losing most of the people here but I
didn't want to say one thing that I'm
really happy to see the industry at
least on the solve on the side starting
to push the sauces and the THCA
I think it's important movement it's
going on it's you know kind of why that
the whole idea why bubble and I were
talking about creating these types of
tanks because once you when you get
something saucy you can't really put it
in the jar you can't put it it's like
you really it's hard to keep it in a
place so the tank itself is something
that I think's good just as if you're
buying them as an empty you know you
just buy an empty kid
and you press rosin at home you can
double press that rosin and have thca
and have your sauce that sauces and
unbelievable of these little things like
really good and you got to put them in
something so it's just nice to have the
options now to mix that seeing people
going for it because I remember a year
or two years ago people just still they
still just hate on rosin that's like man
I don't come a long way
well it's a natural progression of
things they're gonna adapt you know or
you know somebody's gonna find something
that will so it's good to see that
there's more options out there for paper
you know people in patience because they
read about it now they need to have
access yeah and I think that you know
it's always comes back down to the
grower and the genetics like you can't
you can't just fabricate really good
product it's just to you know the person
doing the extraction or separation
shirts it's about you know it's a good
40 percent or so but once you have the
tools and the knowledge every time if
you run a lot of stuff that comes down
to who well is that it's something new
that's a new flavor that's new head
structure or why did that yield so much
more otherwise that all clear you know
just different unique characteristics
I've always found it interesting you
know we washed resin and it gets
freeze-dried and it's all looks beaming
white and you've got we've got different
micron runs you'll get like first run
second one third one fourth one but even
in the first or second runs between 273
90 120 45 have you go to press and you
get different shades different colors
every time savings that you know you
make a variation you make a change in
the way you would press based on you
know if it's a three or four five star
type of ash going in before it gets
pressed but even with those slight
adjustments you're just making those
adjustments but it's pressure or just a
few degrees or things like that based on
the melt because you don't want to blow
your you don't to blow out but
ultimately if you're washing and
pressing you'll see all kinds of
variations it's really interesting
sometimes you see like a second run
seventy-three very small and then the
third run really big and the first one
in the third run is so much better than
the second even when you go to press it
I just find it fascinating it's like
when friend she was talking to me one
time about a lemon tree you know if
you've got this big lemon tree you go up
to it and shake it and the fruit falls
down you know and you grab the fruit and
you all eat off of it you could you go
to it again and you shake it and shake
it again and more fruit comes off and so
it's just interesting how the plant when
you look at it in a small level the
different trichomes how they're
developing you know an indoor versus an
outdoor things that I've seen those
those heads don't really extend out in
the winter cycles so you get a lot of so
if your plant tested you know fifteen
percent THC those heads aren't extended
all right a lot of them by the surface
same thing with CBD mature CBD flowers
so it doesn't wash very well your first
light that gets better with in full
season seems like the heads fully fully
extent and you're able to get more of
the resin in its full mouth
capacity than you were in the wintertime
even though it's still there so it's
kind of like the Sun itself and
intensity of the Sun itself allows for
the secretion and to push up higher into
its head into its sack and if the sun's
not there the intensity is not there it
doesn't probably push up it's not
secreting up and it kind of has more of
an oil at its surface instead of a
little bit away from it but with indoor
you know there's a bandages to endure if
you're looking at football fresh frozen
indoor you if you had a very even canopy
of the same variety you've been growing
in a while
under a certain intensity of light you
tend this and you're gonna grow to an
exact date you know you tend to see very
uniform head structure and that distance
from the plant so if you tested
something that's 25 percent 20 percent
indoor like oh we got a 14 percent yield
of that 14 percent yield you'll get a
good 30 percent plus a full mouth you
know where you might you might have a
big wide gap of varieties if it was an
outdoor winter cycle you know so there's
there's places for it all well that's
what the reality of seasons you know in
farming you know you have to deal with
the those changes that are gonna happen
depending on what season you're growing
as well as which one you're processing
how many people are in the chat about
478 to where I'll respect to the 472 as
you see you and I [ __ ] been talking
no Sam's listening it's having some
technical difficulties 73 so let's get
the chat involved for a second what's
everybody in chat smoking on this is so
fun to watch happen what are you smoking
on people what are you two what do you
got yeah the other thing that's
interesting is to ask the chat from
which country are you are you chatting
from because yeah it's interesting to
see how widespread we are yeah shout out
your country shout out your country or
your area and what you're smoking on
yeah I've always wanted to figure out
how you guys look at this chat you must
have to open it up and like on YouTube
huh yeah you open it up on YouTube and
you can watch it live so ok there we go
we got people from all around India UK
Wow
no yes
Trump lands that's rough land
come on put your foot your neck what
you're smoking with your region people
let's see Mary thing I could see myself
crazy
Cali you can't yeah just make sure you
turn your sound down and then you'll see
there's the chat yeah see it going on
see all that sweet come on Tim all those
people are shot now quick yeah it's it
moves fast when you ask South Africa and
cheese nice go South Africa Kalamazoo
Michigan USA girl scout cookies Kabul
Afghanistan nice Wow go Afghanistan much
love your hash pinkish Ontario blueberry
hybrid America pink push glad when pink
push yeah
Katmandu Abu Maine Scotland homegrown
Gigi floor
nice real igloo for nice very nice
Seattle nice Thai weed in England
Washington State DC blueberry
Starfighter in Connecticut that's pretty
cool I spent Trump led in the 707 yeah
Iowa Wi-Fi OG nobody 13 Ontario all
right how about the Philippines
Australia's cheese in South Africa
Scotland gelato yeah we got anybody over
in the Indonesia Thai area can you guys
hear me yes we can yes we can all right
cool my computer's got 6% left and I've
got iMac up here so I was thinking of
maybe winding it down if you guys wanted
to uh if you had anything else to say
today on today's testers that's all good
we were just enjoying everybody telling
us where they are and what they're
smoking on
I'm gonna end it with a power dab just
for that then I'm gonna just power down
of everything so it's one of those
rights
I did a power that have yesterday were
loop where my bike and we put in the
Swiss tsunami and then I added this
beautiful dry set that one of the just
one of the one of the do is she gave me
some real nice triceps and gave me some
really nice rosin I wanted to give him a
shout out for that kind gift and man and
the rip [ __ ] can good I'm gonna do some
California smoothie I'm doing some
orange cookies sauce and I saw one
cooking sauce with left of it I think
I'm gonna add some cbc cbn let's get it
I'm gonna get everything in this thing
alright alright next week is our three
year Anna Church so uh ooh you see well
I'm gonna like the Pope's of the Pope to
blow some hash to the Vatican wouldn't
be blowing asteroids at the Vatican or
maybe some smoke there you go
this is getting crazy alright well let
me know when the dabs ready Tony you're
gonna we're gonna set and there's
ascended Dawid yeah this is just
straight sauce and after sauce this is a
strawberry banana goo hash full melt
sauce see they're quite a few things
here some pharmacy Girl Scout cookies
sauce here just look at the very bottom
and I have to add add some lemon tree
CBD to it to some of these things are
made ooh that's pretty
that's a nice color you could see it on
the outside this all right well I have I
have thca sauces CBD is a 90% CBD 5%
this is this lemon tree on here so got
like CBC CBD CBN TAC a I've got hash
Rosen's of sauces students Tony your CBC
but what purity level is it was so that
was also in this this last oil that
tested like 45 percent CBE and in like
thirty one percent CBC alright well I
think it's time to say shut up for my
sports teams go Saints and go Barcelona
playing juve on Tuesday so let's get
this champion Lee going mm-hmm all right
let's do this much left thank you very
much and well I will miss you next week
same time I'll see you after so how long
thanks for holding it down so so often
for us at TN skunk man Sam and Tony B
with the power dab thanks everyone for
watching
ash Church and we'll see you next week
for episode 156