Hey sorry about that everybody take two
laughter that off the air all sorts of
technical difficulties can you hear me
at 10 yes can you hear me and now I
can't hear you this oh no are you
kidding me this is a strange strange
thing happening okay out about it
Kathleen or Debbie can yours if I go out
again and I come back in nobody I will
I'll be able to hear you but we'll go
offline so know maybe hashed hurts
getting the best of me today I might not
be able to do this I'm gonna keep trying
for a little bit but maybe Google's
sealing away I'll come back we'll see if
we get bounced done can you hear me yes
I can hear me Margot
yeah all right so was it this slinger
Shh was it a slinger marble show hold on
let me get Sheila back here in the room
Sheila would know just a second oh yeah
all right so are we offline now no we're
live can you hear me I can hear you
perfect but I wonder how long we'll stay
live for okay I still see the live in
the corner oh gosh well thanks for you
know what after 220 of these I have to
say like if this was like a year or two
ago I would have been having a harsh
reality right now let me tell you
so bubble man I have a question quickly
yes tomorrow the Google goes away April
first I'm gonna be able to use this
format in the future I honestly have no
idea what's gonna be happening but I
will figure something out that we will
be able to do what we're doing right now
and whether that happens through Google
or some other option I will make sure
that it happens that's been making me a
little nervous too actually might be why
things are a little wonky right now so
yeah there's no support that's why I got
on I figured it may have been the last
time in this type of format so I wanted
to make sure to get on at least give my
love yes Kelly oh no I can't hear you
maybe it's a simple mute though well we
can walk you through it sometimes it's a
simple mute other
times you gotta go into the little cog
and you got to check what you have set
up for your microphone yeah on the
left-hand side there's a control room
section so if you're having problems
check under your control room and make
sure you have the right microphone
because sometimes you also have to go
into your systems and check your
headphones and microphone output if
you're using a microphone microphone
right yes okay well we still got a
couple hundred people back in the room
they're laughing right now there's a
special welcome to bubble man's gong
show
my phone's just blowing up I can't get I
can't see the link happy birthday and
crashed yes happy birthday happy
birthday again yes ice cream cake oh
you're most welcome I'm glad you like
that did you get him away Lee no you
know Sam was unable to make Legends of
hash this year which we threw down in
Barcelona Oh miss turn it on right there
and yeah you did and so because Sam
missed it we made sure we got him like
some t-shirts and I got the card for him
the invitation and all of the samples
from legends so he could kind of be a
part of it
so that's that welcome Josh and Kelly I
wanted to say welcome earlier but we
know you guys are muted to know we can
hear them too man it's you so Marcus is
having technical issues for some reason
he can hear certain of us and some of us
not so apparently Dragonfly
unfortunately you're in Colin's book can
you hear Colin can you guys hear me at
all I can hear you dragonfly he can't
hear you oh no so I can't I don't know
why it would let me hear some people I
can hear Sam I can hear it
Colin it's having the same problem II
can hear certain people but not other
people this has got to be a phase out of
there
support it I really I can hear Debbie
Debbie can hear me I can hear mark
marking here meaning I can also hear
Harlequin waiting yeah I can hear
everybody Callie can you say something
can you hear me yes I can
so Mike say something check check okay
so I got Mike I can hear absolutely
everybody Martin okay
I can almost not hear anybody maybe I'll
open my laptop and I'll watch it a
little delayed on my laptop and I'll
hear everything that way and I can still
be a part of a conversation but you guys
by all means speak away gee there's not
much happening in campus right now I
don't know what you're talking about I
think you are technically the only
English person here currently okay
what's going on
what's going on in England right now
with the whole brexit and cannabis oh if
I knew I'd be able to tell