I'm gonna record right now and we're GNA
go
live this will be nice nice uh we are a
community not an
industry how about
that I love that as a starting point sir
that's a great conversation right there
we are a community we're also an
industry but we were and still are a
community thank you absolutely well
we're going to just start now we just
went live and we just showed up so I'm
going to copy
this there we
go boom boom boom boom sharing the link
good morning everyone and thank you for
joining us today we
are here for hash Church 4.0 episode 5
and what an incredible crew of ogs we
have in the room just right away the
early birds really the the five minutes
I think Valerie actually was even in the
chat like at 8:20 I got an email saying
Valerie went into the zoom chat I was
like okay she is ready to be a part of
this that was
exciting welcome to everyone welcome
toan and to Wade and to skunkman Sam and
Valerie caral who I actually met for the
first time at skunkman Sam's apartment
in Amsterdam many years ago for a for a
a nice dinner so thank you Sam for that
introduction and here we are so many
years later and we're going to have
another a nice little chat and the other
day when I was thinking about what we
were going to chat about for whatever
reason it came to me that we are not an
industry we are a community and that was
sort of the conversation starting point
I thought that we would have uh this
morning I know it'll head in a whole
variety of directions but uh yeah we are
not a an just an industry we are also a
community and a lot of the people who
are in the room right now really have
fought for that Community um more than
more than more than most so hats off all
of you with my new very short haircut
and uh welcome nice to see you
all that was a nice visit in Amsterdam
so many years ago sort of the yeah uh
the kind of the Awakening part of the
Awakening been going on a long time but
greetings from Amsterdam Valerie well
thank you it's a pleasure pleasure skunk
man it's just uh so sweet really nice to
um nice to connect with you in your cute
little
hat well I think a lot of us are
Community but I think the industry is
you're surfing and growing stronger and
stronger only some of those have
community links to be honest sure
because that's any corporate State ah
there you go where's my red hat got my
frian cap of freedom and liberty
going
nice well you know it's the it's a
corporations sometimes talk about family
but it's mostly a conversation right and
uh a lot of things are changing in the
world that we live corporations are
driven by profit if they don't profit
they cease to exist
Community doesn't have to profit it just
has to
survive and Valerie you were the example
early on of those that fought strong
combined with patience and fought hard
to survive you were the leader to us
that were the dispensaries you were out
there showing compassion and we wanted
to reflect that as well and some of us
did and carried that reflection as we're
aware that Community um was over grown
needless to say by those propers who
didn't necessarily seem or have the same
ideals that you and others instilled in
Us in compassionate giving to those that
were less fortunate than us that were
able yeah well thank thank you thank you
I appreciate that you know I think uh
well I probably would be just a few
years out of prison had it not been a
community that we uh were all part of
you know um Wham was something that was
uh driven by
a the fruit of it came through the the
community itself and really recognizing
that so many great things happen with
the effort of a lot of people like this
movement you know I really joined a
movement that was already well and well
ins sconed in this in this our worldwide
Community you know our worldwide can
cannabis Community marijuana back when
we the
marijuana so I I I've just been pretty
lucky so and get to hang out with all of
you on a Sunday morning for a bit well
not only were you lucky you you you
fought for that change and push for that
change and worked at a which was most
important you worked at a local level
you worked within your region of your
state and everyone rallied around you
when they saw what the what you were
doing and why you were doing it there
were little of us that were like no what
they're doing is wrong no you were
taking patience and making sure that
they contributed at one point or another
to the growth Pro processing or
harvesting of this plant which was an
example that many of us were not aware
is something that could be done but you
went there and you said no this is how
it can be done and when they mess with
you you fought back I mean when they
tried to rage all people people blocked
the roads I mean there's a lot of real
drama to the history that a lot of
people here have lived and you were a
saint to us on a hill showing us how to
do it right and not only that you would
take us in and you would say okay this
is how it should be done you're doing
this wrong you should be doing it this
way and you mentored us as well and
kicked us in the ass so we're also
humbled and thanks for that
yeah I'd like to jump in and add to what
Jan was saying um I I think it was the
first time uh the feds rated you Valerie
I was I been living in San Francisco for
a number of years at that point and had
kind of heard about your work but was
not really aware of the extent and the
compassion that you brought to that work
and honestly um the news coverage of
that event that first bust that you
experienced down there that that Jan was
just referring to served as a model for
my I created a series of collectives and
co-ops uh that up till today it's still
the model that I work with thank you
Valerie you set a high standard that uh
I'm deeply grateful for so thank you I
appreciate that I didn't do it alone H
you know Mike worked with me at we don't
work together now but it was all built
you know built from the strength of many
and that's what really is uh one of the
it's it's Elemental it's key well it's
key to our our conversation today
Community right so we start our families
are our first community and then we
build from there relying on each other
and and uh not nobody co-opting the
working cooperatively but nobody
co-opting the uh the ownership and you
know everything changes this is 30 years
later and it's really it's wild to watch
it I'm glad to see a lot of what's
happened um especially freeing the
freeing the plant freeing freeing the
the people of course anything that's
this inviting and magical and has the
opportunity to create a lot of Revenue
is going to be co-opted
by you know by the the corporate state
by corporations by industry create an
industry around it that's just the way
it is this is we live in a in a very com
commercial
competitive capitalistic world problem
with capitalism is that it you know I
say this a lot it only measures profit
in one way but there are many ways to
measure profit and I think the balance
comes when we begin to see beyond the
narrow scope of financial profit and
that we realize that people's happiness
is part of that profit profit people
that work people who benefit from all of
those things are profit and they they
aren't necessarily commercialized but if
we could you know if they whatever if it
could be figured a way to commercialize
that and make money off of it probably
would work better for for an industry
but nef said about that that's just
a that's one of the frailties of C of a
one-dimensional
system oh that's not a one community
community is like love you've got to
give more than you take it's also the
way you make healthy soil you give more
than you take yeah you're right you open
your hand to give something before you
know it's
full right it's that's interesting Sam
you give more than you take because
capitalism is pretty much the opposite
where you take more than you give and
you can definitely see those two systems
are at I mean cannabis has shown us so
beautifully how those two systems are at
odds with one another particularly
because they removed cannabis for so
long from that system of you know legal
profiteering and capitalism and all of
that of course you know many of us used
cannabis I I certainly one of the first
things I learned about cannabis before I
knew of its medicinal properties before
I knew of all the magical things that it
could do what it what I noticed and that
this was you know I didn't realize at
the time but it was really because of
the prohibition of cannabis that it
allowed me to remove myself from the
slavery of a wage job I figured out
cannabis in a very unique way um I
wasn't trying to like you know make
money so badly or whatnot but what I
figured out was like I figured out a way
to monetize enjoying being with my
friends by getting them something that
they seemed unable to find on their own
at least to the caliber of which my old
factory was allowing me to find because
I had this heightened sense of smell and
taste and I used that to go out and and
really curate great cannabis and and
find people who took this plant a little
more serious than others and that was
really my first experience I mean
obviously I SP to join I was 14 years
old I had the time of my life and it
slowly moved into this oh wow like I can
kind of monetize this and so it's a
strange a strange tension that we find
ourselves in now especially with the
situation here in Canada with the
situation down in California with so
many lifelong people kind of getting
pushed out of this ability to use
cannabis to monetize their life and it's
it's sad it's a bummer I I don't really
know how to feel about it I don't love
the idea that it's just moved over to a
different group yet I understand that
everything else in the world is like
that and it's uh I find myself
questioning it constantly like here I am
in this legal regulatory framework of
cannabis and I I I I remember what it
was like I remember my friends serving
10 plus years in prison I remember guns
I remember dogs being shot and children
being taken away and when I remember
those those things I think well it's way
better than it was like it's way better
than it was but then I hang out with
younger people who are like oh they're
taxing us this and they're doing this
and they're crushing our business and
that's terrible too but not quite to the
level of what a lot of the people in
this room experience by you know being
arrested for basically being a habitual
florist well and providing and taking
that risk by doing so and that's
something that we always realize that it
was just about money that there had to
be compassion and always attached that
there were always going to be people who
could not afford cannabis people that
were going to be surprised you've just
got cancer and now you have to figure
out how to deal with re regimen to get
healthy and you hear about this cannabis
and it just again it reminds us of that
human element that the the it's still
done one to one I mean as much as I love
going on Capitol Hill a few weeks ago
and trying to to to affect change at a
national level it still requires that
one onone somebody coming in and says hi
I just found out I have stage four
breast cancer I need help and that's
where all of us here have been involved
because we weren't thinking of
necessarily about the money as much as
this human is hurting and needs help and
we've all found ourselves healing
through the Cannabis so we kind of all
took it upon ourselves to then help and
do what we we can to risk our freedoms
to help other people because again this
was still very much a gray area what
what Valerie was doing was
legal but what we as dispensaries were
doing we didn't have the legal right and
we had to actually work illegally to
actually change the laws at the state
level so that we could finally be
accepted and not necessarily be continue
to be prosecuted but somewhere in that
situation The Compassion been lost we
continue to do it at Berkeley Patients
Group we still give away free cannabis
every week to those that are that that
have established the need and
unfortunately as the industry is grown
The Compassion is shrunk and we need to
remind the uh industry of the compassion
that Valerie and others established and
weighed for us to continue to follow
because as we know the cancer rates have
gone from 1 and three to one and two in
the past couple of decades which means
there's going to be a long need for many
decades uh for humans to require the the
need for medical cannabis and um
everyone on here has made sure that is a
uh possibility and I am humbled and
thank to call you family at some
point you know I think one of the things
that we're we're looking at most most
assuredly is with the pharmaceutical
Industries move toward um or
absconding with with can I'm going to
say absconding with medical because when
can when cannabis is created into it's
not that it isn't a medicine but when
it's created into a pharmaceutically
owned medicine we won't be able to
supply medicine we'd be doing we'd be
practicing medicine without a license so
our the idea that I mean it will become
privatized it will become a commodity
that a a physician have to approve it'll
be U
pharmaceuticalization as far as people
supplying or offering from one to
another that is um not that we can't do
it on the down low the way we probably
all started right I mean I know we did
we started on the down low um
and moving away from these these in
industrializing and
pharmaceuticalization these things move
us further away from the unity of
building family of being present with
one another and when we aren't present
with one
another we miss the connection of each
other's eyes of observing one another's
suffering of being able to lend a hand
in whatever way that is and someday it's
going to be me it's going to be
everybody you know there's we're mortal
and and so as we serve ourselves as an
industry serves us it's as important to
serve each other and everybody's at the
job of service everybody has a commodity
to sell if you're in the in business and
and it's all the same thing I mean the
the service industry is this huge thing
it's life you know we just get kind of
mucked up in what we in our needs hey
you
guys muted you're
mute good morning good morning
everybody old friends it's making my
heart feel really full it's so
incredibly wonderful to see you Wade
Valerie ATN Mark it's been a while as
well and of course Marcus all the
love to you all thank you so much for
being here this morning feel super
honored and um talking about
Compass I just think that this is this
is where the most important thing that
we can really talk about in humanity
what no matter what Corporation or What
entity or what family or what religion
or what socioeconomic group that you're
in when we talk about compassion we're
talking about a very humanistic quality
just like what Valerie said this one
on-one and unfortunately you know the
big education the big Pharma they come
in to try to take that away and when we
don't have compassion anymore we
lose what it is that we came in here to
begin with you know I know that I
entered into cannabis because of
compassion from the very beginning and
although there's lots of different sort
of sharks along the way that want to
take us out of
compassion you know I feel like when it
is me and I am making those last breaths
on my deathbed with my friends around I
just want to know that I continued on
with compassion because then you know
it's just not worth living my life
honestly unless we're doing it in a way
that is connecting with other human
beings and this wonderful amazing
Collective Consciousness that we have
that we often forget about the power of
it it's almost interesting that you know
modern medicine goes down to places like
South America places like the Amazon and
they go and they try and take those
compounds out of the forest and makes a
synthetic version they kind of do that
to us like as a human population we're
like the rainforest medicine makers of
the of of the people realm and then they
come in into our people and they try and
fragment us and isolate us and isolate
our things and just doesn't work as well
so give thanks that there's still people
like us in the world and that there's
still intact environments for us to
learn from and uh you know there some
people out there that just don't go
along with everything and I think that's
a positive thing and I wanted to say one
thing um just to share with everybody
this morning um is that uh speaking of
uh large
corporations that are trying their
hardest to make things non-comp
passionate is that we got a letter
dragonfly Earth medicine got a letter
from the Environmental Protection Agency
and this would be our our nutrient
company a cease and assist on uh
dragonfly Earth medicine
because
Nettles
Alfalfa and kelp are now going to be
listed as a pesticide so if you are to
be using them in any new nutrient that's
not a synthetic
NPK then you are to be registered with
pesticide EPA and they told us that
they've been watching us for over two
years and they said if we use the word
healthy
biodynamic anything having to do with
plants well-being at all then we're
stepping into the pesticide area and
fertilizer era and I want to let you all
know sort of what Josh was saying is
that they have taken all of our
education that we've been doing for the
past couple of years and they're
integrating it for self to
own so very interesting and very much so
along the lines of what we're talking
about today and uh we're dealing with it
we're getting through it because that's
what we do this is just another
roadblock and we're really good at
roadblocks so um three o'clock road
block three o'cl road block yeah it it's
just you know we we have micronized
herbs with bacteria found all over the
Earth and micronized L fungi and they're
actually trying to stop that from going
into people's
Farms simply because going to a
Wikipedia page as simple as that and
just saying what does Nettles do in a
you know in a in a garden environment
you can't just copy what's online you
know say off a Wikipedia you know
whether you'd want to do that or not but
just I'm CH just talking about the
Simplicity aspect of it it's mindblowing
that this is the danger of compelling
speech when you compel
speech you create a very very dangerous
environment and this is compelling
speech because now they're controlling
what is a pesticide and changing that
language and moving the goalposts and
and affecting and creating this obstacle
for you guys I have zero doubt that the
tension that this creates will turn that
obstacle into well you guys will turn
that obstacle into an opportunity
because you're on the right side of this
and they're clearly uh on the wrong side
of this sorry for cutting you off
joh um M I think what we were just gonna
say is that it just goes along with this
long line of the people and the
community continuing in compassion and
them finding out that that's a popular
game over and over again they find out
that togetherness is a popular game and
they want to own it but we know that you
know love will win because just like you
know if there's only love and fear we're
really interested in staying in the love
and we'll just let them Define and take
care of fear and pretty soon they're
going to tell us that love needs to be
listed under as a pesticide as well
because health and biodynamics and
everything is but that's okay the
positive thinking thing come on come on
there's no statistics and it actually
just like you said Marcus as soon as we
got it it was an incred incredible
opportunity for us to look at all kinds
of things we really have taken it on as
an unbelievable opportunity and like I
had said before we've been moving into
plant medicine and I've been doing a lot
of therapy sessions with people that
have been
absolutely
mindblowing I mean wow the healing that
can happen with plants is we all know
that but now that we're stepping in to
something yes exactly giving thanks
giving thanks for
that um yeah so it's given us
opportunity to look at other things and
cannabis has opened the door for all of
the other plant medicines and all of the
entheogens so as she opens up the door
we all just need to walk through and
remember that love guides the way energy
never goes the way it just moves to
another area I just wanted to mention
too that I I do not believe that all
corporations intrinsically are evil I
mean a lot of them certainly are their
sharks but you got to remember that some
of the uh corporations like the owner of
Patagonia he gave his entire company in
Fortune to help companies that will
fight climate change and help
sustainability so I
mean yeah
good things can be done talking about
corporations I think that it's really
important we're talking about like
public you know ones that are associated
with big government associated with
lobbyists we're not you know when we're
talking about a corporation like
Patagonia they do not have lobbyists
they do not have people that are trying
to continue to talk about you know how
they can shut down people so they can
make their way
up a little bit different right it's a b
Corp or Patagonia is a b Corp and
they're they're principled uh in a
different Foundation right so and and
you could be a borp and not really be
principal I think it's you know it's
endemic it's you know the the the kind
of uh it's the new Conquering the way
that that uh one culture is conquered by
NE where you you tear down the temple
and build the church and
we see I hope that's not too vague of a
of a metaphor
but I see this as happening um in many
cultures and what's happening with the
plant with plants now we're science now
I mean I love to be able to have access
to Scientific data and information and
I'm I feel very fortunate to live in a
time when I am able to do that and I
also see that one of the issues that
appears to be arising is again the the
dismissal or the removal of the shaman
or the teacher from the process so we
have a medicine or we have a
claim and a claim that we associate with
it and then you know how did it even
become how was it even discovered that
it was a medicine it wasn't in a
Laboratory um it was through messaging
from the plant connection with nature
and that kind of Exquisite uh
opportunity uh that we have to be to
deeply listen and be uh taught because
we're all we're all you know we get I
get confused sometimes thinking that I'm
teaching something when really I'm you
know just listening and being able to
hear what I'm being able to listen more
deeply and and listen to some truth some
information so I think I think it's it
really a danger it's a it's more than
co-opting and it's when your goal when
you have a goal if you go toward the
goal the things that are in your
way can be pushed aside or will be
pushed aside and we have to look at that
in our own lives and as we reflect on
the ways that it is happening around us
we're you know we're oppressing our own
Planet at a great cost but we're also
evolving um such as we started off we
could not be we had to all be not for
profits but we could not
get Corporation and that's a full
vetting cycle that is making sure that
you have diverse you hire diversity
you're paying fairly and all that so
there's even in the corporate world
there are things like beneficial
corporations which are the standards now
we lost that when the government
forcefully evicted us at to lay off 50
people therefore putting us below that
70 or 75 person threshold they needed to
have beneficial corporations but it also
shows the need that even in the the new
beneficial Corporation there are even
limits that there need to low to be more
accessible to everyone because I would
love to continue to still be but I due
to the industry itself and its collapse
I can no
long possible as an example but I mean
Valerie you led by example and everybody
kind of way from that we've tried to
lead by example by still compassionate
giving and people have gone completely
away from that so we also have to be
these stewards and reminders to people
that the job is not done and there is
still much more work to
do I think the division that human
beings tend to create naturally can be
really viewed at both ends of life in
the birth and in the death of a human
being and when you look at that you know
when Valerie's talking about connection
and how this connection has been lost in
the pharmaceuticalization of cannabis
well look at the pharmaceuticalization
of births and the the lack of connection
that's there of course very important
something goes wrong a hospital is an
amazing Place uh to be able to be a an
emergency room for for something that's
going wrong with the with the mother or
the baby but just that disconnect of how
different it is when you have a home
birth with a midwife and you have that
eye to eye connect and you don't have
anyone sort of controlling the other
person and and trying to be like I'm the
guy here that's doing this and you see
it in our in the way we die as well and
the way people die in hospital beds
versus you know having death Gatherings
where people are actually taking you
through your death and then you can see
how it affects everything in between and
I'm sure you know it's there's this
there's always this tension and I
somehow think that it's part of The
Human Experience because we're not here
to be the same thing we're here to have
our Free Will and to have these
experiences both sides of the coin have
to exist and in that tension and I don't
really know how to put this into words
but I feel that the value of life can be
found in that tension you know the
tension between life and death the
tension between one person's uh Vision
versus another person's Vision I'm sure
Dr Mark you could get into metaphors of
chemistry and how all sorts of magic
happens in the tension of
chemistry um it's just it's a really
interesting thing how we're constantly
creating division naturally it's like oh
this side wants to do it this way well
we want to do it this way and you know
Josh sort of spoke upon it earlier it's
good that we exist but you know in the
in the words of of one of my neighbors
Heather this 80 plus year old woman she
said well it's all love Mark isn't it
it's all love so don't worry about it
it's all love on both sides even the
side that you think isn't love it's love
too just from a different perspective so
there's my sort of flaky love uh um I
think that that's all I Marcus I love
that because I feel like also what's
happening
with you know what happened with
cannabis we saw that anything that has a
nature connection is something that can
be looked at and can be attacked sign
science is definitely very helpful but
unfortunately science likes to say that
it's more important than nature
sometimes science likes to say hey I've
got it more figured out even than nature
does whereas nature never goes back and
says oh that was the wrong experiment
you know we didn't have it right but
science is always you know redoing it oh
10 years later that that wasn't totally
right or and I'm not going to throw the
baby out with a bath water because I
feel like it's you know science is
really important but I feel like we're
going more towards the technical side of
science more the mechanism side of
Science and and demonizing a a lot of
what Nature has to show us and nature
has to guide us one thing that's
becoming incredibly impar with that is
while I think that Maps is incredibly
helpful in pushing forward plant
medicine and what they're doing I'm also
incredibly concerned because it's taking
a lot of the science side of it so you
go into an office you put something over
your eyes you listen to a certain music
you have this
incredible which people say is you know
like a near-death experience or like a
birth experience it's it's that
lifechanging that then you take the mask
off and you go to work the next day
nature is not
involved but but PS sorry excuse me go
apologize no go ahead Val I want to hear
it go ahead
it's everything is like that whatever
our experience that awakens I just want
to back up the thing with maps like in
order to bring these experiences to
people there are certain safeguards
within the context of the scientific
community and they're there for that's
the way our they've socially been built
it doesn't doesn't uh uh in any way
change our experiences with psychedelics
or um we still have those opportunities
um to use them and I see why that you
know I think we can all see why there
are problems somebody
might you know flip out have a better
experience may have heart attack these
kinds of things can rarely can't but
they can happen and guidance is a really
important tool having the teacher the
connection between the shaman or the the
guide and the intention of our
journey but I think it's true with
everything you know like I'm I'm
sometimes surprised I'm like did anybody
get not anybody but I working with
people in in cannabis like did they ever
get high like I mean did they what
happened to the experience what happened
to that piece that changed us or opened
our hearts or
or you know what is it that that we lose
when we walk away from the experience
because we walk away from an experience
it lasts for an instant it opens or
changes Us in some way then what what do
we take with us from that so I see that
that's um um that's just part of the
problem but it does not in any way
change I think the need for science
science is going to take it to people
that we you know in Dubai it's going to
take it to people all around the world
that would no in no other way have an
opportunity or may not have
another experience it I do totally agree
with you Valen I think it's a really
important part but I think the concern
that I have in this is that these are
plants that come from nature they have a
message of Nature and when therapist or
the men is only another human being
taking nature out of the factor as a
mentor as a teacher when you when I work
with people and I'm working on plant
medicine I could hum for a half an hour
looking at a leaf and downloading nature
and downloading what it feels like to
lie on the ground and I'm just and I
have a concern that if we take nature
out of the picture as nature I mean as
as a mentor in this as a teacher as an
expansive knowledge then we're only
looking towards another human being who
is incredibly limited and I feel like
that's where the clinical setting yes it
may bring it to more people but I feel
like it's lacking and I feel like if we
could at least go to where the plants
are grown in the ground and get out of
the clinical setting maybe we need to
bring the clinicians out to Nature more
something has got to happen where nature
is I I mean and sometimes I go through a
whole six-h hour plant medicine therapy
session with something we don't talk at
all because nature is downloading
everything that that person needs to do
by just simply going on a walk right and
I feel that if we're gonna juice people
up with plant medicine and they're going
to go to these incredible psychedelic
spaces and they're going to be really
looking at why they're here they're
going to look be looking at their soul
path they're going to have an
understanding I feel like if nature is
not involved in that conversation and
that guidance then that person is
severely missing out on the potential
possibilities of where they could where
they could go well well they're just
missing out on that possibility it's not
one doesn't negate the other so not
everybody would be comfortable laying on
the ground in the forest and not not
everybody can access it somebody who's
paralyzed is going to have a hard time
doing that people won't necessarily
people who are sick who can't get out of
bed there are me I guess what I'm trying
to say is I fully agree with you and
that's one path and there are eight
billion of us and or so and and there
are eight billion
ways to leave behind whatever it was and
open to A New Path and I think that
that's one of our one of the things we
want to do is to stay open
to stay open to the other Pathways
because
what I think is happening is um that
door is getting shut I mean lots of
people are taking off and doing iasa
Journeys and connecting and this is you
know it's remarkable what's happening
today it's really quite remarkable and
does it have to be in I mean I think
there are great grave issues that arise
when we remove the teachers remove the
shamans when we take the take the
institutionalize the the the gift the me
the medicine
and
yet I I believe the more the more
Pathways we open the more opportunities
for people to have the experience to
carry it to carry both their intention
and the
outcome it only broadens and it broadens
our language and it broadens our
connection with one another and it gives
a chance you know
like how how amazing can we be well
well get in traffic and see how amazing
you are and and that's where it you know
what we take from our experience and
what we give I think the room for others
to have theirs experience is one of the
keys that I hope we don't erase I hope
we don't miss and I and I mean I would
fully agree with you that that's
remarkable healing and you're people are
very fortunate to be able to be in
your in your service with your with you
serving their needs and attending to
them and that's a pretty sweet that's a
very sweet and beautiful gift but not
everybody can get to you and you really
don't want everybody to get to you I
mean I don't think that's my opinion I
like a small community because I can be
have I can be more at peace with who I
serve yeah and and it is true it's hard
to reach every and the people that we
are reaching now are the people who are
working with other people to you know
give them another look at what a healing
session can look like what it feels like
outside of walls what it feels like
without you know something over your
eyes and just being internal and
Gathering what Nature has to offer and
it is changing the way that they're
looking at their sessions is changing
the way that they are making their
clinics and it is changing the way that
they're seeing patients so you know the
the more that we can have influencers
and people that are working with other
people understand the power of the
mentorship of Nature and the power of
nature as the shaman um then I think
that we've got a much better opportunity
to reach those you know 80 million
people on the planet or whatever eight
billion people on the planet so we're
eight billion versions of nature we're
eight billion versions of evolution
we're not eight billion versions of
Petri dishes but we do well yes and no
okay because we are nature is science
and if we take it back think of this
first of all you guys might be
forgetting how Savage nature is do you
know that the wild the beasts in Africa
give birth Twice first they give birth
for the Lions to consume their baby's
Liv as they're coming out of the vaginas
of the wilderbeast live it's the most
Savage thing you've ever seen and then
they give birth a couple of months later
and those are the ones that actually
succeed the the the bloodline of the
wilderbeast because the Lions damn near
consume all of the first born of these
wilderbeast so science our our ability
to create and discover has allowed us to
remove ourselves from the food chain we
used to be a part of that food chain and
let me tell you it was super Savage like
there's you cannot imagine we thought it
was bad when the DEA were hunting us
down with guns it was worse when lions
and tigers were hunting us down with
their teeth and eating Us Alive forget
about putting you in a cage they were
just consuming you whole and so that and
and if we're if we're in all nature well
then our science is a part of nature as
well you know that that like we think
about this think about the ability to
even use the medicine you guys are using
for healing right now without science
science created that medicine you know
the the tools of science help transform
nature we're not we're not diminishing
Nature by science or Nature by any mean
go ahead I was just gonna say basically
that like melium grows in an
isopropyl hooded stainless steel
environment that shows that nature lives
in all environments we can all be
enhanced or gifted by every part of life
totally understand that everyone's
invited life is amazing that's why we
have fractals and the mandal BR you know
Theory and all these things that show
that there's a NeverEnding
possibility I love uh connecting with
nature whenever possible let's just
leave it at that well and I also think
that the conversation of the will to
Beast you know eating us with their big
teeth that's nature but human beings
that are sort of killing each other to
become a higher position I feel like
maybe that's a little bit out of it it
just it feels like competition has taken
over natural intuition and I think that
we are out of balance with science being
looked at more as the thing rather than
I think we're just a little bit out of
balance I think nature is equally as
important as science because we've
created and we're natural beings but at
the same time science has just taken the
main news it's on the front page science
science science so people are forgetting
that we can learn so much from nature so
we're just trying to continue to be a
loud voice for nature because science
has such a main spot right now and if
you sence the study of nature science is
the study of nature you can't have
science with you can't have it without
nature
I agree we studi I agre the cannabis
plant we're part of the Cannabis
Community the cannabis plant doesn't
express the same type of diversity in
its cannabinoids synthetically as it
does organically in a regenerative
setting why would everyone be going into
the Earth with their cannabis not just
because the bills are high in an indoor
setting the Cannabis is different when
it grows in the soil with rocks and
crystals and spring water and every wow
that plant's different complete
different plant than an aeroponic setup
or a hydroponic setup I don't need to
know anything else at that point I'm
like a plant 22,000 chromosomes there's
very little different between us you
know and by saying that it's not trying
to say that 100% we're from nature we
use electricity I it's not like I it's
nice to not have to go down the rabbit
hole of like well hey what about this
and that like it's fine everything else
is happening it's awesome it's just odd
in the last three years that the
Nature's side of life has been demonized
it's the way it is ostracized Witch Hunt
whatever you want to call it can't
travel can't live there's not an actual
equal playing field so it's kind of it's
kind of just sure life's happening now
let's hear let's hear from a scientist
right I know we all think we're you want
me to speak Mark is that what you're
saying yes yes to all of that because I
honestly believe the the universe is
perfect I truly truly believe this and
any people who can't see it you know I I
I feel sorry for you but the universe is
truly perfect but Sam how much assd did
you take to see that was it like aund
hits like 200 hits no it was only it was
only 50 50 hits
inshine know this was an acid
trip for him to come to the conclusion
that that it's it's perfect uh he's on
the assumption that the universe is
finite and if we know anything from
Einstein we know that the universe is
ever expanding so um uh uh I'll quote uh
Einstein and saying that my sense of God
is my sense of wonder about the universe
so let me just chime in from the science
point of view for a second and say well
okay science
is Marcus science of living things
science of nature is biology there's all
other kinds of of of disciplines and
science but it's so think of it this way
so humans are naturally in inquisitive
right we want to learn about ourselves
and our environment so we're all
scientists but we're not all paid
scientists right so just there's a few
of us who are paid the rest of you we're
all scientists and we're all building on
the knowledge and we all stand on the
shoulders of the people who've come
before us that have you know leted us
down this this path and so let me go
back to the EPA for a second too so
that's interesting that you guys got a
notification from them but remember that
theoretically the EPA which was started
uh uh in 1970 by the Nixon
Administration uh was there to basically
protect the environment right and make
sure that you know people weren't just
making really big piles of waste or
pollution or somehow damaging the
environment where yes like it or not
food is grown in industrial ways and the
Environmental Protection Agency makes
sure that you know things that are sold
into agriculture have no uh longlasting
impact in the environment and um while
it's true that like what you the sort of
like the living soil approach is is less
uh impactful on the environment as
taking advantage of the natural
organisms and using Mother Nature's Own
biopesticides if you will in fact you
know the EPA for several years now has
had a category called bio pesticides and
if you look at the various regulations
um right there are there are no
commercial products right now uh whose
registration covers the use on hemp or
cannabis or very very few and the reason
why is because the onus is back on the
people who own that Reg ation for that
active to run all of the trials to make
sure that the application rate of their
product on that Agricultural Product
whatever it is doesn't have to be
cannabis could be anything Tomatoes
strawberries anything whatever you're
applying to that has the efficacy that
you claim it does so it kills fungus or
keeps insects away or whatever but it
also has to be shown to be safe by the
time that produce gets to the market
that you know either it's been
photolytically or hydrolytically uh
decomposed to the point where whatever
metabolites from that treatment that's
left on those strawberries or string
beans or lettuce is all below the point
at which there is no effect on human
health and if there is effect on human
health they don't get a registration in
that market so so now add cannabis to
this so in order for a company to show
to get an EPA
registration on anything from uh
Insecticide
Fungicide anything that you want to
apply to cannabis you'll have to have
that data package you'll have to have
that data package to bring to the EPA
and now you're bringing you know uh
regardless of cannabis being you know I
guess federally illegal I guess right
now that's Up For Debate since you know
hemp has now been made legal through the
through or low THC cannabis which is
Industrial Hemp has now been made legal
and certainly there are companies that
are going after that market meaning that
they are developing crop protection
chemicals and you'll be happy to know
you guys that again you guys have been
Pioneers in this area and that people
are taking your lead but now again it's
a business they're investing Millions
into developing that safety package and
to know that when you brew that that te
or when you use that living soil product
on cannabis at that rate that it doesn't
affect there's no residuals there's no
runoffs that poisons you know Water
Supplies there's no I don't know I mean
they go through this whole environmental
analysis and that's what the EPA is
supposed to do right it's Environmental
Protection Agency they're there using
our tax dollars to supposedly protect
our environment so I'm not just coming
down as being pro EPA what I'm saying is
that we and you guys especially need to
we need to work with them so they can
properly regulate the use of these
products in commercially grown cannabis
because let's face it or not I you guys
were talking about corporations before
and I know uh Sam has dealt with large
corporations I've dealt with large
corporations that's how I built my
resume and got all those things on the
wall I mean ultimately at the end of the
day this is a money-making business
where people are in the business to
basically make a profit and either
return that profit to their shareholders
or their investors or whatever I mean
that's just corporations that's just
free enterprise and like it or not
that's what we got we can't really do
anything to stop it so you might as well
just get used to it there's big
companies that provide everything for
from the gasoline we put in our cars to
the fast food hamburgers if that's what
you choose to eat to e everything if
there is a market for something and
something wants to be bought and Delta 8
THC is a perfect example of this where
there's a market where cannabis is
illegal in certain States so what do
they do well I turn this CBD into
something that can get people high and
now you can go to websites or gas
stations or bodegas and get all kinds of
you know products that are made outside
the regulatory uh framework that most uh
cannabis uh uh uh operations are are
having to live on there I say that I'm
living in Vermont guys this is new we
moved from Pennsylvania to Vermont and
Vermont went recreational yesterday was
first time I've lived in a state that's
turned from medical to
recreational and I got a big joint to
smoke here on camera so we can celebrate
it but you know it's just really cool
what's happening up here there's a lot
of innovation Vermont's kind of like the
humble to the east a lot of great
Growers a lot of really dank weed up
here in these mountains and I'm living
on Lake Champlain which is really kind
of cool I look out and see sailboats go
by that's kind of cool but um just to go
back to science just and I'll end there
is that you know again anytime you learn
something you're being a scientist when
you learn something new and you're
expanding your knowledge over something
doesn't have to be scientific it could
be you know just a quicker way to get to
work or it could be you know gee if I
stirred my coffee more it wouldn't be so
sweet at the bottom you know just little
realizations like that you're you're
learning new things and as you learn new
things to you're basically being a
scientist so we're just explorers those
of us who are paid scientists have to
explore right at the current Frontier on
what's known and what's not known and we
all know people have been asking for
years and I think part of my attraction
uh here on church right has always been
the science and the research and gez
what what can we do to really push this
thing forward holy [__] folks be careful
what you wish for this is what the end
of prohibition looks like I'm getting a
faculty position here at the University
to study the use of canono to treat
traumatic brain injury I mean I I I have
to pinch myself to understand that you
know when we were out doing smoking
really dank California weed and eating
mushrooms on the parking lot out at the
Grateful Dead shows that we were ahead
of our time back in the 70s and 80s and
you know those of us who followed the
dead around I mean it was just so
[__] cool because that was just like
this Flash in time that existed and we
Traverse this Millennium right I think
most of the people here right that's
really [__] cool I have one kid born
in one Millennium another kid born in
another Liv I was alive during Jerry
Garcia's lifetime really really
important for me anyway so you know it's
um it's at the end of the day we're all
scientists we're all
Explorers and you know there's nothing
wrong with being inquisitive and wanting
to learn more about your environment or
what you're smoking or what you're
growing and
totally agree I think that that's really
awesome Mark I think that you know what
you're saying is true and inquisitivity
is awesome and I love you of course um
but you know as far as the EPA one thing
that I did want to say is I think that
we could entrust in more of these
overiding sort of Corporations or
fractures of the government if their
track record was more accountable when
we look at the EPA what have what they
have allowed in and what they have
allowed in to our soils and what has
happened to our soils with their
allocations and their
licensing to me should not have the word
protection on it so I think what we
continue to come down to is they're
supposedly protecting us but their track
record really doesn't show that they've
done a very good job so I feel like
the same way I'm not even talking all
the way
back for sure I
just B we can bash Pharmaceuticals all
we want but there's life-saving
medication out there that's saving
people's lives every day oh I'm not I'm
not bashing that I feel like it's really
important Pharmaceuticals and and what
like you guys were talking about the
pharmaceuticalization I mean that's
exactly what I'm working on I'm working
on trying to understand you know there
was a really important paper that was
published a couple weeks ago that that
showed that um uh uh canabo acids and I
think in particular cbga showed a
complete blocking of something called
store operated calcium influx which is a
way that helpers uh uh tea cells turn on
the release of pro-inflammatory cyto
kindes this is extremely important
didn't get any press whatsoever and it's
an extremely important discovery that
basically says how can avonoids work to
control inflammation it's always just
kind of like a black box so they they
hit the cannaboid receptors then there's
Downstream stuff that happens we don't
really know this group has figured it
out so to me I read that paper I've read
that paper eight times I I'm just I'm so
excited I'm so like this is the current
Frontier this is right where
knowledge ends and where we could start
looking into the crystal ball on what
could be and when you start looking at
all these ways that you know cannaboids
work on on the body I mean there there's
no class of compounds like that that
have the safety in humans the longterm
you know I mean humans have been using
cannabis for a while so if there was
toxic you know effects we would we would
have seen it we would have documented it
uh Yasmin herd's um research at Mount Si
New York is extremely important what
what she has now shown and this is all
very very recent research is that um uh
cannabis use in adolescence affects the
distribution of gray to white matter as
the brain matures and this is extremely
important and you can't say well okay
yeah you know kids who smoke weed during
those ages they can you know maybe have
com IED I don't know intellectual
capacity later on in life that's not
really what they're saying but the the
endoc canabo system and The cannaboid
receptors are so important that it you
couldn't imagine that using lots of
cannabis isn't going to somehow affect
it one way or another and I think her
research is really important to show
that the last thing I want to say is
this whole Renaissance
and and and what they're finding is that
uh people who are taking again very very
modest doses six months later they're
still showing efficacy in that treatment
I it is just it's amazing and so I
applaud the scientific Frontier in these
areas which are moving faster and faster
and faster as regulation changes and yes
that is driven by profit and the
almighty dollar I I I don't know I can't
fix that and I don't think we can fix
that on hash church but we can coexist
in that system and make sure that your
guys's knowledge is passed on to these
people who are regul so basically there
are products that are going to come out
that's going to mimic you know what you
guys do fly right so you have to be part
of that discussion and part of that
regulation people are going to do this
people are already doing this people
everything along the value chain I know
atn's seen it for years if you could
make it and you could sell it into the
Cannabis industry it's going to go and
it's going to go forward and it's going
to make money and it's going to grow and
before you know it you're going to be
10,000 20,000 880,000 orders and you're
G be oh I need to
sure you don't get a bunch of you know
[__] and and thieves and people who
are poisoning people there has to be
some government oversight and some
regulation I don't know what the right
level is it's not nuclear waste it's an
herbal medication it needs to be
regulated as such but if you're talking
about treatments that go onto plants
that are being mass-produced yeah
they're going to regulate that kind of
thing they should be they they always
have should be but companies large
companies were afraid to do the research
to basically bring that package forward
and say okay here's a fungicide that you
can use on cannabis to control powdery
mildew you could apply it at this rate
at this time and there's no degradation
byproducts that are going to affect the
the the end product I'm not saying that
that product exists but in order for
companies to develop that product they
need a regulatory pathway and then
they've just spent millions of dollars
they need to recoup that investment you
know welcome to Big Business this is
just that's and and Mark that's the
thing that that they're motivated by of
course by profit so they're Afra the the
fear comes in when there's not enough uh
security to protect the those
Investments so because right we we know
we know they're going to be profitable I
think if you look at that's not the
issue that's not the issue that's just
that's just accept it you just accept it
you buy a Cheerio you buy a corporation
you buy a car you buy a Tesla whatever
you buy it's all H it's all
contextualized within that understanding
that's what capitalism is I drive a car
as a matter of fact I have to go do that
pretty soon so but and I think
I think here like you just said it about
being able to use cannabis in TB you're
going to have this this job 50 years ago
I had a TBI and as a matter of fact when
I got it I was rolling a joint in the
car that we we got in a car accident and
it was Nevada so TBI or not I had to go
back into that car and find that ounce
or go to prison with a TBI um the the PO
I think it's it's a profound important
Point not everybody's going to be able
to smoke roll joints and smoke them so
that they can do mitigate their seizure
onset there has to be a way to access
science is is a tool a profound tool
we're the [__] the [__] uper as you're
saying is not the tool it never is and
neither is our what inspires us it's
never the tool it's how we are changed
and how we carry that forward what we're
willing
to what the cost is whether that's what
we're willing to spend or what we demand
of of others and so right now I think we
are in a very tenuous position
but you know as Sam
said it's all perfect and that's
eventuality not in the finite sense in
the sense
that you know in the quantum sense I
mean have I sort of have said you know
I'm going to just if it's all perfect in
the quantum sense then I'm just going to
step into that space because it makes
what I can't
handle just say yeah I can't wait to see
what you do Mar you got to share it
share some of your course work that
you're well I I'll just finish and I I I
think a ATN could probably provide a lot
of a lot of um experience or at least
maybe share some of experiences like
when you're dealing with when you're
dealing with vendors I'm not talking
about people who are touching the plant
I'm talking about every everything else
everything else that supports going into
that you're talking about you know
people who have you know payrolls and
and and and and employees and and those
employees have you know benefits like
health insurance so I I think it was
really quick to see like when you go to
like an MJ biscon that if there's
something that can be innovated that can
be sold into this industry it might be a
corporation but it might just be a mom
and pop Corporation two people just
garage inventors who are coming up with
the next little widget or all kinds of
different you know Innovations because
we're kind of at the birth of this new
phase for the you know cannabis industry
and I hate to use that word industry
because it always sounds like such a
dirty word but it is industry come on
for yeah I mean for for for the lack of
a better word it's it's just the word
that we use but the question is I guess
you know again when you have like
especially with CBD and and the whole
delta8 um Market Market the whole uh uh
uh loop loophole that the farm bill
created which created this um uh uh well
it basically satisfied a market that was
already created look people want to get
high right and those people in most
cannabis unfriendly states in the
country are you know gun ho on Delta 8
because people are making a [__] ton of
money and I've seen videos where I've
seen pallet rack three high like you'd
see like a Home Depot of finished goods
going from somewhere to somewhere and
those those products are being sold
without any real process specification
on this conversion of CBD to Delta 8 so
there's a lot of other stuff in there
and because it's unregulated unlike the
stuff that ATN has to you know I mean
everything that's sold in the regulated
market Delta H says well [__] you just
going to do this in an unregulated
fashion there we've all been there it
will become regulated it's just it's
only made it's only made possible
through the prohibition of Delta 9 if if
if there is no prohibition then we Delta
we would think Delta eight is a version
of covid or something you know Delta
eight is irrelevant Delta eight is not
extracted from the plant it's made as an
active pharmaceutical ingredient from
CBD isolate so this is a Market that
exists because people want to get high
and if people want to get high they need
cannabis grown Delta 9 not Delta eight
made from CBD right it's only a matter
of time it's just satisfying the it's
the market this and this is really
endemic of a
problem that's created when you're just
when there's a a profit
driven um uh creation so they're cre
creting this because it's driven by
profit so they can make M when you can
just really get high it does you don't
need to go through all of
this those warehous that
are facing and that's that and there you
can we work it out on hash Church well
it's it's always worth the conversation
and this is why cannabis is legal
whatever however long it's taken to some
degree it's legal but it's motivated the
legality has been motivated in two
different ways one because people desire
it know it it frees it helps to heal the
Mind Body
Consciousness and because of profit the
potential to make great deal of money
and because of that that we're sitting
in the middle of a kind of mosh pit or
and and I think that what can happen is
that these conversations but really
taking creating accountability forcing
accountability um demanding
accountability from you know you're
never I won't I don't buy anything from
Amazon it's a principled piece maybe
those things will change maybe that
industry that owns just about everything
probably the house I live in pretty soon
um or many people live in um I I think
we have to really work from from this
space as individuals speak to our
community support our community and ask
of it the
greatest the greatest
possibility always asking for something
greater because that's how we get it and
we demand it from one another and from
our communities and uh you know it's not
going to get better if we don't if we
buy into it only if we demand We join it
you know that drop dropping out we
should have bought some radio stations
and televis stations in the 60s you know
um I'd like to add that you know the
profit driven corporations were birthed
out of something different you know the
first time I really understood the
importance of regulation in cannabis was
not from a corporation but from my
friends in Jamaica who were just growing
weed on the side of a mountain and then
you know I'm kind of like I made bubble
one time with the flower and it was
really [__] up bubble and then I
walked around my friend's field and what
I found was some illegal fungicides that
can't even be used in North America that
they just shipped to Jamaica and he used
these and I we had a conversation later
on that night on the beach and I asked
him like what were you thinking and he
was like I was thinking of putting food
on my table man like I can't afford to
lose this crop and so it wasn't a big
Corporation putting people at risk it
was a poor Jamaican farmer who just
wanted to feed his family and who was
because there was no regulations he was
able to do it but at the cost of every
sing I mean John Burell smoked some of
that bubble and he said that he got
extremely sick from it it was really bad
keep in mind when we're concentrating
the resins off of these plants often
you'll concentrate these chemical
powders that have been put onto the
plant and are stuck on that resin so
it's not just corporations it's not just
I got to pay my
shareholders sometimes it goes all the
way to the other side and it's I just
just got to put food on the table I'm
not trying to buy a Ferrari I'm not
trying to you know be some corporate
douche nozzle with a private jet I'm
really just trying to feed my kids and
maybe get them some shoes and some
clothes and so that's the importance of
Regulation we need to have a little bit
of it to to hold each other accountable
and it's not always a corporation that
you have to hold accountable sometimes
it's talk who produced those additives a
corporation
right there is there is it's cyclic and
it goes back you know it goes back there
anyway I hate to jump out of this
conversation with y'all but um much much
I'm so thankful for for being having
this opportunity to hang out with you
all and much much love and it's an honor
for us as well Valerie be safe on your
journey you got many big highs and much
expansion love you so much thanks for
coming out
you guys too my
heart big hey Marcus just I wanted to
add to what you're saying I think
it's hey buddy nice to see everyone hey
Colin how you guys doing it's been a
while Mark
everybody dragonfly fam good to see you
guys
eten best friend Farms always awesome
Wade came up often in a conversation I
had yesterday I bet Adam a g he's uh
he's a good guy man he's uh and if he's
still listening uh we love you man yeah
incredible grower and what a good family
they have up in mesino so mesino
grasslands uh for those that don't know
what we're talking about great family of
individuals really good Growers um but
he calls Vermont home that's true he
calls Vermont home so he's like us in
East coaster so uh but yeah I mean look
I I think over the years we we've all I
think it was a lack of knowledge at
first in North America we were being we
were using things on plants that we
didn't know because we were so young at
the time at least my crew was um green
cure was was pushed on to us as a as a
product to use to bring the pH level of
the of you know the the surface level
down so petrius and uh powdery mildew
wouldn't grow but you know then later we
learned that you can't light it on fire
right and and we've we've learned so
much through trial and era and I think
that's the honest truth from from my
side of it is like we just didn't know
and we didn't have this big Community
that's so open today um we didn't have
conferences we didn't have like private
events and seses where we were sharing
you know like back to you know like I
had Marcus on true sters.com chat room
you know like and I we would chat and
like plural [__] and Kaka and ot1 and
all these guys would jump in and and
that was the only space that I really
knew to ask live and direct questions
that would have direct call and
response um so I think it's it's also a
bit of it all together and as we learn
and evolve you know um having you know
Sage stages such as Kelly and Josh
around and others like you that have
been so deep in in um just learning
about what agricultural me like
practices mean um and Consciousness
means together and how that kind of um
plays a role so that that's something
that you know together we've we've kind
of at least I should say personally I
I've really you know it's been a battle
and a learning experience this whole
journey reading books from Rob Clark and
you know they they didn't tell you what
not to do they told you what what to do
what how to get rid of things and what
to look for but there was never that in
between conversation so I think those
are the things that we have today that
just we just didn't have um for so many
years cross and print right yeah it was
it was it man I I read those books front
to back back to front every almost every
day for years you know and that was just
the way it was because I didn't have
anywhere else to go there was no YouTube
channels and there was no internet with
information or or basis of but as as you
stated I mean we started off as you know
individual dispensaries and then we
realized well I realized that I got sick
from Cannabis off something I couldn't
see and so in 2007 I was like well what
are the standards for testing and
everybody there's no standards for
testing what do you mean there's no
standards there's no one testing except
the University of Mississippi right and
so when I reached out to them to
actually say hey can we get the
standards they were
like but right but but we need the
standards and so there were no standards
and of course I didn't know Sam at the
time so you know I used Ethan Russo and
others to find Arno and then bring
smuggled him into the states with his
testing solution and then you know
started to calibrate an actual
laboratory because I didn't want to kill
people who have AIDS and cancer for the
possibility that they could get a upper
respiratory infection and of course I
know now that that was an actual plate
test that would have determined that as
opposed to understanding the potency I
started in that direction because that
sounded like a logical and found others
Addison and Steve dangelo and others who
were also interested in doing that but
yeah if we didn't have our semi-legal
illegal dispensaries I mean we spent BPG
over a million dollars ourselves in that
testing okay who could have and in the
Private Industry would have spent that
money to actually do that testing to
bring the at least the testing from THC
and then finding CBD from the darkness
into the light you know it was us that
took the chance because we realized
there was a hole and if we didn't
necessarily fix that hole
there's always going to be a hole there
that we're always going to trip over so
we even as I'm a professional lay
scientist realized that I there there
was science that needed to be so that I
didn't kill the people that I were
selling my quote unquote legal illegal
cannabis to because I wanted to be an
ethical Steward because it felt right
because I self-healed myself from
Cannabis because of my Gulf War syndrome
right because of my multiple chemical
exposures because you know I was
gunfighter in a war over oil okay I
lived under the oil fields it was
literally 28 under the oil fields
whereas un out from under the oil fields
it was 120 degrees that's how thick the
smoke was ladies and gentlemen and that
of course destroyed my my nervous system
and my you know immunity system to the
point where I had to figure out how to
heal myself and by figuring out from
Cannabis and exercise was able to
stimulate my appetite T to eat motivated
me to say you know what I need to step
outside myself and find a way to help
others so sometimes we have to be self-
impacted or find a way or someone in our
lives that's been impacted because I
cannot tell you how many people have
come to me and said hey my family member
has this that and the other and they
can't get it and I need to get it for
them because there's no other way for us
to go whereas two weeks ago my group the
veterans Action Council was using
science on Capitol Hill we had 26
meetings in two days and we were using
that nasal spray that the Medics are
using currently in Israel as the litmus
because the majority of people we met
with were on the veterans or armed
services committee so they had military
fellows there so what we found as the
arrow through in the conversation was
this TBI nasal spray because it caused
immediate uh shrinkage and and non
expansion that continues to happen in
the brain well right now Israeli Medics
have that in their kit and right now if
you're hit with a TBI no matter what
they are given this right there on the
spot and it is having great effect and
when we talk to these fellows who are
just military people in regular suits
for the next year this is what got
through them because they understood how
many of their brothers and sisters are
also suffering and will continue to
suffer from these TB because of the new
level of warfare that we are
experiencing are going to continue
continue to experience and so this was a
way of using a pharmaceutical product to
loosen the the strings of prohibition
because that mountain is still so high
for us to move that we still have to
find the human aspect and the connection
to make them realize oh this matters to
me why because my fellow soldiers could
benefit from this and we know that oh a
lot of our military has to be taken care
of and they're not being taken care of
and these TBI follow every body to their
grave so it' be best as we can to do as
best as possible to do as a preventative
which as we know THC or ingestion of
cannabis right after TBI seems to stop
that and stop the advancement of that
psychosis as well as the the the death
which is the swelling of the brain
itself which causes untold amounts of of
Life damaging realities that not only
does the soldier have to deal with but
their family and their whole support
units have to deal with with as well as
we ourselves have to pay for it as their
care yeah they have to be doing this on
the sideline at the NFL as we've
tragically seen recently right that
these guys are out there getting their
brains literally beat in and then
somehow they let that guy go back out
and he got reinjured you know yeah and
and it just it's [__] nuts and the
government knows it because they got
their own patent on the neuroprotective
properties of cannaboids so I mean this
is going to happen this is go this is
going to happen like you said ATN the
the the nasal spray is a quick immediate
onset into the brain and so I think
we're going to try to stack so we're
gonna we're g we're actually writing a
grant to DOD and NIH and others to
basically help pay for this work because
this is really really important work and
I think we all know it's going to work
we're going to see the needle is going
to move on this we don't know exactly
you know again dose and you have to look
at a lot of different impacts when
you're trying to develop a new
therapeutic for something like like this
but you can imagine if you can deliver
across the blood so the bread brain
barrier is a very interesting kind of
Gateway that limits what's in your
bloodstream going into your brain and
and so if you can get things across the
bloodb brain barrier and what we know
about canabo because they're very
hydrophobic is that they can get in we
can get canabo into the brain during
that golden hour of trauma so there's
that that right that one hour it's like
you have an hour to basically intervene
and even like with other brain disorders
ATM like stroke right now with stroke I
mean just take two aspirin and call me
in the morning you know there's really
no way of treating but you figure that
you know again maybe it's the fact that
the government had a patent on it maybe
the fact that these things are off
patent now and now in order for a
pharmaceutical company to get the return
on that investment they'd actually have
to develop new medications to see if
they work you know I think again the
phyto canabo can give us a clue on what
might eventually be the treatment that
gets used you know that gets FDA
approval and all that kind of stuff but
yeah all that research needs to be done
and it seems like you know again I I I
don't know why but when the NFL
publicized that they were throwing a
billion dollars at research they didn't
look at concussion at all they just
looked at pain because all they want to
do is dull the pain and send that drone
back out onto the field because there's
million dooll sponsors that need to make
money on that football game and I tell
you what if you haven't seen it yet you
you all should watch the movie
concussion
with Will Smith yeah Will Smith's a dick
and everything but anyway get beyond
that and go watch that movie concussion
you'll never watch a football game in
the same way again and you'll learn that
again the NFL is basically conspiring to
basically keep this thing quiet yeah
they want to keep it under wraps right
and it's the same treatment for soldiers
it'd be the same kind of thing it'd be
like Full Assault of avonoids into the
brain during that golden hour trauma
maybe this could have saved Bob Saget's
life right because Bob Saget the
comedian they think he just fell in his
bathtub or something hit his head fell
asleep and never woke up you know so
there's definitely you know the canono
are are definitely on the therapeutic
you know radar to
use these things not just to get high
but to use them for their medical
benefits to treat disease like this was
speaking with Rob Clark and Rob Clark
said mulim said you know in the 80s that
within that hour if they smoked a joint
just on the way to the
hospital the amount of neuroprotection
that is it's Untold uh but I'm very
interested now because you brought up
Strokes because as we know that when you
smoke cannabis it dilates or can dilate
the uh the blood the blood vessels right
so if you're having a stroke and you've
got a blockage could that also send the
blockage
to another area and causing more danger
so that's where I kind of wonder what
what I'm thinking ATN is just in sort of
like a a uh uh something where you're
going to take advantage of the
anti-inflamatory
pro-apoptotic uh modes that so
cannabinoids are biologically active on
so many different levels and you would
think again that the the best thing you
could possibly do is get as much into
your brain at that point right after
that traumatic brain injury and and just
see what happens you know I mean could
it be worse so there are there are
people working on this and and
cannaboids are definitely key but one of
the things you guys are missing the the
most important factor are these um
membrane bound extracellular vesicles
that are called
exosomes exosomes have the ability to to
get through the blood brain barrier um
my friend who works at the neurosurgery
department in Florida uh Miami um Dr
brentt Reynolds he discovered brain stem
cells for his thesis in the late 80s
brilliant guy awesome guy uh he's been
doing some research uh at the University
on these exosomes and when they put
exosomes into uh the nasal spray and up
the nose they found that it was
delivering a 45 times uh payload uh from
any other method that they have at the
University there 45 times um so they
they are working on concussion
medications that'll be available in
every not just professional athletes but
your children's sports games as well
where you'll be able to use these
exosomes and exosomes are produced by
pretty much you know most cells like not
only Mamon but also uh fungal and and
plant cells so what Dr Brent did was he
um isolated exosomes from the hemp plant
and low and behold those those those
exosomes contain
cannabinoids so this this is really
really exciting science and I hope that
this little blip gets you lit Dr Mark
and you start going out and reading a
bunch of uh um articles on this because
these exosomes people have been studying
them for probably about 20 to 30 years
now but um I'm not so send me a link or
something like that I can send you a ton
of papers I have about a dozen papers
that I can send you on exomes and you
you will be very excited because
like I said you can extract them from
the cannabis plants and they do contain
cannabinoids in in the exosomes exosomes
are used for cells to communicate with
one another so they send they and and Dr
Brent even under you know the belief
system now that the a lot of the amazing
work that is being done with with stem
cells are actually their exosomes that
they're releasing to communicate so
everyone there's your homework for the
uh week exosome EXO o m uh they're
membrane bound extracellular vesicles
that are produced in the endosomal
compartment of most eukariotic cells and
uh they're interesting they're they're
nanoscopic they're like 20 to 80
nanometers and uh they definitely break
the blood brain
barrier nature along with medicinal
mushrooms so let's let's make sure the
medical medicinal mushrooms continue to
be in the conversation when we're
talking about blood they produce exome
they produce exosomes and if you if you
extract the exosomes from medicinal
mushrooms you'll find the medicinal
compounds from those mushrooms in those
exomes it's unbelievable the system is
perfect and they are bioavailable to our
body immediately and you know they help
our body's receptors and neur and
neurology become more regenerative they
regenerate they if if every cell in our
body has 380 trillion pathogens in it
basically every single cell which how
many cells 180 million I forget how many
cells are in the body but every 180
trillion right yeah and then every one
of those cells has 380 trillion
pathogens and it I mean it really shows
you that exosomes and and when your when
your body's exuding it's because it's
out of balance and and it allows those
pathogens out of the cells it creates an
environment where that part of the cell
can exude and so that's why this help
and well-being regiment this this nod to
herbalism and micology comes back in
because that group of people never got
into chemicals and they continued to to
to walk that line of of cellular
regeneration and bioavailability to
where your body doesn't have to it can
accept it so that's why it's important
it's why it continues to show up at the
table it's why it continues to be part
of the conversations because it's
natural to us and it helps ourselves
Kelly's been doing amazing work with
athletes and Trauma uh in mountain
biking and specifically downhill
mountain biking and uh with Incredible
fractures incredible breaks concussions
people hidden trees rocks that and and
working with top athletes which also
have all kinds of sponsors that need
them to do you know 720s and back flips
and trips and all the things and you
know they they can't be out for a whole
summer and so I would love maybe Kelly
will get into it but uh you know to
bring in professional athletes is also a
type of trauma it's different than
soldiers of course but it's trauma quick
trauma fast and it can really affect you
for the rest of your how many people
have fallen and for the rest of their
life they talk about this fall that you
know made it to where they can't do all
this stuff play soccer all whatever it
is so if you actually deal with the
trauma proper you know your body can
rebalance when you find the compounds
that break the blood brain barrier then
it allows your body to function at its
organic chemistry higher level higher
self and with that I really appreciate
and love you all I have to go outside
and do some work some hand digging on
the in the earth and stuff so big big
love to all you all and every fractal of
knowledge that comes out of us you know
is a positive one a special big up to
Wade laughter haven't heard enough from
you today but just know every single day
is a day that we are giving thanks for
you uh and your journey on Earth and and
everyone else in the world everyone else
thank you so much blessed
love Yeah and Josh had mentioned I've
been I have been working with a lot of
people with heavy duty brain trauma and
I
also am a brain trauma you know I think
an incredible success story um when I
was seven years old I had a car accident
um that I lost my sight for a long
period of time and I was cross side for
nine
months um and and it you know was not
only an incredible concussion but it
broke my skull so I have an opening in
my skull and then from that I have
suffered really tremendous
um uh I mean headaches I I don't really
even you know it's beyond migraines it's
a migraine that goes beyond and so when
my brain has been looked at in a CAT
scan or in any other MRIs I have
showings of maybe a thousand Different
Strokes in my brain so I had the ability
to either go totally natural which is
why a lot lot of where I'm coming from
and I'm I'm really tried and true and I
work with several hundred patients right
now I call them gems I don't even want
to call people patients I don't I don't
even feel like it's a practitioner or
it's a this or it's a that or it's a
Seeker it's just being human on this
planet right now is traumatizing in and
of itself being in a body is yet another
traumatizing thing in and of itself with
all of the different toxins that it's
sitting in all of the different Wars of
different whatever spiritual means
whatever you want to talk about we're
getting hit on all levels so the reason
why I'm G to continue to be the voice
for nature is because I understand that
in a way that I don't need to look
towards other things I understand that
of course science is a
representation of nature of course
science is a way for us to explain
nature
but it's the
misrepresentation of where science has
to go to where then we have to correct
it because ATN you're talking about so
many important things what you're
talking about is is is compassion Beyond
and yet I hear so many different
dichotomies and fractures of Science and
War and and industry has caused these
ailments for then people to have to go
and seek nature to then go and seek more
science because people are utilizing
what is registered and what is allocated
by maybe the EPA or science to then try
to get it out of them to then go back to
nature which is exactly what V said it's
cyclical and maybe cyclical starts with
an
SI because humans just tend to do that
and I think what we really can do is we
can come together and have this
beautiful understanding that all of the
beautiful points of science that are
truly trying to help us without monetary
need without the lobbying without all of
the government control because community
care because what you're talking about
with ATN and I know definitely you know
that's where you're at with Mark so I
think that there's people on the planet
who are utilizing these great knowledges
for good and then people who are using
utilizing these great knowledges just
for money and profit to push forward a
possible ego or competition but really
what it comes down to is that there are
people who need to heal and that is
where we are going to reach the highest
Collective consciousness of all of us
because we're all at that highest level
of healing that we all understand and
we're all following that highest level
of healing that's where where we're
going to actually go to the next level
that's what we're all seeking we're all
seeking that and I just wanted to say
that first of all I appreciate
everything that you all are doing every
single one of you because and I don't
even mean just on this anybody who's
watching as well because you're wanting
to be better because you want to be a
gem on this planet who is making us all
better and I know I got caught off on a
tangent there but thank you all for
listening and mostly I'm just saying
that I have a deep deep deep
appreciation for all of you and I just
thank you thanks for the tangent I'm
smoking good
weed love you
Kelly dope to have you here what are you
smoking on yeah bubble man we haven't
asked this in a long time what's
everybody smoking on I mean uh I'm
smoking on some some raw in here myself
here so this is some tasty little
squeeze squeeze what about you I'm
smoking on my own rosin I'm smoking on
my live hash rosin some snow Gods 84%
cannabinoids 88.9%
Turpin I'm smoking on some beautiful
Bubba width flower that just came off
the hangers from this year
2022 and uh obviously it's a really ni
nice uplifting
sativa with some really beautiful headyy
space thank you to the breeder of that
and I can't remember who it
was and Ed Chen I just wanted to say
that
uh when did you start doing your lab
testing was that in 2008 or soon after
uh we started in
2007 and I had to switch Labs so 2008 is
when I really had an a real lab and I
know you were doing it you know decade
before but the the lab we were doing
with was in Berkeley they were doing um
over testing for uh novaris and bear so
they had six HV plc's and uh like four
uh gas chromatograph so I knew that I
had uh sound um scientists who could at
least and then we brought Arno over to
teach us the extraction because back
then it's $10,000 fine per test right if
you're caught with cannabis in a
laboratory so he taught us to do the
suspended solution so we would take the
100% alcohol shake the cannabis for um
grind it at at an equal part then put it
into a um a tube and then shake it for
one minute and then we would extract
that and then that solution then we
would take to the laboratory and then
that's what we would do that's what we
would do 1500 tests on between yeah I I
I understand what you're saying is the
parts uh were so low of the active
ingredient but in a measured amount that
you could use it for calibration of your
gc's and hlc's but it wasn't illegal to
have the
standard also too reme remember that
when two they first started testing in
California and in the Netherlands also
more than 80% closer to 85 % of all of
the samples tested had uh either
pesticides
insecticides Andor micro so uh yeah
protection for the consumer absolutely
was
needed hey Sam I have a question for you
um when you guys when you and Rob were
doing your work at War Farm was was
there um any sort of testing that was at
your fingertips when you guys were doing
that work or was it um hard to to do
that type of work or no
no we had a legally licensed lab we had
hlc a prep HL prep so for isolating
small single amounts you know Gram
amounts of a of a single cannaboid and
we had uh GCF for doing Turpin and
canono also I preferred a GC because uh
when you smoke cannabis or VAP it uh
you're actually uh destroying part of it
and when a GC does its work it destroys
part of this of the sample you put in so
it's it's closer to what people are
actually consuming then hplc will show
you know the acid and the neutral uh
elements but uh it doesn't really show
what is being delivered to a person not
that a GC is exactly the same as a
person but it's
closer started we started with GCS and
the problem
the coming up the Machinery so badly
that that's why they gravitated toward
the V uvh plcs is because of the
maintenance that was happening because
of the turnover at the at the gas
chromatographs because of the
ignition now the a so hlc is used so you
could quantify plant material and plant
material is enriched with cannaboid
acids what they often do is they just
apply the correction to correct for
after decarbox silation what the canabo
acid which is measured this produces
this amount of cannabinoid so they
should have like either what's called a
total THC or or theoretical
THC but um yeah I mean Sam that's true
that you know what you smoke is what
what it goes up to T
but um I think for um to be more precise
on on what is actually in the plant and
especially if you're doing native like
live resin extractions or if you're
making you know again really quality
hash and and turning it into rosin um
really having the canabo acid profile is
going to give you more
complete understanding of what that oil
actually is agree absolutely with you
Mark about
hlc's but I'm I'm just saying that if
you want to know what happens what the
THC level that's being delivered to an
average smoker in a joint then a GC was
actually more valuable to us for that
one
aspect yeah now there's a there's an
issue I know if you're dealing with this
at all ATN that there's a so-called
thing called lab shopping where uh
producers are again going around to
different labs and trying to get you
know the highest potency results that
they can possibly get on large batches
reproducibly so they can have a more
reliable you know route to Market
without it you know uncovering you know
people trying to negotiate to lower
prices because again this is also just a
pain of prohibition I think is that
there is a downward pressure on
producers to basically you know I mean
again the margin especially if you look
at a mature State like California is is
the margins that you're seeing at the
dispensary and distributor levels are
certainly not um equal equalized across
the whole production supply chain and
certainly I think like if you look at
states that are rolling out new programs
where you have vertically integrated um
organizations where underneath one
license or a group of licenses you have
cultivation extraction
manufacturing and dispensing I I know
California inserts distribution right so
those so those Distributors can make a
lot of money but really so my son who's
out in LA right now and doing really
well I mean just to break into that
Market is really difficult because you
really need to have some kind of
stratification through that
distribution dispensing Market to get
enough volume to make your teeny weeny
margin yeah enough to pay the bills
right Colin you're you're hitting it on
the head man but it's uh but yeah but
like I also find it at at what Marcus
said earlier with the with spraying and
and I IPM
management it's also on the farmers end
they're they're looking for higher coas
too so they can sell it into the market
because that helps them right because
there's this weird smoke and mirrors
that Tac means something right and
quality is not quantitated and
quantitated through any of these numbers
it's a glimpse of what's there in terms
of weight and chemical classes right so
so this is the problem right the current
issue right now that's led to this so
called phenomenon called lab shopping is
that is that when you get bud at the
dispensary it's not Dy there's still
moisture in it right and so certainly
like if you're looking at a COA and
you're reporting potencies based on a
dried weight basis dried weight means
bone dry that means no water so you have
to really have good technique to do the
water activity measurement to understand
what fraction of that cannabis as
received at the dispensary because it's
not bone dry right it has moisture it
has like 12 so but Mark here here's
where I'd argue through my Journeys and
even the last month where I had an issue
not even an issue this is just how it
went where I sent a batch in had 12 or
11% or 9% moisture right I sent it in
right that was the the R&amp;D COA they they
tested it and it said they said that it
had 12% moisture yeah and the tack was
actually higher then lower moisture
content one that they had sent me and it
was again these are the
the it was the same lab right so same
lab same same you know same even within
a lab it's statistically problematic to
make comparisons because there's so much
[__] variation here correct and so
what what this really relies on is the
fact that so when you so so okay how do
to describe this quickly so you have to
do the water activity measurement right
the water act so actually there was a
woman who gave a really good talk on
this at the online cannabis Symposium
that I think is on YouTube and I think
she's also giving the American Chemical
society's um Journal Club a presentation
this month I think if you Google it her
name is Jenny I think and she gave a
great talk on it and just describes
exactly what this phenomena is and so so
so what you need to do is when you're
when you're assessing potency and you're
reporting it on as it it's different
than dried weight right and and Colin
this is really you know important and
again goes to what Sam was saying is
that when they're determining the
moisture content in a moisture balance
which is just a little mini oven that
you put a sample on it just weighs
before and after that just you heat it
up the water goes away but what else
happens tpin go away right can abinoid
DEC carboxilate so now you've totally
changed everything you no longer have
the same denominator that you had when
you started with that experiment so AR
that's why we used to use the glass
desiccator so we do leave it in it
overnight with uh those blue crystals
that turn right right right that's that
get rid an indicator in there that tells
you that that would get rid of 99% of
the moisture not 100% but as close as we
could get in our lab in an easy way and
that's what we always did before we
tested anything with our GC but Sam the
key thing is you're not heating it up
right no we're not heating it up at all
okay so when you're in a Cannabis
Testing Lab and you have hundreds of
samples do you think you can wait for
desicator so
again what this woman showed is that you
could do just do a room temperature
vacuum desiccation and even at that room
temperature vacuum desiccation you're
still losing a big chunk of tpes but
you're not doing the cannaboid
decarbox and it turns out again when
you're when you're testing something and
you're in the 20% regime of canabo total
canabo uh that amount of CO2 is
significant so when you DEC carboxilate
it and again this is the going back to
the original discussion about using gas
chromatography which is when you
decarbox it you're you you you've
chemically
altered the the the plant there's no
other way of saying it I know what
you're saying Sam that while you're
smoking it when you're decarboxylating
it but if someone's using it as like a
tincture or if I know some people who
are now putting live rosin into gummies
and they taste delicious they taste like
the rosin Trad they were derived man
they taste really good so there I don't
think there's any decarbox I don't think
there's I think it's just raw rosin
going into the gummy itself no they're
we no they're decars oh they are decars
you decarb the p and then you can put
drop that and do whatever you need to
but yeah okay but I I don't know if you
agree with me Colin I mean certainly I
think I like seeing the hlc data because
the hlc data showed me what that flower
contains certainly the GC data is cool
and that's what you need for like a head
space measurement for tur no I think it
look I think any look anytime you have
more data to compare against itself and
pit against itself as you know the 10%
variance in each state is also a
problematic aspect that gets tacked on
to all these things like Colorado for
instance is a is a really it's just kind
of confusing to be honest in terms of
how they calculate milligram serving um
so because there's a there's a
denominator that they have to do math on
to get that that actual you know
milligram serving that they believe is
in your your product so if you you test
for say
85% there's a 10% variance that gets
tacked onto that that knocks it down to
70 you know maybe below 70 maybe 68
right so there's a reason why we had a
hlc and a GC and an hclp prep because
that allowed us to isolate uh several
grams of a single canabo and uh it was
really important to have all three of
those but what we used the most actually
was J uh GC FID especially for Tes you
know that's that was our go-to
tool I I just put in the big ethical
problem that we found when we started to
do testing was exactly the whole problem
that we're talking is because we realize
also the majority of those original 1500
tests that the majority of them were
very chemically close together and what
we realized is that there was going to
be a perception that THC percentage was
somehow going to matter to people and we
knew that that was not the real case
here and unfortunately Harbor Side
decided to flood it out as we were
deciding the ethical realities because
it is still prevalent if people think
along the lines of alcohol that oh it's
just because it's a high number I must
be getting more [__] up and must be
getting more of the sensation and more
of that feeling whereas we know it's a
symbiotic relation that Ensemble effect
of the tpin DI Turpin sesquiterpenes and
everything ingested together that are
giving this that effect and so
this is the thing that's also missing
for the that nasal spray is of course
it's THC dominant but it needs all the
other Spectrum easiest the easiest way
to understand thatan is if you smoke
100% pure THC it does not get you high
as pure cleaned up resin of skunk number
one that's only 50 60 7 8% of THC at the
most but
the resin gets you higher agreed by
weight but we didn't all understand in
078 the tpin and all of that because we
were still quantifying the THC and then
finding that secondary Spike which was
CBD so this is also the understanding
we've been able to gain as we were able
to strike all right this off the map and
so it opened up these other
opportunities to where now we're testing
CBG cbga and all the other uh acid
precursors and are understanding and
finding our newer ones because now
science can play and we've checked off
that list now we have to continue to add
to that list but also add to our
understanding of why it matters because
science isn't is still not replicating
what the plant is producing right we
still nobody's been able to take a tpine
recipe and make it exactly what comes
off of a plant and the first one that
does is going to be pretty amazing when
they do but no one's come even close
have you found that's cuz they're not
using the other volatile organic
compounds that are present in the
profile they just are thinking about tur
there are there are other volatiles but
besides that they're not using all of
the
150 uh turpins which are found in
cannabis they might be using 10 of them
or 20 of them but uh the average tpine
uh we were able to find about 50 or more
tpin and we only had maybe 100 or 120 of
the Turin to do our testing with so
there was tpping that we didn't have
which uh even if they're there in tiny
tiny amounts I mean Turin are there in
tiny amounts to start with and yet they
really have a a an incredible effect
they they the right turpins can
definitely make cannabis more potent and
uh mod the effects in a in a major way
yeah the issue is is that when you're
talking about a commodity any commodity
any commodity where large scale
manufacturing third-party testing and
production is happening there be some
ways some metrics of basically testing
for quality and uh yeah ATN I kind of I
I kind of hear what you're saying about
you know THC percentage I think of also
like the psychology of the dispensary
buyer and when they go to buy a product
they they they you know okay they can
look at the product they can smell it
but what's its THC percentage or thca
percentage if they know what they're
talking about right and so it it's just
again a metric maybe it's not the right
metric but it is a metric and when
you're talking about say buying large
quantities of of plant material and you
have I don't know 50 kilos at you know
14% but you have 50 kilos 18% you know
which one are you going to you know I I
I I think that there's like there's a
business mentality there but also like
if you're in our business where you're
extracting well that now the THC
percentage makes a makes makes a big
deal you know what I've seen now and
I've seen this on a couple different
coas where you know the plant makes
cannaboid acids but obviously the the
dispens
or the COA is going to report that total
THC number well I think what people do
to up their THC numbers is they spray
distillate there's a lot of like
spraying and dipping and all that kind
of [__] going on these days [__] they're
putting what uh hhc distillate now onto
hemp and selling hhc flour which totally
doesn't exist right yeah so now that
there's that infrastructure that okay we
can just take a distillate we could just
do that on the samples we send off for
testing the thing about that is that
here's where hplc makes a difference
because if you're testing flour you're
going to see those cannaboids as
cannaboid acids if they're spraying with
THC distillate Ah that's been decarbox
so you'll see a
THC that will come up and we like well
total THD is you know 25% because we add
the THC that's existing with the thca
now granted there is some you know
adventitious decarbox silation that just
happens after harvesting but you guys
know as well as I know that you know we
all like fresh material and I think part
of that freshness is exactly what you're
saying Sam there's that whole underlying
Symphony of tpes and even you know
they're not necessarily tpin but they're
Turpin noids I'd call them because like
those prenol sulfides which that group
out norgan has now you know basically um
used a volatile sulfur detector to
detect our the skunky essence of
cannabis penal sulfides and the
disulfide of penal sulfide and so they
now have actually a method that they're
using at testing labs to assign the
gassiness of a strain based on the
detection of the volatile sulfides and
Marcus we had that dude on church right
we when they before they published their
paper that guy came on hash church
because I remember that was the first
time we had that conversation I think
what was his name he was talking about F
yeah the the
F yeah yeah that's right that that guy
well coming back for sure yeah that
there's a professor there and he's
involved in the American Chemical
Society subdivision and I've met him at
a couple meetings since we had that
discussion on church and yeah so they
basically have a
gas uh you know scale of gassiness of
how gassy your your weed or your hash is
based on the detection of these volatile
sulfides and again that's just that's a
recent discovery just with like in the
last what two years right I mean yeah
Max Max and his team at abstract they're
the ones who kind of disc discovered it
right and wrote that paper well keep in
mind Nick discovered it about 20 years
ago so when that paper came out he did
chuckle to himself uh a few
times got it Nick Z if I remember he did
it in hops yeah he did it in hops he
discovered 1,400 different styes in hops
with that very machine that Mark is
talking about and it's like some
ridiculously like one to the trillion or
something like it was he came on and he
explained it I think they found five or
so in cannabis so far and one of them is
suspected of being much stronger
smelling than all the rest I've got
several of the files here but nobody has
course you
do I asked if they can if they can do
the turp profile of dog [__] because no
what what I want to do is I want to know
files contribute to potency or
modulation of I'm certain they do don't
you think Sam you can't assume that most
of the tpping don't oh but I'm sure what
they do is they I'm sure they they they
modulate in that they they help create
and I've said this before on Church
before and I think there is references
out in the literature you know just
increases the fluidity at the at the at
the membrane at the at a at a cell
membrane so so tpin help
exchange uh uh stuff across the cell
membrane and I think what happens in
that Sam and it might be adventitious is
that there are things that now come into
the cell that uppr regulate canono
receptor expression and I think part of
the Entourage effect is that
upregulation of The cannaboid receptors
that has to happen that happens with
full e full spectrum extracts that just
doesn't happen with
theing like kind of diminishes your your
your thca effects you know yeah I think
so and uh what we basically did was took
25 milligrams of absolutely 100% pure
THC or we weighed these put them in a
volcano with the tiniest Spike of a
single tpine and we went through about
15 of the different Turing the top ones
and uh some of them definitely
potentiated uh more of them modulated
but all of them did not do things like
you say kopine uh I felt was negative
yeah yeah there's a few that do that so
it's it's interesting LOLOL might might
be actually one of them as well I find
Karlene is known to be a a CB2 uh
Agonist right so so it it acts as
basically a canabo and there's been this
discussion about calling it a canono
because the people who found that out
called it a dietary canono you know know
beta caropine because it's in you know
uh a black pepper o you know yeah yeah I
mean like I I think there's there's all
kinds of new recent data on uh that kind
of like fleshes out some of the um
Entourage effect because they're finding
not only more compounds in cannabis
extract that contribute to the overall
biological effect but but they're
discovering new receptors that these
things are hitting so they're learning
more and more and more when I say they
we I mean collectively us scientists and
everyone the whole human race I mean
that we do have a crystal ball it's
called the scientific literature and you
know science is a fascinating subject
for kids uh to learn and to be
fascinated in um it just there's all
kinds of fascinating when you have a
microscope and you have a kid you have a
whole day of activity man there's all
kinds of things but um I I just want to
go back and say one other thing so this
is again talking about some of the
things
that your mic's hot
Nick I'm sorry your mic is hot it's not
muted I was just letting you know I
could hear some sounds coming welcome
we're talking we're talking about file
so I thought I'd invite you in because
you're one of the guys that opened that
you were the guy that opened that
conversation up with me so yeah Dr Mark
if you want to catch them up the
question really
modulate yeah there you go ask that
question so the discovery of the sulfur
compounds that you guys have found and
now um I met with Ian and that group at
the ABS they were looking at the soal
gas factor and assigning gas Factor
based on the quantification of these
these volatile sulfides so yeah there
was just the question on uh because I
think Sam and other people are again um
uh discussing about different compounds
that modulate the effects of
cannabinoids is it known whether or not
Nick is Nick is the the co-p party who
sent me my
tping which are from who' you get them
from what's that who who said what I'm
sorry that's ni this is Nick um uh which
party did did you get him
from
uh the what's the name of the lab AB
bris
or I'm afraid I can't remember the name
of the lab that uh where
they yes that's correct
abstract gotcha no actually I have not
been working with on with them but I've
communicated with them on some of their
some of their research and some some
what they're doing I think some of their
claims are a little a little bit um
broad but uh it's a they're definitely
doing some good work a lot a lot of
people in the space are um whether it's
they was the only people I was able to
obtain the the pure th from and uh I I I
need to do the work but uh I'm having a
little bit of trouble getting pure THC
so until I get P TC I can't do the F
work where where are you
based Amsterdam
oh okay um let me see what I can do uh I
will I see if I can find you some some
fun stuff um and just youve got my email
on here so go ahead and shot me your
address all of the T all of the Turing
are legal here I mean the canono are
legal in Holland except for Delta 99 and
Delta 8 all the rest of them are and
maybe even delta8 might be legal I
forget but Delta 9 is not legal so uh
you
can't is
thatal that's exactly what I was going
to
say what is what
legal
thca no that's not legal because all you
have to do is heat it up and it turns
into THC so of course that's not
legal okay um in any case I'll still
I'll see if I can find something from
the medical space they might have some
so but when you speak speaking of
Standards I just wanted to mention too
when we were talking about standards and
Labs before that one of the big problems
when we first started because we started
our lab more than two decades ago uh was
the problem that uh when you would order
analytical standards from segma or from
the United Nations drug uh people but
when we would test them on our hlc we
would find they weren't as stated so if
you calibrate your machines according to
what they say they are without doing
checking yourself then what you find out
is that uh all of your results
ex yes and so what's one of the things
that we found as well is that a lot of
these sorry guys a lot of cross
here sorry I'm in the Delta Lounge uh
the a lot of the um standards are
actually especially for th and diates
because they're they're kind of tricky
to to to analyze um we found that you
needing a a sulfur chal medicines
detector array is is really one of the
things that drives drives up your your
accuracy um and then the other issue is
that there hasn't been a tremendous
amount of research done into them and so
the the bands are not as narrow um for
for what they're saying so they they're
clustering a lot of things together and
so you actually see like um
for MMP um is listed as you know being
this one one very important th thile in
in aromatics and in reality the standard
we use is actually uh covering several
isomers as well as some other compounds
that are right next to it and so in
terms of Purity that's the indicator TH
or that's the indicator that they use
the THS and thids that are in that
region uh but it's not necessarily
specific to that one uh that one file um
alternatively there's the other issue is
that it's hard to disassociate them
together from from each other um without
some extremely high performance
chromatography systems and we were still
working on that before I left
Yak getting the accuracy down was
challenging it best honest it was that
way with the canono when we started in
the 90s when we built our first
lab you there was no way to separate
really without really really
specializing columns which were rare and
expensive CB uh C and CBD so everybody
was coting all of those together and
Reporting them as one Peak instead of in
fact they were two
peaks exactly um and then the other
tricky aspect is especially if you're
using gcms um The sulfur compounds like
most of the detectors don't like them so
you need to have a SE detector for them
um and even then it's it's really just a
method development that has to continue
because there aren't a lot of
established methods agant has been
working with us and improving improving
public access to to those method so it's
a it's a good thing um but it's we're
still a couple years out getting it
really really nailed down that's the
reason why we never looked at files
because we had no way to determine the
trial percentages or anything else in
our lab we wished we could but there was
no way so we didn't
try that and not only that that the the
best detectors are actually really
they're good at detecting and good at
isolating but they're not very good at
quantitation so it's it's a challenge
all the way around um David you said
something earlier about um you know
what's what's known about the the sort
of the co co effects and and the impact
whether or not they they sort of
potentiate or or they interfere with and
really that research hasn't yet been
done I was just speaking to Ethan Russo
last week about this um he's very
interested in it as well so I'm gonna
try to see if they can set some sort of
studies up with everybody um but what to
me from Evol from an evolutionary
evolutionary evolutionary perspective
Jesus had trou talking morning sorry um
is it makes sense that there would be
some sort of uh neurological impact
because they're so important in human
evolution and Mamon evolution in general
um looking at um the way that they
predict ripening and they predict
fermentation and they also predict
putrescence um those are three very
important survival tools for uh for
mammals um and one things that's really
interesting I found is that if you you
know what durian is it's a it's a very
of sest fruit in the world they call it
um it's extremely high in 3mh and form
MP as well as some other thid and
pentane thids um that are kind of more
the gassy garlic deily nastiness um in
very very high quantities when high high
proportions um the Tigers who are
obligate carnivores will make their way
to a durian tree and defend it because
they like the durian so much it's just
it's got a lot of protein it's got a lot
of fat in it as well um but the fact
that they're able to detect those those
STS and it use and they use it as a
source of of um food for an Oba
carnivore is pretty pretty impressive
well I'm very curious I also used to be
curious in flavonoids because I know
that they can modulate and potentiate
things but orally they can but if you
smoke them it deactivates them so the
flavonoids are not responsible for the
smok different effects in cannabis for
Orly that could be a completely
different
story
100%
I there's an awful lot of Turpin that
really have no effects I mean they don't
get too high excuse I'm not talking
medical here I'm talking
recreational and the same same thing
with the uh canbids most of the canids
do not get too
high yeah they but they do they do have
an impact on the sort of CB1 CB2 as well
as the other receptors and they have an
impact on modulating say for example
your well they some of them certainly
some of them certainly do prime example
is the way CBD will delay the
onset uh reduce the peak experience and
make the whole thing last longer for
p uh and well as an example so not just
not just CBD but like looking at say
pierine and better care filing is the
the impact that that has uh you know
there's the old adage like you know if
you're if somebody's having a bad trip
or or having adverse reaction to THC and
kind having an anxiety issue uh you know
give them a give them a teaspoon or
tablespoon of black pepper to munch on
and it pretty much Nerfs it very very
quickly um and the mechanism is not
understood but it seems to be uh the
case of anecdotal experiences driving U
research and it's really exciting to see
that sort of stuff start to happen well
I for years I've been trying to get too
high on THC products but so far I've
been pretty
unsuccessful you know and just for
conversation I would love to bring in
there's a lot of people out there who
the more that the plant is concentrated
the less high that they
get so so I've talked with Ethan Russo
at length about this and at first it was
like no that's not possible but but yes
it is there's a lot of people who don't
get high off of a dab at all and maybe a
little bit of hash they will they really
don't feel the effects so the more
natural that it is or the more flower or
joint or maybe out of a bong that it is
they would be you know getting a higher
effect and what was brought up
conversation after you know a couple of
years at
length brings the Entourage effect back
into the
conversation without having to elude it
so the amuno acids are destroyed dur
during during vaporization or smoking
so uh like in terms of of Edibles you
can certainly get some of those but but
in general they're they are destroyed by
by smoke yeah like the
flavonoids yep and the
polyphenols well there seems to be
something that's happening when you know
the more raw that people whether it's
even combusting whether it's an edible
you know people that are getting more
effects off of an edible even if it is
in butter and I hear and
understand that the amino acids are
alive there but there's something that's
happening for a lot of people that need
the more raw compounds even if it's
decarbox even if it's heated up so
that's a that's a conversation could it
that we don't understand yet and I'd
love to hear what you all think about
could it be as simple as the when you
take canono THC especially
orally then uh you don't get high on the
THC you get high on the 11 hydroxy after
it goes through the the liver and uh so
what reaches the brain and the blood is
not THC it's primarily Leon hydroxy
which is a bit stronger in effects in
THC and a bit different so uh it could
be would that be the same with
decarbox or you know heating up at
any the liver actually the liver
actually converts the the Delta 9 into
into 11 hydroxy um and the with like
sort of going into that that's that's
sort of an interesting things so
anecdotally um I some people don't have
the enzymes uh the liver enzymes
functionality to process some of the THD
into the bioactive form from oral
consumtion and it depends on the form
that it comes in as an example I've
consumed upwards of 300 Mig of Delta 8
or
and had Zero Effect um whereas you know
a vape instantly affects me it is very
very much lighter than Delta 9 um but
orally I just for some reason my body
doesn't doesn't process the the material
um my cousin um he has the same thing
with Delta 9 he can consume just insane
quantities of Delta 9 Edibles and he
gets no effect uh from at all uh and you
know this needs to be studied more but I
I suspect that there's probably some um
Gene deletes or some enzyme uh deletes
in different people to explain that um
the but when you're talking about the
overall is that way for alcohol American
Indians don't have the
yep Trace migration um by that um
there's a really interesting uh but the
point you're bringing about the whole
sort of full spectrum material is I
think Salient um I think that
the total quantity of all the material
in working together will give you a
different effect um and so as an example
I'll go back the pure pure THC um like
pure THC beverages do almost nothing to
me um they do get me like sort of
instant like instantly um intoxicated
and then it's it's a very thin very
narrow experience it's I don't get the I
don't get some of the relaxation I don't
get the enjoyment of it as much and it's
not just from from the aroma and flavor
of it um but it's the combination of
everything so I 100% agree that the full
spect
material is a quantitatively is a
quantifiably different experience and
it's certainly a qualitatively different
experience than isolates um and that's
similar for anything a good cup of
coffee is is significantly more
enjoyable and it's going to give you a
different impact whether it be
psychosocial or not uh sorry
psychological or not um than just you
know a fingertip of caffeine um it it's
so it is different I think that the the
the complexity of those interactions are
very very difficult to disentangle and
study and the typical approach of doing
you know one compound plus one
modulator is where we need to start
doing this research but we really need
to start looking at significantly more
complicated um
and you know probably significant more
complicated Arrangements of all of these
compounds and instead of doing um sort
of additions doing delet from a from a
sort of full spectrum mix so you say
okay we've got a full spectrum that's
completely Quantified we know what's
with everything that's in it now let's
remove one of those fractions at a time
and see what the result is it's going to
be it's going to take you know probably
decades to complete that research
because of all the possible combinations
and some would say rightly that it's
probably not worth doing
because worth doing Nick we got to do it
we gotta find out because
it's it's it's maybe a million different
combinations talking about true I would
say trillions yeah every person is
different you're a and every person is
different yeah AI help let's go
subjective so Nick and Sam still getting
to that question do you think I I would
just love maybe even to marinate on it
and and get back to me or what you all
think but just that idea that people who
can feel effect off of say a joint or
you know any any other raw form but as
soon as it's concentrated or the more
that it's concentrated even whether it's
rosin even whether it's from a full
spectrum plant it's just the actual idea
of
concentrating those cannabinoids what's
being left out that the person no longer
has effects and so I think that's the
key point it's not about the level of
concentration it's about the exclusion
of other components and I think that's I
think that's a very very important
distinction to make is that it's not
necessarily that conservation is the
problem it's that the elimination of any
of the compounds will provide an
attended experience um is is what's
going to be driving that
and go ahead excuse me Nick I didn't
mean to
interrupt no go ahead oh what I was
going to say was that uh what we found
was that
the other materials in the plant did not
contribute to you getting higher but the
resin heads they did so if you just
cleaned up the resin heads and made them
so that they were like
99% uh resin heads with nothing else uh
I found that got me higher than anything
else
absolutely and and again tolerance is an
issue here and it's subjective but I
think that in general from from all all
the research that I've done and all the
work that I've been doing and and
obviously the work Mark has been doing
with hash and bubble hash and cleaning
those up we see that the vast majority
of effects do come from those residents
um that's not to say that there isn't
other that there aren't other compounds
in the other material that won't uh
change that experience but that the vast
majority of the um uh sort of
recreational interest um is concentrated
and and is concentrated in in the resin
heads except when it comes to things
like you mentioned the amino acids and
the proteins as well as the um the
polyphenol groups and the flavonoids
which are which are a huge group and and
they're starting to be studied um but
it's complex to to study them those will
you're only going to get an effect from
in edible form through oil consumption
just because nature flavonoids are very
important for a lot of people uh but uh
I was really really focused on just the
recreational focus and uh once I found
out that uh when you smoke flavonoids it
deactivated them then uh I I I did not
focus on them
anymore that
was thermally they thermally degrade
they ther degrade they they don't
volatilize and
that yeah that that's the problem with
um with the the spice canavs too the
synthetic can avonoids is that they they
don't cleanly vaporize
right they thermally degrade earlier
when you said the exclusion of
components is it always the exclusion of
components or are or are there different
genetic makeups that have blind spots in
some form or another where they can't
experience
these 100% so there there every so in
both the plant and and the person um so
there's there are like human beings have
have anosmia and there are certain
people that that simply like have a very
low um sort of uh Aroma sensitivity um
and so so it's interesting and that
actually they would be almost be a
perfect candidate for study of Effects
by because that would eliminate their
subjective enjoyment aspect of it does
that make sense um like by by by
choosing people that can't
detect like doing it both ways Nick
where you eliminate one thing at a time
and then eliminate two things at a time
and then three and yeah you you also do
it the way we did it which was we had 25
milligrams of THC and we spiked it with
a single turpine then another single
turpine then another single turpine and
smoked them on different days so that we
could uh evaluate what they did we were
primarily looking for ones that
potentiated and if they modulated want
to know
how exactly I mean I would love to talk
about more about this and there's some
groups that I'd like to possibly bring
into this conversation at some point
because it's a it's really I think it's
fascinating and I think the implications
are are huge for um the recreational
Market as well as for um you know
therapy as as as medicine and I think
that uh you know it's it's it's one of
those things where we need to move away
from the dogma of um single compound
single effect into you know
the compounding effects of
M finally well-managed ADHD and and
cannabis is certainly a part of that um
is that the combination of multiple
salts of salts is more effective than uh
the single primary component and this is
one of the big things that uh a lot of
uh sort of analytical chemistry and just
Western medicine and Science in general
has has struggled with is the the the
the focus on principal component
analysis which is that vitamin vitamin C
is the same way I mean vitamin C if you
make it synthetically it works or
natural pure vitamin C works but if you
take vitamin C and you extract it from
plant sources
and you're getting the other Associated
uh compounds with it it's more
effective and and and I think that the
the the the focus on uh honestly this is
for ease of analysis on just looking at
what makes up 90 or 95% of of the
compound is like that gets you into the
not even the ballpark but in Into the
City of where the ballpark is located
for for what's really driving all these
all these effects and it's it is a very
important shortcut to take but it also
once you've identified those you know
like what are the most the key
components that that drive the most most
of the the effects you need to start
branching out and looking at that all of
the attendant components that that come
with it and why whole Spectrum full
spectrum um extracts or or or or plants
are more effective than single like sort
of sing Single compound dos and it's not
true for everything and that's important
to realize but I think that in this case
there is enough evidence that we should
really start looking into this in great
detail
other research that I've always found
really interesting is why are some
varieties of cannabis seiling lless by
that I mean no matter how much you smoke
you always get higher when you smoke
another joint or another pipe or another
dab of that material where some
materials you smoke you smoke you smoke
and then you get to the point where
it'll kind of make you more Stone but it
won't make you more high and uh I don't
know everybody else but I want to get
higher and this this is something that U
you know coming from from my my
background um I love the the community
around it but gets me a little bit wonky
sometimes is is the use of terms like
High versus Stone versus heady versus
you know like body Buzz all those things
like like trying to Define and this is
also because of I'm very particular
about terms um but trying to define
those in a way that gives us a a sort of
a shared understanding that is that is
uh quantifiable that we we can track it
and we can trace it and analyze it
across different users and different
strains is really important um but again
this may me being just a little bit more
picky um and what you said earlier about
certain strains and that's that's that
was the other side of you know gentics
of people that are sort of anosmia but
there are also strains that um simply
don't like there are choar let's focus
on the on the the proper term they're
choar um that don't express the same um
canono and they don't express the same
same aromatic bance why we're interested
in in all of these different uh sort of
the different strains and these
different cultivars um and you know
using those to as as as using that
variability as as a feature rather than
a bug is is what I like to do is like
let celebrate the variation in between
uh people and plants because we can then
you know create blends of these things
that do you know everything we want and
you could tune them which is which I'm
really excited by is is you know you
know uh you know taking the components
that we want and then from from
different strains and combining them to
create uh something that is not not sort
of expressed in the in the natural
genetics as a plant breeder I'm very
interested in knowing what it is that
people prefer and why so that I can
breed a plant that's tailored for that
exactly what's interesting is um we've
been doing a lot of accessions uh or
studies of of different chemo bars and
uh working with Jeremy Plum I wish he
was on this call because he he'd start
laughing right now um is the uh the
terpinolene dominance that we're seeing
in the US market recreational and hemp
is massive and uh the point where like
we're seeing a a loss a potential loss
of genetic diversity because people are
selecting so heavily for that
terpinolene dominance because it appes
sort of it it act or not actually it it
lifts up the Citrus it lifts up the
tropical and it lifts up the diesel and
gasy character so well that and piny as
well that it seems like we might be sort
of selecting ourselves into a corner
with with breeding stock and so I think
it's really important to not just go for
what people currently want but to also
look at what uh what we see there sort
of attend with those or not attend that
follow those clear uh customer
preferences and so we know that TR is
very very exciting for a lot of people
and that's people judge their but oh
that's that sounds smells amazingly
gassy and citrusy great but you know
maybe they like something that has a lot
more um tropical character and a lot
more of the burnt rubber and uh guava
character that comes from the th uh just
to bring It full circle here and making
sure that uh we can uh you know protect
those genetics so that breeders like
yourself can combine them and produce
something that has
both people have often ask me what is
the best and I say what do you mean by
best do you mean the strongest the best
tasting the best what do you mean by the
best because without understanding what
they mean by the best there is no single
best cannabis for everybody it just
isn't that way or for every situation
there also needs to be a germ plasm
Institute to protect all the genetics so
that there can be biodiversity of what
Nick is talking about yet protecting and
breeding the other you know
characteristics that are still there
that people have come to know and love
and the problem is those don't exist
domestically and they don't exist in
Canada at this time so we need to start
thinking about something like that so we
can protect it because I mean I this
genetic tattooed on my arm has gone well
over a decade and it was one that helped
many patients that I wish had been saved
but it's gone from the face of the Earth
so I think Nick bring up a very real
point that we have to be protecting the
genetics that we have but also the
biodivers that exists so that in future
Generations can understand much less
appreciate
yeah it's kind of hard to CH because to
maintain a germ plasm for example let's
say you have just one land
race you every time you reproduce that
land race to not lose genes from that
gene pool you've got to have a minimum
of 1,000 males and 1,000 females every
reproduction and those 1,000 males they
can't be clones all the same nail
they've got to be from seed 1,000 males
1 then you you you you limit your loss
to really really a small percentage but
uh yeah the the only place that's really
done is in third world countries people
aren't growing thousands and thousands
of plants from
seeds in in the commercial cannabis
world it's just it's very seldom done it
can be done but it's not you hear that
hash churches youve got work to do get
on it we've got a lot of work yeah and I
think you know it's what Sam is saying
is like I think it's important for
people to to keep running genetics and
continue those lines and not move on so
fast and try to to keep those lines in
existence um you know in seed form and
and that's one thing I think that at
least commercially in terms of seeds I
don't see at all you know I used to
really respect you know the individuals
that had 10 you know 10 lines that was
it and that's that every every year that
was it and they they maybe introduce one
or two new lines you know but not whole
revisions and you know whole new drops
of just completely different things from
clone you most companies in the world
can't even maintain clones for 20 30
years for seed production so you can't
lose clones how you going to save
varieties so Sam back in the in like the
90s when like Ben donker like you were
SM you were you created the the you were
there right so at what time did the did
those mother plants start to be really
difficult to obtain was it like the late
late late 80s late 90s like what was it
difficult the whole time obtain them
from who from where I don't understand
how how long did you basically when did
people like Sensei start losing their
mother plants to you know probably from
day probably from day
one uh yeah I mean if you keep a plant
uh as a clone and you keep it virus free
so keep the pests away yeah and it
doesn't pick up more viruses which will
cause it to be uh lose beer and uh
vitality and
uh it
I didn't see any difference between
clones 30 years later if if you kept
them clean safe and secure and that's
actually something that's that's a very
that's becoming a very large challenge
right now because of the amount of um
unregulated growth that's going around
and people are sharing you know the cuts
and all that stuff um the the one of the
ways to do that is actually through
tissue culture because you can actually
you know preserve certain cells that
don't have the virus yet and you can
grow it from companies like say
and power plant are doing this for the
community
yeah hop
viroids oh oh yeah and this for my for
my experience in the hop in the Hop
industry that's a it's a big problem um
and we I mean like it's not a problem
for hops as as much but for for if
you're growing cannabis near them or if
you're processing the same facility
there needs to be very very good
phytosanitary pH phytosanitary controls
um one of the things that um like going
back to the sort of the Pres
preservation of genetics one of the
things that I've done in my own
uh breeding and curation is to try to
always uh speed out genetics that I like
for some for for whatever particular
reason and I always keep the seeds of
you know the the sort of the crosses
that that I I'm not too happy about
because there might be something that
pops up in them um and the like I've got
some from some gentics that have
abhorent agronomic characteristics so
just there're terrible they're spindly
uh they're they're incredibly might
sensitive they the one of the things I
do I really do breed for is uh powder
milder resistance uh and and Bounty
milder resistance I just don't like
fungal infections in my bud um but uh uh
I actually do run sort of M stress tests
on mine so if you ever go into whenever
when I'm in a breeding session you go
into towards the end of it everything's
covered in mes and I'm just trying to
see which ones survive best um but
that's a risky category most people
don't want to do that I understand why
but it's it's it's a fun fun thing for
me that's come on tell the truth that
you say you did that the truth is you
just can't get rid of the little
boogers no no no no I introduced
them actually drove somewhere a spiderm
INF station in a hopfield took some and
put it into my into my my might tent
which is inside another tent which
is and have you found plants which were
might resistant and didn't get might yes
why do you think tury it's it it it's
it's very possible that it's it's I mean
it's I would say it's likely that it's
something to do in the aromatic profile
um but also that their immune response
is
probably I have grown millions of plants
in my life Nick and I've grown thousands
of different uh land races of cannabis I
have never seen a plant that could not
get mites okay so there there there's
not getting mites and then there's
resisting mites at the load that it's
currently affecting other plants and so
they're always together in the same tent
and so so the plant the mites might go
to other plants over this this
particular
cross myself I've seen it myself I've
seen it with the Congo seen lower level
in a room yeah exactly way lower levels
though like 90% were on the crop and
maybe like 10% or less were on this
other
planet and speaking of resistance and
susceptibility the those important Milo
papers came out which they found both
jeans for
susceptibility and genes for resistance
and they found out that it's more
important to not have the susceptibility
genes than it is to have the resistance
genes to avoid mildew in your plants hey
speaking in resistance Brian you're
you're working in a in a climate I think
that is more challenging than anyone
yeah here and You' been reading for
years you know like you know like I have
in you know on the East Coast we have a
tremendous amount of rain like today's a
great example you know we're we're in
the thick of a tropical event you know
that's uh that's just been broken
up yeah it's Challen Sunny up here today
it's sunny up here today but it's really
windy which isn't bad the land I have
here has opened up for good air drainage
air flow um but yeah this is interesting
I was going to bring it up or ask anyone
that if they've seen any resistance
which I've to betrus from the lemoning
group I've seen the lemon
oriented types and I can't break down
the science in terms of the breakdown
for the family of Tarpin of profile but
I've seen things in the lemon category
be very resistant into the later season
for Bettis and resistance and then I've
seen this year out of a whole list of
types I've actually seen only powdery
mil do pop up late season on the gas
mask feno number six backat cross one
and which is ironic because the mom
doesn't show that so it's something
reached out and is not resistant in it
but otherwise it's not bad it came in
late and everything else very very clean
and I've been breeding like five years
back here towards that so it shows with
with Milo being a challenge but I found
it to be a challenge uh cultivar
specific strain specific more and yeah
so kind of leaning off of of things that
might go that that way and I'm finding
definitely in Maine that more that the
fruit forward cookie back type still
kind of working with that complex of of
uh genetics with some other tie in i'
I've got a whole list of some
exploration this year which I can list
off some strains that I'm working with
since if that is interesting anyone I
yes please I was trying to bre science
happening here I was trying to breed
against P try to also I was trying to do
it in Skunk number one and uh I grew
several years and uh I it was so
difficult that I gave up but uh
definitely could be because if you think
about it you I never see but tritis in a
variety like original
hay
so you know
really I really wonder what comes down
because Brian I really want to hear your
uh your strain list and I just wanted to
add yeah there people that want to hear
it yeah and I we also created 40 new
varietals um and everything that we did
this year was off a seed and I think we
did about
1300 plants all from seed all our old
varietals and then mixing in some others
but I'm wondering to wanted to bring it
into the conversation that maybe mo more
than having to do with varietals because
we've been growing in this bare area for
so long we've been adding to our soil
for so long we've been getting it right
for so long we only do seed varietals
we'll keep our clone you know we'll keep
um a mother maybe only because we've
we've grown it out from that year or
something but normally we'll just
continue to grow seeds and I've just
realized that now it's not really
mattering what varietal that we are
working with if we've been working with
it for a long time because I think then
that involves the Endo fidic
relationship within the plant that then
goes into the seed because I think if
they building something that's super
resisting resistant you're building it
through biology as well which hasn't
necessarily been a part of this
conversation up till now yes I think
varials are part of it yes I think tpin
can maybe draw more interesting things
from the air higher lactic acid is drawn
to more you know you know lemoning
varietals I've noticed that also Brian
but the Endo fidic reaction so now it
really seems like anything new that we
bring on to our property is what's going
to get you know some kind of a reaction
have some type of a malady um in it and
then it takes us several years to then
work with it and then now we're getting
to the point where we are having hardly
any we live in an incredibly difficult
environment it's super cold up here
we're in an inland
rainforest and this year we didn't have
hardly any
buritis no and that and that's in stock
and Bud in early and late and it just
sort of goes on and on but the ones that
we did have the problems with were the
ones that were early and Brian I want to
roll right over to you because I'd love
to hear your
list oh well I we've had a great success
summer too for health actually and have
have really not seen much of any
Bettis um really into this later finish
which where kind of a better cold main
sunny and Breezy finish this year so
that helps but the health is really up
and I would show one strain I saw that
was interesting is from Dominion seedco
from duke Diamond that's a local skunk I
don't know how much skunk guet has in
there but I was going to let Sam know
that that one was actually a resistant
and reparative strain where I say it
cracked down the middle even with some
support and did a little quick bind job
and this it came back late season where
it looked like it was about to die off
and it had great resistance repair uh
which I've seen with hemp but not as
much with cannabis and then it's got no
mold there's no mold no Bettis no
septoria that's an old scratch pile
compost that had actually a sour best
[__] ever with a rulin called candy
coated that took some septoria pretty
hard like almost the hardest in the yard
picked clean Leaf know killed the Spore
Colony or tried do and it came back on
it right away and then on the backside a
black dominis super skunk seems to be
throwing lay but catching betrus really
kind of quickly otherwise looking
healthy in this little three plant set
of just experimental run but the the
dominions work there the local skunk
this one feno just really awesome gassy
kind of skunky gas skunk or sweet gas
skunk more than just Rony skunk I would
say so yeah anyway um I have the strain
list though so I'll read it off this
year what we're working with we've got
some cherry chem I've got a Tropicana
kosher Tangi on my gas mask called
masquerade I've got a strawberry lime
feno of my holy Road I've got some 91
Royale and uh grapefruit skunk sided
holy Road I've got a gas mask backat
cross one some black Wilson Reserve uh
cough
bx1 the candy coated ROM
sbse we've got that local skunk guava
mask is doing amazingly well just really
kind of running the the number of fenos
not a whole ton but enough of them to
get a good look on it and had great
results there so the Cherry mask is
doing really well also and I would share
back that the Cherry cam was from self
Fork seeds I got given to me at an
emerald Cup right before I came back
here like six to seven years ago and
usually see the indicia sided stuff in
Maine kind of go like you might have
mentioned with newer indicia types
introduced to the land even though we
like some of them I've had to breed with
like a blackberry pie local cut to get
the resistance out a year or two later
from
it and I'm seeing it even a year later
but you you know going back to it I've
saw Cherry Kem this year from a seed
feno that really showed such good good
health that it did hit a septor little
bit of challenge which you know to bring
it up septor is like crushing trees that
are 20 30 feet tall now in Maine over
the last two years and the locals are
talking about I walk the woods and see
it and it seems like a climate change
but a different conversation type of
thing and I'd get you know information
from the people on that one actually
seems to be where out with it but uh bre
fusium and fusarium too in the in in
your areas and just just this area in
New England and it's been what I've
heard it's new for me in the last few
years but um yeah New York New York you
never had these types of things um so
it's um yeah I don't know
it's yeah we're having to treat you know
even reverse mosis water has to be
treated you know even
with you know going through systems so
it's it's really challenging I don't
know you know what you're doing to yeah
we're seeing we're seeing these
different blights pop up Colin like that
like this you know septoria ferum I've
seen more septoria but it's added a
whole new level of of not negative but
actually positive movement for plant
adaptation in the breeding that we're
doing with the I'm doing all that yes
nice I'm I'm finding I'm breeding more
for septoria since now that any of the
Bettis or PMS like old news Bettis is
hard in main but the septor is such a
kicker with even Big Trees other I can
see it in nature Tak certain types not
others right so I'm seeing it back to
the plants with cannabis it's not it's
not strain specific it's phenos specific
I've seen sisters touching each other
like like Grava Kush and I documented it
this year where it's literally knocked
off the flow is healthy but the seor hit
everything even with a clean out twice
and we just took it down early and it
was finished it was on the IND side
thing too but the more sativa expressing
sister right next door touching it a
foot and a half away not one touch of
septoria on it so I'm kind of like
having to breed more through that these
days than anything else but seeing
things that are resistant you know on
one thing and not another the the light
hit of sepor at the end on Cherry cam
but otherwise it like moved on from no
Milo no betri even in the second stage
cut off the the tops you know right now
checking it every day and I would share
back to that is the lemoning family and
then now into the whatever Cherry you
guys would know more makes up into the
Cherry Pie on chmd like I think was back
cross three or four on the chamd and
it's all cherry pie sided too it's just
got a little GL you know gasl and it
doesn't wash although you might be able
to pull something it doesn't wash for us
you know but it's a it's a flower
strain I'll come up yeah
yeah I was gonna say I got a few goodies
that I can't wait to like throw your
away to see if you pull something off
them like the grapefruit skunk hly Road
you know it goes back to that Calo skunk
one cut from Humble clone that's not
like their typical Tangi and I One my
alltime favorites yeah yeah and it goes
grapefruit skunk you know what I'm
talking about it's really grapefruit ha
grapefruit skunking and know so I can't
what's that I I hate to interrupt I need
to my flight's boarding like seven
minutes so I need to just say say say
goodbye but also in Rel relation to this
specific thing um if you look at um the
obviously the lemine and lenol dominant
so for citrus um there typically is also
a lot of Alpha and beta pining and
cedine and uh those combinations are
what make up pinol and a lot of the um
sort of or coniferous oils that are used
as anti fungal um and I suspect that
those will probably have a lot OFA on
that and they taste great so you know as
a Target like if you can find any Piney
varieties cross them with lemine
varieties you're probably going to get a
decent uh a decent little uh uh sort of
antifungal cocktail there um I really
wish I could stay on but I need to
finish this and I would love to talk to
you guys more um you have my email and
likewise I'm gonna see if I can reach
out because uh this is a this is
fascinating I love it thanks for sharing
Nick always a pleasure all right peace
out
everybody peace
out wow that was a good solid three
hours I want I wanted to hear a little
bit more from Wade because we haven't
heard enough from Wade how how is
everything going in Wade's world right
now um things are going pretty good in
Wade's World um I've been loving this
conversation and seeing some of the
faces and um
uh enjoying my uh dab rig here
um I uh it occurred to me to try and do
a memory test and and review what I've
heard today um I know early on in the
conversation uh Kelly and Josh were
talking about getting a letter from the
EPA about their products and um and it
occurs to me to say that I that's a sign
of respect they recognize that you're
actually doing something in the market
and to some extent you're a threat to an
existing business model um and uh one of
the thoughts I had as that conversation
progressed was I live in California
where we have an abundance of rules and
regulations for
everything and especially cannabis and
to be quite honest in my opinion
especially as a patient myself uh at a
whole new serious level now and My Life
um we've made a hot mess of legalization
it's not really legalization it's
commercialization um but that wanders
off to a different topic and I wanted to
try again like a memory thing um after
after that we got into this thing about
science and nature and I think of
science myself as um and I'm not a paid
scientist Mark but I understand your
point well said um
to me science is really a method of
trying to understand nature in all its
various aspects everything from the
stars and the universe that we live in
to um how our bodies work and we
wouldn't know so much about how cannabis
has the effects it does in the body in
addition to psychoactivity
Heist um if it weren't for science I
mean science wanted to learn about
cannabis uh and did and has and has
revealed an incredible amount and and
Mark uh scalone Dr Mark scalone pointed
to a paper I think he met referenced
cbda um and some of the effects that
it's had and yeah I I'm a big fan as you
can imagine
um um let's see after that it went
towards oh yeah we got into thols and uh
and their the the effects and their
presence and Sam was talking about doing
the 25 milligrams THC and uh and then
adding a tpine one at a time one day at
a time I love that kind of methodical
approach because that's science actually
that's especially if you keep track of
what you're doing records I'm sure Sam
does uh breeding into scale you know I'm
just stunned at the breadth of knowledge
in this group of people that you invite
Marcus and
um in a certain way I feel very humbled
to sit here with you all
today um but I also feel inspired you
know um my life has changed pretty
dramatically in the last
year uh but in a good way because um
there were some health challenges
happening in my life four or five years
ago that didn't make sense to me it
wasn't the person that I always thought
lived in this body you know the body was
going through some changes I think it's
part of getting old but for me it was
specifically a form of cancer that has
manifested in my bones and
um and
so um on that conversation about science
and
nature I love nature very much I've
spent a good portion of my life trying
to understand
how how a garden works and what the
diversity of nature can
do for a plant that I love very much and
now um what I found as a patient
myself um is that uh in the regulated
market in California even in Nevada
County which is where I live I live
between Nevada City and Grass Valley uh
in the Sierra
Foothills um even here where our local
cannabis Alliance has created a program
through a whole supply chain where any
patient who has a medical recommendation
from their physician can get free
product that's been donated by the the
supply chain all of the license holders
in our area uh contribute not all of
them a good portion of them um and I've
taken advantage I I helped set that
up and over the last year I have
actually taken advantage of that program
quite a bit but even
me with all of the people I know it's
it's kind of hard to find versions of
the canvas plant chemistry in products
where I can get the couple of hundred
milligrams that I want couple times a
day I'm not really much trying to
control my cancer because the um back to
science for a second and if this is too
much interation anybody interrupt but uh
back to science um I ended up in a
series of hospitals uh in December of
last year um about coming on 10 months
ago now um and at one of them down in
Stanford I got a course of radiation in
one day one dose it worked wonders at
least my experience other than a sunburn
around my mouth but um uh my appetite
improved I slept better I was less pain
um and meantime yeah I was on a pretty
aggressive CAS course of
chemo um and I think it kept me
alive I'm really
grateful I
have a really renewed and profound sense
of how life really is a
gift your chance
to be involved with family to be
involved in a community back to the the
theme of this morning's
Church uh the idea that we are in fact a
community and
as
as as Wade sitting here on his little
patio looking at my pond and these big
beautiful
trees in my situation I feel really
grateful actually I don't know many
people who
are better
situated in their life to be doing what
I'm doing right now I uh multiple Myoma
is the kind of cancer that I have it's a
spefic specific bone marrow cell called
a plasmid kind of goes crazy uh not only
doesn't die off uh makes insane numbers
of clones of itself and crowds out all
the other types of bone marrow cells and
meantime bursts the Bones from the
inside sorry to be specific and gruesome
but there it is so pain is a bit of an
issue um
and I think that in my case at least
because every person's different our
metabolism our body's needs our body's
ability to respond to something like a
cancer it's been a fascinating question
to me trying to understand because this
is a cancer of cells of the immune
system the effects
of high dosage cannabis use and
specifically in my case of course I'm
mixing CBD and THC in various versions
ingesting as well as dabbing on my uh uh
the Min n thing uh uh and
um
yeah the combination of uh having done
some time trying to understand how my
mind works um through a form of Buddhism
if you will that I did for a number of
years uh through um a really lifelong
interest in how things grow how do
things work and specifically how do
plants work how does that happen how do
you put a seed in the ground and the
combination of moisture and soil and sun
produce this plant that feeds us so
provides these beautiful flowers these
incredible
aromatic plants that uh can have such
profound effects on our experience and
um and meantime here I am you know um
what's true is my cancer seems to have
responded really well to treatment at
this point I'm on a fairly low dose of
uh a chemotherapy drug which so far my
oncologist to say no you don't want to
stop it Wade look at the good results
you having and it's true all my blood
Works going in the right directions I've
known enough cancer patients I don't
remember who it was that referenced that
a patient is not really a great term for
who we are because yeah I've been I've
been a patient under California law for
glaucoma
well before there was such a thing um I
was diagnosed back in
9495 and um anyway cannabis I I love
this plant one of the other points that
I came to mind to say is we've already
looked at or can see in medicine they
have a high THC Marinol is one of the
names of it uh that you can get
prescribed to by a doctor and get it in
a hospital here in the United States
approved by Food and Drug Administration
same is true with epid dialects you can
get it uh delivered to your home um one
of the reasons I am celebrating today
despite all of the other I've been cying
a lot but I really am these are tires of
attitude um because yeah that made me
epids made me think of h a couple of the
families that I know who have family
members who are dealing with severe
epilepsy
one of them's been on our show a couple
of times here your show Marcus thank you
uh our show Forest herd speak of
community uh he's he and his son Silas
have had a huge effect on the
conversation about cannabis in Nevada
County
um uh we're propos anyway back to Silas
he is uh
uh this is a boy if you don't know the
story I'll tell anybody that wants to
hear it for a second um when I met
forest and silus uh
Forest um yeah Silas was seven years old
and Forest was at a public meeting where
he was showing pictures of his son in
the hospital uh because he had just been
told that his son likely wouldn't make
it the age of 10 due to uh what was
eventually diagnosed as Linux G syndrome
which is you got to have like 10
different kinds of seizures and this kid
was seizured 100 times a day or more
well today or no let's see September
11th of this past month uh is one year
since Silas had a
seizure he's still doing several hundred
milligrams of CBD and THC there's a
specific uh cultivar we found back in
2014 or 2015 called medy haes the
results of it were published in
oanes uh in that issue uh that year uh
called medihaze and yeah that specific
version of medihaze the seeds came from
Europe um gave Silas really profound and
immediate relief from his seizures and
we still have a couple of I think we
still have like aund and some grams of a
high potency extraction of that oil that
seems to work pretty well but that
original cut the Clone has gone for a
variety of reasons
um um and Forest did at one point time
and try try and titrate silus off of the
dose of the the mes that he was mixing
into to the other plant oils he had
access to uh and he started showing
signs of uh a seizure might be coming on
and so he went right back to using the
medi haes so you know there's a lot of
good news there Silas is now in high
school he's uh actually coming out of
his shell enough that um he's doing
dance
class as a sophomore in high school so
this is a huge change and Improvement in
his well-being and meantime uh the other
story I just wanted to say the one of
the other reasons I'm feeling deep
gratitude um I met a family when um I
don't know if that Jan's still on the on
the call but uh uh back when Steep Hill
moved from Oakland to
Berkeley um they did one of their first
public facing events uh invited a whole
bunch of their clients to come see their
new place and I went down there thinking
I would meet a bunch of farmers
silly me uh the place was full of uh
people in shiny you know big watches and
shiny shoes and suits and I was dressed
like a farmer kind of like I am today
and uh I was one of like two or three
people in a crowd of 100 or 200 that
were there but I visited with uh the
Reverend Dr kimon and my f friend Fred
Gardner and uh we shared nice food in
the conversation for a while and and Kon
was pretty excited about it but I
understand that's kind of closed down
now
uh I met a family there that night one
of the other one of the few folks that
weren't in Chinese shoes and suits and
whatnot was his family who had a young
man in a wheelchair and he was covered
in a blanket and he had a mask on and he
was in a catatonic State Rus I think
it's called Uh that might be the wrong
term but his hands were CL wrenched and
his legs were locked up and he was in a
fetal position in this
wheelchair and so I walked up to him and
I asked him what what are y'all doing
here and
uh they were looking for somebody who uh
could grow some ACDC or might have some
for their
son who was uh 21 when I met this family
and I won't name anybody uh because they
where they live is actually still a
threat to their home if their Community
knows that they use
cannabis in
California homeowner associations
anyway uh that family they were there I
I had some ACDC in my garden that year
and I had already figured out it did its
genetics did not do well in the hot dry
Summers of Nevada County it was
discovered if you will identified as a
plant of Interest over on the medino
coast I guess is my understanding of the
story there where you know there's a lot
of moisture in the air and the peak heat
in the Summers might get into the 80s
well here we you know we just flirted
with a 100 here and single digit
humidity levels this past summer for at
least a few weeks and uh anyway ACDC was
not doing well in my garden but uh I
said you well if you're looking for CBD
I have some because I was already
starting to I I was creating a product
we called Wonder drops uh it was a 25
to1 and had I was so proud of it man it
had a label had all the milligrams in it
it was tested we had uh 350 milligrams
of CBD 14 milligrams of THC and every
one of those milligrams came from my
garden and meantime we had hundreds and
hundreds of these bottles going out to
the uh bunch of dispensaries up and down
California at one point anyway I handed
it to Mom you know because she she was
the one who was uh really engaged on the
Cannabis thing and she said yeah this is
exactly what we what he needs but he
would need two of these a
day I went wow okay
um one of the daughters of the family
has um engaged with
a an indor operation that allows them to
preserve some of the genetics we found a
specific uh High CBD low THC version
that did well in our neighborhood called
remedy and uh another version of similar
genetics called therapy that passed
through here both of those did quite
well uh for that young man who is now
just turned 30 like I said his family is
now providing his oils for him but uh
the mother and one of the other a son of
that family came to visit to tell me how
well they were doing um and uh to give
thanks I think it's why we do this work
when you um I mean I love the cannabis
plant personally for the psychoactive
effects that Sam is such a devotee of
and most of us
are but I also love her
for some of the other effects that I
have
seen in uh
and just to loop back into the
conversation that we've been having here
and to stop taking up so much
time um science helps me and US
understand the magic if you will that is
nature there's a deep wisdom in nature
if we take the time to
look um the fell who's doing that series
of books teaming with microbes teaming
with fungi teaming with
bacteria um L FR I think is his name saw
him speak a couple times and yeah he's
pointing in a really great Direction the
woman who's uh recognizing the
importance of mother trees and
regeneration of
forests um those of us Kelly and Josh
who are pointing to the importance of
living soil and regenerative practices
and I I went into regenerative practices
myself a long time ago
uh one because I didn't wanted to reduce
the impact of my indoor gardening in San
Francisco when I was doing that and then
when I came up here
because despite doing Wonder drops I was
still giving a lot of lot of my product
away uh because when somebody's sick how
can you tell them they have to pay
you for what you have it might save the
life of their child
anyway that's my testimony if you will
for today on hash church is uh my
gratitude for the the love that
is this plant and what she offers to us
I think of her as a manifest um can I go
can I go into God for a
second uh I think uh uh in in discussion
with my friend Swami chitan of Swami
select uh he he's a he's in a a full
Hindu holy guy you know I've known him
for a long time um he and I talk
spirituality sometimes and it's really
far out to dig into the viic traditions
of
spirituality and
uh we if you will argued if for a while
back and forth
about if there is God what is it
and it was what we arrived on that I
like
is God is the sum total of all
sentience not just in
humans but humans play a huge part at
least on this planet but the trees and
The Rocks Crystals the
fish literally the the fungi the
bacteria in the air that we breathe and
all of that all the way out to all the
stars and galaxies and everything that
we can conceive of where there is
sentience contributes to what we think
of as
God and you can find God within yourself
you can find it by looking at flowers
you can find it
by comeing
and do that to the best of your
ability and Marcus I want to really call
you out and appreciate you for pointing
to the importance of only smoking and
using the best that you can make or find
of whatever it is you're taking to help
your life feel the way you want it to
feel because it's
anyway that was a long stoned wrap and
um thank you for the uh platform the
opportunity the community because yeah
this is to me uh at heart really about
what cannabis was always about when we
were all hiding and were you know used
to be when you met with a group of
cannabis Act was it was the news was
about who'd gotten busted what was our
trial looking like what were the charges
blah blah blah blah uh and now you know
it's about taxes and what's the new vccc
regulations going to look like and how
is Appalachians of origin going to work
and y y y y but but but we've come so
far and we still got a long way to go we
still got a long way to go I
um uh I I want to call out a thing
that's happening next weekend I don't
know if we're going to do you're going
to do another church next weekend Marcus
but um a group of hash makers some of
the the beautiful rosins and whatnot
I've been hitting on here this morning
and our week uh have been some of them
come through me to me through the
donation program but some of them come
to me
through folks who uh aren't really
licensed or permitted to do so but are
if you will sharing their personal use
uh uh
beautiful
work I gotta say because I'm really
stoned and yeah I wanted to do that
memory test to see if I were how stoned
I am and I'll have to go back and listen
to this at some point but I I really do
feel deep gratitude I uh I am getting
stronger every day uh is how it feels to
me
um I will point to most of my cannabis
use at this point is focused on my
enjoyment of the day
particularly as how it relates to pain
management uh because I want to be able
to move around uh and I can do it for a
little while uh sitting this long has
been an interesting challenge uh I'm
doing great at the moment because I'm
really
stoned and it helps a lot with pain and
yes I also ingest quite a bit because I
find that especially for long-term
relief if I don't want to have my dabri
fired up and going all day long uh right
next to the bed or out in the out on the
patio like I am
today
um yeah I'm taking some uh what's
colloquially known as
RSO uh but yeah next Sunday next Sunday
a group of folks is going to gather here
at my farm and we're going to celebrate
hash in the same way that we are doing
here today and uh honestly I'm uh I'm
not even sure what time we're Gathering
next week but if we're doing hash church
I'll be
here the neurosurgery people still want
me to they have their hooks in me back
to science and nature I'm doing anything
I can to heal my bones because again
this kind of cancer kind of blows them
out but uh that was a very very very
very long- winded way of saying actually
I'm doing really good for anyone that
wants to know uh deep gratitude here
really I'm kind of
stunned uh and a big part of that is hey
I
survived what looked like might be uh a
not survival able moment and that's
pretty far out and thank you for working
with us and our veterans as well because
not only have you been sick you've been
working with us so thank you thatan I
really want to appreciate you for
calling me out on that I
um I have um
again uh in the same way that this has
been an incredible nourishment to me
today uh I don't usually say a lot in
the veterans Action Council meetings and
I certainly don't make them all uh
because yeah there's a lot of drama
going on here on the farm um but again
me personally I'm doing great
um yeah heroic effort you guys did last
what two weeks ago now
um 12 12 veterans and spouses of
veterans uh going to uh Washington DC
and putting in the time and the H the
footwork 12 miles you said over two days
on
concrete stone yes yeah yeah um and mean
time because you're veterans I'm a
veteran too that's why I'm sitting in on
it I uh uh again I feel humbled to be in
the company of the folks that are on the
veterans Action Council myself I was
this
um I joined the Navy to avoid being
drafted to go to Vietnam uh because I
was I was of the era where my draft
number uh we had a lottery in place at
that point and I was number
34 and meantime it didn't want to take
student loans College I went for a year
and a half it made no sense to me at all
what was going on and um and so I quit
that and uh and yeah I ended up joining
the Navy the on a Saturday and my notice
to report for induction would would have
meant you're in the Army now and going
to Vietnam hello boy uh uh arrived on
that following Monday but I had already
signed a contract to join the Navy and
meantime yeah the Navy and I didn't
belong great we'll just leave it at that
uh they kicked me out uh at my
request U another long story and at 10 I
will uh write my bio for the uh veterans
Action Council thing I know you've asked
me a couple times uh again I'm humbled i
i in the company of people like yourself
um uh or Al burn or Michael crowz or you
know I mean this Todd scattini I mean
you know you just go down the list it's
like Pearson Crosby I mean I just it's
just wow
so um thoughtful
impassioned people who are are really a
lot on the same page we are trying to
change the laws trying to educate the
people who actually can change loss and
I think to your point earlier at J um
local is where you can really B change
to bear and there it's at least
partially about making the story
personal uh when you can touch people's
hearts you can change their
minds and on that note I'm going to stop
that was yeah I I I would love to come
back if you're doing it again Marcus and
um and I actually do have a science
question for you Dr Mark can I send I
think I still have an email for you
Andor Sam um
about
um yeah yeah I don't know if I could
take we should take it offline or take
it go ahead fire away if you have it
probably other people are thinking the
same damn thing right well you reference
okay if you don't mind Marcus I
um uh I am kind of bound by an agreement
not to get too specific I'll start there
uh a a state health
department is in a certain state is
struggling with the fact that a limited
number this is in the United States a
limited number of their licensed
producers and for the sake of
conversation we'll say there's
10 uh four four or five of them in the
last few months have consistently
started popping up with analoges of
Delta 9 Delta 10 Delta 6 probably some
ohcc I think you
referenced in products that typic
shouldn't have it like in flour or in
other products at concentrations that
are completely inappropriate for
something that hasn't been treated in
some way
meantime the rest of the licensed uh
producers in this state uh are not
having
this the the department of Health's
response to this is to just have the
manufacturers who producing product that
has that have these analoges at a
sufficient concentration to put it on
their packaging and labeling as one of
the canono in the product and I
personally feel a strong objection to
that but I would love to hear your or
Sam's thoughts on that and and um and
obviously it's to me it's a public
health and safety issue because we don't
really know what these analoges do as
well as what else is along for the ride
when those analog are in I can pipe in
really short and
fast that we don't find T rate when
we're looking in our lab so something's
wrong what do you say Mark yeah so so
this is prohibition economics at work
and you know it costs a lot of money to
put THC into a product so the
cheapest the the the guy who can do that
for the cheapest makes the most money in
a free market economy and so if we're
just talking about canono in general
yeah so um again way we were talking
about this earlier this loophole that's
in the farm bill that legalized
Industrial Hemp which is CBD blessing
and a curse because U um I think I've
said it before on hash church as long as
there's there's there's prohibition any
where there'll be a black market
everywhere and and what that means is
that legal licensed
producers have to somehow economically
keep up to have a competitive product in
the marketplace and if the only knob
they have to turn is the cost of their
ingredients you know you could basically
make THC cheaper
from readily abundantly available SE BD
isolate and a chemical
conversion put that into your products
cheaper than you know higher a team the
greenhouse grow cannabis extract
cannabis make cannabis oil put it in the
gummies it's cheaper just to buy the
commodity mix it into the gummy and
you're there quicker cheaper better
quicker and and so so I I think it's
interesting because different states are
taking different approaches to this and
they realize that I think again this can
only happen because of prois of Delta 9
right so if Delta 9 was available and
everybody was making Delta 9 across the
board in in the entire country and even
in the entire world right we wouldn't
there wouldn't be a need for Delta 8
this Delta 8 Market came up from yeah
the farm bill and the fact that in the
language of the farm bill they only
referen that what they did the farm bill
removes Industrial Hemp from the control
dangerous substance act and it's defined
as cannabis with less than than 3% Delta
9 THC there was no mention about Delta 8
and they never contemplated the fact
that you know Roger Adams first did it
in the 40s and then mulam redid it back
in the 70s is that you could chemically
convert CBD into THC and when you do
that conversion under certain conditions
you get Delta 8 which they don't mention
in the in the in the farm bill and
what's now complicated things is that
because Delta 8 is actually mentioned in
the control danger substance act now
they're hydrogenating that Delta 8 and
making hhc that's where hhc comes from
and they're like well hhc is not on the
control dangerous substance tack but you
know be that as it may this is all made
possible because of the Ridiculousness
of probation itself and if you're if
you're making a psychoactive substance
in a chemical reaction vessel it's
different than extracting it from a
plant right it's differing than than
than from nature itself and when you get
that whole Spectrum yeah when you make a
Delta 8 you're semi synthesizing it from
uh CBD which is illegal under the
controlled substance act so I mean it it
might fit through the loophole of the
Farm Act but Delta 8 is not legally
produced well we're we're we where're CD
runs into issues and again they never
contemplated this so I think Sam my
feeling again you know all your work and
everything that went into gws epid
dialects besides is that is that is that
the legislatur got snookered on seeds
rope and oil and they they're like CBD
what's that we don't care about CBD just
THC we only care about THC that's the
only thing that went into the language
of the bill I I I don't think they
realize that again CBD being the active
ingredient of an FDA approved drug
there's another law called the fdn C act
which is the food drug and cosmetic act
and and what that what that law says
which is is enforced by the FDA is that
the active ingredient of an FDA approved
drug cannot be used in food feed or
cosmetic or you know topical use for
interstate commerce it's interesting
that they put that Interstate Commerce
in there so what they need to do is they
need to make an exception to the fdn C
act like I think they've done for like
things like caffeine so caffeine is like
an active ingredient in drugs and stuff
like that but it's also in Coca-Cola and
Mountain Dew and all that other [__]
right so they made an exception to the
FD andc act I think caffeine actually
got grandfathered but I think there's
other examples of things that the FDA
approved as active ingredients but are
okay to use and you you'll know and Wade
knows this in Spades is that what what
Charlotte web the company Charlotte web
did I don't know if this the Stanley
Brothers anymore or not but what the
company Charlotte Web said okay fine
we'll submit CD extracts as a dietary
supplement from hemp because Industrial
Hemp right Canabis with lower than 3%
THC was removed from the control danger
substance act so the farm bill enabled
now the production of hemp it's like
well okay hemp is an agriculturally
produced
food I guess in a in a manner of
speaking right you can make seed oil you
can make seed protein from it right
Marcus so it's essentially a food and
and there's different regulation there
so the
USDA um the Department of Agriculture
only cares to the point where the crop
is grown right so all the Amendments
that go on the land you know whether
it's organic nonorganic and all about
farming and agricultural production
and the USDA kind of washes their hands
after that it sort of becomes the fda's
baywick to pick up okay now that corn
has been grown now it goes to Market
yeah if you're gonna if you're Delonte
and you want to make cans of corn
because that's what you do with corn
right you need an FDA inspected facility
certain levels of quality and production
standards that have to be held to
because you're making a variable
Agricultural Product that's being put
into these Delonte cans of corn that
people are eating right so yeah I
mean I I think where this goes again is
this run into big corporations because
now you're talking about industrial
agriculture you're talking about archers
Daniel Midland you're talking about big
chemical companies that bought the seed
companies that
that engineered seeds to be resistance
to the chemicals that they sell oh
boy and and and again yes like we were
talking earlier the F the EPA regulates
that so I know that USDA regulates the
genetically modified soybeans and corns
that are grown today but um I I've said
it before I think and I think Marcus you
agree that of the big drivers for for
hemp to overtake soybeans is going to be
on protein production per acre when it
comes down to it if you need to grow
protein you need to grow this crop
because this crop produces way more
protein for acre than soybeans and it
requires less chemicals but when you say
less chemicals now those chemical
companies get upset because they want to
sell the
chemicals right yep it's not just the
it's also you simultaneously create oil
so you're producing protein but when
you're defatting the protein you're
creating oil simultaneously so it's uh
it's two products I wanted to say thank
you to Wade I didn't think that was too
long at all it was awesome it was so
good to hear from you I love the whole
recap of the hash church that we had I
love the update of how you were doing I
I know I'm not the only one because I
heard read a ton of people in the chat
saying I've been thinking a lot about
Wade lately I always think a lot about
you Wade and it's uh it's just nice to
hear your Humanity I know how you feel
things because when you speak you you
you get us to feel the things that you
feel it's a very profound and Powerful
tool that you have at your disposal uh
but it's wonderful and it's uh it's it
it couldn't have been a better part of
hash church for you to share everything
that you did and of course I'll do a
hash church next week and we'll talk to
you and all the hash makers that are
coming by your farm and uh I'm really
glad to hear that you're getting better
and that like you know I know things
were rough there for a while I was
following the updates on Facebook and uh
I'm just glad that you've able been able
to get through all of that of course
you're still in it but uh get through
the sort of the I don't know what it is
when we're going through those things oh
lack of hope you know but just the
you're you're such a positive VI vibrant
person and I appreciate uh I appreciate
you sharing with us on in on hash search
it is it is our show not my
show there's Community again again it's
an industry but it's at heart really it
is a
community absolutely and on that note I
think I'm going to wrap it up for this
week so many wonderful people to come in
and share The Vibes uh last minute often
you know got to really thank all of you
for coming and doing this every time
it's uh I'm realizing more and more how
much I need it myself and it's it's
terrible to sometimes feel like I don't
have time I I have to sacrifice going to
see my son skating you know that's this
is his skating lesson time so and I'm
sure there's sacrifices uh for all of
you to be made as well and uh I do
appreciate it it doesn't go unseen or
unfelt and I thank the more than 200
people that have been watching with us
since we started at 9:00 am for almost
four hours of uh what I just thought was
awesome conversation I'm going to
dissect it maybe listen to it again and
maybe create specific hash Church hash
churches for the specific conversations
that we had because there was at least
four or five really good ones big thanks
to valary carral for coming on big
thanks for Hillary black for showing up
uh when she's not feeling the best in in
the chat room and and sharing a bit of
her Vibes I want to shout out Ron one of
my OG mentors who was in the room as
well there he is right there he just
chimed in so shout out to you Ron uh
hopefully we can have you come on one
day and tell some stories and of course
skunkman Sam at TI Dr Mark best friend
Farms Colin and Wade and the dragonfly
Earth
medicine uh love you all really give
thanks for everything and uh we will see
you all hopefully again next week peace
out everybody May the full melt bless
your bowl sooner than later CIA for now