all right I think we're going live here
give me a few more
seconds yes I stayed up late just waking
up here all
right oky dokie yes we are Live on
YouTube I just going to quickly copy and
paste the link over
into the old chat room and then I'm
going to let everyone into the room boom
boom boom boom boom boom boom boom boom
wow everyone was ready this
morning okay well first of all thank you
everyone for joining us today this is a
special episode of hash Church uh we're
celebrating the life of Frenchie canoli
uh really goes without saying
introducing
Frenchie of the greatest levels please
mute your mic speaking if you don't mind
real quickly there and uh just going to
introduce uh Madame canoli Kimberly uh
who we uh she's going to be sort of our
pseudo uh my secondary host today
because this is really uh she reached
out to me I met her at lyt not too long
ago where I got to see uh Frenchie
dreams of hashish this documentary Dash
movie and it is absolutely spectacular I
had tears in my eyes it inspired me uh I
really loved it and I thought what
better place to join and speak about it
than here on hash Church something we
haven't done for a long time most of you
guys have been on hash Church before
some of you haven't so I'm going to pass
it over to uh Madame canoli now she can
introduce everyone and we can talk about
what we're going to be speaking about
today so uh boom shank shank MV let's
get this party started thank you so much
for for having me we didn't get to talk
after the film I was very touched that
you came to see it when uh it was
screened in Vancouver um so thank you
for that I'm glad you enjoyed it um
maybe you know it's really hard for me
to see everybody here in a kind of
efficient way but uh uh let me just go
across the top and uh Bill you're next
in line maybe you can uh introduce
yourself sure can you guys hear me okay
yeah it's good to see you
Kim hi everyone um I'm cherry blossom
Bell I'm Frenchie I'm um Frenchie
canoli's formal uh apprentice and I
lived and worked with him and Madam
canoli um and traveled with them for
over seven years teaching workshops
making hash and um learning from both of
them
equally um and yeah and now I'm
currently present day I'm the director
of manufacturing at Heritage hasco um
Heritage mesino we're located in um
Yukaya California we're at 1076
Cunningham Street in Yukaya and we're a
we call ourselves the world's first
public cannabis hashery um for we are a
retail location but you can all you can
see into my lab and see the product
being made as you buy it and you can go
up to the window and ask questions so
it's it's really beautiful um because I
really feel like you know
um it really fills that value of
educating the public public and keeping
it open to the public and and um paying
it forward in that light like Frenchie
did in a sense to many of us who was
just open source and just answered
anyone's questions so anytime anyone
comes to the window and knocks and has a
question um I will take the time out of
my day to answer it um in in spirits you
know in the spirit of
Frenchie and yeah that's me I'll keep it
brief because I know we have a a couple
people to get through
here so um thanks Bill that's really
sweet it looks like Craig you're next on
the
list Craig could you hear
me yeah good morning um I'm Gonna Keep
it pretty brief we're boarding a flight
we've had all sorts of travel changes so
um I just wanted to make sure I was able
to jump on and say good morning to
everyone I'm Craig from alpen glow Farms
here in southern Humble County my wife
and I back there boss Mama um have been
been at it for a few years up here in
Humble and you know I just want to share
just in case I do get cut off that when
Frenchie came to visit our farm for the
first time and we walked around and
drove around on the four-wheeler to
check everything out he was just so
happy to see how we're cultivating you
know just on the natural surfaces of the
land following the
Contours and working with with the land
provided and uh just the side of a
mountain and um he was just earto ear
grinning as he does and laughing and and
just it was just absolutely amazing to
share our space and um uh just have them
visit our community and and get excited
this is when he first was coming into
the Emerald Triangle so I'll leave it at
that and and much love to everyone and
look forward to hearing as much
conversation as I can through this
morning thank you for joining us that's
really lovely thank you
next in line
Isen hello I'm aen I'm a uh I own a
dispensary in California and uh Frenchie
came to me when he first was trying to
get involved and I was very honored that
he did and humbled and um just gave him
advice as I would give anybody and
needless to say he heed it heard it and
I was able to spend wonderful moments
with him uh my most m able would be our
200 questions we shared uh which uh was
a lot of fun which I need to do with
bubble man and all of you I've got these
200 cannabis questions I'll now we're
down to 50 but that way you know you
know which ones but um it's just humbled
and honored to be here as uh you know a
f fellow hash appreciator and uh thank
you Madame Bell for keeping the
traditional live and thank you madam
canoli for doing everything you can to
keep your wonderful spouse's memory
alive because he left so much for us all
and thank you for continuing that so and
honor to be here and that afternoon I
was it's funny I was just looking the
other day I uh was I found the um file
with the it's two and a half hours of
the two of you talking and answering the
questions and there's some real gems in
there that I need to uh dust off and uh
post you got him to tell some great
stories so uh yeah we definitely need to
share that with the
world uh looks like uh from the top of
my page the next in line would be our
friends at dragonfly Earth medicine hi
Josh and
Kelly hey family hi everyone it's so
lovely to see you all this morning it's
nighttime here but um we wouldn't miss
this commemoration for for the world
really six o'clock in the afternoon is
actually a pretty good time to do a hash
church so feeling pretty about that you
know uh you know we're here at the the
gwa smoke Club in Barcelona we were here
a month ago with Stephen green lifee uh
Stephen quy from Green life and when we
came to Barcelona we really really felt
the impact of Frenchie canoli and all of
the work that Frenchie's put out there
because the love for hash is here in a
way that you just you know you see it in
a lot of places but there's just there's
just a huge amount of appreciation here
we've been really taken in by the gwa
family feeling really blessed to be here
we know Marcus is coming soon uh most
importantly we're just really thankful
for Frenchie and to have mentors in your
life like Frenchie and Elders that
really hold the space in a way that's
classy and fun and strong is something
we always appreciated from Frenchie and
you Kimberly and everyone that's worked
with him in the past uh we feel very
honored to be here today we have a lot
of respect for everyone that's on this
panel and everyone that's listening
thank you so much you want to say one
more thing yeah I just wanted to say
that one thing you know that we are
focused on in dragonfly Earth medicine
is just really education education for
Community Education for regenerative
medicine
and uh connecting with Frenchie on that
level was definitely one of the
highlights of my life he changed the way
I thought he challenged so many ideas he
would take apart everything that you
would say and want to rebuild it in a
Frenchy way and because of that I have
so much love for him and the education
that this movie and Kimberly that you
continue to spread and like Josh said I
am telling you his energy has felt so
strongly here
the love for hash Temple balls people
are talking about it the Frenchy way
look I'm rolling it the Frenchy way it
feels so amazing to be here and honestly
I'm really feeling like he's here this
babus
so there's to be here with you there's a
lot of Moroccan influence here which we
know is deep in Frenchie's heart too
thank you so much everyone we look
forward to the
show um next up on the little bar across
the top Mark um the two of us haven't
met so so nice to meet
you hey chy how are you good um hey
Marcus uh Hey aan everybody Josh and
Kelly good to see everybody Wade so
great to see Wade so uh Frenchie and I
only met once um we tried to meet a
couple times but as you know uh French
he drew a crowd wherever he went and and
we always found it uh uh 10 Deep uh
whenever we came to his booth and we
were never able to hook up at a couple
of the cups we were trying to hook up so
when we finally did meet it was an honor
to meet him and it was at a gold key
event in Las Vegas a few years back and
um it was just so cool because um uh he
was actually part of the registration
process so anybody who who went to that
event uh met met Frenchie but then we
had a a little moment later on over by
the pool where yeah I mean I I so what I
got from him just because I remember
watching him at these events is is again
to speak with Josh and Kelly just said
how he was the educator the consumate
educator and how there was a whole group
of people around him that was absorbing
everything he was saying and everything
he was doing and that's why like in so
many ways he's like people who've passed
before who have left such an inspiration
in their educational uh time on this
brief period that were on this shining
blue ball and it was just it was so
meant for him to be that educator who
brought his passion and his journey that
only he singularly took in life to you
know discover hash and hashes and bring
it to everyone and now every time we
smoke it we could remember him and it's
just such an honor to be here and such
an honor to know you Kimberly thank you
so much thank you thank you that's very
kind of
you um Nikki it looks like you're
next so happy you can join us deep in
the snow snowed in there in mesino yeah
thank you it is it's really deep up here
I mean we got another six inches or so
last night so Swami has been out
scraping snow and ice off the solar
panels right now to make sure we Contin
to have power and it has been going in
and out quite a bit so if we fade away
just understand we're just out hanging
out with the Snowman and it's pretty
thick up here anyway it's an honor to be
here Swami will be back in a second I
know he'd love to say hi too and um of
course it's always an honor to be in a
room with such an amazing group of
people thank you Kimberly and thank you
Marcus for bringing us all together and
as always it's wonderful to honor
Frenchie I mean this is a man we're
going to be talking about forever and
and he's really going down in the books
as one of the greats and just so happy
to have known him and spent time and
this movie is amazing Swami hasn't even
seen it yet he's gonna get to see it
April 29th finally and
it's uh oh there goes the
electricity um well let's uh go further
up north to Humble Dylan and let's trust
try your bandwith we don't have any
intention of stopping and do it in hon
Frenchy every day so thank you all
thanks
Nikki sorry Dylan there we
go Dylan did your there you are there we
are hey good morning everyone and good
morning Kim and Josh and Kelly and
everybody else on here um what a honor
to be invited with with of you folks to
talk and honor Frenchie um I'm up in
honeydew in the matol valley and and
really I I found Frenchie when he found
us out here in the matle he
um uh Frenchie and Leo met met my good
friend Josh free and um at Empress farms
and and Josh they they really hit it off
right away and and Josh brought Frenchie
out to the valley and Frenchie fell in
love with our little Valley and um and
we just all fell in love with Frenchie
our little community and he became a
mentor for us all and really really
opened our eyes to um to what we knew
existed we just didn't really we just
didn't understand it and and still were
learning but this connection between um
you know place and plant and people and
um terar and and what that all really
means and um and he really mentored Us
in that in that idea of Appalachians and
that this was something really important
and that we we needed to take it
seriously and that if we wanted to talk
about how the the weed that we grow here
in in the matle valley and and humble to
special that it's not something you can
just lightly say that if you're going to
talk about this you you really need to
take it seriously and and have a respect
for the the old traditions of what these
these words like app ations mean and and
he was he was he was really um intent on
that and that like don't say that unless
you are serious and you're going to do
the work and there's science and there's
work and you can't just throw this
around lightly and um so he really was a
mentor and he told us books to read and
and sent us links and came and visited
and talked with us and introduced us to
to to all sorts of people and so you
know I just um just what a what an honor
and a privilege to have have gotten to
know Frenchie and have him in our home
and have him you know come and cook for
us sometimes and just you know what
great experiences so he he he he
certainly his spirit is still here with
us and and um with the work that that
we're trying to continue on he he's a
he's an inspiration for us for sure so
so thank you Frenchie thank you Kimberly
oh my
pleasure um wait it looks like you're
next on our little list so nice to meet
you I uh have seen you virtually but I
don't think we've met uh
physic uh hi waade laughter here and no
we haven't met specifically but I
um I I could say some of the same things
that Dr Mark said about uh the couple of
times I managed to run into Frenchie uh
he was surrounded by a mob and I've
always been a bit of a hermit
and so I just gave him plenty of space I
I actually did invest a couple of times
in some of his work uh for my own
personal uh Joy if you
will uh and yeah
uh I would say this my my experience of
Frenchie uh as I've watched some of the
videos he's made um I I feel like as a
traveler he discovered a culture and
developed a passion for it in different
countries where traditional hash making
was being practiced and he took the
heart if you will of those cultures and
brought it to the work here in the west
and uh taught us again he his approach
was I don't have any secrets I want to
share with you what I've learned and
maybe I'll learn something too I could
be talking about me but that was my
sense of Frenchie that he was so open to
uh the people who did who did manage to
fight through the crowd and talk to him
and I did actually um a couple of years
back just before the emerald cup the
dragonfly Earth medicine family hi J and
Kelly uh had a gathering um and I can't
remember the woman's name whose place it
was but yeah Frenchie came he brought
his his big hookah and I did have a
chance
Garcia blessings thank you Josh yes and
uh
yeah that was a wonderful night uh but
again I got there early and he got there
late and but I did chance to
share his work directly through his
hookah and that is a lot where I got my
sense of his love for what he was doing
that I don't have any secrets here it is
drink deeply of what I have experienced
in my life and that's an inspiration to
me because that's that's a lot where my
love for this plant comes from I've I've
seen what the plant can do for people
and so yeah I'm a medicine maker
Frenchie was a medicine maker and an
inspiration to me so thank you for this
event and uh yeah it took
me um a few hours and a pretty strong
discussion with my wife for me to get
out of the house and off the mountain
and into a town where there's
electricity and internet because I
wanted to be be here today and I may not
stay till the end of the church because
it is still snowing up here and we got
we lost power and internet on Monday
today Sunday
and uh we're supposed to have a couple
more feet between now and Tuesday and a
couple more feet by Friday so yeah I
want to get home we're well situated and
everything uh at home but this event and
my love for frie and his inspiration to
me was enough to get me off the hill to
join this group and I really grateful to
be here so thank you for the event thank
you for all of you who showed up and uh
much
love no thank you for joining us that's
so
sweet did I miss anybody I'm not a
master Zoom Marcus is there anybody that
I didn't reach because I can't see them
for some
reason um no I think uh there is one
person in here as Zoom user with their
camera off I'm not sure who that is but
yeah it seems like we got through
everyone else here on the
panel oh Zoom user is now
[Laughter]
gone um Kimberly Swami's here now if you
want to talk to just brought him okay
hold on a second fresh from the solar
panels in the snow hi everybody I'm a
little out of breath it's uh it's 30
inches deep out there oh [ __ ] W last
night I had to go out and scrape off the
uh the Satellite Dish thing and I had to
scrape off the solar panels as they had
a bunch of snow the snow was over my
boots wow and my my fingers were cold
but that's the report talking well okay
frie would love the snow I'm sure
fry well what a great friend he was and
we had a lot of good times
together and we had that special
connection from Goa you know and we have
a lot of mutual friends who knew
Frenchie as Camy back in Goa right he
was a whole another character back there
but he realized his full true life's
purpose when he came to
California right cuz he was looking for
the best to make the best hash and he
finally realized to make the best hash
you need the best flower and when he
came here I think the tpin blew the head
the top off of his head and so that was
just the whole thing that he dived in
and he was kind of in many
ways chronology wise he was kind of a
late Comer to the
scene but boy he got right to the middle
as soon as he could and he R found the
best Farms all in Northern
California and he made the best
hash okay I'm going to change my socks
cuz they're soaking
W and last but not least the mystery
Zoom user is
Ed uh did you would you like to
introduce
yourself hi I'm uh Brett bird I uh I
guess I'm Zoom user I didn't know I'm
not very very Savvy with this stuff but
uh I'm really glad to be here and very
honored to be a part of this Frenchie
meant a lot to me and and I never met
anybody with such a a passion and love
for this and and willing to share his
passion and love and uh
I really means a lot to me and I try to
pass on some of what he instilled in me
and to everybody that uh wants to hear
anything about
hash that I'll keep it short I don't
want to start crying on you
guysen so it's okay to cry we we we love
him and we miss him and it's okay to
share that we love and we miss him
that's why we're
here so T I've been trying to get you to
see the movie and so many other people
have been asking me about when they can
see it so we're going to to make it
happen April
29th um it's going to be available via
Vmail and uh we have a bunch of people
all over the world that are going to be
scheduling some in-person events so that
uh some people can get together and
watch it together smoke it get smoke
together um and then after that we're
going to do a live stream so that we can
talk about the films so that I can uh
get the filmmaker online with us and you
guys can ask some questions and we can
just hear what yall think about the film
and the
experience I I can't thank you enough
for finally putting it uh online
unfortunately every time that it's aired
uh my mother is in hospice so I've had
to travel back to Mississippi to visit
and be with her so it's just been a
series of unhappy accidents
unfortunately and I am beyond excited
and I will have my own little watch
party here probably with my my veterans
Action Council friends uh we'll probably
get together and do a little watch party
out of love because Frenchie was an
inspiration to all of
us we also haven't haven't seen it yet
so we're waiting to see it we were gonna
maybe get to see it at The Hive in
California while we were there but it
didn't get to happen Luna was there so
that was beautiful to spend time with
Hera or Elena and uh and um yeah just uh
really stoked uh to see it up in Alberta
because I think it's going to be in
Edmonton where we see it at the grow off
yes so that might be a really fun place
to to finally see it and I know the
family here in Barcelona want to see it
as
well a number of the social clubs are
gonna hold a a little screening so
that's going to be an option for a lot
of people um so that's lovely and I
shout out to the growup for being so
supportive of the film um you know they
kind of set this precedent of screening
the film and selling tickets and then
they're donating the money to the
nonprofit that were working with the
origins Council because Dylan and some
of the farmers featured in the film are
doing a little project on cannabis
terare and so we're using the donations
to help support those scientific studies
so we're pretty stoked about that
and and we're incredibly grateful
Kimberly for for for the help that you
and the support um you know both
financially but just um with with you
you you hold a lot of that wisdom that
freny shared with all of us so it's um
we're we're really all of us out here in
the matle are incredibly grateful um to
have you be participating and and
helping with us in that work and and
that's uh you know part of the spirit of
Frenchy living on for sure and we're
we're going to try to do right by him
it's um it's complicated science and
it's not something that's that's been
done um so it's it's certainly
challenging but um but but through um
working with Origins Council and Swami I
appreciate you as well I know you're
you're on the board of of OC and um you
know they've connected us with some
really incredible advisers and we're
working with Leaf Works who is uh put
together an experiment that we will be
diving into full scale this summer and
and really trying to to make this causal
link connection between the place and
the plant and how it expresses and um so
so thank you for mentioning that
Kimberly no my pleasure I was just uh
reading the newspaper yesterday that you
know so this whole concept of uh having
a tear wear that's then used to create
an appalation which which is this legal
uh structure to kind of protect the
small farmers for these recognized AGR
agricultural products they have this
precedent in Europe where they've used
it for cheese and for wine and for um
you know sausage products in Spain but
unfortunately in the US we don't have
much respect for this I just saw
yesterday that the government had ruled
that they're going to allow American Air
to be sold sold as Grier when this is a
product that has a a named protection in
Europe so it's a little frustrating that
somehow this concept is not honored or
that it's somehow appropriated and just
like anybody can use it if they make a
cheese that has holes in it and has been
aged for more than 90 days so I think
that's kind of a similar thing with some
of the challenges our industry has
experienced with
legalization having these like Mega
grows that flood the Market with product
that is you know not doesn't meet the
same standards there needs to be a way
to differentiate so that the the
dispensaries the consumers other people
are able to have access to Quality that
they want and frenly that was his whole
focus with his travels you know one of
the main things was he always wanted to
have access to the best product and
realized you had to go to the farmers
that the source of the quality was the
farmers and so I can't think of a better
way to support his legacy than to fund
things that emphasize that quality and
help the Legacy Farmers have their their
correct place in the marketplace in the
in the efforts what we're doing yeah
yeah frency and I talked about that as
you well know Kimberly forever and ever
and ever and we had some very energetic
discussions in the typical Frenchy way
uh and i' lived in South America enough
to know that uh shouting and screaming
is just passion not
anger right but for all of you who don't
know so much about Appalachian in France
uh which as you say it started hundreds
of years ago first with Roa for cheese
because some King wanted to be sure it
was Roa for cheese uh well uh there's
like 10 pages of appellations on Farm
Goods on agricultural products uh crops
in France there's there's uh Appalachian
butter there's saffron there's honey
there's lavender all these different
things which are like French basil so on
they're special products that get their
special flavor and quality from the soil
that they're grown in and from the
culture of the farmers who are the ones
doing the growing and the farmers are
are the car of the intellectual property
and when you have a collective of
farmers they have a group knowledge a
group uh understanding wisdom uh that
develops over the years now some people
would argue that in in the Cannabis
world we haven't been doing it quite
long enough to have that uh fundamental
uh you know wisdom of the people but we
do have a lot of that and we do know and
we do share that knowledge and that's
one of the key things about an
appalation that the the standards
practices and varietals are determined
by the farmers themselves not by a state
bureaucratic Department department and
that's key also to the French way of
doing which is adapted also by the
entire European Union so there are many
many many agricultural crops that do
have what they call the flavor or the
taste of the of the place where they
grow right curiously enough in the
United States there is not a single true
French style appalation they do not
exist and there you'll see driving
around certain Vine wine areas and
they'll say appal on the sign and they
legally cannot use that word the
technical word is geographic indicator
right they can use a geographical
indicator if it's grown in that area we
have it now in cannabis as well because
you can put the name of your county and
say it was grown in that county if you
can verify that 100% of the product in
the jar is from that County so we do get
County of designation but that's simply
a geographical there are no standards
prac IES and varietals for that so
that's the key to appalation uh how it's
going to play out uh in the United
States California was the first state to
actually legally put that word and those
qualifications onto any product and it's
cannabis it doesn't exist for any other
product in the US right everyone in the
US says all lawyers you talk to say well
just get a trademark it's the same thing
and you kind of look at them and say
well you don't quite understand this do
you because a trademark can be bought
and sold it can be moved it's owned by
somebody there are people in Florida
selling Humbolt this and that and the
other thing right so the thing is that
an appalation only belongs to the
farmers who create it and they have to
then create an a business entity of some
sort to uh enforce it and they also then
create their own standards practices and
varietals and so I'll kind of let off on
this because I could go deep down in the
hole like French he always used to do
but if you have other questions and uh
thanks also for you know mentioning the
the origins Council because we started
uh in
2015 that's eight years ago now folks we
started in 2015 talking about appalation
uh Janine and I and Justin calino for
the amendes appalation projects that
that then grew into Origins Council and
so many more people came on board and
now all the Legacy growing areas are
represented by Origins Council and uh
we're keep getting more people too so
Origins council is really the only
spokesperson uh Janine particularly
Adept at it for uh the small farmer of
the Legacy Growers of California so it
needs all our support that we can give
it yeah I'm really excited that the film
is Gen uh donating 20% of all of our
proceeds forever to the efforts of the
origin Council because I think that you
know it's not only important for
California you guys are setting a
predent for for things that are going to
happen all over the world and I keep
thinking if you guys can create the
model and get legal recognition then
maybe we can help protect the Legacy
farmers in Afghanistan or Lebanon once
things legalize worldwide because I just
feel like those Traditions Northern
India those places where we had such you
know profound experiences When We Were
Young they need the protection as well
so this work that we're doing it's not
just for us it's really to set a set a
standard around Legacy cannabis
worldwide outdoor sungrown cannabis and
this tradition of making hashish in
these really old cultures that I think
it's really important for Humanity um
because I agree 100% uh Kimberly because
that was always part of my reference too
because I haven't smoked as many places
as Frenchie probably but I missed
Northern Africa but I've smoked in
Israel I smoked in Afghanistan in
Amsterdam in Nepal uh even in China you
know so it's like uh Thailand so it's
really a worldwide thing and one of the
things that working with hashish is to
remember that this is a plant that's
been you know helping Humanity for you
know at least 10 20,000 years
right uh oh looks
like the mesino bandwidth has has struck
again uh while we wait for also as you
just said kly protect the small farmer
in in Morocco in Lebanon anywhere the
people are growing quality and have a
skill that is an ancient tradition uh
you know walking along The Terraces in
in Northern India in the mountains and
you turn around a corner and you see
this Terrace and all of a sudden there's
20 foot high cannabis plants there with
with birds roosting in the in the
branches and so on and and it's right
next to the compost pile and then they
come down and there's some lady she's
rubbing this this hash like this and and
and you get a little smoke from it and
so on it's just you know you go over to
visit somebody and they invite you in
for tea and biscuits and and then they
they light up a Chillum you know so and
you're smoking now a Chillum with with
the mayor of the village and and the the
the director of the school system right
and it's just part of their culture that
you know is a whole sort of way of life
and you know I still remember the first
little old farmer who taught me how to
use a Chillum way back in the mountains
of Nepal and so he said no no no that's
not right that's not right here here's
how you do it and you know just wanting
to share that sort of stuff and so it's
a tradition that we're part of and we
need to be proud of it and share
it I'd just like to add that India also
taught us how to recognize the small
farmers with their protest that happened
in India last year the the Indian
farmers protest really stood up for
small farmers and how they can out
produce corporate farming while
producing a higher quality in India
really does uphold Community farming and
Community gardening and that's another
nice aspect for us to learn which
Frenchie also kept that India connection
and um all that knowledge going I really
appreciate everything that was said and
also welcome Lena it's beautiful to see
you today um also I just wanted to add
one more thing Dylan you said you know
we hope that we can live up to to to
Frenchie's expectations and live up to
you know his moral compass and I believe
that that's what we're talking about
here we're talking about you know every
single one of those tricomes those
crystals to be farmed by a small farmer
in community in recognition of the soil
in that area and in that terroir
while sharing seeds with the local
community of what grows best there while
then sharing education on how to make
the best
resins you know and and that that is
living up to Frenchie's moral compass
and that is the importance of his legacy
and Kimberly this movie and everybody
here who is watching and everybody who
continues to keep friend
she's voice alive and and and it and it
isn't just about him it was about the
education that he was putting forward
which now becomes you know surrounded in
heart space and community and love and
medicine and people and it continues to
come back to the farmers and the people
and and I just think that that's the
Legacy that we have to live up to and
it's incredibly important for us to
continue to spark that bright light that
he carried
always I think it's that element you
know he used to always say we made too
much of him and that it wasn't about him
it was about the traditions and it was
about this evolution of passing on the
traditions and how important that was so
thank you for emphasizing that aspect of
community um
because I'll just say one thing
just come on hi guy this chilum is for
Frenchie is a chilum of
dryft for remember your
soul blessings and
love uh listen when when you brought up
um the India just now I had a a
flashback I researching the sort of the
origins of the organic regenerative food
movement and I can't remember the guy's
name but some English scientist who went
out to India uh in the early 1900s and
he was going to teach all those Indian
people how to grow uh using industrial
chemicals salt-based petroleum chemicals
and they was going to increase their
yield and so on and uh so he was doing
that and then after about four years his
yield started to go down and his quality
wasn't very good and he noticed that the
farmers around who weren't doing what he
told them to do were actually doing
better that their crop was was more and
so he started to research hey what are
these people doing well they've only
been doing this for the last two 10,000
years or whatever and they've kind of
figured out how their environment
interacts with their products and they
have special cultivars and they were
using manure and they were using organic
methods that we now are referring to as
regenerative method so those primitive
local little Farmers eing out a tiny
little crop were doing way better than
this fancy scientist from England and he
had the smarts and the humility to turn
around and say I can learn from these
people and so he did and out of that
came the rodali and all these other
things that we call organic but it
originated with little local farmers uh
in India who've been doing this for uh
you know I don't know seven or eight
thousand years so we have a tradition
and and that moral standard that you
brought up is is a really great thing
about how to be honest with yourself
yourself and honest with your food and
honest with your medicine uh and how
that has to pervade our whole life and
be part of our basic ethic and and what
we share with people because this this
is this is truth we we're working with
here a lot of that is what we try to
embody with with the Dem pure
certification and it is beautiful
there's five six people here from that
and and we really do work our best at
projecting that and
uh you know recognizing that we are
creating local appalaches but we are
worldwide we have this capability to
talk to you all live we have these
capabilities to learn from each other no
matter what language boy Google instant
translate is is amazing and how quickly
that we can communicate with each other
but this thread of our connection to
Nature and con ction to community is
everything that Frenchie was about and
that continues to move forward also and
Peter Proctor wrote a really amazing
book from uh he's from New Zealand went
to India one man one cow one man one cow
and it's a biod dnamic you know uh way
of Clos Loop farming in India
[Laughter]
well I'd like to say a little something
about Frenchie our path's crossed more
than a few times for certain and uh one
of the things I loved about him as
everyone's already mentioned is uh you
know I thought I was passionate about
hashish I thought I'd met passionate
people about hashish I had traveled to
hashish countries and I had gone to the
Maha kumaa and kashish with the Babas on
the sides of the ganji I did all sorts
of amazing I I traveled to the Bobo
Shanti um communities in Jamaica and
helped make cash with those guys with
the Lamb's bread and did all of these
sorts of things but uh and I'm also
French that's also my lineage is most
I'm about 50 to 60% France and so we
were able to speak French the the when
we would bump into one another but his
absolute passion was just radiating off
the man in a way that uh you really kind
of had to be um numb or or dead inside
to not almost be overwhelmed by it um
and so you know obviously I love hashish
I love talking about hashish I love
connecting the dots um but fren she
really took it to another level and I
you know I didn't get to spend as much
time as I would have liked to with them
as we were on similar paths in in
different places that seem to cross uh
paths but the last time I I got to hang
out with him was in a very private
setting as Wade mentioned earlier frie
often had a crowd around him and I I had
showed up at HQ in Barcelona my friend
David's Club a club of which I was one
of the first members of uh eight or nine
years ago when I when I first went into
that club when it was brand new and he
said you know what I'm busy right now if
you just want to go upstairs for my
little private area there I'll come and
see you later and I went up there and uh
it was just frie sitting up there by
himself and I he didn't even tell me
that Frenchie was up there so Frenchie
and I got to sit in HQ uh and and smoke
hash and play with hash and talk about
hash and it was a a lovely way for us to
spend our last uh our last time together
so I'll definitely hold that dear and uh
remember that for the rest of my life
and just uh you know thank uh thank
Frenchie for everything that he brought
to the community you know there's all
sorts of different people doing all sort
to different things but he really made a
mark That's not uh that's not going to
be going away and you know Wade also
mentioned the way he brought that heart
of the culture you know as we you know
as I as I experien legal cannabis in
Canada as I experience you know Veil
purchasing Whistler these corporate
entities that try to come in and
eliminate the culture that existed at
the core and whenever they do it it
ruins good things so to have someone
like Frenchie take that core information
out of Himel pesh and out of Milana and
Parvati Valley and these very special
zones that a lot of people have never
been able to go to and visit and sort of
bring that into the new world I'll be
honest it's really what Legends of hash
was always about trying to pay homage to
to the elders to the to the culture you
know I meet a lot of people in the
Canabis industry I've been doing this
since the 60s you know I'm one of the
ogs but then I like to think of the ACT
ual people who were doing it four five
six seven 800 years ago a thousand years
ago and we can't forget about them
either because they're the true OG's and
I think that uh you know Frenchie
carried them with him wherever he went
and he emanated that energy and I I see
everyone on this panel you know will
will now carry that with us for the rest
of our hashish days so uh once again
boom Shankar Shankar mahv to freni uh I
think it might be time to smoke a bowl
in his honor
I noticed that um Lena jumped on and I
just wanted to see if she wanted to say
anything really quick because she didn't
uh get a chance to say anything Miss
Lena hi sister hi Belle how's it going I
was technical difficulties this morning
thanks for Dylan for saving
the um just to piggy back off of the
beautiful words you guys have already
said I
mean fren she wanted us just to lead
with passion and love what we were doing
dedicated to what we were
doing if you're not doing that I mean
what are you doing with your life so it
it's always be in the pursuit of
happiness and betterment so um that's
how I like to lead and I know all of you
here on this panel love to lead as well
it was an honor to be able to work
closely with Frenchie and under him and
learn from him the first moment I met
him I uh had just gotten into hash
making and just wanted to better my hash
making skills and
just the radiance he like emanated in
the room the moment I met him I was just
like sold he could have been talking
about anything and whatever it was like
I want to do exactly that and learn
exactly that and be that person like it
was just beautiful so he definitely
helped me further my love for hash
making and he really believed in me well
before I believed in myself so um it's
pretty cool and the moment I brought him
my first hash after taking his class he
was just mind blown and that really kind
of just gave me
uh a lot of determination and like
knowing that I was going on the right
path and working with the right material
so uh yeah
really happy to have known
him I can't get over how some of your
recent posts if I didn't if they hadn't
been posted under your name it would
look like stuff Frenchie posted five six
years ago um especially the ones where
you're really showing the full dimension
of brightness the way he did where he
would line the washes up so that you
could see the variation in color and
then um when they pancake it's just such
a joy to see that because you know kind
of that was the ultimate goal was to uh
harvest the triom in such a way that you
were getting almost the pure resin and
then when you leave it for a second it
just falls under its weight it just
feels like there's I don't know some
kind of like we're talking about this
tradition and this Evolution like those
things connect back to humans to great
grandparents that you know we don't even
know that we have somehow in foreign
countries
and uh it's a beautiful
thing I just want to add alinaa I'm
actually smoking your stuff right
now he nice am my three B it's amazing
and and to that note like it's it's
incredible Kimberly is right you know
when I see your photos I'm like it looks
un it it looks exactly like Frenchies
work it actually kind of brings tears to
my eyes a little bit because you know
I'm just like you know that you really
you really nailed it and your pressed
hash she is just so so beautiful it
really hits home and it's actually all
I've been smoking for the past two weeks
so thank you
girl have like made my year
um as always credit to the farmer I'm
nothing without them like I'm working
with some amazing farmers in a beautiful
Valley and um I definitely feel Frenchie
spirit in my workspace you know I'm
definitely harness him and trying to
make him proud so thanks
guys yeah and um that's you know going
back to the farmer again you know like
that's thank you for mentioning that
Lena CU you know I love that you know we
um we are only as good as the product
that we work with and I'm really shout
out to the farmer and to the land
Frenchie used to tell me I I think the
most beautiful thing about you linaa is
and and even bird you guys work with um
you work very closely with a
farmer um and you really represent the
land and that area and uh and I think in
my experience that's just been the most
profound impact is
environmental um Frenchie even used to
say you know when he was traveling in
producing countries um you know when he
was traveling in the mountains people
would wouldn't they wouldn't care care
that he was the one who made the hash
they asked him how far he went to go
make that hash what altitude what valley
did he go to to make that hash and um
and it's the same thing where as as a as
a craft hashishin you know we kind of
use the ter or um you know the land as a
compass to Source our material um like
you know you represent the matol valley
the Lost Coast bird represents
Willets you know um and uh and I I have
the honor to represent a lot of I ALS
matol and other other Farmers bryand all
these other kchi um and it's it's it's
always these genetics you know and it's
these genetics and these these C these
these strains that that farmers you know
the neighbors have had for a while you
know they've been growing it for a while
you know it's been traded amongst that
same area so it's almost like that plant
those plants really know that area and
that land and it kind of it has the most
profound impact when it comes to the the
pro the turine profile um so again it
always comes down to the bringing it
back it always comes down to the land
and and the farmer so um yeah just want
to give a shout out to all the farmers
who are on here right now thank you I
appreciate all of you very
much and in Frenchie words I mean unless
you're doing it all yourself which is
really hard to do we don't eat and we
don't smoke without the farmer so we
have to give them the utmost respect and
love and take care of them because they
take care of us and they take care of
the um land they're working on and the
surrounding environments like a lot of
work goes into this so thank them
regularly and support
them and the
so hard to preserve
too shout out to the fungi as well we
couldn't do it without the fungi the
symbiotic relationship that that that
that missing component that allows the
plant to express the
terroir you know because that's really
what cannabis is doing for us it's
allowing us to experience these
different areas and I love the fact that
there are very specific hashes cultures
in the world but I also love the fact
that there are terar for us to explore
and to to meet for the very first time
there's going to be some zones that
cannabis has produced in in the in the
in the upcoming decades that will
Express I'm I'm certain unlike anything
we've ever experienced and right now
there's no doubt about that California
is definitely the center of the Cannabis
universe and there's some other amazing
terar out in the world but uh I
sometimes think there that we're going
to be discovering some new ones as well
here with uh with this lovely plant that
we uh that we all have such a a
wonderful relationship with I wonder
about the whole aspect of breeding you
know when Frenchie was in the mountains
he rented a field uh uh from a some
Farmers up there for years and the
farmers used to cultivate those fields
by breaking it up and throwing seeds out
you know year overy year and just
letting the rain work its magic and
after the first year Frenchie asked them
to stop doing that and to let the plants
just go back to their wild State and
respond to the environment that they
were in and I had the most amazing
contct uh conversation with Kevin JRE uh
at one of the ganier council meetings
where he talked about how if you allowed
the natural cultivar to express itself
there was the elements of the humans
that lived in that region and what they
needed and that their needs were going
to be slightly different based on the
environment that they were in and not
meaning not only like the weather that
was there
but like if you're up north in Canada
and it's cold maybe you don't want to be
as energetic as somebody who's living in
a Southern Hemisphere and they're on a
beach or vice versa and so kind of to
your point we have humans that right now
are directing the breeding of certain
cultivars what would happen if we threw
the seeds out there and let nature kind
of develop a cultivar based on that what
they understood the needs of the humans
living there to be I wonder how that
that might differ and there's also this
element of of humans breeding four very
high levels of THC everybody knows I
don't smoke anymore the THC is too much
for me it overwhelms me immediately and
so I just wonder in its natural
environment looking at some of the
studies that were done for example in
Israel at one point the government
commission studies using material from
Buss that they had gathered and this was
like around
2014 and the THC leveled in the material
that they were um getting from these
smuggling operations was so low like the
charas was 3 to 7% the hashish was less
than
177% but I remember getting really
really high in India when we were
smoking that stuff so is it really
necessary or a benefit these high THC
levels because I in California when we
sell to dispensaries they're like less
than 30% we won't even look at it we
won't even talk to you and I'm just
wondering if this is like is this the
right path for humans
to to approach how the the plants
cultivated and what what makes it to the
shelves in a commercial
environment I I I think a lot of it has
been driven by uh prohibition uh because
prohibition drove a a lot of neoy
smokers and when they smoked they got so
high experienced Growers and as uh
Frenchie and others have taught us and
one of the things that we found when we
were initially testing back in 08 and 09
is we had a lot of my first 1500 tests
before we even released the results we
found that a lot of the chemical
structure was identical almost 90% of
the Cannabis was the same
but we knew there was something
different and of course we've come to
realize it's the tpine profiles the chem
of our profiles that are different in
each that we couldn't register under THC
level so back then we had an issue and a
ethical issue and one that we're still
struggling under and one that we found
is that oh [ __ ] we're gonna have a
causation in America because we have due
to Prohibition and alcohol prohibition
there's this [ __ ] up mentality that
the higher the number the more [ __ ] up
you get and that causality is something
we have struggled with and one we had an
organization back in uh the ODS called
the medical cannabis Safety Council the
mcsc I was part of the um um uh
contaminants committee but one thing we
struggled with on the nomenclature
committee was how do we address this
issue because we were able to show that
and unfortunately Steve D'Angelo pushed
out testing quicker than we could come
up with the understanding to convey to
the consumer that there's something
happening that the THC number does not
matter and there's something that's else
happening within these flowers these
unique flowers that are having a
different effect on different people and
what we saw was uh people like
Harborside rejecting anything that have
now a this now created fictitious THC
level and then all of a sudden Berkeley
Patients Group had a whole bunch of
varietals that I've been wanting to have
for years come my way that I was able to
purchase that I would have never had
before because now an imaginary line had
been D driven into the sand that has
unfortunately become the pervasive
reality uh since legalization has
happened because we've never been able
to get behind that Pandora's box once it
was open it run away from us all and
unfortunately we're still struggling
with it and I feel a guilt mentally
because we were never able to do so and
I always have an anger at Steve because
Steve knew this and we challenged him
not to do this and he went at it because
of dollars as opposed to the Integrity
needed so that we could convey it
properly s to explain that but I wanted
to give a historical context from
California because I think it's
responsible that people understand where
we [ __ ] up we had a chance to be good
stewards here and we [ __ ] up and so
y'all can do better than us learn from
our
mistakes yeah thank you for that I think
that's really
important yeah it's hard to let ganja be
wild and be intelligent in the soil and
just interact with our spirits and then
you know if we had a like a good
the numbers and so on and the high THC
you know we had something that came in
at like eight THC and and and six uh CBD
and everybody loved it but we couldn't
sell it because it just didn't have that
high THC number so one of the things
that Frenchie and Madam canoli and Nikki
and I and about five 15 other people we
work to create the ganier council and
the ganier program and the purpose of
that it's still in the process of being
you know developed further and so on but
to get to a place where we could come
out with a score at the end of an
evaluation based on a 100 points that
would not be uh determined by
THC and that everybody's buying by one
number the TAC number and we said well
we want to look at the appearance we
want to look at the flavor we want to
look at the the aroma and we look at all
these things and we come out with a 100
point scale so Frenchie was very much
key and Madame canoli as well in
developing that program and so that's
the idea the point about this I think at
is to educate the customer educate the
consumer and that's on us that's what we
have to do and we have to do it every
day all day and we have to go through
the nose as we all well know the secret
to cannabis is always through the aroma
and the nose because in my research now
I'm GNA say this there's a great book
which I really highly recommend for all
of you it's called nose dive and it's
this amazing book and it talks about
everything that produces Aroma nose dive
it's like 500 pages on the Aromas and
there's only like 40 pages on tpin but
there's flavonoids and Esters and
phenols and volatile sulfur compounds
and and all these other things which are
creating the Aromas in cannabis it's not
only tpin so now all of a sudden we said
we need one thing to determine cannabis
is it sativa oh no that doesn't work is
it THC oh no that doesn't work is it
dominant tpine oh no that doesn't work
because cannabis we always come back to
the full plant it's always about the
full plant and that's our that's our
moral compass in some ways right there
without the whole plant that isn't doing
what it's really capable of doing and
when Madame canoli says let's let the
plant grow to to the place where it
grows wild then we're now back into this
total conversation with nature with our
bodies with our awareness and the plant
is talking to us like it always has been
talking to us but the idea that THC is
going to tell you what's going to happen
is a completely erroneous assumption
it's really all about what the flavor is
and I'll throw in one more thing about
aged cannabis vintage cannabis people
don't even want anything more than three
months old
I say we never got anything until it was
eight months old in the past whether it
came from Mexico or Thailand vintage
cannabis is really where it's at and
I'll shut up now and let everybody else
talk I thank you for saying that both
Swami and um
etn like that is definitely kind of the
new challenge or the the challenge right
now for me is
explaining to everybody that it's not
just about these high THC percentages
and it's about the the broad spectrums
of beautiful cannaboids and tpin because
when you have more of that you know I
prefer something with a with a you know
higher tpine and lower THC you know even
different cannaboids and it like you get
this like when you smoke something
almost wild like I remember when I was
smoking Thai you know stuff from
Thailand I I I felt like this overall
well-being this like like like elated
like I don't get that you know when I
when I came here I I was just high like
I was just super high like Beyond High
um and I think that due to selective
breeding we've we we we you know bred
towards those high THC percentages so we
really shot ourselves in the foot in a
sense and we have a lot of work to do to
make up for it and that's kind of my
challenge as what Frenchie kind of like
passed down to me is this next this next
challenge of educating the generations
under me because that is my job now and
uh that is my generation's job is to
make sure that we're leaving behind
we're first getting a consensus on the
language that we are using the
vocabulary that we are using and then
second to to Really to really educate
like you guys are saying educate
everybody on the beautiful the the the
totality of the beauty of this plant and
all the cannaboids and all the turbines
but so I was talking to Derek from the
ganier program we had a lovely dinner um
just a couple weeks back on Valentine
near Valentine's Day and I was asking
him you know Frenchie in order to get
people to really understand and and to
get people to love it one thing he
taught me was you have to get people to
smoke it and he was like baby that's
what we do we smoke people out we smoke
them out all day and that is what we did
we smoked people out and you can just
see their eyes light up you could just
see the oh my God you know just the like
yes it's good right and and boom you
know they were just experienced
something they never experienced before
time and time and time again and that is
one of the most profound ways that I
found that that really Ed that can
really share it even even to people who
don't smoke they can they can look at it
and appreciate it but my challenge is is
they took that away from
us they took that opportunity away from
me so I was asking Derek Derek what is
it g to take like how do we bring that
back like what happened because we were
chilling we you know everyone had their
rigs out I know Co I get that I I
totally totally get that I really really
do but I mean what happened all of a
sudden all of a sudden it's legal now
now every body can't be smoking all
around like what what changed you know
be taxes money you know it all comes
down to that every single time but
Derek's point was he said something
profound that really stuck with me and
he said that it comes down
to um it comes down
to to change you know to the low to the
small groups and getting a consensus
amongst a lot of small groups then those
small groups become big groups you get
the attention of your small local
government you Chang things in your town
you Chang things in your little city and
then you change things in your county
and the more counties that jump on board
then you change things in your state and
then your state changes and then other
states start to change it's a lot of
work we have so much work ahead of us it
was a little overwhelming to be quite
honest but I that's where I'm at is is
coming back to sharing this together
smoking this together there's something
about being in a circle there's a reason
why a hook is passed in a circle you
know there's a reason why Chillum is
passed in a circle a circle is a
continuous flow of energy it's a
continuous flow of of communication you
know and and it brings us back together
and and and together looking at each
other being in that present moment
together rather than our phones you know
away you know smoking together is you
know it's it's it's probably some of my
closest friends in the whole world um um
and I I want to bring that back and
that's kind of my challenge right now is
bringing that back and and educating
people and and and really sharing the
beauty of it's not just about these high
THC percentages it's not about it being
clear it's not about any of that um but
yeah so um yeah I welcome I welcome
ideas you know how how are we G to bring
the smoking back
guys
please Belle that's I mean you're that's
everything you're saying is so amazing
and it's so true I mean what what you
know as a farmer um and and first of all
i' just like to you know acknowledge
that that that you and Frenchie and Lena
and and we hear so much about you know
it all comes from the farmer and I just
want to to take that back and say that
it really all does come from the land
and that's what I see it's like it's
it's the soil it's the fungus it's the
the the microbes it's everything it's
the the place the environment um
honestly I I get I I'm really I I i'
like to have humility about that because
it's like as Farmers if we're doing what
we should be doing we're just really
providing the space for the plant to
interact with the place and the soil so
um but to what you're
saying this is what legalization has
done is completely
disassociated the consumers with with
that and with that connection and and
it's just really bad policy and there's
so much work to do and and we and and
this is something that origin's council
is really taking a lead on and working
to you know there's you know we we are
not able to smoke people out like we're
not able to bring we're literally
prohibited from bringing people to our
farms and smoking them out like that is
against the law which is just absolutely
absurd and um that is the big work that
we need to to do is is change the way
that this legalization is so that we can
have smoking circles and have events
that you know there's talk about Farmers
Market events but so far what we have in
California there is no such thing as a
real Farmers Market it's like it's it's
a it's a fake Farmers Market because a
farmers market is where you as the
farmer have your product on the table
and you can share it and just like at a
at a actual vegetable Farmers Market you
can cut up an apple and give somebody a
slice and then they're right there
talking to you and it's coming from your
hand and you can tell them about where
you grew it and what was special about
that place and um and that is lacking
right now and it's not it's not lacking
because um I don't believe that it's
lacking because somebody forgot to put
that in regulation this is like the way
of the corporate world is to
intentionally remove the consumer from
that connection and uh
it's it's it's daunting and overwhelming
but we have to keep the faith and
educate and um and you know dragonfly
with the work you're doing around the
world that's part of the education
um it's there's so much more work to do
and so I'm all ideas too but you know it
it's a bummer that as Farmers I find
that we have to become so engaged in
policy and this stuff that really is not
where we want to be doing but if we
don't nobody else is doing it and it's
just going to you know this problem will
continue to compound and and I see in
the chat you know we've got
conversations happening internationally
and and with legalization and it's all
it's there's a part of me that's so
scared of US Federal legalization
because it's like they're just going to
keep [ __ ] it up worse
and um we have to we have to stay super
engaged aged and and that is hard work
for a bunch of farmers and hash makers
but we're the only ones really preaching
this and so you know keep it up
everybody it feels to me sometime like
this is like greater than just us as a
community this is something that's so
deep because our shared connection to
the plant goes back to the point before
we were even a thought in Consciousness
you know that ha having humans develop
with an endocannabinoid system with a
plant that existed 26 million years
before we did you know there's something
that just it would be wrong to not fight
for this and for this understanding that
it you know that the plant is
encouraging community and human
connection and I don't know
conversation because without that you
know the way forward this kind of
militaristic model that we find
ourselves in is not viable and we see
that it's not taking us to a place of
overall overall well- beingness like B
mentioned before that was one of
Frenchie's favorite words of describing
his experience of Canabis if it wasn't
making you feel overall in a really good
place then then something was not right
with it um I think also the hookah that
multi-host hookah we were in Denver once
at an event and I was standing next to a
guy it was the first time he had ever
smoked the hookah and he turned to me
and he said this is like sharing a lum
with four people you know that he was
smoking with at the same time that it
was just such a profound experience for
him and maybe that's more of what we
need is those opportunities to get
together and pass the smoke and have
conversations like we're doing now
because that grounds Us in community and
uh it I just think it's an important
pass forward that's part of why I
advocate for you all so
much thank you so much uh you know we we
we all of us are the Entourage effect in
human form that are here to heal
Humanity so it's interesting how that
biodiverse effect just continues to show
itself in our soils in humanity in the
medicine and honestly you know that's
part of our big mission out here that
we're we're using Frenchie and this this
this Spirit to EMB body change we have
Alice
here from Brazil go ahead and say
something I love you all so
much much love to all of you and to
Frenchie which was the key to bring
education to all of us I think if
there's something that sums up his work
is the way he educated people and the
way he multiplied education and the way
he never held information behind and he
just wanted to share so we could
multiply and we could all smoke more
know more and actually be a real part of
the hash history it's not only about the
past right it's what we're doing right
now so there is time to change and if we
all stay together and keep together like
fren always said for us to be and
brought everyone together right he
brought all these amazing people B I
love you so much Frenchie brought me you
Lena Kim like I love you all so much and
thank
you and another thing I just wanted to
say is that we're all talking about you
know continuing to push forward
legalization in a way that um helps the
farmer helps the community and one way
that really helps cannabis is to
continue to push forward hom
Growers that all of the education that
we're doing is that cannabis is in every
single backyard that apartment complexes
have small little cannabis Gardens that
have some tomatoes and some zucchini
that's growing there we're seeing that
here there's Community Gardens that
people are utilizing and if we continue
to bring that education forward through
Federal legalization we know that it's
going to get [ __ ] up for the farmers
for the for even the consumers but we're
going to be able to have the capability
to consume our own flour to consume our
own concentrates and when we are doing
that and we are pushing the education
forward then people are truly being
healed by getting down in soil they're
breathing the soil microbes that right
there is going to help them create
better decisions for the plant and then
and then the plant that they're going to
grow is going to be in communication
with that person the entire time and
there's DNA that's swapped there's
energy there's frequency that's swapped
and we really believe that the best
medicine in the world is the one that
you grow yourself and also you know
making your own nutrients and making
your own soil and really using your
environment is the ultimate way to
create terroir and Appalachia so and
Frenchie really agreed with that that
just having a pot and soil that's bought
at the store and using botal nutrients
it will never give you any type of
unique flavor or Terra water or or
anything for your area so really a big
part of the mission that we are all on
is teaching people how to make their own
nutrients teaching people how to make
their own soil you know teaching Homer
home Growers how to make their own sift
you know this is the way we engage with
our power and how we use cannabis as um
the opportunity that it is cannabis
could be treated industrial and more
like a prisoner or it could be treated
more freely like a gift to us we could
make clothes and oil and food and
medicine so I just want to encourage us
to continue that nature aspect of of
creating the Cannabis and as
legalization it can be done indoors in a
way where there's regenerative style
techniques used and uh you know that's
uh important it's a best Outdoors but if
you're doing it indoors you can still do
it by using local environmental uh
inputs for your for your farm
I'd like to jump in for a minute uh I
haven't been saying much I've been
listening a lot and I really appreciate
the
uh uh the beauty of this conversation
and one of the reasons that I feel
compelled to speak is that
uh we we meet because of Frenchie in his
work and and Madame canoli the way you
have uh gotten this film uh to the
attention of so many folk is great um uh
but I it struck me to say that
um we
have the dragonfly Earth medicine family
representing ideal uh if in my opinion
uh practices towards creating the best
versions of the cannabis plant in terms
of the health and vitality of the plant
itself and as a medicine maker and other
medicine makers know you get the best
medicine whatever medicine means to you
from the cannabis plant from the best
Farms the best cultivation practices
produce the best medicine and uh you can
make medicine from mediocre product but
it's not going to be what it could have
been and stewardship to the Earth
there's a um a respect for the earth and
the importance of the fungal kingdoms
and the diversity that comes in a
regenerative Garden uh and so deep
respect for that if you will for the
roots of this conversation and meantime
it is Hash church so we are all about
concentrating the results of that work
and
um uh
and you know mad respect for the folk
who I mean I'm sitting in a in a in a in
the office spaces of a a local hash
maker doing dry sift little commercial
quick uh fluesy long time uh
uh flores's been doing the work in uh
with awareness of CBD oil and the needs
of patients long enough that Harry the
owner and friend uh at one time uh
created and owned the domain name
cbdoil.com
which was a while ago and he sold it
years ago uh but uh yeah that's how long
he's been doing it as long as I have
probably um and he's he's a longtime
resident up here uh and meantime my
friend Sweet Leaf Joe's dropped by but I
want to go I want to finish through the
cycle here of of my thoughts on this
conversation today because not only do
we
have beautiful cultivators respect to
the planet best product made for the
Manu facturers to turn that into a
product that's suitable for use and
people like Dr Mark keeping track of
what's going on with the manufacturing
processes ensuring best results again
for the end user and it's on us at some
point to educate the public about why
THC numbers are such a terrible way of
finding best product for your own
needs um and and the last part of my mad
ramble I'm almost done I promise
is there's also this component uh
represented on the professional level by
eten and his work at Berkeley patience
group uh uh I thought uh I saw that uh
Alex Dixon might join the our group
today but uh I run into him he's on the
board with Valerie Corral uh down in
Santa Cruz uh uh and again Sweet Lea Joe
and myself uh have for years been about
making sure those who really need
cannabis if you will the very end of the
supply chain being discussed here
today and the beauty of
this we have the bases covered if you
will and I think the one whole in it is
we really do have to help the
consumer uh particularly folks who are
new to cannabis to understand that
cannabis has so many different
properties so many different
possibilities and a lot of it has based
on what does your body
need anyway um deep gratitude for the
Gathering today and deep gratitude
Frenchie for calling upon us to respect
the the generations going back you know
has been said thousands of years um and
uh not all of the changes that uh have
happened have been to the best of the
cannabis plant itself I I at one point I
thought that our focus on THC had
created an
imbalanced overloaded branch of the
possibilities that the cannabis plant
represents and I'm sure if skunkman Sam
had been been able to join us today he
would call me out [ __ ] on that and
uh I will stop there and I would like to
give Joe a chance to say hello and I do
have to observe that it has snowed a
couple up times down here in town and I
live 800 ft in elevation higher than
where I'm sitting at the moment so in
respect to my well-being and my wife's
very
strong respectful love filled
request I might have to step out
early Joe hi everyone I'm sweet leaf Joe
the founder and director of The Sweet
Leaf Collective um
we help lowincome terminally ill
patients veterans people of color the
lgbtq community seniors we basically all
underserved demographics we help access
free medical cannabis and we've been
doing this since 1996 we're California's
oldest cannabis brand and um yeah just
wanted to to come and check this out
Wade invited me today and I like also
what Wade was talking about too you know
it is important to protect small
business and the cultivators and all of
the strains but the other part of the
picture is protecting access to those
who can't afford it because as we saw in
2019 when compassion programs Health
Equity and cannabis nonprofit shut down
in
California due to
taxation people died so there's a human
cost when people do not have access to
free medical cannabis and they cannot
afford it so that's my little
feel and I'll just lean in and say I uh
I first ran into Joe's work back in the
90s um I was very very just beginning my
professional work with cannabis myself
but I was doing volunteer work for a
group called The Shanti project who was
um all about helping
people dying of
AIDS that's how I first met Joe and you
can probably tell I had a number of
friends who were doing the same who were
dying from AIDS and uh my thing was uh
providing emotional support and uh
caregiving I want real deal people it's
important
work thank you for being also the
leaders I mean you're three years older
than BPG and we're 23 years old and
people like oh that's crazy for a
dispensary and it's like well we learned
from the collectives and you one of the
original collectives so I want to give a
shout out to not only one of the the
oldest but one of the most enduring and
uh we continue to support and uh will
always continue to support those because
uh I'm a patient myself as a veteran and
uh that saved my life and unfortunately
a lot of these dispensary owners
nowadays aren't patients and don't
understand the reality or the
um the responsibility that we carry to
do things right and responsible which is
why we worked with people who were doing
it right who were doing it with
Integrity like Frenchie like Joe like
Wade and others who are there to not
only do it right but to take the time to
educate you on on why it should be done
right and not only do we explain it by
living at as an example day in and day
out waking up tomorrow and getting up
and doing it again planning today for
tomorrow so that that hash or that
cannabis is ready so that that patient
because that patient is coming tomorrow
for that cannabis expecting that
cannabis for them and Joe's right people
died unfortunately and we had to fight
within our own State uh to to have
compassionate giving and we're going to
have to fight again and band together
again here in another year to go Lobby
to change the law again so that we can
continue to give free cannabis to those
that are in need and this is something
the other states have to realize and I
hope the audit that's about to happen in
Canada since you're coming up on your
five years there uh that you know
compassionate giving and medical
cannabis can stand the test of time
because it's now legal since December of
2020 and I'm working with the group the
veterans Action Council will actually be
in um Vienna uh we have representatives
and we have another side event at the 66
CND where we're working toward
legalization for adult used by
2029 and we believe that's a possibility
so that no one will be executed around
the world for cannabis ever again so uh
we're we're at the local state federal
and we're at the international level
and when the galactic level decides to
call us up we'll be there and ready to
push cannabis into the Galaxy further so
again humbled and honored to be here and
thank you Wade and thank you of course
Sweet Leaf Joe for your Decades of
leadership and uh humble ability to
navigate the very difficult Waters that
it takes to get the Cannabis to get it
to people for free and the logistics
that go in between nothing but mad
respect and
love you just made me realize uh at and
there is a milestone to be had who will
be the first person to smoke hash in
space who will be that person and who
will grow that hash yeah well Kimberly
as you know sometimes they bring me in
on hash Church to break down all the
science that happens in in hash and in
cannabis and yeah this this unfortunate
thing about needing to know the percent
THC in a plant material that
produces all this other stuff and it it
produces THC produces thca actually
right so when we smoke it it converts it
to THC and the difficulty about taking a
Botanical and Quant ifying the amount of
an active ingredient on there is that
the Botanical itself has a lot of
moisture content and in order to provide
an accurate assessment the
standardization is usually to report the
amount of a chemical substance in a
plant based on dried weight based on the
dry weight of the plant material so it's
been completely dried so the challenge
at the Laboratories is well
the Cannabis they're getting is not is
not dried right so they have to dry it
so let's talk about that for a second so
when you dry something you're going to
put it in a vacuum and you're going to
heat it up well gee what happens to
cannabis when you heat it up right
there's the volatilization of the tpes
and as well as the loss of the water I
mean it's it's even known now that some
of these Labs because they're trying to
crank through as many samp as they can
one of the knobs that they can turn here
is they turn up the temperature right
that way they can process more samples
because the more samples the lab
processes the more money the lab makes
right so when they turn up the heat
guess what happens to the cannaboid
acids they
decarbox turn into THC right so now what
you're putting into the hlc to measure
the the canabo content on is not only
been dry but it's been detered it's been
decarbox and it's difficult when each
individual lab has a different
sop that's doing this process right so I
think the difficulty has always been the
reproducibility between labs and there's
lawsuits in states where producers it's
this THC inflation to be able to get
their stuff into the market and and at
and knows when there's wholesale
exchanges you know what is the what's
the metric well it looks good it looks
really good well hell I was talking to a
guy who is in Washington Square Park
bought something in New York City that
thought it looked good didn't get them
high at all it's probably just sprayed
hemp right he's buying it from a weed
truck where there used to be food trucks
now there's weed trucks in New York
City it's just it it's a metric that
not the right thing and we were talking
about this Marcus with Jeremy and that
group that came out with that paper the
nose nose which I think is one of the
most fascinating papers that I've read
in the open uh cannabis literature which
again puts the emphasis not on THC
content and not typically on on like
tpine content like you can't look at one
tpine as one instrument in this
Orchestra right you're listening to this
Orchestra play this beautiful music and
you can't just isolate one tpine and say
wow it's kopine I need a krya offline
dominant or Lon it's it's the way that
they play this music together and and
these are just the turpins that we can
see are the ones that are analyzed in
the laboratory there's a whole host of
turpins and as was uh graciously pointed
out earlier non-terpenoid molecules like
the uh the sulfur containing molecules
Marcus right we had these discussions
about these new
volatile as it turns out those those
thols are
actually um uh a sulfur compounds but
they're they're prenol they're prated
sulfide so they are derived from
isoprene so essentially they are uh
thiolated or sulfur containing compounds
but their starting material kid you not
is isoprene which is the same starting
material that all tpin are derived from
so I'll stop by just saying it is so
difficult in this age of prohibition
ending and commercial production
happening without having some sort of
metric and until we figure out this
issue about how to standardize there are
standardization methods but when you
take a wet cannabis flower so everything
that we smoke in our pipe or everything
that we would make hash out of it's not
it's not on a dried weight basis right
and when you convert that sample in a
laboratory to a dried weight basis
you've just not only lost all your water
you've lost all your tpin you've lost
all your aldhy THS all these other
compounds that we don't know about and
you've decarbox your turpine so what
you're putting into your hpo machine is
no representation of what you're bu
Mark let me bud in for there's our
friend I just wanted to mention that you
can uh bring your moisture level down to
practically zero with the with the
desiccator so without heat no heat at
all and that preserves the majority of
the Turpin right the problem with that
though Sam is and you bring up a really
great Point there's a couple
presentations out on the Internet by a
researcher named Jenny Curry g i uh j i
n i c r r y and she's an analytical
chemist who works at a Testing Lab who's
given a couple presentations on this
recently and you're absolutely right Sam
the problem is is that if you're going
to do desiccation it takes overnight
overnight that lab is not making enough
money to run those samples maybe if you
had a hundred desiccators cuz we used a
glass one that held about I don't know
maybe 50 grams maximum and it took at
least one day to uh because we were
storing it at maybe uh I don't know uh 8
10% moisture so we you still had to get
rid of the rest of it right but it's
fair to say though Sam right that if
you're desiccating and you're removing
some of the moisture you are probably
going to be losing some of your most
volatile compounds in that loss that's
one thing it depends what the room
temperature is if the room temperature
is fairly low then no that doesn't
happen but also I wanted to mention that
the thols I'm doing some tests
now some pure
thca and I'll be
using uh some of the fils that were
given to me to test the see if they can
either modulate or potentiate THC the
way some of the tpes can I'm sure they
will I'm not sure but I'm curious as
hell well I love like the the garlic
essence of like some of the hazes and I
think that there is something to that
beyond the gas essence you know but
those guys actually have developed kind
of like the the the the gas scale based
on some of the volatile Tarpin that
they've or volatile sulfides that
they've identified yeah and the one that
I got is the one that they suspect is
the most likely and also that uh is the
most potent I mean you you you're
talking about the tiniest amount on a
pin head it can stink up the whole room
for like days
and how is your wife uh loving that Sam
well I I haven't taken it out yet when I
do it I'll do it out on my balcony good
call good call well welcome to uh our
celebration of Frenchie skunkman Sam
it's been uh too long excuse me I was
just uh meditating on my puffco and uh I
spaced it out the
time on your puffco or your Magna
Carta well I'm not using my Magna cardi
yet I don't have it in my hands so I'm
using the puffco and uh I'll try to make
the card as soon as I get
one is somebody talking or no so we were
telling stories about Frenchie do you
have any stories about Frenchie Sam well
Frenchie and I had a very very close uh
relationship he wanted to use more
science to prove you know the various
theories and feelings he had about
hashish and uh I I encouraged him in
every way that I could to uh to do so I
I think right when uh at the time he
died he had done some recent work where
they they were taking hashish and then
pressing it rubbing it and uh storing it
for you know 3 months 6 months nine
months to see what happens to the canono
inter turpine profiles because uh you
know he he had a lot of feelings that
new turpins were created or there was
something going on and uh I I wasn't so
sure about the new tpin but I says the
way to answer the questions is with
science and so he he's it took him a
couple years to get it together but he
was doing it right when uh unfortunately
uh he left us yeah that was studies that
he did with high North labs in
Toronto um and it was just the initial
uh study to kind of establish the
Prototype and figure out uh the protocol
sorry um how to do the longer term study
and so that's something that I to fund
in the future as well because Frenchie
had the experience you know one of the
things they would do when they would go
back year after year in the mountains
with the Italians that were up there
with him because it was just a couple
French people and some Italians back in
the day that really went to the areas
that he was at before they would go down
to Goa for the winter you know when the
snow would hit up there they would leave
a little bit of the chus that they had
made that year they would bury it
underground so that they would have
something to smoke as soon as they came
back up and they would have these little
G togethers and over the years you know
once he had been doing this for five six
years there were Italians that had been
there 10 years before him he started
smoking hat that was 8 10 12 years old
and really had this you know kind of
amazing experience of how good this aged
charas I should say it was Char charas
was and that kind of plan the seed in
his brain of there was this whole area
in the commercial Marketplace that was
still open for development around aging
hashish and I think being French and
having the experience you know the
culture there with aging wine or certain
alcohols that are that are aged and
develop a a different profile and
expression with the passage of time that
was something that was really
interesting for interesting to him
and of course he loved talking with all
of you who have the scientific
background because he really felt that
the ancestors they intuitively knew
something because of what they had
learned generation after generation you
know working with people he would asked
them in those traditional cultures why
do we do this thing and the answer was
always because it makes a better hashish
because it makes a better charas they
couldn't explain the science but they
knew what they knew because because they
had paid attention to the plant and
their their parents or their
grandparents had passed the knowledge on
and he really wanted to be able to
validate their their understanding
through modern science and uh and yeah
leave that with the
world well I'm I'm in favor of cannabis
science that has been my life and uh I I
I encourage him in every way I could to
to we we both had a deep deep love of
hashish uh I I had very slight uh
different feelings for example I and I
think uh Marcus also likes this prefer
unpressed dry sifted resin uh it I don't
know there's just something about it
that I like a little bit better but uh
uh for any sort of long time
preservation uh I I would strongly
recommend pressing it like uh like
uh everybody else uh around me
does I just like to say too you know the
other thing that Frenchie used to
comment on a lot was how um hard we
are like one person's preference to
another sometimes within the concentrate
uh community and he used to say you know
it's so funny you never hear a tequilo
drinker trashing a CNAC consumer for
their choice and he would be the first
person to say you know bless whatever
you want to consume if you should
consume what makes you feel good and
what meets your needs and your
preferences but that there shouldn't be
this judgment against another person
because they want you know so in the
case of Frenchie he loved the
traditional pressed and even aged
hashish he wasn't going to say that he
didn't think you should not smoke your
unpressed loose live resin by any means
you know um so I just would like to
throw out I think we need more tolerance
that would
be what I was talking about actually
wasn't live resin it's dried plants it's
been dried for two weeks it's been cured
for a couple of months then you dry sift
it and then you smoke it as unpressed
pollen that's it it's very slight
difference but uh it it's different and
I agree different smokes for different
folks whatever turns your crank is
what's good for you as long as it's
clean and safe for the consumer but you
let 1,000 ideas
Bloom uh just in the spirit of aged
resin we have a a traditional ball here
that mean Jean gave to us and it's N9
years old it's got to be I don't know je
maybe if mean Jean's out there he can
say exactly how old it was but it's it's
probably over nine years now we did add
some other stuff in it there but it's
very beautiful we've been smoking snakes
out of it in into the joints right now
and uh we all really love smoking
hashish like this is it dry or is it
water hash dry sifted do you know water
hash water hash yeah yeah and uh it it
would have been nice if you could have
analyzed it uh nine years ago and uh
every five years or so along this trail
that I'm I'm very curious about
that we would like to do that as well we
have some preco hash also from uh 2019
Mendo breath which is kind of fun
and uh you know we can uh give that a
test and if you have some we can talk to
High North because we work with high
North out in Ontario from our British
Colombian farm and uh maybe we can do
some of that testing that would be fun
to do we're going to keep it you know in
a cool dry place in a good container and
all that but I know when I did uh
storage uh studies in my laboratory
years ago when I was busy working uh I
found that cannabis after one or two
years of just storage in boxes in the
dark and cool room uh lost the majority
of its tpping but it canabo profile was
still identical whereas dry sifted
resin uh also it loses the majority of
its turpins and it'll start to turn from
like a a golden uh T sand colored to a
almost red reddish color just from the
oxidation of the uh
THC yeah I've got some red uh pass right
here actually that
um I can show it real quick here get to
the different view this piece of hash is
is 13 years old that's in
here 13 person that I know would do that
is Kenny from Tricom technology he would
uh whip out
I mean literally 15 20 different
varieties two years old just to show you
the difference in the flavors Etc and
there's definitely uh the that the uh
yeah it's
definitely um for sure uh it's
definitely couch lock kind of hash for
sure but definitely you could tell the
tpin all that were were definitely gone
you really had to get in there to get
any type of flavor and the flavor really
didn't come out until until it was
actually lit so not many people I know
in America will actually age hash but
not many people I know would do that
many hashes that many years that he
likes to do but to also like Sam what he
was doing to see the differences and
what the changes that transpire happen
but uh yeah
it's couch lock yeah you can only you
can only cure for so long although you
know this this particular hash which is
you know almost 14 years old now it
still has an incred flavor it has almost
no smell it smells almost stale which is
like what I've seen from resin that's in
the you know almost 15 to 20 year s Sam
used to have some really old resin as
did one of his partners he wasn't
necessarily curing it as much as
preserving it but it was I was doing
that was at minus 30 Centigrade and it
was I sucked all the oxygen away from it
for long-term storage and then it kept
and the tpin were kept everything was
really really nice but if you're not
super careful about your long-term
storage of dry sifted resin for example
then uh yeah it it it definitely changes
and there is a point of diminishing
returns did Frenchie freeze his once he'
had it piece pressed and he wanted to
keep it for a few years would he would
he freeze it or store it at room
temperature temp he would store it in
the basement almost like a wine seller
because he was interested in kind of the
transformation what was happening with
the Turpin and whatnot over time but in
the study that he wanted to do like you
have done he wanted to have some that
was stored at very very cold conditions
and then you know kind of like three
different temperatures yeah no that
that's exactly what you need to do for
science
so Lebanon was Notorious for producing
red hashish but to my knowledge they're
no longer producing red hash today but I
believe their drying methodologies are
the same so what's different now uh it
had soil uh I was able to get uh uh
Lebanese when I was in Saudi Arabia for
the Gulf War oops um and uh I was able
to trade with epod and uh I got it and
it was a little dry and brittly it was
compact it would come in Long uh thin
slats and uh yeah it was just red and it
didn't have a right flavor to it but
from what I'm told that's just from the
the dust of the
soil absolutely red soil makes lebanes
red it may not be the only reason but
it's the majority of the reason iron
silicate
[Music]
um I think part of the uh the problem
with the Lebanon is that there's it's
just become like extremely punishable
there and I we we were just talking with
a a cannabis man from Lebanon in a
coffee shop in Amsterdam and they come
out here because any anything they do
there
is it's just really hard to get around
in Lebanon right now especially after
the bomb and that whole thing and even
this is Mick back here from gwa and he
he's saying that a lot of the
traditional nice to meet you guys a lot
of the traditional hash that's going
around here 95% of it coming from
Morocco at this
moment yeah that's that's what's
flooding Europe is Morocco and most of
it is about the best you can get is z z
which uh they take 100 kilos of dried
plants and they make at least two kilos
of uh collected resin from it and I know
cuz I tried that double zero that you
gave to to Ed at positronics back in 96
and that was the first and only time I
ever had that and when you snapped it it
you used a knife and it clicked just
like glass I remember that sound and I
remember smoking that and that was
lights out some of the most amazing uh
hash I've ever ever had that's because
it was anywhere from 70% resin heads to
hire I I don't remember that particular
piece but uh you know when I made it for
gifts it was usually uh you know 70 80%
resin
heads I I I remember being laying on and
I went around and did all the different
hash places in Amsterdam and I just
remember laying on the bench there at
patronic staring at the sky and um I
when I left I had just one little gram
left and I ate it and I remember Landing
in New York and trying to walk toward
the Customs guy and everything was in
slow motion my wife said I was fine but
I was [ __ ] lit out of my [ __ ] mind
and I don't know how I made it through
there but you know the universe was kind
to me and uh yeah it was yeah still
without a doubt one of those memories
that stick in my mind and that's due to
you and due to real dou
zero we had conversations with Frenchie
about going on a tour in in
Kimberly in Morocco and visiting Farms
because he was saying that a lot of the
Farms there were just not growing in a
way that he thinks is best for the resin
and that he felt like the local
cultivation could be you know done
better for their local
cultivation and uh you know they use the
beaten Sith technique there and there's
also like interesting to see how the
beaten sift technique that's come into
like bags here in Barcelona you can get
beaten sipped bags you know and make
hash the Moroccan way and it is it's
less heads but you can still make really
beautiful you know kind of Patties or or
big think pressed hash which is
beautiful to smoke in ganja dues or
tobacco which a lot of people do here um
but uh the beaten sift technique is
interesting and I don't see it as much
at home um because the pure resin heads
are better for dabbing and it doesn't
make sense to have a 70% heads but the
tpping ratio on it is in a way a lot
higher some and also I was thinking Josh
just mentioned Morocco that was
definitely something that Frenchie and
we were dreaming about because he would
talk about Morocco and sort of get stars
in his eyes and say oh we got to teach
him biomass we've gotta go back and
retach him there are people up in the
hills who are still doing it properly
and that passion to bring you know the
old world practices and the old world
techniques even to the people who were
their still even the people who have
lost it he was still out there teaching
them their old ways or reintroducing
their old ways
and just really thinking about that and
dreaming about that and how that's one
of my greatest dreams to get out to
Morocco because he just talked about it
so much I I feel like I have to
go honest I shout out to Marcus because
it was actually and having bubble bags
which brought an ideal to people at the
different size screens mattered I mean
has literally uplifted the quality of
hash now granted there's different
people who have knocked off what Marcus
has done but regardless that type of
understanding that different types of
flowers produce different size Micron
size you know flowering tops I mean it
mattered and it still matters and I just
want to thank bubbl man and the others
who use that technology that has risen
the quality all the way around because I
know uh fren she used those bags and was
very successful in helping him get at
the Quality so the technology standards
have also helped raise the standards
outright so I just want to bring back to
thank Marcus for his ingenious uh time
and place in the hash history to uh move
things forward because we wouldn't be
where we are if that understanding in
itself wasn't out there for people and
it really
matters but you know kind of
piggybacking on what you just said about
um going to Morocco I think we have a we
kind of owe them a debt because we
brought these cultiv ours that really
were not suited to the local ter there
and now they're needing to use more
water they're having problems with pet
they're having all kinds of issues that
they didn't have in the in the past and
I I think you know we do we do owe them
uh some help in in seeing that maybe
they should let things go back or you
know use cultivars that are more adapted
to the environment there and not try to
change the environment it's kind of like
I'm seeing pictures of people doing ice
waterer
in the Himalayas you know where in
traditional Chas cultures in
environments that are very humid and not
suited to drying the material after it's
been washed and so I just would love for
people in these traditional environments
to understand that just because we're
doing something in Northern California
in one way that suits the climate the
environment that we have here that it's
not necessary going to be the perfect
fit and that maybe what they have
traditionally is what the world needs
and not for them to replicate what we
what we have I don't think we've always
done the best service by trying to
replace the the original genetics that
were in these producing
countries agree agree you want to say
anything talking about I just think it's
beautiful to see traditions and
Technology get together you know
we all here and Frenchie and all of you
honor so much the tradition but we can't
deny where we live in right we live in
the world where is I mean we live in the
present and I think it's beautiful like
Belle's work is completely uniting also
tradition and Technology honoring the
tradition and honoring the different
colors of P the different amounts of
plant matter that can be in that hash
and um I went
Miracle eight years ago and then now and
then in just in brief eight years I
could see the big change in Traditions
to technology I I know that people here
in Europe probably know way more about
me than that but for the first time
people in the street were trying to sell
things to me talking about the
Micron before eight years ago they were
not talking about what Micron that was
made they were showing me some
strawberry banana bars and a bunch of
them come to ear come here to Barcelona
too but they were showing all these
different kinds of genetics so of course
it's beautiful for us to um think of a
world when it's untouched but
globalization somehow happened and
that's what we have nowadays uh I just
hope we keep honoring tradition that we
just don't develop just technology and
forget about the tradition so both
directions are
important both both directions are
important to have to keep our Roots but
to grow up towards the St you know it's
uh it it's it's important to have them
both and I'll tell you there was several
years where I would take some I we made
some incredible water hash with Dr
Atomic he brought some of his flowers
over to my house and we made some he
brought like three or four pounds of
flour when flour was worth $3,000 a
pound and said whatever let's just make
some nice bubble hash with it and I took
that bubble has to Bob Marley's birthday
bash in Kingston Jamaica that year and
he took it to Nepal for the Shiva ratri
and everyone we shared it with and
everywhere we shared it with he actually
put it on a plate at a celebration of
hash in at shivar ratri in in in
Katmandu and it was the People's Choice
it was the Bubba's choice of hash for
that evening it was the one that no one
could get over no one could believe of
course they weren't you know dissing
their traditional hashes but they had
just never seen any anything like this
this was six-star full melt bubble and
they were smoking it in chillums in a
cave in in in catmandu and it was just
uh and and very similar experience
happened in Jamaica I smoked it with a
variety of rasta farai from different
tribes and I also uh not only smoked it
but we put it in the steam pipe as well
so it was vaporized and it was uh it's
neat to
see we couldn't have what we have today
without those Traditions so it's kind of
like by creating something new you're
really paying homage to the tradition
because you couldn't you're you're a
step in a ladder and you couldn't take
that step without all the steps before
you and if there's no steps after you
well then the ladder ends and that's uh
that's sort of a sad thought as well so
I think one of our most important steps
recently has been well by recently I
mean last few decades has been using
simpia to produce water hash or dry sift
and uh yeah that because simpsom and
resin is uh funly fundamentally got more
of what we
want and cleanliness is Next to
Godliness That's all folks in the case
of a Morocco you're definitely seeing
like you know runs and Kush mins and
things coming over from Morocco a lot um
which is like kind of a bummer but also
maybe cool for them because they love
ganja too and they're just exploring
these new flavors as well um there are
definitely uh some regions where you
know I would imagine that the the
Moroccans still you know it's it's a
little bit more land raced but we we
have been talking about going on a trip
this fall um to explore during the hash
times you know to see what's what's
going on out there you you will not find
pure land races in Morocco because all
of the crops are seated and they're
seated by the uh the new multi pooly
hybrid Imports so it the pollen is
everywhere and uh there there are no
pure land races anybody who says so
it's they just don't really understand I
I totally agree and even this cona back
here knows
about higher in the mountains you know
maybe is the best place that you're GNA
find anything that res has no trouble
getting higher in the
mountains zero zero problem first time I
visited Morocco was
1971 and they had only been
growing Keef because they were growing
Keef until about 65 that's when they
first grew
uh hea and they grounded up and made
hash out of it before that they were not
making hash of Morocco it hashish is new
to Morocco ke smoking is hundreds of
years
old and was it true that it was a
Nigerian guy who brought Lebanese
screening techniques to
Morocco uh
that's the story that was told um me and
Rob from the family who was the big wazo
in uh the Riff they had been growing
more and longer uh than anybody else and
uh we talked to the grandfather and he
told us it was an Algerian black guy
Mustafa who who who brought the method
from Algeria and I don't know if was
ever a big producer maybe he had seen it
in Lebanon that I don't know but uh
these people were serious serious when
we were we were introduced to the
younger parts of their family and they
were were helping us do some work there
and but before they would work with us
they wanted the grandfather to meet us
and we had to meet him and we had to be
approved and uh when we walked into the
their their
home above the front door there was a
big giant male plant wrapped into a
circle and hung there like an
uh uh a Christmas
wreath yep that's the other way to do it
is with your
hands Sor I didn't mean to interrupt you
Sam no problem
was that Charis in the
making
absolutely Milana
Val our friend Kush Kirk um in southern
Oregon has dedicated a few plants
completely to making Charis um the last
couple years and it's been really
awesome and it's a fun project and he's
inspired other people to do that so I
think that's a really ever checked out
what the yield is or does he do it from
living plants or does he do it from dry
plants from living just like normal like
he does it from living plants and uh you
can you know ask him exactly what his
yields are they're really good you know
they're way better than the other you
know doing it in the Himalayas or
whatnot because the plants are have
larger crystals you know bigger crystals
and stuff but it's really beautiful hash
and it's traditional and um it's uh it's
so it's
different hey this is we I got to jump
in here for a second uh again I want to
thank the folks that made it possible
for me to come into town floracy this is
some uh Tropic can of cookies and Sam
you might approve this is uh this was
harvested from this Summer's outdoor
Done Right regenerative blah blah all
tiger it's tiger Sky tiger Ranch here in
nada County anyway it's dry sift done
cold lightly pressed to make a uh a yeah
a nice little
package don't know if you can see what's
going on there it's more than a gram but
it's really lovely smoke I I
specifically asked for one of these
because um it works beautifully with my
hand does it have the no heated no all
no water no nothing but screening and
Light press wait does it have the THC
level I'm
curious um
yeah uh how about I it what it's got
here this is you said this is two grams
two grams yeah so it's 9 50% two
grams yeah 980 milligrams in a 2 G
Little P
with a little gold leaf lightning strike
on it so that's like
407 or
48% yeah just shy of 50% Sam yeah yeah
and meantime yeah available in a
dispensary in California I won't get
into price but yeah yeah it when when I
made dry sift that was
99.9% resin heads but about the highest
I ever got was in the low
80s THC and that was from skunk number
one cleaned up absolutely clean and uh
it was uh almost like smoking honey oil
it was
amazing but didn't you prefer your 60%
Sam because I think that was well it's
easier to smoke because when when you
smoke the really really really clean
stuff it wants to drip through screens I
mean it it was it it depends how you
smoke if you smoke it in a vaporizer or
a glass pipe it's not a problem but if
you I I used to smoke in a roar bong
with the three really really fine
screens on it I think you might remember
and if I put the
99.9% on it and I put heat to it it
would leak right through all three
screens the guy who pardon the
interruption the fow who
handed me this at my request points out
that in California to have it in on the
Shelf th000 milligrams in any package
that's why it's
980 okay but then what you could have
done was I'm not saying you should but
you could have made one gram on the
package then 1,000 milligrams it would
have been P THC I'm not I'm not saying
that's better because I don't find it is
I think you need the uh the full Pines
and everything flavor everything else
because that that's way better than uh
pure Crystal
thca I I agree and uh part of why I
needed to jump in is it has started
snowing here um and there was patches of
blue sky but yeah it started snowing
again and like I said uh the difference
in elevation between the town where
there's electricity and internet and
where I live uh is uh 800 feet we live
at about a a th000 meters elevation
3270 ft is what the title says on the
farm but uh yeah there was 5 feet on the
ground Wednesday and today it's down to
about three feet but we're supposed to
get that much more again this week and I
promised I would leave in time to get
home safely so I'm I'm going to sign off
have such deep respect not only for this
group but uh Frenchie and Madame canoli
I I do look forward to seeing the film
at some point soon I haven't my health
has not allowed me to travel very much
in the last year or two since the film
came out but
um uh I'm I I'm healing like many of us
uh it's it's a process life uh and so
thank you all for showing up today and
uh I
I feel like I know every one of you so
well and some of you better than others
but um again deep respect much love and
uh take care of yourselves you're the
only one you
got bye thanks Wade much love brother
yeah forward to the next time maybe sh
for now yeah CH sweet
leave I I app appreci that little
conversation about the dry sift because
it it reminded me that you know this was
um one of the some of the last
conversations that I was having with
Frenchie was about um you know because
he really wanted to have that that
connection to the farm and try to figure
out how to do that also commercially and
and to be able to put something into the
California market and he he was talking
about you know the regulations do ow for
what they call ke and we cannot do ice
waterer hash on the farm without you
know a whole rigamaroo of of Licensing
even though it's nonvolatile and so he
was talking about um you know working on
kind of and and Lena and Belle probably
could fill in the gaps on on where where
he was going with his thought but he was
like wow we should be doing dry seaing
on the farm and then we can press it and
we can have put out a packaged product
that would actually you know come
straight from the farm and have never
had to you know be frozen or or travel
through the distribution chain and um so
it it's neat to see that somebody I
don't know if that was made in a
facility or on site by a farm but um
that's cool to see I've not seen that in
the commercial Market
before one of the Reas they should bring
it back to dry sift sorry Sam I didn't
mean to cut you off but water is is very
difficult um just you know like kind of
the whole fluid Dynamic element behind
it it's expensive to chill water pumps
are expensive to have water um honestly
dry sift is is uh a lot more conducive
really environmentally if if if you
really think about
it the the main thing about dry sift is
the yield is is quite low that you just
get you know one two 3% yield from the
best of the best of the best per kilo
you know that's a
killer and uh but what you can do is if
you have uh a laboratory facility after
you dry shift it theoretically you could
take the rest of the material and do
some sort of an extract either an
alcohol extract or a water extract or
whatever to try to get more because uh
with with dry sifting you're throwing
away 90% of the THC you know that's just
the way it goes you you dry sifting
yields are low water sifting is higher
and of course solvent extraction gets
almost
everything yeah we were trying to figure
out how to do it at scale which is the
difficult part and producing quality at
scale but the goal was to be as close to
the farmer as possible because the less
people who manhandle your product the
better um product you're going to have
on the shelves and we thought we could
do something and like work through the
Maze of Bureau but it turned out to be a
lot more difficult than we originally
thought it definitely is there's there's
there's a number of people I mean Cry
came out with their liquid nitrogen unit
I've never really seen it used but I
have another friend who's been working
on a very similar unit that will
basically go and reduce biomass from the
field direct can be right off fresh
plants it can reduce the you know the
plant matter into just basically sift
and then that sift can then be taken it
would have to be dried because if it's
off of a fresh plant the wax membrane is
going to hold some moisture um so it is
not really dry sift in that sense it's
fresh sift but then being able to use
you know a static uh technique or
something to then clean up the sift I
think it'll happen I think we will see
the day where we can um you know scale
uh sifting to a to a larger scale but uh
it's certainly not easy and it's very
counterintuitive the more you try to get
with screen that's one of the reasons
that's one of the reasons Marcus that we
always try to dry it for a couple weeks
cure it for a couple of months and so we
had raisins rather than grapes you know
reduce that moisture content so you can
work with the resin uh but I know why
people like you know fresh live resins
because they're definitely got more
turps I would just to is hey
Selena
Selena sorry I didn't mean to interrupt
I was like oh my God that's Selena it's
good to see you guys um we have this
incredible dry sift here from Ki and he
can explain it um it's probably some of
the most amazing dry sift you'll find in
Barcelona it's absolutely like
incredibly
flavored and um yeah I mean they are
producing like some really incredible
dry sift material here this is static
static uh static clean and uh zti by
cush Ms right yeah buban inspired me for
a long time know he's been following
bubble man since
2005 and everything that's been coming
out and just you're the original
inspiration brother and here's this
amazing product being put out
organically from the local community
here in a smoking club which it's it's
kind of illegal out there but it's legal
in here so it really is kind of an
embodiment of everything that we're
talking about here did you have
something say a ask him what is the
yield of Clean dry sift where you get it
cleaned up as much as you can with
static because that's I know more than
90% resin heads so what's your yield
from a kilo of
cannabis we you
know static one% and
static okay yeah basically what you're
saying you know one to two% one or two%
okay well I keep for a miracle but dude
I mean the flavor on this is literally
like
I hope to be smoking it in a couple of
days yeah give us the wait to you
bro right
on yeah definitely some of the most
beautiful
resinous you know
odoric uh stuff on the menu has been the
organic dry sift pressed hash here it's
just so incredibly beautiful and then
you have the Aged hashes which you're
just whole other experience for sure so
I actually can't say which one is my
favorite I take it
back they're all they're all
good a lot depends on what the plant
used to make the material
was and how you grew it there's a lot of
sought after hash cultivars in this area
too and it's really cool to see what
people have chosen here you know uh some
of it's from California but a lot of it
also is just hunted and pheno hunted and
created here and that's the funnest
thing about traveling is seeing the
different flavors and techniques used
and uh it's also fun seeing how
different people have been inspired by
one another uh to make these you know
really phenomenal products for people as
the web gets wider The Weave gets
tighter oh yeah time for another dab
well um Frenchie was uh just super
important in the sense of uh I think
passion more than anything like you can
talk about specifics and different hash
and dry sift or age but really it was
ultimately the attraction of his passion
I think that really is the really spirit
that really it's like the spirit that
enters it you know it's you called it
Josh he's he's a
pasen there you
go it's so cool that passion rhymes with
hasion it's just like it just embodies
him 110% because now I think about
passion and I think of passion and then
I think of Frenchie it's just what
happens
now I'm gonna call him a Pas from now on
a new word created we we need to do Mark
is we we need to next time we discover a
new uh turpine we can name it after
Frenchie and call it
Frenching right there there's actually
there there's what there's fench all
that's close to Frenching but right
there's already French all
well fench all benaw yeah
canola there you go
all these new compounds that we don't
know yet but yeah I mean isn't it it's
so cool that you know again we live in
this great page of information there's
so much video content of Frenchie right
like if you just if today's the first
time you've ever heard of Frenchie who's
this guy you got a lot of You Know video
to you know write Kimberly I mean
there's so much content and this movie
I'm sure will maybe give us kind of like
the the
backstage view of of his life and his p
i what are we gonna see in the movie
that those of us who mostly know
Frenchie from just his online Persona
what are we goingon to see in the movie
that we wouldn't necessarily know from
just seeing stuff on YouTube and
stuff you're muted
you did she know
that sorry about that um yeah I was
trying to be respectful when the rest of
you were talking I was gonna say his his
love for the farmer you know just that's
really gonna um come true so so
clearly
um um Kimberly since we're on the topic
would you mind explaining to what like
exactly how the live stream is going to
go down because I've had a couple
questions people ask me you know how you
know how that's going to how they're
going to be able to view that where the
multiple places are that's going to be
live streaming it so the idea is um we
want to have a worldwide celebration of
the film to just create a bunch of noise
and to have an opportunity to come
together after you've all seen the film
on the
29th um so we're planning three
screenings each would be at 700 p.m in
the local time so so first in Europe at
7 pm the film is 90 minutes then after
the film we want to open up a live
stream like this I'll be using a
platform called restream that'll have
the same kind of living room environment
and then that's going to stream to our
Instagram our Facebook our YouTube and
our LinkedIn simultaneously so people
don't have to sign up for a new platform
they can just log on to whatever their
preferred platform is and they'll be
able to access it uh there um and so
then we'll do the same thing again East
Coast time at 7 and then you know so
starting the live stream at 8:30 after
the film and then West Coast times so
you could kind of depend on what your
schedule is if you're free in the
afternoon and you want to hang out when
we do it in Europe you're welcome to
join for Europe if you want to come for
East Coast time welcome to come for East
Coast time and then you know we'll have
that ultimate one on the west W coast
and people are creating um uh ticketed
events in some of the major cities and
I've got that information on the
Frenchie dreams of website um but also
people are going to be doing like their
like ien was saying you know just having
your family and friends together to
watch it in your living room and you
know with your favorite smoking uh
device um so I'm hoping all of you will
join us afterwards in the live stream
and that some of you will join be in
this kind of living room environment and
we can talk about the film we can talk
about what you're smoking I hope a lot
of people will have a um a hookah so
that we can virtually pass the hookah to
each other because that was Frenchie's
kind of preferred methodology to get a
bunch of people together and smoke you
know the hashish if you put the hashish
and the quazar shisha head you know the
low temperature just Vapes the material
forever so great way to have a a party
and um have hashish to smoke forever I
want to do some test um uh events before
then so I'm hoping bill you and I can uh
break out the hookah and show people how
to set up their hookah for smoking with
hashish you can also smoke flour in it
if you prefer to smoke flower um just
thought that would be a fun way for us
all to kind of be United in uh in this
event and this little celebration of the
film on the 29th on April
29th awesome Kimberly thank you for
sharing that and uh we'll put it in the
link as well and I'm sure there'll be
some groups out here in Vancouver that
we'll do some live uh streamings of the
hopefully we'll get book club actually
there's a really cool uh venue here in
um Vancouver that does um a thing called
book club and it's just basically place
for people from the Cannabis Community
to gather and actually like you said
earlier um be able to have conversations
and dialogue I think it's one of the
last most important things missing right
now from Cannabis and Belle mentioned it
earlier about getting together and
smoking it doesn't necessarily have to
be smoking um it can just be consuming
but we need to be able to get together
and have Gatherings and be able to have
these conversations and I've mentioned
it before the way when bars became a
thing pubs with alcohol all the
workingclass people having these drinks
after work and those conversations would
shape the world eventually we would get
coffee H or tea houses next more of an
intellectual group they would gather and
drink their tea and their conversations
would shape the world uh and it happened
as well with coffee and it's going to
happen with cannabis as well and it's
the one thing they seem to be holding
back from us even in Canada Federal
legalization big Whoopi we don't even
aren't even allowed to have vapor
lounges so book club is a private club
it allows us to gather uh they charge a
very small fee I'll talk to adalo and
axel and John the founders of book club
and see if maybe they want to do a live
and I'd love have you guys as one of the
um I can H have 10 people online
simultaneously so I would love to have
you uh you join us there I think your
son's waiting you to go and do something
else huh he is absolutely my wife's been
spending the weekend at an off-grid uh
house on the on the Pacific Ocean around
the in the Indian Arm not too far away
from where we are right now so he's very
anxious for me to spend the rest of the
day with him he gave me a hard stop he
came in he came in at 1128 he's like Dad
two more minutes oh 11:29 dad just one
more minute and then I explained to him
what we were talking about so he's uh he
has the an understanding of that so
thank you everyone for joining us thanks
uh Madame canoli for uh reaching out and
and sort of suggesting this I think it
was a great idea thank you everyone that
Frenchie's touched and all the the hash
aines out there that are watching we
have uh 234 or 240 people that have been
watching with us for the last couple of
hours uh and like I said I'll put all
the links for the streams and anything
that I can to facilitate in the
description of this video and in the
meantime I always like to end it with h
a simple May the full melt bless your
bowl sooner than later hey hey Tanner
you want to say goodbye too see you
later Everybody by peace out thank you
so much bye everybody