hey what's going on everybody welcome to
bubble man's world welcome to another
episode of hashed Church episode 157
just one week after our three-year
anniversary some may say that today is
the three year anniversary and if you
would like to celebrate it as such by
all means please do in the meantime I'm
gonna send out some links to our
panelists for at least to this week's
panelists and we'll see how that goes
we've got a good old chatroom happening
right now a couple of 105 107 people
watching and 148 while the numbers jump
in quick I'm just gonna put my
headphones in as I'm probably gonna be
causing some some sort of a feedback
loop as I always do let's just make sure
that I'm getting the right links out to
everyone so that they all have the right
link to click I see it is already seen
it let's see if he's gonna come in and
make his way good morning sorry dude you
were missed for the three-year
anniversary let me tell you
oh I'm sorry burn it I was in New
Orleans so it was impossible to really
do anything it was a nice it was a nice
three years so congratulations though
needless to say on a great three years
Wow wasting no time it is already in on
the fire check this out
ooh nice squish sir what is that pretty
thing
oh yeah well this here is the seedsman
haze I like it already
right what temp was that president I was
pressed around 200 degrees on the
Sasquatch m1 Wow very nice squish oh
yeah what temp to 200 degrees justjust
just around 200 degrees I remember it
was a little bit higher and we we
dropped the temp but yeah it did a you
know that dueled butter and also a nice
drip there as well I took some macro
photographs early
so I figured it might be the way to go
about it
sweet well I got my bubble man vaporizer
fortunately before my trip and was able
to use it on my trip which was very
helpful so kudos on your latest
accomplishment needless to say yeah dude
I'm glad that you got one that put a
smile on my face to see that you had
when I saw that forest forest also
posted one the other day I'm like right
on Tony stop he's getting them out to
all the right people you know yeah yeah
yeah
it's I was impressed there's I was also
able because I I ran out a little bit on
my trip so I was able to put my own wax
in there so yeah yeah yeah yeah as
opposed to the rosin so I had a little
little learning curve with that because
the BHO when it's heated tends to expand
so you have to make sure that the the
lids on it etc etc so when I finally did
it cooked down but it definitely it
worked
alright so this is for Ontario he's
asking me to show dry sifting bubble so
here you go on Terry oh there you go
three different grades of dry sift
separated out from one full melt bubble
hash in the bottom of the jar and we'll
be looking forward to Ontario hashish
posting his dry sifting bubble that he's
going to be showing us in the Facebook
room later today we'll look forward to
seeing that
masya Ontario hashish and in the
meantime why don't we smoke some hashish
well now that we're doing picture time
and sharing I think it is already like
five bowls in and I'm I need to join the
party and get in here buddy and I don't
know what's going on with the rest of
our crew maybe today it's you and I say
let me say hey I'm happy dude up I'll do
a whole house Church with you today I
tend not a problem no it's not like we
don't have anything to talk
[Laughter]
between between you and me I think that
we'll probably be able to find enough to
discuss
needless to say yeah a lot of things are
happening here in California the new
regulations still kind of digesting
those but the governor signed the a B
133 the other day which allows for
collocations amongst other things
it's kind of an emergency situation that
is transpired because the it's not like
the state of California was dragging its
feet it's just that time is getting away
from them in that January first they
want to be able to issue permits so ona
goodies are still racing to get people
into their systems and local people are
trying to get into their local systems
or get their local municipalities to
change laws so we're still in that
neophyte phase as opposed to watching
all the exciting things happening up in
Canada where it's still so draconian and
still in the individual state status as
opposed to the inter province love that
you guys have well but we got a
nightmare of a scene in a way too
because there's this major major
division that still occurs in our
federal and in our non federal system so
you know once they figure it out and
offer us everything we need because
obviously they're not offering us
everything we need therefore we have to
continue with civil disobedience if
they're not going to allow you know all
the extracts and all these different
things then people are forced to you
know produce them and sell them through
dispensaries and other means so that's
what Canada's continuing to do and
hopefully they'll figure out at one
point how to get rid of this sort of
prohibition problem in regards to trying
to pass it over to a legal system it's
going to be interesting to see yeah here
in California we've we very fortunately
have Lori Ajax who's the former head of
the alcohol Control Board she's the one
that's been a sign or the initial for
the marijuana control and okay very
fortunate that they've been holding
meetings all over the state and that
they are open and listening to us so we
have fortunately we don't have to
approach
at the moment we have to actually again
out see that everything that we get you
know there's still the issue of the
hundred milligram limit on edibles and
things like that which the our edibles
allowed by the the federal government
there in Canada are you allowed to
produce edibles or is it just like
flowers and extracts you're allowed to
produce well it for my own personal I
can I can produce every type of extract
that's from the MMAR that's from the
court case that Owen Smith went through
but yeah yeah Michael's not seeing the
panel today not sure oh well because
there is no panel today right now it's
it's myself and and it's yeah that's all
that's all there is we are the panel
today we are cooking it up early have
your vaporizers ready you know I haven't
even hit a DAB so if you have something
to say let me mute my mic and heat this
court there you go nice got the banger
that fits and oh that's the adapter that
fits in very nice very nice I like that
makes them many so much better but
California is you know we're really
pushing for proper regulations and
pesticide testing which of course is we
just had a major release by another one
by steep hill saying that uh over 90% of
the clones on the market are
contaminated which is well it shows that
the market needs for somebody who's
watching you know their need to get on
their game and start producing and get
in the you know mother and clone game
because genetics are needed and it's a
major issue if you're perpetuating a
problem and selling clones to people I
mean I'm doing it right now because the
suppliers that I have I thought were
clean but it turns out that you know
that's not necessarily always the case
and one of the difficult things about
not being vertically integrated because
my city hasn't allowed for that vertical
integration yet so by not having a clean
supply of clones or
clean genetics to start with as we've
talked about multiple time it's you're
basically giving people a problem to
start without the door and it's only a
problem that they're going to find
because we found that these wonderful
and growing environments that we
recreate insides or the perfect
environments for nature to thrive and
nature will find its way in different
ways so you know starting off with an
automatic contaminant be it something in
the roots or something like white
powdery mildew etc you've already behind
the ball because as soon as you grow it
the problem is going to show itself and
you're going to think that it was your
problem or something that you did in
your room or your environment that may
have caused it but in reality it's
starting off with the plant that you're
bringing in and the perfect growing
environment that you're setting for the
plant you're creating those perfect
conditions unfortunately to host and you
know deal with those situations so I
know Sam has talked about in the past
you know when ways to get around this is
to get solid genetics that are seeds and
start from there if you're unable to
find but I would strongly suggest use
varieties which are resistant to powdery
mildew or whatever the specific problem
is that you have you'll find you know a
difference in resistance between a
Coryell varieties and widely varieties
to powdery mildew for example and it
literally is what you start with can can
affect so it's and the ways that we have
found this our lakes myself I've grown
little areas with starter plants and
then to see which ones get white powdery
mildew or not because of it's very
prevalent here in the Bay Area so it's
easier to get white powdery mildew than
most things and so you can actually
start to see through and pull out those
plants that are just up to the white
powdery mildew and as you will see
plants or you know equatorial tend to be
at that natural defense so that you can
literally see a plant that's covered in
white powdery mildew right next to
another plant that has white powdery
mildew and so
but that doesn't have it so that's how
we go through that type of selection if
you don't have access to a good seed
stock or a geneticist who's knows that
this in fact is a what it says it's too
because most of the real problem is that
in anything with wide leaf drug
varieties genetics in it from
Afghanistan the Hindukush that general
area there have no natural resistance
for powdery mildew because the
conditions are not conducive to powdery
mildew whereas ecuator ids they had to
have resistance right and so it's been
biologically built into the plant
through yeah they're the ones that
reproduced and the problem is is that
the most popular strains like your
cookies and your og cush is and things
like that are tend to be from the upper
mountain regions and tend to be widely
varieties and highly susceptible to
white powdery mildew and that's a issue
because that's that's kind of come from
the consumer because of consumer demand
but not necessarily from the brewers of
the growers demands from the growers are
growing it because I mean as far as I
know white powdery mildew is a problem
all over the United States and into
North America I'm not sure about it's a
problem worldwide exactly I mean you
don't see it very much from fields crops
in Afghanistan because it's dry there
and yeah but in general where ever
there's began work I'm sure there are
some which do get powder and they'll do
even in Afghanistan hmm hey welcome dr.
mark and Scott Benson as well to the
room it was just a Eddie and myself for
a few minutes there it was kind of kind
of unique it was cool
and now Wade is in the house with his
smiley face it's going on Wade it's all
good today beautiful sunny day gardeners
flourishing nice yeah I saw your photos
with Forest
the Swami ah and I was like I was visit
that looked like a fun visit we got a
little bit of rain on us yeah yeah no
Swami's doing good
it was a real treat to see them there
his plants are struggling he's doing a
he's transitioning from working in pots
to working in soil and because he's so
fervent about using no animal products
nitrogen is a real issue for his garden
though yeah we we explored what
possibilities there were to increase the
nitrogen without adding any fish
emulsion or any of the other things that
a lot of folks use and meantime he's
very meticulous about organic and all of
that but yeah what was what were what
were some of the alternatives that you
guys were talking about for producing
nitrogen for his plants green manures
he's not willing to use animal manures
of any kind and compost so it's really
cut across that takes a while Wade
knightly another thing that he could
think of would be using the seed meal of
high-protein seeds for example have seen
Christopher oil you could use that that
is fairly high carbon and I'm sure
Italian what you need and most
importantly Sam I bet you it would put a
smile on Swami's face yes as Aussie
didn't have to squash the billion seeds
right is there a source for that Sam
that you know of that you could name in
Canada probably Marcus knows better than
me yeah in the u.s. there really isn't
anybody squishing it I've got my I'm
listening
I've got some friends doing things in
Nebraska etc but they're more dealing in
Decorah caters
and there's got to be an oil company
using oil in the US and that you'd think
like nutiva or somebody like that would
be ready to reach out to a new team is
California so reach out to them and see
what they're doing with their these old
game your what they do with the seed
after the squash should is they make it
into animal feed really high in protein
uh-huh yeah yeah it's high protein yeah
it's it's animals love it too I mean
they they will gravitate toward it when
their have different types of protein
for some reason and it's you know it's
very good for them its digestible
okay well into the room forest good
morning everybody
yeah I I wanted to give thanks to forest
once again I think that that hashtag
that you started make them watch and
that whole mentality behind it and the
words that you wrote prior to that
hashtag which I shared on my Facebook
page was I was powerful [ __ ] man
you know I have a unique perspective and
I just ship have nothing you know I
think a lot of the cannabis industry and
for good reason this isn't a judgement
but they've had to just tiptoe around
all these judgmental people you know and
all their reasons why the cannabis
industry is bad and evil and even in our
own community you know there's just in
my opinion they're putting up with
ridiculous regulation that they really
don't have any choice because they've
just been abused and mistreated for so
many years but see I'm not in that
circle you know I don't have something
to prove or to sell so I have nothing to
lose to call people out and and really
point out how they're you know there's
these old ideologies that they can't
point back to any reason why they even
believe them other than they were told
at some point they should how they
impact everybody you know so yeah that
post was one of many that just I feel as
my role to just really put it in
people's faces that we're at a point now
where if you are going to hold on to old
ideologies and in outdated beliefs that
put people's lives at risk and severely
impact can
members quality alive you shouldn't be
protected in your little bubble and not
have to see the damage that causes so
that's where the make them watch hashtag
I came from they should see what it
looks like the watch a child slowly sees
to death they should see what it's like
to suffer from conditions where your
skin fall off they should see what it's
like for a cancer patient to go through
chemotherapy with and without access to
cannabis I mean the only way you can
have these outdated really you know
callous and heartless to be blunt
positions is if you can shelter yourself
from the impact that has on people
around you so I encourage families in
patients out there who are suffering to
film it and post it and tag it with the
make them watch so that they can see the
real impact that cannabis prohibition
has so yeah a prior prior to that
statement you you posted a photo of
Silas may 20th fairly heavy not looking
as healthy on pharmaceuticals back to
September 17th like lost major weight
looks just so much more aware and
healthy and that's on cannabis and and
you wrote you know don't tell me that we
as parents do not know what is and is
not safe for our children we have to
live with the consequences of the pills
we've given our child every day 95
percent seizure free 100 percent
pharmaceutical free so that was also
very powerful I wrote that and sort of I
wrote that to the people who are very
consistent in their well we need more
proof where's the proof we need more
scientific documentation etc well like
Forrest says in the last sentence of his
statement here and what you said you
know don't tell me that we as parents
don't know what is safe and not safe
that was that was that predated the make
them watch but I just thought both of
them were like cracked right out of the
ball thank you this is where it all
started was with patients because
remember it was the AIDS patients and
you have suffering here in the Bay Area
that got so sick and tired of literally
watching on their friends wasting away
and dying yeah that they're like [ __ ]
you [ __ ] this I'm gonna break the
[ __ ] law
again if it was not for them we would
not be here you and I i agree we've kind
of gotten to a stagnation point and i
think what you're doing there for us is
touting a whole other level because we
were able to open up that first wave but
at the same time it's opened up a whole
other wave of medicines to these very
intricate delicate illnesses that you're
dealing with that are there on the very
rare side of the realities they're not
common things like depression or
unfortunately aids and other things like
that
they're so narrowly along a finite point
that they you've literally been ignored
by everything from the pharmaceutical
companies you're trying doctors who are
desperately trying to find any way to
find any type by their standards that
they have access to you know discarded
even a TN absolutely and so III think
your awareness and your ability to raise
awareness because of the difficulties
that you face and the connection that
those vulnerabilities have with the
everyday person really becomes its own
arrow point and spear in its own
trajectory that I think will do nothing
but help millions of people and
especially thousands of children with
these rare conditions that can get some
relief and some relief is better than no
relief as you know temporary you know
it's the same here in Vancouver I just
have to say that it really was this sort
of the gay community who are the first
to stand up and just be like and it was
it was a part of the gay community who
was suffering with AIDS and it was this
wasting syndrome and it was all of these
different things that cannabis just
seemed to be miraculous for in how it
was improving the quality of a life that
was being decimated if you hung around
you know in the beginning of the BC
compassion club with Hillary the
majority of the people that she signed
originally were were terminally ill they
were they were it was really almost like
palliative care she was offering but
they were also homeless so they were you
know it was just it was unbelievable
like the firt you know
we should never forget that group of
people and how they really were the
front lines for you know here on the
west coast I think pretty since Tinley
everywhere they were ostracized by
everything and by everyone everybody
didn't know how AIDS was it wasn't until
Princess Diana actually shook the hand
of an AIDS patient in a hospital in like
1985 that people realize oh I'm not
gonna catch this this way but I mean it
was originally just dismissed as a a gay
disease and because of that the you know
is we're not necessarily looked proper
upon by society as much as necessarily
they are and respectfully are now and
they had to literally come out and fight
for their freedoms dog I mean and then
they pulled its society all of us
together and I got great respect for the
gay community for their hard work their
dedication and their networking [ __ ]
they taught us and in the cannabis
community we thought we knew networking
[ __ ] we had no idea how to network until
we saw the gay community come out in the
AIDS and the cannabis community and they
showed us how it's done people we
thought we straights had it going on etc
etc no we had no clue their networks
before internet etc etc were a class
that we all envy because of how able and
how quickly they were able to organize
and get it together so much respect to
all those pioneers and those survivors
and needless to say much love and
respect to all those who passed and
those family members who had to suffer
along the way yeah you know some of the
most inspiring activists I've worked
with started you know in Los Angeles and
other areas with working with the gay
community during the AIDS epidemic and
you know the stories are just
heartbreaking and what's more heart now
more it's probably the wrong word but
what is also heartbreaking is the fact
that community didn't rise up to support
you know just like you're saying they
shunned them they had all this judgment
towards homosexuality and you know you
look back on that and people look back
on it with shame you know the people who
have a good you know moral compass in my
opinion but we're
we're just humans we just have to repeat
this history you know the MER at this
point now where the word medicine and
how it pertains to cannabis the doors
have been blown wide open I mean I had
always thought yeah this is great this
is harmless and it helps people get
hungry this wonderful you know there is
absolutely no moral or ethical reason to
prevent these people from eating it but
now we're on the cusp of you know slowly
discovering but rapidly in the terms of
medical understanding discovering that
it is interacting with one of the most
important regulatory systems in our body
and could hold the key to some of the
most important medical discoveries we've
seen in generations and went from this
is harmless and yeah this can help it's
just the right thing to do - this is
without a doubt one of the greatest
medical discoveries of our lifetime and
has the potential to change the world
and anyone who's saying that the studies
you know there just needs to be more
research as soon as I hear that come out
of my mouth I know I'm talking to
someone who has made little to no effort
to look at the research that's available
because at this point the only way you
could say there's no research or more
needs to happen is that you've locked
yourself in a bubble or are just
repeating mantras that you've heard
other people say and you're hoping that
they're true because we have human
clinical trials in this country we have
peer-reviewed papers coming out every
other day at this point you can't even
keep up with the science that's coming
out so you know it's just at this point
one of my main goals is that exact
concept of people protecting themselves
in this bubble by saying well we didn't
really know we didn't really understand
and one of the things I try to do every
time I speak or if I've made a
conference or if I'm talking to anyone
is that when we're done talking you're
no longer gonna get to stay you didn't
know so you're gonna know and you're
gonna either act on it and look back and
realize he you acted with pride and with
you know with a good moral compass
you're gonna look back on it and realize
that you you know put a lot of people in
a really dangerous position that could
cost a lot of people their lives for
really no justifiable reason at all well
I think the problem is is that people
are so easily manipulated
and directed and you know they're just
and and and everyone I'm not talking
about people that are you know
brainwashed by a particular type of
religion or people like I'm not talking
about and I mean belief systems in
generally allow humans to be manipulated
easily and a perfect example is these
anarchists that go around to different
events they like to show up at the
Olympics they like to go to like the end
games of baseball and football and
basketball and hockey and what they do
is they start riots they start riots
with just normal good people that are
out enjoying a football game or a soccer
game or whatever and these [ __ ]
show up they got the tear gas they got
the gas masks that's how you know
they're there to start riots because
you're like did you notice there was
guys with gas masks on it's like yeah
they brought those gas pasts they do all
this little [ __ ] and they they do a
little push here and a little push there
and the next thing you know everyday
normal people are flipping and burning
cop cars I've seen it in my own city
twice when the Vancouver Canucks lost
the playoffs for the Cup but Markus
these people are not doing this for
their own reasons but for the revolution
the revolution I'll tell ya hey well I
mean go ahead I just say one more final
thought and this is something we all
have to combat and we you know before we
move on from this topic is that it's not
just that they're easily manipulated but
we also have this like inert need to
protect our worldview and paradigm
whether it's right or wrong we don't
adapt to change very well it's animals
and you know there's this whole
cognitive dissonance built in function
into the human brain that is I don't
know there must be some sort of
protection mechanism or it's beneficial
to us at one time but but now at this
point you know with that information
coming at us in ways it never has in
human history it's not it doesn't serve
us very well we have this need to just
protect ideas and sometimes it's
harmless and benign you know and
sometimes it's it's very harmful and you
know I think this is one of the things
we can do is really what I try to watch
that in myself you know
is this something that I want to believe
or is this something that I know and I
try to point that out with people that
were talking to in ways that are
hopefully not challenging to them
personally so I'm not attacking the
person we're just trying to get them to
understand where their own ideas have
even come from and we adopt so much that
it's just becomes our personal identity
that is really just candid to us through
our culture in our communities through
television through you know radio and
pop culture influences and in school
friends you know we just adopt pieces of
things and at some point when we're
challenged
you know it's it's really good that
we're making sure we're looking back on
this and saying okay am i holding on to
this because it's just something I've
always believed and I'm not sure why or
it's just something that I I have good
foundation to to adopt as part of me and
part of what I'm advocating for and I
see with cannabis it's all falls under
that category because all the arguments
that you hear we're really not backed up
with much of anything you know there's
just things that people have been raised
to believe and have been told and
they've been ruined are still continuing
to be repeated like the harmful effects
on you know development or brains and
kids and all these things that we've
just that you go back and look at the
research and there's very little if any
supportive evidence but people just
adopted so it's really good for people
in the cannabis activism realm to
recognize that and to be able to provide
information in a way that helps people
like shift ideas without triggering that
that need to protect their worldview
which just shuts down their ears
completely it's very true well we in the
and the can days when my my activist
Road days we learned early that it's all
about planting seeds planting seeds in
their minds because you can't change
someone's opinion however if you could
prove in this piece of information or
this link to this knowledge so that they
themselves can then go to that link
themselves in their own time when
they're ready for it and they're ready
to absorb it and then they actually look
at it and actually read it it affects
the collective unconsciousness not only
themselves and so those planting
seeds as we said it was back then it was
having a pamphlet and getting into
somebody's pants and hoping that they
forgot to wash they forgot about that in
their pants and then their mom goes
through their pants and it pulls out
that piece of paper and goes hey what's
this and it sparks that discussion you
know what I'm saying
it engages people in forces them to have
these uncomfortable conversations that
they don't want to have but for some
reason because as you stated the
collective conscious has taught them
this and so they can't go against that
because of change but if you can give
them the idea and it has to come from
themselves and it has to be instigated
by themselves so if you can give them
the seed that can sit in there and give
them time it in time will form its own
manure and break down and start to grow
and when it starts to grow it becomes
their idea and then that change can come
from within them from their own
instigation as opposed to us try to beat
it over their heads because I realize we
going out there we could only reach
certain amount of people there is always
for every one person at a rally back in
the 90s there was 10 to 15 to 20 people
at home because they were afraid to come
out or show their face etc etc which now
become the standard reality of people
being filmed at rallies back then it
wasn't the case but it was still the
fear but it became that reality
consciously so we have to again plant
our own seeds so that it can sprout and
teach others through our own education
and passing that knowledge on to them so
that they can judge and grow for
themselves I couldn't agree more but I
would just add one last thing which is I
found there is one way to make a direct
and immediate paradigm shift in someone
and that's with direct experience you
know we've had we've worked with
lawmakers where we've had kids there and
they're like I don't know we need more
research right bam child has a seizure
and their idea on what is and what it's
not appropriate changes immediately
because we have a reaction that then you
know changes are I think it changes us
physiologically you know when we have
this you know almost maternal sensitive
this reaction to parent paternal sense
when we see people have these
experiences and I've seen people change
immediately and but that's hard to do
but it's one of the reasons I think we
I'd like to see more integration of
people who a lot of the community things
we should protect from cannabis
integrated with cannabis I want to see
children in gardens I want to see
children in farms and interacting and
showing that this plant is not gonna
reach out and grab them and say and you
know rip them from limb to limb that the
the the perceived harm is it's really
just that it's it's it's it's fear
without a without reasoning in the basis
and this is also and this can bring us
back to where Marcus started us and if
we need to move on and that's good but
that's also the idea behind the make
them watch hashtag people change through
direct experience I want them to see
what it's like for people to have a
seizure adult or child but see the fear
in the parents I see the pain experience
the trauma and it's not quite as
effective but it still has more impact
than just verbal dialogue when they have
to see it and experience it and they're
uncomfortable and they don't want to
watch it that has an impact on the mind
and I think we can change hearts and
minds that way and it's hard because a
lot of people don't want to share that
personal pain and struggling and they
shouldn't have to there's no other
medical condition where you have to
expose your suffering that way publicly
to prove that you have it in and
maintain access but with cannabis right
now I think we need to and I think it
really directly impacts exactly what you
were saying as far as you know people's
ability to change their perspective and
that's how we change communities and
then when they understand what happens
is I've seen it then they say well we
are all for these kids yeah I know
that's fine yeah kids with seizures that
helps we all agree they should have it
but there's this mental disconnect that
you know it's just gonna spring out of
thin air and and then families are gonna
have access to medicine but I can't we
want them to have it but we just don't
want it grown right or we don't want to
in our communities because we might
smell it for six weeks out of the year
and you know that's part of a lot of the
work I'm doing
is really trying to focus on well these
are not mutually exclusive ideas you
have to be able to understand that if
you want to and protect these vulnerable
members in your community or adult or a
child then it has to grow somewhere and
it has to be tested somewhere it has to
be manufactured somewhere and this is
the angle I take into these local
community fights in California I mean
it's just every county is fighting tooth
and nail and it seems like they're all
arguing like it's 2008 still you know or
2005 like oh you should have setbacks
and we don't know if we want it here but
that's just the wrong conversation I
don't even want to allow my board of
supervisors or local officials to even
have that type of conversation in 2008
fine but with the amount of undisputable
scientific evidence that has shown this
is life-saving medication you no longer
get to say you know or choose if we want
to in our communities that's not a
choice that is an option you don't get
to choose if we're gonna have insulin
for kids who need it you don't get to
choose even if we're gonna have opioids
and opioids are killing people by the
millions but it would be considered
completely unethical to say you can't
have morphine after you have heart
surgery or you have an amputation of the
leg we know that these things are not up
for debate as far as human rights but
with cannabis for some reason we're
still debating it like it's an if type
of question like oh yeah it's just some
people like to get high and are we gonna
allow that in our community or not but
that conversation is over it's no longer
okay to see if we're gonna have it in
our communities the only ethical
question is how are we going to do it
and how are we gonna do it in a way that
protects our communities and protects
the most vulnerable there so alright I'm
off my soapbox dude that's an awesome
soapbox I really appreciated everything
you said in that it's a very important
perspective and I've said for a long
time now that it's definitely going to
be the children unfortunately because we
really shouldn't have to be exposing
sick children but this is the thing that
changes the minds of the most staunch
prohibitionist the one who's just
Walla Hill he believes in all the all
the propaganda and in it and a half a
second you can see that change with
exactly what you described have someone
having a seizure right in front of them
and then being relieved with a drop of
cannabis oil they're no longer just
changes their mind it changes their soul
for it oh yeah loads them to that and
that's what you can see it in that
representative city councilperson county
person etc eyes and that's what's needed
and so they need to be shocked they need
to see the horror of these kids whose
skin cannot basically stay on and that
this medicine literally holds them
together nota unintended you know
they're shocked they're shocked as well
is is the real shock has to be how could
I have been led down such an evil path
because when you notice that in that
instant and you see that like Forrest
mentioned the fear in the parents eyes
the real experience of it happening I
mean I'm guaranteeing you nine point
nine out of ten would stand there with
their jaw on the floor unable to really
process what was happening well and
that's why I share these pictures of
these EB kids and and they can be
graphic
you know that's it's hard to look at but
let me tell you I know you guys have
seen it but some watching might not have
if you go to the Gladius Network on
Instagram or on Facebook you can see
some of these pictures and they're the
most mild pictures I have to share there
I'm trying to not intentionally exploit
your posts gory photos and I have a file
that parents have sent me that I just
don't know if people are ready to see
yet I don't want to scare people off but
if you look at those pictures of those
EB kids realize you're seeing the most
tame pictures I can try to show to get
the point across without making people
not want to come back because it's
terrific can you say yeah the conditions
called epidermolysis bullosa be ull OS a
in the f you wanna you
have your paradigm shifted go ahead and
google that se what those kids go
through what what is the root cause of
this is there a single cause yes yeah
sorry I didn't catch oh yeah it's a
genetic malformation so they it's just a
genetic fluke where their body doesn't
produce the protein there's a protein
that holds our layers of skin together
like a like velcro yeah and when when
you don't produce that this layers of
skins slide on each other and when they
if you bump it hard enough then it
starts the blistering process so it's
just like a burn all right it blisters
and then peels off and dies and tries to
heal but it your body never stops doing
that which is why they call them
butterfly kids a lot of the parents
don't like that they like calm like
turtle kids because they're tough but
the term is like they call butterfly
kids because their skin is so soft that
when you bump it it comes off and we've
seen huge improvements in their ability
to heal and regenerate skin quickly and
get them off the other medications
because remember some of the damage and
this goes back to what Marcus said about
the pictures of Silas I've hurt my son
treating his condition but it wasn't
with cannabis I've given him drugs that
I it's hard to talk about I hold so much
regret forgiving him for such a long
amount of time
horrible drugs from our doctor and these
kids are no difference what happens it's
not only are they sick but then you give
them drugs that just destroy their body
so they're being given the e back to the
EB kids now you know topical ketamine
right and in their two and a half years
older younger and they're on dilaudid
right and topical more afine so what
happens over time is now not only are
you sick and struggle these conditions
but your body becomes an addict and it
never functions well we know in that
condition so what we're seeing was a
mistake you're just treating the
symptoms and you're not treating the
underlying cause of the disease itself
and you're deadening the body's own
nervous system which is there to sense
right discomfort to tell you that
something is just not not correct but I
a wider
again so there's two things that Canada
miss can potentially help with not only
is cannabis wonderful in its wound
healing properties but also just any
inflammatory aspects alone
so are these treatments topical for us I
know they can create like a subdermal
thing but you're also treating this
condition topically yeah so I spent a
couple years now working on a topical
cream that with no bells and whistles
it's just designed to work and we worked
with these EB families and yeah I don't
have them prepared but if we want or we
could do another show on this I could
get pictures ready but the it's just the
anti-inflammatory properties or you know
from with knees like the size of like
cantaloupes just completely swollen to
within three or four weeks it looks like
a completely different leg just hues so
significant anti-inflammatory properties
yeah and pain modulation and management
and then when they we see that we get
them off of some of these drugs that
suppress the whole system and some
families are doing large internal dosing
as well so the kids have a g-tube and
they'll just do up to upwards of 150
milligrams THC and 300 CBD a day
internal dosing the kids show no sign of
intoxication whatsoever but that also
will knock the whole body inflammation
down you get benefit to the
endocannabinoids system so they can be
functioning in the most efficient manner
that it can and essentially you just see
these kids start to transform through a
combination of a quicker time for the
wounds to heal and healthier skin and
healthier skin becomes a little bit more
robust and one of the key things that is
efficient for effective for
epidermolysis bullosa kids is the
control of itching in cannabis cream can
do that we're still trying to make it
better but when your skin like when you
get road rash if anyone remembers or a
big kind of skin wound when it hear a
tattoo all right when it starts to heal
it itches right that's the dangerous
cycle
because as the wounds healing and then
the kids are starting to itch right and
what happens when you itch you break the
skin and these kids and then you're just
reopening this wound constantly and a
lot of times that's what gets them is
eventual either staph infection or skin
cancer from the constant wounds so these
creams really help with that as well so
it it's kind of that whole cycle you're
not able to cure the condition but if
you are able to in pain and modulate the
pain decrease time for wound healing and
overall anti-inflammatory properties in
the body we see dramatic quality of life
changes in these kids and there's
significant progress going on with gene
editing right now we don't have to get
in the crisper and those things but you
know these are probably gonna be some of
the frontline kids to look at potential
gene editing applications of some of
those so our goal is to you know really
improve their quality of life and just
you know make sure they're here so when
the cure comes they can experience it
you know I I can I'd like to donate to
something a little bit to you I have a
vast supply of 88 to one CBD I got the
SC lab tests on it it's clean it it's
beautiful stuff everybody I have given
it to has thought it was absolutely
amazing so I'd like to give you some if
I could forward the SC lab pick along
with it and the second thing I want to
say here is I forward if all the
information about the kids and your site
and everything do jeff sessions with a
letter asking him to pull his head out
of his ass and take a good close look at
the whole thing I would love your
presentation to Congress let me get
those guys in front of me I'd love to
tell them exactly what we think with our
kids they're people when government will
see what happens if anything those guys
are too busy covering their own asses
right now for the money that they're
spending doing other nonsense but I want
to offer
you this CBD I've been trying to make it
available to people for seven dollars a
gram but I want to give you guys all you
need no charge well that's wonderful we
will put it to good use and get it to
those who need it thank you very much
injury right very nice very nice welcome
enjoy by the way and D for 20k and I
don't know if there's anyone else I
missed but I did I never want to
interrupt good conversations but I know
you guys don't take it personally so
welcome to hash Church episode 157 just
about one hour in here to the to this
today's episode got about 542 people
watching in the chatroom and listening
away and yeah I love gathering every
Sunday with all of you and seeing where
the discussion goes it always feels like
I know you feel like you don't want to
be up on a soapbox for us but it just
seems like such a such an important
aspect of the like the tip of the spear
soar to speak you know there's a there's
a whole handle and there's all this
other component but the tip of the spear
should get a lot of attention and I just
don't think that there is anyone that
could argue with you because of how
you're coming at this and where you're
coming from it's like you said you don't
have a product to sell you're not well
it's also how intelligent he comes
across and you know you the empathy and
sympathy comes through in your voice
because you've experienced it firsthand
and you know you you hear that if you
don't you're not human and you are
pushing them and pushing them into the
uncomfortable region in ways that no
other person can and I'm thankful that
we have spokespersons like you that
unfortunately are have come through the
hard route and had to educate yourself
regarding the realities that you face
but you and Silas the type of catalysts
that are going to affect real change for
many and we thank you for taking on your
difficulty with the dignity and a grace
that benefits us all well it's my planet
I'm just honored to be here with you
guys you know that and the pave the way
here and what I just saw was that there
was this disrespect that I thought was
inappropriate to people like you the
activists in the community and it was
justified with this illusion that it's
all a game and none of the things you're
saying to all the patients you've helped
is real and they just had all these
excuses to justify not taking some
really really heartfelt activist
seriously and I just felt like I had
another angle to offer that to help to
combat that exact dissidents and their
thinking and I said with us working
together we can make change and so I'm
just honored to be here with you guys
it's not a game to me you know this is a
serious subject
you know I stayed on CNN to I mean it's
all fine there's a lot of great fun
things that come out of cannabis it's
not all serious I realized that I am NOT
the the you know most fun topic when it
comes to cannabis and I enjoy all the
other fun sides of cannabis as well but
um it's the fact that it's only framed
that way that really bothered me that
every time there's a thing on you know
the news or CNN I go it's 4/20 in
Colorado and everybody's sparking up and
you know the citizens are tired of it
Ness and it's just always framed in this
way that it's just a big game so I just
felt that I had something that really
show that there are parts of this
conversation that are not funny and it's
very serious and should be taken very
seriously and I felt like I had that to
add to the conversation and as long as
it's legal they wanna make fun of
medical make fun of industrial but
legally allow it I'm a happy guy yeah
yeah I'm with you there well but you
know the public making fun of it the way
comedians have always chose to create
the stereotypical jokes about it I think
all that has a big negative sort of
impact on people that are trying to see
this plant as you know for what it
really is you're just you're sending
mixed messages I haven't seen
this new show yet but I've heard
disjointed is a lot of like not the most
popular cannabis humor its kind of
negative and I don't know I haven't seen
it but I I have and it is all the
negative stereotypes plus one on the
guest list
use ad they had an opportunity to really
do some intelligence missin yeah some of
the lingo was current but I also saw one
of the people who was assisting or in
the production and she is persona non
grata for what she's done in our
community and it's only making us all
look bad and I thought we were past
these degenerate stoner
stereotypes which is why we have and I
come to hash Church because I want to
have intelligent talk with intelligent
people as opposed to these stereotypic
hey dude what's going on man and a
cooking baked me and again he straight
you know but you know we've all had to
deal with the unfortunate realities of
life and and many of these realities but
when people you know had AIDS and stuff
like that people didn't realize that
they were ostracized completely from
their families and they were basically
ostracized by everyone we were literally
sometimes their only physical contact of
somebody who would even speak to and
that was beyond disheartening to see
society so ignore the realities that we
were forced to deal with those realities
and those are humbling realities you
know when you have to stare into open
cysts on people's arms you know open
sores to the point where you're
uncomfortable just even looking at them
you know but you have to have the inner
strength to stand there and say this
person is a patient they need help they
need help now and I'm here to do that
and that to me is where I feel so
insulted by disjointed even though it is
humorous it still is a poke at our
reality that you know a lot of our
reality isn't funny as you know for us
firsthand it's not funny it's it's
there's ugly realities to this but I
really hoped more first
thing like that and I just that's my
opinion
I'm not a fan of the show but I
encourage each one of you to encourage
your old man to look at it just to see
you for yourself you know to judge for
yourself because some of this stuff is
giggly but some of the stuff is very
cringe-worthy the most cringe-worthy for
me is when they went and did Jack
carrers
funeral and they mocked it and I was
there and it was not handled in any type
of disrespectful way in any way shape or
form nor the portrayals they changed his
name to heron as opposed to Herer but
that type of portrayal
it was literally a slap in the face to
me and my community and it's very
difficult for me to then get behind
something like that that totally insults
heroes I mean I would not know you if it
would not been for Jack Herer coming to
my University in 1989 and me getting off
my ass okay and then to have him mocked
and a show like that so they made it
seem like he grew a career the strain
which was not the case the strain was
bestowed upon him out of utter [ __ ]
respect out of all the hard work and
dedication that he is done and so to
perpetuate that into the eyes of the
ether of the collective consciousness is
disrespectful to Jack's name and the
hard work that he's done and all the
hard work a lot of us have done and so
yes it's made in jest but it is
insulting the way that it was presented
to me yeah I'm not a big fan of this
sort of does that mean you didn't think
the show was funny
hmm I would say he did it was
cringe-worthy in areas yes I did laugh
at times and yes they did I think the
cast is called a B and the dabber and
stuff like that I mean they're current
with their lingo don't get me wrong and
it's nice to hear the current lingo
being used properly as opposed to you
know the silliness that were o or the
puns were always left with but it just
it didn't
it was disingenuous and
the majority of cannabis humor movies
over the decades have been kind of like
making this look a bit like losers of
course that's not just making us look a
little bit like losers listen it's a
huge part of this of the of the story
like if you look back like first of all
the culture that's that's basically
setting the tone for everything is
Hollywood Hollywood makes the movies
Hollywood makes the TV shows everyone
wants to export America's culture
everyone's importing it to their
countries everyone wants to be a part of
it that's a major point of contention
with me because people can blame William
Randolph Hearst all they want he may
have started it but it's these cup these
people that are continuing to propagate
it by you know shitty jokes on Jimmy
Kimmel or or whatever it is you know
anti and sort of prohibition based
stereotypical jokes that I just feel
like man like when there's a side of
this that forest is coming in and
sharing with us how can you make jokes
like this that this is this is a
disservice to the community it's keeping
people from seeing the actual benefits
of the plant by goodbye hahaha and when
people think they're going into fight
activity in their community that's what
they envision like well we just don't
want that in our community you know
people though the non cannabis related
community that's their only experience
is their television for the most part or
story horror stories they see in the
newspaper and that's when they go in and
say well we don't want this in our
community a lot of times that's what
they're envisioning is this dumb stoner
culture that really doesn't exist in
very many places in it does yeah it's
harmful
well Cheech and Chong they were
snapshots in time and I actually one
time I did a panel with Tommy Chong and
afterwards we were at the smoking circle
getting high and I asked him that I was
I could affirm him as an activist I was
like hey you know I really felt your
humor set us back a long time
and he said I get that kid respectfully
but you got to understand it was the
darkest days of prohibition the only way
we could get through with humor and I
said much respect coming from you I get
that because you have literally or than
one of the few people have carved a
reality out of nothing in the Hollywood
and that's very difficult to do however
the continued perpetuation of those
stereotypes and prolonging them into the
70 past the 70s into the 80s into the
90s and into the now and now it's
disjointed are the problems you know
yeah well that's it I mean we didn't the
understanding of cannabis in the 70s was
not what it is now and that's why you
know in my first kind of opening
statement I made there was we can't even
talk about cannabis like we're talking
about it in 2008 today let alone you
know so yeah I love Cheech and Chong we
had growing up all that stuff was great
but but the time is death that's the
whole problem the the understanding has
changed the evidence behind the
understanding is there and has changed
but the conversation hasn't and that's
really where the problem is and that's
what I see a lot of people doing in
their local communities is they're
allowing really outdated tactics and
arguments to be made about cannabis and
how it's gonna be integrated or not in
our communities in a conversation that
in 2017 is completely different if
you're open and understand you know the
the just wave of good data in science
that it's just being done every day and
coming at us like a tsunami you know if
we can just keep up with just a little
bit of that you can see that a lot of
the conversation is just old and
outdated it doesn't even pertain anymore
or shouldn't but unfortunately it's just
prevalent in communities and it's
continuing to be successful
unfortunately we're seeing bands you
know all over California in every County
to Tommy you know when if you go see him
and you go see him speak his memory is
impeccable he's articulate you can tell
he's a smart guy and in that sense he's
kind of show
that the stereotype maybe isn't a
stereotype he's out living all of his
contemporaries that were drinkers and
smokers he survived cancer and beat it
using cannabis so it's it's you know I'm
in that same boat of not liking the you
know back in the 70s absolutely I
thought it was hilarious I was a huge
fan of Cheech and Chong I just thought
man these guys are and it's true you
know we were I was a very very little
kid at that time I can't really
understand what the mentality was some
of the panelists can I'm sure it was
probably a pretty damn dark time after
Nancy Reagan came out and said just say
no was that in the 80s in the 70s so
that was in the 80s so he did he did
that in the early 70s they did it during
Hamlet it was a comedy routine it was
meant to be funny
yeah and it was meant to be poking fun
at ourselves I mean it's the classic
example is it is art imitating life or
his life imitating art right I mean
there was already kind of like a
[Music]
Hispanic community in East LA that was
just like Cheech right so and yeah they
were all smoking weed and it was just it
was part of just the culture of who they
are and it's just kind of like the
deadheads and the fish-heads I mean you
know in a sense
look we mark you you remember we were
able to smoke at fish shows or a dead
shows in arenas where if during an ill
young you took out one lighter you are
immediately swarmed by by security so
what was it that Bill Graham was able to
do why was why were the Bill Graham
shows when the Grateful Dead played why
were they allowed to smoke weed at the
venues and again if weed was being
smoked at the venues that means there
was a traveling circus outside that was
bringing all kinds of different you know
things and you know not just drugs but
wares and everything like that so like
when the Dead came to town it was a real
real traveling circus that actually
brought all kinds of you know not just
creepy people but just weirdness into
the town and and sometimes like in Vegas
you would never even know that the dead
were in town because Vegas is already
pretty
weird to begin with but I just go back
to teach and Chong just be more of a
reflection on society you know I'm of
just I would compare them honestly now
in a way that I've never really seen
before I would compare them to what Dave
Chappelle came and did years later with
stereotypical race humour and pushing
that envelope maybe into and and he got
the same thing he got like a lot of
groups saying hey man you're not doing
us any favors here we're trying to have
people take us seriously but yet at the
time
Chappelle's comedy was so disruptive and
so hilarious and made us all think in a
different way that who's to say what's
good and bad I suppose I would say Tommy
Chong when I think it was in 2016 so not
too long a year-and-a-half ago or so the
Sacramento Bee the Capitol here in
California did a three-day story on my
family in Silas they called it the Silas
project you can look it up Sacramento
Bee and Silas projects but the sheriff
had raided Silas is grow I was fighting
here and raised in hell and they did a
three-day story on that and Tommy Chong
picked it up and shared it on his
Twitter and all those things and that
you know and it's still this day I don't
see a lot of that sort of posting coming
from him and some some others but I
definitely appreciated that and it
showed that he is keeping up on some of
the other contexts that cannabis
activism is has taken shape in the last
10 years and got a lot of attention from
that because of him so mm-hmm
Thanks is that Cheech Marin is heavily
involved in is establishing a a museum
for Latino art in I think it's Riverside
California you can google it there was a
story a couple weeks ago in the news on
it but again he's assembled the largest
collection of of Latino art and he's now
gonna you know basically I think they're
looking to raise a couple million
dollars to tourist library side I
believe it is into basically a museum
where this art can be shown so I mean
these people are doing beneficial things
in society they're not just yeah
I think that you know the positions they
played back in that you know comedy
routine they're actors man they're
acting that part they're both really
really high intellect people with a lot
more to contribute to society than just
up in smoke you know they were just
portraying couple stoners in that movie
well what other contexts could you do it
in back then I mean the understanding
the cannabis was pretty much enjoying it
would have been some other comedy
routine making fun of it so they were
just making fun of her so if you go back
and listen to their company routines on
their first couple albums they're
actually [ __ ] hilarious
and if you listen to it hi it's even
better but I was actually one of the
guys who had the big Ambu record album
and inside the album they had a big
bamboo rolling page I still have my I
was one of the guys old enough to
actually roll a joint in that paper it
was about a quarter with worth of weed
but we roll the joint a big brown
Mexican weed that mean take the seeds
out but we we smoked that I remember the
teacher Chong joint that was a good and
that last you have that album with the
paper skills papers those papers were
made by Esmeralda at the time that that
big album came out I know I bought ten
of those albums and had those Esmeralda
papers around for quite a long time oh
yeah you have to clean the seeds out on
the record album right you know high
modern tradition of having seeds just go
down the side of your record album as
you were cleaning out your weed you
don't do that anymore but you know first
people are afraid that's the whole deal
I mean to paraphrase an idiot who is
arguing with Trump right now the more
afraid dogs are the louder they bark and
you got you people in the committees
that are barking the lightest are the
ones that are most fearful of this and
until you find a way to placate those
people are bringing them into the fold
of understanding it's gonna be a
difficult fight because
there is fear of the unknown it's the
scariest thing that human beings have
and these people don't know and so
they're afraid and well this is why I
think they're fighting a losing battle
because you can't you can only watch Fox
News or only watch CNN or only be red or
blue or however people like to sanction
off their information and you can only
search for bad research that's been done
over the last 20 years trying to find
harmful effects of cannabis to reinforce
your views but illness is
non-discriminatory cancer hits one in
three you know rare disease I'll be a
rare is rather common you know when you
have one in fifty thousand one in 300
thousand of a whole bunch of different
rare diseases you know it hits people in
all demographics and when that
experience happens that change is a
ripple through their community you know
so when I get people from church groups
who come with their kids seizing and
they don't want their church to know but
within six months their kids have
relative stability and everyone's asking
the family why and they start to feel
more and more confident to share them
because they see that everything that
they've known has not been 100 percent
accurate and everything they've been
told that that's like a seed in that
community you know we get families from
the military and from the Sheriff's
Department who come in it's really
hardcore ideologues but like we said
experience has a way of kicking your ass
and really changing the way you see the
world and that's why anybody thinks
they're fighting cannabis from from
being around to be in uses of medicine
it's just has no idea what they're
talking about because it's just a
different conversation when it comes to
the the medical needs of cannabis and
how it's gonna hit people whether you
believe in it or not and when your
doctor tells you there's no other option
the only thing that might help you is
maybe some of these cannabinoid based
therapies people's worlds are gonna
change and it changes within those
communities and I'm seeing it happen now
I'm seeing whole church groups that were
against us one year one of the kids in
the in the group gets ill and
the sudden everyone's experiences is
different in their attitudes are
different so have you sorry have you
have you ever linked with sub cool
forest I did sub cool show for the first
time a couple weeks ago are you doing so
cool good
I think he's muted right now yeah I'm
done at once but we had a good time they
let me let me go off and that's always
always fun awesome
I know subs been doing some pretty
awesome community work in the cannabis
community from toy drives to all sorts
of different like planting gardens to
help different people and he's always
sort of been really good at at that sort
of quality of stuff while while running
his business and doing all that other
stuff I got I got to give him props for
that and I wasn't sure if you guys had
linked up but definitely I'm glad you
have because he's just helpful yeah he
makes me nervous driving and doing that
though cool cookies now he's smoking a
bowl oh goodness
well that's good it's good that so we
got a nice big room happening here right
now for a Wade made it back in seemed
like he was having a little bit of
internet trouble there it was kind of
like I was kind of picturing this
hilarious skit in my face cuz to me Wade
just seems like the most chillest most
relax dude and I was picturing like him
not getting into church and like just
like screaming and running around his
house like dammit I want to get into
church like as a joke cuz I know that's
not what you were doing you were
probably like super calm going oh geez
this isn't working I can't get in here
oh I'll keep trying I'll just keep
trying
whereas myself I'm not gonna lie I have
gotten fairly upset at my computer when
I feel the responsibility of getting
Church going even you know like having
to be somewhere on a Sunday where the
internet works and I can it's a it's a
responsibility I'll tell you and have
you found it helped a lot when you got
angry at your computer absolutely I feel
that when I get really
angry with my computer and like break it
right over my my face that's when I I
just feel that things work out the best
for me no absolutely not
things never work out yes I can hear you
some cool welcome I'm actually just in a
parking lot just so you know I'm not
actually driving down um no I had I had
a comment I wanted to make and this the
duality of what you guys are talking
about you know California right now in
Northern California where I live is set
to bury the [ __ ] country in cannabis
and Keith I want to bury the country and
week but I was at a restaurant on
Tuesday afternoon having dinner I'm in a
local place I like to eat at because
there's lots of tourists and I like
people and like to talk so the lady
asked me what I did for a living I told
him - I agree cannabis and I told her
that I also sell my cannabis and raise
money for Sick Children and she said
well what does cannabis have to do with
children she was 55 years old up early
mobile biga last diamond on her hand
driving a BMW family full of yuppie wine
drinkers and she looked at me and she
said oh well does that work that's what
we're fighting in this country she is an
intelligent articulate woman who was
[ __ ] clueless that cannabis can help
kids with autism and seizures and stuff
and this is not this is not us you know
this is not what I call us the stoner
community or the fam community this is
what I considered to be America she was
clueless that cannabis could maybe help
kids with seizures and stuff and of
course you can imagine the mouth full of
information she got from me she was
backing up a little bit I just had to
that's really what I'm seeing this week
we are we are producing so much cannabis
and medicine right now that we could
treat the whole world and yet most
Americans still think that a valium is
the cure to our problems I just wanted
to point that out it got under my skin
this week well there's definitely a
system that's been put in place for that
all to be the way it is and it seems as
though people will only hear it when
they're told it by particular you know
the people they trust the anchor on the
news or the newspaper that they hope one
person at a time just like every well
you can see how
that's going mark Sheldon whereas when
they want everyone to know something
they put it into their little media
system and it's just like wham four
billion people in one shot it's like
great isn't it great when you finally do
like talk to sort of random strangers on
the way back from the airport in the
shuttle to people that yeah you meet
wherever when they ask what is it that
you do and in order to tell them to
describe that no this isn't you know
Cheech and Chong and getting high this
is really about medicine and the
reunification of human beings with this
plant because until the last century
which as Todd used to say is the
cannabis deficient century humans were
you know United with this plant so this
is just the reunification century and
well so it is a mission of education and
it is sometimes one person at a time
I've talked to people again who had no
clue I got their email address and then
I sent them like the Missoula movie sent
them links - Church sent them links so
they could actually see for their cells
no there are clinical trials there is
validity to taking this thing to the
next level and yeah I mean so winning
people over one at a time it I think 10
years and from now this will be a mute
discussion but I hope so though and I
would also say we should always
represent as weak someone's got a
reverberation in the microphone there
I'm not sure who's not muted but I think
it just disappeared I always got to give
props to the stoner community - for
being the stewards for so long and
basically who you know who the heck do
you think came up with all this who
started digging and digging and learning
all this information it was people who
were using cannabis oh my goodness to
get high to feel euphoria to feel
positive to relieve stress to be like
yeah so as as much as the stereotype is
we should always also respect the the
actual experience of feeling elevated
feeling the so called high it's not
bad thing it shouldn't be a bad word we
shouldn't be embarrassed by it because
it is how it's the thing that has kept
it alive because you know you know for
cannabis to be around in the way that it
is for people like Wendy Turner to get
cannabis for her son Colton and for
people like Forrest and meet people like
Wade it's like people who were getting
high who were the stewards of that
planet for all those decades you know
you can call it medicine it is but it's
it was it was that euphoria that that
got a lot of us involved passionately to
the point where as you won receptors
right yeah so I was prevailing receptor
or one of the most prevalent receptors
in the human brain so I mean that's not
a happy accident and we were talking
last week with Chris at the fountain of
youth you know I did a little bit of
research into that I'm absolutely
convinced that when people smoked
cannabis before they really understood
the biological impacts and then the
cannabinoid system think about when
Native people smoked it probably for the
first time and felt like no more pain or
no more anxiety or they probably did say
hey this could make me live forever
right this is the Fountain of Youth I
always think of John's quote where he
said it's hard to feel bad when you feel
good well said yeah interest said that
like a year ago on hostage he's like
it's hard to feel bad when you feel good
now it's just like wow that's just so
simple and that's about as accurate and
that's it it's profound yeah so the
terpenes drew us in and the cannabinoids
made us stay that's my quote me let me
share something else with the panel is
uh and there's some people here that
don't know so I have um and this is new
to me this is I just find this cool so I
have alpha one it's a respiratory
disease so liver disease my my white
blood cells attack my internal organs
and I don't I don't have a protein that
protects it so I'm I'm dissolving from
the inside out
so I quit using cannabis when they told
me I had
lung problems for a long time some
people that know me closer know I had a
bout with alcoholism and all kind of
drugs and everything 292 days clean of
all drugs right now except for cannabis
but this is my point when I when I when
I started using cannabis again I really
obviously like wow why the [ __ ] did I
quit using this but recently my diseases
just really kicking my ass the pain I
experienced it's just brutal and you
know we talk about the benefits of
cannabis and I'm so cool and I smoke
weed all the time but the last couple of
days I've actually noticed like just
brutal pain from this disease and then
I'll smoke a couple of bowls which for
me it's really weird because my smoke it
hurts like [ __ ] it hurts my lungs I
can't breathe it makes me panic a little
bit because my lungs not in great
condition but follow me here about five
minutes afterwards when my lungs recover
from the carcinogens of my life all of a
sudden doesn't suck my panic goes away
in in and all these feelings that I have
from this illness this horrible pain and
it causes all throughout the whole body
it just goes away and I mean it's funny
that I've been an advocate for this
plant for so long but I'm telling you
again today that even though it's tough
for me to consume the plant but if the
smoke and I consumed mine the benefit
that I get from this plant mentally
emotionally spiritually overcomes
anything that he could do to me because
I have to consume smoke and he in the
last week or two it is like I'm just
like oh god I'm in such pain let me take
a couple of hits of this wax I dunno
like hey I mean I want to put on some
[ __ ] Stephen Stills and enjoy life
and so I just had to say that I mean
after 45 years of smoking it still does
what I needed to do that's why I'm fond
of it that's awesome man and I guess the
vaporizing is just not happening for you
it's just not strong enough it's not
giving you that relief that a good blast
gives you it's um the problem mark is my
lungs only in will move like a like a
quarter of an inch so I can't empty the
damn bag same thing than email
I can't inhale long enough so I use a
teeny ball and a teeny teeny teeny
height and then I just smoke like the
tiniest piece of wax I drop the teeny
piece of wax I don't even use add a
brick it melts and flows down but the
amount of smoke I get that teeny amount
of smoke I get from these great
concentrates we make after I say after
my lungs go cool the smokes going like
right now I got how about 15 minutes ago
and life changed I mean when I left the
house I was like 20 pounds I'm going
through a divorce and you like just
[ __ ] it I smoked a couple bowls and
I'm like hey let's get our hash Church
and hang out with my friends they should
cool we should get together and talk and
see if we can you set up with a good
supplement regiment because I've talked
more than a few people who have only
experienced cannabis and cannabis
medicine through smoking have their life
completely changed with a good
supplement regiment and supplement
consistent supplement dose and I'd be
happy to put some things together and
talk to you about some new ways you
could approach that that could introduce
new types of relationships that might
really help some of the things you're
going through as well yeah I this is
Wade I want to say yeah I used fingers
quite a bit so cool because
yeah I've smoked most of my life and I
can't smoke enough cannabis to get the
thing that I want and long ago I started
that in hash to what I was smoking and
still it abuses my lungs good as much as
I want and so I supplement with
tinctures and you can find tinctures
that are made that taste good for you
and meantime have significant enough
dose that I find it's as good I mean I
smoked because I enjoy smoking at this
point not because it's adding to my
cannabinoid levels in my blood
Forest tells me sometimes that I maybe
have too high a cannabinoid thing go on
in my blood but I enjoy the state of
being that I work for and I get a lot of
it from tinctures and occasionally I
have a chocolate or something but yeah I
can't get there with just smoke anymore
yeah mister you know some mr. buzzkill
sometimes go ahead sir no force well I
want to explore this um so and I'm gonna
every time I talk on me I sound like I'm
going to a coup feel special but it's
not like that these are just the facts
I'm super [ __ ] high-strung this
illness has really got me I used to take
20 values a day now I dump let's smoke
high quality bubble hash all day long
Jill said yesterday you realize you got
lung disease you smoke yeah I like it so
I take a thousand milligrams of cannabis
every night and a form of a peppermint
pattie or I would not sleep at all and I
think and you said something I think I
have too much damn cannabis not long
like like for real like I smoke
constantly and I eat constantly
I've never tried concentrated Rick
Simpson all like made from something
that'll really put me down but I want to
talk about tolerance I mean you said
you've eaten glycerin all your life and
tinctures and stuff I mean how many
people are you know like me they're in
their 40s or 50s and they use canvas all
their life for medicine and as you said
you just can't smoke enough anymore or a
tincture I mean what is what is what is
the solution of that fell off well I
mean yeah understanding what tolerance
is I think is really important for
everybody I'm sure mark could add a lot
to this so if I miss something let me
know but tolerance is essentially it's
good to understand the physiology of
phyto cannabinoids and essentially to
boil it down simply as as they mimic
endogenous cannabinoids so the body has
a hard time telling the difference
between the two so th sees chemical
structures so closely resembles an and
amide that when it bonds to the cb1
receptor the body thinks it's the signal
from an anthem ID it acts accordingly we
get miracle responses in the body right
we don't get the consequences of
neurotransmitter rate regulation gone
wild so when you're flooding your body
with high doses of THC your body has
more than one safety mechanism and it's
your endocannabinoids system is a safety
mechanism really it's job is to trigger
and respond to things that are going
wrong in the bar
specifically when you're flooding your
body with THC other safety mechanisms
start to trigger in one of those is the
body's observance of over-and-under
production of an and mind so it starts
to think wow I must be really over
producing endocannabinoids because I
look at all this an and amide in my
stream even though it's so what it
starts to do is it starts to
down-regulate cb1 receptors which means
it starts to shut them off and
essentially what happens is it's not the
people with high tolerance are able to
just handle a bunch of cannabis
they just can't absorb the cannabis so
they're urinating it out and it's
flushing out the body in other ways
because your body is a safety mechanism
has turned off a large majority of the
cb1 receptors and this is where the
concept of a reset comes in with some
people so and when you pull them when
you withhold the phyto cannabinoids from
the body all of a sudden the body says
oh my god I've quit producing all this
in an demise something must be wrong
and it starts to upregulate and turn in
turn on all the cb1 receptors
essentially so you can if you find that
you're in a place where you built up a
lot of tolerance what you've done is
you've shut down a lot of cb1 receptors
and you can find that if you can get
those to up regulate and turn back on
you can get just as much of a feeling
with less cannabis because you're able
to absorb more so you can lower the dose
without losing some of the effect that
you like but it takes time to allow the
body to up regulate those receptors but
when I say time you know we're talking
there are some studies have shown 72
hours you know but you know a week is
more than enough a lot of times to have
that sort of effect force can I tell one
of my stories you know I'm famous for
stories do I tell one of my story that's
Marcus's show you guys ask him it's
short it's short so when I am when I got
popped the second time and did my little
jaunt up in a can and everything I was
under lock and key for around 19 months
and before before I left I had sent
Jilly about an eighth of Jack's cleaner
and about an 8:15
to organ as we were supposed to meet the
day before they grabbed me so she put
some of it away and bless her heart
forever and when I got out there was
more time I had to pee for all you know
that you know the game but then there
became a day when I was allowed to get
high again for the first time in almost
two years
and is this a guy who smokes you know
full-time all the time and so I'm in my
head I'm that guy so Jill's making
dinner and we get the weed out if
there's only a couple grams left she's
saved and so I take one hit of the Danny
Boy I'm telling you right now before I
finish the story I should have [ __ ]
stopped there but but then I took
another hit about Jack's cleaner that
lemony freshness and she went into the
kitchen and I got so high like
uncomfortably like every person that
ever came to my house in Florida I got
up so stoned they got lost when they
left it was like instant karma payback
the Jill was talking like Charlie
Brown's teacher walk walk walk walk I
couldn't talk I couldn't communicate and
my favorite part of the story was until
the next day that I can actually
communicate help [ __ ] stoned I
actually got cuz I got going I'm really
alright I'm really hard she kept going
oh good good the next morning I was like
look the house was flying through space
so that that I mean I guess all my
receptors reset my body went back to a
virgin state and and the other funny
part about this story is for about six
months every time I got hot pass out and
she would go I thought this guy was some
hardcore stoner or some [ __ ] and it took
four or five months before I could
function again as a normal person
smoking cannabis I doesn't know I like
that story two years off that's a
substantial a break for sure the last
thing I would just add so cool and again
let's let's get in touch after the show
and I'm gonna help and I can even send
you some things is that there is a
completely new experience people have
when you keep sustained levels of
healing cannabinoids in the body for a
two to three-week period of time right
and when as opposed to what we're used
to which are these blasts which are
spiking waves get these big increases
these decreases and you can continue to
do that but when you keep a supplement
level sustain level in the body differ
types of reactions start to happen and
in we at this point I've seen so many
amazing results in different conditions
that you know you get more and more
confident saying just I would highly
doubt that it would not have some sort
of improvement in your in your condition
and a lot of times it's just it's a
different type of relationship you know
and but when when you experience it it
just shows how much we still have to
learn about this amazing plant in
different ways we can integrate it into
our lives forest I appreciate it I will
definitely take you up on this it's the
anxiety level and I ain't gonna go off
again the problem with alpha and and and
cannabis is so Friday I felt great I
started harvesting my [ __ ] there's teeth
falling all over the place my condition
feels pretty good I feel normal and this
is I'm digressing into personal shipping
but then when it hits it's just a whammy
like like last night I couldn't take
three steps without gas praying and
panning so I don't move very fast and I
honestly believe that it's not just
alpha I believe that is a panic
condition I believe my lungs are
vibrating or whatever the hell's going
on
and I can't breathe and so exasperates
itself enough always believed if I could
get an infusion of cannabis at that time
whatever cannabinoid works from cbn or
whatever the hell it is if I could get
an infusion of cannabis at that time
without taking a giant hit of hash and
the lungs that are already trashed I
think I could get much better results
than sitting there and I told you I gave
up drugs so when I have a full-blown
panic attack I cease your attack the
only tool I have right now is I went to
a class that taught me how to not get
myself to be present not to be past or
future trip and I can actually take a
panic attack and not lose my mind but
God would it be cool if I had a liquid
or something that I could consume that
would act fast to bring that down you're
telling me there's something available
oh well yeah kava kava extract sub I
expected somebody for a friend who was
having serious anxiety and it's not a
very big yield it's a beautiful golden
oil and just a tiny dot of it
on the end of a flat Chinese chopstick
will bring a speed freak down to ground
in ten minutes it's the hottest thing
since sunburn when it comes to anxiety
I'll be like almond extract by the kava
and I'll expect it for you how the
extract is is amazing and you know it
that in but we've also seen with PTSD
and other issues the the the problem is
is it's learning how to look at it in a
little bit of a different way where
we're reactive with cannabis right now
so we have an experience and we go to
cannabis for that reactive response and
and with a lot of these supplement
health approaches that can be used with
cannabis it's a proactive response right
so instead of we using cannabis and
looking forward in time to how you're
gonna feel in a few minutes or an hour
we want to look at supplementing these
cannabinoids in the body in a way where
we look backwards so it's we look back
and say okay how many anxiety attacks
did I have in the last 30 days we get a
good journal of that and see what we
have and we start to work with these
supplements for two-three weeks and then
we look back over that period of time
and we measure how many did we have well
gosh I only had three as opposed to 17
okay we're on the right track and it's
just a it's a different type of process
and it's a different type of it takes a
little more time right it's not
something that it's it's immediate but
I've seen it time and time again
especially with PTSD am sort of things I
serious anxiety attacks and those sort
of things that it absolutely can benefit
and I think you're absolutely right I
mean if you are in a state of panic and
you're concerned about your health all
those things modulate your
endocannabinoids system and your
endocannabinoids systems job is to
regulate the things in the body that
prevent panic attacks and prevents these
other things from happening so they're
all tied in together which is you know
why I advocate everybody being on a
supplement of CBD and certain other
cannabinoids THC being one of them CBC
etc
because like an omega-3 you know because
it does have this proactive preventive
ability to help the body ride through
heavy times of stress that we might not
see coming all sorts of things so anyway
we don't have to keep sometimes I hate
speaking in front of really smart people
but I'm gonna head and do it now one of
the things that I mean would think I
would know this stuff but this show is
definitely about education so let's
learn together so I have the recently I
had the opportunity to be a judge for
the High Times Cannabis Cup and that
gave me the hash we could talk a whole
show about that but that's not what
we're talking about they gave me CBD
medicals like 35 kinds of CBD medals and
that was the most CBD I've ever consumed
in my life and the two things that I
noticed that surprised me was it did not
sedate me at all
like I thought if I took four or five
hundred milligrams of CBD but at
nighttime I would go to bed but
absolutely not
the other thing and you talked about
looking backwards and I want to tell you
that during that time I think my head
was clearer and I think I felt smarter
what what do you think of those
observations about high quantities of
CBD
yeah you grew brain cells well I mean we
see across the board and this is one of
the myths I like to to dispel a lot of
the concern with cannabis is right the
effects on children and learning and
does it decrease IQ points or not I can
tell you without a shadow of a doubt but
again we're working with developmentally
delayed and severe conditions but we see
across-the-board cognitive improvement
in kids we have kids who I mean
sometimes dramatic from not speaking to
starting to form words and starting to
use one word sounds you know so severe
conditions but from kids take Silas for
example from kids at times he's a
one-word kid you know he can't really
structure sentences together and as his
brain gets healthier and when we
introduce cannabinoids all of a sudden
we were getting full sentences out of
him like he would say things we'd built
turn and look like it had to be another
kid you know so
I'm a hundred percent on the train of
when you improve neuro cognition
function neurotransmitter regulation in
the brain when the body is able to work
you know homeostasis isn't just a
buzzword when it's able to be in the
proper balance there's no reason to
think that the functioning of your
physiological system is going to be
better in that that also includes the
function of the brain and in cognition
so I'm not one that has to be convinced
I see it every day all that turns around
the ability to pay attention if kids
can't pay attention because they're so
involved with what else is going on in
their body and the irritation is so
great they can't pay attention so you
might miss take that for the for not
developing but a minute they can pay
attention the minute they can actually
get some relief and start paying
attention they advanced rapidly just
like any other being this business of
being able to pay attention it's
something that we don't pay enough
attention to in our society morning I
was gonna talk to you when you're just
saying about the high melted CBD I just
good morning guys one something I just
went through this dude like I was having
a lot of problems with my knees and
stuff like that and I'm not really I
take CBD but I don't take high amounts
of it and they had these CBD bites and
it was at the High Times Cannabis Cup
here and they gave me a bag full of CBD
edibles and stuff like that just like
you said and I can see and I was able to
run up the stairs like I was just kind
of relaying when he said that to me I
was like [ __ ] I just that's what I'm
diggin shitty bags beside me right now
my I had all these CBD bites and they
were so good and they were 250 rounds of
bite out of time but I can totally
relate to that so I started eating more
and higher amounts of CBD right now and
I'm Korean and me at all I'm getting
more done I'm more active I'm getting
into do more things so going back to
rehab
like I Center in the gym for my injuries
into tai chi and stuff but I've been
eating a lot amount of high CBD now for
the last month just like over the
thousand milligrams a day and it's oxy
make me feel pretty good that's part of
the cannabis education you know we the
cloud you're set we're trying to provide
is that being present
aware of your own body right it's not
gonna hit you like a steamroller in
certain applications of cannabis
medicine you actually have to observe
and pay attention but sometimes when
you're observing and present in your
body and looking you notice miraculous
effects that can kind of you just miss
because you feel good you're doing
something else and you don't notice that
you didn't have that same pain that
would have been there because it didn't
occur and that's why a lot of people who
are really trying to deal with chronic
issues the number one thing I recommend
is that they're journaling their
incidents right how many incidents are
you having how intense are they so that
you can look back and look at it you
know with an impartial view of seeing
exactly what was occurring because we
distort things in our mind we get busy
we're going off and when we feel good
sometimes we just don't notice so then
we quit on the treatments or we don't
continue as maybe a supplement that
really benefitted our lives and then all
of a sudden the pains back you know
because we're not just being present and
observing and treating it like the
medicine it is that it needs to be
maintained and there's some work in
there but when you can really approach
it that way
observe your body be present journal and
log the incidents so you can see what is
and isn't working you can really dial in
a system that can have huge benefits on
quality alive but it is a proactive
approach as opposed to a lot of our
experience with cannabis was just more
reactive and immediate I noticed from
taking 1/2 a teaspoon of CBD a day that
I have I've been doing that for a past 4
or 5 months now and one of the things
I've noticed over a period of time of
doing it is a tremendous feeling of
well-being that I find in my body that I
didn't have before and I just feel I
wake up in the morning and I feel
well-being and I get up and I've got
energy and my three titanium cages in my
back aren't hurting me and my frozen
sciatic nerve from the titanium cages
isn't bothering me and I had this
feeling of well-being and so I gravitate
I eat a have a spoon of it every single
day because it leaves me with that
feeling of well-being I
you can call that a hi if you want to
look at it a certain way I know that Sam
doesn't feel like you get a high off CBD
but the feeling of well-being is it goes
back to my original statement it's hard
to feel bad when you're feeling good and
so I would love to share a funny story
on myself about how I learned this thing
we were talking about the effect of high
CBD dosing back and it has to do a
tincture sub cool
we were making a from ac/dc a tincture
that was really high in CBD not much THC
at all and we'd gotten it to where we
had 350 milligrams of CBD and that a
little half fluid ounce bottle like this
this is an example of it I don't know if
you can make it out but yeah anyway
early version of it the top wasn't very
good and I had one in my pocket
and I was sitting on a bench outside and
a long story short the top of the bottle
came off and it poured out on the bench
and I'd put a lot of effort into making
that tincture and having it and I was
really wanting to it was a tragedy to me
that if they'd fallen on the bench and I
got down on my hands and knees and
licked it all up off the bench I'll tell
you what sleep that night I felt I it
was amazing within about an hour like I
have used my body pretty hard in my life
I don't have any serious conditions
really other than glaucoma which is what
brought me to cannabis in the first
place
but yeah I felt better I could not sleep
that night so cool you said something
like that earlier night that's what made
me think of this story I couldn't sleep
but I had a great night
I've caught up on some reading I've been
one to do the next day I got up I was
ready to go oh I had a great day by that
afternoon I took a nap woke up that
afternoon took dinner and went back to
sleep slept all night man
was really soon and ever since then yeah
I've tried to keep some I found actually
that small doses of CBD still in the
acid form which is a little bit hard to
do but in a tincture you can preserve
them still in the acid form and small
dosing actually works pretty well for me
I'm taking probably 20 25 milligrams a
day over the course of the day a few
drops at a time of a tincture like that
and it really helps a lot with my
general sense of well-being is how I
think of it it's more of a physical
experience than a psychoactive one
there's right yeah I think there's
really no psychoactive aspect to it
other than how good it can feel to feel
good feeling of well-being has to bleed
back through your entire sensory network
in your body in order for you to have it
so literally that means your whole body
is saying kudos to you and that's how
the sensation of feeling good comes on
and it's the same when you feel bad when
you feel bad your entire body is telling
you you're feeling bad and hey some make
yourself up elbow dammit and I'll come
and get you some Bratton but anyway look
look when when when when I have my own
home again and people don't get yelled
at for coming to my house you can come
stay with me if you would like to okay
um I was gonna show mark did you see
this on my feet I thought this was
pretty cool so I'm a wound up guy and
I'm also through nerd and I thought
maybe I loved ink so I thought I would
put my money where my mouth is this week
so one of my favorite terpenes is
Mercian so I had it tattooed on my hand
write them up right on the hand and I
turned weed with nice yeah but then when
I was doing some research I mean the
thing we're talking about man cannabis
terpenes are [ __ ] amazing and I'm
gonna say it wrong one of you smart guys
can help me it's a car car park our car
Pauline
but it's oil
but we're really close I have it on my
left hand yeah really yeah that's cool
man don't cuddle state terms carry on
what I believe
carry on Holly carry off away there you
go you got it all right now try beta
carry off aleene's and I got just so you
know I got oh I got a cat it's called
California honey I found it online
I'm assuming it's orange all right that
Turkey boy it's great it's great to
bring up conversation I love
conversation and so when I reach for
somebody now immediately they said why
does that tattoo on your hand BAM
because I love Terps I need my [ __ ] keep
doing your thing so I love it mark can I
ask you a couple questions about cuz
you're the man so I've been pressing
flowers having a blast I just learned to
change temperatures often different
strains but I have as I mentioned I'm
making a mountain of Keith and it's
early Keef so far it's gonna be late
Keef so last night I did a pressing
about 150 degrees I had a blowout
because I didn't position the bag right
and I actually ended up putting the
whole blowout back in a bag and making
something really nice but but what I
wanted from you when we're pressing
super high-quality Keef and I'm talking
about Keith it keep when you put in a
jar after a few minutes it becomes hash
can you tell me I say what you're
holding can you tell me like what
temperatures and times would you mind
sharing that with me for lift not bubble
the sift right well this was actually
some sift that we pro know this was
bubble actually sift it depends on the
on how how how much moisture is present
in it and how how clean that you've
gotten it because that'll also affect
the moisture
and so for me I get asked constantly
what my numbers are but they change
depending on what I'm running so for
sift you know if it was if it was really
sticky and kind of had a moisture
content and I might hit it as high as
200 degrees and you know if less
moisture I'll go for a longer time at a
lower temperature like 180 or something
and pressure on hash like like with
flowers I don't have a ton and then it's
hung and I pump it on my butt but when
you're dressed a little teeny packet of
whites if that was just harvested a
couple of days ago this is a delicate
thing so ya go over pressures you're not
smashing the [ __ ] out of it well you
know what that that's why there's
different ways there are there's the
electric generator that's not an an air
compressor that's like two grand us
that's the butter that's the best then
there's the air compressor with the foot
pedal then there is the hand pump which
is vert I like the hand pump in the m1
I've been using that a lot lately so
that my unfortunate thing is that I
don't have a pressure gauge between my
pump and my m1 right now but I can tell
you from past I've always hit around 80
psi is what I have my my compressor set
out when I'm using a compressor and I
hit it you know I hit it pretty hard I
prefer getting the majority of my of my
squish in one shot so we did this one
the other day and it was over 90% of
what there was to squish and we did this
at 200 degrees you can see it didn't
affect the color by any means it's very
chirpy smells amazing this is seedsman
haze it's just reeks like Turkey no lean
it's beautiful hey what's going on Josh
and Kelly hey family all good nice to
see everyone today hey guys nice just
sitting on the porch sitting on the
porch enjoying some daylight yeah we're
hoping to get some sunshine on her face
here in a moment
now it looks like it's gonna be a sunny
day here as well but I have to get out
obviously maybe in the next couple hours
I'll make my way out onto the house
sound for some of the last boating of
the season as we fall into fall awesome
I love fall in British Columbia but I
love winter a lot more so fall is kind
of us like its shoulder season for us
yeah it's wading through the mud until
the snow falls shoulder season so how
are things going in the Kootenays really
amazing we've had a really tremendous
year despite all of the that we've had
we've had a really nice dry hot summer
so it's been really helpful for all of
our crops you know we could have not
done with the smoke that was pretty
awful but we were thankful that we
didn't have brain all summer like the
past three summers and we didn't have
ash falling off on Oliver all over all
of our herb or anything so that was nice
we have a lot of it in greenhouses and
we've gotten a few rainstorms but pretty
dry and sweet out so yeah a lot of
flowers amazing food all of the food
Gardens have rest themselves on ways
that you know we haven't seen in a
really long time and the fruit trees
apple trees are over abundant and yeah
we're making lots of food saving it so
we need to build another root cellar
basically yeah yeah we're collecting all
the food but we don't have anywhere to
put it right now we could definitely I
was open Tony would be here I like to
find out something about Puerto Rico but
uh yeah I'm wondering how they are
actually because they just got smashed
so hard I haven't heard anything back
same with dr. William Courtney and his
wife are in Dominica oh yeah also got
hit pretty hard and they haven't been in
touch so everyone's sort of hoping that
all of well everyone on those Caribbean
islands is okay it's kind of a scary
thing
having that ripped through Herman and
Jose
yeah well heading there so we usually do
to disaster relief and a lot of the
organizations that we work with might be
heading down so as of yesterday there's
big conversations that we might be
headed down with a group to go help
women and children in this one we'll
find out in the next week well right
just work a little bit weird yeah we
figured we'd just be sandals on the
ground helping out you know what I mean
sandals on the ground sounds like your
people there Sam who's that guy wearing
Birkenstocks it's it's winter you know
it's uh it's you guys mentioned
something earlier though if you don't
mind me asking kind of a disco so
there's going to be about I don't know a
couple of hundred tons of I think
they're calling it campfire oh gee is
the joke so this is this is cannabis
that is smoke flavored bacon flavored
and you know you know people are not
going to throw it away you know this is
going to be part of the 2017 season is
Ash and and smoke flavor cannabis so is
anybody seen any of this coming out it's
for the patients up right it's so when
you work it it won't have any flavor
that makes good sense so you can just
turn it into if it's distilled that the
distillation was done probably and it's
clean it shouldn't have any flavor
whatsoever right I didn't think of that
and I don't know if you guys know if
you've been watching us here we're not a
typical harvest here mark I think he
would be really impressed so we are
harvesting some giant colas for the
market our our garden is a charity card
and we have four families that we're
going to give $2,500 to if we can get it
to market but I have a 6x6 gorilla tent
with an air conditioner in it and I have
mr. bond flying out on the third we have
three giant freezers and we also have
Frenchie cannoli coming out so we're
hashing the garden I mean we chop it we
put it in freezers or we chop it and we
put it
Frenchie's little spinny machinee thingy
because i want to see some simple balls
out of my own garden and you know i
don't know i'm sure people are doing it
but we're actively hashing like a
seven-year 80 pound garden because i
don't have anywhere to hang that much
weed I just want to turn it into hatch
so I thought you'd like that
I am absolutely in 100% full support of
you hashing your garden I'm in support
of everyone hashing their gardens I
always grew my garden to hash it just
because well I
it's the hash that I was looking for on
the plant so it seemed to be make the
most sense to go right right for it
heystop yeah up here after Frenchy comes
there makes a big mess at your place
okay
I'll come and show you how to make cold
shift without water and make temple
balls without water there are about 10
times as nice and soft and good as
anything Frenchy does oh [ __ ]
and just throwing the glow down when
she's not even here to defend himself
I'll invite him in real quick hey
Frenchy interest talking [ __ ] about you
on wait now wait now wait but I will
kiss Frenchy on the lips and I'm not
kissing John yeah Frenchy he will have
gradation and zizi's these is I oh [ __ ]
he's like the coolest guy I know when it
comes to talk we'll call it injuries
balls versus French cheese balls
that's the morbid florist just put in
the chat room there so who's got the
nicest balls because stops going to hit
both of those balls falls at balls and
he'll let us know somebody repaint them
already
indras called balls by the way yes are
you guys I'm gonna cut out thank you
guys for letting me take over a minute
learn lots of stuff you'll laugh since
you guys are talking about CBD I don't
happen
have any CBD so I drove my ass to Sonoma
patient group and I'm gonna go in here
and get me some CBD do it really quick
if you're gonna hash your whole garden
like that with Frenchie might I hope you
have a good worm farm start because all
that all that leaf matter is just the
best worm food yeah I was talking to
ballin last night about I was talking to
bond last night about how to properly
lasagna the motto all I'm gonna use this
stuff called earthshine on my 400 gallon
pots which dissolves the roots so we're
gonna pile most of our bulk leaf
cannabis the stuff we can't sell to the
cookie makers on top of the pots and
then cover it with straw and let that
act it's like a kind of a compost things
that dissolve everything in those four
hundreds over the season so we're
absolutely gonna put as much carbon from
the plant back into our garden we can
that's the way to go you could probably
throw some worms in there too over the
winter and they would come alive I mean
they would stay alive and propagate just
just break it down stagger add to it on
it I've got it if you guys sent me
follow me so I became a worm farmer this
year and I learned that worm farming is
as much work as cannabis so I have these
giant bins out back in my house that we
work every day for a long time but then
we got busy so now I went down the other
day thinking that my worms were probably
dead and whoa they're not but what I
have is three boxes of slime it used to
be eggs and garbage and stuff and I have
a million worms so I figured I would put
like a double handful in each pot before
I put the hay down and they'll be good
to go that's the way to go good job I
love it yeah beautiful
hey sup cool make sure that you reach
out I'll be happy to get you some things
and help you set up a good supplement
regimen foster I really really
appreciate it and I'll have may like
reach out right away I know he's got
your contact information as he doesn't
cool this is wait I know you're running
but I wanted to let you know that over
the last few years some of the genetics
that you've put out there have been good
mother plants for crosses that we've
been doing here in Nevada County we're
getting really lovely things thank you
or put now it's not there that makes my
blood next I'm cool same here
thanks guys I love you guys I love I
love the cannabis community I do not
know what I would do without you people
right now
thank you much love did he say you
people you meet us peoples us us peoples
these are my peoples the cannabis family
worst comes to worst my peoples comes
first people for you right there
peace out sub thanks for coming in bro
but though from the kid yeah always nice
to have sub stop in and share a little
bit of his time I mean the guy is
definitely busy when you know every time
he comes in Sunday morning is in this
car driving like I got to go to the
garden just gonna harvest 120 pounds
alright well that's good I like making
his own worms and and worm castings can
be an issue because commercial worm
farms often feed their worms with grains
and they don't have a proper way of
vetting the grains to know that there's
no glyphosate in there and it's easily
it's possible and I bet if you test a
lot of the worm castings commercial that
are on the on the market you'll find
glyphosate and other residues in there
so what you feed the worms is absolutely
crucial and it's not just getting worm
castings as being a really magic thing
for your gardening so once again knowing
your inputs is huge especially when
you're making hash or doing any kind of
concentrate you really got to know what
you put into the plant when you grew it
that's why I was out making what when I
use my rabbit poo I mix in 15 percent
oak leaf mulch because the worms love
oak leaf mulch that's so that's the
beauty I love that llamas alpacas
rabbits like the best poop on earth and
utilizing leaf material now that we're
coming into fall is tremendous you can
think about a tree and what it up takes
from those deep roots they're like a
mineral mineral miner's
and if you utilize those leaves is your
carbon source and your lasagna layering
or in your worm farms you're gonna have
a lot of minerals and our big focus
right now is raising our bricks readings
and raising our roof acto meters so that
we have higher mineral content in all of
our foods so it's more nutrient-dense or
your nutrient dense ganja yeah you know
what rabbit poo is the best food there
is it's better than the other ones that
you mentioned you can plant a seed in a
turd right out of a rabbits butt and it
won't burn and it'll grow well and so I
use rabbit poo and rabbit poo tea
extensively throughout the growing
season and if you look on my Instagram
at my buds they're thoroughly populated
with trichomes everywhere the buds are
huge some of them I've got some 14 inch
long tops that are eight inches at the
bottom where they start I've had to prop
the plan up numerous different ways and
they they look like someone sprinkled
sugar all over them and I didn't use any
other chemicals or any other nonsense I
use rabbit poop worms I get the worms in
the rabbit poo from the rabbit meat farm
it's got rabbit urine in it and I use
that and I don't use any other stuff on
it whatsoever so I don't spray it I
don't put any bug stuff on it I don't
put any preventative mold or moisture
things in place because it doesn't need
it when they've got the right amount of
food they fight for themselves and they
do a magnificent job you've got to give
them what they want they need food they
need attention they need love they
reward you with the medicine it's a
simple paradigm that's our Instagram
handle intro yeah yeah what's your
Instagram handle for those who wanna
it's under pure extracts John Davis on
Instagram that sounds good I was
envisioning a rabbit poop clone puck
it would make sense rabbit poo is the
very best stuff I've grown everything in
it and everything likes it nothing
doesn't like rabbit food except for I'm
not I wouldn't want to bathe in under
anything but as far as all my face my
tomatoes look at I did it bathe in it
probably yeah it might actually be okay
who knows but it'll be a while before I
give that a try though but as far as the
plants go I bathe them in it and I do a
lot of things that other people don't do
I don't believe in failure feeding
because I think follow your feeding when
you're spraying manure on plant leaves
is the primary cause of starting mold
and other stuff to grow up in your lead
system so I don't do that instead I
during the season ice I water my whole
plant from the top down a few times and
keeps everything off of it and I just
take good care of them and I keep every
three days I put rabbit poo teeth in
with them and they just it doesn't burn
and and they just keep producing more
and more trichomes and by the way my CBD
plants are just eating that rabbit booty
up like crazy I'm not seen CBD buds like
I seen on the to CBD plants I'm growing
this year from feeding them the rabbit
food ate so I don't know what all is in
rabbit poop exactly but I've been using
it for 58 it probably has a lot to do
with what's getting fed to the rabbits
that's what you should be looking at you
know I bet you that rabbit poo is full
of rabbit [ __ ] I knew you were gonna say
tear knows stuff as well is that the
rabbits have an immaculate digestive
system so that no seeds pass through
their manure so you can feed them almost
anything seeded plants and then you're
gonna get a really high phosphorus in
that manure you know whenever there's
seeds or flower heads then that's pulled
out all of the phosphorus out of the
soil
and you know the green plants are gonna
be working on your nitrogen so you can
actually feed your rabbits in
conjunction with what's going on with
your gardens and you're not going to be
transmitting any seeds into your garden
here's a concept in your whole garden
cover crop it and then rabbit tractor it
yeah
rat rat attract bees I use 50% rabbit
poo I use 30% really good soil that I
mix up myself but I mix it out of good
things not Kraft no chemicals and then I
use a 10% oak leaf mulch and I put in a
little blood meal and a little bone meal
and I throw in a small handful of
minerals and the plants I've never had a
year when they didn't almost try to get
out of hand size wise you know the first
time when we started growing him in the
ground wheat we grew up 5 feet tall and
then we stripped all the leaves off of
it covered it with root tone and buried
it in a five foot deep hole and nothing
happened for weeks and weeks and weeks
and then finally one day we went up and
there was a three-foot tall plant there
and then four or five days later there
was a ten foot tall plant there so
changing that root it changing that part
of the plant into a root was a big plus
and so then we started feeding more
rabbit poo and then I came across the
idea of splitting the stock in four and
laying them down and just growing
branches not growing any more topper any
more main stock and when you just grow
branches all of your buds look the same
if you grow 200 pounds all 200 pounds
looked the same and so that was an
extremely good method the plants respond
well and they I put them in 600 gallon
bags when I'm growing in a season and
half of that is the rabbit flu and a lot
of people are thinking wow you can't put
that much fertilizer in but you know
I've been doing it for 56 years me and
Annie grew it forever in Southern
California and we are complete and total
a rabbit poo members yeah rabbit poo is
fantastic I think that rabbit manure is
definitely one of the best things that
you can utilize on your farm you know
people in BC we all dream about rabbit
tractors but we also have grizzly bears
and those damn things too they love to
have a basket full of rabbits for sure
but they are and the other thing about
the thing about rabbit manure and also
sheep manure because of their diet is
that a lot of people in France and
people who are growing like lavender
farms and they're utilizing it for
distillate for perfumery
is that they love sheep manure and
rabbit manure because of the terpenes in
it and they believe that it does bring
out terpenes in your clans or you can
use sheep's wool for mulch yeah and the
rabbit manure is also already pre
digested enough that it doesn't have to
read compost so it doesn't it's not
doesn't get hot so that's why it's such
a fantastic addition into your pots or
into your soil Larry what I learned
about it exactly was I was extracting
lavender for her birthday for seven
years in our plant in Kansas and their
main scientist dr. Daniel Julian flew
over on a jet to come see our factory he
only got it built up in Kansas and he
related the story of how they use rabbit
poo with the lavender and we got the
oils to bring out the oils yeah well I
get into Robert Hayes supply line by
bugging them for two years about
extracting some lavender and they
wouldn't ever pay attention to me
finally to get rid of me they sent me a
package of three-year-old lavender
flowers and said okay when you can
expect this and we like it we'll call
you otherwise you know you don't call
back anymore okay so I expected it in
four days later I got this crazy French
guy on the phone trying to speak English
and French mix up at the same time
telling me it was the best lavender
extract he ever saw in his life and they
want to know how in the world I did it
so a life-long
relationship with dr. Julia on the
20-year long relationship with him
figured big-time into what I know know
about flavor and fragrance extracting
and oils and so I got to work with him
for a very long time and I can tell you
that there's a lot more to the rabbit
food than we really even know about
every birthday but they studied it for a
long time and whatever it is that the
rabbits what you call an immaculate diet
is usually alfalfa and stuff like that
sometimes unfortunately glyphosate -
yeah well it hasn't been showing up yet
but maybe it shows up in everything it's
oh no it shows up in rabbit dung and
there's been studies that I've been done
on it so this is actually you know one
of the concerns about using using it as
again rabbits will eat just about
anything follower and glyphosate those
pass through their system well it's too
late mark because they've already found
that same crap in mother's breast milk
so it's a little late to be worrying
about what rabbit food does at this
point in time I just act like it's good
unfortunately as so people have studied
glyphosate in rabbit poo but they've
studied glyphosate in animals so you
know just bringing them and the number
one diet of commercial rabbits is is
often alfalfa pellets and alfalfa
pellets are being tremendously sprayed
by you know glite as well as GMO crops
so we have to be careful knowing you
know it really is easy to raise your own
rabbits because you can actually take a
small little rabbit tractor right along
your lawn if you only even have a small
lawn and you can create a tremendous
amount of rabbit manure in a really
small space leave it or not there's a
lot of totally organic rabbit meat farms
around and that are springing up that
only feed their rabbits the stuff that
they grow that as organic I've been
using some of them for years and some of
them
you go to them and the way they take
care of the rabbits is heartwarming you
know and so I don't recommend anything
commercial because everything that's
been commercialized unfortunately at
this point in time has been left me
wanting for the most part I don't use
any chemicals or stuff in any of the
plants that I grow and really I've been
expecting for a long time and and the
fact that insecticides and sulfur
compounds and micro butanol and other
stuff started showing up in plants is a
very disturbing trend we're trying to
defeat it by putting filtration systems
in our system that gets rid of it but I
wish everybody out there would stop with
the spraying of bug spray and powdery
mildew spray and stuff on the plants
because people have to ingest this stuff
and you guys want to make a dollar but
if you're gonna make a dollar and cause
more discomfort and more upset I think
you should try to find something else to
do in your time yeah and don't call it
medicine part bye-bye steep hill where
they're talking about eighty-six percent
of all the clones tested
we're contaminated with pesticides or
just saw that just saw that that's crazy
we have an idea FM we call it an
integrated pest and fungal management
program that we put out to the community
anyone that asks us about it and
predator mites and predators are so darn
easy to use that's not really something
you use in a cloning situation as much
well we're starting to feel like you
know the only clean clones out there are
the ones that actually come with
predators we've had to destroy 53% of
our extract and donate extract from
organic farms this year for Michael
butanol and a lot of those come with
flour tests that show clean and as soon
as we take that and extract it all of a
sudden it starts popping and it's been a
real problem and a lot of people get up
when we share those results back to him
but you know I like nothing I can do
about that but it one of the good things
is it's caused people to really question
their clone sources in the nursery
practices a little more so I'm hoping
this isn't as big a problem as it is
this the last couple years in the future
but it's there's products we make a
nasal spray for kids with epilepsy that
really needs a actually needs a high THC
low other compounds sort of profile and
we haven't been able to get one the test
the high THC gardens are just failing
left and right we haven't able to get
one the pass in a couple months so it's
is that what you're looking for yeah
yeah so basically with the nasal spray
we want the highest THC ratio we can
because we want to use this little
cannabis oil as possible this side we
don't have to go down this rabbit hole
but it has to do with the viscosity and
being able to aerosol eyes and the lower
the percentage the more oil you have to
put in which ends up making it thicker
so it's just it that's kind of the
thought behind it okay well I can supply
you with some of that and plus I have a
process that I use that I've developed
to take very thick cannabis oil and make
it very motile very easy I need I need
to drive up and we need to visit here
soon it sounds like yeah oh one thing
that I wanted to mention here is that
was the reason why and a lot of other
community members created the peer
certification it goes beyond Omri it
goes beyond NOP so to be able to find
flowers of people that have a peer
certification it means that they're only
growing off of a closed loop system so
all of the claims are made they're on
their property all of the seeds are made
they're on their property all of the
inputs are all what they have created on
their own property to keep it totally
closed loop and or knowing their inputs
that that come from off of their
property and working together as a
community and working together to keep
the medicine clean and knowing our
sources so within the pure
everyone's communicating with each other
on how to create the cleanest medicine
for the masses before the medicine and
everybody's flowers and concentrates are
coming up totally pure which is really
helpful so it's a way that the community
can help one another and sort of step
outside of the current organic standards
that are going on right now and
consumers it that's obviously needed the
other thing that's needed is we need to
take each one of these compounds of
pesticides and fungicides and spray a
mother plant
grow it big test it if it comes out
contaminated make clones from it well as
a big mother plant before we flower it
test the clones if those are
contaminated clones those clones test it
until we can find out how many
generations does it really take to get
rid of these goddamn things and it's a
warning for growers if people realize
this they're much less likely to have
anything to do with them in any way it's
powerful because you're not making a
dollar and like Indra was saying I
believe it's you know people are like
you know I'm gonna leak this out and
make a dollar when you end up losing a
dollar and making people sick so it's a
really powerful wake-up call for
recreational FAR's to not become w r ck
what creational well people don't be
compassionate there's the variance
idiots take it off today and then not
spraying it again for three years and
three years down the road take a sample
of the soil in your greenhouse and it'll
still be severely contaminated with the
spray from three years ago but that
depends on what the spray is also
doesn't become contaminated forever both
ultraviolet light and just soil
microorganisms can disperse and destroy
the some of these chemicals and that's
real and we're working with some farms
that did use pesticides and some
chemical fertilizers in the past and
they had
using Korean natural farming and also
just clothes micro remediation
closed-loop systems part of the reason
another aspect of closed-loop systems
that work is in the part of having a
closed-loop is that you're digesting
organic material and you're doing that
with microorganisms that excuse me that
clean the land and and and transform you
know those terrible compounds so I don't
know if we would ever know exactly how
long it takes we know that they're
they're very vigorous compounds to get
rid of but um so are some of the
mediating compounds so we're getting
some soil tests back that are showing
clean after one year now 200
two and a half years and so we're
showing some promise on that and we're
looking but we're using pretty serious
micro remediation with it I think not
that many people grow in the ground to
be honest I mean it's what I prefer but
what I'm interested in is showing the
the mother clones once once you've
sprayed them you know are they really
safety to use that year are they really
safe to make clones for the next year's
crop etc etc and that wouldn't be that
hard to do the science with it but it
hasn't been done yet
you'd be contaminating your land so I
know for me I would be like oh [ __ ] I'd
have to leave it can be done indoors
under light I mean right yeah
probably be a good idea for someone to
get on it eventually you know how far
does it pass it's kind of a frightening
thought well it's true but a lot of this
should have to pay for the testing of it
they should have be I mean from my point
of view the pharmaceutical companies and
the chemical companies that make
fungicides and pesticides are running an
ongoing science experiment on humans and
our environment and I think that this
one of the things that cannabis can do
for us as a culture is help us
understand that all these compounds were
putting into our environment putting
into our bodies putting on the plants
that we eat giving to the animals that
we eat it's it's a it's a it's we are
the guinea pigs in a giant experiment as
my I personally agree with you but yes
that said the majority of Americans eat
chemically grown food and GMO corn GMO
everything else it's just the way it is
and I don't hate to agree I think the
guinea pigs are probably insulted by
that you think well I don't want I'm not
saying that we are all pigs we are all
okay I'm poking fun at the euphemism
guinea pig that song yeah well I just
want us to it's a point of view about
what's going on the early organic
chemists who first worked out that oil
petroleum could be used to make
fertilizer for example or weapons
recognize that their lab assistants were
coming subject to all kinds of cancers
and they decided that it wasn't really
going to be that big a problem because
medicine would solve the problem by the
time it became an issue in the
population and I want us and I it from
my point of view it's still going on
that way we're really putting all these
compounds out there like glyphosate
because it has some properties about
being able to kill plants as if that's a
benefit
and cannabis I think is the conversation
that we're having that I think is really
important is that if you really want
medicinal cannabis cannabis that you can
assure the people that you're providing
it to is clean and free of issues you
really have to follow these practices of
sourcing everything from your own work
if you will your own place I feel very
fortunate to have a piece of land where
it's I've got enough space to have begun
the process that the folks that
dragonfly farms are exemplifying so
beautifully I think the mushrooms play a
part in it but a really huge thing is
sourcing the inputs that you're using
and all these various processes yes sir
wait don't you find this everybody every
large grower has gotten clones from
somebody else I get comments from other
people but they're always suspect I have
to recognize that the plants that I work
with if I haven't bred them and gotten
them here myself or that I'm working
with someone that I can trust the
cuttings they're providing are clean
that that that that plant if I haven't
if it's not my plant I don't know that
but yet in this work that I've been
doing for years one of the things that's
happened is people had gifted me
examples of things that they've found
that might be of benefit and more than a
few times though it turned out they were
a benefit and it's part of why I feel so
interested in how different cultivars
respond to the circumstances that I'm
able to give them and I've tried to
refine the circumstances if you will
again one of the reasons I'm interested
in how many generations can you clone a
mother plant and then a clone of the
clone and a clone of the clone before
there is no parts per trillion parts per
billion and it's truly cleaned up again
I think that would be a great thing to
do and I think it would be even more
interesting to try different soil
recipes in on that and different foliar
recipes and just to see what different
tech
you could use to speed up that process
because I do believe that it would be
different based off whatever environment
you are using I mean it could be
environmentally trained as well yeah I
mean I Hayes's are some of the land
races we get through it faster because
their genetics are closer to the earth
and maybe the hybrids would hang on to
it more that's just made up in my mind I
have no idea but yeah also maybe maybe
like viruses if you took just the very
very top atypical Mears tips maybe they
wouldn't have the contaminants or or
viruses in them yet and then reproduce
somebody in vitro yeah what happens I
plant corn take the corner you can buy
now corn seed and go out and plant it
and don't spray it and don't put like a
phosphate on it and don't do any of the
petrochemical stuff you have to do and
just watch it grow on its own in the
wild what do you think you get a smaller
corn claim very much smaller and
probably not a survivable plant so we
have the idea that we could put enough
poison in our foot to fend off other
stuff it's a little bit insane it's like
putting all of us on chemotherapy and
it's making a kind of a crazy assumption
which it doesn't make sense I know the
world needs food but there's been many
many studies showing that organically
grown food can be grown on a large
enough scale to provide the food without
the petrochemical thing all of the
plants that rely on petrochemicals if
you try to grow them on their own
without anything except rain fail
dismally and so we're like one season
away from starving to death and and
people don't realize it I mean what
happens if the petrochemicals aren't
available one year all of a sudden and
then now now you're looking at all the
crops putting out next to nothing or
dying off
and I think it's a dangerous spot we put
ourselves in instead we should be making
our plant stock strong healthy organic
able to put up with things without
petrochemicals it that that is available
all you have to do is use heirloom
varieties and join groups like the Seed
Savers Exchange well I do they pass
around heirloom varieties were worldwide
and I buy all the time I buy the seeds
in the little seed vault thing so that I
have them in case of a zombie apocalypse
I have all the dry and organic food and
stuff in case of a zombie apocalypse but
still all in all the the people who
produce the majority of the food are not
doing that they're using petrochemicals
and that's the problem a lot of the
stuff that we've got going on in our
bodies as a result of these
petrochemicals being in our food it's ok
they they don't want you to smoke
anything that might have insecticide on
it but here's a tomato that is so loaded
with chemicals that if bugs try to eat
it die and fall off on the ground
hey John so quitting your intestinal
flora it okay I just won't let you know
butane is a petrochemical and just to be
accurate just to be yeah Gannett we
don't use petrochemicals as crop
protection agents you know fungicides
insecticides are not petrochemical they
might be petrochemical base but that's
really you know sort of irrelevant
really it's not a relevant when you
putting it on the food mark how can you
say that ok she seems like he's in the
generation of these chemical things yeah
uh just to be accurate petrochemicals or
chemicals of derived Trillium and all of
us rely on infrastructure and airplanes
and automobiles and
trains that all need petrochemicals to
push things through the sky and through
over the ocean and had sucks that we
burn a lot of petrochemicals and we've
heard a lot of gasoline but all that
organic food still uses a lot of
petrochemicals in all the refrigeration
required for it and and all the impact
that society I mean let's face it we're
addicted to oil and part of it is yeah I
mean I'm not like you know saying that
this is how it has to be forever but as
long as there's cheap oil the reason why
you know I had a lettuce cost you know a
dollar ninety-nine at the grocery store
is because they're able to produce it
cheaply and you know that's what the
working family can afford that a four to
eight dollar had a level support I'm not
saying that organic is going to be you
know eight dollars a head but the point
is is that you're right the controls now
that any quantity 'he's use these
chemicals
there's micro no use that are out there
and the reason why we have an
environmental protection agency was to
register the active ingredients for
those uses and again we've been stymied
by the current administration because
the current director the EPA will not
allow even companies to approach them
with a registration for use on cannabis
so again an heiress is kind of left in
the dark because they're not going to
regulate just saying that oh it's
federally illegal and none of these
companies again can basically make a
product with any claims on it or
register it and when you get it
registered the you know thing about that
is typically with the EPA is that you
have to show both safety and efficacy so
you have to show that for the intended
market like if you're you know intending
us to be played on food or whatever that
it is safe and everything and so you're
for I mean all of these things what may
a crop protection chemical tip today is
one that breaks down and is very very
safe and is a very very safe profile but
it's very effective at controlling the
corn worm or whatever they're applying
it to be used for and yeah this is large
and the opposite of a systemic but yeah
yeah I mean kind of opposite of systemic
because a systemic what what they're
using now is active on like grams per
acre as opposed to grams per acre which
were the large broadcasted DDT and
things where they were just spraying
entire fields now they can reduce the
amount that they're spraying but now
what they're finding again with some of
these new things like the Neo Knicks for
example is it's having deleterious
impact on on off target off target
insects like the bees right so everyone
knows about colony collapse disorder I
mean this is one of the things that
again is problematic with the use of
things like imidacloprid which has a
really human safety thing which is what
the manufacturers were concerned about
if we spray this on produce our people
gonna get cancer are people gonna crawl
over right turns out people aren't at
the use rates that they're using it
because it's very effective at low use
rates but now after it's been used for
10 20 15 years that are finding now this
off target just like with with with with
glyphosate with glyphosate the target
enzyme in glyphosate is something called
epsp synthase which has to do with the
shikimate pathway to make aromatic amino
acids and so it completely inhibits that
and yet that doesn't have an impact on
on on mammals and humans or mammals but
what it does have an impact on is the
gut bacteria that's in our gut and in
the gut of other animals and select when
these rabbits are foraging and they're
foraging in fields that maybe weren't
sprayed directly with
the safe but maybe it was sprayed
downstream from where you know there was
either drift or erosion and you know
there could be again persistence of of
glyphosate in in in the environment but
most chemicals today will microbially
and physically degrade in the
environment by the time that produce
makes it to market and there's no
residuals or whatever residuals on the
produce they've done tests to show that
human exposure at those levels even
chronic exposure is not problematic but
none of this has been done with cannabis
and so as you know cannabis unlike
produce is not lost
and at least most of us don't watch
cannabis I know mark and all the hash
makers know no dude we watch no but the
point is is that you don't normally wash
cannabis but anything that is is
hydrocarbon like is the best way to
describe it in Juris so it's not
petrochemicals but most of these active
ingredients that are in crop protection
chemicals today are very fat soluble
will stick to the trichome and we'll end
up concentrating in any concentration
process and so you may not see it in the
flower like Forrest was saying when they
tested flower it came back clean but lo
and behold we test to concentrate and
now it's coming up because you're
concentrating it so the last point I'll
make is this goes back to the smokey
comment earlier that sub pool is making
which is if you distill it and if the
distillation is done in the right way
theoretically you could remove the
cannabinoids from anything that's left
behind including pesticide residuals or
smokey tasting residuals so this will be
the year of the distillate I think just
because of all the fires that are
happening out west I think you'll see a
lot of I know just from my phone's
memory officer a lot of interest in
making distillates this is here it seems
light and you guaranteed if there's that
many people making distillate
gonna be some smoky distillate in the in
some of these pens yeah well really
identify what those smoky compounds are
because actually some of the smoky
compounds are athlete's actually plant
growth regulators the essence of what
the forest released when it does burn
actually initiates new seed germination
so some of those compounds have actually
been explored as plant growth regulators
and things that up regulate things for
seed germination that happen and also
you know you're just talking about with
organic you know if you bring a
refractometer into a health food store
and you're you know testing the the
ratings on a lot of these foods they
really actually have zero nutrients you
know a lot of these organic foods that
are even local in our area that we feel
like are really healthy and good for us
are coming up really low on the roof
refractometer you know the idea of
nutrient-dense food is starting to
become a thing of the past unless we
really take a hold of this and start
adding Andry adding minerals into our
soil you can take a little garlic press
to the store to your cannabis farms or
to the place where you're getting your
alfalfa and just press it a drip out
onto the refractometer
and make that decision on where you're
gonna get your alfalfa from or your
chard or your carrots or whatever you're
doing it's one way of testing it and
even just with us here out on our farm
you know we feel like we have an amazing
soil we have all closed-loop systems
everything that we put into our farm is
from our farm here and you know when we
first your 10 years ago our vegetables
and fruits were very low and now over
time by adding a lot of minerals into
the soil adding more and more leaf
material you know oak leaf maple leaf
these kinds of things that are our
nutrient density is raising up a lot
higher in our food so the idea of just
organic doesn't really mean anything
unfortunately also organic means that it
has a tremendous amount of blood and
bone meal in that you know you talk to
organic farmers and there
number one and number two ingredients
that they're adding into their soil is
blood and bone meal and when you test
that blood and bone meal it may be
registered for organic youth but it
isn't organic and that's a loophole that
people are continuously using in the
cannabis industry and also in the
organic food industry and we would also
like to say we do use plastic for our
greenhouse but other than that we have
no other inputs coming in and we're
growing amazing food I mean we're just
using it you don't have to go for
petrochemicals or nothing you can wear
it is taking the the weeds that were
weeding out of our garden and putting
them in the water liquefying them and
watering them back into the earth and we
have the biggest plants in the world and
well I just know I'm not understand we
have amazing food and potatoes and I
can't wait to harvest our squash patch
because it's like phenomenal amazing and
it's possible and it can be done on
large scales and organic isn't
necessarily ant the answer and as a
community we really need to challenge
ourselves to to do more in order to say
are there what about what about
closed-loop vegetables and fruits you
know so that we know that the people are
remineralizing by utilizing what they're
taking off of their farms man I'll tell
you we've done this earth in pretty good
we got to figure some [ __ ] out here in
the next couple of generations because
it's really crucial it's actually really
simple it's called give more than you
pay there it is
give more than you take beautiful Sam
that's exactly what it is I feel like
you know even organic farming is that
they're taking a lot and even even farms
that may be utilizing you know maybe
their cover crop or whatever but they're
still growing it out of the same soil so
that those cover crops can only uptake
what's in the soil already so if we're
not getting back to the soil and
continuously taking from it it's just
not going to be helpful
cover crops are good at fixing nitrogen
- from the air
but like you said earlier Sam that takes
a few years to really kick in yep that's
absolutely true because I bet an organic
biodynamic farmer for since 1972 and you
know it it takes time to build up really
really nice soil it's work worth doing
here in California there's actually
funding for farmers to build soil
content and what they're really talking
about is the same sort of thing we're
talking about is strive to add organic
content to the soil of course if your
cannabis farmer they're not willing to
talk to you but yeah and I got to sign
off here pretty soon
but I wanted to say thank you Marcus for
what's happening here and Forrest I'd
like to go with you to see Indra and
Zander I'd like to look forward to
meeting yeah that sounds like a fun road
trip needs a met yeah yeah so anyway
much love much respect thank you Marcus
thank you all of you for this
information and the work you guys are
doing
I learned something here every day it
blows me away
thank you so thanks for pointing out
Wade thanks for coming out and spending
some time with us we do appreciate it
hey thanks so much Wade we really
appreciate everything that you're doing
and you know we sent you an email last
week so um I don't know if you got that
but I will look I will look for it and
if I haven't found it if you don't hear
from me in a few days please bounce with
me another one
we just want to know how we can support
you in forests that's that's that's
really the base of it and how we can
continue your garments and then in turn
helping to support forests and what he's
doing we're a hundred percent behind you
guys and whatever we can do we're in
well that sounds like another trip
things that happen yeah Cheers
ciao thank you guys
yeah come on up to Canada forests all
I'll be there for that trip oh it's
happening it's gonna happen the next
year
nice amazing clatters Network world tour
okay of course well you know Canada
Canada has a federal program so you
could get into some pretty good spots I
think to get that information out yeah
I've been looking at a few events and we
will talk about this another time but
yeah we're gonna time it right maybe for
next summer and there's some things
going on and hopefully because right
yeah absolutely so there's so much
information out there these days that
people actually have a hard time finding
the good information yeah so this is if
you can imagine a problem it's that's
why it's good to push that good
information up to the top every time you
find it get it out there so it makes it
a little bit easier for people to find I
you know I'm so deep into this to me it
doesn't seem that hard to find at all
but I know so many of the histories and
so many of the backgrounds of where the
information is coming from that that is
also very helpful to know what kind of
what the quality of the information that
you're getting is so I think once you
have a good foundational understanding
you're able to sift through things more
quickly you know you don't waste a lot
of time on bad you know papers and
articles and info but it's giving people
up to that level where they can just be
competent enough to be able to sift
through some of the nonsense that is the
you know negative part of the wonderful
thing we call the internet and free
information you know which is even doing
research on the sites that are releasing
that information in the first place you
know like there's definitely like you
know is it a trusted source of
information or is it one of these sort
of just like people fishing for for
attraction just not necessarily sharing
truths so we had one question that got
posted a few times I don't know mark if
you want to talk about it here on the
side chat because they asked a few times
about cancer and preventative cannabis
use
you see there yeah I mean I asking for
was research reference articles that
dealt with that issue and I think some
of the better ones are coming out of
Spain yeah well for those who can't read
the question the question is is there
evidence for cannabis as a preventive
medicine against cancer yes yes the
answer is yes unequivocally yes in fact
the US patent on cannabis proves it
right so it does have neuroprotective
activity in that it's a fat soluble
antioxidant so it deposits in the fatty
tissue like the brain and it quenches
free radicals free radicals form
mutations that lead into cancer
so yes yeah absolutely it does so in the
pancreas and does so in the liver as
well the other thing that it doesn't
deliver and we were talking about CBD
before one of the things that CBD how
CBD works is it lowers the metabolic
activity of metabolic degradation of
other component that's in the liver so
basically that's what's called
cytochrome p450 and related oxidative
enzymes and deliver that basically start
creating all kinds of things in the body
so part of the activity that CBD has it
basically lowers the degradation of
what's already in your in your blood a
good example of that is with THC you
take CBD and THC together and it makes
the combo last longer the effects right
exactly for that reason yep exactly
well I think you know although there's
not papers on this that what we know
about how cannabinoids interacts with
the cb2 receptor how they trigger
apoptosis and other cell death cycles
you know cancer is happening in our
bodies all the time the nerve our knees
are fighting them so you know
supplements of these cannabinoids
although I don't have a reference paper
to
point you to logic would suggest I do
then my wonderful I'd love to see it but
you know lo it would suggest that you
know any assistance you can have and
triggering that system and cancer cells
in the body is going to be beneficial
yeah absolutely so it's also
anti-angiogenic so you know the way that
tumors survive is in the what's called
extracellular matrix they emergent
growth factor and the growth factor
stimulates blood cell or blood vessel
formation from an existing artery or or
existing vein or a paleri to basically
sprout an artery or vein to the the
tumor itself and so if you can inhibit
the tumors ability to reroute vascular
plug feed itself it's one way of choking
tumor so it's it's anti it's also an
anti proliferative so they've also shown
and this is primarily the work by Manuel
Guzman in Spain it was probably Sam
arguably the lead researcher in terms of
cannabinoids and their impact on cancer
and actually looking to see molecular
mechanisms and fundamental markers that
show the impact that cannabinoids have
on tumors and you know anecdotally you
go to the you know internet and you'll
see yeah Rick Simpson oil you put it on
a tumor you keep putting it on
eventually it goes away so there is
something about this that you know
cannabinoids do have basically make
cancer go away is it a cure for cancer
maybe not has to be defined I think more
in the terms that medical science can
actually see it in terms of dosing and
understanding what the appropriate
medicine in terms of form and delivery
is a very very key thing I think that
I've said this before many times on
church I think the US pharmaceutical
industry has got the world believing
that whatever it is there's a pill for
it and so to me it's like you have to
get beyond that paradigm
something that you're gonna eat that
you're gonna ingest that's gonna go down
into your stomach that's going to
dissolve and have some miraculous effect
on your health you know if cancer is
here you put the medicine here on your
arm if that's where it is
so again localized delivery is really
really important because that aligns as
we know are not very water-soluble so
they have to be delivered in such a way
that can they can get to where they're
you know basically gonna be effective
you know we see I hear people some of
the people who come and ask for health
or saying well we're thinking about
cannabis but the type of cancer that we
have doesn't really respond well to
chemotherapy our doctor said but they
said they might have these new drugs
that help block the blood flow to the
cells and they actually caused some the
die by some word they trigger it may
trigger the cell death that's like wow
that's exactly what we do know and we're
still learning new things it does but
what things worse right now
that's what cannabis does it blocks
blood flow so it slows the duplication
of these rapidly duplicating cells and
it causes them to have a lifespan kind
of takes away their immortality that and
that's essentially what cancer is is
this rapid duplicating non dying cell
until it kills you and it's it's great
to see that there people are starting to
understand that a little better but it's
kind of sad when you know they're not
being encouraged to at least try it as a
benefit you know not necessarily cure
but something that could be beneficial
and told to hold off for the newest
pharmaceutical drug they're trying the
design that does the exact same thing
maybe the other thing that I wanted to
mention too is the fact that cannabis is
an adaptogenic you know along with a lot
of other plants and in you know the
plant kingdom as well as a lot in micro
mycology you know mushrooms are also
Anacapa genic so the cannabis decides
you know a lot of times when people
utilize with our immune systems with our
own intelligence and our own bodily
intelligence it really decides on how
it's going to help and heal us and along
with that adaptogenic in our body it
also becomes ad adaptogenic to our minds
I believe that cannabis helps us make
better decisions because it is an
adaptogenic it makes
us more adaptable beings on the planet
as well which I think you know it's
giving us a higher intelligence along
with the other adaptogenic mushrooms and
you know vegetation that's given
directly by Mother Nature they really
gotta just eat your immune system I mean
number one in us all the things we can
do just how many can we find that are
immune boosting you know that's that's
along with the cannabinoids and a line
with these adaptogenic things that
Mother Nature has given to us well don't
you think there's a connection into
music because I'm a musician I've played
music I think just about the same time
as I've been getting high so I begin I
just as long as I've been playing music
so for me the two things are very
connected and I what I get from one I
put into the other I feel that like my
spirituality and my ability to reach to
other people has to do with both the
plant but both music - so to me it's
like there's this universe that's been
created that creates you know like when
I express myself in my music I'm doing
so because my cannabinoid receptors are
firing and I'm John Cole trading and I'm
trying to let it come out man I'm doing
my best Garcia I'm just like letting it
go man and then when I look out in the
audience and I see like this dude just
totally like doing his thing - so he
just took a hit of some weed and he's
just he's getting into it - so it's like
to me I'm connecting with this guy right
I've never I don't even know this dude
right but we're connecting and we're for
that moment like we're on a different
level of spirituality and so I think
it's like yeah it's like I always tell
people it got us drawn on the walls of
the cave and what got you know musicians
I think especially jazz musicians when
they realized that maybe I mean the
stresses of life and the stress of the
worlds around them they could just you
know get nice and then a sudden it just
comes out in triple bars and comes out
and cheats because they're able to kind
of de-stress themselves to bring things
down
to where their creativity just overflows
into that other space that may not have
been there if you didn't consume you
know I don't know maybe and when you
stimulate your immune system you're
gonna stimulate all of those happy
receptors as well and that's why I just
can't see you know in separating
recreational from from you know
medicinal distressing you know I mean
last night we did a little bit of a test
trial we had a gathering with our
community we live in a really small
community and we handed out um probably
over 30 joints to everybody and I'll
tell you it was the best party that we
have had in a really long time it just
like a lot of people who might not
normally smoke or people who you know
might be smoking something that's not so
great I mean really everybody was
hugging one another last night and it
was like an ability to come together
through cannabis people love free joints
[Music]
those are nice joints - those are like
fat tase that's what I would say those
were so yeah that's nice it's good
Canadian joints when they be fat ace
yeah fat fat ace well-pleaded hey guys
it's about time my time has come to an
end I've got appointments starting at
noon so I just want to thank you for
having me on again and I will see you
guys next time
yes thanks for coming out Forrest in
fact the entire show is coming to a
close here so I want to thank everyone
for coming out as always it was great
discussion good conversation into our
third year here on hash Church and we
will see you all next week so thanks for
coming out everybody he says I had mark
everybody