hey hey hey what's up everybody we are
live and direct hash Church 2.0 episode
18 episode 18 and it's a bubble man's
birthday episode now I'm not obsessed
with celebrating my own birthday but I
thought what a great way to get people
to come into hash Church today so I
already got over a hundred watching
right now and I am about to about to
send out the links to the rest of the
group so let me just do that real quick
and that and send that and I think we're
good everyone good everyone good let's
just make sure that we're everyone's
hearing what needs to be heard yeah okay
good sometimes I worry about whether or
not the microphone was working or
something else so wonderful
we've got one hundred and seventy six
people watching now so that's pretty
pretty cool and we got a ten in the room
doing a birthday bond for the mr.
birthday boy I can't hear you buddy
oops hold on that's weird let me figure
this out real quick I figured something
was kind of going on play test sounds
okay well that's working that's working
hmm I can't hear a check and anyone else
in here I mean can you check one sec cuz
I checked my let me know if you guys
heard that ts speaking I heard a chant
well that's not good ooh can you hear me
now is not good at all I'm gonna figure
this out now
check check check check Nicole can we
figure this out that's yeah trying to
we've heard you can and you can hear me
as well yeah try again it yeah there we
go can you hear that is weird you knew
that check nemecheck do here check so
you guys can both hear me and you can
hear it's yeah but I can't hear at yeah
and I need to hear at 10 it's been so
long I've had him in hashed Church so
nice to see you brother but I know what
the problem is because I can hear my
test sound I can hear default speakers
built-in age
my mark skelton let's see if Mark can
talk hey Mark can hear me yeah alright
real quick let's try that can you hear
me now oh this is bad Marcus and Debby
just showed up
good morning guys this hurts my soul
happy birthday really hurts my soul that
I can't we can still say happy birthday
to joint birthday Paul in the detox we
can hear about that try default speakers
does that work come on there Bubba man
this is so strange
it's also not acknowledging anyone elses
warning guys talk it's not grabbing your
camera either so there's all we do the
whole thing if I have to but I'm gonna
try and figure it out first here to see
if there's something I can't do to
figure out and everyone can still hear
me oh no I won't give up damn it I am
okay it comes to this no I can't hear
anyone so I'm not quite sure King here
now testing testing one two
this has got to be annoying as healthy
people watching hmm you guys just keep
talking I'll just hope eventually to be
hearing you and if that works out
hey 80 and here Les Paul is that that's
behind you everyone that's not a Les
Paul it's an actual ukulele that looks
like a Les Paul but okay yeah not not
for sure no no no no but I knew Italy
yeah electric equal a li that way I
could play in and be you know raunchy
and laughs sometimes okay well if I jump
off it might close the whole thing okay
let's see what clothes is up I'm gonna
restart it and send the link out to
everyone so don't fret we'll see you
guys in a bit
all right here we go find out for sure
all right so you stepped out so what I
do have is I also have the IAC M news
which came in the International cab
annoyed medicines so cannabis use is
associated with lower probability of a
beastly and healthy people that came out
today also the degradation of THC over
the course of four years under different
storage conditions research has been
done on that and the US Florida lifted a
ban on smoking cannabis woohoo go
Florida yeah cannabis use in adolescents
decreased in Washington State after
legalization another study has come out
to prove that there is not increased
youth use and cannabis even in medical
rates and it looks to be in legal states
to cannabis use mitigates inflammation
associated with alcohol use see more
good news about cannabis and alcohol
Marcus is back all right good night I
could hear you I want to welcome all of
you guys it's a little bit interesting
is there's a new paper came out showing
a benefit for cannabis for autism
spectrum disorder some solid science
there International us believe it was a
US paper I could try and find it to send
its out but I think it's really good
news it confirms some of the things
we've been seeing okay I wanted to I
wanted to welcome a few people to the
room I mean obviously you're all welcome
to the room but I wasn't happy birthday
Marcus thank you can you hear me
happy birthday brother thank you thank
you I know now we can't hear you I can
hear you I can hear you no problem
really oh can you hear him
yeah you can't you hear Marcus yes yes
yes welcome Sam I wanted to welcome both
Debbie Goldsberry and Callie Blackwell
into the room it's nice to have some
ladies in hassed Church yes my friend
Sheila and Sheila
Sheila's good friends in the glassblower
community in fact she was at a party
here in Philadelphia yesterday right
yeah at marble slingers oh I was just
gonna say it was slinger they're
slinging marbles cranes I spent a lot of
time in Philadelphia in Chester County
in my life so I know your area very well
all right let's get this out of the way
first ladies and gentlemen happy
hip-hip-hooray
bond grips mother lovers this is great
no birthday action today I'm not gonna
lie it threw me off when I went nobody
could when I couldn't hear anybody go at
ya sorry trying out some new technology
from D nail some AlphaTech they gave me
these new comets I got one on the way
and a new carb cap too so trying that
out I was talking to him the other day
about about that very thing and about
what you thought of it I love that we
both get to be ambassadors for D now the
R&amp;D is fun yeah the comments are great I
find that they're oh they're basically
it's a little sapphire or quartz ball
that goes in route correct in the first
gen of the d-mail top I mean the second
generation of D nail tops had that hole
in the top and so does this one the new
core I guess it's a the Beagle made this
one so this actually has a hole in the
top too so it causes a rotation there
are this is the alpha or the beta run
actually will have a handle on it so
it's pretty awesome just got the other
day so trying it out and give it a very
nice ya know I was stoked when I saw
those I hit for the first time a say
what was it it was it was a red I want
to say Ruby but I don't know if it was
what is